Hey how's it going everybody
this is etho welcome back guys go get
your snacks aha
oh you didn't expect that did you well I
have I have coffee and cookies next to
me right now oh and as soon as I stop
blabbing on here I'm gonna enjoy them
but first I got to record my intro so we
are over at the library here and last
episode I got this thing wired up I was
actually really happy to to get that
done I don't know if it came across is
that but I I kind of been fearful I
wouldn't be able to do this and it
actually seems to have turned out okay
so I'm gonna cut be referring to this as
the book matrix okay it's not done just
yet we got it wired but we still have to
do a few things with it so the point of
this thing it's going to hold all our
enchanted books for the library here
right it's storage for them but it's
also a retrieval system for them so we
push a button over there and it's got to
deliver the books to us the one we
choose right so we got a couple things
to figure out yet I believe what we'll
end up doing here all these droppers are
facing like the middle here right so
we'll probably want to funnel them into
the middle and hopefully I got some
packed ice here I'm hoping the initial
inertia initial inertia from the
droppers shooting them out is enough to
carry them oh it's not ooh
well you know when you know what it's an
even number this way I don't like that
it's got to be an odd number things need
to be symmetrical I just will do it this
way then all right and we'll make this
the middle this is one seven wide we're
gonna try actually let's do it this way
let's keep a open line over here I'm
trying to avoid putting water right at
the top here like to push them
where they need to go because then you
got that water noise all the time right
although well hopefully we can get that
water noise a little bit farther away
anyway
so let's just make sure we're going to
put some stuff in there and we'll grab a
lever and just make sure it makes it all
the way to the edge there it should oh
you know I I just thought of something
this isn't going to work alright so that
does that okay
as far as I can tell it will always work
right but one thing I just realized if
we have it here in the middle there's a
chance that we'll probably go to the
left right let's just try this yeah darn
it okay so we do need to put water up
here all right
I'll get that going the other thing
though we got to figure out how we're
going to place the chess we want as much
storage as possible in a little space as
possible right and we kind of need them
all connected together so we'll put a
hopper down here and see so each of
these lines is going to hold the
enchanted books through one type of
enchantment like protection or blast
protection would be another one and so
on and so forth two double chests is
quite a bit of space might go for three
three chests for each type yeah let's go
for three should I make it mmm which I
move it forward so you got this problem
now are the ones in the corner don't
have as much space but I guess there are
some enchantments in the game that
aren't as common as others so maybe
we'll put those in the corner aha yes
there we go guys I got it put together
here and I'm pretty happy with how how
it turned out
so the challenge with it I wanted to be
able to access the droppers right that
way we can manually take books out if we
want
we have to have some way of putting them
in and we got to be able to put them in
the very first chest in array here so
yeah we can still reach the first chest
in it it funnels its way down to the
dropper right so that's good and then I
also wanted it to be to have that
automatic retrieval system so we have to
be able to shoot it somewhere we can
collect it right and then we also need
to run redstone to it so there's uh
there's actually quite a bit to this and
I I'm happy we got it figured out and
take as little space as possible so we
got everything side by side very good
and this is like the colossal mess of
chess it was a puzzle to get them in
here because you can't put chests next
to Chester you get an alternate trap
chest with chess and then you get a real
problem in the corners so there's a
there's one spot where I had to use a
hopper instead of a chest but otherwise
we have three double chests for each
type of enchantment which is awesome
that's plenty of storage space and now
we are going to move on to the item
elevator and stuff to move the books to
us so the goal is to get the book
somewhere over here like around here
maybe even a little bit forward would be
fine because this is where we're going
to do the enchanting and these are the
buttons to call the books right so can't
just like run the the books underneath
this way because we have all the wiring
and over there right so I figured
something out and I'm pretty happy with
this here let's try this out too just to
show you that no matter where I throw it
or where the items get shot they seem to
all go in the hole there it's great and
you can see they then run that way
fairly quickly they get taken over here
opposite direction of where we want to
go unfortunately but look at this I used
Pat dice for for the redstone here so
that's awesome it's able to pass through
to the redstone that way because we're
surrounded entirely by redstone this
whole thing that's the way I was able to
get it through it now we got to get to
item elevator and we need to align the
items against the wall otherwise we're
going to have trouble so had an idea
let's do it like this see we'll have the
water stream in the corner so it pushes
them against the wall here and probably
a couple blocks forward let's see we
want to a decent mount a space here too
so we we can walk move it a little bit
more Oh I managed to do this without
spilling water all over the Redstone to
which I'm very happy about yeah I think
we have pretty much enough space now one
thing I'm not so happy about with this
is it blocks our view of the library
right it's sort of a giant wall in the
way but I think it's fine like this area
is pretty open as it is it's almost nice
to have have a wall here umm because
otherwise you can see the whole building
in one room you know so having a little
bit of having the view blocked a little
bit isn't the worst thing in the world I
guess alright so basically what I'm
going to do is probably put an item
elevator around here do it like this
actually on second thought this is a
terrible idea I was going to go up and
then carry the books across the ceiling
of the library and then drop them down
on me why do that when we can go down
here go underneath the red stone the red
stone goes down like like two or three
more blocks here so we can easily go
underneath it and then make the items
come up or the books come up over here
with an item elevator uh-huh
then it's all hidden underground and we
don't need this extra junk over here and
in the ceiling now I didn't expect that
I actually got an item stuck in there I
was thrown a bunch of junk in here and
the sign got stuck on the very edge of
that ice block because I guess the water
is going on the right that one's going
to left that's the middle right there
and it can get stuck apparently so I'll
have to take out one more ice block over
there oh yeah it happened again uh-huh
but it does seem to be working
got the item elevator in so just the
moment you see the repeater pop up over
there any moment there we go
pretty cool pretty cool and I like it
let's go underneath just to show you
yeah so I got it pushing against the
wall again so it gets aligned properly
that's actually pretty big oh I might
want to put another water stream there
goes up to the item elevator here and
then up so it's pretty good now another
thing I'm going to have to do is put
down a bunch of signs and label all
these chests I wasn't able to decide
which I liked more either this way like
put some bookcases in front you can
still access the droppers like that it's
a little bit more tricky but it does
block the water and stuff makes it maybe
a little bit nicer because otherwise you
can see through the hoppers here so I
think up up but Jace's in front and then
I'll probably put signs on those like
that perhaps that labels what's in the
chest and then over here I got a workout
workout this button area too I'll
probably put it like this
maybe put bookcases down oops
I don't have still touch I really need
to get my ex fixed
maybe bookcases there then like wood
more bookcases on the top put the
buttons on the bookcases and then the
signs in between labeling what the
buttons call I think that would be cool
and I'm going to put a a tune that plays
to whenever we request a book so let me
get to that and we will check out the
finish system here
aha yes yes it is done guys I got a
complete here haven't tested it though
but if this works the way I wanted to
it's going to be amazing so cool
alright so this is the labels for all
the enchanted books I tried to group
them together as best as I could I kind
of messed up a little bit but it's
pretty good so we got our armors on the
Left here all our armor related
enchantments and then kind of kept the
helmets together which is good
we got fishing rods together here and
then we got our bow and chapman's on on
these lines we have our tool
enchantments down here and then finally
these last three signs cover our sword
enchantment so it's grouped together
pretty nicely I did not find this out
very well it's night time now I don't
want to risk a creeper not by this
redstone all right let's go so I also
had to put signs on these because the
only way to actually get the books into
here I can't automatically sort them so
I have to manually put them in here
which isn't too bad
uh-huh and I've started filling up the
chests which is great um so let's try it
out let's see let's just make sure it
works that I got it right so let's say I
come here to do some enchanting and I
see oh I need silk touch on my diamond
axe so just look for silk touch there it
is
alright takes a little moment
oh I'd read it too
oh not good
are they both okay first problem first
problem so I bet you those two are side
by side aren't they yeah they are so
they must be oh it must be triggering
two at once okay let's see if any others
do that it might just be specifically
those ones let's try let's call it
sharpness book sharpness book here it
comes
oh come on
no why did that not work no I've put so
much time into this it has to work
oh yeah and I'm sure a lot of you're
wondering what do I do if I have like
three enchantments on one book I just
picked the one that I think is most
valuable and I put it into there so I
think sharpness three winds out of these
I find sharpness books are actually
pretty rare compared to a lot and you
use them a lot too
alright fortune three is also very very
rare wait did I have that I might have
had that in the efficiency one for some
reason
oh no I'm not sure oh um yeah let me try
that again
that was silk touch maybe one knot next
to it was getting triggered okay we got
two again efficiency and silk touch okay
it was efficiency all right why did
sharpness not it did this time I heard
it
what why did it not work the first time
I did click it right the first time
alright um there might be some issues I
have to work out here this carpet
probably change it up a little bit I
just left it like this for now though
but might try to mix in a pattern to it
so it looks a little better and we also
in the future should set up some way of
dispensing lapis here I realized I never
did that
and like unenchanted books and then have
a spot like where we can like just throw
the book into a hopper and then it goes
into storage somewhere would be nice and
then I take it from that storage sort it
and put it into the matrix over there
book matrix uh-huh anyway that is how
this is going so far pretty happy with
it I'll have to work out the few issues
with it though but maybe we'll go do
something else for the rest this episode
alright everybody so how about we work
on our sandy city a little bit more
today as well we pretty much got the
structure figured out on this building
now all we got to do with it is add some
details some stuff to make it stand out
and and like look unique type of thing
like the staircase is an example or the
tree does little things on the outside
to finish up the build and one of the
things I see a lot whenever there's like
a desert city or desert village in a
video game they tend to have these
markets marketplaces or market booths
booths I hate that word the th on on
booths is impossible for me yeah
whenever there's there's one of these
they set up these little these little
stalls though outside the buildings so
maybe we'll do that I'm going to try
orange wool first
we'll do the classic pinstripe thing see
we got whites yes all right and there
and there and that's probably as wide as
we can make it and set up maybe some
more fences here uh-huh
nothing too complicated two more spring
good good
um we will probably set up like a well
in the city somewhere as well I think
that would be a good detail addition
okay that looks this looks a little
strange somehow feel like we need to
continue this if we're gonna connect to
the side maybe we'll leave it open all
right so we got a few of these booths
built booth booth I didn't say booth no
problem the booths booths booths I don't
know it's a tough one all right so we
got the orange one we got the red one up
there and then I threw a blue one back
here carpet on the ground and now I
brought some more stuff with me as gonna
put the armor stand back here and make
it look like it's actually selling
something I'm trying to avoid spamming
item frames all over the place because
they will cause a lag in this area and
I'd really really don't want that
armorstands do as well but if it's just
one that's not too too bad all right
do that and that there he's selling
clothes or armor or something let's
throw in a light maybe over here right
there is good hopefully little trapdoor
thing lots of little things like this
help all right and I was going to I did
bring some straw or some hay bales and
some melons maybe we'll throw a few
melons outside here some some
mm what would that be maybe some special
cactus fruits because I don't think you
could grow melons here to be honest
there is an area here it's like it
enclosed maybe we would put a cage here
for animals so we could like fence it
off perhaps and then throw an animal
back here that might work out okay
something like that that could be cool
and then maybe even change this out with
grass so they have something to eat okay
I got some sheep over here it's gonna be
a little bit tight in here
there's not a lot of space but they'll
be fine nope can't fit through the door
they're too fat come on I know you don't
want to go in there but it's very
important for the looks of this place
that you you just stand here all right
very good I like that I think that's
cool let's throw some leaves down here
maybe some extra straw for feeding them
oh let's do it that way ah sure all
right
actually I kind of wanted to go this way
how's that that way one goes down one
goes right one goes this way so they're
all different yeah yeah I like that
okay and I saw something on the reddit a
little while ago somebody made a barrel
I think they use spruce stores for it so
I want to try maybe put one of those
here
it's like spruce doors around two blocks
like that and then put a slab on the top
it's pretty tall barrel though that look
weird I don't know we'll try it out for
a while anyway
and maybe one last thing we'll do today
or try to do is set up the well so I
brought a cauldron with me and I was
thinking over here would be a cool
maybe let's dig a three-by-three a lot
of times when people make wells in this
game they always put the water right at
the top of the well which I never
understood like the point of a well is
to get water from underground right so
the water should be deep down in the
well should innit
like sometimes sure it fills up but I
don't know I think I'm going to dig the
well pretty deep and then put water at
the bottom and then might have a
cauldron with water and at the top and
we'll connect some defenses to it does
that work maybe one more and then like
connect it to a support beam of some
sort does it connect to the side no it
doesn't okay it would look better if I
think if we had like connected to the
side there and there but since it
doesn't alright we'll do it that way and
then throw up a beam maybe over here
actually let's take this out and I'll
probably throw some sandstone around
here or some stone as well okay so this
is the well I came up with I don't know
if it's good or not but we'll grow with
it I guess and I made it go from
sandstone to sand and then to gravel at
the very bottom where the water is so it
becomes the ground becomes more porous
as it gets to the water if that makes
sense put water in the culture in and
yeah are you ready for this detail this
is gonna blow your mind you ready for it
there's actually water in the barrel now
Oh uh-huh
not that you'd ever see it okay so here
we go this is the comments I picked out
for today's episode it says hey etho you
should totally do something about the
lava creeper entrance like something
with position like something that
positions that like something I know
what it says I don't know if it makes
sense like something with positions that
block the lab trying to I'm trying to
translate what it actually is supposed
to say like something
would position the block the lavis
something that would block the lava
stream so you can pass Oh something
about the sentence usually I can just
change out some words like by the press
of a button and then revert so the lava
flows again so basically saying some way
to block the lava so I can pass through
it it's something I've wanted to do
actually because I've died or or killed
many animals in that lava by the creeper
face but there is no space for Pistons
anywhere there I've tried it before when
I first built it and just not enough
space to fit them in unfortunately but
what I think I'll do I'll just set up
more portals around the man cave so that
if I if I need to move things to certain
locations it's a little bit easier than
going through the creeper face all the
time all right second comment for today
it says hey etho you should totally do
something about that that's the first
one hey etho I have a couple ideas for
the gold farm although it looks like
some people beat me to it yes a lot of
people commented on this so I was
thinking probably spaceship slash sci-fi
themed like maybe the Cloud City from
Star Wars with rockets and stuff
attached to the bottom that looks like
it's like it's holding it in the sky I
think that's how Cloud City works I
could be wrong or maybe just a spaceship
theme love the things you're doing in
your survival world keep up the good
work so last episode I asked what we
should do about the look of the gold
farm over there because it's pretty
messy doesn't really suit the world too
well in my opinion so a lot of people
said spaceship I don't know if I could
actually build a spaceship I don't know
if that's something I would be good at
but I might try it my try it's we will
see but anyways guys I hope you enjoyed
today's episode I have been having some
upload issues lately if you're wondering
where the videos are I'm not sure if
you're going to get this one when I
watch it too either so if there's a
delay that's that's what's going on the
last video I upload I uploaded I had to
upload three times and then it's
still didn't work and then I just left
it and took over a day for YouTube to
process it and then when I released it
it was only in 360p even though I
uploaded in 720 and then on top of that
the sub boxes didn't work on it so
people didn't get in their sub feet so
lots of issues hopefully it's better
with this video we will see but thank
you for watching guys I'll see you in
the next episode and if you have any
ideas again feel free to leave them in
the comments okay have a good day bye
bye