hello hello everybody
welcome back uh now might be an
excellent time to get your snacks
together to help make this possibly the
most
enjoyable moment greatest moment of your
life
but in all likelihood it's probably just
another etho video
um i have been hanging out here
at the enderman farm i did do a few
enchantments since last episode
and this sword did survive when i died
in that corner
the other day so don't worry about that
had a few people asking
uh so this was a level 50 enchantment
and i got efficiency three
fortune two unbreaking three that's kind
of
strange strange that it's fortune two
instead of three and efficiency three
instead of four or five
but that's still a good pick we got uh
diamond boots i did a level 22
enchantment to get these
you basically have a one in three chance
of getting feather falling four
if you do a level 22 enchantment
and lucky me i got it first try which is
awesome
something is going wrong with my
computer right now i hope i'm still
recording
um i also did a looting three this is a
level 50
and i got that and we're about to do
another one
i'm gonna get it ready here this is just
a temporary enchanting station
i set up here i'm gonna check to make
sure i'm recording and then i will
do the enchantment we're trying to get
protection for on
our armor suit and i'll show you why in
a second
all right i finally got a level 50 here
for we're going to do a diamond chest
plate
uh we're trying to get what is a
protection for
and there's about an 86.4 chance of that
if you're going for protection 4
on your armor stuff you probably want to
do
a level 50 enchantment as much as it
hurts
dang it man ah
oh well
so here's the deal
uh with the feather falling boots
i'm just thinking about traveling with
ender pearls
um so just uh with my armor on right now
i have
well let's just take it all off and hope
for the best here
if we throw an ender pearl with no armor
on we take two and a half hertz damage
that's fall damage that we're
getting if we put our feather falling on
let's wait to heal up here it greatly
reduces that
um come on come on
there we go oh even more than i thought
so we only to have a heart there
one heart
i wonder why it's inconsistent
one heart when i was doing it before i
thought i got one and a half hearts
half a heart half a heart
half a heart
anyway another way of reducing fall
damage is
using armor that has protection on
because that's like a general protection
from
things like fire and other things that
hurt you in the game
environmental damage and fall damage is
included in that
so we should take even less damage with
this on
half a heart full heart that's about the
same
we need more i think we need more pieces
with protection for on
it's too bad we didn't get it on that
and then i think we could probably
travel around with
just about no damage at all with ender
pearls
which would be really quick
uh with this xp pearl farm thing i have
here i'm
getting to level 50 in i think under 10
minutes no problem
uh it's it's actually pretty fun killing
them too
i like it instead of like going
afk the mob farm you're actually putting
work into it
getting levels with this one which makes
it a little more interesting
with the 1.2 patch coming out that's
going to change
things i think for me it comes out
tomorrow from what i hear
but when you're watching this it's
probably out already
and with that we get the new map heights
so they're doubling in height basically
which means all mob farms are pretty
much going to be
half as effective so
pretty much need double the space to get
the same amount of mobs to spawn
i'm guessing i don't know for sure
haven't tried it
but it's twice the amount of area the
game needs to check
to place mobs and that means it's twice
as likely it's going to cancel out and
not place any so this will probably be
half as effective when that comes out
don't you knock me off
um anyway we're not gonna do another end
episode we're gonna go
to the other world the real
minecraft world i am going to
i don't know what we're doing today i'll
think of something
okay so i thought something fun we could
do today uh
loaded with pearls right now i thought
we might go check out those mountains
over there this is by the cave
do a little exploring that's the glowing
tree up there
first i want to do sort of a speed test
on the ground here
see how quick we can get around i have
the feather falling
and protection 3 on
as you can see these don't take damage
from the fall damage
like the armor doesn't wear out from it
so
it can last forever basically if we're
for careful
getting ahead of myself that's pretty
quick
i should probably throw it a little bit
higher though
yeah it's cool so should be fun
exploring the mountains with these um
and i guess we'll get one of these going
to start off with
probably need some food so the patch is
coming out tomorrow
i didn't really want to do anything with
mob systems today because of that
um might work on the base a little bit
clean things up if we have time
i really do hope they
nerf the iron golems though like the
iron farming that is
going to be ridiculous if they allow
that to pass
because it sort of distracts the fun out
of caving
if iron loses its meaning
to me anyway if they do allow iron
golems
the farming to work in 1.2 if they don't
fix that
i'll probably skip using it for
a long time and hope they remove it
i'm not sure they might have removed it
already
loading island over there
just because it feels cheap to me and it
would wreck it my enjoyment of the game
i think
oh i'm not healing
mountain biomes would look really good
if you uh
take the time to plant some trees around
them i think uh
i think i mentioned this before but i've
actually accidentally loaded
one of my new worlds in 1.7.3
and when it has green grass and you
plant trees and oh it just looks so good
the land generation is really nice it's
just
barren and and i don't like the color of
the grass
oh we got prairies over there let's head
over here
more floating stuff
uh with the new mob ai if you watched my
last
uh minecraft
episode i showed a new mob system i
built an smp
that should work uh with the new ai
i'm pretty sure
so we will have a mob system that works
that doesn't use pistons
nice and simple one i'll probably build
that in this world
oh as my first one at least
first mob system because it's nice and
simple
um
want to explore too too much
just uh i've been curious what's over
here
oh it didn't make it and i'm
gonna gotta get some better food
uh yes
okay what do we have it's gonna take a
peek up over here and then we'll head
back and probably start building
is that a floating island uh no
hmm i like it
this is all new new generation here
i usually don't uh go too far from where
i start in worlds because i don't want
to
generate a whole lot of land in case
they change things with patches but i
think with the new patches they seem to
just withhold the features in older
worlds
which keeps them consistent but then you
don't get the new features
like the jungle biomes i won't be
getting jungle biomes sadly
but at least my world won't
have or won't look terrible
okay i'm gonna head back this was a nice
change
oh rolling hills over here
very nice i like it
i think that's uh i don't know that
might be a new arch i haven't seen
there's definitely one we've been to
already
i'm actually kind of lost i gotta go
gotta go this way
too slow too slow haha all right
let's head back
all righty welcome back home again i
think for the rest of this episode i'm
just going to work on a little projects
around the place
to make things nicer and work better
um kind of wondering what's going to
happen with these guys when 1.2 comes
out
i think yeah they're still there i
haven't checked on them in so long
need to work on that again i'm actually
surprised i've only found one village in
my world so far because i've covered a
lot of ground
really anyway
first thing we're going to do i'm going
to
install the lighting under our track
here
so that we don't get spider spawns and
then i'm going to cover it up with the
has
with the sandstone slabs uh if we have
any carts get
stuck in there i can always get them out
using furnace minecarts so i'm not too
worried
about covering it up
yeah thinking maybe adding one of those
bread makers down here for the cows
but anyway i'll do this first and we'll
see how it goes
and this is the lighting is just so that
don't get spiders spawning under the
half slabs i don't know if i said that
already
and i can't use or i shouldn't use
torches for it because we'll get the
particle effects
through the half slabs i think
yeah i'm getting particles
not seeing them though maybe we won't
kind of thought they would
anyway okay here i go
okay i got that all covered now um i've
noticed something here though
i wanted to show you like three of these
guys going around at once
but make that four
having a little issue with
loading them into the minecarts here
although it might work now that we have
a fourth but
uh let's see if
oh we did we got one
okay we got one let's see if we can get
another
yeah so they're kind of forcing each
other into specific corners
like uh this guy is in this uh
this corner here and then the other ones
are in that corner there
so minecart won't pick them up from this
corner
which means i have to be careful that
when i get the setup
that
like i might not be able to grab them
from the corners
because they throw each other off like
that
anyway where is he
i know he's around here
there he is ah this looks so awesome
i love it
okay so i am tempted to work on that
today i don't know how to do it
at the moment i'll have to think about
it a bit more
i was kind of thinking of
maybe fixing this in the middle here
um i'm not sure how i should light this
middle part it's really dark
i either have to put something here like
some kind of
object that comes out of the ground or i
would maybe
make a chandelier in the ceiling
that comes down and lights the middle
not sure yet
um need some more half slabs
running out of sound quick again
because i've been converting it to
sandstone
i think what i'll do here i'm going to
try to do kind of what dot cam does
with his rails i like the look of it
uh where he has the glass
all along
and then he puts half slabs on top
i think that's how he does it
you can see down still
and how does it look over here hmm
it's an idea i don't know needs more
light
for sure
um i might try it without the glass
okay i was thinking about it and i
probably shouldn't put a railing there
even though
i do want a railing just because it's
gonna block the cow face even more
if uh it goes up at the end there
and even the way i have it right now
it's blocked quite a bit so i might
try lower the center part here
a little bit kind of make a semi circle
that's lowered
and see how that turns out and if i do
that i could probably find a
way to hide some glowstone or lava or
something into it as well
probably glowstone we got wood around
here
so i'm going to do that the very center
would be
over here
and i haven't forgotten about your
suggestions on what i should do about
the frame
and it being uncentered because it's two
blocks there one block there
and a lot of people said just to stretch
it
copy the middle the middle pixels and
and duplicate them an extra line in so i
think
i'll try that today hopefully and
i'll copy this line here and stretch it
and we'll see how it looks
all right let me know what you guys
think of this i did uh i did something
here
hopefully something good i lowered the
middle
i was able to sneak in some lighting
that way
so it looks a lot better and i also have
some over here
it's kind of kind of expands out
which i like i might try put some fences
here and
here
i think my sound quit oh well
um you can see a lot more of the picture
this way
and yeah there's still no railing
here um let's take a look from
distance so
it's still rough below that but i should
be able to
clean that up too sometime soon and i'd
probably put another
light hidden somewhere around there in
the middle so i don't have that dark
spot
over there um i don't know has a little
more character than it just being
pure flat like it was and if i go down
the stairs like this i can still
continue and run up
to the other side which is good it has a
good flow to it
um maybe thinking of putting
fences here and just seeing how that
would look probably
won't look very good though
yeah it's not gonna look good i know it
already
fences allow you to see through still
which is nice
and you won't walk off but they don't
really connect to half slabs so
i don't know let's look from over here
yeah i don't know something to think
about i guess
okay so now i'm just going to stretch
that cow face and i'll probably get rid
of these
and then we'll see how it looks
you know what it actually turned out
pretty good here i like it
i was worried when i changed it i would
have to change it back because it would
look a little strange
but it just looks like a fat cow
which nothing wrong with that nothing
wrong with fat towels
so i think we're gonna keep it good
suggestion guys i wouldn't have tried it
with if you didn't suggest it
and now it's symmetrical yay
oh it just just makes me feel a lot
better
um i was gonna try this too
is that weird is that weird if i do that
i don't know i like to try to give
things more character
yeah i'll try it for a while um
one thing i was thinking
1.2 is actually out for me right now i'm
very tempted to just
quit recording here and go play with it
but
i have the day off tomorrow so that's
what i will be doing tomorrow probably
quite a bit but i was thinking
if i do that fence thing i might do the
upside down
wooden stairs i think there's upside
down wooden ones i hope
and put them underneath the fence and
it'll be like an overhang
that might look good the fence didn't
block out too much vision either so
just an idea and i'll round out other
things like over here for example
i wanted to mimic the bottom where it
goes down up down
up but you know it looks really chunky
compared to
the lower part i'll be able to smooth
that out in 1.2
which is good it's going to be an
awesome patch
looking forward to playing it um
as far as the tree farm goes i don't
think i'm going to expand it anymore
i kind of wish i would have added a
little more variety to it
but i didn't expect it to get this big
to be honest it's huge
so i'll just keep the walkway around and
then for the newer donors i'll try think
of something else we can do i have a few
few ideas but might be a while before i
get around to doing them
so and the thing i like about this too
is it's a it's a good number i think
it's 200
20 40 no 40 80
120 160 200 trees in here
which is good good size um
eventually i'll have to clean it up some
more fix the ceiling and do something
with that
um
yeah got lots of work to do around here
it's good though it's fun i like uh
cleaning up the cave and doing stuff
like that just not all the time
i like building or designing things too
it's good to have a good mix over here
i still haven't connected this
i don't know what i'm going to do
with this in between space here
i got a whole wall over here pretty much
and that little bit underneath
here
i have to think about it
actually i just checked the time of this
episode and it's getting to that point
where we should probably wrap it up
so before we do i just want to do one
last thing here
with the snow golems i was trying to
find a quicker way of harvesting snow
because as you know if you click you get
two snowballs so if you
rapidly click you get snowballs pretty
quick
but i recently wore out a mouse from
clicking so much and i would like to
avoid clicking more than i need to if
possible
so i tried harvesting the snow from a
distance you know how you can
break blocks quicker usually doing that
doesn't work with snow
same speed as normal
so then i tried setting up two of these
guys
side by side so that we could maybe
aim for the very corner and
as this one disappears maybe we'll get
that one and it'll
speed it up or something but
it doesn't happen so
i don't know i just know there's a
quicker way of doing it can't figure it
out though
or not today anyway besides clicking
like a madman anyway we're going to wrap
up this episode
here or end it and uh
i'm gonna probably play some 1.2 tonight
maybe play on the minecraft server a bit
tomorrow i'm gonna enjoy my day off and
play some minecraft some more i've
been a little bit limited on how much i
can play in a day recently
with my work uh so i'm gonna enjoy that
even on the weekends i'm usually really
busy so it's not like i have a day off
on the weekends to play
but yeah i hope you guys are enjoying
the 1.2 patch it looks awesome
lots of neat things in it i know i'm
gonna like it for sure
so take care guys
keep playing minecraft keep enjoying it
and thanks for watching