[Music]
uh-oh uh-oh did you guys hear about the
oh seven snapshot by chance I heard
about the oh seven snapshot a little too
late maybe if you're not familiar with
what happened in the oh seven snapshot
there was a big glitch a major one that
when you update from it like the Oh 8 or
oh nine which were on right now you lose
all your villagers which is kind of a
big deal we don't want that right so I
was forced to load a backup that I made
before I did the nether update which
means all that progress we made last
episode remember we went to the nether
we we got all that good stuff and then I
died at the very end and lost everything
unfortunately I had to load the backup
and now we got all our tools back all
our armors back the puddle stoppers the
split pants seashell scuba goggles eater
of worlds broke another pick the Trident
is back tried pool pooper-scooper we got
it all back and there's just nothing we
can do about it we just have to accept
it it's oh man so sad so sad right
uh-huh
anyways I thought that was kind of funny
because normally you know when glitches
happen it's like know why I lost all
this progress and stuff but because we
made negative progress we actually came
out ahead it I think I actually did a
fist bump when I found out I was like
yes I'm forced to load the back up
guilt-free I get all my stuff back so
you can see here I got about three
chakra boxes full of nether goodness
here I did go back again and got more
stuff I brought some TNT and used that
on like the warp box that was a quick
way of mining mining that stuff now that
TNT drops all the blocks it's it's a
it's like a really great way of mining
stuff in general soul say it or a soul
soil you can mine with a shovel mouse
who can collect that quickly
basalt TNT doesn't work good on basalt
though it seems to have a high blast
resistance so I just mind that with
pick and got a bunch of that playing
around with the new blue torches and
lamps and stuff the blue lamps look
really good next to the horns ones
actually which makes sense their
contrasting colors right they should go
together and yeah they look great
I did something over here it's it's
finally happened guys it's a reality
we've got the blue shiny thingy here we
can make the blue fire for realsies
which is awesome and I made it so it's
resettable so like we have an excuse to
burn more blue shiny so I actually wanna
take a moment to talk about this thing I
know it's like just a stupid little
gizmo but I had a whole lot of fun
making it like it's very unlike any
other redstone contraption I've ever
made it's very weird very weird like if
you tried to make this I think you guys
would quickly start scratching your head
and be like how did how did you do that
because like it does only work with the
blue shiny rocks like if I put dirt in
here it's not gonna trigger dirt doesn't
make blue fire only the blue shinies
make the blue fire which means like the
only way that's possible is if you make
a minecarts item filter you guys are
familiar with the hopper item filters
right you do something like that to do
that with a minecart is really strange
and I've attempted it like twice in the
past and like each time I gave up I got
frustrated and it's like this is stupid
when is anyone actually gonna use this
anyway well it's like the only way to
make this possible this device here so
it's like okay I'm gonna try it again
see if I can come up with it so we have
a minecart with hopper item filter here
the way this works that is sitting on a
detector rail and then we use a
comparator if a hopper minecarts on a
detector rail like a parrot can read the
signal we use that to figure out when
the next next one goes in right and you
see it goes down to 16 and then to get
shot in there to bring it back up to 18
that triggers the switching of the
Pistons here and stuff now the
thing is because of the month this is a
tricky part about because the minecart
is on detector rail like if you put a
hopper directly below that the detector
rail would keep the hopper powered and
locked right so you need another
minecart below that and I got this one
sitting on an activator rail and when do
you ever use activator rails right so we
use an activator rail here to lock this
hopper minecart so when it's powered
this is locked so that it doesn't take
the items out of this hopper minecart
and then when we add one to this we
unpowered for a split second so we can
take the items out and because hopper
mine carts are so fast the best I could
get to run is it taking three out
ideally you'd only want to take one out
maybe someone can design this better but
there's like leg with the comparator
triggering and then it's torch so I
can't make it instant uh-huh anyway so
to make up with that I send two more
back in with this dropper ideally you
would hook it up so that you take some
of the items out of here send them up a
water stream back into here to keep it
self-contained but I was kind of lazy
and didn't do it we can't put this
dropper right next to the detector rail
there though because then it would be
locked all the time so I have to slide
it across ice into it uh-huh
pretty weird right I thought that was
neat though kind of interesting I should
have mentioned this earlier it might be
too late now there's probably a million
comments about it I dunno you can mine
the nether wart blocks and the Warped
ones with the hose that's a new feature
in the snapshot so they gave these a
proper tool it's not the axe like like I
was expecting it would become it's
actually the hole which is I think the
first time the hole is the proper tool
for for blocks right on these two I
don't think I just want to double check
here I don't think you can enchant it
still though know so that's efficiency
can't put that on it yeah you let all
the animals out there free you're back
in there
okay so I think we should definitely go
check out the zombie pigmen farm today
because there's been some developments
with that and with the snapshots so we
got the new piglet mobs and we can trade
gold to them for items which is really
cool thing is they spawn in the nether
wastes which is where like our Pigman
farm is so that's gonna affect things
big-time
also even zombie Pigman got update they
got a new skin now so we can go check
that out let's see here let's go over
here
so yeah Sambi Pigman they got like the
ear flap now this is a little minor
change I think it's good though
these are the big line guys right these
guys the ones with the bows are nasty
they did turn on me I wasn't sure yeah
so it's still the same same old trick of
a mob it's a zombie Pigman after they
kill it they they go for you then so
it's kind of important to note with this
farm the old gold farms like this they
don't work as well as they used to if
you stay at them for a long time because
like you get zombie Pigman and pig lands
both spawning on it now nice throw ease
oh good job
did he not even get aggressive no he did
what you can see I mostly got pig lands
on the layers right now because I've
been at it for a few minutes here so the
zombie pigmen over time they die but the
piglets stay and accumulate and then it
kind of stops working until you leave
the area okay so I just found out
something else interesting here I went
over to our nether fortress because I
wanted to see some pig lines fighting
the wither skeletons they're like mortal
enemies but the pig legs don't seem to
spawn in the nether fortress at all
which is interesting because this is
another waste biome like they this is a
biome they can spawn in but they just
don't in the port
I've seen them outside of it but not
actually spawning in it okay awesome
check this out so I went back to our
nether hub and there's a piggelin just
hanging out here all on his own did I'd
imagine that or did he like just
teleport here and yeah look how fast he
runs what okay I never saw that before
so he tries to get opposites of you or
something I don't know they're probably
still a work in progress right there
seems to be a couple issues here anyways
one thing about these guys if you're
wearing gold Armour they leave you alone
yet then you're friends so that's nice I
think this is gonna be our guy we're
gonna try trade with though so I got a
nametag here for him so he doesn't he
spawn on us okay awesome so I'm actually
I'm trapped in a little holding area
here I got hopper underneath them keep
that locked for right now
hello that's enough to keep him
contained he's like two blocks tall so
the trapdoor is thick enough that he
can't get out I'm gonna throw him some
gold here and to see what happens right
I need to be wearing that gold armor you
didn't do anything with that okay that
that didn't go as I thought it would
let's try this again with gold armor on
I should probably look up how to do this
I just assumed oh he got it okay okay I
think I'm thinking maybe it's like
dropping below where he can reach maybe
like if it falls in that part of the
hopper that's a bit lower so he gave us
some glowstone dust there see go be a
little grab that doesn't look like so
you probably gotta use like some carbon
or something to look if it's on the edge
of the hopper yeah then you can grab it
okay so it's it's too low in the middle
of the hopper uh-huh so he takes the
gold he looks at it for a moment and
then he gives you something from a
random loot table a little different
than trading like with villagers because
with trading you choose what you want
with this it's random from a list
certain things are more preferable than
others and you can automate it with
droppers - that's so cool you could grab
that one right away - higher resistance
potion we do it again before he's done
yeah there's a there's a time delay to
it
he's got a process to trade here's a big
thing yeah he gave us some gravel only
one piece so I think it gives you
between 1 5 yea leather from these guys
there's a lot of really good stuff oh
snap ok this is way easier to automate
than I was expecting I've been messing
around with it here that hopper is not
locked right now does it need to be the
dropper always seems to deliver the gold
right to the Pigman like before the
hopper can grab it so you don't need to
control locking the hopper or anything
is this leave it open and then the
Pigman like doesn't even need to see you
or throw the item at you just like you
just drops it off in the hopper it seems
you seen that so it's like so easy then
you just need to hover clock to time it
I'm gonna try something did that a bit
more okay he just finished the trade and
got another one so I think this is about
the perfect amount of items nine items
that's what you want okay cool cool and
yeah we're getting all kinds of goodies
here including there's a brand new Block
in the game guys you see this you
probably have already but you know it's
it's pretty nice so there's a new type
of obsidian called
crying obsidian and it looks pretty cool
and it's it functions a lot like
obsidian it's hard to break you know got
some crazy particle effects to it it's
like dripping goop oh that guy's been
there for like forever - and I can't
believe that's what got him I thought
for sure I would just walk too close to
it one day but no skeleton did it
alright everybody so I'm just doing some
testing right now I made a copy of our
let's play world so that we could go
into creative here and try out a couple
things thinking maybe some band-aid
solutions to the penguin farm not that I
really need them because I usually don't
spend too long at the farm regardless
but if we do want to try fix it one idea
was to use wither skeletons these guys
do try to attack them and they seem to
see them from pretty far away even you
see that like this guy's pretty far away
and he's still going after them and then
they just fall down the tube which is
cool but it doesn't work with the baby
ones the baby ones don't try to play
them so that doesn't really solve the
problem because we'll just give tons of
baby ones eventually
so the other idea was to maybe use golds
to lure them and just have that refresh
every soft with the mechanism
[Music]
seems like the range on the gold is only
about eight blocks though then they'll
see it very far and also if they spawn
near zombie pigmen they try to run away
from them and that can mess up their
path by me like that guys running away
this does work on the baby ones though
which is kind of cool but yeah anyways
we're back to the real let's play world
here at DM and other idea is maybe we
just built a new cold farmland gold firm
number four could be fun
I do like building gold farms and
there's been a lot of a lot of changes
that might be worth doing because gold
is super valuable because you're
basically trading it for these items now
I don't think I'm gonna be making golden
carats anymore that's kind of a waste if
you can get these kind of goodies also
we're missing two items from the loot
list here still we don't have work now
Liam yet and we didn't get another right
Oh which is super rare it's like a 1 in
200 and something chance here we go
again so we are deep down in the nether
here guys in new terrain a workforce
down at y level 15 you guys told me this
is a good level apparently for finding
the ancient debris so I'm gonna try a
different method this episode last
episode we did the TNT method which I
felt worked not too bad actually I
thought that was pretty good it was fun
a little dangerous we we paid the price
at the end because I got a little
careless but this is a more safe method
although the lava pockets are pretty
freaky so far I found one I'm gonna I'm
gonna mine for bid I'm not gonna harvest
them until the end and just like mark
them and see I'll spread it out they are
and how much mining I need to do so far
it feels slower than the TNT method but
I'm gonna go for a bit here you had a
better feel for it
whoa all right so we didn't do too bad
here actually like started off really
slow we found the one and then if you
look over there I marked them all with
torches
there's no torches over there I did a
big section as like man this is not this
is not good not good at all let's start
buying these but then I hit like a
pocket of like five in a row or
something then there was nothing that I
I hit another pocket and then nothing
and then another pocket so because
they're like so rare I feel like when
you're mining them you you go through
these like empty stretches oh there was
one below hey I'll take it
[Music]
yeah sometimes you'll go for a long time
without DNA and then you'll get a whole
bunch sometimes they spawn together like
this like where there's two I found one
with three together which is cool and
why 15 here though they're definitely
more prevalent than up above when we did
the TNT mining so I think TNT mining at
this level is probably the way to go
anyways let's I also found it kind of
weird like most of them did not spawn in
the ceiling level here only come looking
to at this level most of them are either
in the ground or one block above
yeah check this out here's their triple
there was one underneath here man I
would freak out get four together and
good stuff so we mined them all up there
we got 18 ancient debris from that and
that took about two full pics to mine up
so now that we got our ancient debris we
got to smelt it and put in the blast
furnace if we want to smelt it quickly
just want to double-check we can do it
in the furnace yeah okay just wanted to
make sure then throw it in here so that
makes net the right scrap I did check
like they'd be good break down the
nether right hosing it from the big lens
into this but I don't think you can
otherwise there'd be a way of like
farming nether right which would be
interesting but that's not a thing yet
anyway
you combine four of these together with
four gold you get the nether right in
yet so we have enough for four ingots to
start off with here which isn't a lot
now you don't like make boots like this
or anything no no no what you do is you
just take your piece of diamond armor
and then you upgrade it with one like so
so I'm gonna go for a full set of armor
just to begin with you can make tools
out of it as well which would be nice
but we don't have enough right now now I
this one is damaged or actually let's do
this one first so this is it's got an
enchantment on I think you lose the
enchantment yuppers no enchantments
this one's damaged I don't know if it
fully repairs it looks like it does okay
cool cool and so I don't waste that so
we got our full set let's put it on Oh
snappers I don't know wait a second
it it looks cool I do like it yeah I
don't know about the helmet though I
don't like that line in the front
diamond helmets don't have that oh they
do they do
I guess it's consistent then seems weird
my guy really looks cross-eyed with that
line in the in between the eyes now I
want to give it a little trial here to
test it out so this is pretty much the
same as diamond armor like we get the
same number of armor bars it does
actually protect a little bit better
than diamond armor though like if you
look at the pants on Diamond armor it
says to Armour toughness +6 armor if you
look at these again it's +6 armor but +3
armor toughness so one higher their
armor toughness is like if you take a
heavy hit it protects you better if you
take a weak hit from something it
doesn't really do much for you so it's
like slightly better than the diamond
armor
the big thing though is it has higher
durability it looks a little different
and it also has knock-back resistance
which I think might be interesting
wanted to check that out so I don't know
if knock-back still works the same as it
did a few years ago I haven't tested it
in a long time that went right through
me what really gonna shoot myself here
ok we gotta have a I gotta change this
up a bit that's not gonna work
alright we're gonna do some science
stuff here so we're gonna try to test it
like this where we load the dispenser
with arrows and then it'll shoot
ourselves and see how much we get
knocked back I'm gonna do it without
armor to begin with and then we'll try
it with the nether right Armour with the
knock back resistance so a little
history last time I tried testing out
knock back a few years ago the way it
worked was it would randomly roll
between four different numbers it was
like it let's say someone hit you with a
sword the amount you get knocked back
from that hits is random it would choose
between four numbers and if they were
sprinting when they hit you it would
also apply a multiplier of I think like
1.1 or something one of the hits though
one of the random choices out of the
four was like a critical knock back and
you would get knocked back way further
than that the other three so I'm kind of
curious if that still applies so I'm
gonna let's look at our Zed
Zed's is the important one here so we're
at 150 point seven one forty nine seven
two eight seventeen just gonna do a
couple rolls here I got rid of the slabs
on the side here because I kept bumping
into them and it was messing up the
results without them there now it's a
lot more consistent and we seem to go
about two one forty nine point seven
thirteen on the z-coordinate just about
every time here little variations are if
I'm not centered wrong completely or we
got seven twelve that time or like
arrows don't exactly come out perfectly
straight either
from the dispenser I have no other way
of hitting myself though but it seems to
only pick one knock back value like it's
always the same so with that in mind I
don't know if that it's still like that
with sword combat I can't test it with
dispensers it only picks one knock back
value we know that now so now that we
have the nether right armor on let's get
centered again didn't move oh okay so
it's really good armor that time we did
Oh what did it move interesting okay so
sometimes it activates sometimes it
doesn't I'm a pincushion here I'm
figuring it out though so knock back
resistance seems to do two things
actually first off the more knock back
resistance you have the more likely you
won't be knocked back so with a full set
here we have plus four knock back
resistance so three in a row there we
got knocked back this time we didn't did
did did forget an unlucky here did
didn't didn't I think it's about maybe
thirty or forty percent of the time we
don't get knocked back with a full set
of armor which is pretty good
the other thing knocked back resistance
does is affects how far we get knocked
back so we're going to knock back to
about 150 point 261 here right with no
armor we go all the way to 149 713 so
with full armor we're getting might half
the knock back distance which is not bad
and then as we remove more and more
pieces the number changes as well so
with no armor we go to 0.7 with one
piece we go to 0.8 six right with two
pieces
goes to the point 0 with 30.1 yeah so
each piece makes a little bit of
difference and with only one armored
piece on you still can get that knock
back invulnerability it's this less
likely it seems yeah see we didn't get
knocked back at that time but anyways
guys it's time to wrap up the episode
again for today there's a bit of a goof
around episode again but I really
enjoyed it I hope you guys did too I'm
gonna try to get back into building
projects and stuff next episode let's
see here so the comment of the day says
looking forward to Ethos nether Enderman
farm his comment on the ceilings got me
thinking it would be so appropriate if
warp forest has some sort of element to
reverse gravity so not only is there
stuff on the ceiling but you can walk
around up there too this kind of concept
would be perfect for the nether terrain
in my opinion I thought I was a good
comment you know that's interesting idea
what if they add some special effects to
the new biomes like walking around on
the ceiling that could be fun one idea I
I was thinking of as maybe like if
you're in the workforce for a long time
maybe you have to eat the fungi or
something otherwise you get some sort of
warp sickness and you start warping
around like an Enderman every so often
you know and it gets worse and worse the
longer you go without eating something
or whatever could be a fun mechanic you
know ah yeah they could they could do
stuff like that they did add an ability
where you can climb on the weeping vines
now - which is cool
anyways that's gonna do it so hopefully
you enjoyed today's episode guys thank
you for watching as always and I'll see
you again in the next one take care have
a good day bye bye
[Music]