[Music]
i
invite all of you to please join me for
a moment
as we point our noses up to the sky
we're gonna get all snooty here as we
stare down on the world with our judging
eyes and let's determine
once and for all what the 16 best log
textures are
i'm curious how my opinions are going to
line up with your opinions on this
obviously my opinions are just straight
facts though so i'm never wrong but uh
yeah
it should be interesting let's pick them
up and let's put them down in the right
order
all right here we go we're gonna arrange
them from least useful to most useful
and hopefully
nobody disputes my first choice here i'm
gonna go with the
the birch logs i've never once been able
to use this in a build
the contrast the peppered look just
doesn't work even after the texture
update you know it looks a little bit
better now but still i just i just can't
do it guys can't do it
jungle logs i mean the texture is great
on this one it's the color
brown and green i think we all know what
that looks like okay then uh
i would go for oak actually surprisingly
i find the lines are pretty harsh on
this one
it's great for like ruined weathered
rustic builds but if you want something
pleasing on the eyes
this one just kind of stands out to me
and usually i want to build something
that looks pleasing
all right next we got the spruce log
surprise surprise you would you might
think that would be at the top of the
list no no no
i find spruce logs are kind of like the
younger brother to
dark oak anytime i use spruce in a build
it's like i should just use dark oak it
would look better
and that's why it's more towards the
useless side
another surprising one i would go for
warp next the problem with this one
i want to use it you know but it's got
two colors in it it's got the light blue
and it's got like the purplish color and
that makes it so much harder
to use in a build because you introduced
two colors with it that's kind of the
problem with the birch as well
i'd like acacia but i find it's like a
little too bright most of the time
and then the one i've been sleeping on
for a long time here is jungle logs the
stripped ones actually looks pretty good
especially mixed with some of the other
logs in the game
it's like i'm abandoning a child almost
but for many years dark oak
was my favorite log and now it's kind of
taking a back seat we're going to put it
pretty close in the middle of our list
because we got this guy now and this
guy's just so much better for most the
cases where i would
want to use this uh we'll go for crimson
next surprisingly this works with a lot
of blocks in the game like all the
nether update blocks
were pretty much designed to work with
that plus like a lot of the terracottas
look great with it
and uh this is very versatile actually
as opposed to like the warp variety
which has two different colors this is
just like two different shades of the
same
sort of color makes it a bit easier to
use
acacia you know the gray colors grays
are super
abundant in the game it's nice to have
another variety of it we'll go for birch
next
it would be much higher on our list if
we didn't have the oak but this is still
good on its own
for like tropical beach sunshiny sort of
builds where you want something nice and
bright
i think it's like 70 percent of people
choose blue as their favorite color
and if it's not their favorite like
mine's green blue is my second favorite
still
and specifically the shade of it the
aqua blue sort of color is great
love it uh again very versatile
this crimson color i think it's a little
bit easier to use than this one you know
minecraft is
all about nature all about earth tones
and so you want the oak
and you want the dark oak as the best
most useful blocks
in the game by far these two are
especially good
all right anyways that is my log list
hopefully your opinions aren't too wrong
on the matter
because i'm definitely not wrong no no
no uh check this out
uh a zombie pigman spawned from that
portal somehow got in the minecart and
it just happens to be a baby
zombie pigman so he doesn't suffocate
going through the tunnels
what a sneaky guy i think mobs don't
despawn when they're in mine carts
anymore
which is kind of interesting but let's
get into it here so i got a technical
project
i want to do today and i got a building
project i think we're going to start
with the technical
check this out this is our grand
collection of pink
left we're almost out almost all out of
ink so we got to build a squid farm
today because if we run out oh
bad things are going to happen our squid
farm used to be in this tank with the
guardians
they would laser the squid and kill them
and we would collect the drops but
uh squid don't just spawn anywhere
anymore they only spawn in oceans and
in rivers and this is not an ocean
even where the guardians are spawning
this is not an ocean it's like desert
plains and
yeah there's no way to get squid
spawning in there anymore it's just not
possible
so we're gonna have to find a new spot
and i don't feel like draining an ocean
today so it's probably gonna have to be
a river
looking around our area here i was
actually kind of surprised we have a
spot
right around here with no rivers
so we don't have to like drain the
rivers
which would be such a huge time saver i
think if we're around this tower here
you get major bonus points if you know
what this is from
uh i think that i think we've got a
river right here and look as soon as we
approach it
squid spawn in here so this is like a
prime location nice big chunk of water
river biome to work with yeah that's
great so the hard part of this is all
done for us pretty
much uh i think we will drain a little
bit of the river though i think this u
shape over here the part that sticks out
and then maybe we'll connect that side
of the river to
like over here somewhere just so we
still have rivers and it looks nice in
our world
maybe we'll make a tunnel through the
ground or something i don't know we'll
see
but yeah we'll drain this spot and then
we'll have to stand like a hundred
blocks towards the tower there
just double checking making sure these
are in river biome
and not in desert like if we go over
here it's water but it's actually desert
and that won't work it's got to be river
so just double check
all this we got room to expand if we
need to
but i think we're just going to aim for
like 32
columns of water i don't have a lot of
experience making squid farms but i
think i've heard
like you don't really need a lot and
it's like diminishing returns
obviously it's better if you have more
water but it's like less
effective the more you have i'm hoping
that's good enough we'll see
so we'll have 16 on that side and 16 on
this side
yep so that's our general plan we got it
figured out let's get to
setting things up we're going to drain
the u-shape first
please go away walker i don't want you
anymore
habit that loss serious problem not for
me though
you know i was just thinking they made
it so hay bales and beds reduce fall
damage if there's any block in this game
that should reduce fall damage
it should be the sponge right
oh snappers all right so i've been
preparing the area here squid spawned
from y63 down to
46 i think so i'm digging a big hole and
we're gonna stand in the middle and
we'll be able to view both sides
hopefully is the plan
but i found a ton of caves while doing
this and i think we're actually like
within range of the guardian farm so the
these have been killing my rates on the
guardians for sure
or we should probably light these up i
found a pig over here hey buddy
just chilling out in a cave that was
kind of interesting
and also down this path look at that
look what we found here old school mine
shaft with the chest still
uh-huh uh-huh and there's this skeleton
farm okay there's a ton of skeletons
here before i just
they didn't want to spawn this time uh
yeah
skeleton farm right by this place that's
kind of cool
i keep accidentally taking screenshots i
don't want to take screenshots
okay this isn't super useful for us
right now but you know maybe in the
future if we
build stuff in the desert here you know
it could be could be kind of useful
found a dual keep spider spawner all
right everybody so here's the deal i
decided let's hop into a creative copy
of our let's play world this is not our
let's play world actually
just so i can show you a couple things a
couple oddities with squid
that uh will be hard to show you in the
let's play world just because we have to
stand like 100 blocks away from this
farm for it to work properly
and uh there's gonna be some confusing
stuff here so first off
one test i did was to check if squid
actually spawn
in bubble columns and they do both
upward and downward
i thought you know you could just put
magma blocks on the ground to make a
farm and they'll get pulled down into
them in fields
but that doesn't really happen uh they
totally ignore
being moved by the bubble columns
and they'll only touch them if they
accidentally swim into them
so the other thing is the game tries to
move them
with the bubble columns and then they
like get snapped back into position
so you'll sometimes see like flying
squid and stuff so that's fun
uh anyways what we're planning on doing
with our squid farm
is to have two columns one we'll have
just regular water i think downward
flowing
will probably work that'll go down and
we'll have a bubble column going
up it'll be a pair of two and i'm
planning on putting
like a mine cart that goes around on our
track just because i want to do
something kind of fun with the squid
farm i don't want to build like a
standard
boring thing and then the cool thing
about this
is uh squid
should get picked up by the minecart it
might be a little weird i don't know
we'll see
oh yeah there he goes you got picked up
by the minecart and whoop down he goes
goes over an activator rail and ejected
into a blue campfire which kills him
quickly
upper below to pick up the drops and i
just wanted to like double check like
what happens if you get a million of
these guys in just to make sure that
doesn't break it
and it kind of does a little bit
but i think it'll fall through
eventually
i hope maybe it's struggling a little
bit oh there it goes okay
good stuff all right so we are back in
the let's play world now we're gonna
start building this thing
so we're lining the soul soil up with
the spots we picked out before in the
river biome
and uh we're starting at y 45
i think is what we want like above this
whole soil here 44.875 when we're
standing on it
and uh as you saw it's a really simple
design it's not going to take us very
long
so we'll have activator rail power rail
and then to get it to go up
we put one over here too and break it
and then
we take advantage of the fact that
minecarts can travel diagonally through
blocks
and we'll just encase it with glass like
this get rid of the middle one
and build it up so i think we can share
the campfires between two of these
things so i'm going to try to do that as
well
we'll put it like over here all right
very good very good so we kind of got
the squid farm set up now we're just
testing it out it's in the rough stages
and from what i've seen we probably
need like double to triple the water at
least in here
how many squid we got this time we got
one we got two we got three
on that side and four five
i think we want like 15 or so right um
yeah so we did hook it up though
flip the lever and we got rid of the
redstone blocks we have a switch for it
instead
and the minecarts come down and grab the
squid
oh there he goes they get ejected into
the campfire and then we set up some
droppers down here
that whenever something's in here it
automatically shoots it out
and then it goes into a water stream all
combines together and just for now
it is shooting out right over here so
we'll probably want to set up some
hoppers here and some chests to collect
the drops
so in general i don't really like the
afk at farm so i tried to design this in
a way where
when we approach the farm like when
we're in the area
uh this since this is the first water
that gets loaded we should get a nice
wave of squid spawning every time
we got one we got two three yeah i think
we got like five there
so so it's not too bad like every time
we approach it if we're getting 10 to 16
ink or whatever
that's pretty good okay so we got one we
got two
i think we got three here three isn't
really ideal we might need to double the
size of this but the problem is
we uh we don't have any glass we don't
have villagers to buy glass
we uh just used up all our sandstone i
believe as well working on this so
we're hurting on the resources we really
got to work on the infrastructure of our
let's play world and this was one of the
things
like we needed a trickle of squid coming
in again so that's why we did this today
okay so moving on here we're gonna get
to our building project which
just happens to use ink sacs for the
dark prismarine
and now we can craft this without uh
worrying about running out
aha so what are we going to be working
on well a certain project
caught my attention today i was looking
at it saw it wasn't finished is like
why don't i just finish that this house
over here
has been kind of half done for quite a
while now it's like yeah
you know i could probably finish it now
i got it in me
uh yeah we got a we got a bit to do on
this so i know it looks like it's pretty
much done but no we got to build the
whole roof and everything for it
and we ran into a problem when we worked
on this before we got to the second
floor i was like wait a minute
wait a minute since i don't really know
how to build houses
the roof is like over here and there's
not going to be enough vertical height
on the second floor
if like the roof over here comes across
it's only going to be like one or two
blocks tall in certain places so
yeah that discouraged me last time i
worked on this but not anymore i think i
know what we're gonna do we're gonna
have to build this side taller
and just make some adjustments uh
overall though just looking at the
structure i still do like the block
palette i chose for this i think it's
pretty good but there are definitely
some
design choices i questioned myself on
now like why
why did i use full blocks here is a big
question huh
why would you do that use pains they add
depth
and uh just look better always most the
time anyway
so we're gonna switch those out i think
we will get rid of the window
i'll just show you a couple a couple
changes we're making here but i'll do
most of this off camera
get pains there so we have a bit more
depth in the build uh
a lot of the windows i think we will
keep the fences but not this one
next to the mushroom stems this will
also be glass
i think that makes sense so for a long
time i had a huge aversion to using
jungle planks i kind of just wrote them
off from being in the game like i was
never going to build with them
but now it's like i just love the things
so we're going to switch out the acacia
floor i think the jungle planks will
look a lot better
they have that like peachy color that
works really well with brick
while the acacia here kind of stands out
it's a little hard on the eyes
and i think this will just be a lot
nicer so something i've kind of learned
about building
lately is like you want to establish
patterns in your building and then
follow through with those patterns so
that like when you see something you can
anticipate
how it should look in other places as
well if that makes sense so i'll give
you an example here like we have brick
then we have a spruce log running across
white terracotta that's good over there
same thing brick
spruce white terracotta but then there's
some places here where it's like
i ditched that rule this goes
brick to prismarine there this is fine
over here
but then on the balcony especially i
noticed
we have a spot here where it just goes
to white terracotta
and now like what do we put above this i
don't know i think i'm going to switch
this to brick and then we'll do the log
and then
white terracotta above that makes more
sense to me
so let's get this switched out not quite
sure what the mushroom blocks are about
but i think we'll ditch them or
well maybe we'll just make them a bit
more gentle we'll go for this instead
we got a bit of a weird profile on the
fireplace and chimney on this thing i
think i was trying to taper it down to a
single
block thickness at the top here and i do
it really quickly
uh it's probably got to be a bit bulkier
so we're going to
adjust this as well ditch the brick here
keep that stone brick all the way up we
will add walls
to round it out a bit and kind of
get like an in-between block with it
well uh this is like
two or three hours later of very finicky
building but
we got it done check it out oh just look
look at that shot now look at the
difference it's uh
it's pretty much the same isn't it
uh-huh there's a reason i don't build
roofs guys
what's the point you can't tell anyways
uh no you cannot
actually now that we can fly around in
the game it's kind of important
uh that side of the building was like
pretty much done though before we
started that's the money shot over there
but you can see now
we got the other sides of the building a
little bit more complete as well
this is our chimney side kind of
scattered
brick granite and the terracotta
together
chimney i think is looking a lot better
we got uh some actual roof action
happening here
that's kind of cool i like that and then
this is other main side of the building
here so the roof used to go
kind of like that i ditched the the two
ends on it and kept the middle section
where it was
and then i just added this bit on the
top to heighten the building and i think
that looks pretty cool
as it is i like that so that's that's
great we finished the
walk under thing here add some lights on
both sides
keep it nice and bright and then this
side of the building is
a bit weird i did it last
and i kind of rushed through it yeah so
we probably won't get to working on the
interior on this today but i'll just
show you what it's looking like inside
for right now how we got the rooms laid
out
uh i'm kind of in a phase now where i
really like to add mini farms in my
my buildings like this just so that they
serve some sort of function
and there's a reason to visit them so
like we added the cocoa farm to one of
our sandy city buildings recently
and i'll probably try stick something in
here and then
decorate it a bit as well um this goes
out to like a balcony sort of thing i
don't know what you would call this
place to eat your breakfast you know and
enjoy the weather got a bit of a garden
thing
and then you can get to the other side
of the building we're on the
the walk through thing right now that's
right below us
um and then we can go here there's kind
of like a little upstairs
sort of thing and then it goes down very
cramped on this side
and out the side door here uh-huh and
we'll just take a fly through so you can
see the roof
because i actually built a roof guys
look at this there's a roof on this
thing now
you can see it only when you're flying
though
but uh yeah it's uh a mess oh it just
feels so good to get that done
because we see this all the time right
it's always kind of bothered me and now
it's like oh
it's actually done look at that
unbelievable
that of course we need to do some
landscaping on the outside here we
really
got to figure out how to blend these two
together and this thing
might i don't know what to do about this
building it's like uh
i like the inside of it but the outside
is a bit weird
uh anyways we're gonna do a little
technical project over here as well
recently we upgraded the tree farm
we added like a sorting system to it i
want to add one more thing to it today
uh this is great for farming spruce and
jungle logs
the 2x2 trees but recently i also
discovered we can farm
dark oak with this tree farm and it's
one of the main building blocks i use
so i want to get that set up the only
thing is
the way this works is we have six
dispensers and and pistons that go up
here
and it like snakes back and forth up the
thing here with a bunch of repeaters
but when we farm the dark oak we only
want two of these to activate the bottom
two not the top four
and the only way to really control that
is to take the tnt out when we want to
farm dark oak and put it back in
but what we can do what i realized is
just add a switch
over here after the second dispenser
we're gonna lock the repeaters we'll
have like an on off to lock them
and then the signal won't be able to
pass through so we also built a similar
version of this tree farm on hermitcraft
but i like what we did there a little
bit more where we have two towers one on
the other side as well
it doesn't really do anything on
hermitcraft this is for show
but on here i think we'll also add the
tower to bounce out the look of the tree
farm and we'll
use that to run a redstone signal up to
our
dark oak switch up there to lock the
repeaters and we'll add like a lever
here or something
to send the signal up or maybe a button
over here to switch between them
oh no darn it
there might be a flaw with the plan guys
uh when i flipped the switch
the tree farm blew up ah
no no no no why
oh it would have been so good now i
gotta rebuild everything
and the worst part is it blew up the top
half and uh i saw a tnt fell
down through the hole here i'm not in
the mood for you right now
this is a bad timing uh yeah tnt fell
down here too
yikes well i think it's a good time to
rage quit right now so that's gonna be
it for today guys but we will do the
comment of the day i'm gonna take a
break and then i'm gonna fix that
uh it says hey ergo have you ever tried
speed running
minecraft i know you did certain
challenges and achievement speed runs
but have you ever considered tried speed
running a certain category
for minecraft a long time ago i once
tried getting all the achievements in
the game
and i got to like the three hour mark
and then i just quit
so nobody ever saw that video um
no i haven't really done it too much i
of course we did the speed challenges in
the past
i think um i would enjoy trying
speedrunning
i don't think i would like ever be good
at like the top
level like i don't think i'd ever set a
really good time um
i enjoyed this strategizing and learning
part of it and improving my skills
the luck factor no no no no that would
just frustrate me
to no end and i don't think i would ever
get to like a top tier
uh movement and stuff in this game
it's not my specialty really so
i would do it for fun not for like
showing off i don't think
um i do have an idea for another one of
those speed challenges though i think
i'm gonna do it
hopefully sometime soon here and uh it's
it's a wacky idea
i've just been wanting to try so
hopefully that'll come out soon
and uh we're going to end the episode
for today guys though hopefully you
enjoyed it thank you for watching as
always
until the next one take care
bye bye
you