hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series I just love watching
the same like watching them fall down is
so satisfying for some reason and then
like all the eyes are looking at you as
they follow they're all aligned facing
you it's kind of creepy huh I just do a
tool repair oh it looks like it's done
now don't quite have the mending
enchantment on everything yet just a
couple of my tools in my armor alright
let's get out of here though I I wrecked
another Mouse guys another Mouse has
worn out from cooking in this game from
placing blocks and a lot kind of stuff
but they usually last for like a year or
two for me and then that's it
so yeah totally broke the left click
button pretty much so I I'm using an
older one which has me very worried
whenever I have to fly now I'm not so
confident ok I did it I did it ok like
whenever you switch like a new keyboard
or your mouse
whenever you play a game again that
you're really used to it's very easy to
make a mistake because your brain hasn't
adjusted to the hardware change yeah we
survived there that's all good let me
get up upset no not upset let me get set
up to do a little experiment here I was
thinking about mining new speeds and I
want to play around with maybe gold
pickaxes and gold axes see if there's
any way to instant mine wood or or
cobblestone because yeah we have taste
too here you can instant mine a few
blocks like clay for example pretty
easily stone but you can't break
cobblestone instantly with a diamond
pickaxe there's no way to err let's try
it out
so I'm wondering if you switch over to a
gold pickaxe if it could do it because
it can mine almost twice as fast as a
diamond one for a lot of blocks yeah so
we want to get an efficiency 5 pick and
axe for this test let's do some
enchanting here got 70 levels to waste
Oh
efficiency for so give us a chance to
hear the sound some more - it's so weird
that sound I do like it though 11 levels
wait a minute
twenty three levels oh no let's go back
go back I like that more cool so we got
our tools ready to go here efficiency 5
on both of them I really hope this works
because now that we have mending in the
game you could actually you could
actually use gold tools so the mending
would counter the low durability they
have so I'm hoping they can do something
diamond tools can't yeah they go through
stone like you would expect let's try
let's try the next tier up so the next
tier up after stone would be like
cobblestone mossy cobblestone nether
brick brick
I think stone slabs and bone blocks
might be the next year so we got a few
few different things here that we might
be able to instant miner if we could oh
that would be amazing
alright Oh brick let's get the breakdown
so here we go please work please work
please work I'm sad darn you would think
you would right I'm sure people have
tested this before but yeah I don't
think I ever done it so I was curious
looks like it doesn't work though
alright guys so today we are back in the
nether here again last episode we
started building this gold farm which is
kind of working already but we got to
improve it a lot
we need more spawning space probably
start making more layers to it to begin
with here and then we got to try
optimize it once we get a decent amount
of these guys spawning there's a chicken
over there chickens all alone uh-huh
yeah so to begin with here I'm gonna go
underneath this pink donut we got and
I'm gonna totally copy it three blocks
down just to increase the amount of
spawning area we have for the big men so
hopefully we get a lot more and then
we'll check out the spawning rates after
this and decide what we do from there I
guess you know I was thinking about why
our zombie pigmen so mad what makes them
so mad it's because they can't have ice
cream in the nether it melts so I'm
giving them Donuts at least okay so I
got the second layer in here each layer
is actually pretty big I'm sure it's at
least 500 bucks I'm gonna count it
though if I have to do another one but
let's just see what happens now I also
don't give those guys a path to get to
me I just yet I want to see what happens
when we shoot shoot these guys cuz if
they can't get to me what do they do oh
they're still trying to get to me that
looked really really crazy like I was
definitely getting some lag there and
they were like stuttering and then they
moved very quickly and looked pretty
weird let's try it again alright still
not really getting an infinite loop
going of death and they're still not
refilling the platform's very quickly so
yeah we need more space more space I'm
going to add a third layer I guess and
take it from there building building
building building tastes more blocks
placed more counters
yeah so this is pretty repetitive by the
way I've been doing this for a couple
hours now just about done the third
layer here though and then probably have
to add more and done alright it's very
cool so we got three rings all done now
while I built this third one I decided
to count how many blocks it took as well
and I thought like before I counted I
thought it was maybe 500 maybe a little
bit more guess how much no really yes no
it's actually sixteen hundred and twenty
per per ring so yeah I was a little bit
low on that yes three rings that's four
thousand eight hundred sixty blocks
that's roughly seventy five stacks of
blocks to make this currently and we
might need to go bigger let's let's find
out let's shoot them see what happens to
the lower guy's as well well that guy
fell off those guys fell off in a weird
place so the guys on the lowest ring
there are still tracking us that's great
even though they don't have a path to
get up to me here and we got a bit of an
infinite loop going on that's good
they are falling farther than they need
to so when we actually put a floor to
kill them they won't have to follows far
and they'll spawn a bit quicker again
yeah look at this we're getting the
infinite loop going that's good still
seems a little bit on the low slow side
though doesn't it I feel like we should
be getting more Pigman oh I really don't
want to build more rings we might have
to add another one oh you're not
supposed to be here got him awesome no
more building that's it guys I've had
enough here we got five layers that's
eight thousand one hundred spawning
spots for these fools and I think we're
gonna call it there for extending the
platforms we're gonna actually get to
building the killing mechanisms and
gathering the drop mechanisms that kind
of fun stuff the reason I keep adding
more here though is for one thing it
gives us more more spawns it's more
likely when they tries to spawn a zombie
pigman it'll be successful but also I'm
having a little bit of trouble getting
this infinite loop thing going so that
after they die the next the next wave of
zombie pigman that spawn are gonna be
mad at us too like those guys over there
I think they might have lost interest
and I've never made a zombie pigman farm
like this before so I don't know exactly
why it stops working like I walked and
this guy saw me I think and I needed his
call and then that attracted these guys
I'm still trying to figure it out
exactly I tried looking for a tutorial
on gold farms just to try shed some more
light on I didn't find the information I
wanted I did see a good good gold farm
by a snow crash though I think I'm gonna
mimic some of his designs because he's
pretty much doing the same thing I had
going on here but to collect the the
drops in the XP he uses slime launchers
horizontal slime launchers on ice and
that is a really clever idea so I think
I'm gonna do that as well okay yeah
let's start adding the other mechanisms
to our gold farm now so I checked that
bottom ring is at y 241 we got to drop
the zombie pigmen I believe 24 blocks to
kill them so we got to go down to I
think Y 217 which is a little bit tricky
cuz my elevator here isn't the best it
doesn't have like a way out anywhere on
the way to 12 to 22 oh I missed missed
clicked yeah this is a good way of stair
casing down though if you guys didn't
didn't know this trick in place like
three blocks down every time to 18 let's
go down one more and that's good okay so
I think that's a good level now since I
can't use water but it's like it's hard
to
to maneuver through in the nether here
okay so I'm just gonna put a floor down
here and make sure it kills all the
zombie pigmen on all the Rings when they
fall down looks good yeah got them all
okay so check this out guys if I stand
at the very middle here the middle of
the Rings instead of at the very top it
seems to work a lot better the infinite
loop just keeps going and going then I
haven't had it stopped yet the number of
zombie pigman is thinning out I think
they're all where are they all ending up
there's a bunch over there they're not
supposed to be there we'll fix that
later don't worry magma cubes I guess
they'll just jump off right and these
spawn when they fall down I don't think
fall damage and kills them though yeah
it's working pretty good it's working
pretty good I'm happy with this so we've
got our ice platforms over there now I
think what we'll do is add a bit of a
cage to keep them from flying out all
over the place when they fall down here
we'll try to keep them all contained so
they fall into lay a one by one area
down below there and that keeps
happening you have no idea
it's not safe anywhere but if I get
anywhere near these guys oh of course he
just has to have a flame sore too right
it's very dangerous around here yeah so
this is what we're gonna try to do we're
gonna build up the sides here out of
glass all the way up to try contain the
zombie pigmen so they don't fly all over
the place like they were doing and we're
gonna keep the kill zone over here
though I think like we could make the
zombie pigmen walk all the way to the
middle to where we are the advantage of
that is it makes it a lot easier to
collect the drops because I'll be kind
of in the center that way the downside
though is if they got to walk all the
way to the middle where we are that's a
lot of time a lot of watching time we
want to kill them as fast as possible so
that more will spawn so we get better
drops or more drops I should say so yeah
we'll try to keep the killing zone over
here we may even experiment at adding
more kill zones at the diagonal so
they'll have to walk all the way from
there to here
if they could just like maximum distance
from here to here that would be a very
quick kill but it will complicate the
farm more and more the more kill zones
we have yeah let's build this up and
take it from there
are we at the top oh we are at the top
awesome maybe I don't have to cut all
right let's just go a little bit more
here oh my out of glass I'm gonna have
to go get more glass I think before we
didn't finish this all right I'll just
go a little bit higher here
I should put slabs at the top though I
don't have a mommy just threw away a
bunch of glass for no reason don't ask
me why all right let's let's try that
out just see what it does boom
okay so are they going to all go into
there yeah it looks good looks good yeah
so that keeps them from flying out all
over the sides I would like to get this
down to a one by one if we can kind of
like we did with the Enderman farm what
happens if we put trap doors here oh you
guys are on the wrong level all right I
gotta take a step back or else they
won't spawn again so are they gonna try
goat they do try to go okay that's good
that means we can get them into a one by
one yeah so I'm gonna do this on all the
layers yeah I don't know really what's
going on but I can't stop dancing here
oh I got a dance partner now great this
is so weird
alright and if I change perspectives it
looks like this I think I'm stuck in the
ice block or something
aha what is going on this ain't the gold
farm I took a little break guys I came
to the desert this is where I do my
mining whenever I need sand we need more
glass to finish up the gold farm I can't
remember if I showed you guys or if I've
even really explored this but there's
actually a village nearby where I get my
sand have I'd looted this
I haven't oh man guys like the guy take
the iron iron it's hard to come by
oh that's sweet okay I probably haven't
checked the villagers in either we got
infinity for 17 rip off very secure
houses around here it's actually a
pretty cool village right like that's
got the layer on top of the hill and
then the lower stuff there pretty cool
this is like a challenge map now now
that I know how to fly like the alpha
fight stuff here is really fun trying to
fly through all the tunnels and stuff
I'll show you guys where I get my sand
from now I saw some people asking about
it because I've been mining from it for
quite a while now and it's
it's getting depleted a little bit oh I
hit the wall still good still good yeah
it's it's over here
I think right nope I'm lost
oh it's over here it's over here okay
yeah so this is all mined out now like
this is all sandstone pretty much up to
up to here and on top a lot of the hills
are mined out now so I was just doing a
bit of exploring this make sure the
biome keeps going there and yeah looks
like it's a huge huge desert am I filled
up yeah I'm a porcupine okay I'm gonna
get a little bit more sand here we'll
get back to work
oh man I'm getting excited now guys this
firm is getting pretty close to done now
I would say I got our spawning platforms
we got our glass tunnels so they they're
falling down a one by one we're gonna
test it in just the second to make sure
it works so we did that one over here
this is how I'm doing the trapdoors by
the way so I'm flipping this one up and
then at the top of every every block
year trap door but then down here I
switch over to glass I don't know if I
have to use trapdoors here or if I can
use glass I didn't test it I was gonna
use trapdoors because running a little
on time you guys can experiment with
this if you can do something similar
okay here we go
um I should go to the the level that was
good for us a third one here I think
line-of-sight is important for reang
growing them weird where do we want to
stand let's stand here this should also
hopefully make it so they can't get to
the middle here anymore unless there's
any spawned on on the middle already
that was a good shot there we go oh he's
down so this should be good hopefully
they do get a little bit stuck on the
glass walls we put up but it's not too
bad
what do the little baby guys do can they
fit through that I wonder oh man that is
so cool look how fast it is - it's not
bad oh how how wait a minute
were they there before or how did they
get to me here what a guy yeah I might
have to investigate I'm not you
shouldn't be able to get to me
right okay they're still going they're
still going good good yeah I'm really
happy with this do exactly what I wanted
to do I'm not seeing any baby guys
fitting through those trap doors I'm not
sure if they can I didn't test that
either but it's looking good let's go
down here oh yeah this is a not perfect
down here just yet I should really seal
this in but yeah all the XP you should
be in this one by one all the drops
that's so cool and let's go down below
as well just an idea what's happening I
said magma cubes don't take fall damage
I'm pretty sure they do what I meant is
if they fall down here I think they
split right if they hit the bedrock they
split so it doesn't get rid of them they
just jump around down here and then I'll
I think they'll be spawn over time
though well I've done something wrong
over here
let's take a look I'm missing it I'm
missing a glass block
aha okay we just hit a new record 2500
entities this firm is gonna be crazy
guys oh did I just walk off the edge no
I did I'm fine yeah we got to start
picking up these drops now that's our
next step I removed the platform in the
middle here and it's working great
without it yeah definitely got to do
something about these entities okay you
know what this is actually a little bit
of a tricky thing cuz if we remove any
of the blocks on the side here of the
one by one when the zombie pigmen fall
down and splat a bunch of the items are
gonna fall out the side here as well and
spray out and then they're gonna be hard
to control yeah so we can't really have
the side open anywhere right if we do a
slime block launcher thing that means we
would have to open up the wall with the
piston or something and then shoot the
items out uh how do we do it and then
not if they shoot out I'm not sure
they're gonna make it all the way to the
middle that's a pretty far distance
actually the way I got the setup I do
have an idea though guys don't worry I
got an idea what I think we're gonna do
and sorry it's a little bit dark here if
I place down a torch the ice is gonna
start melting I think what we'll do is
let's get rid of these yeah sure I'm
going to have a hopper here maybe facing
down another hopper below it that'll
pick up the drops that'll just leave the
XP and then to get the XP out of there I
think I'm going to do the piston
translocation trick I think that's a
good idea instead of doing the slime
block launcher stuff try change it up do
do something different so this will be
totally sealed like this yeah I think
this will work out pretty good actually
so the hopper is gonna get rid of the
items out of the chamber
that'll just leave the XP orbs this
works out good too because I think if we
just use one main hopper to pick up all
the items it's gonna get jammed up we're
gonna get too many items for one hopper
alone I think so if we split it up to
four different ones it's gonna work a
lot better in the long run I think and
then the piston conveyor belts gonna
pull the XP orbs out of there bring it
along here right to the middle it worked
out perfect - so they it lines perfectly
with the middle and kind of got lucky
with that and then we're gonna have
another piston elevator to pull the
items up to the top to where we're
standing the the XP orbs up to us there
I think I'll be okay I did some testing
these these conveyor belt things are a
little bit hit and miss like for moving
players they're also a little bit hit
and miss with moving items but from my
testing I found they're actually pretty
reliable for moving XP orbs they seem to
handle them a lot better so we'll see
how this goes I think it'll be okay
though but yeah basically do do this
pattern like so put redstone here then
between each of the snaking connections
here this little zigzag we got going on
I'm gonna cover over this with glass
probably so we don't get any spawns
happening and maybe set up a hopper
clock for each of these branches that'll
send the signal from here all the way to
the middle and up yeah so this is
getting a little crazy guys but
hopefully it works now we'll try it out
basically we got a hopper clock way over
here let's put in thirty two items sure
why not
that's gonna make the conveyor belt run
every so often to deliver the XP orbs to
us we're gonna cover over this with
glass we don't get any zombie pigmen
spawning or gas which would be even
worse break all this
that's a monostable circuit right there
that good everything is all sealed up
pretty good here I'd say I think we're
okay
so yeah this this is the main branch the
main conveyor bet branch this one
actually connects to the elevator in the
middle I got set up here I tried to do
the wiring so that's I think that worked
right I will find out yeah I tried to do
the wiring here so that no zombie pigmen
will spawn so I got slabs and pretty
much filling up all the empty spaces
there except for at the bottom here
you'll see like for example right here a
zombie fitting a good spawn so I'm gonna
put a slab over top this I'm going to
put a slab over top this and now I think
it's all good cool so the actual
elevator here I think we want this at
two tix
I think XP orbs can handle two ticks
like that we'll find out
let's go up I keep saying we'll find out
because I really don't know I didn't see
the lights go on there I'm a little
worried but we'll find out okay no I hit
my head it looks cool right I like that
I like how the blue glass looks it's
like it's sealed I gotta work on my
flying I just have this tiny little
platform I'm planning on landing it on
here this is the afk spot oh I heard the
Pistons go all the way up okay good good
good
so I don't have the X the items actually
being picked up beyond that one hopper
there's no actual collection system but
the XP orbs on that one side hopefully
will be delivered to us
yeah this side here the other three
sides aren't done yet oh I think I see
him coming I think I see him coming no
no where did they end up I saw them did
they get stuck in the middle ah okay
maybe maybe I should have been more
patient maybe on the second run and who
grabbed them probably would actually I
bet you I got changed some delays though
you get that working properly yeah let's
go back here we'll be patient this time
we'll wait gate first run there I see
the XP orbs go into the middle oh so I'm
actually got delivered this time
oh they oh did you see that they fell
out
oh why would they fall out this I do not
understand okay I gotta watch this
they're coming up everything is good and
gravy oh is it just because I was
leaning over the edge and they they like
came towards me and then fell off I
thought they got pushed out the side but
I think I was just not standing in the
proper place alright guys well I think
we're gonna have to wrap up the episode
here for today we got a lot done on that
gold firm though I'm very happy with how
it's turning out so far hopefully for
the next episode hopefully at the start
of it I'll try to get that done we'll
check it out but yeah to get it done I
need to do like another glass run clay
run and redstone run and I've I've liked
mind and placed over 10,000 blocks today
it's crazy I think I've been at it here
it's getting very late I think we got to
call it here so here's the comment
before today it says I asked you guys
what you thought should be implemented
in the next version of Minecraft got a
lot of great suggestions from you guys I
really like this one too it says instead
of a whole slot
system they should do a weight system
you have infinite slots but after
passing a certain amount of blocks you
wouldn't be able to put any more in the
current system is a bit stupid man I I'm
totally with you I don't see this ever
happening with the game as it is now
but I'd really wanted them somebody to
make a mod like that ah would be so cool
like if you could only carry a few
blocks at a time if you actually had to
move like when you go mining if you had
to move the stone and the ores with
minecarts instead of like carrying 20
stacks on you that would be so cool like
if you actually move stuff around in the
world and lifted blocks with cranes and
you know if the world had a lot more
motion to it then it currently does
would be incredible mining would be a
lot more fun I think and other aspects
of the game of course it would make the
game very clunky so probably not a good
idea to do to do that in the vanilla
game but I think it would be a good mod
idea anyways guys hope you enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and until next time take care bye bye