[Music]
hey you're on fire man
you're gonna die you died you're dead
i warned you where did these leaves come
from did i do this
i don't remember doing that that is so
weird
um so welcome everybody
uh i just updated the snapshot i've just
been
wandering around my world like a fool
here uh
looking at all that's changed why is
there no grass there
dirt oh you know what i bet enderman
just took a block
like just now that is weird because we
got all these guys that like to hang out
under the snowflake
i got to build a mob system around here
because
there goes a spider creeper party
dope uh because there's definitely a lot
of mob spawning around here
but yeah a new snapshot the rendering
has changed once again and
i believe it has been improved or fixed
or whatever
because things look a lot better now
that's all i do for now uh the first
thing i looked at
is the leaves the leaves seem like
they're back the way they were before
uh before they looked really transparent
and weird from a distance
and i i'm thinking maybe what that was
was
not all the sides were rendering on the
leaves and now they are again
maybe this is with mitt mapping on
but you can tell even stuff in the
distance like if you look at that tree
there it's
it's transparent um before
the leaf blocks looked like they were
like solid blocks almost like wool
from a distance and now they have the
texture back to them it's good
and the sky the sky looks really neat
somehow i don't know if that changed but
it seems
seems more amazing i don't know it's
like
it's it feels more real somehow it
really pops
i could be crazy i don't know i
i've noticed some changes though one
thing also that's been standing out
this place is gonna be crazy at night is
uh this water
it's a little harder to see now that
it's night but there's like a dark stain
on that side of it
that's not going away
all right everyone so last episode we
worked on this portal network idea i had
an idea so crazy it might just work uh
and we we got a bit done here we got our
portal set up we have a few of these
done now
uh where we can light it we can clear it
that's done with the foot and steel the
clearing is done with the lava
and then we also have our four second
timer we put in
which will let us go through and close
the portal behind us
and now we're going to connect our
portals together today
and that will let us to transfer between
them
we couldn't do that last time because i
had to come up with a
filter design redstone pulse length
filter i guess you could call it
i'm not exactly sure the technical
jargon for it but
basically had to come up with a device
that would let me
determine if if it's a
short false if it's let me try again
i i made a device that lets me tell if
the pulse of a redstone signal is
exactly a certain length
that's what i needed so if it's too
short
signal won't go through if it's too long
signal also won't go through has to be
the exact length
because we're using that timing as a
source of information that we send
between the portals
because last time we also set up this
thing down here
or started to this is our two-way
repeater line
and we're going to be able to send
information through this line
this is actually really crazy it unlocks
something i didn't really know you could
do
in redstone this has some crazy
potential because you can
connect any any device you want up to
this and it can send
information through the line to other
devices
and then those can receive it and do
what you tell it
and you can send it different different
codes or signals and
have devices interacting with each other
all over the place
um through the single line of redstone
which is
sounds really cool i don't know exactly
what you would use it for
i'm using it for this portal network
idea but it seems like it has a lot of
potential
to do something crazy um
[Music]
yeah where am i going sometimes i feel i
need like a co-host as i do my episodes
here someone yell over my shoulder
you're supposed to go
to the surface and look at your redstone
device
maybe not yell but maybe just a tap on
the shoulder you know
and point up to go up i don't know um
i need someone i can boss around too
that would be fun let's just sleep
really quick because it's night time
so we're gonna check out that redstone
device i made
and then we're gonna start setting those
up and once we've got three of them done
we'll be able to test to see how it
works
[Music]
that's guy things are rendering
kind of slow but i am recording
uh my my new computer arrived
and believe it or not it went on sale
even more 50 bucks cheaper so it
it was uh i think 1900
plus free shipping yeah i haven't set it
up though
um that's probably gonna take me a few
hours it just arrived um
a day or two ago i feel bad i still
haven't
had a chance to start it up yet but i
finally uh
got it on my desk and ready to go um
okay so this is it this is the thing
right here looks pretty crazy
complicated and that's it's not too bad
for people out there that don't like
redstone
you look at this doesn't make a lot of
sense
maybe maybe you understand it
but like when you have a lot of redstone
around and there's
all these little devices in it it looks
really complicated it's not
too bad once you understand like all
this here is just
to do a simple function you don't think
about redstone
and i need to put a repeater here and
here and here and torch there and
that you just think of it okay i want
this function to happen
so i need to put this device in and then
you copy it
if if you do enough redstone you can
remember how to build stuff from
experience and maybe even tweak it
um but otherwise you can just look at
guides and and figure stuff out
but i will run you through this anyway
really quick here
so again what this thing does is it
checks if my input signal is exactly
a certain length and if it is it will
send out
an output over here right and my
input currently is a stone button which
is exactly
10 ticks or one second
and i have this configured to let the
signal through here if it's exactly 10
ticks so if i press this
there we go you can ignore this piston
by the way i'm just using that to check
how long the output is if it's one tick
like that
a sticky piston will leave the block
behind so that's that's how
i know it was exactly one tick output um
so i can configure this let's uh let's
ignore this right side first off
this from here
this area here this device is just used
to tell if the signal
is if my input is
less than something and if it is then
don't let the signal through this
torch so um if i press this
actually let me get a this is probably a
better way of doing it
we're going to go through this quick
don't worry i'm just about done um
if i send it a quick pulse that
switch that torch doesn't change if it's
a long pulse
it does all right and if it's a long
pulsing i use this right side
to tell if it's too long which is if it
goes over by one tick
and then it won't let it through because
this piston retracts
and can't even see it
you see this comes right when that gets
back and you
i don't want to hear it from you you go
away
now if i use a long longer pulse like
this would button
which is 15 ticks or 1.5 seconds
so time a half longer this powered no
okay
um you can see it sent the pulse
way before this block came back so
that's basically how it works and then
this device here is a pulse shortener so
it takes the 15 ticks from our wood
button here and makes it
a shorter amount depending on what we
set these two and we can finally tune it
to the tick
so this is by the way what i'm going to
be putting outside of the portals
to communicate which of the portals i
want
open and each each of these ticks is
going to represent a different portal
so right now i have it set for
a 10 tick pulse so it will match
what we had over there and you saw that
piston it did its thing
maybe we'll put the block back just to
make sure
the output doesn't matter like the
length of it really
i'm just curious oops
button glitch i still don't know why
that happens it happens once a little
while it's rare though
okay so now if we were to make it one
tick
longer
no go if it was one tick shorter no go
so
that this is nine ticks let's make it
back to 10.
there we go so it's very fine tuned and
we can adjust what length we want
based on how many repeaters or what we
set this to so this would be one tick
shorter for
so nine ticks now press it at ten
doesn't work anymore shorten it one
please work there we go it works
yay so that that's the device that's
figured out i'm going to start setting
these up at each of the portals
and we should be able to test it so see
you in a bit
well quite a bit of time actually passed
but i did get three actually pretty much
four of them done
uh it's now late at night though and i
might sound a bit tired so we will have
to wrap up this episode
um probably soon um but yeah we got some
stuff done here
uh this one's done this one's done
got all these crazy redstone things
going on back here but
again as i said you break it down and
it's really not that much it's
uh two or three basic functions we have
the timer for
uh the portal here and we have the
the filter over here and that's about it
back here
it's those two those two things are
taking up most of space
um so
one of these is actually giving me
trouble and i'm not sure
why but we can try this out this is my
selector panel here and this is just
temporary i'm going to
change this up a bit and most likely try
to purify this whole area if we can
but this one i have set at
five i think i can go quicker than that
actually
but that's the lowest setting i have
currently this one's at six
we have another one down there that's
set at seven
um it's like setting the frequency on
this so
now when we click the button let's see
i think uh
this is the first one that's going to
come on let's see if it comes on with
this
oh let's try this one
no this one definitely this one
ah so that portal came on now if we go
to
eights on here well no i guess that
would be ten
um that one goes off that one goes on
and then the one that's giving me
trouble here this might not actually
work
but this one down here is supposed to
turn on
let's go check it out
no it didn't work so what's happening is
actually why didn't that work that's at
seven
i should have worked it didn't get stuck
as far as i can tell that's all good
wait a minute um i don't know if these
uh
two-way repeaters don't work maybe
i'm a little concerned
okay let's try this out what did we have
that at
is this it is what we want
yeah what is this this is uh four five
seven eleven i'm pretty sure that's what
we had that
at go back
once it's all set up we will have to run
back and forth like this
um eleven four five
seven eleven
i don't know
okay let's clear this if i press it
again for the same one
it goes off and on just fine
11.
okay let's go back here
it works if i turn those ones on from
here though
which is weird see those get stuck
anywhere
those look fine this didn't turn on
again though
man what is going on and it doesn't look
like they got
stuck like they were before
did any of these get stuck doesn't look
like it
very confusing but anyway maybe we
should try out
try these out and see if they actually
do what i want them to do
so let's let's try turn one of those
ones on from
here um so
10. was the one for the stronghold i'm
going to put signs
and have a code for each one that way i
can remember because right now i'm just
kind of
guessing from memory oh wait that didn't
work either
what maybe i'll look in this one one
second
okay i looked into the problem and i'm
almost positive i know
what's going on now so this is what's
happening by the way this
is getting stuck like it's getting stuck
in the powered state
these aren't turning off and this
happened
when i pressed this button up here
when it was at this setting so this is
four
five six eight
yeah it might be might be a bit longer
i'm not
or shorter i'm not exactly sure the
exact
pulse length i have here but
uh that wire comes down here it goes
through one of these
two of these no problem
this one over here is fine it doesn't go
through there though
uh three
four
and then finally the fifth one glitches
out
the block gets stuck behind so that
means this only got powered
for one tick this piston here
and left the block behind and now it's
stuck powered
if i hit it again it'll pull it back but
you know we need it to work the way we
want
so that fixes it
so pretty sure this is the issue
if it's sending
i've heard that these pistons take 1.5
ticks to extend i'm i'm not exactly sure
what it is
in game it's two ticks
but when you combine them like this it
might be
less but anyway these are extending
pistons take time to extend
so this one extends that one extends
that one that one that one i've
inadvertently
used instant wire here because when this
goes off
this instantly retracts this instantly
retracts and
and all the way down the chain here
meanwhile the pulse is still going
through this one and then
then that retracts instantly and the
pulse goes away basically
if i had one more in here it would
uh they wouldn't make it to it so
i have to change these i have to do
something with them i can't use instant
wire with this it needs to carry the
signal exactly like i
had it um so
a bit of an issue i'm gonna have to work
that out now
but let's see i don't know
how about we manually test this i wanted
to do an automatic
automatic test today but i'm gonna have
to figure something out with this
it's very complicated all these things
and there's lots of ways it can go wrong
how about we turn
this on well we might have trouble we'll
see
turn this one we manually turned it on
we're gonna go to this one oh man
i thought i had a spider on my desk it
was uh
light from the glass reflecting off of a
bottle it scared me though
it was like moving um
okay so we're gonna go through this one
on a timer
and we might get sent to the nether hub
i'm not sure because we didn't disable
that this is my where i get my sand from
and then when we go back hopefully the
portal closed on us and we should arrive
at the stronghold
portal oh
i guess we had one outside
we did arrive at a different one though
which is wow look at all the gas
so it did kind of work
we got bugs i'll fix them not today
though
well it's that time again everybody it's
time to
read the comments and wrap up the
episode um
if you guys don't like redstone don't
worry we're not doing the portal thing
again next
episode we're gonna change it up we'll
probably build something or
who knows sometimes i get really focused
on a project though and that's one of
them
and the last two episodes i've done a
lot of redstone
and stuff like that which i think is
good from time to time because my
channel
logo is uh would you call it a logo
saying whatever is minecraft done
technical and i like to stay true to
that every so often if i can
um so
uh let's get to the comments and by the
way the map
is back it's looking great in the new
snapshot the
z ordering was fixed or whatever the
problem was
z fighting so
looks good even from a distance it's
really nice
but yeah here are the comments for today
it says etho by the way
what do you think the best biome in the
new minecraft 1.7 update is
i have not seen them all yet actually
but like i didn't see the
snow new snow biomes really like the
packed ice in that i never saw i didn't
see
that tyga forest one with the two by two
uh pine trees and the
mossy structures i did i didn't see that
one but of the ones i did see
i would say i like the flowery forest
one the most because
it's got nice green grass nice trees
it's got flowers it's got uh might have
been a coincidence but seem to have a
lot of waterfalls and
and and water around it and also the
mushrooms look pretty cool
i like i like naturey stuff in this game
and i think that one did the best job at
that
uh let's see next comment
it says etho are you planning something
special for your 300th episode
if you are please let us know keep on
keep up
keep on keep on the good work
winky face no smiley face oh he went he
went bold there he went for a smiley
um like i said we're not doing
redstone might be a little bit but
mostly building and and that kind of
stuff but i have been
had this idea for a design for something
i think a lot of people are going to use
when i show it or or look into or
it'll be interesting i think so we're
going to try to do that for the 300th
and it's something that will be useful
for a long time i think for people
um i was planning on doing a montage
that's that was like the one thing i was
gonna do
but the last few i've done didn't really
turn out well i've had desync
issues so i think we'll do the design
build idea i had and try to get that all
done
um i got sad news i checked this and
he's not here anymore
what did you do to him tom
was his name jim i can't remember his
name i'm pretty sure it was jim but
he's been gone so long already it feels
like i've forgotten his name
i don't know i must have logged in on
peaceful and didn't realize it once and
i've made backup since then and done a
lot of things so i think he's gone for
good
ah jim jim jim maybe he'll show up one
day
should really be changed like if you
name a hostile mob they shouldn't
despawn if you go to peaceful
i think but i don't know
like you're intentionally trying to
preserve him if you name him
but whatever that's just my thought on
it
um but yeah that's gonna be it for today
guys
uh make sure you tune in for next
episode
should be cool and i will see you again
next time
bye
[Music]
you