hello everybody welcome back to another
episode
episode of either blaze minecraft
hello everybody welcome back to an
episode hello everybody welcome back to
another episode
hello everybody welcome back to another
episode of Eno plays minecraft yeah so I
just watched a youtube video on the
world's fastest talker and I don't know
how he does it that's the best I got
that's my limits decide to try it for
myself so yeah welcome back guys to
another episode here I have a few really
cool things to show you today guys
actually but before we get into it let's
let's finish up our redstone riddle from
last time so I showed you this all those
slimes man I tell you I just killed them
too so that when we recorded here we
wouldn't hear them and they're back
jerks I'd there's something interesting
about these guys actually you know how
the sword knocks back any enemies around
it turns out it actually kills the
little slimes if you got a bunch of
little slimes you think take them all
out in one one swing it's kind of cool
right leave us alone
oh I'm dying myself here alright this
firm used to be automatic I think
they're swimming over the water is the
problem right now there's another one oh
my goodness
hey you know what there's a cool little
feature in the game I don't like to do
that because then the creepers get me
but just for the further moments what
are the chances all right okay so here
we go so this was the redstone riddle
place a normal block and the dispenser
or the dropper shoots out an item put
down a powered block it doesn't break
and replace and the reverse happens
alright so as most of you suspected bud
power is involved so it's it's being
powered or unpowered and then updating
maybe before I tell you the answer here
all that
interesting thing is in the setup really
here I'll just show you how bad blood
power works exactly because I know a lot
of people find it confusing okay I'll
try explain it like this I guess
in redstone we typically think of it as
being on or off right powered or
unpowered but in reality there's
actually like three levels three levels
of power to it or four if you count off
um so this repeater is powering this
this lamp right you can see it's on oh
hello hi there how are you nice of you
to show up or my mob sounds down they
are let's turn those up let's just let's
do that alright stick them out like a
pro so this is being powered then it
powers any adjacent blocks to it like
this lamp here and it also powers blocks
diagonally like this one here but it's
off right now we refer to this as a
strong power source you see the
repeaters turned on over here even
though both these blocks are on these
lamps are on this one is not being
powered we call this weak power alright
and then the diagonals one here as bud
power so lamps are not affected by bud
power even if we update it but things
like Pistons are droppers dispensers and
trapdoors those are the only five items
I know of in the game affected by Bud
power all right and bud power works kind
of like this so if we have a redstone
block here the redstone block is like
the strong power the redstone lamps here
are the weak power so if we try to pull
a signal out we can't repeat it in turn
on and then these blocks that I'm
placing here are what are bud powered
all right so if we place a lamp in any
of those it won't turn on but if we
place a piston or a dropper dispenser it
does get activated okay so here's how I
did the puzzle basically put down two
redstone blocks rights
it's being powered right now it shot out
the item if we tried to power it again
since it's being blood powered right now
still thinks it's powered okay put a
block next to it doesn't shoot the item
then when we remove it it's no longer
powered but because it was being
diagonally powered we didn't remove any
blocks next to this dropper so doesn't
know it's unpowered right now didn't get
updated so right now thanks it's powered
if you place a redstone block next to
its since they thought it was powered
and you powered it again nothing happens
remove it it updates realizes it's
unpowered now do it again and it gets
powered alright so that's how I did the
right one this left one is the tricky
one though so it was unpowered and then
realized it was powered and I did that
by putting a redstone block underneath
it when you place certain items in the
game like a dropper by default it's
unpowered it doesn't realize it's being
powered right now so when you update
next to it then it sees oh there's a
redstone block below me okay I'm being
powered remove it's still powered okay
so if we place a net another one still
powered you cannot do this more than
once
only after you first place it is the
trick most items in the game don't do
this though like Pistons and stuff it's
only droppers dispensers doors I think
maybe fence states if I remember right I
think it's an oversight in the coding
because when you place it it should
update but it doesn't ah anyways that's
the trick
hope you enjoyed it sorry for rambling
let's carry on
whoa all right everybody so with that we
have the tunnel to the library complete
now let's go check it out here hmm I'm
getting better at this
it's so much fun flowing through here I
love it
we got to try pretty it up though it
looks not the best rate now usually I
can make it up to this pillar and yeah
again did it so it's pretty consistent
from what I can tell long as I don't hit
a wall or something on the way so goes
down here takes a right turn and then up
over here is the library right where
this cobble is so we got to go up there
that's that's the goal right up at the
top there which is I think about why 90
or so so we we need an elevator to get
up there of some sort and that's kind of
where the piston trick came from so I'm
going to show you this I was trying to
build or design an elevator in creative
to to get up to the top there trying to
figure out something something cool to
do right and while doing that I was
trying to make an elevator that works by
retracting Pistons instead of extending
them because when Pistons retract it is
quicker than when they extend so I
figured I'd be able to make an elevator
faster like if I had sticky pistons with
glass blocks that pulled me up or
something and that didn't work out too
well but while doing that I did notice
something that has changed in the 1.9
updates I believe so check this out we
have a piston here normally Pistons can
push and pull blocks like like if it's a
sticky piston regular Pistons can push
stuff then push entities they cannot
pull entities though right well now they
can check it out ah isn't that cool so
it actually pulls you to the back of the
piston
and I don't think too many people know
about this like I tried to keep up with
the updates whenever they happen I read
the patch notes and all that stuff I
didn't see this myself
so I wanted to let you guys know about
it today if you didn't know about it as
well it also works like this actually I
brought some armorstands so we can see
it a little bit better and I guess let's
make a button or something all right if
we do this check this out ha ha getting
ideas just that we're gonna build an
elevator all right and I think this is a
pretty big game-changer
I hope it's like intended or if it's not
intended I hope they keep this feature
because I think it's going to like add a
lot of a lot to the game it's another
future Pistons you can do it doesn't
really take anything away so I hope they
leave it what I want to do with it first
off here is to build like a conveyor
belts it's really easy to do this too
which is a nice thing doesn't take a lot
of setup maybe let's go one block up
here let's start here or no my goal is
to end up on this cobblestone so since
it pulls you to the back of the piston
we'll do that all right and all I got to
do is every second block here place a
piston right and then every every piston
put a block like here here here and here
and then all we need to do is redstone
repeater I'll change this out to stone
brick once I stop recording one tick
between each one and that's all there is
to to doing this let me get let me set
this up off-camera and I'll show you
it's really cool okay so let's go check
this out basically last episode I wasn't
really sure what to do here with this
tunnel because we can't fly all the way
we hit the bedrock right so I wasn't
sure what to do about it but this
conveyor system works out perfect so
we're going to set up so that we can fly
right into it looks
it's a little bit short Oh what happened
oh maybe maybe I got something wrong I
bet you it's because I'm recording now
something something has changed oh snap
okay I didn't realize this ah now we're
making it all the way for some reason
okay I might need to just make the
timing longer on these then because it's
only one tick between each piston which
is really pushing it we are one redstone
tape between each piston let's try it
again
yeah hmm this works when I'm not
recording
I think cuz I'm lagging a little bit's
it's not working now oh all right well
let's try to change these the two tix
then this should definitely work for
sure that's just look twice as slow is
the problem if it's it set at one tick
it's actually 20 blocks per second which
is faster than then horses and minecarts
and all that stuff you can even have
another space between these pistons if
you if you use a horse or a boat instead
so it's like 30 bucks a second but it
turns out there might be some issues if
we are recording or if your computer is
lagging ok let's try this now
oh snap and I was all excited I thought
it was going to be super fast I would
rather it be consistent though then then
quick
what what okay - for sixty six point
three and sixty six point three remember
that failed all rights again exact same
position all right
or in square in spots failed okay we
expected that failed in a different spot
this time and out ah alright this is a
little bit iffy right now I think we'll
move on to the elevator we're definitely
doing an elevator and hopefully we're
not having issues with it now for some
reason okay guys so this is our goal our
targets we want to go up the elevator
and end up right here on the library so
we're facing the enchanting table so I
filled this up with stone again ooh
maybe you let's do this go down a bit
more rather than like mining this all
out with my pick I think I'm gonna do
TNT it's so much faster
is it safe though I think it should be
okay alright
that way I'll have some space do the
redstone stuff too as we go down and I
brought a dispenser so hopefully put it
over here I knew I wasn't going to get
it so hard to place this sideways almost
at it nope this is like a game can you
jump and place it sideways at the same
time I'll tell you what let's just do
this I've given up okay yes fill this up
with TNT and we'll make a button and I
am just keep spamming the button and
hopefully it digs us a nice little hole
here
all the way down Oh careful careful
Oh oh yeah I got it ease up on these
button presses that almost flip the
library that would have been so sad it
like shot up there then fell back down
alright I think that's doing a good job
aha
so check it out guys we have a pretty
good area here to work now to put in our
elevator a lot of space I think we mined
out like 5,000 blocks in five minutes
there I like TNT TNT is awesome alright
so I'm going to show you how to build
the elevator now
so like the conveyor belt here we need a
one tick pulse going through it we
cannot set any repeaters to do when I
did that before that was a mistake
I should I knew that didn't work but I
did it anyway because I forgot you
cannot like if you said that the - it
makes the redstone pulse two ticks if
you said to three it's three four you
have to keep it at one so if you want a
to tick redstone pulse you have to just
use two repeaters set at one each all
right that's what we're going to do for
the elevator here we need two ticks two
redstone ticks between each of the
Pistons all right so you can set this up
pretty nicely actually like you can have
it so you just step on a pressure plate
and then you go up sort of thing and
I'll just show you maybe how you could
set it up here give it give yourself a
little bit of a delay maybe whatever you
want
before this triggers and then come on a
stable circuit to make a short pulse all
right pull the power through one tick
and then just make it go up to two here
oh I missed let's go around like this
just to show you I'm probably going to
hook my elevator up to the conveyor belt
though so
I don't have to activate the elevator
separately and just go through the
conveyor belt and then up all in one
motion is kind of cool all right
yeah that's working good move this up
what happened what's going on
oh yeah I got I got a hooked up to two
right now let's take it up to the second
piston that's good so I'll show you the
pattern in the back here it's pretty
simple so one repeater goes to here and
the Pistons right there right we're
building it out a poopy Brown because
we're we're trying to make this nature
theme down here when it's all said and
done and poopy Browns a nice neutral
color and everybody loves poopy brown
okay then on the other side we have the
second repeater goes up repeater
repeater again piston over here
pretty simple pattern I'm still trying
to get into the flow of building it here
okay so then we would go block and then
upside down slab upside down slab and
then yes I think over here yeah Pistons
right there so the next block here and
here and again let's put some redstone
dust on these and you kind of just do a
wavy thing all the way up and repeater
repeater good oh so I think that should
take us to the very top here now all
right or no there's two more up there
yet pick us up to the third one now
good one-two-three
oh so it's pretty simple I have to go
all the way up here which is going to
take a bit of time I'll try to do it
today but we'll see I was building this
and I ran out of poopy brown part way
through near the top there so I have to
get down go get more materials now now
I've come back the way I'm putting these
pistons in now is a little funny I'm
basically just placing two at a time
floating down very gracefully flip like
a feather
ouch and then go back up and it takes us
to the top of the distance new place all
right then I place two more probably
could do this a little bit better but it
works oh I was not so graceful that was
more like a cannonball falling all right
thankfully we heal super fast in 1.9
I don't think that's a good change for
combat honestly but I do like it for
survival minecraft because I don't have
to wait around so long it's like oh I
took damage I just got to eat something
and it's back up and it heals quickly as
long as you have saturation once the
saturation is gone you heal like you
normally did before let's see two more
Pistons alright there and there I should
take me to the very top and I didn't
work on the wiring again oh come on
careful careful careful all right
very good working good though having
those two ticks between the pistons
works great with the horizontal thing I
think that's the problem but with the
way it's laid out it's kind of hard to
fit to two repeaters in here we go again
so got the elevator pretty much all done
now I did run out of poopy Brown again
though I'm totally out of hardened clay
so I'll have to go dig up some more at
the Mesa biome but yeah check it out
guys I put I put carpet here I thought
maybe maybe we were getting pushed over
to where the repeater was and getting
stuck on that or something it was
working good once I put the carpet down
but now it's failing again so I don't
know darn it
it's hoping at least for the video it
would work
hey ah come on come on just do it just
do it and no no no no all right I think
I might tear this out I'm not sure
alright you know what I probably end up
doing I might just make it work with a
horse or a boat or something that way I
can have one extra airspace here and if
I have one extra airspace I can fit in
an extra repeater pretty easily and then
it'll work for sure I'm I'm almost
certain oh come on it's like what I
start recording that it just fails like
if I if I start recording like halfway
through the conveyor belts then it stops
so it's definitely being affected by leg
because recording takes is a big
performance it on my computer right yeah
we need two tix it's this way at two on
unreliable at one tick okay so I'll just
show you the elevator now as well that
now that's almost done ah so I put the
pressure plate back in here kind of
ripped out the conveyor belt here cuz it
was really really annoying me today so
you're supposed to enter it from the
side like this go up
see if it does it I didn't do it now
that I'm recording that's weird for some
reason I was slowing down towards the
end when I wasn't recording now it's
like pretty consistent for some reason
but yeah you you come up and you're
facing the enchanting table here of
course we have the buttons to get the
books over here so everything is kind of
nice and compact together at the library
it'll be pretty nice and then I had some
people wondering how I'm going to get
back to the man cave ah pretty simple
since we're up on a mountain you just
fly there which is pretty nice or if we
want to go somewhere else I can make it
pretty far here ooh man caves over here
whoo I almost made it and back to the
waterfall so that's pretty cool um last
thing we got to do though is make the
tunnel look better let's see I want a
really easy way of doing it though is
the problem let's see if we have any
birch leaves over here so this might be
a better choice as hoping we could just
maybe line that edges with leaves and
just go through it really quick because
we I don't really want to spend a whole
lot of time doing this and every level
of detail we add to is going to make it
take way way longer because it's a
really long tunnel if we could just get
away with leaves it would be awesome
flying okay so let's just try it out
maybe over here see what happens if we
span leaves a little bit originally I
was gonna gonna just grow trees in here
and and hope hopefully this chisel out a
path through the middle but I don't
think that's gonna work actually because
once I start breaking the leaves I think
they will just despawn have to actually
place them even doing this though is
probably take a bit of time okay
basically I just want to cover up all
this stone and that will make the tunnel
a little bit smaller as well hopefully
we can still get through it how does
that look whoa I don't know um-hmm I
feel like it needs more detail I hate to
say it but I don't want to add more
detail more detail means more work I'm
also a little bit concerned if we add
this many leaves might start lighting
our world because leaves are pretty
resource intensive there's like a cave
down here too by the way this might not
be too too bad how about that what do
you guys think about this let me know in
the comments we might go for this kind
of look might mix in a little bit of
wood and stuff as well just so it's not
quite so plain but again I don't want to
spend too too much time on it kind of
want to move on to other projects you
know yeah all right
anyways so we're gonna have to call it
here for today guys but we do have the
comment of the day as usual this one
says I personally don't want to entice
etho to play other games minecraft
related or not a lot of youtubers have
slipped into this habit of starting
other games and gradually moving away
from Minecraft then subsequently asking
their audience why the views and subs
have dwindled etho is one of the few who
has not abandoned this core vanilla
series and it is why he's still viewed
regularly by me
minecraft is not as easy as other games
to keep coming up with new ideas and
other youtubers have worked out that
some games are easier to record and edit
than others bear this in mind
whoo that's a lot to say but yeah thank
you for your comments I think a good
bounce I found is like having two or
three Minecraft series in one or two
other games going at the same time I
like that bounce I think it's good I
think
I will always be playing Minecraft on my
channel however it goes but I do I gotta
tell you guys it is a lot easier to
record other games minecraft I think
it's agreed by all youtubers pretty much
it is one of the hardest games to make
videos for um I'll give you an example
like the very first time I played don't
starve and post it on my channel I
recorded 10 episodes in one day recorded
edited and uploaded ten episodes in one
day
and the first episode of that has over a
million views now so it man I tell you
that is the way to do it yeah and then
the next day I recorded five more so I
was pretty productive on those few days
at most I've ever recorded I think -
minecraft episodes in one day so it's
it's pretty tricky but yeah I do enjoy
it and I will continue to do it but we
might play a few other games on the side
anyways guys I hope you enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching hopefully
you'll find some fun with that
new piston trick I think you could
probably do some cool stuff with mob
firms and and that as well with it it
moves all entities pulls all entities so
not just people but armor stands mobs
boats horses whatever you know you know
what I mean so it's pretty cool anyways
thanks for watching
have a wonderful day take care bye bye
you