Eagle
[Music]
no no you go down this is my spot
you stayed down there okay I'm gonna I
wanna start it up where did all these
cows come from alright alright so
episode fades in I hold shift and then
I'm like wow what was that that was
amazing wasn't it that was a very
special intro made for me by Rader he
did the music and tiggy who did the the
visuals and also she's saying that part
of it they made that for me as a special
gift they surprised me with it
in celebration of a very special event
that some of you may how did my frame he
knows what to do that's right you who in
the back I started recording and there
was none around and somehow they all
gravitated to this one area where I was
and they're running around because I
keep hitting them
I should just yeah but today is a very
special episode as some of you may know
this is the 1 million subscriber episode
I said the 1 million subscriber episode
the 1 million subscriber special so
great I'm so emotional right now yes
okay then get it together play cool man
play cool I didn't know my voice could
go that high did you guys know that I
had no idea so for today's episode I've
decided we're gonna do a talky I want to
talk to you guys and I don't want to
just be like staring out into space the
whole time so I've decided we're going
to go teaming during the episode
something easy for me to do well while I
talk and there's a stronghold here that
we never checked out
we found this a few episodes ago and
I've always wanted to go look at it so
let's go take a look
1 million baby whoa ahh self-control
self-control alright here we go
if I remember correctly I do believe
this is where the portal is so let's try
to get down
oh yeah there's exactly where I came up
before excellent
now this silverfish let's just get safe
before I begin talking here good right I
brought a bow okay this will work
oh man where do I begin guys what can I
say
I mean huge huge thank you to everyone
all of you that have been with me from
the beginning all of you that came in
the middle at the end any of you that
have come and subscribed I really do
appreciate the support you've shown me
even even those of you that are not
subscribed I do that a lot myself follow
I won't subscribe to channel but I keep
going to the channel page and just
checking every so often the new videos I
know there's a lot out there that do
that too so thank you head to everyone
basically for all your support I'll
probably say that a bunch of times this
episode may be the begin wits I'll talk
about how I kind of got into YouTube
I've told this story before
to some extent so as a lot of you know I
I made a boat dispenser thing and I post
it on the Minecraft forms and I wasn't
really expecting much to happen from
that I just I wasn't even trying to get
into YouTube or anything like that as
its like hey I made this let's see what
people say about I didn't bring I didn't
bring coal that's gonna be a problem
and unbelievably like I was not
expecting us at all that the response
was amazing like tons of tons of replies
tons of hype people were really
impressed with what I built and were
very very kind about it so I started to
chased that feeling I decided you know
what this turned out good I'm gonna try
make a few more cool things and see what
people say about that - I I'm looking
for coal right now and did that for a
while great response from people like
people were so kind people that people
are really kind in the Minecraft
community I don't know if you guys know
this but I got into online gaming when I
was about 13 and in that time I've
played lots of different games we need
to find cool aha why didn't I bring coal
and I gotta say like a lot of games they
don't have like gaming communities
minecraft has an amazing community where
people are very kind in the ones I've
played before in games I played before
people aren't so nice and there's
something about Minecraft though it
brings out the nice side in people
people are very positive people are very
very kindly and very vocal to like
they'll they'll say stuff and and show
you support which is really great like
any other game like if I was to make
something and had a community from
another game and people saw something I
built or something it's like the general
attitude I would expect from people as I
could have built that a lot better than
you you know get get responses like that
instead but in my graph people are like
oh that's so cool good job I'm I I never
thought of doing it that way or you know
just people are generally a lot nicer I
find in this game which is great
I went on the tangent there didn't I you
know what I'm gonna stop a second Cole
and then I'll be back because I'm just
wandering now okay I got some torches
now so let's keep going but even even
with the generally kind-hearted
minecraft community of course there's a
few jerks out there that's to be
expected but even with the generally
kind-hearted minecraft community I feel
almost like people have been especially
kind to me like in the beginning when I
started posting videos they weren't very
good and people were nice it's funny
even like today like I'll see
I sometimes see comments like from
people that don't like my videos like
I'll see comments like instead of it
being like I don't want to eat those
videos ito sucks it'll be like I don't
watch ethos videos because I don't find
them interesting but he's I respect what
he does and he's a nice guy like even
even the haters are very kind I find
it's it's it's great to see and really
that's what got me into doing YouTube I
I like the feedback I was getting from
people and I wanted to you know continue
getting it so I kept making videos in
fact when I first started I had no idea
you could even make money doing this I
didn't find that out until a few months
later and that was a great perk to it
all because that allows me to make more
videos like and do it as a job which as
I've said before is a very very great
job and I enjoy doing it it's like I get
to make money doing something I enjoy
that I got into because I enjoyed and
people support me this is really great
but yeah I watched let's play videos on
YouTube before minecraft like for quite
a while actually I enjoyed watching
Let's Plays on YouTube and then surprise
surprise
after a while people started suggesting
I make a let's play in my in my comments
and that was like oh you know what I
really like Let's Plays but I don't
think I have what it takes to do it
I would like to try though so sounds
like a cheap spider spawner
I doubt it is how do I get out of here
so I decided I'd go ahead with the let's
play and just you know release one
episode or two episodes see what people
think if if people liked it I would
continue if not I would delete the
videos and move on with my life
and of course I needed to get a headset
because I didn't have a headset so went
to the store I was very very close to
buying one yet cheap $15 mic even that I
thought was gonna be a waste of money
but for some reason I went before that
more expensive like $50 maybe it was
even 70 Logitech g3 30s which I still
wear today I'm on my second pair now
before I bought those though I remember
thinking man this is gonna be the
biggest waste of money ever the only
reason I think I went through with it is
because I figured I would use it to talk
to friends and family on skype I needed
a good headset I didn't have one best
decision ever Wow
buying buying minecraft was probably the
best money I've ever spent that was
probably the second best money I've ever
spent buying the headset oh yeah I
didn't go up here so that turned out
pretty good and people were nice I
continued and people are still pretty
nice so I'm I'm still going does this
just end these strongholds man
I gotta find a new place now okay
there's got to be more to this where
haven't I been I keep going in circles
have I gone down I've gone down all
right I dug down to the spider noises
and now we're in a cave strongholds up
there Oh
watch watch his zombie what's he doing
another creeper I'm expecting this
creeper to kill the other creeper okay
I'll do it I'll do it
Oh so anyway I remember one thing I did
before I started my let's play though
this was really a really crucial moment
before I recorded my first episode I did
like this practice recording session and
the goal of that was to kind of get used
to commentating cuz it's something I've
never done before it's it's not just
like okay I'm gonna start recording and
then I'm gonna be amazing I figured I
should at least practice a little bit
and also I wanted to make sure my sound
settings were right my video was okay
that kind of stuff as well so started up
minecraft and I started recording and
you know I was trying to make jokes and
try to be entertaining and funny and and
all that stuff because I figured that's
what I had to do to be successful at
this letsplay thing so I did that for a
few minutes and then I watched it back
and I tell you guys that was the moment
I was about done with the whole let's
play idea cuz I watched his like okay I
have no talent this isn't gonna be good
I shouldn't even bother and I was I was
I was done at that moment really and
then I thought about it you know for
just a little bit you know it's like
I really analyzed it like what makes
people watch these YouTube Let's Plays
these videos I thought okay well you
gotta be this really funny guy cracking
jokes all the time being entertaining
but after I thought about it for a
little bit it's like you know another
thing people that might make people keep
coming back as if I make the videos
interesting maybe I don't need to be
entertaining maybe I just need to be
interesting and grab their attention oh
you know what it just so happens people
have been really interested in the
things I've been making in the game
lately this works out perfect for me and
it just so happens on YouTube I've never
seen anyone really make a technical
let's play of the game like featuring
things like inventions in the game were
complicated mechanics that was not
something that really existed at that
time so I would sort of be special if I
if I did that and so I recorded my first
episode with that in mind I decided to
go like a real technical let's play
somehow I had no guide of how to do that
or anything because it didn't really
exist I had to make it up as I went and
I'm still making up as I go here because
you know I don't know what people want
exactly it's it's kind of a hard hard
guessing game I don't even know if
people are gonna like the special I'm
I'm just sort of experimenting and
guessing what people like and I think a
lot of times people don't even know what
they like until you show it to them and
I know a lot of times in the episodes
it's like I think something's gonna like
really get to people people are gonna
really like something I do and I don't
even comment on it and then it's like
some other little thing I never even
thought of people just love like like
get your snack
people loved when I said that for some
reason and that's just one example of
like I don't know what people are gonna
like and what people don't like it's a
it's a fun challenge every every episode
I record but anyway it turned out it
worked out really having fun with this
still minecraft is a great game my
favorite name is this one we found
before yeah I gotta say big thank you to
knotch
seriously not only for making the game
but just supporting the whole YouTube
let's play thing as well if it wasn't
for that I wouldn't be doing this I
don't know if you guys read I think he
tweeted it or something but he said he
was given the option where he could
choose to take all the money YouTube
lets players made and and pocket it for
himself like YouTube approached him with
that option and he said he said no like
that is pretty awesome because of that
decision I was able to dig Wow like I
was doing it even before I was making
money but because of that I've been able
to make this my career at least at the
moment so big thank you to knotch
big thank you to Jeb and Dinnerbone for
continuing to work on the game as well
as as well as everyone else at Mojang
who are involved like the game was great
but just adding more contents and
especially adding the ability for people
to customize the game has really gotten
the community more involved in it I feel
and it just gonna prolong the life of
the game I'm using my other pick so big
thanks to those guys big thanks to the
mine crack guys and and everyone else
I've met through this YouTube thing I
meet a lot of people doing this actually
like hundreds and hundreds
of people not just youtubers either like
just like I played PvP games with people
I've met a lot of people doing that
through race for the wall and yeah
through YouTube as well of course like
other youtubers and and even just people
I call themselves fans of me I've met
quite a few of those as well and it's
great meeting all these people and and
everyone being nice like I said it's
really cool so for a moment here we
should also probably talk about what I
plan on doing for this special itself
truth be told I've been pretty oh I've
been pretty nervous about this special
it's like I think people are expecting a
lot and I've had no ideas what to do I
hate to say it like a few weeks ago like
okay so the specials coming up in two or
three weeks I got to do something for it
and I started working on a few ideas and
after a few hours of those either either
the the idea wasn't very good and I
realized it's not going to turn out in
the end or it was gonna take too long to
do so I sort of just abandoned those and
in scope instead I decided I should
focus more on maybe beneficial things
instead of like some fancy show for the
special so of course we did the
mindcrack ending there with the two
parts clip show big thing I thought that
turned out pretty good
that was a lot of work to do I had to go
through like a hundred episodes or
something crazy that took a bit of time
I gotta say but all in all it turned out
pretty good I was happy with that and
then another idea I had is
maybe maybe something something
beneficial that should focus on is
getting playlists' on my channel so
that's that's gonna be one of my main
goals here in the next week or two is to
within that time is to get playlists on
my videos because that's something
people have requested for a very long
time and I've been neglecting to do so
instead of putting my efforts towards
making like some fancy show maybe I
should spend it on doings beneficial
stuff like that so that was one of the
ideas another idea is spending time to
to get and also experiment with getting
a better video editing program because
I'm still using virtualdub
which is not really I would be surprised
if there's anybody on YouTube with a
million plus subscribers using virtual
of honestly because I'm pretty sure I'm
the only one let's see if put clips
together and that's about it so I think
I think that would be a good goal a good
good good place to put my efforts into
getting better at video editing because
I don't want to make any drastic changes
to my channel and my like the way I
present my videos too much but I think a
little bit of video editing would go a
long ways and people would appreciate it
so I want to look into that for sure
lots of people no surprise requested I
do a face cam for my 1 million
subscriber special and I I tell you I
put a lot of thought into that I was
considering it but I think the
conclusion I have is I don't want to do
it just to satisfy people's curiosity I
think if I do it there needs to be a
real point to it
so my plant with that by the way is like
I'm not really set up to do that at the
moment like I don't have a webcam I
don't have a green screen I don't have a
non cluttered place where I could record
I don't have what else do I need
I need like this episode for example
this is what I'm talking about there
would have been some benefit to having a
face cam in this because this is a this
is a more personal episode I feel and I
wouldn't have minded having like me
talking in the corner of the screen
because I'm talking to you guys not just
about the game in this episode so
there's definitely times where it would
be beneficial like this episode the
other thing though is like I said I'm
using virtualdub and I can't overlay
video using that that editor so I got to
work on stuff is what I'm getting to it
and I'm hoping to move in a few months
here I got to get into house hunting and
find them find a house to move to fine
I'm finding it hard to get time to do
that though because making videos takes
a lot of time and finding a house takes
a lot of time too
so that's when one of the things I got
to do and when I when I finally get a
house I'm gonna set up a proper office
place proper office office space with
all that stuff with a green screen with
webcam all that kind of stuff and and
then maybe get into doing face cam
episodes or even streaming with the face
cam or or using it when it makes sense I
think that would be good because there's
there's definitely some niceness to it
but until then I don't really see the
point is this isn't a V log Channel
it's about the game more than anything
it's not like I'm I'm recording in real
life videos here and choosing not to
show my face
it's just I'm recording my desktop and
I'm not really set up for it and yeah
it's it's not really it doesn't really
make sense at the moment to do it I feel
but anyway that's kind of the plan
something else I thought of for the
special I don't know if we'll do this or
not but a lot of people have requested I
resumed my Mac map making a series a lot
of people enjoyed that I have worked on
that map a little bit since I stopped
that but I find since I'm not making
episode wrong too much anymore I'm not
working on his on it's like I would have
liked to the reason I stopped that
series is because it was getting very
repetitive and people were kind of
complaining um so like it was it was too
slow moving to does the main thing so I
think what we might do with that is I
might start streaming me making the map
because there's a pretty slow
progressive thing and then people can
watch me make it and also have input on
the map making because one thing I
struggle with a lot in this game is
making simple decisions like what blocks
to choose and you know just little stuff
that shouldn't take me long to do but it
does and getting other people's inputs
while I'm making the map would probably
help me out a lot to be honest so that's
something we might do my twitch account
is a so TV by the way in case you're
wondering and if you want to join in if
we do that I'll probably tweet it my
twitter is etho LP before i start
recording if we end up doing that
people say and of course if it's if it's
not productive we probably shouldn't do
it that way but we should definitely at
least try it now if you guys have any
ideas of what you would like from the
special or or something I should divert
effort towards please let me know in the
comments and I will check those out
something I did actually in preparation
for this special is I I want on this
like major brainstorming thing it's like
I gotta come up with something for us to
do and I spent like 30 minutes just
staring at a wall trying to come up with
ideas didn't really decide on anything I
liked so that never happened but one
thing I did do is I decided I would
check out my older specials to get ideas
of what we should do for our special
here and try to get some inspiration
from those and man I tell ya I first
watched the 1,000 subscriber special I
thinking I would get a good idea from
that and while watching it I basically
just cracked up laughing in tears cuz it
was so bad like seriously oh and I kind
of concluded I'm not very good at
special from watching that and you know
what I think we're gonna do here just
cuz it was so it was making me laugh so
hard I think we're gonna go check that
out
this episode I'm gonna replay our 1,000
subscriber special and give some post
commentary on it so it might be a little
weird but we'll try it out here so let's
go check that out alright everybody so
this is young etho year he's very
excited to celebrate his 1000 subscriber
special and he's got this great plan on
how he's gonna do it so enjoy
here we go hello everyone II thought
your again with episode 9 of our let's
play minecraft adventures and we're
gonna do anything this episode I noticed
I just passed one thousand dollar grows
on YouTube a thousand Wow I am blown
away meeting over a thousand people
willingly choose to watch me do crazy
stupid stuff in this game and I think
that is just awesome I don't know how's
everybody who's who is subscribing and
please continue watching we'll have lots
of fun together mm-hmm and to celebrate
the event I planted this tree to
moderate it oh and here comes it's gonna
be a great tree needs a long pause there
for it but I think we need that all
right so the premise behind my special
here I was gonna plant this tree but TNT
in it and setup lava below that I could
trigger with a button the whole thing
doesn't make a lot of sense and also I
wanted to put a creeper on top of the
tree that would dip that would be
trapped and get blown up so that was
that was gonna be my special no no
inspirational speech or anything that's
that wasn't my style just pulling up a
tree so I'm setting it up here
lava down turns nighttime yeah oh yeah
by the way I want to point something out
here notice the render distance we got
the fog there I had the exact same
computer then that I have now so what
what was wrong here is I didn't know
there was different render settings in
Minecraft at the time every now and then
I would accidentally bump the F key
which you used to change the the far
distance the render distance at the time
and I had no idea why my frame rate with
some
better than than other times so I would
just I would randomly bump it every so
often and my my view distance would
change I had no idea why I could see
farther at times and not at other times
I thought because I was around water
that it was more foggy in the game and
we also the tree notice notice it's on
fast graphics too of course I wasn't
taking a chance so I didn't know if my
computer can handle it
so I set up this tree one of these sign
where is it where is it
yeah it ends up being okay let's sit
this up the tiniest tree you can get in
the game I'm so upset there we go
that's what we got a the smallest tree
you get in the game
I wanted this big grand epic tree though
an trees take so stinking long to grow
and you're waiting for him oh yeah no
bonemeal you couldn't use bonemeal back
then I forgot about that so it turns
nighttime I'm setting up my mom trap to
trap the creeper inside my traitor this
was like one of them is all millet this
is like one of the favorite things I
made like light of the people back then
is this fort or mob trap thing people
loved it so I wanted to feature that in
my special that is yeah all right good
job good job
this is a safety precaution mmm
get away from those creepers yes and I
torch he placed a torch
I love how its pitch black here you
can't see anything so this is where the
guest of honor is gonna sit and you got
an inventory full of torches and you're
not using them I really got a better
tree out of this button whatever I wish
we could see all right so
I start to look for people oh wait we
missed it all right let's try to get our
guest of honor all right so we got a
creeper following us
come on him and I just like okay I need
to get this hooker in here that come on
for my special or my specialist that
kind of turned out well parties for you
he doesn't want to budge it was like I
had no idea what to do at this point I
had no experience with recording I
didn't know I could just like do another
take here for this turned out at 9 a.m.
and skeleton messes me up running away
try again and desperation here this
doesn't turn out nope yeah failed again
I'm getting really frustrated at this
point and I think I dream up and we went
to another one look at the creeper
behavior here by the way like Disney it
works this time it's totally different
they're like jumping as as they're
walking nice stairs for you and you're
so different back then come on come on
come on yeah go don't hit him this is
what Jamie's idea for general spaz by
the way I wanted to control this creeper
here and he gave me so much trouble
nope frustration and then a special
runed
oh I was so so sad I didn't know what to
do what do I do now i I'm not talking at
all it's just like I failed I failed so
then I get this idea yeah all right
party time I messed up the tree I'm
gonna rebuild it out of wall plus
alright here we go
I do my thing if everything wait for it
okay tree get this fire burns up awesome
having the time of my life here and a
piece of and that was my special
party's over
time to clean up oh so good so good how
things have changed
bring me the record bring me the record
come on or whatever you wanted oh maybe
not okay let's
oh dear let's focus for a second year in
the skin dangerous I just fell look at
that event you I did I did yes oh
yes all right this is so stinkin
dangerous out here let's play the record
so for today's comments guys I picked
out a very very special comment in fact
it was the very first comment I ever
received are you ready for it
alright this is it guys the first
comment on my very first video cool by
Stephen Fei you saw even even though he
didn't say much he's he set the tone for
the other commenters he left a very
positive spin on things and I appreciate
it oh there we go
hey zombies man ah good times good times
seriously everyone big thank you you
have no idea how much okay how great
it's been these baths it's almost been
three years now that I've been doing it
thanks to you guys without you you know
I have nothing so it's really a big
thank you to you guys and help you keep
watching and keep enjoying the episodes
I put out and I'll I'll keep trying to
give my best but yeah that's it for
today
[Music]
thanks for watching