is that what I think it is did you see
that okay something just happened on the
screen I noticed it did you notice it
huh
ah right behind the leaves on this tree
I saw something green it looked like he
was spitting on the fence oh it's a oh
no it is a creeper I thought I saw a
creeper and then I saw the zombie is
like what I'm losing my mind so welcome
back guys how are you doing today
I'm doing just fine got lots of ideas
for today's episodes so we're gonna get
to it right away here there was some
very good feedback on the last episode
some some people gave some suggestions
on how to do things so to follow up with
the east road we're gonna go there first
I want to give a shout out to checking
my notes freezing fire I saw on the
Minecraft reddit he posted different
ways of doing like lots of skeleton he
posted on the each road here right how
to do like right turns u-turns um
launching elevators all that kind of
stuff which I thought was pretty cool
and his is a design looked really clean
what is going on is that the same guy no
I can't be they both had leather armor
to anything I can't remember if I killed
that guy oh man alright so what we're
gonna do that is the way he did the
right turn something really good so I
want to try that out to start off with
here I'm gonna bring some blocks and
yeah so go over to the corner here
see if we can pull it off see if it
works as
so maybe we'll do the outside part first
I'm getting stuck on stuff all right so
just looking at the notes again I think
that what we got to do water source in
the very corner here go like that let's
see then we want water okay this is
important here we got to have water
going opposite direction so it'll slow
the boat down so we'll have another
stream going this way so when the the
boat goes this way this will slow it
down and that way it doesn't crash into
the wall and break and then I think it's
just normal I should be using my silk
touch here this stuff is not is not free
all right water there and I think that
will do the turn pretty good oh I can't
put that there
okay I just double checked how to do it
make sure I got it right so it looks
like for the outside turn what we got to
do is get water flowing this way three
blocks long and before the boat
approaches this like the boats going to
be going this direction right we got to
slow it down otherwise it's going to
crash into the wall so then we do this
just a short little stream like that and
check in my notes all right so then we
have another stream going here and this
basically just becomes like the normal
road so it'll go over here slow down
take the turn and then we got to keep it
going this way so that's how you do that
corner now let's try the inside one this
looks a little more complicated okay
this is the inside corner I just went
ahead and did it it is very very finicky
I don't know if it's going to work 100%
either but
basically its water source block here
here and here
it's flowing this way to slow down the
boat so normal Road goes to the slow
down then there's a water source here
and here right so it makes the diagonal
that helps it to get snug against this
wall then this seems to have to go five
blocks this way otherwise I don't know
if it's because of inconsistency or what
but I was having it crashing on me with
it only four blocks long but we'll try
it out here we'll see if it works
last time I tested it it did work it
seems to matter what time I hop in the
boat though so here we go
due to a little bit of lag that's fine
alright alright uh-oh it did make it ok
cool it looks like it failed there but
yeah that is not too bad I'm going to
hold the right key just to see how far
away from the wall it is it looks like
it's right against it that's perfect oh
wait no I tent oh I can't move the boat
when I do that I gotta hold forward and
right I see so it's just a little bit of
ways away but overall pretty good tell
you what I'm going to go get some some
more ice and we'll finish up at least
one side of the road here
cool so let's try this out I got one
side of the road done here it's so
inconsistent though I don't know if it's
actually gonna be feasible um it's gonna
make it it's gonna make it no it's like
a death trap traps me underneath the
glass block and everything so here's the
very strange things about boats you'll
notice I didn't pick up any sticks or
planks right that's because the boat
actually broke over here for some reason
um it's so weird so very weird it's
almost like boats calculate their
position twice or something like where
where the server thinks it is and where
my client thinks it is or something it's
so messed up really needs to be fixed um
try one more time
oh it's out wait a second do I have any
on me no I'm going to make a couple more
here we'll try it one more time today
we're going to head out to the amplified
terrain area we haven't been there in so
long I keep meaning to go there and some
of you're like what what on earth etho
what why haven't you gone there what's
going on uh have you abandoned its in in
a way I have because I haven't been
there in so long but no I definitely
want to keep doing stuff there come on
make it make it no very very strange
stuff alright anyway I'll have to keep
working on this hopefully we can get a
solution ok guys so before we take off
to the amplified terrain we're just
going to be chopping down some trees
here first or I'm going to be I need
saplings lots of these dark oak saplings
we also need some of this wood and I'm
doing an experiment here I'm curious how
many saplings you get on average from
one of these trees and the reason I'm
curious is because today
what we're gonna be doing at the
amplified terrain is building a
semi-automatic dark oak ah no stinking
thing man there's so much stuff in it
two semi-automatic dark oak tree farm
yes I spent like an hour and creative
today working out how to make one and
it's pretty good the only problem I'm
having with it is I'm not doing enough
saplings back from it to like keep using
it so it's only if I have extra dark oak
saplings that we would ever use it which
kind of stinks so I'm wondering how many
is possible from a tree on average okay
this one's probably not an accurate
sample but this one I chopped down a
little earlier we got rep to four
already there's a few leaves left
so yeah I'll chop a few trees and then
we'll compare the average I chopped down
eight trees and kept track here so this
is the results we got ten from this tree
seven and six seven let's see what else
is there one of them I think head get
meats I think one of them had eleven
eleven yeah five and five so took those
numbers and it averages averaged out to
seven point three seven five from my a
tree sample here so on average you get
about just just a little under double
saplings back from from each tree
the problem is with my tree farm I'm
only getting about two saplings per tree
so that's like half of what I need
all right we're off to the amplified
terrain all right so here we are guys
it's been a very very very long time
since we were last year the problem with
having a base so far away it's not like
you can just pop in and do one or two
things or something you got to really
make a point of going there ah which I
haven't done until today until today we
are going to get some stuff done here so
I looked around I think I'm going to put
the tree farm down here was it here I
think it might be further down yeah I
think in this this light area here it's
gonna pick up a fair bit of space I'm
going to just build inside the hill too
because it's not really anything too
fancy to look at so I'm going to have to
clear quite a bit of land maybe I'll
start here and we'll have like a tunnel
that goes a few blocks and then we'll
have the tree I also think it's going to
be a little easier to collect the
saplings with it at all all being
underground like this so that's another
reason I'm doing it awesome so we got
some land cleared out here I'm going to
writing it through the plan idea and
then we'll start building it so the tree
I don't know where to put the tree I'm
just going to put it here I didn't
measure anything or figure anything out
it just feels about like the right
distance so it's going to be whoa it's
going to be underground right but the
trees there we're going to push the wood
to the right and then probably make a
giant cube of wood over here so it's not
going to be totally underground I'm
going to cut away the mountain so that
you can see the giant Cuba would
hopefully but we're going to start
setting it up now the thing about these
dark oak trees they are extremely
destructive you have to be so careful
with them probably up there a bit more
here - gotta love that hey speaking all
right hopefully that's good so because
of that because they're so destructive
am I using the wrong now that's the
right wood it looks like spruce wood for
a second we can't place any like blocks
anywhere around like this ring here
except for wood if we put any other type
of block there or redstone or anything
it will get destroyed over time as the
trees grow because either the leaf
blocks will replace it or the wood will
or something within this area so that
makes it a bit tricky these trees are
also very finicky on the growing
conditions um so yeah basically get our
shell all around it's probably have to
go up a little bit higher that's good
just a bit more all right so we got a
wood casing around the tree here if we
made this out of stone the tree would
not be able to grow it's very finicky so
we have to use wood because the tree the
tree ignores wood when it's deciding if
it can grow or not we also don't want a
place like pistons right next to where
the the tree is going to grow because
these will get destroyed so we have to
go one more block out let's sit up here
and we're going to be using sticky
pistons for this part
tu-tu-tu-tu-tu-tu and we go eight blocks
up so we want double extenders eight
blocks up and this is a little tricky to
get going as you can imagine alright so
it should look something like this
so eight blocks tall all sticky pistons
two blocks wide now we got a wire all
these which looks a little challenging
but it's actually not too bad on the
inside of the tree just let me let me
show you this - it's still going to be
wood like this but these are going to
push the wood blocks two blocks over so
any wood like over here is going to get
pushed two blocks to the right and then
when this retracts it'll be empty space
again so pretty cool now if you don't
know how to do horizontal piston
extenders these double extenders this is
probably the simplest way of doing it if
you can unfortunately we can't do that
because that would involve us placing a
piece of redstone in one of these
corners where this wood is and it would
get destroyed so we have to do something
like this
but slightly modified it's a little bit
bigger all right so let's start over
here each of these is going to be three
by three okay so basically oh man
memory lapse how does it work again oh
maybe I I think I might have done this
in the wrong spot actually the table
goes over here yeah okay I think that's
right
so repeater there and there there and
there
this one is get set to four this one at
two um we need a block over here and
redstone dust there and there and that's
that's all we need for the double
extender so let's try it out and we
might dissect the tree a couple times
throughout this just so we can see
what's happening all right so if we
press the button pushes the two blocks
pretty cool and retracts so the next one
just goes right over top of that and on
the other side we just have to mirror it
so do that and start on the next one and
then we got to connect at this point
here on every layer and when it's all
done it looks something like this so
got on both sides there's four layers
total alright oops and I connect the two
sides together by running a wire oh yeah
and by the way to connect vertically to
each of the layers I just have a half
slab stair chase running up and it
connects at this point at each of them
um but yeah the two sides are joined by
this wire here so if we send it a pulse
it does ha so pretty cool now if there
was a tree grown here it would do this
notice there's nothing on the side I got
to fill this hole I keep falling in it
all right
pushes it right through like that so
that's pretty cool so I think we should
probably try it out before we do any
more just to make sure it works you
never know you never know here we go
span bonemeal not a good sign
all right it could be I need more space
possibly a little worried yeah okay I'm
going to try clear more space hopefully
that fixes it
aha I got it to grow here so let's push
a button alright that pushes the trunk
over now if we look inside yeah there's
still some wood at the very top there we
can't really get that layer because if
we build this piston or a any higher the
tree is not going to grow it's going to
be in the way so eight boxes the limit
here um I was having trouble with
getting it to grow I think possibly
because it was dark
oh no it's growing now I just I cleared
up cleared out enough space and it works
now I wasn't sure so most the time it
doesn't grow that tall anyway um so next
thing we're going to do we got to add
something in here to shear the leaves as
much as possible and this is something I
probably can improve on still with my
design
but I'll show you what I figured out
before I think we have to connect where
let's see I think okay clouds you have
had your day you've had your fun you you
be gone now I think starting from one to
three down if we put a piece of stone
right there is where we want to start
and this goes out like this and I think
like that and then run wire over top
this oh did I not I do have pistons good
good good
I planned ahead oh but I can't place
them all right it's going to be
challenging so now we're going to have a
big wall of Pistons running up here and
these are going to extend and shear any
leaves that they touch and drop the
saplings all right I think that's it
again if we have any blocks in this area
I don't think the tree will grow so we
have to be careful and we're going to go
up three layers total and now that I've
added those leaf crushers it looks like
this so that is five blocks tall one two
three four and then another one here so
five wide five by five right yeah 25 and
per side that gets some leaves not
nearly all of them though and because of
all our contraption stuff not as many
leaves spawn when the tree grows so that
is where our deficiency is coming in and
I might look into improving this more
later let me just show you the top two
to give you an idea of one area where I
might try to improve it yeah at the very
top here we have all these leaves that
if I could crush these and somehow
collect them we would get
um well at least 25 more more than that
more than that this is a lot of a lot of
leaves isn't it the only problem is I
believe if there's a block at this level
here and I think even this one here the
tree won't grow so we would have to have
like a double extender going down
somehow for it to work and the tree to
still grow to crush these leaves which
is a little challenging um
anyway maybe we should give it a try and
by the way the nice thing about these
crushers here I don't have to really
connect anything to them or do anything
fancy because they connect directly from
this staircase here it powers them so
the thing that pushes the tree trunk
over also activates the crushers for the
leaves and oh do I have any blocks here
run it one more time here alright is it
going to grow no that would have been
very lucky if we did I got more bonemeal
over here set up a little workstation
I'll probably move this jump pad over
here and get rid of it and is there
anything in the way nope we're good
still so hmm it's not going to crush
many leaves it looks like only 10 this
was a very tall tree I might need to
build this up higher actually yeah it's
not going to get very many here uh-huh
but one thing we could do for collecting
them is run hoppers maybe this way I
don't know something like this and then
any saplings that fall will hopefully
land on these hoppers and end up at the
front here but yeah that's basically it
for right now then all this wood is
going to get collected into a giant
clump hope hopefully but I haven't
figure that out yet but it'll probably
get pushed to the left here and then
forward somehow uh-huh so if we want to
clean up this area too if we want it to
look a little nicer we can hide it kind
of like this you know and yeah that way
we don't see any redstone wiring if we
want to hide all that and it'll just be
like a little tunnel we enter alright
guys so that is probably going to be
about it for today but we're going to do
just a little bit of trading here too
we got a new librarian in the village I
want to see what we can unlock let's do
this maybe we will do the common thing
as I do it so last episode I talked
about how maybe pressure plates and and
that kind of stuff buttons and whatever
should be able to be placed on glass
right got this reply it says glass
doesn't allow redstone power to flow
through so a pressure plate on glass for
the traditional sense it would be
pointless though for your instance I
wish it would I had a few people comment
about the whole like pressure plates on
glass thing so there is an instance in
the game where something similar is done
you can put pressure plates on fences
right the fences don't actually get
powered from it if you were to put
pressure plates on glass it would be
pretty much the same thing you couldn't
pull power from the glass block like if
you put a repeater by it but you know it
just adds a little extra something you
can do or a little extra flexibility in
the game so I think it would be a good
thing all right we have to do this can't
believe you didn't you didn't unlock a
new trade after all that paper trading
all right glass usually if that's a
glass trade I just do it because it's
simple yeah easy way to unlock it let's
trade them some more paper give them a
bunch actually all right it should be
about it for the books right all right
what's it going to be 14 emeralds it
might be the level 3 thing
Ott's feather falling one at the most
expensive price I believe that's not
good do a little bit more trading 2nd
comments did you ever finish Wilson I
I've forgotten a lot of people asking
about Wilson Wilson is technically
finished guys I did finish him so don't
don't give me that you never finish your
projects thing I did finish him this is
kind of so-so not too good I'm not happy
with him currently he is finished but I
want to make some adjustments to him
like an update so it worked Wilson works
he's alive he can be brought to life and
you can feed him and cure a sickness and
all that stuff he dies the ages but
there's a few improvements I didn't
think of but they're going to take a lot
of work to implement so I I just haven't
gotten to it yet but Wilson is is
finished sort of alright guys so that's
going to be it for today I hope you
enjoyed today's episode been trying to
get more regular with our series here
with our single-player series because
for a while I was going like 5 to 6 days
between episodes and that's that's just
a little bit too long so I'm trying to
get it back to like 3 or 4 days between
if I can so hopefully I think I can keep
up with it but that's it for today I'll
see you again in the next one have
yourselves a good day bye bye
you