[Music]
oh no
oh my skin's gone again hello everybody
how's it going
oh i just had it i swear
uh check it out it's wonderful
it's working much better now
that 27
getting much better rates i've been
lighting up a lot of caves doing tons of
caving
and i got almost guts i know i keep
saying that but i
almost got it all done um
i'm sort of at the slow and painful part
of it though
uh where i got just tiny little dark
spots that i have to look
look for and light up and
but yeah it's going pretty good we got
we actually have gunpowder now
yeah lots of caving um
while caving i found a few cool things
too which i'll show you
let's see let's go up to the top
[Music]
here the slimes though
that's one thing i need to prevent i
need to stop slimes from spawning
because they're taking up my other mob
spots that could be used for creepers
for example
so i need to put half slabs down in
slime chunks which is going to take a
long time to do that
and i checked it out and i got about 32
slime chunks i need to deal with
you can hear the record from a long ways
away okay
first cool thing i found is over
over there you can still hear it
and i am level 33 from caving so we
should do an enchantment
but yeah right here is a zombie spawner
nice and close to the surface which is
pretty cool
um i'm tempted to do something with that
not really an xp
farm but maybe something fun with mobs
um it wouldn't really be that
valuable of an xp farm i only got one
pearl left
the other one i found
you can hear them in there i think it
was on
this mountain let's go check
i left the torch on the outside just
looking for it
i don't see it
i think that might be it no
hmm
it was pretty close to the top there it
is
oh way too short
this is pretty cool
there's a mob spawner up here why 90
93 i think that's the highest i've ever
found a mob spawner before
up in the mountain here so that's that's
really cool
and again i want to do something with it
i'm just not exactly sure what
but i'll think about it um
all right let's head on over to the
other base we'll enchant something
and i'll see you there
let's do a shovel again
pretty good pretty good um
okay so i just tuned the note blocks
there too so let's try those out
see what you guys think of them i just
did in a very
systematic way um
see let's get our iron
one two three four five six seven eight
um yeah i just kept increasing it by
three notes or three
whatever octanes or not octanes octaves
i don't know what i'm saying um
just listen tell me what you think
that's the deepest one
and it keeps going higher pitch by three
each time
i thought that one was broken i'm not
sure i'll have to look at that
it's always been giving me trouble
probably missing a wire
all right so that's how i did it oh
there it is
uh soil block is missing
[Music]
yep okay i think we got it
so i think we are ready for today's
project i got all my stuff together
and organized um here's what happened uh
yesterday i think or two days ago i was
ender
balling around the nether and i hit
a zombie pigman
and just about lost
everything i had on me because they just
kept hitting my butt
i didn't have i wasn't able to re-equip
and everything
so today we are going to work on the
nether hub idea
a bit and try to get that going because
i would really like
some better transports than trying to
get around this mess
i've given out a lot of thought
originally i was going to do it like
we have on the minecraft server where
you have lots of different
um you know things around the hub
destination points that's what i'll say
destination points around the hub
and you just put the mine cart on the
one you want to go to hit the button
and go from point a to point b and point
b to back to point a type thing
very simple works great on the minecraft
server
and it's very easy to set up
however i am on a single player world
here i can do
i can make this as fancy or as simple as
i want
and i think i'm going to go try or try
go the fancy route wait a minute
so this is at 87. trying to figure out
how high we want the nether hub
i think we want to go a little bit lower
so i brought the tnt
yeah i think most of my portals are down
lower
well it doesn't actually you know it
doesn't matter what height we do it we
can always move
these portals um
maybe
let's go down to about let's go down to
i 64. 64 would be a good place for
another hub
um because i may make some tunnels
where you can look out into the nether
and that would be cool
if you build in the roof or the ceiling
it's very easy
to build it without getting interference
from gas
and same if you build it way down low
uh because you don't encounter these
open areas but if you want a good view
i think 64 is probably the way to go
okay so maybe let's just
i'm a little well wait a minute wait a
minute
let's let's start in the center
go down all the way to 64 and then start
hollowing out a huge
area and i'm probably going to get this
stupid block glitch a bunch of times yep
here we go
very tempted to update to the snapshots
most of you guys said it would be okay
if i did
so i've heard this problem is fixed but
i don't know if that's true or not
oh it's so frustrating because once you
do it
there's like no way out except by
relodging
okay i'll see you guys in a bit
we are down here tnt is placed we're
gonna see how much of this will blow out
with
i think 13 tnt
one there there
there and i'm trying to make like a 25
by 25
circle hub i think
um so we'll see how this goes
oh yeah and by the way oops geez
uh we are at y68 so i'm expecting it'll
blow about
four blocks down or so maybe more i i've
never really
used tnt a lot in the nether so
i think nether netherrack is much like
soil though
all right
[Music]
man well that's the bulk of our work
done i think
right down to 64. sweet
awesome pretty round two no it's not
perfect but it's
it's pretty good so i think the next
thing i'm going to do is start laying
down
a stone brick floor i got to make i want
to make everything gas proof it's very
important to me
i don't want to have to fix anything
once i've built it in the nether here
so maybe at level 63 i will put down
a 20 25 by 25 circle
um out of stone brick and then i'll get
back to you
oh i love tnt hahaha
yes
whoops
one two three four five six seven eight
nine
ten eleven twelve we got the circle laid
out let's fill it in
great so we got our circle
done here it's a 25 diameter like i said
and it feels like a good size i think
it's good
the next thing we got to do is move our
nether portal
our main one down here
and this is the center point you'll
notice so i've been
i've been doing this by odd numbers like
this circle has a 25 diameter so
we're gonna have to arrange the portals
in a way that they're an odd number two
there's a pigment up there i'm gonna hit
i know it
see i'm gonna break this portal up here
get some more obsidian
i did i can't believe it oh no i was
inside
never mind hey
hey
um
yeah whatever um yeah i'm going to break
that get some more obsidian
and we're going to make an odd sized
portal
this is where i had the nether portal it
was in a 4x4
pattern now we're gonna make it a five
by five odd number
with this as the center so we will do
this
and let's hope it works or links up
properly still
like that unfortunately though you can't
really customize portals they always
have to be the same way
two three four
two three four so i think we're just
going to make it look like a
one wide by three high thing
you'll see
okay so that's all the net the obsidian
we had this is my extra i brought
be really cool if you could do like a
three by three portal or something
i know you can look with like mc edits
or
other editors but
not with regular minecraft
uh let's do
that either puts a column on this side
or the side
it doesn't matter much i guess we'll
just do here
and let's light it up try it out
and this should take me back to the man
cave
very good and if this portal is not here
it takes me to the snowflake
portal
all right how does that compare to this
circle size it takes up quite a bit of
the room doesn't it
we may have to make it bigger i'm not
sure yet
uh but what we got to figure out now is
what we want to make the nether hub
out of because i don't really want to
make it stone brick it's
it's really dull so we got to put a
lining over top this
uh either wood or or sandstone or
something we can get stairs and half
slabs out of
and i think i'm going to go with
sandstone but we also got to figure out
another
block to go with it so i'll mess around
with it a bit and figure something out
the smelting just finished let's get our
xp
we were at 6 i think
13 16
did i miss one oh my mouse keeps going
crazy
20 oh yeah you quite a bit from smelting
iron in that
22.
let's be adventurous with this i think
i'm going to go with purple wool and
sandstone
always wanted to use purple wool with
something very rarely do i use wool
actually so
be nice change and
it goes well with the portal color too
so as far as this circle size again it's
25 i think we should go up to
31. so three blocks each
each side and that will make this feel
better because i wanted to put
a skin over the portal as well so it's
going to come out
at least one more block yet so we kind
of get something like
like that you know just the one wide
slit
but yeah we'll mess with that in a bit
um i'm going to cover this with
sandstone as well
and later we'll probably incorporate
some design into it
but i just want to get it covered we
want half slabs so we don't get any gas
spawning in this big open
space you know so i think that'll work
out good
and i'll get back to you guys in a
little bit
purple sheep
and now it is a few hours later and we
have done a lot of sand
collecting lots of uh flower collecting
and wool collecting and we can go again
again thankfully
so this is a circle the new 31
feels like a good size i left this part
empty
so i wanted to try to put the wool by
that
and just see what it looks like and
where these torches are i
think i'm going to put lamps there
they're kind of behind so from back here
you still see all purple
no lamps in the way um
i think this is going to look pretty
good when it's all done
but yeah back to the whole
um minecart system style
like i said i'm not doing the a to b
tracks i'm
i want to actually set up a station
well this is pretty good
yes i like it i want to set up a
minecart
station we're going to have four
destination selectors so one at this
direction
one there one there one there and
each of those we're going to have up to
choices of destinations that we can
program in as
as we create them with what i have in
mind
and you're going to select your front
from uh
from each one there's going to be 10
buttons and you hit the one you want to
go to
and select it that way so
i think it's going to be cool i kind of
miss you know ever since
wait am i supposed to put it there yeah
ever since uh i got rid of the old
booster glitch on minecarts i noticed
there's
not nearly as much attention to minecart
stations and all that it's kind of sad
because that was a big part of the game
for a long time and people made some
pretty cool
stuff so i've never actually
made a minecart station myself believe
it or not
it's always something i've avoided
because i was scared of minecarts i
didn't know
many of the tricks like a lot of people
did
so this is going to be fun for me
yeah i love i love these two colors
together
all right um
we should do something about the portal
try skin it let's get out our sandstone
and just play around with some stuff
try to incorporate purple in it too
snag that there it is
okay half slabs and you have slabs yep
okay so we want to get it down
to the slit
like that uh it doesn't
i want to try making a look wider though
so if if we hide purple in
like that that helps it blends in with
the portal and it makes it look
wider um
let's see if we can make it something
that looks like a 3x3 i think that would
be good
even if it's not really even though it's
like a one
by three it'll look like a three by
three
yeah come on move quicker
it's hard to build while recording
because i always wanted to go really
quick
uh but then mistakes happen and
yeah i just feel like cutting it always
but we'll just
we'll just try this out
give me that thank you um
get some of those down
and put some on this side we'll just see
how that looks
and go from there
that's better i like that more
see yeah because we have like we're
utilizing a three by three area so it
sort of makes it look wider
even though it's not to me anyway
um
purple purple
just try to spread it out some more
oh yeah but we also gotta add some
lighting
in the middle have lighting on the
outside and lighting in the middle
that's pretty cool too okay i'll tell
you what i'm gonna get some lamps put
those around
see how it looks and maybe mess with
this some too
so i got a bit of a surprise i guess i
used up my big glowstone collection and
these are the last
12 lamps i have available
i'm gonna have to get more glowstone but
i did all around here
and i also changed it what do you guys i
don't know which is better what do you
think is better
have it like that because i changed it
because i realized i did exactly the
same as
as in here
see i did that here as well where the
stairs are
are like that and then the block sticks
out
oh but i did that different that's right
going back something i noticed uh with
the recent patches
the end loads really quick for me now
which is cool
like almost as soon as you go in the
portal it loads instantly
so yeah it could either either do it
like
that or do it like
we had it there like that
looks more together if it's like this
but anyway uh something else i thought
would be cool
if we put a glowstone here not a
glowstone
lamp um yeah we gotta get underneath it
oh yeah and i broke another pick i'm
really using up tools today like i went
through a lot of tools i'm out of
shovels again
um
and then change this to stairs wait that
wasn't supposed to be there
go stairs then
that's cool um
i wonder if we can do that at the top
too
oh out of stairs
but yeah i'm having pretty fun lots of
fun with this project
um i was going to show you all the caves
i lit up today again
just so you could compare but maybe next
time we'll do that i think we're running
low on time
and uh i did want to start on the
station today too but
i think we're running low on time but i
do have that mostly figured out
oh yeah there's no there's no top on
this thing oop
there we go
okay that's cool and then
maybe if we did that
oh yeah i'm liking this you know i think
i do like this more actually
than this the eye shape
okay so i'm gonna i'm gonna continue
this and
wait actually
bounce out bounce it out because you
only see the top half now you can just
see the bottom half
that's that's probably better too
cool all right i'll work on this some
more and i'll get back to you
i found 19 more lamps at my other base
so we were able to finish it and it
gives out a lot of light
it's good the only real dark spot is the
middle ring
because these give out a lot of light
too
um so i think when this is all done
we should maybe suspend some lighting
from the ceiling in this middle part
if if we want it's it's pretty bright as
is
and it doesn't affect spawning at all so
it doesn't really matter
then with the portal we'll also probably
attach it to the ceiling
and that'll be cool
i wanted to try this also if we put
supports here instead of having it
floating like that
let's try it out do it here too
that way it looks more complete
[Music]
mm-hmm that's that's pretty good um
maybe stick some purple wool in
over there
yeah i like that also i
i did bring some of these let's play
around with that too
so i'm i am thinking about doing a ctm
map solo guys what do you think of that
idea
um i have one picked out which i'll keep
secret for
now uh and it would go along with the
huge
thing thing about ooj
i have a lot of fun playing with those
guys but we only play like once every
second week or so and i like ctm maps i
would play them a lot more often
if or i want to play them a lot more
often i actually do i play off camera
like i just played deathly trails a fair
bit and before that i tried
what was it called vex
vex um
oh what was another one what's it called
i can't remember for the life of me
nightmare realms
vex's nightmare realms i played that uh
for a little bit but
the problem is when i play alone i try
to rush through it and
i don't set up bases so if i die i lose
everything and then i can't continue
really so
if i was to play and record it would
force me to slow down
a bit and actually get through the whole
map
that would be that'd be pretty good so i
would alternate
between uge and my solo thing and do
that and in addition to the lps and that
because
ctm maps you can i can record it just
about
real time and get lots of episodes out
doing that they don't get nearly the
views of other things i do
which is okay because i mostly do them
for fun
anyway so
yeah just an idea let me know what you
think of that
and let me know what you think of this
pretty happy with it yeah
so next time i think we could move on to
the stations
and the stations
to elaborate on that a bit more uh it's
not a full station like i'm not going to
have
cart handling or anything like that just
just a launching
selector thing really um and maybe a few
other fancy things but
that's about it
all right here we go etho i have watched
almost all of your videos and i have
loved every single one of them
i have enjoyed watching you build the
creative things you build
thank you very much but what i would
like to know
is what is your favorite thing that you
have ever built in minecraft
thanks and keep up the great work
it's a hard decision but i think i would
go
if i had to name one thing i would go
with the whole ice base
thing from the old world uh just because
it was
a collection of pretty much all my mob
related knowledge in the game and
yeah i put a lot of thought into that
thing which it's a shame i
wasn't able to fully complete it but i
did get a lot done
and it was working really well so it was
cool to see that
as far as from the viewers perspective i
think the best received thing i've ever
built was
the was spazz's canon general spazz's
cannon in the 50k
special a lot of people seem to really
like that
of course also notable mentions are eats
road
silverfish farm more recently the sheep
farm there i'm still pretty proud of
that even though it's not done
i i don't know there's a lot of things
the storage room the old storage room
even the design for this i'm pretty
happy with this place here the man cave
uh i don't know there's a lot of things
i'm pretty happy with
but uh yeah that's a good question thank
you very much for that and
for everybody's inputs
well guys thanks for watching
see you later have a good day