[Music]
hello greetings and welcome
how many of you remember this
monstrosity the duel
blaze farm you know i kind of forgot
about this place i thought i would check
it out
because i couldn't remember where i left
off on it
and yeah it's like almost done i
forgot i built this thing the killing
chamber and we got
a light switch and everything
uh but i do remember i i stopped working
on it because i was
frustrated i couldn't couldn't figure
out what to do and
i came here today and it's like what was
the problem it's so
so simple all i have to do
getting jammed here why didn't i just
move this conveyor belt up one block so
that
um instead of them being pushed that way
into the lava if they get pushed
from this side and this side into lava
that way the two don't
join together it'll
it'll work just fine i don't know don't
know what i was thinking so
what i have to do is the hole
is right there i need to change it to
that one
right there um and then
that'll make the soldier moved up one
block so that they
join with this lava properly
i don't know you know as i as i keep
playing this game i feel like i'm
getting better at it and
stuff just becomes clearer but
yes this looks like an easy fix i don't
know what the trouble was
so i'll work on that and hopefully i'm
not overlooking something that was the
main problem
i'm pretty sure
yeah all right get to work
oh man you know this project
i'm starting to remember why i got
frustrated with it because it's like
nothing wants to work ever
even when it seems like it should uh i
did kind of just fix
one of the problems i was having like i
made the changes
and the problem is when this piston goes
off
it pushes them into the lava but it
usually pushes them a little bit beyond
that so they don't actually swim
up they'll they'll go on to that
pressure plate so they'll
get pushed through to the other side and
that just
breaks everything like you kind of just
thought there um
i helped to make that a lot
better by putting a fence you can't see
it but there's a fence underneath that
lava which
brings them up half a block and i also
have
upside down half slab there so they can
actually go on to the fence
otherwise uh it would stop them
and that just gets them off the pressure
plates so that
if they don't go up the lava they won't
be on the other pressure plate on the
other side at least
and then when a blaze comes by he can
correct them
usually sometimes they'll wander off the
fence onto the pressure plate anyway
but then the huge problem i'm having is
over here now because i've changed
change this all around and i can't i can
only put one pressure plate down
now otherwise it will activate these
conveyor belt
pistons and
yeah so i i'm kind of fed up with this
um what i'm gonna do
and if this doesn't work i'm gonna be
really fed up i'm just gonna
get rid of this whole conveyor belt well
not get rid of it but you did the whole
pressure plate deal with it
and just took up a clock hook up a
monostable circuits
have it fire regularly and that way i
can control
their movement a little bit better
instead of leaving it up to them
and yeah that way they shouldn't get
stuck in blocks either because
uh the blocks will only extend for like
two ticks and then pull back
um yeah because
that's what happens the block extends
and then they just substitute to death
if there's a problem and there are lots
of problems
so i'll work on it some more
okay we got a few levels from the blaze
let's see what we get here
amazing i love it
yeah so you can see i got the
caterpillar ripped out there
and i'm about to start rebuilding it
again takes a little time to do that
every time
but that's okay um
i've been a little bit stubborn about
not wanting to use a clock on this
project
but i'm giving in now i'm i'm just
i'm done with being stubborn and it's
not really
like i don't like clocks because they
cause lag but i can i can hook it up to
this button here
the light switch so that it's not
running if
if the lavas down like this and blaze
aren't spawning
so
i should i should just not be as
stubborn and just do this
um this comes with a few changes and a
few benefits as well
like i don't need to use sticky pistons
anymore i can use the regular ones
because i couldn't use the regular ones
before because sometimes the blaze would
glitch
into them and then that would totally
jam everything up but now it doesn't
matter because if they do that
just wait another second or two and
it'll fire again and they'll
they'll go through type thing and
the regular pistons won't cause them
suffocation damage as they go through
this
this belt here so that's a huge
improvement
um i'm gonna have to do a little bit
more redstone wiring though because
we're not using pressure plates anymore
and this this part here
i'm not going to have pressure plates
here either i'm going to hook this up to
the clock because this is a
a bit of a trouble zone
so i just have three pistons
these two will get activated first and
then that one on a delay
like this and again they're regular
pistons so they won't cause suffocation
if the blades don't get pushed by the
arms
and yeah so that's a little update i'll
continue working
and show you what happens
and here's another quick update i just
finished
redoing the the caterpillar belt here
with the regular pistons it looks a lot
narrower now
but we haven't had the redstone yet
which i'll do next
and give you a run through of them
because we don't have the blocks in
front of the pistons anymore so it seems
a lot more claustrophobic hopefully it
still looks cool
we should maybe go above actually let's
get out of here
see what it looks like from above now
yeah so we'll put redstone beside it
it's not going to be
extremely compact the redstone because
it's
things are a bit tricky when you do a
diagonal pattern like that
yeah it's still pretty cool okay well
i'll do the redstone and we'll see how
it looks
check it out man oh you picked a bad
place to spawn boy
there's one spot you picked oh
right in the killing machine that's not
where you want to start out
oh it doesn't kill him oh now i gotta
tap him
find out wow there's
wait a minute wait a minute does that
mean they have more health than blaze
what the heck two hits
i'm gonna have to look at their health
after this that was weird i thought he
would have died long ago
anyway i've been working on the redstone
it is
pretty straightforward um
got a little bit of a problem right now
which i'll
hopefully figure out soon so both sides
this is the pattern they're connected
here both the sides
excuse me this one's at 1
then three then there's a four
one three four one three four
and then the other side it goes
uh two four four two four four two four
four and that just makes it so
uh they alternate so that one fires
first then that one then that one and
that one all one tick of parts
um but the problem i'm having is uh
nothing unpowered and i don't see where
it would be backtracking in the currents
or not yet anyway so
powers there that goes to that block
there's no redstone near that so that's
not it
um same deal with that you got a
repeater next to that block so it's not
sending power
through there anywhere um
it's going to this block but it that
should just power it further
down oh wait wait wait wait
it's very strange
i know it's something simple i just
can't see it
why would that be causing it
because this power is not getting back
this way
i don't know
this power is not getting through these
two repeaters
to over here it's only getting through
here
oh there it is right there whoops
you see what was going on there because
it's going to this repeater and then it
goes back
to the wire and then it goes back to the
repeater and back to the wire and
it does a loop so if i okay i found it
yeah so that should fix that side
okay so what i got to do now is hook up
a mono stable
i don't have to but i want to
and then also a clock
in the middle here and hook that up to
these things
and i'll probably be covering this
redstone i'm not sure with what
if i want it to be visible or not i'm
not sure because it kind of looks cool
it's a nice pattern going on there
yeah so this is getting a little scary
um
should be up and working now i haven't
tested it on the blaze yet
we'll do that soon but i got a clock in
um it is lagging the game a lot
a lot a lot i'll probably try a few
things here to
decrease that i think if you put
pumpkins like glowing pumpkins under
these repeaters it might cause
less lag because it doesn't have to do a
lighting update then
because the pumpkins emit way more light
than the repeaters when they're powered
so i i'm hoping that'll help the leg
issue
um
it's pretty cool though this is the
clock here i sort of went for a fancy
look
instead of function it could be
delayed a lot more too but i don't
keep it like this for now and that just
branches off over here which goes
to both sides
both both sets of pistons and then
also goes to up here which is
for that stuff
and i put in a cheaty
monostable circuit right there i don't
know if
many people know about that trick i just
kind of stumbled on it right now
it's a sticky piston that goes up which
causes it to
really shorten the pulse here i'll try
to demonstrate it
so without the piston
the pulse is like this look look how
many repeaters are lit up it's it's ten
ticks from the button
so that's two and a half repeaters set
at four
um do the same
thing with this little cheaty thing
watch out it'll start at two and a half
and then it'll get
shortened when it goes through that
now it's just one repeater if we lower
these we might be able to see exactly
how long it is
get these all down to one oh now that
oh that might be a way i can shut it off
who knows
um okay well i gotta set these at least
to two then
what's gonna do now now it's fine
you see though it's still only one
repeater so it's it's a quick false
that doesn't stay on very long so that's
a little cheaty monostable circuit the
only thing about it it only works
certain directions it's a little bit
iffy
um wow those things are going crazy
still recording at 30 frames per second
which is good but when we get the blaze
going in here
we are gonna have problems for sure
they don't need to be firing all that
often
really attempted to put in a longer
clock
whatever still don't have a shutoff for
it yet i did start
branching a wire out over here though we
gotta hook up a t-flip flop
to two o'clock somehow to turn it on or
off
um let's try this out with blaze
still working yep let's get it going
and this is going to cause lag let's
we'll to see if they go through this
thing okay or not accidentally spilled
some lava there too which is
slowly disappearing
let's head down a little lower
big project spending lots of time on
this
he didn't go
why is he not going
okay maybe the mono stable is not a good
thing
they're not getting pushed at all for
some reason
so we'll get rid of that
and reset this
oh i did it again duh
you gotta wait for it
oh they're looking at us through the
pistons that's not good um
and what the heck they're not moving at
all
i gotta increase the delay between
pistons maybe
could be because they're tracking us
okay i'm gonna
i'm gonna leave the area and retry this
let them despawn
okay let's try it again uh we're gonna
stay up here this time
so that they can't see us and then later
we'll put blocks around the pistons once
we're sure this is gonna work
i'm a little worried because i just
spent a lot of time on this
and if it doesn't work i'm gonna be out
of ideas again
i don't know why it wouldn't work they
should move
what is it doing
wait is that one going before
it's almost like i got the timing wrong
i think that's what it is
pretty sure that piston fired before
that one
huh i bet you that's what it is okay i
think i see the problem
i spot another problem there's a piston
missing here apparently
supposed to be one right there
yeah i'm pretty sure that was a problem
i haven't tried it yet like with the
blaze but it looks like it's firing
a lot better now that i've added an
extra piston that was
that was what was throwing the timing
out too because that adds an extra two
ticks to that side
um and you can tell it looks a lot
better now
when it's going let's get the clock
going
let's hop up oh i can't
um put a little extra glass there
look at this this looks a lot better now
yeah you can tell that's right now and
that's also why they were getting stuck
right at the drop there because there
was no piston for him
so let's get the blaze going and i'm
pretty sure it'll work this time
we can only hope
so much so much lag though i don't like
that
but only when this is running
which is probably when i'll be aft
anyway so it won't really annoy me but
i'm gonna try the extra lighting and see
if that helps
okay there we go yay
what's wrong with him he's going on his
own okay
um
they seem to be seem to be having
trouble getting up there
uh
it would help if i sync the two together
which i may do i just like the the oh
timer thing that looks cool you can't
really sink them
well tougher to sink them
doing it that way
um they're getting there though
the thing is if it misfires now it
doesn't really matter because they don't
take damage from it
i may also put back the fence in the
half slab trick
although i don't know if that would help
yeah yeah it should actually um
okay let's go down see if they're still
tracking us
through the pistons now that we've got
that extra glass
i think when the arm moves here that's
when they can see you
frames are not doing down to 27 now
and i do not have particles on yeah
they're really getting jammed there now
okay well i'll watch it for a bit
they're not getting jammed in there at
all
all right
yeah you know what this thing's doing
pretty good i i'm impressed i thought it
would have been a lot
a lot worse at this point we're at over
200 blaze
at like 220 there plus there's a few
more down
and uh recording my frame rates at about
10 to 15
and when i'm not recording it's it's
over 30 so
that's definitely tolerable at this
point and i would probably
not want to go over 250 anyway
because you like you can do two harvests
and be level 50
if you if you get them at that point
which is what i would probably do
so should work should work out fine
that's what i'm trying to say
um i want to hook up a dispenser with
poison potions
and bring some splash potions here too
because that'll be a lot simpler
um i'm going to attempt this while
recording i hope but
you know what no i'm going to
well i can't it's going to say it's
going to make a backup but i can't
um
oh i probably shouldn't do that i'm just
worried i'm gonna freeze and then i'm
gonna lose my world again
see how many die
there's a few dying oh that's not bad at
all that we only lost like four or five
and that's from them going down the cone
not from our conveyor belt
so excellent uh
hitting them like this though it takes a
long time i don't
i don't like it that's why i want the
potions
i just wish i had a water source here so
i could brew them
like i can on the minecraft server but
i'll just
have to set up an easy way to transport
them here or something
because i'll probably use this more than
the enderman farm now
and now we're going to enjoy the fruits
of our labor level 42
[Music]
pretty good pretty good so i'm gonna
uh i'm gonna bring over some damage
potions there and we're gonna try those
out i guess
we really don't need poison potions
because
it gets them down to one hit with very
few dying
i also want to bring over some melons
um
in the future we will set up
um you just want to get out don't you
we will set up an enchanting room there
as well as
some food providers
maybe a melon farm or something would
you back away from the door
there i can do that you know um
damage damage damage it's good stuff bad
stuff
oh that's not it harming
oh there they are
so we'll bring a bunch of these over and
we'll try out and i'm gonna make a
backup before i do it just in case
i should really shorten the the delay on
that door
because i'm i'm worried about that guy
now
okay let's head back to the nether what
else did i want to bring
i wanted to bring something else
i'll remember when i get there
okay we're going to do a stress test
here uh we're
at 264 roughly
blaze let's suffocate them
i'm just curious if this is going to
make me blue screen or what's going to
go on here um
running at the solid two frames per
second at the moment
what do we oh yeah look at the look at
the spike in the graph that's awesome
um that must have been when i started
recording
is it done yeah it must be done okay
this is it
this four frames five frames per second
solid
oh man whoa oh wow that shot up real
quick
grab the or grab the rods
yeah it wasn't bad at all up to
20 20 frames per second
yeah it's sweet i'm gonna use this all
the time now
and we got amazing rocket fuel now
not that i need it i have like two
double chests full of coal that i'll
never use
sweet so the enchanting room i'm going
to build is probably going to be an
exact copy of the one i built on the my
track server just because i like that
one so much
um don't know where we'll put it but
that's that's what i'm leaning towards
and then we got our next group ready to
go
up to 27 already yeah this is this is
awesome
so happy i finally got this thing going
because oh
oh what the heck
is there a leak i guess we got a leak
interesting i wonder how that happened
but yeah i'm glad i finally got this
thing going because
i tell you i've i've had to tear stuff
out so many times and redo it and have
it not work again
and redo it and redo it and redo it
it just it feels good to finally get it
right or at least
i'm pretty sure it's right
and on that note i will actually will
enchant one more thing and then
i'll say goodbye
all right here we go level 47
okay another silk touch it's weird when
you just get silk touch on something
okay guys thanks for watching uh i'll
see you again next time i'm not sure
what we'll do
i i kind of want to get some grass
around the nether there get that going
so it doesn't look so
hard on the eyes but i don't know
we'll figure something out next time see
you then