[Music]
hello everybody greetings
thank you for joining me again i have
finished
or not quite finished but mostly
the storage room and i'm quite happy
with how it turned out so let's go
take a look at it
there it is and
that is the unveiling of the chess when
we walk in
and the the shutters stay open for as
long as we're in here and then when we
walk out we step on the pressure plates
again
and it closes like that so i think it's
a pretty cool effect
uh it's gonna need a little bit of
tweaking yet though
oh let's oh trying to jump over the
pressure plates
my sprint didn't work there we go
so yeah i really like how that looks
with the light coming in through the
stairs
it's almost like uh a display case
type look to it and in the very middle
of the room i've made this
uh big pot light type thing which i
think looks pretty cool too
let's get some light in here
so this is a fairly complicated
uh that's a stair there that's also a
stair
well not not super complicated and then
underneath these half slabs
is pumpkins and that's what
makes it light like that the light
shines through the half slabs
and you can see like if it's like that
that stair and that stair lights up
but if you have them completely blocked
off
you don't have the light leak through
and that's kind of a problem i had with
this storage room too
i had to change the lighting i was going
to use lamps before
and try to do something fancy with them
but there was an issue with the light
leaking through
um actually we need to change this too
well
i'll show you the problem first
um the lamps
were over there before
where that glowstone is and problem is
the pistons are there
as well
hopefully we can see
and what that does is it makes these
stairs light up too
and there's really no way of avoiding
that because the pistons
are are right there and you can't uh
can't really move them so all all these
had
light leaking through the bottom stairs
and it didn't look quite as good
in my opinion so we're just going to use
straight glowstone on this whole
thing so that we don't have that problem
right i'm very sad i'm all out of
efficiency picks
so i'm gonna have to do some xp
grinding or something
um what we're gonna do with these
probably is get rid of all this light
wood and just make it
a solid glowstone thing back here
has all right otherwise it looks kind of
weird
yeah that's probably better that way
okay i just switched them all they'll
have glowstone there now
uh with this lighting it's not
actual lighting it's a visual just
visual lighting
but like as far as the game consists
considers it
if you look at the block lighting right
where i'm standing it's at level zero so
it's pitch black right here
and again with that that's not lighting
anything it just uh
just a visual thing the only thing
really lighting this room is uh
the pumpkins under there
and under there and if we walk
towards it we can see this is a block
lighting right here
the bl right here we're at one
two three four five and as we approach
the light it gets
gets higher um
there was some concern about mobs
spawning in here because if it's
pitch black it's possible mobs could
have spawned on the corners
not to worry i have switched those out
these are actually upside down half
slabs now so
no mobs can spawn in here anymore
can't spawn on stairs and they can't
spawn on half slab so it's completely
safe
and out here it's bright enough that
it's not a problem
and let's go take a look at the wiring
shall we real quick
there's two layers of wiring this is the
bottom pistons over here
and i'm going to clean up this room when
this is all done make the walls all
all smooth stone and what not
pressure plates is right two pressure
plates are above here and here
they power this wire and it sends power
to
this t flip flop here which is kind of
hidden away
um it's powered by default
i believe so it's a supercharged one
which makes it a little quicker
and that goes up to torch here
and up over here so the first pistons
that activate are the ones in the middle
those are set at four then there's a
four delay between
each chest section and then it goes to
four
four two four four two four four two
four so it's pretty simple pattern
other side is the same and the top layer
is the same as well this wire
in the middle keeps going up and
connects to
middle of the top pistons and
again four four two four four two four
four two four all the way down
and that's all there is to it so it's
pretty simple i was going to do
something with the lamps
but i think it's just better this way
and it's
a lot less laggy now that i got rid of
what i had wired for them you can see i
have like uh
like i had something here before i did
but i tore it all out
probably should have recorded it before
i did but oh well
wasn't overly cool uh there is an
issue with this though and i don't
really know what's causing it
it closes perfect exactly like it should
each of the pistons is uh two delay
apart from each other
but when it opens you can see some of
the stairs
on the top row are not
opening together like this this stair
here comes up before this one
this watch
even though they have the exact same
delay
uh there's a problem and that happens
for all of these i don't know
why exactly they close perfectly
in unison they just don't open right
so you saw that one came up first then
that one
that one came up first then that one
which is weird because this one is
supposed to have
a delay that's too shorter than that one
so i don't know could be just a visual
thing
like a drawing issue with the game
or i don't really know
let's take let's take a quick look up
here
oh this is uh
went too high
see i'm sure it's i wired it right it
goes
four then this is a two and that's at
four so there's no
reason and the piston
is below the wood block
so i got no idea
it's only with the top row the bottom
row does it just fine watch
see that one came down first and then
and then that one and that one and that
one like it's supposed to
all the way along just the top
one's messed up i don't know why
anyway if you know the reason let me
know in the comments
um i don't think it's like a bud switch
not updating thing because of the way i
have it wired that shouldn't be a
problem
but maybe it is i don't know uh
i would like to include other colors in
this
i'm really happy with the way this is
shaped
and this arch is pretty cool too it's
nice and gradual
we got what is it that's a stair
upside down stair here and then another
one
sideways over here and that looks pretty
cool i think
i'm happy with that this side is not
finalized yet though it's really flat
and we'll have to do something with that
but
really happy with the shape of this room
i'm going to put signs
over
like in these spots and i'll probably do
that right now and figure out
what chests i'm putting where and you'll
see how i organize this all
so i'll be back in a little while
all right i got that done took a while
quite a while actually
had a lot of stuff to move here i will
go through the chest real quick
misk items up here so like saddles
records
and anything else that doesn't really
fit anywhere
got my dragon egg in there um
then over here tools and i've been
putting buckets in here too
now i'm not a huge fan of using signs in
storage rooms usually i prefer
to have a display block or something so
if it's
a chest full of gravel have a a gravel
block next to it type thing
that's the way i did my old storage room
and i really like that because you can
see
from a distance what's in the chest like
from here i can't read that
at all but just this
is a simple storage room so we will
settle for that this is full of pearls
because i go through quite a few of them
rather quickly this one is potions
um because normally i have to run to my
potion room to get speed potions and i
should have a
a chest for them here just to make it
easier
this is plants and seeds and stuff
actually this is my food chest
should actually probably move these
mushrooms to the plant one
because you can't eat them straight
sugar maybe sugar too i don't know
nether wart
yeah in other words a plant not a food
what was i thinking
um then up here we have stone and stone
related things so
plain stone um we have mossy stone
crack stone regular stone bricks
and a chest full of cobble here
chest full of soil up here and i put my
grass blocks in there too
this is my wood chest which is basically
empty but
we'll have regular wood and then the
plank types
and maybe sticks and whatnot in there
odd blocks going here
i almost was tempted to have a double
chest just for gravel because i have so
much of it
but you don't really or i don't really
use it for anything so that's
more than enough on hand
and i do have like two double chests
full of netherrack but this isn't for
bulk storage this
is just to have a little bit of
everything at a decent
amount of supply of each thing this is
my sandbox
so we have regular sand sandstone
we'll have the new sand
stone types in here too glass glass
panes i might move these
this is my wool chest and dies so we'll
have all 16
walls and 16 dies in there this is my
steps so that includes that includes the
half steps
and the stair steps um
there's six types of these and i don't
know how many types of these i can only
think of the five
um this is my rail stuff so
tracks detector rails power rails
carts all go in here
now i just call this my function chest
so this is blocks that have
uh unique functions sort of
and lights and pistons and what not
going here
redstone chest and
you should maybe be moved i don't know
and this is my oars chest
and that's all there is to it so i think
i can pretty much
categorize all the items in the game
into
into those fairly easily uh
things like coal and blaze rods will
probably go into the furnace room when
it
when i get that set up um
but that's the storage room maybe
quickly play around with using some
sandstone slabs on the floor and roof
and see how that goes
so most that stuff came from these
chests down here and they're
pretty much empty now uh there's a few
things left
if you're prone to seizures you probably
should close your eyes for a minute here
just gonna go through them real quick
mostly just bulk items left in here
and these will get moved to the main
storage room which we will build
uh hopefully sometime soon keep saying
i'm going to do it but then
other things are coming up
so i do really like the way i have this
room shaped
i don't really want to change that at
all but
like this floor here is just one big
solid thing of uh
wooden slabs it would be cool to break
that up somewhat
with uh maybe these other textures
so i wanted to see how they all look
together with the wood
and pick the one that suits it the most
so we'll just put these all down pick
our favorites
yeah so out of these i think the brick
doesn't go at all um
these these two don't really look right
to me either
sandstone looks the best in my opinion
and this would be
second so let maybe let's try something
with sandstone
um one thing that was suggested is i
should make a chest
pixel art i don't know how that will
turn out but i guess we could try it and
just
just see so i think i had a look at
the way the chest looks right here
and it would be we got about an eight by
eight space to work here
maybe we'll just highlight it out of uh
we'll put this here for now highlight it
out of sandstone and see
how it looks
and if it looks crummy we will try
something else
so
with regards to episode 2 of the ultra
hardcore series
um a little bit of a spoiler here
in the tribal council round i do get
voted out
uh i got blindsided
i really
uh i hate to disappoint you guys but
that looks pretty good
actually yeah i just didn't see it
coming i thought i knew where my
alliances stood with everybody
but that's that b double o i tell you he
is
one sneaky son of a sweetheart
because i i had my trust in the wrong
places i tell you
but i'll i'll keep that in mind for next
time
but please don't be disappointed in me i
tried my best
let's try this
that is a terrible looking chest uh yeah
we won't do the chest that's for sure
um
all right well i'll just do some pattern
i guess i want to see what this looks
like too
if we were to replace this with the
sandstone instead of the wood
that's kind of cool i like that
i can't do a whole lot with this because
we need to pick a block that has
both the slabs and stairs and there's
really not a whole lot of options
there is these which don't go with wood
in my opinion same with these
nether brick might go but we don't have
half slabs in them
and i don't like brick with it so that
leaves zero
options really so
this room will probably mostly just be
wooden planks because i can't think of
any other
way of doing it that would look good
okay tell me which pattern you like the
most we'll call this
pattern one or option one it's kind of
like a target
i guess not too bad
i'm going to try another one now and see
if you like it more
this is it in the dark
and we'll call this one pattern number
two
with the dark
and we'll call this one pattern number
three
and with an option of also having a
dot in the middle
not sure which one i prefer the most i'm
sort of leaning towards number one
even though number two is sort of a
favorite of mine it doesn't
look quite right to me with the sharp
angle
but let me know which one you guys
prefer
all right everybody uh there was a few
other things i wanted to do today
but it's going to be a shorter episode
after all because
it is 2 a.m and i need to get some sleep
unfortunately but before we end this
i just wanted to show you my new cool
trick
for crossing bodies of water in the game
uh if for some reason you don't have
like an ender pearl or a boat or
something and you need to cross
water quickly maybe if someone's chasing
you or whatnot
i know it's impractical but it's a lot
of fun to do this
uh i've been trying to teach myself this
uh
this new move i'm calling the lily pad
hop
uh you kind of angle your mouse down
like this
run and failure
it's very tough to do actually let's try
it one more time
or until we get it
all right let's try it one more time
oh man i think i might have had my mouse
angled a little bit too far forward
i'll try like this
oh see that time i clicked the mouse too
quick it you got to get into a pattern
of doing it it's
it gets easier the more you do it i'm
just a little bit out of practice
at the moment there we go there we go
here we go we're doing it we're doing it
lily pad hop ah almost made it across
but i thought that was pretty cool
anyway that's it thank you for watching
until next time probably in two days
again that's what i've been trying to do
bye
you