[Music]
hello again everybody how are we doing
today
you're doing great you're doing just
great i'm telling you
it's a command you don't have a choice
in this you're doing great
uh i'm doing excellent uh thank you for
asking
just just a little bit better than you
but as long as you're doing great that's
okay i noticed this thing's messed up
the lights on none of these are on gotta
fix it
i never did wire up the different areas
yet
for it something we got to do
there's so many things i need to do that
are on the to-do list
oh there it is it's missing a block what
is going on here
um yeah so many things to do so little
time
always that's the way it goes
but little by little things will come
together in our man cave
uh i'm surprised nobody has ever
commented about that that hole has been
in the glass for
i don't even know how long my
uh but yeah let's do an enchantment to
start out with today i got 31 levels
all from caving to a whole bunch of
caving
awesome around the mob system at the
other
base because it's not been doing so good
lately not
not quite the drops i would be
um oh you bugger
um yeah since 1.3 came out
drop rates are not what they used to be
messing up the farm and i talked to a
lot of other people about this too and
they've noticed the same thing
it's just uh
i don't know what it is i okay so
you know that tutorial i made a lot a
little while ago uh
the half slab world where only only the
mobs will spawn in the mob system
uh i went to that world in 1.3 here and
it works
the rates are the same as in 1.25
but in in this let's play and on the
minecraft server
in 1.3 it's a lot slower than 1.25 just
from the version change
so some somehow it's like
mobs are able to spawn in dark areas
more often than before
but if you completely get rid of the
dark areas it works just like it did
back in 1.25 no differences in spawn
rates by looks of it just
somehow they're spawning more in dark
areas or something
i don't know don't know what it is the
rates are slower though
that's that's what i'm getting at uh
we're gonna
try work on the village a little bit i
don't know don't have a lot of time this
episode
so it might might not get a whole lot
done
um but i gotta clear out a lot of land
again and i don't have any tnt so
here i go
hmm where do you come from
can i kill you
oh
yep sweet so
uh what we're going to do here is we're
going to start sealing this place
off so we can do some villager behavior
tests
and we gotta let make sure everything's
lit up i have a world back
up in case we lose them uh goofing
around here
but truth be told i'm a little bit
without a plan
on this project um
and people have been really torn in the
comments about it too
like some people were
back we're really sad i was not doing
the industrial theme
and now i'm kind of thinking maybe i
should go back and do it not just
because because they want to do it but
because i don't really want to harvest
the ice that's going to be involved with
this because i
i don't have the silk touch picks or a
good ice tray like i have on the
minecraft server i'd have to set one of
those up and then
of course i wouldn't really want to
record that because i've shown that
already
twice so i don't know it's just
it would take a lot longer a lot longer
doing the snow theme here and also as
people pointed out i'm
going with a snow theme on the storage
room already maybe
i should do something else but
i don't know just lots of things to
consider
but yeah i don't really know what i'm
too well uh
what okay well here's the thing this is
this is the goal with the village it's
not just going to be a village
the goal is to also make them interact
with things we build
and have them entertain us that way
that's that's what i'm hoping for with
this
so we're just going to do some behavior
tests
see how plausible that is to make them
to control them the way we want to
so i'm going to get those guys in here
make sure there's no way for them to
escape
or for zombies to get in
i think we're about there
okay oh boy
okay we got the track how much do you
think these guys will cooperate with me
that is the question
don't want them out okay gotta try to
get them down
this can go bad very quickly
um
[Music]
see i kind of need to go down one block
but as soon as i do
they're gonna take off oh oh
stupid pic
ah of course oh
miss ah
wait where is he
of course he found a way huh
no yeah you come on
should have known if there's a way to
mess it up
i will find it
traps got him
sweet
and he is going in
[Music]
all right that's one
the other guy let's pick man
how's it going through the blocks so
quick
what is this thing it's just a four
all right next guy come on down
and he
he's just chilling down there wondering
where his friend went
you should move go
they never cooperate
man
i'm worried this is going to kill him
oh hey whoa
do you think he'll go into the wall
oh now he moves oh and i pushed him into
the wall he's fine
he's good okay
enjoy your new home
sweet i like how he kind of slid in
there too on the ice
like you like use the bargaining down ah
okay we'll remove that just so they
can't get up
so we got two villagers in here i'm
going to
get some sunlight down here next and try
set up a fake house
let's do let's do a test over here so
i'm gonna dig
how should we do do this
maybe i'll put it no i can't put a door
there i'll put a door here
dig straight up and have sunlight
here
this guy man he escaped again i don't
know how he did it
he's a smart one though
too smart for his own good
all right oh
i think you must have fell down so let's
put this further back
there okay we got
we got the sunlight down
right there moonlight right now
goes there so i think
if we were to do this
just like that and put a door on here it
should be a valid one
or valid house right
maybe let's make it just a tad bigger
just want to see if you'll run to it
or not that's all we're testing
okay i grant you a new house
my friend
might take a while
i think that's i think that's right
he's trying to escape
hmm okay well i'll watch him for a bit
and see if he goes in or not
ah they don't like my house it's not
good enough for them
it won't go in these guys man
so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna try to
expand it
just by one block
shoot and see if that makes a difference
move hey
you're gonna you're gonna affect the
results if you
start in the house i want to see if
you'll go to it
okay a little bit bigger now let's see
if they'll register that
yeah okay he's making a run for it
again dude
dude not cool
i can't believe he could get up here
oh oh yeah i guess it's pretty easy
dang i thought i had it sealed
um i hate to leave these guys i gotta go
get something though
hopefully they'll be okay
okay so we know this counts as a house
so we're gonna
try something else here we're gonna
remove the door um
this is where things get fun i hope
uh we're gonna have a pressure plate
here now
and
it's just a very crude test
actually no we can put one there put a
pressure plate
there that there
we're gonna put the dispenser here
okay and
there now if we put water in
do nothing until i wire it up of course
what am i thinking um
how do we want to do this
it'd probably work even if i inverted
this
only when they go off okay
okay it can't be inverted
just a second
he trapped himself he actually trapped
himself he can't get down
what a guy
let's help him out
there you go
okay let us make sure they can't get up
this time
we will do
[Music]
that and that
and take this up okay
oh he's trying he really wants out
i got another test set up for you let's
try this out
i want to see if he'll think this is a
house and if he will
he'll fall through so if he steps on
this
he'll make water come out and see if
he'll swim up
and then he should come back down just
want to see if he'll do that
um can you come over here
it's got to be within 16 blocks of the
door for him to see it
so one of you has to come over here
just a bit closer
oh oh oh oh you can do it
it's still night that's still night he
should go in
oh he
oh they're killing each other okay
i need a water flow
okay now it should work and it should be
safe
i think i got the dispenser on the side
so when they walk on it it'll pull them
to this wall and they should swim up
to the top here the whole point of this
is just to see if we can control them
and depending on how this works we might
build their houses using this
and make them swim up to a higher
platform or something
like that
i'm not sure if they'll go in it looks
like it's daytime
okay here they go finally and
up they go
oh no he doesn't know what to do
oh he did not like that
i think they can get down though oh
maybe not
yeah they can get down
he thinks he's inside
i bet you it's mobbing up and down
i bet you think i bet you he thinks he's
inside though
oh maybe not
yeah i i got to set up some breeding
here before i kill these guys
there he goes again
this is interesting
not sure exactly how i'd use it though
but if i ever need if i ever want them
to like go upwards on their own
somewhere
that's how i would do it like i could
make a water elevator to get them
however high i want
somewhere and they would just
they're looking at each other
[Music]
hmm
yeah they're really looking at each
other
uh let us control this a bit better
i want to do i want them to do that
thing again
we have a problem
there you go
[Music]
oh boy and he's watching him he's
concerned
all right enough goofing around
yeah so this snow theme i don't know
about it i think we have to change
because i i'm really out of my element
here i have no plans
no house designs in mind um
it looks really plain and bland and the
snow
is really white like too white i think
it
i think that's more like how the snow
should look but i don't
i don't have my brightness at that i
always have it at max just so people can
see better
in general um
but i don't i just will play around with
it for a bit
see if we can get it to work uh i know
someone suggested i should try to make
igloos for the guys
so let's do that with the ice windows
so that would be the entrance we have to
have the door still
an igloo with the door
the thing is i don't want the houses too
big
either
oh man it's just it's too plain it's too
plain
i don't know how to do it better
and i i was gonna try something with
wool but the thing is if i'm doing this
lava stuff
it's just going to burn up if i get
close to it
so yeah i think we need to change the
style
as much as i hate to say it or admit it
uh
let's i trapped them
they're trapped they can't get out um
maybe let's just see how this would look
if we switched it to
stone brick everything where we have the
snow
see if we can get the industrial theme
going
at least
i don't know guys this is just it feels
like everything i try looks weird
and bad i'd have to switch that with
iron bars for sure
the glass i just want to see what the
grass looks like and it's terrible
just terrible
oh that was weird it's breaking the
grass real quick with my fists there um
i think what i'm gonna do is just go
into creative mode and try a bunch of
things until i figure out the style i
actually
like because i'm just wasting time
messing with this
again if you guys have ideas let me know
i'm gonna have to wrap up this episode
though i didn't have much time to record
today
so didn't get much done
but i don't know just gotta figure out a
few things before we continue with this
project
so we can actually make some progress
and we are going to finish things up by
reading some comments
hey etho will you be incorporating
redstone into the village to keep with
the minecraft and technical idea for
the let's play that idea was what set
you apart but will
you be able to keep innovating as you
were able to when the game was younger
dr duck uh yeah the plan is to
incorporate redstone and and
interactive things somehow
like we kind of played around with today
now i know how to make
stalls where i can force the villagers
to do things
that's kind of what we were
experimenting with today and
i'm sure i'll come up with other ideas
i think that the ice theme is a bit
risky because there's only two specific
blocks for it
ice and snow yeah you'll have to use
them
with neutral blocks to make something
more interesting etho
yeah i don't i wasn't liking it too much
either it was pretty bland um
what actually happened is that i just
finished the ice tunnel on the minecraft
server and i was really excited because
i
i liked how that looked but on a large
scale i don't know if i can make it
make it cool so that's kind of the
reason i want to change
i still like the original block choice
for the village stone brick iron bars
lava like your minecraft
blaze farm nothing is the most epic
looking practical build i've yet seen in
a let's play
i just think having a little piston door
in the side of the man cave which opens
to a giant deep fiery pit full of your
etho minions is supremely more epic than
another snow build
either way i can't wait to see it keep
it up etho you are the greatest
thank you um
yeah i'm going to do some stuff in
creative mode and
and uh we'll continue this when i figure
out something i'm happy with because
i just i don't know the stuff we've done
so far it's like i put it down and then
i want to change it because i'm not
happy with it so
figure out something more more definite
for next time
but with that i'm going to say goodbye
thank you everybody and again
apologies for the quick episode um
hoping to get back into my routine soon
and i will see you again next time
thanks for watching
you