[Music]
behind the scenes
hello hello how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode of the let's play series
and
scene all right scene transition we're
gonna be moving crew over to set
location number two
scene name the donkey
get the donkey in frame next to let's
get him next to the crewmate okay
and do we want the frame on or off hot
on off um uh let's go head on that way
we can get right into the action that
way okay
three two one and
so check it out everybody i i got myself
a donkey the other day i was going
around exploring we finally have donkeys
back in our world amazing
and see
okay that was a little weak a little
weak could have done a little better on
that one
we'll keep it though
after editing hello hello how's it going
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode of the let's play
series so check it out everybody i i got
myself a donkey the other day i was
going around exploring we finally have
donkeys back in our world amazing
getting a little late guys we'll resume
filming tomorrow
take a break for now
all right let's get back to it yeah so
the other day i spent a bit of time
doing some stuff around our pumpkin farm
here and i checked the chest they were
totally full
of pumpkins down here
so i did some trading and guess what i
discovered
we have this like villager here that's
been here for forever
and apparently
he's a cheating villager i didn't know
that
so we can trade infinitely with this guy
without having to wait for him to refill
that's kind of nice right i like that
aha pretty cool pretty cool and the
other thing i found
i
i looked around here around the beacon
and apparently
there's like something weird going on
here there's a giant hole
right underneath the pumpkin farm if i
can find it
somewhere
yeah over here look at this
oh where did this come from
i dug it obviously okay everybody so
here's the plan you can see i got
ourselves a temporary drip stone farm
set up trying to grow some more of it
because we are going to be building a
lava farm today underneath the pumpkin
farm there
or larva or lava
or la hava
whatever however you want to say it okay
i say it my way you say it your way it's
all fine just like the rest of the world
uses celsius and some of you
use fahrenheit you know
i use fahrenheit and that's the only
right way to do things because that's
the way i do things yeah so in 1.17 a
new feature got added to the game where
you can actually farm lava out of thin
air basically you just need a lava
source a block drip stone under that
block and you can see it's dripping
lava particles into the cauldron after
about 20 minutes it'll fill up and
you've got yourself a brand new source
of lava which is pretty cool now the way
this works you cannot
in any way totally automate this like if
you
have a dispenser with empty buckets in
is this gonna it's gonna cook it
so the only way to harvest the lava
after it fills up here is to right click
it yourself so you can right click it
with a stack of buckets and boom it goes
in your inventory but if your inventory
is full
like i saw
then it just shoots out into the world
so whenever i'm designing something in
this game i like to have a clear goal in
mind for what i'm trying to achieve and
for the lava farm here my goal was to
try come up with the simplest like
repeating pattern
i could think of for making a lava farm
so i thought about it for a bit and
basically there's two approaches to this
number one you either move the lava to
you
or you move yourself to the lava if you
want to move the lava to you the only
way of doing it i think is with the
cauldron tape like this so
or something similar so basically
you
would move the cauldrons around
which one do we go next this one here
in a loop sort of thing and as they fill
up they get delivered to you
so you would stand in one spot and they
would get moved to you and you just hold
right click and they'll fill up your
inventory the problem with the piston
tape method is redstone is complicated
to to in a certain extent and piston
tapes kind of need a fixed size so if
you want to make like an infinitely
repeatable pattern
this really isn't a good approach so
instead
i figured out we got to make it so we
moved to the lava now there are a lot of
different ways of moving around in this
game though so we have to pick one like
are we going to be walking it getting
pushed around with water streams riding
a horse what are we doing here well i
figured we got to pick an automatic
method of moving
would be ideal and
it needs to be consistent and also
we need to set up a collection system
with this farm so i figured let's
combine
our collection system
with our movement system to try to
create an even simpler pattern
and we're gonna basically just do this
we're gonna have water
water needs to flow at least two blocks
so that it
has a flow to it all right
and then we're going to take advantage
of the fact you can now put rails under
water like this
and then
we will ride along here in a mine cart
our heads above water it's all fine
oh i'm actually getting pushed
wait a second
that was weird i thought i'd have
control here still
look the rails
i didn't know that
so if you put a minecart in flowing
water it has a preferred way of moving
weird anyways i'm getting distracted
yeah so basically
as we harvest the lava it's going to
shoot off into here go underneath the
slab here and then we'll just have our
next row of cauldrons
right over here so it's a three block
wide pattern so then our lava buckets
are going to go underneath the slabs
here under the cauldrons and land into
another water stream below that's going
to bring all the lava buckets over to
one end of our farm they'll get
collected together go into the shulker
loading system and we'll have shocker
boxes full of lava buckets waiting for
us when we're done harvesting here which
will be pretty cool now it's trying to
figure out how should we actually do
this water stream below because i kind
of don't want to put break points in our
farm like between the cauldrons i would
rather have
break points in our water stream here
because you can't like merge
two eight block water streams together
right you need a break point at some
point and if the lava bucket was to fall
down here
well you just lost it
so the way i usually would deal with
like having a continuous water stream is
you double layer it you have like
another layer over here that goes over
the dead points on the lower one
and then
if an item lands here
it will fall between the crack there no
problem guaranteed not to land on a dead
point
or if it was to land like
at this fence gate here it would go to
the one below as well so there's like no
point in the water stream where items
can get lost
i was just trying to think like is there
a better way of doing it and yes there
is
basically
i i tested this out it seems to work if
you have like uh
it's set up like this only a single
layer is needed actually oh
let's put that
we'll have the fence gate here
water goes over the pressure plates and
it seems like no matter where the item
lands as long as i think like if it fell
far enough down here i think it would
get stuck
but you see if it lands on the ice there
it still has some momentum it can
actually
carry its way through
oh i'm a bad thrower
oh it just barely makes it you see that
but i think maybe if it fell through
that water fast enough it would get
stuck but
as long as we don't drop the item too
far it seems to work like this no matter
where it lands aha so yeah it's been
announced guys officially the next
updates 1.18 is coming out november 30th
which is pretty cool i was thinking
about it today about this patch and uh
it's pretty crazy what they've done
honestly like you think about a lot of
older games
what happens what do they do well the
patches get simpler and simpler as time
goes on you know they might add a couple
new content things here and there a few
bug fixes
but rarely rarely do old games touch
like their core
game engine right
and what emoji do with this update it's
like oh you know what we're gonna
completely redo the terrain generation
we're going to completely redo our file
format probably some network code have
to be adjusted like all this nasty
main engine stuff that you don't want to
touch with a 10 foot pole mojang are
like nope we're going to update it we're
going to improve it people's computers
are getting better they can handle it
and uh it's pretty cool i like to see
that
uh as far as like what the update is
going to do to our world here i still am
not entirely sure i think they changed
the mob
uh spawning right so a lot of our mob
farms are kind of going to be affected
by that i think
and from what i've seen there's going to
be caves underneath my bedrock so like
64 blocks below our bedrock is gonna
have new caves and we'll probably go
down there and explore and you know
open up the underworld is is kind of the
plan at the moment
i love that sound it's so good
uh this stuff grows very slowly like
very very slowly we only need 288 of it
that's how many cauldrons we got set up
that's like over 10 shulkers full of
lava after a full harvest
but
uh it's been hours hours hours hours and
this stuff is taken
forever i just did a little test here
because i wanted to make sure we only
have one lava source at this block here
right above and then it spreads out the
ones it spreads to does not create lava
just where the lava source is this one
has filled up three times in a row none
of these have filled up so
we're gonna need to fill this all up
with lava the whole thing there's no
cheating oh yeah and with the mine cart
it seems like it'll prefer to go east
but if we nudge it the other way it will
just keep going that way as well so it
just uh keeps going the way it was going
right but i think this is gonna be too
slow so i should probably just use power
rails
all right so i got a little bit lucky on
this actually i think power rails would
have been too fast like every so often
we would miss picking up the lava
buckets as we passed by
but it seems if you combine power rails
with water it actually provides a bit of
resistance and this is like the perfect
speed
all right everybody so i've been hard at
work here working on this lava farm and
i'm very happy to say i think it's
totally finished now i just gotta go
show it off to you guys maybe explain a
few things and we'll go for a test run
of it as well
so to begin with we have this opening
here right and i thought this kind of
works we need some way of getting down
there and i'm in a mine cart so we just
have a minecart track at the top here we
hit the button and bam we'll get taken
down into the farm and then we end up on
the other side and then if we go down on
the other side we end up on the side
kind of thing we have empty buckets
there for picking up the lava when we
head down
and it's just like a little minecart
track tunnel thing nothing too fancy we
got mushroom walls but then
oh
baby we get into the heart of the
operation here
and honestly like i kind of like how
this looks i i built this underground
because i thought it was gonna look
really bad and i didn't want to see it
all the time on the surface right
but uh yeah it kind of turned out cool i
like it uh so we got six rows of 48
cauldrons each row
each one has lava over top each one has
one of these uh drip stone which took
forever to farm that was the very last
thing i did
and just finished it some of these are
still filling up
but uh yeah we got the minecart track in
we went for power rails
uh we got our collection system joining
all the rows together here and they end
up in the middle they go underneath to a
shulker loading system but uh yeah i
think we're ready to go here for a
little test run so let's do it this is
my absolute favorite part of building
something when you you spend all the
time building it up and it's like is it
gonna work is it gonna work and then you
go for the test run and oh
baby or else it's a oh i messed up
greatly on this thing
time to fix it uh no we'll see what
happens here i don't i don't see how
this could go wrong though so the idea
is we'll pick up some buckets fill up
our inventory and then
head down we face this way and just kind
of hold right click the whole way
through
and they'll shoot out of our inventory
the land and the water stream below
oh yeah and when it fills up uh or when
our
when we run out of empty buckets then we
got a switch too
so this now this farm could be totally
automated right i decided not to totally
automate it though
because i kind of like uh manual farms
to a certain extent
or i like the idea of having like tons
of lava here and we just go for a
harvest right
so it's quick to get it it's easy but
i'm still involved in the actual
collection process
i think that's kind of the dream
i don't really like the afk farm now we
got to double check that stuff isn't
landing where it shouldn't here
hopefully we're fine
oh that's a scary face oh and i i used
up all the buckets pretty much so
oh there was another roast oh my
goodness
okay so we need a lot of buckets
i thought i thought that would be more
than enough i didn't count it uh but
yeah they're filling up our shocker
loader here
um and they when it totally fills up oh
i guess that was all that had
there it goes it breaks it those go down
into here we got five
uh there yeah i said there would be
about 10 right so i guess there was a
bit more to go
um
but then the minecart goes back up
okay we might have a little bit of loss
with this and we'll see
but i don't think it'll be too bad oh
there is one here too one there okay so
there is a couple problems nothing major
though which which is fine i just want
to double check this as well make sure
there's nothing stuck on these pressure
plates
yeah i think this worked okay like we
were getting a bunch of lava buckets on
the very end here but i think if we put
glass over here we can still pass
underneath that but we won't throw uh
the buckets out
on the side here
how did i do that
oh i guess if i right click with the
full bucket when i'm in the glass
is that what happened then
happened again wait a second
is it a big deal i don't know i don't
know what's happening
as long as i'm not actually placing the
lava i think we're fine
again
all right let's double check
any lava buckets and you'll have buckets
i don't see any lava buckets very good
very good i think they all went down
oh boy okay decision time guys do we
keep the guard on the front of the farm
here or do we remove it it'll look
better without the guard i think but
it'll function better with it
i don't know i'll let you guys decide i
don't really care
i think it's fine either way uh okay
one little thing here i thought was
interesting so the whole time i was
building this we have a bit of a tragic
story here this enderman poor guy
he got caught stealing
i don't think i've ever seen this happen
before so what happened as far as i can
tell
you see how we got a brown mushroom down
there those grow randomly i think he
stole a brown mushroom you see it's in
his hand and then one grew where he was
standing
and he cannot place that down now he's
stuck
because there's one in the spot
again so he can't place that down which
means he can't despawn
and he for some reason he can't teleport
out of there either he hasn't tried to
so he's just like permanently stuck in
this hole all right good stuff so i
think we're done with that farm let's
move on and i think we're gonna head to
the end next yeah so i thought we would
go check out the shulker reactor again
today i know a lot of you guys really
like this farm and you wanted to see it
in full action so we got a few guys
stored on the sides here we're gonna
send them into the middle
and then we'll we'll see what it's like
when it's when it's crazy
i have been using this a fair bit
testing it out some more it does have a
couple problems
but i did i i was able to farm a few
stacks of shells from it so it like it's
working but it needs some tweaking is
kind of where we're at with it
and i'm having trouble flying today
apparently okay let's land so what i'm
gonna do i'm gonna send these guys into
the middle
just by washing them away
but i think what we really need to do
for this farm like to make it work well
is we need to rinse the sides every so
often and
and not just when we choose like set it
up on an actual timer
okay
so once the sides are covered in water
they can't teleport to the trap doors
anymore
so they teleport to the outside
and then the ring of water washes them
again and then they'll teleport inside
and then we remove the water on the
outside again and they can teleport back
over to the trap doors and we end up
with the situation where there's like a
hundred of them in the middle reactor
now
and things get pretty fun so i guess
let's go check her out
here we go
i love this farm
so yeah there's there's a few guys in
here at the moment
now unfortunately it's not gonna like
sustain this in in any way they're gonna
teleport out of here they're gonna kill
themselves they can't duplicate when
there's this many in the middle
um so they they gotta teleport out of
here first
but yeah it's pretty fun still
oh there's not that many over here i
guess this was kind of a dead spot
so what i found is if i run this farm
for a long long long time like hours
eventually everybody thins out in here
and they all end up on the outside walls
so i gotta do some tweaking with like uh
how much space they can teleport to
i think i'm gonna remove some of the
trapdoors on the outside there
and uh just go from there
and then if we set up that rinsing
system on the outside i think this farm
will work pretty well
uh-huh yeah so it's a little bit hard to
explain this is a complicated farm but
essentially our problem at the moment
is when they duplicate in the reactor
some of them will teleport to the
trapdoors and some of them will
duplicate within the reactor and keep
the reaction going the ones on the
outside are like extra storage they get
out of the way so that uh there's not
too many in the middle that it stops the
reaction from happening
but the issue at the moment is too many
of them are teleporting to the trap
doors and eventually there's not enough
in the middle they all kind of die out
and then the reaction stops
and
yeah then we have to send them all from
the outside back inside but if we just
get rid of the middle row here it will
probably help things out a lot and
though more will stay inside and fewer
will go to the trapdoors
all right found something out new here
that i didn't know uh i was removing the
middles on the trapdoors right and there
were a couple shulkers on the outside
still so i had to remove them with my
trident
and uh
i might have missed and my trident went
into the void and apparently even if it
has loyalty on it and it goes in the
void
uh it doesn't come back to you so i just
threw my trident
in the void okay i know this looks kind
of bad but just hear me out for a second
i have an idea
i want to try out um this hit me when i
was building the lava farm and basically
for a long time now i've needed to build
a villager system like a villager
trading system a good one too i don't
want just the junky one i want a really
good one kind of want it to be like
something unique as well
and i just haven't really been able to
figure out what to do until today
the idea hit me had a eureka moment okay
uh but it hinges on whether or not this
guy can restock his supply
the idea is
i'm gonna drown the guy pretty much he's
gonna be in water
right this is how i'm gonna keep my
villagers
the bubble columns will keep him alive
though he's not going to drown and like
whenever i do a trade with them
and the the inventory you know that's
the big problem with villager trading
the inventory
you
have stuff flying everywhere right you
got to pick stuff up you got to drop
stuff off i want the inventory to just
shoot into the water stream and go into
a collection system and and sort it for
me and this is a perfect way of doing it
if if they just stay in the water stream
right
because i can just funnel the water
stream wherever i want with the items
inside and it's going to be amazing now
can he actually restock we got this
thing next to him
uh i think he should be able to right
i'm just going to make sure let's do a
little bit of trading here with this guy
and we will find out
i want all the bricks he got buddy
okay
he can't he can't trade anymore let's
give him a bit of time
oh snappers all right i think it's gonna
work he was able to restock which is
great so yeah the idea is if he's in
water we can deliver all the items
wherever we want that way nice and easy
plus any xp he creates
will get shot through the system as well
cool all right well i think that's what
we're gonna go with then i'll have to do
a bit of fine tuning and you know it'll
take a bit to make it look good as well
but uh i think it's gonna work out i'll
try to get that figured out for the next
episode everybody but unfortunately for
today it is that time for the comment of
the day it says etho
do you know that there are different
variations of flight rockets you don't
have to use the level one ones craft a
rocket with three gun powder instead of
one
so this this is actually an interesting
thing that i don't know if a lot of
people have played around with so
i used to always use rocket threes like
forever it wasn't until hermitcraft
actually i noticed everybody used rocket
ones and then i started using them
because that's what people gave me or
what i could buy at the stores and i
found out i actually really prefer the
rocket ones
they don't last as long it's true that
it's like less value for the inventory
slot right but
a lot of times when you're doing stuff
you just need quick little bursts to get
somewhere right
it's not like you're traveling far all
the time
and i find rocket threes
you just spend most of time waiting for
the rocket to run out before you can
land right or else you're gonna conk
into the wall and die
uh so yeah i much prefer rocket ones
anyways thank you for watching guys i
hope you enjoyed this episode and i will
see you again in the next one take care
have a good day bye