[Music]
um
what a nice night this is wonderful
beautiful perfect night for some
[Music]
fishing ah
so much fun fishing
fishing oh no
oh nope
[Music]
blasting
oh what are we to do with you wilson
will soon i will feed you a nice steak
steak
[Music]
it works uh i haven't gone crazy
it's a backup i thought you guys knew
that
it's a backup don't worry
uh but seriously guys what are we going
to do with wilson
we got to get this guy done he's a
complicated guy that's for sure
uh so the plan i got now
what we're gonna do is
we're gonna get rid of the attention
meter
this one here and we're gonna just
basically merge that with happiness so
happiness will be like the attention
meter uh and we're going to move
hunger over to the right ear so there's
only going to be four stats from now on
because um i feel like happiness
and attention are very similar anyway
the way i i planned on doing them so we
may as well just get rid of one and
simplify things that way
okay so that'll be hunger
[Music]
where'd he go there it is this will be
hunger
we're going to replace i think most if
not all of the hopper
hopper hopper combos with dropper
dropper combos
we're going to move weight up to there
[Music]
ah let's try it again good thing it
didn't hit me all right
that'll be weights and we'll remove the
bottom here and maybe put something else
there instead
later wait
and instead of having like two really
important stats happiness
and health health is going to be the
main main important stat
with this setup so if we go back here
let's just see what we got to do
yes all these i'm going to change or at
least most of them
with a dropper dropper
okay so i just went through the wiring
now and i changed all the hopper hoppers
with
dropper droppers now it was pretty
boring so i decided to cut it from the
video
spare you guys one i took one for the
team
now we have all dropper droppers and it
looks a lot simpler back here because
it is a bit simpler these are easier to
use
i want to work on the health stat now
this one here with this you can see like
every time we send this dropper a pulse
one item will go from it into this one
seven eight then if we power this one
one item will go from here into this one
and that's how we can go between
you know adding and subtracting to the
stats
uh this health one we're going to do
like we were planning to do the
happiness one before
let's see what do we gotta do and the
idea with that is we were gonna use
these
three other variables to calculate how
much to add or subtract to that one
um and to do that
is going to be a little tough i'll be
honest
i thought i had some blocks maybe not
let's go over here first let's let's try
to work this out
i messed around with it a bit in
creative see how much i can
figure out based off of that um
gonna want this to go oh i wonder if
that's gonna power
that though oh no we will go like this
go over two three
four five uh we'll have to tear this out
i guess
we're gonna put the wire this way
all right and
um maybe we'll hop into my creative
world
and just see what i built before give
you a better idea of what we're doing
okay guys we have hopped over to a
creative world now
and i'm not gonna lie this is
i've i've strapped the recording over 10
times now i keep trying to explain this
and i keep failing over and over and
it's
frustrating this time though
we i've done something different this
time i actually completed this thing i
decided to just
finish it so i can actually show you it
working and maybe i'll be
able to explain it this time let's hope
uh we'll power through here um
basically what we got to do is figure
out the change to our health stat every
update right
and that's going to be our weight
variable plus our happiness variable
plus our hunger one equals the change to
our health one
and our health one is being represented
here by these two droppers
so either items are gonna flow from this
one into this one
if that is addition that would be
addition
uh items will flow from this one to this
one if it's subtraction so
if there's less items in this
fewer lights will be on like you can see
if i take these out
no lights are on anymore so
that's what we're doing here each of the
variables
has this possible change weights will be
either
minus two items uh in those
in those dropper combos or minus one or
zero happiness will be
will range from negative two negative
one zero
plus one plus two hunger the same
so the absolute minimum
or most you can subtract per update will
be
negative two negative two negative two
which is negative six
and the most you can add is zero plus
two plus two which would be
plus four so somewhere within that range
depending on the others
i'm failing i can feel it depending on
on the other variables it will determine
the change okay so we got to send out
different number of pulses to this
depending on
this the status of our other variables
and that's what this thing does here
this is
uh this i came up with this is what i
would call
a variable pulse extender depending on
how far this reaches like pretend this
is our hunger variable this thing here
depending on how far the power goes
it'll either go up to here
here here or here or here uh
every step further it goes the pulse on
this
wire here gets longer and longer because
these repeaters
there's more and more ticks to them
right and then that goes into
our comparator here we're using this
trick
where it loops back to itself and it
does a quick pulse
the longer we power this the more pulses
we get out of it right
so the more power the longer this is
powered the more pulses we get out of
this and this goes to
our edition so items will go
from there to there um
one of the cool or useful tricks i got
from you guys
is you told me i should just always
subtract
um and then do the addition afterwards
so that's what i'm doing here
every update i will subtract
6 from it but since we're only dealing
with one variable here
i'm only subtracting two so if i press
this
[Music]
this represents subtraction that's
addition so
we subtracted two and added two or in
other words no change
see there's there's 52 in there
[Music]
okay but depending on how far this
reaches
there's only 32 items in
you can see it only made it up to the
first light here
so it's subtracted to an added none so
this is going down by two every time
[Music]
and so on um
but if we make this go all the way to
the end one
now it added four subtracted suits
subtracted two so it's adding two every
time
uh please tell me you guys are following
me
uh we're about done here i think i think
you get the point
now it's at 50. so this is our how we're
adding and subtracting
to our health stats okay uh what was i
going to say so
at one light here there's no change at
this
at this level this one it adds one this
one adds two
so that's three this adds four and it's
guaranteed
minus two every update as well per stat
okay i'm gonna do it okay
it's gonna be really boring to watch me
so i think i'll just do it off camera
and i'll be right back
and there it is guys we got it in that
is
oh such a relief to get this figured out
this was the most complicated part of
the whole build by far
and now that we got this figured out
it's going to be smooth sailing because
i
i know how to do the rest of it so it's
good to get this out of the way
and we got one of these for each of the
variables this
this top one is for the happiness bottom
one is for the hunger
we got another one for weights
over here which we do a little
differently because i want a different
mechanic to it
um they're not fully done yet we still
have to
run some more wire we'll do it later
though
so
our clock for this whole thing our our
update
will send a pulse to these pistons
we can't do them at the same time we'll
have to have a delay between the two
but when they extend they will
make this stuff run goes to the pulsar
which both layers meet up here
then we got to run this to the addition
line on the health variable
over here
just start to set it up here i think
this one
this one yeah and that will
that will make the items flow from one
to the other
actually i think i got these reversed
now i look at it
because yeah if items are going from
here to here
this is getting shorter so yeah i did
that reversed we'll have to change
that yeah okay
um so we'll have to connect over to this
one
uh this was supposed to be the
subtraction thing but i'll have to
change this too if i got that wrong
this will make six items flow out
so if that's at 16
it sends six pulses and it goes down to
ten and then we add in that other stuff
and it all figures itself out
ah we're moving on that's it for wilson
for today that is
uh you can only do so much with wilson
every time it's
it's a lot to it so sorry wilson we'll
work on you another day
but we got oh voice crack but we got a
lot done
that's the main thing um let's do
some building for the rest of the
episode
something more relaxing uh you know what
i want to do actually let's go back down
now that we got stuff going on here like
we got wilson over there
we got the mushroom farm up over this
way which we haven't finished either
so many unfinished projects we'll get to
it
and we're i think i'm i want to add some
more stuff over here too
now that we got all these things going
on
we should maybe finish up this area a
bit better
um this was actually going to be the
first place i was going to work on when
i started this world and i just
left it like this and started working
over here first instead
but the plan since i want to
shape or keep the shape of the original
cave as much as i can i always felt
i should have a pool of water here that
we can walk around like go
go around like this and then get to the
other side or
have other paths that go from that
this will be like an intersection
basically
um let's get some wood
and some fences and stuff i think i got
some around
and we'll just try lay it out a bit
yeah we got some good fences
okay get a snack
sounds like it's raining out there
this will probably help up too okay and
we'll just try lay out a shape
for our walk wave if we want to keep
this
design with the grass and the wood on
the sides um
i think that would be good
come down
would be three blocks here so we could
start
maybe putting it over here already
let's try this out
and then we put fences on top of that
and then there'll be water down here
hopefully we'll do something fun with
that too not just a pool of water but
something cool
with it so if we come down the stairs
is that too sharp of a turn do you think
go left and then we'll walk around
i think it'll be okay
yeah that's that's quite a bit of space
it's actually three and a half blocks
pretty much because of the fences
then we'll go over here
it feels a little weird i'm not gonna
lie
to to change this area because it's been
this way ever since the beginning
and to change it almost feels wrong
how's this look
but you know it needs to be done
let me come up a little further first
i'm gonna go grab an axe
there he goes those guys are so loud
like you can hear him
and he's so far away still can hear him
that's gotta be more than 16 blocks
come on uh
yeah we got got our axe here fix this up
um let's see
we might uh
i guess we should make it curve a little
more
i don't think we want it to come all the
way up to here it'll look
weird if it's really like narrow and
pointy because i
i feel it should connect
here like right here and that's yeah
it's the same height even
so like we'll mirror it on this side and
the pool of water will be
in this in this section here
so this would come up to
maybe what is that one more
come up to there and then it goes in
three blocks like that then
two we just got to make it meet up
how would that be that's a that's a
decent size of water i guess
if if we put it down there uh then this
will go
to there and then probably like this
these chests these have been here since
the beginning
and this is like my original items too
so it's gonna be
weird moving stuff but i think in the
long run i'm going to like it more
for sure just feeling
nostalgic about it i guess that's the
main reason
i haven't touched this area because it's
been this way all all
along
but these chests really need to be moved
this is all my wool from my my spider
farms remember how much i used to use
those
got a double chest plus i think
i think we got another one around here
or half of one yeah
so much string this is my wooden slabs
these are the ones that don't burn
i made a bunch of them before the update
slime balls
oh man more wool
i wouldn't be surprised if i had another
stash somewhat too
also this is cobble and netherrack
though
gravel yeah so how would this be this
looks pretty good i would say
so we'll keep this three wide we'll have
to move this a bit
then we'll make it go out this way for
sure
and probably
maybe another path going this way
um this is this is actually
a path i used to go down a lot down here
this goes to this one to my original
slime farm
over this way
never come down here anymore whoa
but yeah uh since we used to come down
here though i feel we should make a path
for it
that's the way the cave was originally
going
where are we now up this way
no enderman that
this way right yeah
so i think we'll have another path that
goes down here and it'll go underneath
the river i guess
that'd be cool and that'll be our one of
our ways of getting down to that part of
the cave
and i want to have like a whirlpool
in in the water here that we can jump
down potentially
to get down quickly um
we'll have to have a way of getting out
of here then
i wonder if i could jump that
i could it wouldn't be easy though
anyway that's a start to something
this will have to go
all of the paths have to be at least
three blocks or more
take that out um
yeah so uh uhc is out guys and so far
the response seems to be very favorable
from everyone which is good to see
it's always hard deciding what format to
do but the
the the quest to kill the ender dragon
seems to be
okay with people usually we do like
a season where we try to kill everyone
right so
it's good to see enderdragon went well
that was what
uhc was originally about the first two
seasons
and it's kind of cool to go go back to
that
and have another enderdragon one
and it gives us a reason to have teams
it's nice working together in teams
for that kind of thing i think we should
have some stairs or something that go
down
at this point wooden stairs
let's get this back
let's make a few
all right so i guess we'll
do it like this maybe
yeah and then we'll go down and have a
five wide path down there too
that's pretty good that feels right this
will get
taken in one more block
anyway it's a start to something we'll
work on this more later or i will anyway
um that's probably about all the time we
got for today i think we'll
go read the comments and call it an end
okay guys we have two comments picked up
for today not just
one but two and our first one
actually you know what i haven't
explained how i picked these comments in
a very long time so maybe we'll do that
today
what i do is i go to my previous episode
and i look for any comments
that you know stand out to me that
um maybe somebody
said something about what we should do
with the builds like what direction we
should go with it or maybe a trick to it
or maybe they said
or ask the question that i think other
people like to hear the answer to
or you know even just saying something
nice or
a joke who knows something that made me
laugh i might bring it out in the next
episode
like we're doing today so the secret
psychological trick to all this or my
master plan with this whole comet deal
is i'm trying to get people to leave
nice well thought out comments you know
that have
some actual substance to them not just
like
people saying first or i was here before
you
or start arguing about something trivial
trivial not trivius um
i'm trying to encourage nicer comments
uh by doing this
because i do read the comments and i
enjoy getting
ones that have substance to them you
know so
uh i guess what i'm getting to hear is
if you want your comment featured in a
future episode like the next one make
sure you
you put some thought into it and say
something you know that would appeal to
me
that will catch my attention i guess um
anyway here we go
this is what we got for today first one
hey etho have you ever been thinking
about what you would do if you had not
started with youtube
uh you can tell i'm a little desperate
here this guy can't even spell
no i'm kidding i'm kidding i did a lot
of comments every episode i just saw
this one
um just asking because i want to know
so badly it's actually a
good question what would i be doing what
type of job would i be doing
um
[Music]
i don't mind doing physical work but i
don't mind doing like a desk job either
like that's what i'm doing now is
basically a desk job
um you know i'm pretty flexible
there are certain things i wouldn't want
to do like i would never want to become
a doctor or anything like that that's
just
such a stressful job and like
so much schooling that kind of thing
that doesn't appeal to me at all
uh i don't actually have any specific
training like i just
oh baby
he's dancing i only have a high school
education so
like i'm not trained for anything
specifically
i am pretty good with computers though
and before i even started this youtube
thing i was seriously considering
becoming
an indie game uh programmer and
developer
believe it or not i don't know how
successful i would have been if i
continue doing that
but who knows uh basically
uh microsoft had this program
uh called the xna framework where people
were able to create games and and get
them published on
xbox 360 through the indie games channel
and i was considering making it a game
for that like spending
you know three to six months developing
something and then trying to sell it
and see how it goes which
you know it sounds like you wouldn't do
too well with that
but people were posting their numbers
like how much
how much they were making profit for the
games they were making and how much
like time went into it and people were
making some decent money doing that
and who knows could have been
could have been my job if i wasn't doing
this like some people
two three months programming their game
were making
you know twenty thirty forty thousand
dollars depending
on how good their idea was and how well
they did at the job um
determined how how much he got paid for
it basically
some people made hundreds of thousand
dollars some people made nothing
so i could have released the game and it
would have just been a big flop who
knows
but that was one idea i had youtube took
over though
this is a much better job it's more
reliable
uh it's fun i get to play video games
for a living it's
actually kind of similar to what i was
thinking of doing um
but uh yeah there's a lot of work
involved with this too don't
don't get me wrong but it's a good job
ah second question etho
please update your world file
i got this quick this comment a lot last
episode people
really want a new download and don't
worry guys
it's gonna happen i am going to make a
download for this world after this
episode
and you can you can hopefully get it
and and try out my world here so
all that's all that asking and and
bugging me is finally going to pay off
because you're gonna get
the world download so
good for you guys
[Music]
and i hope you enjoy it um
okay here's the thing though mediafire
i tried i tried putting it up for
download
um they keep removing my download
i keep getting copyright infringements
and i actually saw what for
last time apparently some movie company
that made the hunger games or that owns
the rights to it
flagged my video or not my video my
download which doesn't make any sense
because it's not a video or
or music or images or anything that they
should be able to you know own a
copyright to
but i guess they're just fighting any
video they see
um so i'm not going to use mediafire
anymore i saw one called
uh i think speedy chair is what i'm
going to be using
and hopefully that works out okay
uh in fact my mediafire account got
or is uh locked down right now because
of that
i can't even log in anymore it's like
i've been banned
so hopefully this
the the speedy share one works out okay
anyway that's that's definitely the end
of this episode
thanks for your comments guys i hope you
enjoyed the episode and i will see you
again
next time bye
you