[Music]
get him guys
snowball boy whoa
I must have broke the minecart I don't
know where you went
is this seeing how many N termites I
could get the spawned these guys also
like the ender mites they look at them
they don't they don't they don't hurt
them they just like them they're like
their pets you see
well sometimes sometimes they attack
them not not too often though uh-huh
crazy mob all right here we go Oh
out of my way Joe so welcome everybody
this is etho how are you guys doing
today
and here it's my gel farm getting more
food because I lost all of mine
something very strange happened when I
logged into my world today I logged in
and I had nothing on me and I had no
idea why so I tried to remember what
happened and the best I can recall I
think I died last time I played in my
world and it was like you're mighty like
I wanted to go to bed or something so I
never went and recovered my gear but I
have no memory of like how I died or
where I died in my world here and I lost
all my stuff well it might be out there
somewhere I have no idea where I checked
the wither skeleton farm because I
thought maybe one of those guys jumped
me or something I don't know I couldn't
find anything there though so I had to
make new stuff and we got really good
stuff now we got boots of the traveler
protection for feather falling for we
have laser drill again this time it has
silk touch on efficiency 5 on breaking
three I've got the scoop spoon
efficiency 5 on breaking
so touch chittery sharpness five
unbreaking 3 knock back to fire aspect
to looting 3 I just had to do it because
it's possible even though I don't really
like knock back and fire aspect on a
sword and then we got treats those Chapa
efficiency 5 unbreaking 3 so touch 1
sharpness 5 crazy crazy crazy also
something cool here let's let's do let's
do this ok so before if you had if you
had a fire aspect and looting on a sword
and you tried to kill a cow it would
only give you one or the other would
either cook the steak or it would give
you more estate it wouldn't do both but
that has changed guys it has changed
your cow farms are now even more amazing
because we're at 52 steak you get either
1 2 3 4 killing these guys normally we
got we got 4 there I think that was 3 &
4 was that 3 and we're not getting too
lucky here let's try this a few more
times to I think I yeah just to oh I
think those 5 4 - oh there we go I think
that's a 5
I got 6 once that I tried this for 5
oh there we go that was a six so yeah
pretty cool that they combined now now
if you have a cow farm make sure you get
a fire aspect and a looting sword and
you can repair them no problem
anyway I got food again I had no backup
steak so I was I was eating watermelon
for a while here first thing I want to
do here is uh oh let me freak okay this
part of my cave is a little bit boring I
don't like it as much as other areas so
I'm planning to let's see where is the
river the river is up here right
and this just dead ends which I don't
really like either so my plan is that
area is right above here you see how
it's dripping water down I'm gonna make
a waterfall here and then I hollowed out
underneath the stairs right there so the
water will go under we'll have like a
river then I hollowed out this area too
before there was just a solid wall here
which looked pretty plain so we're gonna
have a river that runs through then have
like a little waterfall here and it will
end up by the fishing shack so I brought
some ice I'm gonna do that we'll see
what it looks like well it turned out
okay it's not perfect though like this
there's a few things budging me about it
mostly this waterfall but yeah we got a
waterfall here now and then it goes
under under the walkway and this is the
new River area the river is pretty
hidden which I I kind of liked actually
just through a bunch of random wheaten
and grass and stuff down here bushes
some hidden lighting the lighting is
very close there's a few spots I think
that can still spawn mobs so I'll have
to deal with those this water stream
here or waterfall turned out pretty good
I like this one uh-huh
but the thing is up over here oh yeah I
almost I might change this grass up with
Basel yet too because I don't feel
there's enough distinction between the
path and the side of it you know because
they're the same color and all that but
this I would have really liked to put
the waterfall back a little ways but
then I kind of realized this area
wouldn't look so good because
particularly like how the water feels
like it goes down to the left here and
if I was to bump this back like I'd have
to cut it like right there and I don't
think that would look as good when
you're coming down these stairs so will
this try that out for now and I might
make some adjustments while I was
working here I noticed another problem
yeah it turns out I should have expected
this but I didn't think of it the
minecart physics changes have broken a
lot of things such as this thing
sometimes sometimes it works because
they derail because it's flying by at
that time it works there we go it flew
off so yeah I don't know we're gonna
have to come up with a fix for this so
I'm gonna try a few things off camera
and off hopefully I'll come up with
something yep all right
I'm having trouble here this is very
weird by the way it's very weird place
the block down place power rail it's
getting power from somewhere unless it's
could be that block no it's not that
block I don't know guys this is very
strange and I can't connect our rails do
it it ignores them probably have to read
log yep that's what it was there was an
invisible rail here it all makes sense
now
scheme beet rollin man I thought I had
it
thought I had it boom beautiful do it
again
works perfect uh-huh guess what if I
change it to a hopper minecart it has
different physics now they used to well
I thought they were the same before at
least yeah there goes all right well it
seems to work now I ended up just kind
of getting fed up I tore everything else
redid it with regular rails and just
slowed it all down it doesn't need to be
quick so yeah it's fine like this
cool cool so I ended up doing the second
one here a little bit differently
because it's facing a different
direction the minecart was behaving
differently so there's no power rails in
the last two rows there I really have to
slow it down and even even then it's
still going pretty quick tip in there
and there is definitely a huge
difference between normal like empty
mine carts and hopper mine carts look at
this the empty minecart goes way way
slower and it's gonna get stuck on there
even it's that slow you know what I want
to try a check storage minecart to see
how they compare I'm guessing it'll
behave the same as a hopper mine carts
in terms of keeping its momentum but we
will see all right it's good to know
these things
and the crafting table it's like where
did I put that crafting table I just
looked at it I didn't place it oh no I
don't even need a crafting table what am
i doing I had the chest all right
yeah it's much quicker yeah same as
hopper minecart uh-huh
what about if I ride it I wonder if
that's gonna be the same this is a bad
idea I feels about the same as the
hopper minecart to you I guess it's just
empty carts oh no no it behaved
differently look we'd be derailed uh-huh
so it goes even quicker I'm pretty sure
that means it was quicker if the players
riding it compared to storage mine carts
and the hopper mine carts anyway so
we're gonna we're gonna get out of this
cave guys I'm sick of being in here so
dark so gloomy it's a little nicer up
here but I have an idea for a project a
nostalgic project a little out of the
ordinary it's not gonna be too efficient
but we're gonna be making a cactus farm
I don't have a tectus firm in my world
yet and one of the very first things I
ever built in Minecraft I don't know how
many of you know this but I made a giant
cactus farm and we're gonna replicate it
to some extent
in our world here so static for me this
is before my time with you guys though
so a lot of you most of you have never
seen this before even in my old world
old old world not my like first let's
play world even before that all right so
I was looking around for a spot for it
and I think we're just gonna build it in
the trees this way a little bit it'll be
off on its own I am very sad about one
thing though the like my favorite thing
about this cactus farm was the sounds it
made it was very very peaceful very
tranquil
because cactus would randomly fall down
into water every so often and it was it
was just a pleasure to be around and I'm
noticing ya items they don't make sounds
anymore whoo and they fall in water I
they removed that quite a while ago
actually now that I think of it because
it was causing like the splashing
sound so that kind of kind of stinks for
this purpose anyway but we'll still
build it it'll be cool so I think just
let's see I mark the spot somewhere and
we're gonna build out a brick -
originally I made it out of cobblestone
pretty much the whole thing we're gonna
Brittany's brick though it'll look a
little nicer
getrekt that knock back man
alright so yeah where is that spot I
lost it now here it is so I have posted
two videos of this a long time ago in my
channel so I was able to reference those
to figure out the dimensions and stuff
so I should be able to replicate it
pretty well how close how close is it to
the water here that's a little ways out
still that's good alright so what I can
tell we want a 15 check in my notes yeah
15 by 15 square so 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 7 plus
7 is 14 plus the 1 in the middle so
that's about what we want and we will go
down a layer oh no this is my bad one
let's use yeah so we'll do a square all
around then we're gonna do another
square up in the air 9 blocks up is what
it looked like it was and we'll take it
from there as in the middle of building
it and I have a problem now whenever I
join my world's my team crashes oh there
we go
all right we're good never mind so we're
in in the game again that was really
weird man it loaded weird when I started
it though you notice that how like when
I was joining my world all I could see
is this one chunk and then it would
freeze wait to zombies not always now
now I can't test it cuz it started
raining that little zombie didn't light
me on fire I'm wondering if it's just
them or if they don't always let you on
fire now yeah so my team was crashing
then I restarted the launcher though and
now it works so maybe that was what was
happening anyway so we got we got the
brick square going on here then I I'm
doing a second to square around that and
the cactus they fall in these gaps here
and they'll fall down to the bottom and
it's very inefficient very inefficient
because then I merge the cactus together
at the bottom layer here all to the
center point I could have made it so the
cactus all moved to the center but I
didn't do it that way when I made this
originally so we're not doing it this
time either there's a thing about like
efficiency in this game it's good to
make efficient firms and all that but it
does get to the point where everybody
makes the same exact farm and that gets
boring you to be honest
so some if inefficiency is actually good
in the creative side of this game I find
I don't know
so anyway I'm gonna lay down some more
brick here it looks like I'm gonna have
to get more it's taking a lot of brick
oops
alright guys so on the outside here
we're gonna put stairs all the way
around and then we need to put something
here to attach the water from falling
down
I used ladders before
I made it originally intact this would
always get stuck on them but I didn't
know you could use signs at that time
the block water as well
yeah a long long time ago a long long
time and then in the middle here Oh
where's my glass we're gonna do a glass
pyramid let's see let me put some of
this away and this episode guys I'm
gonna be doing something I've never done
before on my channel I'm a little
nervous to do it but I have 30 copies of
pixel piracy to give away to you guys so
we're gonna do a giveaway on this
episode and I'm worried I'm gonna do it
in a stupid way but don't worry there's
no like I'm not gonna force you to to
like my video or subscribe or anything
like that anybody can join in as long as
you got a YouTube account and I'm also
gonna check it make sure it's not just a
recent YouTube account like it's gotta
be at least a week old I think that way
someone can't just make a hundred
accounts and and try to join in a
hundred times to improve their chances
of winning but basically if you want to
join if you want a free copy of pixel
piracy at the end of your usual comments
that you leave me still leave me a
normal comment right but instead of
ending your comment with a period end it
with two exclamation marks that that
will be our secret code that way I know
you wanna copy a pixel piracy and then
I'm gonna randomly choose a bunch of
people that have ended their comment
with two exclamation marks and I'll
contact you on YouTube through a private
message and I probably won't be able to
like double check to make sure you you
got it all working so hopefully there's
no problems otherwise I could spend a
lot of time managing all this but a
little background information on it as
some of you may have seen I start a new
series on my channel called pixel piracy
and the creators of the game contacted
me after I released my first episode
they were
really excited about it apparently it
helped boost their sales quite a bit and
they're doing like a promotional thing
that currently as well where they're
trying to give away hundreds of copies
of their game and try bring more
attention to it it's a good game I
really like the game honestly so I don't
mind doing this for them
and they kind of showed their
appreciation to me by giving me 30
copies to give you guys so yeah it's
good it's good for everybody in my eyes
so if you want the game you don't have
the game already that's that's what
we're gonna do all right so hopefully
just try to think if I overlook
something there if there's gonna be
problems with anything like I'm not
careful with the way this do this with
the way I do this the comments might get
really spammy I don't want you to by the
way I don't want you to just leave a
comment with like two exclamation marks
in a comment looks like spam to me I'm
not gonna pick it I want like a normal
comment that you'd usually leave on an
episode for it to be considered okay
alright and I think that's about it so
I'm gonna work a little more on this and
then over top this pyramid you put one
water source block and it flows down all
over the place and then the cactus go
above here and hopefully it'll be
amazing oh yeah I thought of something
else guys before I forget I'm gonna be
given away the 30 steam teas the pixel
piracy probably within two days of this
episode going up so you shouldn't have
to wait too long so check your pms if
you entered okay alright
this thing I'm not sure how it's gonna
look when it's all done I put it in the
trees here for for a clever reason if it
looks really bad
we can try grow some tall trees in front
of it if it looks good we can cut some
of these down so we can see it uh-huh
well doesn't this look like
really like an alpha build though Oh dad
it's only alpha materials guys just
brick although people didn't really use
brick back then maybe I should have
built out of Kabul anyway so oops one of
the funnest parts parts of building this
originally is I put the water down
before I put the cactus down so if I
messed up one of these jumps I would
have to swim up this water there was no
ender pearls back then and it was it was
challenging this is back wasn't it ah I
was about to say this is back when I
wasn't very good at the game so I I
missed a lot of these jumps and I had to
keep swimming back up when I built this
good times good times then after you do
this you get to do the fun part with the
cactus is exactly how I did it
originally whoops
although this was back before health
regen so I had to keep going and getting
food to finish it this is really
bringing back memories oh man so hard to
do the jumps Oh cuz if you if you just
take the damage you can't jump Oh like
right there
oh no oh wait wait I didn't hop up here
Oh anyway I'll finish this up off camera
because it's gonna take a while
alright guys so it's done here this is
just that silly project I wanted to do
today it brings back good memories for
me I might change out the brick with
cobble actually I did the bottom part
with cobble and I liked it a lot more it
was originally made out of cobble and
I'm not sure the birch is really doing
it to be honest I thought it would make
it better but not so much
anyway so all the cactus fall down there
6040 at dis total the glass block cuts
them and they fall and they fall into
the water streams down here pretty cool
I originally made this but it wasn't
just the cactus firm it was also a mob
firm because I had grass in the middle
and you would usually get quite a few
passive mobs spawning in the middle here
and they would walk off the edge
sometimes the hostile mobs would walk
into it was Turnus down and it seems to
be doing it man it's still sketching
these guys pretty good so there's a
sewer system to it as well oh look we
got some arrows yes some bones oh wow
okay there's lots of guys down here I'm
not seeing a lot of cactus to be honest
not sure it's gonna work I'm gonna put a
hopper there just for now originally in
my original one this water stream
extended about 50 blocks and the cactus
would fall down into my storage room so
I thought that was pretty cool
let's head on up for a second though
yeah
cactus still fall on the walls like they
used to that's great before it used to
make like a sploosh sound constantly so
you'd be in here and be like spooch
spooch spooch all around you it was very
very nice and relaxing unfortunately
that doesn't happen now and this was the
first like technical project I did like
I actually used a pen and paper to plant
it because I didn't know how to merge
water streams back then
so I had to figure it out so the water
stream would run its full length
like yes like these the water stream
they meet up here and then there's a new
water stream here oh the water glitch oh
that was weird
and then they merge here new water
stream don't we got a carrot we might
need to put more glass blocks up there I
think
cactus must be landing on the glass
blocks let's go check real quick I
haven't seen a single cactus I think it
still works it should right there's no
class or no cactus on the glass box here
let me think we did see one on the wall
oh yeah there we go okay it's just kind
of slow it yes there is 64 cactus up
here though yeah a lot of people they
know my channel from the boat dispenser
thing that probably never would have
happened if it wasn't for this Gattis
farm because this is a project like I
figure it out the cactus trick on my own
and I thought it was amazing how you
could Auto harvest them and it's like
hey how'd you get out and I wanted to
share it with everybody cuz I thought it
was cool and and this farm would blow
people away if they saw it but that
never ended up happening until the boat
dispenser it's like you know what I
really got to do this YouTube thing
people would love to see this and yeah
so this was like the stepping stone to
it even though I didn't start YouTube to
show this the next big project I did I
was like you know what I'm just gonna do
it so yeah these mobs are actually kind
of a problem because they're picking up
my cactus come on guys get out of here
bunch on the walls and they're stealing
all my dentist uh-huh anyway so just a
fun little build for today oh man I see
a cactus uh-huh
we're gonna get at least one out of this
it's awesome I think the majority of
them they either fall on the wall out
here which I mean it's fine I don't
really care
or they they land on the other cactuses
up there when they when they break
because they they're not level the
tactus is it would work much better if
they were level but since it makes like
cone shape a lot of them get destroyed
it's all good though
it's not about efficiency with this I
don't use mini cactus period so we gotta
try something here too I think what's
missing yeah
moody let's what else should we do here
let's get rid of oh why is this off you
were to mipmapping
uh-huh let's get rid of I think I used
to play on fancy graphics still let's
give it a smooth lighting oh yeah I
don't think that's rendering like it
used to still it looked a lot different
before yeah I don't know oops what else
could it be though maybe it's too moody
no yeah it just doesn't look quite like
it used to
oh well I did build this before the
nether by the way this glowstone used to
be torches
and in a lot of my builds I would put
these these things like this that would
call my pot lights and I used to really
hate smooth stone like there wasn't a
lot of block choices in the past in
Minecraft everything was built out of
like glass cobblestone stone the slabs
would wood planks sand you know brick
and the wool and that was about it it
didn't have sandstone or anything like
that but I would always avoid using
smooth stone and to finish an area if I
built something underground like this I
would change all the blocks the cobble
and I thought it made it look amazing
yeah anyway so here is the comment for
today guys episode 3 3 3 a etho if there
was one huge change you could make in
your single-player Minecraft world what
would it be oh man so I've had I'm gonna
answer this in regards to this series
instead of the world specifically I had
this idea I'm still kinda tempted to do
it where I would somehow incorporate
command blocks into my let's play like
but still keep it survival
I would mostly use them for like set
block and a few other commands I
wouldn't use them too like you've give
me things or spawn mobs to make mob
systems or anything like that I think it
would be really amazing to have a
survival world with command blocks
because you could do a lot more stuff
and do a lot of cool things a lot of the
times like people will make these neat
things and show them on YouTube they'll
do it in a creative world and they don't
get used ever like it they show them but
there's no practical value to them
think of how amazing it would be
if you could like have a command block
that makes a tunnel appear right in
front of you were a 3d statue animate in
front of you or you know there's just
could have a lot of fun with it I think
uh-huh but obviously a lot of people
would not go for that idea they would
feel it wrecks a survival aspect to it
so I I've been scared to enter that that
path but maybe eventually we will see
anyway so that's it for today guys hope
you enjoyed today's episode and my silly
little project here don't forget about
the contest and thanks for watching
I'll see you in the next one bye bye
[Music]