hello everybody this is Ito welcome back
how you guys doing are you ready for
today's life lesson I have one for you
okay there is a fine line between
bravery and foolishness keep that in
mind
all right here we go here we go oh this
should be easy this is holding forward
right I'm not gonna fall I think we're
okay there's no lava here anyway all
right so here's what we're doing guys
last episode we went scouting for a
witch hut and it didn't really find one
because of the weird way my world is
generated even though they could spawn
in certain spots there was actually no
hut there so I left it up to you guys to
try find me one and you got and you guys
did very well you actually sent me
screenshots and all kinds of stuff the
the one closest to my place had a giant
mountain in the picture I saw though so
we're gonna skip that one because we got
to clear all the land and set up a
perimeter I saw a picture of this one
over here we're gonna go check it out
and look around a bit I didn't see any
mountains we'll have to just do a little
bit of scouting ideally we want nothing
but water around the witch hut so we
don't have to clear clear very much land
and we can set up a witch farm really
quickly that way
that was a long load I'm guessing I've
never been here then whoa
void worlds okay strange things are
happening what no you don't do it like
this
oh man it No
are you kidding me okay we got to go
back we have to go back to the island
um when I went through the portal my end
reporter activated I guess it does that
sometimes I didn't think it would work
over that far of a distance though that
is very bad over there we do not want
that oh man okay well let's do some
measurements and just see how bad this
actually is
I got TNT like we can blow up a little
bit of mountain but not like all that I
don't think all right let's get inside
here so we have to clear land at 128
blocks away from this witch hut so if
this is three 588 roughly we need 128
blocks this way
so like 3700 and it looks like it goes
up to oh it's actually pretty close I
don't know though don't know although it
I don't necessarily have to like afk
right at the center of the witch hut
right I can afk a little bit that way
and that way yeah that's that's true
okay so this might work if we stay far
enough away from this mountain it looks
like we would have to blow up that
mountain over there though
to clear the land and this is all nice
and flat I can easily do this with a
shovel over here so let's just look a
little bit further this way it's
actually quite a bit of water here this
might be not too bad
yeah I think this could work out I'm
gonna set up some pillars and we'll just
kind of get an idea of where we got a
dig from if we were to to do it to make
the farm here this this would be our
biggest obstacle all right so I'll check
it out guys I got the pillars up in the
four corners so this would be one of the
corners here I don't know if you can see
it it's pretty far away but right over
there is one of the pillars the other
corner and there's one right over there
again it's pretty far away it looks like
we got pretty lucky with his spawn
actually like there's a lot of water
here and where there is land it's only
about two or three blocks thick for the
most parts this is the big thing though
here this is Mountain but I'm pretty
sure I think just get away with torching
it up right I think that would be the
way to do it I don't even have to clear
it you can't do that really in the swamp
because you'll still get slime spawning
that's the whole goal is to get rid of
possible places for mobs to spawn and in
the swamp slime spawn regardless of the
light level so I think we could only do
that on the hill here
and oh there it is there's another
pillar there so yeah it's not too bad
this is the other biggest section of
land here but we could take care of this
with a shovel
I think yeah oh oh no oh I have my
render distance cranked up right now so
that's why everything so slow but yeah
we basically got to clear all this and
it is about
maybe three or four blocks thick in some
places at the worst that's not too bad
at all ah all right we got to have some
fun with clearing land here guys we're
not gonna do too much on this today but
I just wanted to like get going here so
you might notice I cleared a bit of land
already five minutes
seriously five minutes I did legal one
pass on this we got one more pass to do
and that's that's basically it and we're
almost at the the pillar there you see
it's over there so this is not gonna
take very long at all we got to do some
TNT stuff though this has to be fun
right we can't we cannot clearly did not
blow something up that's one of my rules
I don't know if it's really gonna speed
things up too much but it'll help I'm
sure oh did you see that pig flying you
like a caught on fire and everything
awesome all right we don't want to go
too deep though let's see we gotta get
down to why 62 how deep this blow up why
62 okay that's not too bad we can
actually like even do a little bit more
TNT if we wanted oh I think I heard it I
think I heard it there goes big you know
oh yeah
all right so I think we'll get out of
here for today we did a fair bit already
basically all that you see see where the
land is and the ocean gets deeper so we
cleared all that have a little bit more
left to do here and then just little
pieces of land throughout the place and
then just torch up the big hill so maybe
in maybe two hours I would guess for the
land and about five or six hours at
least for the caving that's gonna take
the longest because we got to light up
all the caves around this area to
prevent the mobs from spawning but yeah
shouldn't be too bad actually
so I tell you what everyone we need to
bounce things out now we've done a lot
of destruction today I love the
destruction it's a lot of fun we cleared
all that land but now we need to do some
construction we got to build something
got to restore the balance you know yes
so for a long time I've wanted to put a
fence next to this path if some of you
have even commented about it like why
doesn't Ito put a fence or some lights
or something next to that path it's so
plain so we're doing it we're doing it
right now you're watching it it's
happening right before your eyes and
it's amazing yeah so I don't know what
it is lately I've really enjoyed
building more and more in this game like
I've been trying to get better at it
trying ever so hard and hopefully it's
kind of paying off I don't know if my
building has improved I'll leave it up
to you guys to judge but what I've been
doing basically for particularly in the
last year I whenever I like look on
reddit or if I see screenshots of
something people have built I analyze
whether or not I like it try to
determine what I like about it and then
I try to remember the trick her the
pattern or the block choices or whatever
I liked about it and use it in the
future and after doing that for a while
I think it's paying off I'm starting to
come up with a couple tricks here
especially lately what I've done is I've
downloaded
all these cool epic city maps people are
making and because generally speaking I
don't actually see a lot of other builds
in this game beyond my own like I don't
play on servers really like public
servers you know they usually have an a
really good build team that has made
something cool I don't get to see that
kind of stuff beyond what I see in other
people's videos so downloading Maps
lately is really giving me ideas and I
want to try it out so one thing I saw
was this cobblestone fence basically
what they did it sort of looks like a
pile of rubble if I can limit it anyway
they just mixed in cobblestone blocks
stairs slabs fences and then put leaves
over top of it and I just loved how it
looks oh I want to try it out here and
see if it if I can do a decent job on it
so I'll be right back then we'll see if
it's any good or not okay everybody so
there we go that is the fence I got it
complete here what do you think of it do
you like it you love it it's the
greatest thing you've ever seen yes okay
I'm glad we decided that it actually
turned out pretty close to the one I saw
I'll give you my impressions of it now
that I've seen it though I think it
looks pretty decent I think it's better
than light if I just did a wood fence
like something like I did at the farm
over there like that's pretty plain
pretty boring so I do like it my only
concern is at the moment there's not
really a lot of no there's not really a
lot of random stuff around here so it
might look a little out of place you
know things look better in context and
right now it's kind of out of context I
think uh-huh those Endor borders by the
way I think the thing that's triggering
them is when my game starts lighting so
right now I'm recording it seems to
happen a lot more often when I'm
recording where the
randomly do that and before when we went
through that portal you know my game was
lighting like crazy so you might want to
hold off building is I don't know we'll
have to try work that out it's like the
ender pearl doesn't calculate properly
once the game slows down or something
anyway let's head over to the Nexus I've
done quite a bit of work here again guys
nothing too exciting right now
nothing too exciting but I wanted to
show you where we're at anyway we're
actually very very very very very very
very close to done so that it's gonna be
functioning here uh so we had to run the
wires basically and you can see it goes
quite a ways down now we have to go
deeper it's not quite done yet
in total there's gonna be eight of these
wires on both levels so the bottom and
the top level and we gotta join them all
together and it's gonna be crazy
and then there's a ninth wire here as
well so basically eight of the wires
control the the bits these Pistons it
switches them either to the left or the
right and then the final one will be to
send the signal to the droppers that
hold the items so depending where the
bits are determines which dropper it
reaches now to actually finish a wiring
in the Nexus this is what I have to do
we have to take the eight wires we're
gonna build at the bottom that's the
easy part of this because we can always
just go deeper if we need more space for
the wiring down below there's going to
be eight of them down below but we also
need eight of them at this top level
connecting the top together here these
are the loose wires over here and
there's gonna be like a green wire at
the top we got to connect that to the
green wire down below yellow one from
the top to the bottom orange red and so
forth all eight of them plus the ninth
power wire all has to be hooked together
and then we take those eight wires and
connect them to the hexadecimal decoder
we built over here last episode and we
are done easy-peasy not quite so so easy
there's a lot of work to it the thing
that's gonna give me trouble here though
is if we just run a wire across like we
did down below
look at this it's gonna cut right in
front of this room here where the
building is so we're gonna have to build
it up above the Nexus here up above the
world so high like a diamond in the sky
and then connect them together probably
on the sides of the wires or something
anyway we're getting very close so it's
gonna be pretty cool once it's all done
here all right so I think we'll just do
a couple random things to finish off
this episode guys oh well oh no this is
not what I wanted to do live live what
can I feed them I got nothing I can feed
them stop burning stop it either pumpkin
don't there goes my right start it and
I'm trapped down here yes we're gonna
head over to the gold farm we built here
guys I want to double check if it works
or not in 1.84 and all the iron golems
eventually did die in it so I have to
replace those and just kind of reboot it
here so the wither farm is not too far
be a lot closer if I could if I had a
ride here yeah it's just up here it's
not too far
all right oh I would have liked these
that would have come in handy a couple
seconds ago got all the fire resistant
potions in the world here darn it okay
so the old gold farm or the second one
we built is up here
see see didn't know who up at the wither
farm up up these beacons there's a
ladder and then we just go up here some
of you might not have even seen this
farm before it's been so long since I
was here last there's a couple of iron
going left okay what do we got in these
Ches Oh oh-ho-ho I will take these power
rails that's actually what I want most
of all here the reason we're doing this
is because my gold reserve is gone and I
need it for power rails all right here
so we have 1 2 iron golems left I'm very
scared to go inside there did I bring my
boat I did and I have arrows okay
that was a good shot there we go
it's safe so yeah it looks like it's
still working they're tilling the zombie
pigmen it's great are they not fighting
back now oh look at this I think they're
not fighting back anymore or was it the
regular zombies that were killing them
now I think it was these guys too they
were they were killed in iron golems and
they're not any more awesome okay that
means this is gonna work just like it
did originally so let's go ahead and
maybe add a torso iron golems in here 10
seems to be about the sweet spot so the
way this works we go up the ladder here
an afk and I'm probably gonna leave my
game running over nights to get a bunch
of gold stored up here let's just make
sure it's going okay so the zombie
pigmen spawn and then iron golems is
Rackham and they are not fighting back
anymore which is really really cool
that's the reason I stopped using this
is because it kind of got broken in the
1.8 Prix
release that I was using very cool all
right and then there's a hopper minecart
running blow the whole firm that picks
up the items we and they get deposited
on here and it actually produces quite a
few gas to your stews that we can use
for potions wait a minute wait a minute
no no no no the items don't get dropped
off here they get picked up here one of
each into the hopper minecart so that
all the slots don't get filled up with
gold swords and stuff the actual items
go down here oh and there's stuff here
not too much but there's a little bit I
will raid this lots of gas dears Oh
actually there's a decent amount of
stuff here I want it all alright well
that worked out perfect not only there's
a firm work again but we got enough gold
laying around there to finish up our
track to the desert so I want to try
something I pre placed all the levers if
I can machine gun and click my mouse
button quick enough we can place the
track while we ride here I don't know if
I can do it quick enough though let's
try it out alright
terrible absolutely terrible not even
close
darn it that would have been so cool no
it's it's really tough you got to be so
fast oh man we're going the wrong way
start it I'll just do it the
old-fashioned way I suppose so we're
gonna finish up our episode here with
one more random project we're building a
beacon in the end for mining n stone a
little bit quicker and while we do this
let's go over the comment of the day I'm
not gonna have enough blocks M I know
alright the comment of the day this is
something that has been suggested
several times before and I finally
decided to do it says ESO I think you
should make a list of the unfinished
projects so that when you are done with
the Nexus or other projects you can see
what is the next project all right now
first of all to respond to that I have a
weird way of playing this game
I have a very tough time just focusing
on one thing I get bored if I do that I
like to just do what I want to do for
that day and I don't know if that's
really great for you guys but man I sure
enjoy it way more that way so yes
there's lots of unfinished projects but
we are not gonna mount one by one as
well anyway enough with the defense let
me get to it here this is the list
number one the library and Wilson it's
number two those are two very very big
projects and after the Nexus is done I
think we'll focus on those a bit more or
at least functioning once it's
functioning we'll take a little break
from it and probably start on one of
those other big projects we also have oh
sandy city we got to build the walls
more buildings and finish up that
pyramid that's kind of a fun little
building project whenever I feel like
you know building something instead of
doing like redstone that's a great one
to do we got the minecart store
system at the amplified base I got the
concept all working in that for working
for that but we never actually hooked up
the tracks yet so I got to do that lots
of these projects are long grindy things
I have to do off camera which is why
they kind of got left where they are by
the way number five is the minecart
sheep farm at the amplified bass we
started that and I do plan on finishing
it I just kind of forgot about it and
he's to going see how quick this
actually is with his - all right next
one is the arena at the man cave there
we kind of got sidetracked with the
Nexus and I sort of want to try finish
the Nexus while I'm in the groove here
with its ceiling pattern in the tree
farm so at the donator tree farm really
isn't much faster is it darn it at the
donator tree farm I started putting a
pattern in the ceiling a long time ago
but I never actually finished it because
it was gonna take a couple hours but I
would like to do that eventually
silverfish farm and bomb factory at this
second base I don't know this stronghold
base never actually got finished because
I was having trouble with the mob hey I
and a few other things but we can
probably return to that as well
fire work room at the manty we talked
about that just needs a skin tunnel to
the desert we're working on that right
now by clicking and stone and we just
lead the track to its portal network in
the nether is a bit complicated and yeah
I'll try to fix that fix that up we got
to like get rid of all these straight
portals we've been building and handled
them properly to do that underground
village
maybe I'll just read through these
because could take a little while
underground village in the man cave we
got the Nexus project Pokemon we could
pretty much finish quickly if we just
moved a bunch of villagers that's all
set up we just
have to move the villagers from the
underground village to project Pokemon
get the ore storage room in the man cave
which we never look at because it's a
mess the Simon game skeleton spawner in
the man cave we have the gold farm
musical portal in the end here dual
blades farm it's like all working but
never really pretty DUP that place the
nether hub design we have to settle on
on what we're doing there with the ice
and all that stuff the horse jump
project is like a long ongoing one and
finally the guardian farm and there's
probably a lot more that I just didn't
think of but there we go guys we have a
list so I'm gonna do my best guys I'll
try to finish up the some of these
unfinished projects as we go on here try
knock them out one by one we do we do
get stuff done though come on I know you
guys give me a hard time about this but
we finish a lot of stuff to that list is
probably longer than the unfinished
projects list if I was to guess I hope
and we will probably continue to start
new projects every so often that's why
we started the which firm today not just
because it's good for me it's good for
you guys I feel otherwise the episodes
will probably get very repetitive and
boring if we are always doing long rindy
projects like mining in stone here but
anyways hope you guys enjoyed the
episode if you have any thoughts or
ideas on anything I've said if I forgot
some of the projects on the list feel
free to let me know in the comments and
I hope you have yourselves a wonderful
day I'll see you in the next one take
care my life
you