[Music]
really well this got a whole lot more
interesting now I guess we're playing an
ultra hardcore now guys it's the thing I
got hit by some spiders here and my
health doesn't regenerate anymore
I'm guessing it's another glitch I'm on
it I'm on the latest snapshot again 32a
this one I'm allowed to dig straight up
that's fine but I might not be able to
heal anymore oh it's going down it's
going down oh I think my hunger was
glitched out like it showed it was full
but I don't think it actually was and
then my hearts weren't going up because
of it okay we're all good everything's
fine
let's see do I have enough torches maybe
two more okay so I've been doing a bunch
of caving under under the ocean here and
I am getting my butt kicked I've
actually died twice almost lost my stuff
both times but just barely got back to
it here I'll show you what you got a
face under the ocean give you an idea
what it's like because there's no where
there's hardly any caves right so they
all spawn and there's a little bit of
area available here and it's it's just
nuts I'll try light this up let's just
run in like a crazy man
okay we got lucky here there's not that
many creepers but I would keep running
into situations which is like seven
creepers just come out of nowhere and
eventually we get one of them gets me
but like these guys even just eaten
you're fine it's the creepers creepers
are the bad ones alright everybody well
I'll show you kind of my issue right now
I did a thing I knew it was kind of a
bad idea to do it but I wanted to see
the results I lit up the caves or a lot
of the caves not all of them I just
wanted to see what lighting them up a
bit would do how it would affect the the
mob spawning and all that if there was
like a hard limit to how many would
spawn things like that I was curious
yeah things are fun around here now so
my issue at the moment is I can kill
these guys and basically at the speed I
kill them there's more and they distract
me from miles away so I kind of kicked
out of this area right now this is so
many of them because all the caves are
lit up so now they're spawning in the
water right oh we gotta tried to do okay
I've been killing lots of Trident dudes
probably about like ten of them at least
since last episode still haven't got any
more tried in so that one we got the
very first one was pretty lucky I think
okay no no that's the second one I
killed yes two in a row no that was
probably my my twelfth or so now oh you
guys got a second one though that's cool
but yeah I got to think about what I'm
gonna do with these guys cuz they're
kind of an issue now making life
difficult but yeah I got the first
Trident we found they'll all fixed up
here so I put mending on it I got
impaling
four and Riptide three right now I
thought these would work a little bit
better under the water to be honest
because the big problem is if you're
underwater and you're swimming you can't
you can't use your rockets until you
activate the light wings which you can't
do underwater you have to go to the
surface to do that and then like then if
you fly under the water then you can use
it right I was kind of hoping that the
Riptide would make it a little easier to
swim but you only move like I should
check but it's not like five or ten
blocks or something which is not super
great it is really good above the water
though it's incredible because then you
can activate your wings with it and
basically fly without using rockets
right or can not throw it again so guy
going out often oh I don't know how to
use it oh it's gonna be it's gonna be
raining that's why yeah you only use it
above above water if you're in the rain
but look at that that's like one shot
and no wings right there it's pretty
crazy
uh-huh lots of fun though lots of fun if
you you can use this for attacking them
too I think you do like does it hurt you
oh it hurts you when you hit I think it
does damage someone you Rockets through
looks like I only hit some one of them
maybe let's let's go in this mode yeah
it only hits one so it's not like yeah
it's not like you're going bowling or
anything and knocking them all down so
it's not super effective against the big
pack so I guess they always drop them
out of the shell because it's in their
offhand it's a guaranteed drop alright
so that puts us up to seven now I think
let's let's go double-check I'll show
you guys what I got from caving here -
yeah we're up to seven so we just need
one more for the condo
it's but we got lots of iron lots of
redstone horse armor named him all kinds
of goodies from caving in the area here
which is cool
I thought next up here we would try do
some building if we can but we might
need to send up a dark room or something
it's let these guys stop spawning
because I'm having issues getting a
moment's peace here yeah so I'm trying
to think what blocks who want to use
here like what's what we should build
our base out of and I think we'll use a
lot of prismarine prisoner een and like
clay blocks maybe the stripped stripped
wood I think most of these are gonna
look really good with prison marine
because that's that's pretty nice like
blue and orange like that's very nice as
well I think birch very good I like that
too dark oak yeah do I got spruce on me
oh I do
yeah like all these colors are good with
prismarine right so I'm liking that a
lot as far as the base build I'm
thinking let's go for like lost city of
Atlantis underwater maybe not a city but
like underwater base kind of thing maybe
in rune would look cool so I just want
to play around with it a bit cuz we got
we make stairs and stuff out of prison
now which is really cool
I think that's gonna be our main
material because of that and I just want
to like to try put together a wall here
it'll look like nothing too fancy just
want to experiment so we can do
something like that and then put a
border on it maybe like a strip of bark
that what is called strip toke hey you
go away try and do things here yeah
let's let's put this up on the sides and
then we'll just see being decorated
enough that it'll look good
oh and we're ups okay so that's like
what a big big flat wall looks like tada
if we put this down at the bottom as a
border the baseboards that's not a board
no we might need to take a pause here I
had a nice like one minute window
there's cool okay let's get some
lighting on this too because it's hard
to see so if we were to try make this
look like a window maybe like a
diamond-shaped window let's let's do
that
throw some stairs in here all right one
more sometimes they like get close to
you and they don't actually hurt you
just like stay there and freak you out
like this guy no he found me okay you
get out of here
so you can do stuff like that and then
maybe put glass behind that to see what
colors do you have oh we got all the
colors ready to go let's try yellow or
orange would be pretty good too probably
oops
strafe right strafe right you'll never
hit me I know the secrets you know hit
me I can avoid getting hit until I get
close to them then it's like nope it's
gonna take it okay yeah it's kind of
cool right probably want to add a little
more detail to its like maybe bring this
out one more throw in some stairs there
or something
I'm gonna ignore you guys do we have
stairs out we don't have oak stairs no I
love this autocompletes
make situations like that very nice all
right
maybe stairs yeah yeah I think I think
you get the story there's no color
though I didn't put any clay in there
hmm you got another one all right so
check it out I did add a little bit more
onto the top of this thing and
experimented with decorating it's it's
actually pretty easy if you just spam
coral coral and the seagrass and there's
Shelton
we got a few options for decorating
right and I think that looks pretty
decent
it's colorful you know it serves its
purpose it's a wall and threw in some
sea lanterns up here with trap doors in
front I think that looks cool two
different colors is stripped bark in
there I don't know about this top thing
this looks a little silly I think but
the rest of it I'm pretty happy with so
I think we can do that as our as our
block pellet or building themed rights
little workouts but enough is enough
guys I got to do something about the
whole breathing situation and the
zombies and stuff they're driving me
nuts here so in this time I did get some
more novelist shells we got 12 now so
I'm gonna go ahead and make our very
first conduit here ah-yi all right let's
try ignore them
if we can head back over here so the way
we set this up I think you need like a
3x3 area of water with this in the
middle right and then all around that
you just put prismarine in different
blocks right to finish it extend the
range of its which we use the fans and
stuff I'm gonna use the fancy stuff guys
might find it
okay so yeah then on the outside like
the five five by five area around it
that's where the frame goes and you need
like forty two blocks of the frame this
is not distracting at all oh man like if
I clear them out it's fine for a minute
or so but it's such a bad thing
so we need a darkroom yeah I tried
putting a villager underwater by the way
hoping that they would go after it and
they do go after the villager but if I'm
in the water as well they will switch
targets from the villager to me like
they prefer me over the villager which
I'm it caught me by surprise I thought
like if they targeted the villager first
they would stick to it but no I'm pretty
tasty apparently okay this is our moment
guys we might have a minute's peace here
I do want those Nautilus shells though
but one more nautilus shell they're good
yeah cleared out a bunch of these guys I
move the conduit as well I didn't like
where I put it there so I moved it
behind the window check this out ooh
alright so that is the conduits power it
gives us night vision and water
breathing you see where at one bubble
it's not going away pretty cool so every
seven blocks you add to this increases
its range by 16 blocks and it goes up to
ninety six blocks range if you have 42
blocks in the frame so what would this
be five by five by six 16
26 up to 30 blocks right now so we need
to add 12 more in order to max it out so
I guess that's why they do this shape
right it's kind of the dream shape and
when it's fully maxed out it'll actually
damage mobs nearby update blocks away
should start happening yeah taking
damage pretty cool does two hearts
damage every damage tick I did get
another trident by the way see if we get
another one no not another one okay I
don't know what I'm gonna do with them
all
okay so if we hang out in here is it
only damage one at a time it looks like
it
this is focusing on that guy and out
switch to him okay and do we get like
experience or anything no it's just the
basic mob drops okay you know I don't
know if I actually like the night vision
from it but I do like the water
breathing I think this look better when
it was darker right we could switch over
to like moody lighting - it's another
option ooh that looks weird it's like
really yellow yeah I want to see what
happens here I sent a few of them
through the portal like I'm guessing
they don't do too very well in the
nether right we get swarms
I don't do very well another
either looks like they just walk around
like normal zombies
yeah they got no water to go to so they
don't care they just act normal okay
yeah all right everybody so I just had
to stop by the man cave here for a bit
to get some more food and stuff figured
may as well enchant some of these
tridents we got so I got four total now
three of them got nothing on them so may
as well try and chant them rights I saw
the next one here is loyalty three which
is really good little two three I'm
breaking three oh yeah you don't even
put on breaking on rights peeling for
channeling Oh looks pretty good all
right so next thunderstorm we gotta try
this out impaling lets you do extra
damage to like aqua mobs like guardians
loyalty is when you throw it it returns
to you automatically and channeling is
the really fun one that's when you throw
it a lightning bolts hits wherever it
lands so you can throw it at a creeper
and get a charged creeper we're at a
villager and get a witch or a pig and
get a zombie pigman so that's gonna be a
lot of fun I think Oh
throwaway joke throw a trident at
something no throwing away your only
weapon is not a good idea I comes right
back though because I got loyalty on it
oh snap
so the channeling only works during
lightning storms by the way so we're
gonna have to wait for that Oh another
one
uh-huh well you know it was fun for a
while having these guys around and we
got lots of Trident sand Nautilus shells
from it but honestly it's getting pretty
annoying now so I got a beacon set up
right so we can dig fast and stuff I
want to think we should set up a mob
system a dark room at the very least
where the mobs can spawn and they'll
they'll stop spawning in the water and
annoying us rights we want to trap them
I wanted to maybe see if we can make an
old-school mob system with the water
elevators last one I made like that I
think was like on the minecraft server
in the ethos lab and thinking about it
here I have to go into creative a bit to
play around with it it's actually really
difficult to do one like that now
because zombies and skeletons they don't
float in water anymore so how are you
gonna send them up a water elevator
rights you got to use the bubble streams
but the problem with the bubble streams
is you have to have it all source water
blocks in order you get the bubbles you
see like these don't have the bubbles it
still it's got the water sources there
now they spread uh-huh so how do you
forcefully send mobs into the stream
here is the question because if we try
to connect like a water bucket up to
this you see the water goes this way
because the water water comes out here
and forces it this way right so it's
gonna be a bit tricky I think I figured
out a way of doing it okay this is
really weird I'm trying to fill up the
water elevator here with water source
blocks because most of this is just
downward flowing water right now you
need the source box for the bubble
stream so the way I'd do it I think I
left off at this level here take one
from there put it up we just moved up a
block
it's a bubble scream to get higher kind
of weird right and it's done okay so let
me try show you the gizmo I came up with
here they get them into the water
elevator so let's say we have a water
stream we want to go this way
and push them into here you see the
water streams taking us into the middle
though that's not what we want so what
you got to do I think to get this glass
here and over there we're gonna put a
trap door let's see trap door yeah
facing down like that so now if we
remove that stone kind of hold some of
the water in place we're gonna want to
dig down 2 blocks here and at that
bottom level there there's gonna be a
pressure plate so when they step on the
pressure plate it's gonna activate a
piston to shove them into the elevator
try to guarantee it happens right that
piston is going to be over here and we
want to use a specific oh I knew that's
gonna happen at least once like once you
start going up you can't fight it let's
open it wouldn't because it takes like
15 seconds to get back down there it's
alright it's alright
I'll let you guys know how I'm getting
in and out of here I guess
okay let's try not do that again be very
careful I don't step into the elevator
yeah
pistons gonna be there and what we want
to do is also put a sign here right so
they'll get pushed off off the edge here
the water they'll fall into here step on
the pressure plate and then this will
push them into the water sweet and we
got to connect this pressure plate up to
the piston here so one way you can do
that pretty simple here or the way I'm
gonna do it probably is this repeater
there with some redstone running up the
stairs here so that'll power this block
which in powers of piston rights we
didn't seal this up then and it looks
like that's good to go
like that'll be fine for witches
skeletons and zombies but this setup
actually has issues with creepers and
baby zombies as I found out in my
testing you see that's kind of like what
it does there so creepers and baby
zombies they're a little bit smaller and
because of that they kind of gets stuck
so I'll show you what we got to do with
them yeah as the creepers they'll kind
of like jump up and down in this water
here sometimes they step on the pressure
plate but sometimes they don't and
they'll just kind of get stuck here it
would be really good if we could get rid
of this this water here but we can't
really because we need the water source
next to it but I found out a trick we
could do here as well all we got to do
same thing is up here trapdoor like this
right that block there still a water
source that way and the bubble stream
still goes up but now we have like an
air space here so creepers won't jump up
and down water let us fall down sticky
piston will push a trapdoor there and
then it pulls it back that's all good
the only problem is when this pulls back
I'm gonna go up to me man I can't show
you without doing that problem is when I
pulls the trapdoor back it's in the
wrong position that's good don't check
that yeah so now when the next guy comes
by he's gonna get stuck over here
alright so what we got to do is just
change this to like a redstone block or
something that way it stays stays like
that and that's good to go that'll
handle the creepers then for the baby
zombies what I'm gonna do is actually
change that block there to make my block
because they'll get stuck on this
pressure plate keep the piston extended
and
just be a real nuisance right but this
way if we have the magma block there
they'll eventually die at least and I'm
gonna try that out with the system so
basically that's good to go I'm just
gonna have to build the spawning pads
now and stuff a few more of those noise
I really like this trident naturally
alright guys so this is like an hour
later now check it out we got ourselves
some spawning pads here the hard part of
this was figuring out a good pattern to
use I don't know if this is a great
pattern but it's gonna work there's no
dead zones in the water streams that was
the tricky parts and it's a spiral
pattern which is what really confused me
but I think that got it okay here so a
couple key features of the spawning room
all the water streams go to the main
channels obviously there's four four
ways to get into the elevator around
around here all right rose and we got
carpets in places here that's to prevent
spiders from spawning and then in these
areas where there's connections between
the water streams basically I got a slab
here and then a sign here to hold the
water source from flowing back this way
right and then above these I put some
slabs as well so that hopefully when the
mobs go in the connections they don't
jump back onto the pads and and like
never get to the elevator right want to
keep them moving so I think we're good
to go here I think we're gonna go try it
out so I'm gonna go up the elevator
myself
is it we still got Bubble streams it
doesn't rekt anything let's just spend a
couple moments up here and then we'll go
back down there should be some mobs
there a little moment to spawn I still
got the torches in so it's not gonna
spawn it to to many hopefully all right
oh I think the mob might be coming up I
see a break in the bubbles maybe oh is
cuz that's far away okay let's let's
just go down somebody's chasing me right
now they do follow you down these holes
by the way oh I hear some somebody I'm
just gonna take out the creeper I think
I'm hoping we can see the the gizmos in
action here so you see they're all kind
of going towards there anyone right up
the elevator there goes it Skelton so
it's working pretty good I think I'm
gonna take out the torches and then it's
gonna go crazy
can we go down oh dear
okay there's a jam there is definitely a
jam in there I guess Oh Nelly don't you
do it don't you do it nope nope nope
nope I'm out of here
oh dear
okay slight problem with the system I
guess if the wrong trap doors extend at
the same time I guess it's gonna kill
the water sources and then the bubble
streams shut off permanently okay I got
to think about how to fix that now okay
no they all converted at once you know
what I'm not even gonna fight him not
even going to bother see if they'll
follow me down here they're trying yeah
looks like they're gonna come oh it got
dark all of a sudden hello creepers nope
this is not where you should be ever
everything is fine nope torch is gone
everybody panic yeah so if I wasn't
clear basically the problem is if a
trapdoor extends into the bubble stream
and then another one also extends next
to it it's gonna destroy like the water
source there and there and then when it
retracts there's no water there anymore
to refill the area so a couple of ways
we can fix this
either we add some redstone control to
like not allow this one in this one
extend at the same time
or this one and the one next to it on
that side but the easiest way is just to
only allow mobs in on two sides at once
maximum so if we block this off here and
then lock it off on this side then it's
gonna always have two water sources
there to repopulate it
the downside obviously is like it's
gonna slow down the rate that we can get
them into the elevator here but I think
it'll be fine and also I got to redo the
water streams after I got them all
perfect we've got a direct them over
here now somehow okay well I did a
little bit of a hack job here I just
made it work our elegant waters stream
system here is not really as good
anymore but it's fine look a giant
spawning pad here now and kind of some
sloppy carpets all condensed together
here but I had to do that to stop the
spiders from spawning but it'll be fine
I think it's okay when this is all done
I would like to have like two or three
layers of the mob system as well not
just not just the one here but just for
today we'll do one all right so I got
the water back in place there so now we
should be good guys we should be good
and I'm just saying they're gonna start
coming up here pretty quick I would
think oh yeah we got a skeleton up here
might have been that from there before
though give it a sec yeah
we're far enough oh yeah here comes a
creeper whoo all right so right now
there's kind of free flowing into the
ocean we'll also want to build like a
cage so that we can hold them in some
place - and they'll build up there and
once the mop town gets high there they
won't
the drown mobs won't spawn and the water
is often and everything will be good I
think I think we got two mobs three mom
kind of thought they would spawn a
little bit faster than that be honest
that's their jam dn do we dare did we go
check no I don't know if I can actually
fight the bubbles that creeper right
there um I want to see if it's jammed
but I don't want to go down there okay
lots of mobs the downside with this kind
of system as well is they kind of hang
out on the pads sometimes but the upside
is we don't need a million Pistons it
looks like they're taking the channels
pretty good you've been with me here
they're trying to fight it a bit I think
we're good I think we're good here
nailed it all right so this is working
out pretty good now I got it sealed off
so they're all kind of just filling up
there we'll do stuff with them later I'm
sure but for now that's that's good cuz
I don't know how many mobs you got there
it's like 20 or so right now so while
they're there we're doing a lot less
ground mob spawning nearby fact that
you're the only one I see right now yeah
I don't see any others it's pretty good
might actually be able to do stuff under
water now well anyways guys I think
we're gonna have to call the episode
here for today my question to you guys
what did you think of the conduits
personally I didn't actually like the
night vision very much but I did see
some comments on the last episode like
Oh water's pretty dark isn't it hmm so
maybe maybe it's something we should
keep I I kind of want your guys's
feedback on that is it too dark did you
like it with or without I don't know I'm
not you all right let's get to the
comment of the day though again on a
subject that we really hates onions I
don't understand your problem with
onions regular red onions are pretty
strong on their own but having them on a
burger makes them much less strong also
cooked onions aren't strong at all now
that is a bold bold statement right
they're bold exclamation I say no for me
like you know sometimes I'll share a
pizza with someone you do the half and a
half and they have onions on their side
of the pizza if there's just the tiniest
little sliver of onion on my piece like
if it's next to theirs you know
sometimes some of the ingredients move
over onto your slice tiniest little
sliver it is so powerful like this
flavor so strong so terrible
maybe I'm hypersensitive to it I don't
know I've always wondered like habit
things taste to other people you know
cuz obviously we don't all have the same
sense of taste right how could we how
could you guys be eating onions I don't
understand
obviously they taste different to you
but for me they're super strong super
powerful super nasty uh-huh
anyways I better leave it at that I've
dashed onions and well no not enough you
can never bash him enough uh-huh I'm
gonna leave at that for today so hope
you guys enjoyed the episode until next
time thanks for watching take care have
a good day bye bye
[Music]