[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back guys to another
episode of our let's play series so yep
we are rocking the 17 wo 6a snapshots
now just came out the very first of the
1 points 12 snapshots is here and with
it let's get this going
48 new types of blocks well it's it's
three types of blocks but 16 colors of
each so we got the concrete powder we
got concrete and we got terracotta
glazed terracotta blocks so to get the
glazed terracotta you need to smelt
hardened clay yes that's a wonderful
sound isn't it that might be a problem
look at that green glazed terracotta I
really like the black stuff guys like
that I think that's my favorite out of
the 16 but we'll get these I got to get
a bunch of blocks together here today so
we can start building with them and
having fun ok mr. sheep I know you're
curious about the new blocks but sure
you're worse than taxes alright get out
of here yes I thought we would lay these
out first guys and just take a look at
them in case you haven't seen them yet
in your and you're curious what they're
like they're very very bright and
vibrant and full of life aren't they
it's gonna be quite the game-changer as
far as building goes in this game I
think because we didn't have a lot of
vibrant colors in this game before like
maybe prismarine per per blocks some of
the clay colors are pretty byte brights
and the wool and stuff but yeah well I
guess that's quite a few blocks but now
we got like 48 new ones and the wall is
a lot brighter to kind of go along with
the new colors it's gonna be interesting
I don't think people are gonna build the
same way anymore because previously most
of our
builds are some kind of gray color like
a stone then you got your earth tones
like the wood and stuff browns and
greens and that those are the main main
building blocks in Minecraft and now we
have all these bright vibrant things and
the cool thing about them is they are
directional as well so depending on
which way you play some changes the
rotation and you can combine them
together and create all sorts of cool
textures and patterns and stuff it's
gonna be interesting I don't know
exactly what I'm gonna do with them
myself but maybe we'll try to do some
building today
oh there's I never noticed that there's
creeper faces and those I just noticed
that that's awesome uh-huh this one
reminds me of a sword when I see it and
that's like the the mouse pointer okay
let's try something out here first off I
know you can instant mine these with
haste - we got haste - right now an
efficiency 5 on this thing
just like clay you can instant mine it
which is awesome makes it a lot easier
to fix your mistakes and stuff but we're
gonna change our beacon here to haste 1c
and you can't instant mine with it okay
so it's not quite like hard and clay and
something really worth noting about
these terracotta blocks is when you
build with them you're probably gonna
want to build with even numbers like if
you're using them in your floor or in
your wall because the texture aligns on
the edges of the blocks and not in the
center of the block that means you have
this weird thing where you have like one
big circle and and a half circle but
this as as your center if you're
building with odd numbers doesn't look
quite right right but if you go by by
twos or fours or sixes then you're fine
if you're rotating the blocks if you're
not really rotating them it's not as big
of an issue okay so I just tried out a
little bit of building with the
terracotta blocks and yeah I don't know
I might have to I think I'm gonna have
to see what other people do with them
first to steal some building tricks or
whatever because like they don't
I find they really don't mix well with a
lot of the existing blocks in the game
like that doesn't look good they look
cool on their own but then when you do a
big cluster of them together I'm not
sure I like it either though yeah I
think the trick with these terracotta
blocks is we're gonna want to use them
sparingly not like big clusters of them
but just little bits here and there I'll
probably look good but going to need to
practice using them because I don't know
what to do with them honestly so we're
gonna move on to the concrete powder
this is a block I'm gonna be using tons
of I think everybody is out of all the
blocks introduced the powder is probably
the real winner in this update
so yeah the way you make it you take
your die as we just did there you need
gravel and you need sand dye goes in the
middle gravel and sand and you get 8h
crafting yeah so you only need 8 died to
make a stack of this stuff okay I did
not realize this it's actually a
shapeless crafting recipe so that's
awesome you you can put the gravel or
sand in there however you want and the
die and it'll craft it up okay that's
cool okay guys here's the big moment can
we do it
can we do it no oh no cannot instant
mine concrete blocks it's too bad I like
that whenever you can instant mine a
block in this game it's so much more
enjoyable right or if you make a mistake
you don't have to worry about cleaning
up afterwards oh well I made a stack of
each of the concrete powders your guys
so we inject them out to your 16 colors
in total and they're also pretty bright
vibrant blocks very similar to sand
blocks like a similar texture and like
sand blocks they also have gravity but
when they touch the water or if water
touches them they converts into
concrete's that's how you get the
concrete blocks which have a very smooth
texture which is gonna be hard to use
with like most blocks in Minecraft
but it's good for like pixel art or
things like that I think right maybe
some unique builds could take advantage
of them
I did notice so even though they have a
similar texture to sand like if you look
at sand has these two dots over here if
you look at orange sand it also has
those two dots just a different color
right these though they have their own
unique texture and even between each of
the colors each one has its own
different noise pattern or texture which
is kind of cool right they're not all
the same these are gonna be really
really good in the game though because
you can use them for so many different
things like let's say you want to use
them for flooring right or for four
paths not a problem I would even argue
that the the texture on these blocks is
nicer than the wool texture right I
think you people are gonna use this as
as carpeting in their builds instead of
wool just because it looks better than
wool in my opinion yeah it's a nice
block and you can use it for walls why
nots right it has a nice texture to it
so why not use it like this wallpaper or
as paint sure looks great I think here
let's go ahead and sleep real quick and
a lot of the blocks can blend well with
the existing blocks in the game which is
really the important thing I think like
let's say let's say you wanted to make a
pass right out of out of the brown
concrete powder here it kind of looks
like mud I find looks like mud mixes
well with grass because it's got a
little bit of a grainy texture to it
also mixes well with dirts
which is a nice plus can be another
filler block in your path or or things
like that also for terraforming like
let's say you want to make a volcano in
this game didn't have a lot of black
blocks or before it mainly just coal
right and and cyan clay now you have
like this beautiful black texture or if
you want to make a
black sand beach you can do that sort of
thing now so there's a lot of a lot of
options here like mixing this with magma
blocks and lava could look like a
volcano lots of unique things like that
are possible now let's say you want to
make an alien worlds with crazy blue
grass or something you can pass this off
as As Brass kind of or some super bright
grass over here or you know lots of
options lots of cool things you can do
with this stuff so I'm very excited
about that I did also notice like I
placed a few of them together here
the dots here are the same position on
each of these so they don't rotate or
anything I have that configured or on
right now like if you look at the grass
blocks they all have a different
rotation oh yeah I set this up so we can
check out the different concrete blocks
as well so let's change this over so
like sand you can do the the floating
sand trick with it and it seems to have
particles yeah I didn't I didn't expect
that is it always black though it's not
the color of the block huh that might
change later but yeah basically you do
that and it turns into concrete's
so I looked on the reddit some people
have found very simple ways of farming
these concrete blocks already it sounds
like all you got to do is have like a
water stream or water somewhere and if
you select your powder and your pick you
put in your in your other bar right and
then I think you just got a right and
left clicked at the same time oh wait a
sec wait a sec we probably also need a
way to prevent you from placing it I
wonder if we could just use a torch here
so it doesn't like place it forward
let's try that again
yeah it's right and left click hold it
down if you feed yourself the powder
with dispensers or something then now
you could keep it going forever now just
afk as you make this stuff that's pretty
cool put a hopper below the blocks
little pick it up - that's not too bad
actually right I think that looks pretty
good
maybe maybe not the blue wolf for the
border we might need something with more
contrast but I do like this blue
concrete powder here yeah I think we're
gonna go ahead with this what what can
we call this concrete powder by the way
because concrete powder doesn't exactly
roll off the tongue it is like see pal
kind of stupid I need some blue C pal
yeah we got to think of a short form
though because concrete powders gonna be
tough to say constantly uh-huh I also
noticed while doing this I accidentally
while I was trying colors out and I I
put some light grey C POW next to the
clay and very closely color you could
use those two together for sure which is
cool that's a good sign whenever you mix
things like that it means it's gonna be
pretty useful this is what it looked
like before we just had light blue clay
with regular clay and now we have the C
pal so it's it's a good texture like if
you put a bunch of it together it
doesn't look bad
I don't think anyways I'm curious what
you guys have to say about this I think
it looks pretty good it's a it's a good
good color good texture blends well with
the the wall here if we're gonna keep it
maybe two well maybe not enough contrast
I also changed out the blue shiny rocks
here with the light blue concrete powder
okay I just had a silly idea for an
experiment guys we are going to do a
physics test get rid of these make our
floating concrete's
so if we're standing on this and it
drops as soon as it touches the water
down there it's gonna turn into solid
concrete so if we're standing on top of
this are we gonna hit the water we're
gonna hit the concrete block after it
forms let's find out
here we go oh we fall through it okay so
we beat it down actually that's
interesting okay how about this one guys
what if we have a fence and we drop
bunch of concrete powder on top of it's
what happens when they hit the water
that's just one block convert today all
converts to some of them break into item
entities I'm not sure let's find out
maybe well we'll throw some sand in
there just for some chaos as well I
don't know if it'll affect it or not
probably not okay there we go
put the B's in there too so now if we
break the fence okay so it looks like
yeah they turned into item entities most
of them probably one of them fell on top
of the concrete block and there only one
turned into concrete itself I got
another one for you here this one's a
really weird one so we're gonna have
floating concrete powder oh you know I
should put this back one more block
yeah floating concrete powder we're
gonna run water underneath it's right so
the water's gonna update it so it falls
but it's also gonna touch the block so
what happens first does it fall or does
it convert we're gonna find out if it's
if it falls it should turn into
concrete's one block lower if it just
converts it should stay in the same
place I think it fell and converted
right I expected them both to go but I
guess it converted before the water went
any further
right now there's also a little bit of
an oddity with this so if we put a water
source block below it
check out what happens it almost looks
like it teleports but maybe it's this
falling very quickly but it it destroys
the water block without turning into
concrete it's still the powder form
which is kind of cool but I bet you I
bet you if we remove the block below
it'll be difference right
okay so let's not put the glass block
back over here where it was and then we
will put the water over here
how does it destroy it then it should
fall through the water source block huh
that I did not expect okay are you ready
for this guys we're gonna do some sponge
physics next so if you have a sponge you
place the water bucket next to it turns
into a wet sponge right so it happens if
you place it by a sponge and also by a
concrete block you see where I'm going
with this not concrete block concrete
powder that's concrete powder we're
gonna put it right between the two it
does both so that turned to concrete and
it the sponge absorbed it's okay where
was that sponge it was over here right I
think I think it might be positional cuz
if we have a sponge here and we place
the water turns into a wet sponge these
don't convert though if we do the same
over here two of them converted one of
them did it yes so it's definitely based
on where it is in the chunk I'm pretty
sure probably the greatest thing about
having all these different brights
colors though is we can finally juggle
the proper way there we go so many
colors that's amazing
unfortunately though it doesn't last
forever anyways guys I think we're gonna
have to wrap up the episode here for
today unfortunately I don't know how or
why but I strained my voice recording
here like I can really feel it now and I
probably shouldn't talk anymore having a
hard time and unseating words too and
then okay so here's the comment of the
day it says raise your hand if you
didn't know mushrooms could even be used
as fuel I think it was a maybe one or
two updates ago Mojang
maybe even longer but Mojang recently
changed it so you can burn a whole bunch
of different things in the furnace
including like wall and banners and some
stuff you wouldn't expect most of it is
not good fuel efficiency though for the
cost mushroom blocks are that are an
exception I would say but you're
generally best burning planks or
mushroom blocks coal your general fuel
in Pocket Edition though I found out the
slabs have the same fuel efficiency as
planks so you should definitely convert
them because you had double that way but
not that's not the case in in computer
edition PC so some some interesting
oddities with the the fuel stuff anyways
hopefully you guys enjoyed the episode
if you have any comments or feedback or
ideas on how to use the new blocks feel
free to leave in the comments below but
hope you have a wonderful day thanks for
watching take care bye bye
[Music]