hey how's it going everyone this is yo
and welcome back to another episode just
want to show you guys let's check it out
I found the roof forest so I am very
happy about this looks really good too
very very cool
I'd like the roof forest a lot
especially with all the hills
um but yeah this was the main one of the
main things if not the main thing I
wanted to find in our traveling so last
episode we kinda gave up looking for it
because I explored everything out that
direction up to the ocean and so I
decided to go 500 blocks in the nether
another direction threw down a portal
and lucky lucky I came out rates right
into mush right into a roof forced I
always want to close a mushroom forest
for some reason but we could has
mushrooms in so yes I got the dark oak
saplings and the wood and and I'm using
it and everything is good in the world
stop moving the camera so fast why is
this I don't think I noticed that before
I didn't realize water was pouring in my
portal here so yeah we went 500 blocks
out in the nether got really lucky and
came out right at one of those things so
that was cool we were going to head back
so I just wanted to show you that I have
something else to show you
with our nether portal network system I
have been working on it and it is
working properly now so let's go check
that out
yes so very good news guys the portal
network idea looks like it's gonna work
out
it's gonna be pretty cool I think one I
I get it all done and polished up okay
these guys get life now no they're still
they're still all the way off all the
way off zip your lips all right if you
listened I mean I mean I think I'm in
peaceful mode now because I can't hear
them and then I'm just going to get shot
at when I'm over top lab or something on
some little bridge so don't forget I
can't forget but yeah this idea it's
going to turn out good I think so I got
three three portals hooked up to the
network right now and last time we we
checked this out I hit a big snag with
the two-way repeaters see like this
right now I feel like there's no gas I
would just be out and open and getting
shot at and yeah all right I don't think
they're around but the two a repeater
was creating instant wire unexpectedly
and I got rid of that design I have
replaced all the two-way repeaters with
this design this one uses a comparator
and repeater and you can see if I send
power here all the way down there all
the lights came on so it sends a signal
all the way down that way if I power it
from here everything this way gets lit
up so it goes both ways no problem I saw
another good design to that use locking
repeaters but apparently it could get
stuck like the signal would let it light
if it got powered from both directions
it could get stuck in a permanent on
state so this one I tried it out it
doesn't do that I think it will be
really good now
we solved that problem there was also
another another big improvement I did
here oh well please don't wake up more
yes I can get out of here
I got all the Redstone encased in these
boxes and I was able to get rid of my
redstone for detecting if the signal was
longer than a certain amount I got rid
of like I had two Pistons here and all
that I was able to get rid of all that
and replace it with a comparator and
this this was shown to me by let me
check double check his name I want to
give him credit because this is an
awesome improvement to the circuit here
his name is Charteris I hope I said that
right
so thank you Charteris for showing me
this he took the circuit I had and was
able to get rid of my pistons and and
just simplified the whole thing by
replacing the pistons the logic for
detecting if the signal was longer in a
certain amount with just a single
comparator so it's quite a bit smaller
no piston noise anymore and I think
it'll lag a little bit less because if
there's no piston movement and that kind
of thing these repeaters they don't do
anything and this is just to get by the
wire here so it doesn't connect so yeah
that is awesome
thanks again Taurus and I'm come on I'm
doing that a lot today down to four
anchor pearls oh let's see what I mean
and it was going to happen
Oh Gigi maybe you know I have a bow I
can fight back what am i doing well if I
I could hit something I could fight back
wait for it wait for it no so he's
hiding behind that pillar really well
man I mean she's pretty good shot
against guess there's not that day
though all right so all in all the
circuitry has been improved
significantly in this oh I don't want to
get in through here I guess oh man this
is a this is quite the challenge not
being able to tear mom's know I missed
oh man that scared me I was minding my
own business and they just just attacked
me through here okay right right so
demonstration time let me show you how
to do how this works I'm wasting too
much time in this episode so I just have
a cheat sheet over here because I
couldn't remember what settings to do so
if I want to go to the strongholds I set
it to ten so four five six seven eight
let's add two more and that one goes on
that's the stronghold this one here is
to the zombie purifier thing so that's
11 we add one
like that's and I also have the sandpit
connected right now so that's eight so
minus three uh-huh so it's using just as
a recap to how this thing works it's
using the length of the redstone pulse
to determine which portal to turn on so
that turned this one on here so now if I
want to go to the stronghold or to send
things to the stronghold not what was it
I think it's ten ten right so one two
three seven eleven ten that's ten we hit
this button that turns a stronghold
portal on and then we go through like
this we activate the timer so this will
close behind us
here the piston activate just as we went
through I hope and now anything we send
through this portal is going to go to
that stronghold portal so if I throw
stick sir or send storage of mine carts
through with items in or mobs I'm trying
to move a villager or
or enemies or anything I want to move
through a portal will now end up at that
destination cool I got my sticks back
we're here to stronghold if I want to go
to sandpit four five six seven eight I
wonder if there's a quick way of setting
this I don't know do the same thing I
think it's gonna be really neat when
it's all done my nether though we we
need to plan this my nether is looking
really crummy it needs an overhaul try
make it look nice sometime soon so yeah
we're here at the sandpit one so that's
how it all works I'm going to try to
connect as many portals as I can get one
out to the blaze farm one to my man cave
and just there's a lot of a lot of
places I could connect the two and I
could even use this for transportation
doing some fancy stuff too so it has a
lot of potential this project but yeah
my neighbor my nether isn't looking too
good so we should add that to the - to
the to-do list things we should do in my
world try make things look nice I never
even finished this hub it's it's like
really bugging me I hate how this all
looks over here now I liked it at the
time but not anymore and I can't even
get a horse through anyway anywhere so
just need some updates maybe rethink the
minecart situation - I do want to have a
minecart system still even though I want
to use horses if I tend but having both
would be good anyway I'm rambling let's
head on back to the man
okay so today guys we are going to visit
an old friend of ours someone we haven't
seen in a long long time that we miss
ever so dearly
our good friend Wilson he's still
waiting for his brain I checked this guy
out today and he is a lot closer to done
than I realized even I forgot what I did
with him lust and turns out his hunger
is working his weight is working his
health is working we can add happiness
to him but there's no way it decreases
currently and there's not really any
good ways of increasing it besides
cookies I just gave him a quick reboot
here to to get him going
he's running in super speed mode right
now you saw his hunger went down so he's
he's almost dead he's got one one light
left there yeah we can feed him we can
we can heal him I had the sickness thing
working with him hunger went up um I
think what I need to do or what I would
like to do currently when he gets sick
there's no way to tell he's sick so we
need maybe we should put an indicator
lights over there if we can or over
there I want to try hook his face up to
more of the things to like currently
it's hooked up to the happiness meter
and if he dies his face will change too
but I wanted to go sad face if he gets
sick maybe and if if his hunger runs low
maybe he'll get sad too so I'm going to
take a look back here and see if that's
possible
hopefully it is and then we might move
on to something else if I can get that
working very good very good some good
progress has been made on Wilson today
so this is like an hour maybe even two
hours later I've been
tinkering with the wiring back there for
quite a while kind of lost track of time
doing all kinds of things one thing I
fixed he was having a problem where he
was sometimes coming back to life after
he died like he would he would switch
between his death face and like his
house would go up just a tiny bit which
would bring him back to life and keep
the whole thing running so he would keep
he kept dying and like coming back to
life and die and come back to life now I
can definitely kill him when he dies so
this controls if he's alive or not if
this is empty he's dead
so that's here let's put some in here
when there is stuff in there that power
is this and makes that piston extend
here when it's empty this retracts and
this is the line of wire that adds to
his health so increases his health and
if that block is not there the signal
can't pass through so it's just a little
safety net to make sure he doesn't
regain health after he's dead and and
keep coming back to life but the most
important thing checked it out a new
facial expression has been added to
Wilson this is his sick face not not
totally different from his other faces
but this was a real challenge to add I
gotta tell you it was very difficult
because this has to override his normal
expression if he's sick but then that if
he dies the death face has to override
this sick face which gets kind of
complicated
have to do like some checks to make sure
he's not dead when showing this
otherwise it doesn't make sense
um and I also made one other change now
when he is sick his happiness drains
very very slowly over time so longer
takes me to cure him the less happy he
will be there we go give him a Golden
Apple and he's cured he's no longer sick
which is very cool so I was thinking
about adding a light here the thing is
I'm considering maybe getting rid of
this and doing something something else
maybe a fancier way of feeding him oh he
died okay
sorry Wilson sorry buddy it might be
cool if instead of like just walking up
to here and throwing food in this little
tiny hole if maybe we could set it up so
that we bring him cows or something and
then he shoots fireballs from the sky
down on the cows and it kills them and
then eats that or brings the meat to his
mouth or I don't know maybe maybe work
out something a little cooler than this
and I don't know what I'm putting in
those and I think I won't be able to
fill all four spots or have space do so
might get rid of this and have a fancier
feeding system um but yes sickness seems
to be all good I was not able to hook
his hunger bar up to his facial
expressions there's just not enough
space I don't think but I might look
into it one more time now when I get
time but here's something I need help
with from you guys and I don't know if
this is possible maybe there's some
musical geniuses out there that would
know for sure but is it possible to give
this guy like some some vocal way of
expressing emotion like can I make him
whimper or make a happy expression using
noteblocks
somehow is that possible the only reason
I asked it I don't think it is possible
but it might be the reason I asked
because like on Pokemon for example on
the on the old Gameboy with the the
crummy little chiptune audio synthesis
synthesis in--this sizer man that's hard
work to say
um since that's going to bug me I'm
going to get it right right when I
stopped recording to that it's able to
make like the Pokemon battle cries like
when you play them in battle using the
just combining a bunch of notes together
so I'm wondering if that's possible with
the note blocks like if we have a whole
cluster of them together somehow playing
different noises is it possible to tune
it in such a way that it makes different
sounds that sound almost creature like
and if it is let me know I would like I
would like them to express happiness
sadness like whimpering um if he can say
hello somehow I'm really stretching here
but there might be some crazy
combination or no block set that sounds
like like he's saying things I don't
know if there is record a YouTube a
video of it if you can send me a link on
Twitter maybe would be a good way to get
ahold of me
um and I will check out what you did
hopefully I think the inbox on YouTube
is broken or changed I don't know how to
use it anymore so sending me PM's that
way doesn't really work anymore okay so
I do have a few other ideas for Wilson
might people do one or two more today
but I don't want them to be just like
this box I want them to be interactive
to do to do cool things and not just be
a bunch of lights you know I really
liked how his face changes for example
that's cool but one idea I had is to
install a player sensor which we're
going to do now one two three four five
six seven eight nine let's put the
middle let's call this some middle yes
yeah we're going to do a player sensor
and hopefully we can read it so that
when we walk into this room he can sense
that we are here and then
react to us like if he's in a bad mood
maybe he tries to attack us or if he's
in a good mood maybe he gives us gifts
or something I know just little stupid
things like that might be cool or stupid
one or the other oh you know they didn't
do I didn't check the height this is
second so there's there's a really
simple player sensor you can make in
survival minecraft or twice 30 sethbling
had a video on it actually where you use
passive mobs which when they're over
thirty two blocks away from you they can
go into a inactive state where they
don't move anymore
redstone yes
Wilkins get dangerous so if that happens
maybe maybe put it around here
finish your thoughts what were you going
to say we're gonna get get a cow down
here but yeah if slimes man slimes
alright I'm going to finish my thought
down so if if the passive mob is over
three two blocks away from you it'll
stop moving but then when you come and
range it it'll start like pathfinding
again and looking for areas to go to so
all you really need to do we're going to
get a cow down here for Seidel and my
stone on me that was smart so I just
went ahead and I got that area ready for
our cow so now for the fun part of
trying to get one there's not I don't
think there's any up above roaming
around my world so I have to get them
from here and I made this a long time
ago with no intention of ever taking
cows out of your so
that was weird let's see if we can hook
one up here maybe nope we need a lot of
height I think that's going to work if
we can pull it up from from here oh that
was close that was really close
where did you land oh that's gonna be
really tough if we we do this with our
hook no need more height is the thing
maybe this will work now
oh so many cows and I still missed all
right come on oh oh oh he was out he was
out she was out whatever come on okay
now we need to move further out it looks
like Oh can't they're flinging really
high so I can get lower anyway let's try
this out try this one on for size okay
there we go
and uh come on so close now they're just
they're going up they're not going
sideways for some reason
oh I'm so close this is like the winning
combination right now what just happened
okay I didn't see that happen before um
looks like we got a cow in the UFO
finally no Jason you gotta pull it back
right when you hit them yes yes no no no
no no that that was my problem they kept
trying to run back down temp Levi
actually got one in the UFO that was
awesome
oh so we got a child there now Oh
the UFO doesn't work anymore they
changed the velocity of pulling them on
the fishing hook so it's the wrong
height and when I pull them they don't
reach all the way up so the fact I
actually got one up there was pretty
cool maybe I was just doing it wrong
come on come meet Wilson alright so you
go down there cooperate this is not
going to work out too well
cows are really big so that usually
they'll just go over the whole like
they're really fat you're really fat you
know that come on hmm so close oh oh I
pushed it too far no no don't move don't
move so the easier way of doing this I
guess would be like this probably a lot
easier no no no no I'm not done
you're not done I gotta take them off I
gotta take her off the lead whatever
it's a chow otherwise he'll probably
swing back up at me there we go woohoo
get our water back no no nut milk Oh No
start it we have a problem
oh and scooch it into the piston all
right drink the milk stop giving me milk
I dated the water back I place a torch
there we go
all right so now any time she tries to
walk out of here come on
no no go back down that happens
so she's activating this redstone here
constantly she's looking for an area
outside of here to walk and when she
tries to move she gets pushed right back
but there is times also where she just
stands still like this so it might take
a while to detect the flare when I'm up
there but I don't think she'll be able
to get out of there
it should be good so um I'm going to
hook this wire up to a timer so that if
it's not pressed like in 30 seconds or a
minute it considers me gone otherwise if
it's been pressed within a minute it's
going to think that I'm up by Wilson
here is the way I'm going to rig it
somehow so we've got to run the wire up
here and then figure out ways to use it
in a cool cool awesome fashion I guess
but anyway I guess that's going to be it
for this episode everyone so here's the
comment for today
it says hey ezel will you be continuing
your map making series because I waited
a whole year for episode 9 please
continue exclamation marks sad face why
so sad don't be sad it'll continue don't
worry
cheer up
the next episode of that is going to be
very important because I'm revealing how
the game works like all the stuff I've
been keeping secret since since I
started the series it's going to be
revealed probably next episode and I'm
trying to set some things up just so
it'll flow smoothly I'm going to be
revealing the name of the game I picked
out a name for it and also just been
busy with other things too so yeah it'll
come out don't worry we'll be new
episodes anyway I'm going to say good
bye everyone I hope you have a great day
and I will see you again next time bye
bye