no iron golem emergency emergency
get them all what is going on
these aren't villagers on these my whole
village got flooded all of a sudden me
what hey all that was crazy how did they
get in what was that uh is that a zombie
siege is that what happens oh I wonder I
I don't think I've ever witnessed one
but apparently they're back in the game
like they actually worked now yeah that
seems to be what it was I just did some
reading to see what oh man there's still
some here yeah I didn't do a thorough
check of the village oh no baby zombie
what I'm so scared now I don't want to
lose all my villagers you have no idea
how long it takes me that refilled of
the village if that ever happens um
let's just do a quick check so yeah I
read what the wiki said about zombie
sieges I'm pretty sure that's what it
was it says there's a 10% chance of them
happening every night and it is
nighttime if like if it happened during
the day it would not be a zombie siege
for sure at least I think it's still
what I checked it was a yeah it's still
night time it's just about turning day
interestingly they only happen when
you're by the village apparently so it
says it you have to be at the village
centre which i think is around here or
something or maybe down here even so I
was working up here on this minecart
thing right
and then I look over and just tons of
zombies and it it says you have to or
it'll spawn them if you are within the
center of the village plus the size of
the village so I think it means how many
villagers are in it and plus one on that
as well so you also need 20 villagers
and ten doors check this one out yeah I
think we killed them all all right so I
guess though all those conditions were
met and that was a zombie siege I've
never seen one before very scary so if
you afk don't it afk it at your village
or you might lose all your guys oh yeah
finally happened oh no it didn't you got
stuck somewhere that's not good oh you
got stuck right there darn it
oh the powers off that's kind of an
issue
here let me get that going for you oh
and the track is missing there okay we
got a couple problems thought I finally
had it um oh yeah another important
thing about zombie sieges guys well you
died uh they happen regardless of the
light level in your village so you can
have a perfectly lit up village like
mine here doesn't matter nobody's safe
especially not you they they will kill
them all so be careful okay I think this
is almost working oh you hear that mr.
villager the zombie
you better run inside go through this
door it's very inviting
nope not that nope nope you're going to
the wrong door oh come on why'd you do
it
Oh
yes finally yay Oh
oh he got hurt and he didn't get ejected
ah well he's got a second chance here he
might die in that minecart if I don't
get him out or no he's gonna get stuck
over here because nothing's gonna boost
him at the start yeah I gotta give him a
little push let's see if he goes off
this time this thing's actually kinda
tricky to get working properly nope
okay so we need to activate a rails here
I guess all right let's try one more
time here oh you got her tray at the
start - oh he's dead no hey do you want
to be a test subject let's go let's go
over here don't you worry or do you have
a good trade this guy has a good trade
you
you're a perfect test subject yes yes
you have you have the nose for it I can
tell all right now I'll fix this later
but just for now I want to see if you'll
get it ejected okay there's two there
now okay finally let's get rid of those
two look at this happened again unreal
so they came out of this room there was
one in here last time spawning behind
the doors it looks like
so I've discovered there's a stubborn
villager condition yeah didn't get
ejected while you gotta ejected but then
I got put back right in or he went back
in I don't know Lea this though I can't
get this guy to go he fights it I really
don't like this change in the game mobs
can fight minecarts and if they do you
can't do anything with them so stupid
and if he happens to get on the track
where he'll go he fights it and when he
gets rejected he just goes right back
into my Kurt every time
oh right everybody so I think I'm done
all I want to do on the village today
you probably noticed a few changes I'll
take you on a quick tour of what's been
done minecart thing I don't know what to
do uh
this villager near by the way he he
cannot get out he is trapped he will not
cross the minecart tracks it's kind of
funny if you want to lock a villager
inside a door just put a track in front
um he's been in there for like an hour
now let's see so yeah we got some trees
going in here I just planted some crops
so uh you know what's happening here
little baby villagers are getting in the
spot and then they fall down and trample
it's so I may want to just get rid of
that little crevice there got a bunch of
bushes around and let's go downstairs
redid some of the the framework and
whatever got stairs going around this
spot now all the chests have been moved
and been clean up so that that spot
looks quite a bit better
they got moved into the green building
sort of had these little compartments in
the walls before and I just put the
chests in there fit pretty nicely new
windows on the houses another tree over
here this area got done a little bit
it's a little bit nicer I think it's
amazing what just a few leaves around
the place does makes it look a lot
better I think up here oh I've been
killing a lot of villagers this is new
we have a portal so if I ever need to
move these guys to the nether it's nice
and easy now just left-click to turn it
on and right-click to turn it off
pretty simple and over here is the
villager school that's been finished now
I haven't seen any little guys go in
here yet though I haven't had too many
of them running around the village but I
think there's only been three or four
but they all grew up before going in the
building so they may just not be finding
the building right now or it might be
too far away from the village for to
work but there is the good life over
here if they do well in school and have
good trades they get sent back to the
village if they do bad they go down the
bad life and this just goes up to the
surface for right now nothing nothing
fancy up there but they'll get eaten by
zombie basically they might wander
around the world for a bit though which
would be cool all right
Oh endermite what else what else do we
have
oh you know something I saw every now
and then I'll find a zombie in the
village not from a zombie siege just a
random one ah there was a zombie like
right in this corner trying to get in
and this guy he knocked them over the
wall into the village so that's how some
have been getting into the village this
guy's been giving him a boost over the
fence
apparently I couldn't believe it and
we're going to add one more thing over
here I'll do it with you guys
there's a note block thing underneath
you can get out of here finally please
they'd like to sneak in these places
when I'm working then I can't get them
out so yeah there is a date lights
detector over here I got a length of
three on the wire which seems pretty
good and then it gets inverted that's
like right when it turns nighttime and
these guys start running to their their
homes and firework dispenser over there
so we're going to do this to the note
blocks 13 12 9 3 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 9 3 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 9 1 2 3 1 2 you know what it
is 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 okay
all right this should bring back
memories Oh
let's click there we go so now whenever
it turns night it plays that little tune
I've really missed that tune and shoots
off a firework well I think this is the
first time I've returned to the Enderman
farm since we built this ender pearl
screen but we're all out of ender pearls
again time to refill our stash so just
going to do a little bit of exploding oh
yeah
what oh that scared me why did that do
that you hear the fire sizzle Deb
Strider 3 oh yeah Wow oh this is a
problem oh darn it I think our hoppers
that filled up a little bit let's check
this out now I can't remember if I put
any chest below these hoppers I I was
supposed to but you know me I tend to
forget these things let's get these in
here before they disappear okay what's
below
yeah there's chess but they fill up now
the hoppers probably just can't keep up
right oh it's only one chest one double
chest hmm yeah this needs an upgrade
uh-huh so you know what it is I think I
figured it out the ender pearl ejector
thing here it does them one by one at a
rate that the hopper should be able to
keep up right but what's going on is
they travel to unloaded chunks and then
when I get there
- those unloaded chunks all the ender
pearls are probably stacking up and then
when they go through the end portal -
those those other hoppers we just saw um
they just bounce off the hoppers because
it's a stack of them and it can't it
can't absorb them right so it just
bounces off so what we got to do is add
a second one of those right before they
go through the portal alright so that is
exactly what
I did here I set up another dispenser
thing at the portal right at the portal
like it's right over there let me show
you real quick how to build one of these
in case you don't know they're actually
kind of useful if you ever need to
dispense items at a certain rates what
you do get your dropper or dispenser and
then comparator next to it make that go
to a block redstone block repeater
redstone so that makes a clock and then
make it go up one and that way it'll
power the dropper so now if there's
items in here tada pretty simple and I
believe if it's set at one
it'll dispense it at a rate that hoppers
will pick it up we could even test that
if we wanted here let's try that real
quick just to make sure so if we put a
hopper here they shouldn't be able to
pile up oh that's looking good no items
are getting stuck or stacking on top the
hopper so it's at a good rates cool so
let's head down here we'll try it out
for real whoa
we'll send up a stack of grass I don't
think I've let any grass blocks flow
through here while I've been testing so
throw it right against here a whole
stack of it at once good should go up
and there was 63 there let's just make
sure we get 63 - I have a feeling some
are disappearing somehow which is
another issue I don't know if it's the
same issue like if it's related or what
but yeah also another thing like a whole
bunch of items are going to approach us
at the exact same time because they're
unloaded and they all pile up there's
not really any point to putting a chest
here I don't think this like store
though the big amount of items that have
come all at once I just have them or
they'll fly up Oh No darn it David this
doesn't work I thought redstone would
count as a block I just not this was the
easiest place for the item to go right
here hmm what to do what to do I can
move this all over one block I think
there's a trick you can do if you ever
need your comparator power like the
analog single signal to go further you
just add another comparator on to it so
we just shift everything over one block
if we want and then we can keep this
solid so that doesn't happen
ah-ha so the droppers getting powered
here but it must be staying powered
somehow so this isn't working you could
also just get rid of one comparator and
put a block there but again it thinks
it's powered for some reason let's run
it over this way I wonder why that made
a difference okay anyway it works so
we're gonna try to out one more time
here all right looking good give it a
moment and let's go check what's on the
other side here and don't we're pretty
close oh please work please work please
work please work please work please work
no really okay how many bounced off five
why did five bounce off let's check how
many are in here so there should be 58
there's 58 that's good I don't know why
five would have bounced off well I guess
if it continues to be an issue I might
be able to just like put a border around
the hoppers let they can't jump jump out
of there you know items stay put might
work let me tell you guys the actual
plan with this thing so you can see I've
added a bunch of chests might want to
add more I'm not sure yet and basically
all the ender pearls will siphon down to
the bottom so we have ender pearl
transport from the Enderman farm right
to here through the portal and
everything which is pretty cool the next
step if I was to add on to this I would
like to set up ender pearl Oh for my
ender pearls let's drop them off ender
pearl dispensing stations around the
world so I use ender pearls quite a bit
but I do hold back because I only have
them stored in one spot in the man cave
I got that one ender pearl dispenser so
like if I'm walking around here usually
I don't ender pearl around too much
because then they don't last I'll have
to go back and refill but if I had
dispensing stations like every few
hundred blocks of Parts I would probably
use them quite a bit and they would be
very handy so what we'll do is we'll set
up a minecart like a storage minecart
loading station over there and then
it'll make its rounds and drop off ender
pearls that all the refill stations that
we set up and do a loop and then go back
and refill again now the thing with that
though is if the cart travels to an
unloaded chunk it's not going to make it
very far right so we have to put it only
in areas that we frequent like I
wouldn't like run it all the way to
amplified bass or something because you
know I go there and then amplified bass
and there's no way for the cart to
return in the in-between land because I
don't go to those areas so it would
probably just be round so like the man
cave maybe the windmill here the next is
the village that kind of area and
pretty cool but that is a future project
there is one other thing I was going to
talk to you guys about today and I want
your feedback on this oh it's it's
nighttime now okay
thought he was broken some people have
suggested I cut down these trees which I
might be doing but the other thing this
over here what was I thinking guys why
didn't anyone stop me I don't think I
gave you a chance but yeah this uh this
thing's not really working too well is
it the giant snow thing I never finished
it and I either have to finish it or
change it and I think we should change
it because it really does not suit the
desert at all right so what I should
have done instead is probably just build
like a pyramid because the whole point
of this was to hide the mob system over
here right it's pretty big it was quite
the eyesore before um I wanted to blend
it in so what Oh No
turn it so what I think we should do is
build a giant sand pyramid probably have
a sandstone is there anything specific I
should put inside any ideas for that let
me know um or if it's a bad idea let me
know too I would like to save these
penguins the penguin guy in the mammoth
but don't know if that would work
anywhere else in the world that's
another reason I did this because I
wanted to have these guys okay I'm about
a it's time to wrap up the episode let's
check out the comments says OMG if you
could figure out a way to get the chief
villager knows to look like it's hanging
that would be hilarious I'll give it a
shot I'll try alright so now let's go up
might need to curve it a bit does that
make sense or should we make it just go
straight down
maybe we'll try a few different things
here okay first first attempt let's go
like this oh we got an edge over a bit
this and yeah let's just go straight
down from there and see what it looks
like oh man okay that's I think that's
looking a little strange what happened
to the other clay block oh there it is
this looks bad it's like he has a beak
um no no not that
we could try curved it one more outward
so I would think gravity would suggest
it would go like this let's go this way
and then sag down how's that that's so
bad because it's got a lot of tensile
strength you know up closer to the the
knob and then it thus Nas yeah it
extends like that mmm okay let's just
try straight down I don't think this is
working
one last attempt straight down all right
let's take a look
yeah it's Pinocchio villager I think we
have to leave it the way it was unless
you guys like this more I don't know
it's kind of strange anyway that's gonna
do it for today guys thank you for
watching I'll see you in the next
episode bye bye
you