[Music]
hey what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back to another episode of the
let's play series
right now we are in the middle of the
ocean if you couldn't tell yes it's true
what are we doing here
none of your business ah no i'm just
here to collect some blocks nothing too
exciting
what are we collecting blocks for none
of your business
uh just to have them basically yeah so
on on that note this is going to be a
very weird intro
to this episode because i'm trying
something a bit different as well yeah
so my plan for this intro is to do like
what's etho been up to kind of thing
i've been playing a whole bunch since
last episode you know collecting things
organizing just taking care of some of
the like grinding not super interesting
projects i've been wanting to do
that's uh probably not worth featuring
in an episode but it's probably worth
mentioning so i wanted to like compile a
bunch of those together uh-huh yeah so
here we go everybody what's etho been up
to well the first project i tackled was
over at the amplified base because that
is the closest flower forest in our
world and we needed to make a new flower
farm because our old flower farm really
wasn't working too well anymore not only
because the redstone was outdated but
because uh we've gotten new flowers in
the game in the recent updates like the
lily of the valley cornflower blues we
had no way of generating those in our
world
and another thing that's changed over
time is like where the flowers generate
in flower forests has changed
and i couldn't even get alliums anymore
because they didn't generate in the same
spot anymore uh so i've just been
whittling down our stockpile of flowers
over time here and we've kind of ran out
we needed a new flower farm set up we
were able to set up farms for most the
flowers in the game just by setting up
four of my seven by seven flower farms i
really like these because uh they're
quick they're efficient but
especially i can build one in under five
minutes they're super simple
um if the space is cleared out already
now you might notice we put the flower
farms underground what's that about well
i searched the whole surface of our
flower forest like a 300 by 300 area i
could not find lily of the valleys
anywhere i spent over an hour looking
for those things
i even went up in the sky and checked a
bunch of spots couldn't find them it
always goes lily of the valley than
cornflower blue than the oxide daisies
so i ended up checking underground and
that's where we eventually found some
and that's where we set up our farms
so then after the flower farms were
built i went on a bit of a dye
collection spree i wanted to fill up
that new building in sandy city all the
barrels with the dyes so that they would
be readily available because that's the
main reason we needed the flower farm
was to get more dyes and for the next
project we headed over to that new lush
caves caverns we've been working on
underground
and it's very important whenever you're
working on a project that you have an
easy way to and from it otherwise you
will end up wasting a whole bunch of
time just going back and forth between
the project and it won't be nearly as
fun either because you'll dread every
time you have to go pick up something
right so we had that long tunnel from
the man cave to the cavern but we didn't
really have any other way to getting to
it i wanted a direct access with an
elevator just
in the area as well that way if we ever
need to transport animals or if we just
need to pick up something
from somewhere other than the man cave
it would be a lot easier i got the
elevator mostly finished but then i
realized we didn't have enough ice left
to fill in the bubble column on it and
we'd have to go get more so we paid a
visit to the ice farm and it's been a
very long time since i lasted a harvest
because
i made the farm like ridiculously big
that like i hardly ever need to get more
ice uh actually the last time we used it
was before netherride tools came out
even um
i know this because
the farm's so big it'll break a diamond
pick like a full usage of a diamond pick
if i'm not careful but now that we have
netherrites i can farm the whole thing
without worrying about it breaking which
is awesome it actually takes like uh
seven or eight minutes to do a full
harvest uh-huh yeah so then after we
finished harvesting all the ice we went
back to finish up the bubble vader we
were working on we just put in two
blocks of ice all the way up and then
broke some of it most of it actually
just melted from the the sea lanterns we
put in so we didn't have to really do
anything
could have just left it and let it
handle itself but i was impatient
next up i decided to head over to our
spruce tree farm and give it a little
upgrade as well now this is one of the
farms i like the most in our world i use
it all the time it's great for just
getting bulk wood for crafting chests or
hoppers or that kind of thing right so i
use it quite frequently and i want it to
to look good you know
i want to be happy when i'm using the
farm so i decided to add two more legs
onto it just because i thought it'd look
a little bit better i'm kind of curious
about this actually when you guys play
minecraft do you do this in your worlds
as well where you'll like go back to
projects and just keep adding on to them
or is this more of a me thing
because i know we like meme about the
whole oh it never finishes his projects
right but honestly i don't like to call
a project finished i like to go back to
it later and just add on to it if i
think of something that would make it
better
i don't want to be like oh it's finished
don't touch it ever again we move on to
the next thing it's no i like to go back
and like keep adding on for some reason
yeah so speaking of uh never finishing a
project i noticed uh while i was in the
area i was looking over at the nexus and
the roof on it was kind of blocky
looking right especially the sea
lanterns were just kind of sticking out
on the top and i got thinking maybe we
should try round it out just real quick
um so
put some courts around it some iron trap
doors and then for the dark prismarine
on the sides it was also pretty blocky
looking so i just put some stairs and
slabs
around it to try smooth things out to be
honest with you there's a couple things
around the nexus that don't look quite
right one of those uh scars is the
bamboozler just this nether brick and
glass thing
i should build something over top of
this at some point but uh until then i
figured i would just uh switch out some
of the materials so it would be easier
on the eyes
we got this old blacksmith building out
by the wheat farm which never really got
finished and the funny thing is i think
we built this before the path next to it
right and then we put the path in and i
never connected the path up to the old
house or there's even a path by the
course fruit farm which this kind of
ends as well so i figured let's
extend the path that way we will bust
down the fence and uh connect all three
together and just make our world look a
little bit more united after that i kind
of felt like doing a bit of a mindless
mining you know how it is sometimes
you're watching tv or whatever you don't
really want to think about anything but
you want to do something
so i went over to the pillager outpost
and there's this big chunk of land i
needed to
mine out because some of the pillagers
were still spawning on there the idea is
we're going to hopefully make this into
a raid farm eventually
but uh until then this was a little
problem that needed to get finished on
it i had this idea as well that i wanted
to run by you guys because i hate
absolutely hate moving beacons in this
game like it's one of my most dreaded
things i've resorted to using tnt
sometimes to clear them
and i thought why don't they make it so
that you can put tnt in a beacon and
that unlocks a self-destruct option
is that a good idea or is that like too
much for vanilla and then finally i went
back to the caverns again this time i
wanted to get started on the triple
amethyst we found we want to make them
into a farm so that we can just hit a
button and automatically collect all the
crystals just by having the pistons
break them for us
uh the problem is
this is like the most annoying farm to
build in the game if you've ever done it
before it's tedious it's tricky every
single one has to be made differently
and there's a lot of like puzzle solving
as you go with it and that my friends is
what ethos been up to
okay so the experiment is over that's
all the footage i had saved on my hard
drive guys i got through it all and now
we stop and we analyze what how did that
go what do you guys think about the
episode so far hmm
you probably noticed it was a little bit
different huh
there's a reason for that is because i
was uh testing something out i've never
done an episode like with a big chunk of
post commentary i just i wanted to see
what it would be like you know i i
wanted to challenge myself a little bit
today and just see if it was better what
was good about it what was bad so i
think it's good for showing a lot of
information i think the episode loses a
bit of heart though doesn't it so the
nor the way i normally record if you
don't know
is also a little bit weird i generally
will
uh do something in game here i'll record
a single clip
and then i go straight to editing with
that one clip and i'll i'll attach it to
the the end of the video
and try get it as polished as i can
sometimes i forgot to say something or i
i mess up my words so then i go back
into the game and then i record the next
clip and i'll remember to say that thing
i i forgot to say or that i messed up
and then uh
i'll do the best i can with that clip
and i'll just attach to the end again
and somehow it makes a video
a patchwork style video uh-huh uh the
other thing i was kind of curious about
is what style of video was going to take
me longer to do and funny enough they
kind of worked out to take about the
same amount of time
so the downside of real-time commentary
is i end up cutting out a lot of what i
say and it just goes to waste right uh
also
um
like when i'm doing stuff in game like
what i'm doing right now
i have a hard time thinking and doing
the thing i'm
working on and i work very slowly so i
can get stuff done super fast and
efficiently in game
if i'm just focused on doing that and
not commentating at the same time
and like stopping every few minutes to
give you a progress update and talk
about decisions and that kind of stuff
that all takes time that adds up
uh post commentary you know exactly
what you're doing right so you know
what's gonna happen in the episode
and you can nail the commentary almost
perfectly
uh right on the first time right because
you know what's happened already what
you're trying to say and do
the downside is editing took forever
on this on this episode so i think uh
it's about the same actually
anyways you guys said to remove the
guard on the the lava farm here the
other day
and also i asked about the amplified
terrain should we
go for amplified terrain or the new
style
and uh it was a close uh
close vote i would say but i think a
slightly more of you said keep amplified
so
that is the plan for now but we might
change it in the future
anyways let's move on here so
thank you rabbit
i i forgot i had my carrots out um
something i do every update is uh
i'll say what's broken in the world
because stuff breaks every single update
right so as you know we've gotten new
caves under the world
that means a lot of my mob farms have
been affected
including our general like zombie
skeleton creeper farm here it still
works it's just way slower than it used
to be
and that means eventually
i'm probably gonna run out of like tnt
and stuff if i don't make a new one or
fix this one i probably gotta look
underground just to see how my caves
need to be lit up i might not try to
save this i'm not sure yet instead i'm
kind of leaning towards like going to a
new area and setting up a creeper farm
like if we make a new base sometime
that'll be a project i would like to do
and get like a nice efficient uh source
of gunpowder this is our current stash
of like tnt and gunpowder though and
we're still getting a trickle from that
so it'll last a while i'm sure another
one of our mob farms that got hit by the
1.18 update is our guardian farm so it's
not faring
as badly as the hostile mob farm
um it's actually doing okay but it's
definitely slower than it used to be
with all the unlit caves underneath the
thing is with our hostile mob farm that
we just looked at
oh it only has maybe 500 spawning spaces
well this one has got like several
thousand with this big volume of water
right so the ratio of spawning spaces to
the unlit caves isn't as bad and it's
still working
okay uh but i definitely want to try
save this because we put a lot of work
to into making this as well as the mural
back here and i would hate for us to
like just say goodbye to this you know
so uh yeah i'm gonna go and try light up
the caves under here at some point now
there's another really bad thing about
the 1.18 update uh performance has
gotten quite a bit worse you might even
see some
loss of frame rate as i'm walking around
sandy city here so especially around the
man cave and around sandy city
it's extremely laggy in my world i think
maybe because of the map wall and just
we have a lot of stuff here right so
i've had to resort from going to 12
chunks
render distance i used to play on 17.
that seems to fix the problem but we
can't see as far um
and it's kind of a double whammy because
uh another thing that kind of broke this
update is the end reporter we had set up
now it still works everything functions
exactly the same as before
uh the difference is
you might have saw in the patch notes
they changed the way chunks load in this
1.18 it used to load in a square around
the player
and they changed it to a circle
and i had this set up in just the way
where
we would teleport to the very corner of
the square that was loaded if we had 17
chunks
rendered the more chunks we render the
further we can teleport
um
but because it's a circle now even at 17
chunks render
i can't teleport to the next station
it's unloaded right now which kind of
stinks i think i would have to go way up
like maybe even 22 wouldn't be enough
we'll see here
oh now it went
okay
anyways the end reporters need some work
now because of that i'll probably have
to have an in-between station now
thankfully that's pretty much all the
problems i've had with the update not
too bad i just gotta go caving and
everything will be pretty much back to
normal build another end reporter
we're good as new right
um there's actually been some really
good things with this update as well so
previously if you loaded a chunk at a
certain x and z coordinate it would load
everything from the bottom of the world
right to the top of the world
uh in this update they seem to manage it
quite well they only load a certain
amount and
like right now what's our frame rate
we're getting 91 frames while recording
pretty good right
and i'm at 32 chunks loaded or rendered
so underground everything's working just
fine the man cave is above us and sandy
city where it's extremely laggy but
thankfully
if i get far enough away under the
underground here
i'm not affected by the lag up there uh
you know what i just realized i never
showed you guys the amethyst farm
aha let's check this thing out so this
is where we're sitting right now now i
said there was three of them and i got
one of them converted over
and then i got tired of working on this
thing uh so this took three or four
hours just to get one of them done i did
get started on a second one and it's
kind of funny
like i watch other people's uh let's
plays every so often right and i've
noticed like whenever somebody's working
on an amethyst farm they'll be all
excited like before they start it and
then after when they show it off they're
like
all right guys i got the amethyst farm
done
it's just this absolute dread after you
work on it for a while because this is
so so difficult and time consuming
uh and tedious and stuff but yeah this
is where we're at with the second
crystal right now and i've discovered
there's not just three here there's
actually six of these geodes
that i'm going to want to convert over
eventually not today though no no no
i've had enough
uh so with this first one though i
actually got it to work with the water
streams
uh which is kind of cool like you should
probably build these with hoppers
why is there
i missed the spot apparently
actually i should put one more there aha
let's go inside let's check this out so
you can see we got wiring all over the
top here
i found it's good to have like a mix of
like redstone dust and observers
observers are great if you need to run
the signal down somewhere
all right let's go in here
and you can see all the pistons so like
the idea is the piston will extend here
and break the crystal when it's fully
grown it'll drop it into the water and
then it all kind of gets collected
together and i divided the geode into
halves
so everything on this layer kind of gets
collected together
by the water streams
and then some of it will flow over the
side here down to the second layer
we got some more crystals up above here
you can see
and these ones get collected all
together in uh
water streams i got some more
channels hidden over there
right so no matter where the crystal
lands
in this area it should eventually end up
going down the tube here
uh-huh so that was kind of tricky to
work out
uh but it's it's working good as far as
i can tell then if we go down here this
is like a nice path that goes up to the
elevator on the outside is where we're
at right now
uh as far as how to harvest this thing
right now i just got a
redstone signal here now the crystals
grow very slowly
and it didn't look like many were ready
in there so i don't know if we're gonna
get anything actually
oh we got a few
you gotta leave it sit for like
at least an hour though i think before
you'll get many
that's cool we got a couple here
and we can use these to make the tinted
glass and
like if it's a full harvest i'm sure
we'll get at least the stack but uh yeah
it wasn't ready now the cool thing is
because i've been spending so much time
working on this farm right the tree farm
was able to run for quite a few hours uh
but i ran out of boatmeal so it's kind
of shut down for now i gotta go get more
but we got uh
a couple of shulkers of oak wood and
like several stacks of rooted dirt at
this point so we got to we got the
rooted dirt if we ever want to build
with it now which is awesome now i just
moved the beacon down here got that set
up and i'm going to be mining out a bit
of land so there was an awesome
suggestion in the comments of last
episode
sorry i can't give you credit i can't
find your comment again
if only if only google had a search
option for the comments maybe there is
one i just don't know where it is but uh
that would be lovely
uh but yeah someone suggested
set up a terraria
like music in this area because we're
trying to do terraria themed
right i thought that was a great idea so
my plan is to
uh whenever we harvest the crystals
we'll play a little terraria jungle
noteblock tune i think would be cool so
i'm working on setting that up now so i
i've been experimenting as well with the
whole mosque to get rid of deep slate
you do need to mine out the top layer
here
right and then if you have uh some moss
and bonemeal
you can speed up the the layers below
that but you do need you do need to
remove at least one layer it won't grow
sideways it only grows downward
so then we can just do that
and then it's so much faster to remove
the the next layers
and get rid of that and then if you want
you can spread it again
so that's pretty cool that helps a lot
okay so it's a little bit tight down
here but we got a little bit of space to
get started i tried to
center that end and that and between the
three geodes up above and then if we
need more space cleared out we're going
to go this way is my plan
and we're going to get started in the
very corner here now a lot of people a
lot of you guys want me to explain
how i do the note block thing in this
game right what's my secret am i a
musical genius
yes no i'm not no i'm i really wish i
was though
i i know a couple things i've been
trying to learn a few things but i'm
still very much a nervous okay uh which
is good news for you because if you
don't understand how i do this i'm here
to tell you it's really easy to
turn songs into notebox in the game okay
so
if i can do it you can do it trust me
now if i right click this one two three
four five six seven
that's a c sharp how do i know that's a
c sharp
because i'm a musical genius no it's
because i i looked at the the minecraft
wiki if you go under notebox there's
this awesome reference picture there of
a piano and it'll show you how many
clicks each
of the the keys on the piano relates to
the note blocks okay
now the other thing about
notebox in minecraft they're very
limited on their range it only covers
two octaves
and then it gets it starts over
so that's 24 notes
12 notes per octave what is an octave
okay so we click this note block seven
times and it's a c sharp
and then i copied that over here
it's also the same
all right so to go up an octave is the
same as uh right clicking this 12 times
so it runs through all the notes
basically so is it c sharp right now
let's do that so if we add one
it's a d
d sharp e f f sharp g g sharp a
a sharp b
c
c sharp all right so that's our twelfth
time now when we compare them
it kind of sounds similar right they're
both c sharps but this one's one octave
higher an octave is when you double the
frequency when you go up an octave
you're doubling the frequency if you're
going down an octave you're cutting the
frequency in half so our brain kind of
interprets it
as the same note
even though it's a higher pitch but it
has similar characteristics right
yeah so if i'm understanding things
right
if you go up an octave
you're doubling the frequency of a sound
wave
right
so you have twice as many waves hitting
you but half of the time they're lining
up perfectly
with the octave below that so that's why
they sound similar to you right they're
lining up actually while if you shift
the notes over
by just a few then they're not going to
line up and that's why different notes
sound different
does that make sense i hope i hope i
said that right
so that's useful to know about the
octaves because if you see someone
playing a piano or whatever you have
notes on someone uh tabs of a piano or
whatever you search online for that and
you want the song
but it looks like it's an octave or two
over or three or four you are allowed to
shift octaves like add 12 notes or 24 or
36 or whatever
okay or subtract
uh the other thing that i found very
confusing about music is the whole flat
and sharp system
uh so basically a flat you minus one on
a notes a sharp u plus one okay so let's
say you have a c
six right clicks on the note block right
a c flat you minus one
so it's only five
uh right clicks or if you have a c sharp
as we saw before plus one
it's a seven now where this gets
confusing is sometimes you'll be reading
notes and you'll have a b okay that's
five that makes sense you minus one for
a flat
as a four right clicks on the note block
wait a minute a b sharp is a six then
and a c is a six
what's the deal here
why don't they just write it as one
thing yeah i'm just gonna assume
somebody in the comments is gonna
explain this way better than i ever
could why
they don't just use
one letter to represent the same thing
right
i think the idea is it's helpful to
stick to the letter in use in a song
because it shows how
that note relates to the other notes in
the songs
better
and also anticipates as a reading that
notes what's coming next in the song
if i understand that right it's a
over a 100 year old system i'm sure
there's reason to it
okay anyways
uh moving on something i forgot to
mention about the octaves like let's say
you go online and you search how to play
so and so song on piano you'll probably
see someone playing
it on piano right
and they'll be playing on the left side
of the piano probably in the right side
and that covers like a huge octave range
six or seven octaves we only have two
what do we do
right
so the general rule is um
use other instruments if you need
different octave ranges so for the left
side of the piano usually i'll use the
planks
the bass
so it's got a lower
[Music]
sound to it right
so i usually use that to represent the
left side of the piano
and for the right side you just use the
piano
or if you need to go a higher octave
there's uh
like chimes you could try out or if you
need something between bass and piano
you can go for guitar ah that all being
said the super chitty method which i'm
going to use for this terraria song is
to just download noteblock studio
it's a program for minecraft
it lets you load in a midi file so you
can download a midi file for a song
and then it'll transform that song
uh
into the minecraft notes
and it shows you how many clicks and
everything it's super amazing okay so i
gotta load up on my other monitor right
now i'm gonna play the terraria song i
found the midi four
[Music]
so the problem with just using noteblock
studio though is a lot of songs just
turn into a garbled mess like that too
so
yeah it's not it's not a perfect answer
either so you kind of have to blend
methods sometimes like reading notes off
of a site or
finding tabs listening by ear and trying
to match notes yeah there's definitely a
bunch of different methods and tricks to
converting songs into minecraft can't go
over all of them here but just try start
with something simple and you'll figure
things out as you you do things
the other thing i haven't really talked
about yet is tempo
honestly you're kind of on your own
there
for my old hermitcraft videos i cheated
and like would speed up the tempo and
editing or slow it down
if i ever had to do it in game i would
try to pick a song that had
a good matching tempo um
sometimes you get lucky and it you can
just do it with repeaters sometimes you
might need to use like minecart tracks
and detector rails or walking over
pressure plates
things that have like in-between timings
to repeaters
um yeah
i think for this one though so usually
what i'll do is i'll do a little sample
of the song
way too slow right so that's good
because i don't really want this timing
i think i can get away with just the
sort of the defaults
where the minimum
note timing is just one tick on the
repeater that's kind of what you want
okay so
i think this one's supposed to be at
five
so it's a little bit faster than like
what we heard in noteblock studio
but i think it's close enough that we
can get away with it okay having a
little bit of trouble with this one it
turns out uh it's okay
[Music]
um some of the timings are actually off
i realized and now it's all built and if
i want to change it i have to like start
over so that's one thing you got to
really watch out for
uh the other thing is
and if i try to change it i'm gonna have
to deal with the repeater timings not
matching up too well
and go with a different method and i
don't really want to do that so
sometimes you just have to accept
imperfection
now the other thing is sometimes
instruments can be overpowering and i've
noticed
i had more bass in here right
like according to what noteblock studio
said it's almost a little bit uh
[Music]
too much
i don't know if i made a mistake or
what's going on there but it sounds
really weird
[Music]
okay i forgot to put a plank under one
of the note blocks
this is supposed to be bass but it's
piano so that really throws off the
sound of the song and on that note you
definitely want to try play your songs
many times as you're building them
because it's very easy to make a mistake
and then
if you miss that mistake it's very hard
to correct it later
and uh actually you know what i don't
think we're gonna change anything else
on this i think that's good for what we
wanted to do here we just want a little
tune to play when we harvest the
amethyst crystals right i think that's a
good length to it now we could we could
make it more fancy and add the clicks
and snares like we heard in the notebox
studio
you know it's an option
uh the thing about these if you ever do
them obviously it adds a lot of work to
making a song
but i learned one of the tricks is you
don't want these with your other note
blocks they're very overpowering it's a
very sharp harsh sound
you want that quiet if you ever use it
so you want these farther away than your
other note blocks so that they get uh
dimmed down a bit all right everybody
well i don't know how you did it but
somehow you made it to the end of the
episode with me again here those of you
still here
all right let's do the comment of the
day what do we got for today where's my
oh i gotta look at my f f1 oh i took it
off my hot bar no wonder i can't find it
okay here we go comment of the day
any plans to bring back tara from a
craft oh this is a question i've been
getting a lot
uh no i i hate to say it guys
terraformer craft is over
it's gone no more season three is over
yeah there probably won't be a season
four either i hate to say it unless the
mod gets updated i've heard rumor
that people are working on it that would
be awesome i would like to see or i'd
like to see more changes to it in the
future
uh but we've done three seasons on it if
it doesn't change i probably won't play
another one because honestly
it's probably
the toughest three seasons of any series
i've ever done terraformer craft is
extremely difficult to make youtube
content on um just by the nature of like
how it works like in minecraft i can
build a structure and be like oh check
out my structure guys
in terrafirmacraft it's like
all right guys i'm making milk and it
takes about the same amount of time
and it's like isn't this milk amazing
and uh it's hard to get people to think
yes yes etho that milk is amazing that
you just made i know it took you 12
hours to make it
uh-huh okay so what happened to the end
of terra farmercraft why was there no
proper ending let's talk about that so
it's very difficult to make endings in
minecraft series
uh just by the nature of the game it's a
sandbox game with no real proper ending
um
except for the dragon fight
right
but generally most series don't have an
ending like that so
what do you do well if it's a longer
series like a let's play like maybe
hermitcraft or my let's play here
if you were to ever end it it's easy
because you've done a lot of stuff in
the world you can just do like a world
tour check out what we did in the series
as like a final wrap-up right so that's
not too difficult with something like
terra firma craft though where you don't
build anything
how do you do a final episode hmm
well my idea was to finish up the quest
book i was kind of done with the pack it
was like okay let's finish up the quest
book it'll give us a nice satisfying
wrap up to the whole thing right i was
kind of done with it at that point
uh and then as i was doing the quests in
the quest book to try finish it they
were just kind of dragging on
and
also
i discovered some of them were broken
and then at the final episode i still
had plans to keep playing it but then i
played three hours to get ready for the
next episode
and i discovered like every single quest
in the quest book was broken not just
like a few of them every single one so i
would have to spawn in
a bajillion items to wrap up the series
and it's like the idea is to get a
satisfying ending spawning in items not
really satisfying so
my plan to end the series kind of fell
through and it's like okay well i don't
feel like playing this anymore
uh because it's all broken so
it just kind of ended
so hopefully that gives some closure on
it at the very least for anybody
wondering all right everybody well
that's it for today hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching until the next one
take care
bye bye