let no everyone welcome back
this is etho and it seems a lot of you
liked last episode so I'm happy about
that today I think I'm going to focus a
little bit more so on resource gathering
I don't know if I want to film it but
that's what I'm doing right now I'm
going to start a new sand mine thing
here the last one I was working on is
pretty much empty and I could there is
more desert around there but it's I
really shouldn't have been digging
around there because it's nearer that
cave I should I picked the spot now
that's a little bit further away so I
can scar the landscape without worrying
as much about about the beauty of the
surrounding area and there's lots of
sand around here so it should last me
hopefully forever so this is my new a
new sand line starting right here and
I'll probably cut out that direction
well it didn't take me too long and I
already got a huge chunk cut out of the
land got quite a bit of stuff from it
just have a chest here I've been filling
so that's what I got from cutting that
out and yes I do know you can make
sandstone from sand a lot of people have
been commenting on that so should last
me a while again I got one two three so
hard to tell the difference between
sandstone and sand well there's another
one oh yeah there's quite a bit like all
that sandstone for that that's pretty
good
and I may convert some of this to it I
don't like doing it because it's a
little bit wasteful but at the same time
I don't have gunpowder to make TNT
anyway so there's nothing else I'd
really use it for except glass
so with that sandstone is able to finish
another section of the tree farm and
we'll probably go through that at the
end of the episode but right now I think
I may go do some caving gets more ironed
so I'm very very very little on iron and
I might try to put the other montage of
it so I think I'm going to go caving in
that new area has shown you a few
episodes ago around that area I want to
try light up the Chiefs there
how did you get down here
gosh
almost snuck up on me man that must be
my sand quarry oh hey
five gunpowder days
so my stand for yes oh we got a chest
here nice very nice and then chest over
here nice Oh
well how'd you find me
stockers oh I see there's a responder up
here found it I'm just too overpowers
with this gear all right reet out we got
a dungeon awesome
skeleton done it yep
Oh what is this double time no I was a
double yep I am invincible weird cool
cocoa beans I will leave that to leave
these don't need those are those
Oh deserts Oh what's this awesome
it's another dungeon here sweet there's
one right below here like 30 blocks down
and then there's one over here so
excited a lot of mobs around awesome
zombie that day this is a dungeon very
strange there we go is it a double date
this is an amazing kind if it's a double
skeletons ok there's there's a scalp and
smaller this is pretty sweet
what's with this cobble over here except
from the s is the wall nice Lots iron in
there sweet what do we got here oh we
got a record cool cats or bread
gunpowder no it's by the village okay
and there's a there's my sand pits
there's another dungeon over there and
another one over there alright I'm back
from teaming and it it went good we got
just about three stacks of iron from it
got a record we found 2 dungeons plus
chief spider spawner and just a whole
bunch of good supplies so on all pretty
happy with it and this sword is so
overpowered it's crazy not to mention
this pic but the sword lovin the sword
so the other day I did move this
mushroom farm it's still working still
very very slow but it's one of the first
projects we did so I want to keep it
around and today as thinking just for a
starter project here maybe we'll try to
clean up this area a little bit this is
the the potion room storage room this is
what we're all the ingredients are
stored so I think I'm going to try
convert this into more of a room instead
of being like open on the sides here the
cave system next to it I want to convert
it more to an actual room with a door
and an exterior and all that so for the
door I think I'm going to put its like
over here doesn't doesn't do matter
where it goes because no matter where it
is I'll have to still jump around over
the water streams and stuff to get
around in here so main thing is that it
looks good on the outside and we have
wire over here so I don't exactly want
to Center the door on the center of the
room because the wires in the way so I
think what I'll do we'll try extend this
path so I try to keep it symmetrical
ish and still conform with the terrain
that's so one of the goals I have with
this whole cave area that it kind of
goes with the terrain so places where it
goes up like this is where our place is
that
to naturally went up even though I might
have smoothed it out a little bit more
and same with here this is a place where
it went down a bit so over here I'm
going to make it go up probably won't be
quite as steep but just to keep this the
natural shape more so and I was thinking
I might do like a 3x3 grass area here I
kind of looked this over before I
started this and it seems we can have a
cool effect here so have a 3x3 there
that gives us one two three this will be
the fourth block this would be the fifth
so if the fourth block is where we need
it centered so I think I'm just going to
put some wood here like that and some
more stairs like so and then we can
probably do another 3x3 thing here and I
think that will work out good for going
up to the door
I hope cardioid till this cave is like
all done it's gonna look gonna look
pretty cool I like these grass walkways
it really makes it feel like it's not a
cave and the thing I really like about
the cave is I don't have to worry about
what time of day it is
doesn't matter if it's day or night the
lighting is always the same which is
kind of cool that was a huge problem
when I used to record I would always
it'd be like a minute before sunset and
it's like I would have to wait that
minute out before I started recording it
was really annoying that kind of thing
doesn't bother you when you play
normally but when you're recording
it becomes an issue okay and I'm going
to make this go up I guess because it
goes up naturally and I don't know if
I'm going to do another 3x3 it might
look really checkered t if I do that I
go up one two three blocks yet shouldn't
maybe did a staircase that start to say
I don't want it to be going up when it
comes to the door I want it to be flat
ground at the top here okay and the
doors probably not be over like over
here whoop this pitch is too good this
is try to points in a dug to block so
yeah the door probably shouldn't be here
because the wires will probably get in
the way here so I'm going to move it
maybe over here or over here just back a
little bit and there should be at least
three blocks of flat space so I'm going
to tinker with it a bit off-camera and
we'll see how it goes
oops so the way I've been doing this
incline is not going to work its way too
gradual it's about two blocks to low
where I would like it to be when it gets
the end and it doesn't look all that
great so I will be adjusting this and I
was using stairs before I should be
using half slabs the nice nice thing
about using half slabs is you can sprint
up it without your sprint failing on you
but if you use a stair which is kind of
the reason why trying to avoid a steep
staircase or something is because you
can't run over it without your sprint
stopping so I'll try something else here
so I changed this up again and I'm
lighting this a lot more let me know
your opinion no it's a gradual staircase
you can run up it without your sprint
giving out and then it there's a break
in it over here this will be grass and
you have the other section over here the
door will be somewhere over here I'm
guessing so when you get to the top you
have a nice view of it it's not like
it's right in your face when you get up
like like if it was right over here that
would that would kind of suck so I think
that'll work out okay um let me know
what you think oh I've been getting
terrible frame rates today I don't know
why I should do a reboot probably anyway
I'll also probably rip this wall out so
we can have it more open in here and if
I do that we'll kind of have like a nice
upper section over where I'm standing
that kind of does a half circle or a
quarter circle shape which is cool might
be able to do something nice with that
and I'll probably do wood on the sides
like I did with other stairs
these are spaced a little differently
though so it's not going to be exactly
the same actually you know what I would
maybe like to do here is a wooden pillar
with lighting in the middle maybe a 3x3
wood pillar to help get some light on
the stairs because it's really hard to
light these stairs without unless I do a
chandelier above or something
so I'm type of light lighting above
let's just see how this goes
I thought I saw fire it's as a torch
the J do like a wooden pillar
type thing oh yes
cheap mints I've been trying to get that
one for so long okay I might put a light
over here like on top the soil and then
maybe another one directly above and
have this or maybe I should have that I
should probably have the light a little
higher like up here and up here
perhaps I'm tempted to try uh pour lava
in the middle this actually to be honest
I don't know I think it would work I
should test it and creative before I do
that though if if lava works the same as
fire or similar to it that would work so
maybe I'll try that out and see how it
goes but regardless this is kind of like
what the pillar would look like maybe
it's a little too big mmm
okay so putting lava in that pillar does
work without it catching on fire if you
do it right but the thing is it's it's
really bulky I didn't really like it so
I took it out I tried putting the rails
on the stairs to see what it would look
like you know I'm not sure how I feel
about it it's almost a little bit too
jagged so I may have to do something
with half slabs like a block type that
has half slabs so not a whole lot of
choices with that maybe I did grab some
fences to see how it would look if we
did like we did before on other stairs
OOP something like that ah missing like
crazy today
it's amazing how much defenses add to it
actually I'm liking that a lot more now
but I'll let you guys comment on it tell
me what you think as far as let's go so
for the door here I'll probably do a 3x3
piston door like I have at the potion
room
actually let's head down there real
quick so the way the potion door works
is it does a spiral I do really like it
with the block missing in the middle I
don't know why like I prefer it over a
solid 3 3x3 door for some reason this
one OOP it does the spiral closes like
that just kind of cool with this new one
I'm going to do I think I'll and then
change the pattern and make it so the
middle block here the lower middle one
and the upper middle one go up and down
and then the four corners go in with a
little bit of a delay from the middle
ones and then finally the two side ones
will go in I think that I'll have a cool
effect so I'll go with this one then
these two and then the side that's the
plan I don't know if I'll make it out of
iron and nether brick like I have here I
might try make this area a different
style than what I have over here I might
I might move away from the stone bricks
in this area and no more sandstone and
maybe more would look more leaves I kind
of think more of a warmer feeling to it
than I have over here's is more cold in
my opinion I don't anyway I think this
episode is actually going to be pretty
long after I edit that month
how long that will be but I recorded
over an hour of me gaming so it might be
long so we will wrap it up here I did
want to go to the tree farm before we
end this actually I got a plant two
trees yet too so we cut here and then we
will look at the new donors there we go
we got a whole bunch of new trees here
each tree represents a donor so kind of
a way of giving thanks to them having
them in my world somehow so let's go
through the signs it and looked at
everybody's names again I am very
appreciative of everybody that's donated
I am putting the money to good use I
recently got a new hard drive actually a
two terabyte one two because I ran out
of space on my other one from my videos
there you're actually taking a lot of
space so I am able to backup my LP
episodes and my tutorials and everything
now on the new hard drive which is good
just in case I accidentally have a
problem or something with my channel
believe it or not I actually almost one
time I almost deleted like a hundred of
my videos it was pretty scary and it's
made me think twice about having backups
I was editing a playlist one time for my
LPS and didn't really pay attention to
see if I was editing the playlist still
or if I was just in my main video
manager area so playlists didn't turn
out like I thought it did so I selected
all the videos and hit delete and the
Box came up are you sure and I said yes
and as just as I pressed it is like oh
man I did not check if it's the playlist
I'm editing or if it's all my videos so
lucky for me it was the playlist I was
still editing otherwise I would have
deleted 100 videos and that's actually a
pretty common occurrence among youtubers
believe it or not so
good to have backups so very much
appreciative thank you everybody for the
donations again don't feel compelled
like you have to donate I do really
appreciate the money but especially the
token of generosity the act I really
appreciate the act shows that you really
enjoy the channel and the videos and
everything so thank you but if your kid
don't feel like you have to donate I
don't want to take money from kids just
feels wrong okay but if you have a good
paying job or something then then I
don't mind so much okay I will see you
guys again next time and hopefully we'll
get some actual building done we didn't
do a whole lot today but next time next
time okay see you guys okay I also
forgot to mention something important
there's like another 30 or 40 names I
need to add to the tree farm
the most recent donations so if you
didn't see your name there that's
because I haven't added the newer ones
yet I don't know where I'm putting them
yet so when I figure that out then I'll
add the new names so there's at least 30
so just be patient okay