hello
oh man let's try that again
so hello everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys to another episode
haha oh man
this is unbelievable i have a sign in my
inventory
what a coincidence you know what we
should do
we should take this sign and write
something on it
yes that sounds like a fantastic idea
let's
uh let's write something that will make
us smile
how about uh go
get it no no no not that no
yeah you are yeah okay there we go yeah
there we go perfect it says
go get your snacks ah yes what a
wonderful message
perfectly normal sign nothing strange
whatsoever about it you'd have to be
crazy if you thought it said something
else
yes okay let's change the subject
quickly
so today guys you know we did that dream
sequence thing last
episode and that was a lot of fun uh
when i was
in the old world there i was thinking
about doing a tour and like if i should
do it in that video or not
and i decided maybe we will do it today
because
about six months ago uh
we did that alpha and b and beta
episodes remember those
where we toured my older worlds but we
never made it out to chocolate island
world uh which is what most of you guys
wanted to see and i said that we would
do it later so
it's later let's go visit chocolate
island
shall we i'll see you there
all right guys so here we go
we are going to be doing a bit of a
world tour
today a nostalgic tour oh started
already
old gravel what do you guys think of the
new gravel like now that now that we've
gotten
used to it do you miss the old stuff or
do you think the new stuff is better
i think i like the new stuff more to be
honest the old gravel was pretty bad
oh so yeah we're gonna look around the
world here
there's a zombie over there um
i've downgraded to version 1.73
beta 1.73 so things are going to look
quite a bit
different even the lava is different in
the past
i liked it more now it's like cheese
whiz lava
um you know i thought we did a tour of
this back in episode 200 and i just
checked it out but that was like a
montage type of deal
so i i don't know if we have ever
actually toured the old world
since we started the new one and
if you're unfamiliar with my series
basically an episode
or episodes one to a hundred we spent in
this world here and then
the adventure update came out 1.8 and
we moved to a new world because
everything here pretty much broke
and now we're in this stupid new world i
miss the old one no
i like the new world this one was really
cool too though i did like this world a
lot
before it broke um this here this is
cool this was a mod made for me
by ibel it's called the g all nether mod
it allows seamless transitions from the
nether to
the overworld you can actually see
through
the portal the nether and stuff it's
pretty cool
but yeah it's been a long time since i
was last here and since i've
played beta again even so this should be
fun
trying to relive things let's see what
should we do first let's snoop
i like snooping uh we gotta find some
tools here
do you hear that splashing i hear
splashing no chest noises oh here we go
let's take a pic let's take some blocks
uh that is the new cobblestone texture
so this was
there used to be an old texture that had
like black lines in it it was pretty bad
should we take a sign now we've had
enough crazy signs for today
what is that sound is that uh
where is that coming from is it down
here
oh man okay
what i am already confused i thought we
shut this thing down
didn't we or wait a minute this was
i think this was the first mob system i
built right
then we must have made a second one and
shut that one down
and then we made a third one
and then a fourth one a pretty big part
of my series used to be mob systems
trying to figure out how to
make them and stuff uh
yeah back in the day like
even simple things that we take for
granted like
uh it was common in old mob systems just
to have like a pressure
plate between the water streams or
something like that it wasn't until i
built this that i got the idea of hey
you know what you can do a sign trick
like this and then the water will just
flows over top and
and it's seamless because before the
mobs would like
step on the pressure plates and then you
would have to wait for them to cross
over to the
the next stream and it took a really
long time
and then i think later even at this time
the the trick with
stopping spiders from spawning wasn't
known i don't think it
i think i figured that out later
hey guy be nice
oh man
he's pretty nice signs signs galore
that did like no damage oh yeah and the
first mob evader here
yeah this was uh when i was trying to
figure out how to move mobs upward
without getting stuck
did i never i must not have shut that
down either
because all right now i'm lost
this is a bit of a tour for me too like
we're gonna be looking at stuff
and i anything that grabs my attention
basically
here let's take the what did we call
this
the minecart thing yeah let's take this
up
oh no minecart sounds so nice
oh man i like the minecart sounds now
they're just a little loud usually
oh yeah the tornado that's what we
called it the tornado comes up
to the surface underneath the clay which
is
all still here by the way it's amazing
it's never seems to disappear
as is the iron all right yeah so we have
the drop down to there
to the nether and then
this must be the mob system look at that
i thought
i thought i filled that in i guess not
so this is where the intro to my videos
takes place
i love that creeper face so cool
uh that's what we mimicked last episode
and
this is where i spent most of the time
in the series on this island here
it was kind of cool used to be like an
island covered in grass and then
later i removed all the grass
yeah you see it's all dirt there and
then
i built a passive mob system up there i
think that's what's running right now
actually yeah look at this
i think uh what was the point of this i
think this was my
barn right wasn't i trying to get wolves
in there or something i can't remember
even let's go check it out
or no somehow i kind of remember these
being
oh what okay
can you place block some buttons i guess
you can right
no microsoft i just found a glitch
you better fix it okay
yeah i don't know what those are for i
think they had something to do with
wolves
let's go up here i built this and
i think i was gonna tear it down or
something because i didn't like it
oh man oh yeah you can't get uh oh a
brown sheep
they're rare you can't get uh
food from towels can you just leather it
wasn't until later that you could get
steak
oh it gets dark like right away
there's no smooth transition just like
dark darker darker all all at once there
um yeah so the basic mob firm was there
then i built some pipes to bring the
the sheep and the cows over here
that squid has been up there for a very
long time voice crack
what's up with this guy did they not uh
suffocate
oh yeah that's right they didn't
suffocate for a long time
in the game i forgot about that
they used to like wash up onto the
ground and then they would get stuck
like that
i think
okay oh
there's this switch here what does this
do
opens all the doors i guess
yeah looks like it was there another one
on this side for the
the middle yeah
okay this was like drop the mobs in the
middle and then this was supposed to
open up and fry them
i think anyway we spent a lot of time
here let's go
inside the building try to find a bed
um used to be water here i don't know
why i removed it
like i put up another another rack wall
here and start removing it
who knows young etho was pretty crazy
not new etho not at all
um yeah no pistons for the longest time
so most the doors were actual double
doors
zombies didn't break uh doors down
either so you didn't have to worry about
that stuff just took up a full block
this is my how i did my storage in the
floor
yeah oh okay there we go some of these
actually have stuff in
oh the dispensers look different too
look at this they got like the angry
face
uh oh here comes my cart
oh this is awesome this was to get
around the the
storage room quicker so
like long long time ago i was dreaming
of doing something like the nexus even i
wanted to
have dispensers that would automatically
shoot items out
never was really able to do that i i
discovered later
redstone was not quite that advanced
back then
but i dreamed i did dream i can't get
out of here
right click right click okay um
but i had a display item for each of the
things in the storage room
leather oh this is the mob drops that's
right
here let me let me try to find a bed
we'll skip the
night here the rain
oh man for everybody that says i
never get anything done or that i used
to be more productive i will point out
one thing to you
this this main room that we're standing
in right now
took me i think 50 episodes to build
uh-huh i was not very productive
in the past i can tell you that for sure
so if you if i it takes me forever to
finish something in my
my world i have actually improved
believe it or not
there's no bed here guys there's no bed
skeletons strafing to the left i miss
that actually
um i thought i had my house here
remember my little house
must have tore it down at some point
well where did i sleep
oh man oh where do we pick up cactus
from the cactus farm some trees there
i must have had a bed somewhere right
i could not find a bed anywhere like i
have no
memory of where i used to sleep at all i
thought it was
in that house but it was gone so
who knows who knows um let's see if we
can figure this thing out this is old
mob evader
it's like the coolest part of the whole
base it's so cool like you could see the
mobs coming up
i really like this idea of having a mob
system running in the middle of your
base and you can watch it and
and we had this cool zelda tune for some
reason no mobs are swimming up this so i
don't know
why we are in hard mode
did i disable it or something who knows
was this farm farm animal loot
that dropped the feather outs hostile
mob loots
it's doing something with a trap door
why wouldn't
i have this open all the time i wonder
let's see oh no zelda tuned
oh there we go oh i missed that so much
i love that tune
i should put that in our world somewhere
what would we use it for though i wonder
i think the way this worked i had to
have items on both pressure plates yeah
then
the lights turn on and
i think when these ones would despawn
that would signal the five minute
warning
yeah they would start flashing
until you picked up the items then it
would reset
right yeah that's so cool
um let's look around some more oh come
back
no missed it
what else did we have around here let's
check our
loot did i have iron oh i had
oh yeah old iron texture even
let's look at this in the sun
i kind of like that actually it was a
little smoother
than the current texture or kind of
kind of glossier i guess look more
reflective
uh up here was the baconator this was a
later thing i added to the world
used to do these water stream things i
thought they made you move quicker i
don't
know if they actually did though um
mobs from the passive mob firm would get
sorted the pigs would come this way
the sheep and the cows went to that
other spot
i believe maybe the wolves came here too
wonder what happened to the wolves
yeah no food or no uh
no hunger bar back then so you would eat
to regain health that was it
it's so weird not having sprinting
i really like sprinting i gotta say
but i did like the old
method or health system more what do you
guys think about that like
those of you that played in the past
compared to now
um i think i still like the old system
where
where the food didn't stack and then you
would use it to recover health i don't
like the hunger bar
at all really even to this day
this was something wasn't wasn't it this
was a
combo lock type of thing
oh how did it work though
i i don't remember there was a trick
both boats had to be in a certain
position to open these doors
i don't remember how it was controlled
though
hmm i think that's a t flip flop like a
boat t
flip flop uh this is the main control
room
for the mob system i don't know if we
ever hook this stuff
up though did we we got like a sep
separator thing for all the different
mob drops eggs feathers
bacons bacons not bacon
um possibly what happened is we started
that ice base
when i was trying to do this because i
didn't have enough space for
what i wanted to do here maybe
two second base delay
don't know what that's about this was
for the mine carts
there used to be a control room down
here that i tore out
where i could make the minecarts catch
fire if i wanted
or put out the flames over here was the
cactus farm and the tree farm
aha let's go up and check these out
so much faster yeah these are like just
little
weird box rooms with legs um
the tree farm worked i had like a ring
of dirt here
and i would chop down all the all the
trees they were right next to each other
look how green the the leaves look what
is this biome
oh it doesn't say or does it no i don't
see it
they seem very green though don't they
um chop down the wood and then the
leaves would despawn
drop saplings in the water all the
saplings would wash up to down here
then i put them in a chest cactus farm
much the same thing
except that is auto
shearing the cactus i guess yeah
oh yeah and there's an upstairs too
let's go check this out
it's turning nighttime again oh man
the green wall uh so
so yeah chocolate island no grass here
i wasn't able to have grass because that
would mess up the passive mob farm
so anywhere i actually wanted to have
grass i used green wool instead
this was supposed to be like an organic
area we got a bridge here
little ponds gazebo oh with the fancy
chairs
what on earth is going on there
uh i don't know why the mop system's not
working like the hostile one we'll have
to go down and check
let's see let's take a look here this
looks pretty complicated i don't know
exactly what's going on here
i think there was a this was for the
spiders i think over here
seems odd that there's only just one guy
though
oh he's not even in it
sneaky little guy um
the passive mob farm looks like it's
working really good though
like non-stop what was that yeah there's
wolves in there too that's cool
those guys were getting separated up
higher i guess
i think this was a pig and wolf
separator here if i remember right
oh no no because it's connected here i
don't know
maybe it was um
there's an upstairs to this too then
don't know how i got around is there a
ladder somewhere i'm missing
there we go yeah this is the the sorter
for the
oh we got chickens there too for the
chickens and the sheep
cows the wolves and the pigs all got
separated
cows would fall down swim up
land on a door oh yeah it's a little bit
messy looking
i think if it was a pig they would fall
down there maybe
maybe is what was going on
i don't know if the chicken's working
keeps jumping up and down
or was this to divert them a different
direction i can't remember
crazy stuff
was there a way up here let's just
pillar up to check it out
we actually have a lot to see we should
hurry i am taking a very long time here
yeah look how green the grass is what on
earth
oh man that's the color i like
why isn't it like that now i i really
like that color
um yeah they would spawn on here and
then they would all get funneled to the
middle basically
pretty cool lots of water around
um i think that's oh wait no that's not
it there's the downstairs too we never
checked out
and the mob system here let me get down
from here
oh that worked oops
you know i remembered what this thing is
it's a water
combo lock these were water sensors
you'd
pour water and that the boat would float
up off the pressure plate
uh but it doesn't seem to work i just
tried it out
but let's go check out the downstairs is
this the way down
maybe kind of yeah sure
i guess this works okay
this is the second mob system that we
we've undid
uh and we built a bunch of stuff down
here so what do we all have we have
the quick kits right oh secret projects
that's not the quick tip this is the
quick kit
how did this work no
not like that door lock there we go
pistons just came out i think that i was
having time in my life with them
um i actually need a quick kit
let's see if we can get it to work empty
totally useless come on
you push a button all the dispensers
would activate and they were supposed to
like give you armor and food and torches
and all that stuff
aha never really hooked up i guess
over here this was the suicide booth
that's right i'm scared to do it
no i don't want to die um
that was to get me between this space
and the ice base
quickly i would sleep there and then i
would like kill myself here and get
transported there item despawn timers
was to the wiring
for that zelda tune thing then what else
do we have
what is all this that's the combo lock
thing
um that was the old
yeah this was the old mine cart thing
that would set the mine carts on fire
but doesn't look like it's working
secret projects
we don't talk about uh that was like one
of my most disliked videos in the past
and that really uh made me sad
when i released that video that's why we
don't talk about it
um all right let's do this let's uh
let's try out the old eats road i guess
since we're here
this was the item loader right put the
boat in
is it still working
there's no like uh oh i used a ladder to
stop it i see
we might actually be able to use two
here
let's try that out this was supposed to
be the quick launch
system i believe the second boat would
get jammed in behind here one
it would like launch this first one a
little quicker
oh it does work look at that and like
you could walk on it and they would
never go out of place
it's pretty cool
whoa here we go
spent so long on this tunnel
uh that's the cave story tune
get off station oh no i did it wrong i
did it wrong
i'm still pressing uh shift instead of
right click oops
that's actually pretty cool i don't know
if they work like that still but i
really
like this old system with like the
the stopping and the auto launch it was
pretty cool
this was also a boat elevator
and this might be a dead end here let's
make another boat
i don't know if i built anything here i
can't remember
whoa holy smokes
i'm gonna look i think it's just like a
strip mine though
if i was to guess but i am curious oh
there's a ladder
ladder drop
okay it keeps going
let me see what's at the end here i'm
curious
i've walked about 500 blocks here
i think you're just dead ends
oh man what a troll
what a troll that was such a long walk
oh
totally worth it though
all right so there's a boat elevator
here i'm not sure how to load this thing
it's only two by two it might not work
no my boat uh-oh
that's not good let's see if we can fix
it
i think there's supposed to be a boat in
here at all times
oh this is where you load it aha
i see can i get in there
okay we're in here please take me up to
the top
nope don't do that oh it's working we're
going
we're doing it what's up here i can't
remember
probably nothing oh the boat is stuck
here that's the that's the real boat
okay right click right click uh
it's night time again let me sleep real
quick
the bed is occupied by me obviously
all right this is i believe where we
used to do our testing
a lot of testing oh look at all the mobs
man
the beautiful green grass
up here yes okay oh this is spazz's
house
i remember this oh and uh there was even
there was another mob system here and
this
is my greenhouse thing you would uh
oh man how did this work i think
what you would do oh i remember i
remember okay
i got a little bit of bone meal here
oh oh we might be surrounded
you would stand in the middle you could
uh
spam bone meal on the grass and it would
it would plant like flowers and grass up
there
then you take a water bucket
place it here and it would harvest all
the grass
and the seeds and stuff and they would
all come washing down
here
so many animals yeah you see there's
some flowers and stuff but
yeah aha still works
still works and then we found out you
could just use dark rooms to harvest
flowers and this was obsolete
like the day after i built it um
okay some more motivator testing over
here nothing too interesting out here so
let's head back
no
this thing still works guys
the spider sizzler oh i love that thing
i was doing a test here to see how far
you could drop mobs
before they would die to figure out uh
how much fall damage they could take
because
back then there was no wiki or anything
had to do research
on your own to figure that kind of stuff
out
no way man i totally forgot all about
this thing
how this worked now i know why the mobs
aren't spawning
i forgot i did all this i like
upgraded the mob system a long time ago
got all these fancy lights in here
oh yeah there was a spawner there i made
this room
here let's go check this out this was
really cool we're back at uh
at uh chocolate island by the way
oh oh door open
door open um button
no button i was not very good at
redstone
i don't know what's up with the door
huh oh there was a lock that's what it
was
aha so if these were down the door would
lock so that mobs wouldn't walk up
into here because they would like track
me through the walls
but yeah you guys remember this let's
see i think this still works
yeah that was to turn uh or to bring up
the half slabs that stops the spiders
from spawning
in here at a flip of a switch
oh and then this is the lights and since
the lights are on that's why we're not
getting any mobs
what else was there
i think this is just wiring axis and
stuff this one went up
to the light control the way i did the
lights was with lava though it was
insane so many pistons
and redstone and stuff up here
uh and then there was a was it a piston
elevator here or how do we get back up
see the lights are off mobs are spawning
let me check
yeah they are good we're getting spiders
and stuff too
quick drop this must be the way up over
here
surface elevator was it just a
oh it is a spiral one okay
wow like i totally forgot about doing
all that
my house is here that's where it is
window oh look at the window guys we can
see so much
uh yeah over there is where i did some
testing with the
sunlight detectors you guys remember
that uh
in the past i didn't use like super flat
worlds or anything like that we didn't
have creative mode
so a lot of my tutorials and stuff i did
actually in this world and that's where
i figured out the
daylight sensor trick thing thingamajig
and did the tutorial and all that
um mobs should be spawning now we are
running really low on time though so i'm
trying to hurry but i do want to see
this
yeah look at them now look how many
there are
oh wow yeah i just checked we're really
low on time here so
maybe we'll just check a few more things
that is the 360 cannon over there
and i believe is it down here yeah down
here there's a slime farm i want to
check out
then we are going to head over to the
ice base
and that will probably be about it i
think for the tour there's more stuff we
could
check out but uh nothing
too significant that i can think of i
might have missed something though i
hope i didn't
hi okay
oh there's slimes down here oh there's
creepers down here there's lots of
creepers down here
no no why so many creepers
oh it's probably super dark for you guys
i'm sorry
no repeaters glitch no
um you know what i probably should have
got
when we started was a sword or something
but oh there's that creeper in there no
no all right so that's the slime farm
we're getting out of here we are so done
we are so done i think the water they
gonna shoot me
now we're good the water pushes all the
mobs to corner though
uh there's a whole line of pistons there
all right to the the ice base
can we get there through the nether
maybe we will try that too
yeah so let's go through the nether and
see if there's a portal
we can take through there this i believe
calls the cart down from the top
so it's always wherever we are right
maybe eventually there we go
it does it all right
so let's go check out the nether i know
we have a 360 cannon in the nether
for sure oh goody well we're stuck
gg um a little safe house here
what else oh i see a path
is that what we need to take there's
also a lower path i think
it's so dark
what is this path here
man there's a way down
let's take some boats we might need them
here let's turn these these fools down
too because they're really annoying
does this go to this tunnel
no you know i remember
hmm i started making it like a
zombie pigmen farm
towards the end of the season that's the
360 cannon up there
let's see where this goes i think i was
an idiot in the past
another like just random dead end okay
oh this is where i started slabbing the
place i see
that must have been what i was doing
here just this is where i was gonna do
the zombie pigmen farm
okay so nothing really here then
uh we must have to go into the nether
ceiling then to get to
the portal maybe we'll try that out
okay so i went up to the ceiling this
was a boat drop
to get down possibly at this time
there's no fall damage if you're in a
boat oh
old school booster no way i thought
these were done for
they still work i guess there's no power
rails right
oh we gotta try this out i like me some
old school boosters
it looks like it's all messed up though
this was something doc invented i
believe this
how did this work there's that pressure
plate under this
this is on a pressure plate as well oh
this calls the carts
that's right you you sit on this one
then you hop to this one
that opens the door in there
but the stuff is not in the right place
i don't think here let's
try this is this gonna work oh you know
i
i think i remember i think i remember
this goes here and then you put the
other one
next to it to start it right
beautiful yeah it definitely seems kind
of broken here i got it to work once so
there we go yay
i think at this point of time though in
the game it's kind of broken for
whatever reason
and then it goes here there's another
one to send you back
i really miss this kind of minecart
stuff like that that was some really fun
stuff uh
then this goes down is this just to the
cannon
i may not have i may not have had a
portal to the ice base
i think this just goes to the cannon
right yeah
huh you know back then i didn't know how
portals worked and i might have been
afraid to
try use them
this thing was pretty cool too
man tnt is there any here no
the wiring on this thing was pretty fun
to figure out
and it exploded many times how do you
get down
the variable timer on it let's just go
down like this
oh i think a gas shot at it
ah no no tnt here that's too bad
okay i had a lot of trouble finding this
place so i just reloaded the backup
i have and this is how it starts
woohoo let's let's try to figure out how
to get out of here without dying
oh i i left myself a water budget very
nice
see i wasn't so bad guys even on the
latest download there's a way
around it you just gotta go peaceful
mode
um i i've seen a few people complain
about
about the surprise in the latest
download
so yeah this is the ice base guys this
was my attempt at making the perfect
mob system base or whatever
and it is actually working pretty good
but then what happened is enderman came
out and when enderman first came out
they could move cobblestone
and every single type of block so they
just destroyed
any mob system pretty much thinks except
for maybe
furnaces i think that was the trick
around it
oh man that's so cool
that was like my goal the whole time
get as much gun powder as possible
and i finally made a mob system that was
like unbelievable
amounts of gunpowder oh we're gonna die
and then like a week or two later
the 1.8 update came out it's like no
i finally did it i finally have a good
mob system
we also have a passive mob system here
this one
automatically sorts the the mobs
um we can sort chickens
pigs pigs are getting auto roasted right
now
cows and i guess sheep are falling down
there yeah sheep too
wolves i think there was an issue where
wolves didn't spawn here or something
stupid though
if i remember right the rest of these
were supposed to be for the hostile mobs
but i never got around to that
um oh yeah look at all that food
um didn't get too far with this base
this this all does fancy stuff so i
think this one
yeah if you just want to kill the mobs
they'll fall right into lava if you do
that or if you want to
incinerate the items
this was if you want to let them out and
that was the crusher
what did this one do that was water
okay
and i think this is the lava one so
there is a control for all those
different things on each of these
and
should we go up let's go up really quick
i don't want to spend too long here
there was also a slime farm here too i
remember but
i don't know how to get to it i don't
think it was anything too impressive
though
chickens are just getting auto killed
there i guess
let's see pig falls down
then this was the the pigs order
sheep go straight
uh-huh man i think
i think i added a way of sorting squid
too
maybe i don't know but that is the the
ice base
this was just like uh i just want to
check this out too real quick
yeah this was the passive mob farm
diamond shaped
spawning pads and
oh i did controls for two oh wow
this goes up higher than i thought i
think there was a way to disable this
too
there was like lava that flowed down all
the way through all the
the spawning pads and could shut this
one off
that lets water out okay
and then it flows over all the pads and
you can shut the pads off doing that
and the light was close enough that the
grass wouldn't
die i believe
anyway that's the ice base we're gonna
do one more thing
one last thing really quick to end our
tour
that's right everybody we gotta do the
fireworks before we end this
it's tradition right um these were not
loaded for some reason
i thought i left them loaded in my
backup but i had to manually load them
with tnt
i'm sorry whoever had the netherrack
cannon over there it blew up and that
one was missing for some reason
so i don't know what's up with that uh
i didn't load this one either but here
we go
before fireworks were a thing we
we did this little project here this was
not a little project
i think it's broken no
why don't they work
i wonder what's up with that um wiring
must have got blown up
right
oh man we can manually trigger them
that's not as cool though
oh possibly
this doesn't work in 173 this might have
been
for an earlier version
i think at this point tnt lost the
ability
to get launched i think
yeah all right no fireworks i'm sorry
guys
i'm sorry hmm we'll use
whoa hit the mouse will you guys settle
for other
types of fireworks maybe let's do it
let's do it all right comment time
got one really quick one picked out for
a really long episode
says etho you are a terrible actor
bum bum no offense though i love you
yeah acting is not really my specialty
i i think i make it pretty clear when
i'm acting
and uh yeah i'm fine with that
no no offense taken ah
did you believe me did you believe me oh
come on
i got right into character there as like
a bad actor
obviously i'm an excellent actor and i
just proved it right there
you totally thought that i thought i was
a bad actor
brilliant okay thank you for watching
guys i'll see you again
in the next episode
take care have a good day bye