hello while you ask some people how are
you doing today I'm doing well it's
still working on the potion room it's
coming along I've been working on the
dispenser area so I set up some ladders
here just to get up here for now and oh
hello there's there's a cave up to the
surface yeah so I cleared out some space
to set up our dispensers to hold our
twelve items or whatever twelve
different items so I got a hook all
these buttons over here
you know there's twelve buttons we got
to hook those up to twelve different
groups of dispensers up here so it'll go
something like this we'll have a water
stream here actually fit pretty nice
I'll go there to the center so if any
item falls in these streams they'll go
to the center like so then I'll have um
still design what to do about the
dispensers as thinking originally that I
have ten for each group oops like this
there are better ways I could position
these that would take less space but I'm
worried patches might change way like
items going through blocks works like
otherwise I would just put put them like
this like right next to each other and
they'll items will fall down through the
block but I'm going to keep it like this
for safety yeah so ten per ingredients
I was thinking I could do five per
ingredient and then just send two pulses
but really that would make things a lot
more complicated and this is just not a
bad way of doing it so I'm going to try
run wire along the top of these
dispensers if that eventually gets
patched I should be able to do it in a
way that will work still so if you don't
know this you can place wire on
dispensers if you place it next to a
block buy it like this otherwise if you
right-click on a dispenser or you just
you just look at it so I think that
would do the trick here maybe we'll try
it out sounds like it let's test it
split this up so in total there is going
to be oh I don't know over a hundred of
these dispensers it they'll be good
because I'll use them for storage as
well like I got so many spider eyes I
wouldn't mind having a place to keep
them yep dispensed five that's what we
want perfect
the wires will connect over here
probably like this and then there'll be
another water stream right here go off
to here with fence gates hold the water
in place so give me one second and I
will rig it rigged that all up here all
right guys I got this finished now you
got our ingredient dispenser arrays all
set up here with water streams with the
Redstone groupings in total there's 100
dispensers here and ten groups but we
need 12 groups total so I'll either have
to split these up a little bit to do
some fancier wiring like to send more
than one pulse so so like we need 10
ingredients to come out but we could
like just to have 5 dispensers full and
send 2 pulses to that that would be like
5 times 2 is 10 or for the last bottles
for example we could have 10 dispensers
and send 3 pulses to get 30 bottles out
like we need which isn't as difficult to
do as I thought it was going to be I'll
show you in a second that first I'll
show you this working I got a button
here will power this 10 items get shot
out of the 10 dispensers and they fall
down and then they make their way to the
center for potions I'm going to make
more often I'll obviously want those
closer to the center so it doesn't take
as long if I had ice I could speed this
up but I don't and as far as I know you
can't get ice with silk touch anymore
which sucks but that's the way it is
yeah
so that's up here so we'll be standing
here items will fall on us yeah I did a
little test I thought I was going to
need three repeaters to send a double
pulse to a dispenser but you don't
actually you just need one repeater you
see it shot to you and you can have it
if you have it on add to delay it will
only shoot one but if you go up to three
then it'll shoot - so that's the minimum
to make that happen so yeah won't be
that difficult to send double pulses so
for then the potions I won't be making
as often like the regeneration potions
because I probably won't get a million
gas tears or anything I might i'll
probably just
have a group of five instead of a group
of ten and in that way I'll try to get
them all to fit in this thing so I don't
have to add more dispensers because this
is probably quite excessive as it is
well it seems like I'm having problems
with the multi pulsing after all it's
just not working for me like like when I
tested it before I was trying to do a
triple pulsing here for the glass
bottles but this is what happens we've
got some cobble in there still 22 when I
press this button here it should send
out three different delayed signals and
they are at least three torch delays
apart from each other so this one is 1
this is 4 and this is 8 so should send
out 3 signals that the dispenser can
take but according to my last test but
that's not actually the case
in total only one got shot out there
even though it sounded like five pulses
went out four pulses went out somehow
from that so yeah I just we're just
going to do with this simple way added
40 extra dispensers though not a big
deal we'll have more storage space doing
that it's just a cross here with the 10
per arm so if I connected here and here
it we would have 30 for the glass
bottles or something like that so up
here I'm going to thirty of these are
going to be for the glass bottles in ten
are going to be for the netherwart
and that will just I will just simplify
everything and I can load these from
below so it's not terrible okay
okay as walking by my farm here and a
bunch of squid just fell to their death
missed it though that's what happened
and it seems Enderman are still getting
down my jave really annoying
alright guys I got lots to show you now
I worked on the potion room for a good
three hours at least and half that time
is probably on the wiring just because
it was really tedious but yeah this is
it still not complete but got a lot done
on it and I decided since I put over 500
redstone into this thing that I'd go all
out tonight replace the entrance with
iron blocks and lapis very expensive
elegant then I also noticed the shape of
this room was almost exactly the same
sorry these guys are annoying let's get
rid of these guys first I needed a lot
of black for the potion room so I ran
around hunting squid and then right when
I finished that I found some in the
potion room itself which was pretty
ironic now that I don't need them well
there's still some up there you know
what I'm going to do I'm going to get
the looting sword see if these guys
don't the spawn or something hopefully
they'll be around yeah put a lot of time
into that it's a big project be awesome
when it's done though see sword sword
sword where are you there you go this
works on squid this as well as using to
get the all the black bowl there I think
one time I even got seven ink sacs from
one squid with this which is pretty
pretty awesome
let's try it out somebody has made a
tutorial on this 3x3 door that's really
awesome - but I think I'm going to stick
with this one just because it's done
okay here we go
first hit will use our pick and then got
four five and three not bad okay let's
look at the picture so it's a pixel art
of a potion because it matched the room
pretty much perfectly a little bit
different than what I normally do it's
pretty pretty out there and somehow I'm
going to have to transition from stone
brick to this iron actual iron block
door here and over here we have the
actual brewing area so you would stand
here and you can hit all the buttons and
hear that click divot after everyone oh
I can't reach here let's just have to
stand a little bit closer that's okay so
yeah each of these is an individual wire
that goes up to the dispensers above
which was a huge pain to do so some run
underneath some run above we'll just run
through it quick and then it goes up to
redstone torches which take the signal
straight up other sides the exact same
here is a huge mess because originally I
was doing spiral staircases up for the
wire so I wouldn't use what I have to
use redstone torches just to speed up
the
the wire rates I guess the lower the
delay after the button press let's see
how do I get up here it might not be a
way to get up here anymore
and then there's wire everywhere
basically I will be putting up this
world for download very soon again so
you'll be able to check it out then if
you want these guys went all out in here
- I've got glowstone can't remember how
much you saw last time it's been so long
I've been working on this on these signs
I will have they'll say they reading in
it so if I ever come to restock it'll be
simple to find where to put the stuff
it's easy to restock because
everything's down here or you can reach
above half slabs are just so I don't
fall into the stream below because if
you do that then you can't get out due
to that water glitch most the time and
now it's about it pretty pretty good I'm
glad it's all done have some repeaters
up here to extend the signal so this arm
this arm and this arm are connected
together here and then this one's on its
own pretty boring I know I know okay
also yeah this is like this is where
like three the torches come up and one
of them keeps going up here and one goes
to this group here the other one has to
extend all the way around and it goes to
this next group then on the other side
much the same stuff happens this is
running a wire a long distance
so much redstone and just by chance that
came out right over by my house here
I'll be able to have a secondary
entrance up here which is nice let's
kill some squid just fitting them with
the pic first so I don't waste by a very
precious sword here excellence okay so
for these storage areas I did them out
of wooden planks it mostly because it
blends in with the chests pretty good
cuz they're both a similar color also
blends in with glowstone nicely and
sandstone that's why I chose that
so probably keep them three chests high
below the bottom one is glowstone to
brighten up the area and I'll probably
put stairs at the top like this and that
will make it look like a solid block but
it's not so you can still open the chest
which is pretty cool and a good tip I
got from you guys is I should color code
these by putting the wool blocks behind
the chest so you'll still be able to see
them I'm hoping you can color coat the
chests I'm not sure if each potion will
have its own unique color but we'll I
don't know we'll see what happens that
then I'll probably have signs saying
what's in the chest as well we need to
work on a ceiling and air force maybe
try to transition from the iron to the
wood I didn't think of something maybe
sandstone would work I don't know ah
what else I do have iron here as well I
really went all out on this still got
probably half a stack of them though of
iron block solid iron blocks because I'm
pretty darn rich for this I was thinking
I will put sandstone blocks above the
cauldrons no brewing stands yes and then
I should probably make this sandstone
too just so we can connect together and
then behind that I'll probably put
glowstone yeah that's good so I'll do
that for all these and then I'll load up
my ingredients and it will be done let's
try a stripe with sandstone here again
I'm not good at choosing blocks so if
this looks really weird this is my best
and I'm just not good at it
hmm
I don't know anyway that's the potion
room function is the most important
thing and I think I got that down pretty
good here so I'm happy
yep enchanting another shovel here still
trying to get badges spoon let's see if
we can fortune tree on a shovel okay as
it's trying to think what I could use a
fortune 3 for on a shovel it seems
almost completely useless
yes there is probably few things
overcome like gravel get flint every
time I guess that's kind of cool let's
make a huge gravel pillar or a short one
because this is taking a long time let's
see how quick we can get down with our
efficiency forward to it still takes a
lot yeah flint every time it's cool I
want to see if it works on these
mushrooms too - don't really harvest a
whole lot of mushrooms so I don't know I
don't have anything to compare it to but
I don't think it's helping could be
wrong probably get more seeds but that's
pretty much useless
so yeah I'll probably just use it like a
regular shovel all right back in the
potion room again still gotta do some
stuff but it's coming along
I got it organized that was a another
big part and I even put some ingredients
in the dispensers so we will be able to
test this this episode which is good
I'll show you how I organized this so so
in the middle these are the most the two
most important buttons here the top ones
glass bottles and the bottom ones nether
warts so use those for every every group
of potions or make that and then on the
left here we have the extra boosters you
can add like redstone to make it longer
glowstone to make it
more more powerful or or better I just I
don't know how to say it higher tier
with both stone and then gunpowder to
make it a splash potion so those are the
three optional boosters you can add and
then you have our positive boosts gas
tiers and you guys told me how to say
this I'm going to get it wrong because I
can't remember what you said blistering
melons over here so these are two these
to help you to recover over here we have
blaze powder and magma cream which are
both related to blaze and they this is
for strength potions this is for fire
resistant ones so they're kind of
grouped together then over here there's
also sugar these are what I'll probably
make the most of of anything and then we
have two negative ingredients that
fermented spider eyes and then the
spider eyes and you use those to make
negative potions like poison weakness
slow potion potion of harm
I think there's nine nine different
potions actually not eight like I
thought or seven like I said nine so
what I've been told so we have ten
groups of chess we'll use nine of these
for the nine different ingredients and
then we'll have one group just for like
holding last bottles or any other random
stuff we want okay now let's go up in
here I'll I'll hook up a nice ladder or
something once I polish this up more I
got the signs here and the way these are
organized I put a lot of thought into it
the potions I will be making more often
or the ingredients I'll use more often
or closer to the center here so they'll
make it to us faster than the ones light
over here this is as far as they'll have
to travel go like that
to the center it's quite a quite a ways
it will take a few seconds so redstone I
won't be using often probably gasps
tears I'm not going to get a whole lot
of those anytime soon
blistering melons will arrive a little
quicker
same with glowstone a little quicker in
the middle we have sugar like I said
I'll be making those quite often so
they're gonna arrive quickly same with
nether warts quickly blaze powder is a
little bit slower fermented spider eyes
you use these quite a lot if you're
using if you're making negative potions
so I wanted them somewhere in between
first for delivery speed then far away
we have spider eyes and magma cream
probably won't be making a whole lot of
those and let's go up here and
everything in this cross our will arrive
quickly we got the glass bottles they'll
all arrive quickly and gunpowder
probably won't be using gunpowder a
whole lot at first but once that get a
mob system going I'll probably use it a
ton so I wanted that to be a quick
delivery item as well and that's that's
about it yeah let's do our first test
run here this is what this has all been
about all this work been really looking
forward to trying it out finally so
stand about here
first thing we need last bottles sets
this button here and while those arrive
we can also oh oh you know what I did
dang it dick spotted the first mistake
yeah you know what I did I put a cover
over that hole so the ones from the
second layer are going to drop three on
the top
darn alright give me a sec alright that
should take care of that problem
so in these dispensers is ingredients
another work there sugar is here so get
sugar in don't have a whole lot loaded
just yet but eventually they'll get
filled up little by little J let's try
this again
glass bottles should get 30
a fall kind of strange 30 awesome okay
so to fill these just go like like this
and if we don't have enough inventory
space they'll get thrown up onto the
ground right at our feet and we just go
go around loading them in it's pretty
pretty simple you don't have to make a
bunch of trips back and forth to the
chest
pick up your water water bottles this
way which is nice
I'm a little worried that those
dispensers are going to shoot out over
top each other now because in that that
first test there was one we only got 29
bottles instead of 31 landed on a
dispenser on the other side so we'll see
how this goes that might have just been
a very rare case
and 30 as you can see is kind of tedious
that took probably close to a minute
just loading up the bottles but a lot
easier than it would be if you did this
just randomly day now we get our nether
warts should get 10 9 10 great so really
you could just press this button and
press this when we get the two at the
same time and then you go around loading
loading these up to make awkward potions
from the water bottles which I think you
can make every potion from an awkward
potion so that's why we're doing it like
this instead of making thick potions and
mundane potions you pretty much just do
an awkward potion every time
good and this one should be about done
yep okay and then we would choose our
final well not necessarily final but our
next ingredient to make the potion so
let's do a sugar one first sugar step
button there sure your falls down should
get ten again great and you just go all
the way around like we did with the
nether wart and once you do all this
you'll have 30 paste potions that what
they're called swiftness potions so not
a bad way of mass-producing them then if
you wanted to make swiftness potion
level 2 you would just add glowstone or
if you wanted to make a splash potion
you just hit this button for the
gunpowder but yeah all done we got our
potions brewing way here and that's the
potion room pretty cool I like it well
everyone I guess I'm going to end the
episode here today
got a lot done again and if you have any
ideas on how to improve this or to make
it look better I always have a listening
here don't be afraid to leave a comment
I'll sure read it still got a bit of
work to do it's not supposed to be open
like this and around the stores and done
yet but yeah turned out pretty good so
far
I like that door probably won't work on
this next time though we'll start a new
project because I need a break from it
and that one's up and working now so
it's no real urgent
need to polish it yet but yeah that's it
for today thank you for watching and I
will see you again next time with a new
project