[Music]
readings everybody this is so and
welcome back guys to another episode of
the let's play series what do you think
of that intro that was pretty bad right
it's ok we only got to do it the one
time guys just to stand out as a
different episode and we will never talk
about it again okay so I have an idea to
start us off with today a building
project should go fairly quickly I would
think it's a little bit complicated but
not crazy
there's two two things I've been wanting
to do and we're gonna combine the two
ideas together first off I've been
wanting to build a vending machine inner
worlds which is basically a building
that will give us stuff we use a lot
like we'll be able to refill like
rockets and or pearls food scaffolding
torches bones for bone meal wood and
stone are eight things I use pretty
often in our let's play series here and
often I run out and I have to go all the
way back to the man cave to refill and
they're not even organized at the man
cave so I have to like run around
gathering gunpowder and whatever to to
make rockets and and that kind of stuff
how cool would it be if we had all that
stuff just in a place where we could go
and refill alright that's the plan so
I've also been wanting to use the new
lecterns for like a redstone II project
so we're gonna use those as our controls
for the vending machine so what you can
do with these is put a book and quill on
them and they actually emit red stone
using comparators so check this out if
you put a comparator on there with some
dusts depending on what page you are on
it will emit a signal that's different
so right now it's one a distance of one
if we go over a page to two it's a
distance of three and one of the neat
things about these lecterns is you
actually have a pretty good amount of
control over how far the redstone emits
based on how many pages are in the book
so if we want like a one to one
Paige / redstone distance all we got to
do is create like 15 pages so we're
gonna add 15 to the book like so now
when we flip through here we're at 1 for
one page - oh I didn't hit done
oopsies alright let's try that again if
you don't hit done it doesn't save your
changes alright we hit done oh wait a
minute wait a minute maybe I actually
have to write something on the 15th page
let's put an A there and now it's 15
pages long ok ok so now that it's 15
pages at page one distance of 1/2
distance of 2 3 is 3 4 is 4 and so on
and so forth so that is pretty cool the
plan with our vending machine here is
we're gonna use two lecterns the first
one's gonna choose what item we're gonna
get out of the vending machine and the
second one is gonna be how many of that
item we're gonna get out of it and then
there'll be a button in the middle to
actually call the item is the plan so
kind of figured we would do it in our
village here just so that we have some
redstone devices in our village if you
build something purely decorative
I find you never use it actually so if
we actually want to like go to this
village and use it we need some some
practical useful redstone devices here
or farms or something of that nature
or will never go here so we're gonna add
a vending machine I think over there's
my plan how's it gonna look so we can
have a path that runs through here still
if we want yeah I think we'll do that
we're gonna use the two lecterns like
over here I'm also gonna set up like I
brought some other stuff with us like a
stonecutter we'll probably set up a
little workstation sort of thing here
probably some crafting tables just so
it's it's nice and practical and useful
to us as we're working on the
village will have all these things at
arm's reach I wish probably an
enderchest here too because I'm just
kind of scattering them on the floor
they will snake this and put it looks
like she put that in the middle over
here yeah something like that oh and if
we could cover this we can still access
just don't get it through the block
because it's the ender chest is a little
bit lower right so now the thing about
these lecterns is they will actually
which is our book this one here we'll
put that there
this one here they'll actually emit the
signal through a block as well so we can
we can keep a brick piece of brick over
there and then put the comparator on the
other side and it'll pick up the signal
through the wall so we'll do that and
I'm going to try hide most of our stuff
underground here is my plan so maybe
we'll set up a water stream that comes
up from underground with our items and
then I want them to like fall out here
on to us uh-huh yeah so this is pretty
much all we need for our vending machine
just this little little tiny thing so
we'll choose our item here we'll choose
how much hit the button and then this
water stream is gonna deliver it to us
basically so this is all we need for a
footprint this is tiny little building
now I did realize something here like we
have this beast of a building over here
this is kind of what we want to do over
here as well and all we got is this tiny
little stupid thing so why am i hiding
the redstone underground if we want a
big massive building here I think
because the redstone is gonna be like a
big glob like a big big blob of redstone
and it's not gonna have much shape to
its like that like this building has so
we're still gonna hide that underground
and my plan is like when we start up a
second building it's gonna connect to
this and like stack on top of this
thing's roof and combine together so
we'll have a big massive thing over here
as well in the future they'll probably
like spread out this way but we should
still height at the Redstone underground
just so we can shape
shape things better and yeah so this is
what we're gonna do we're gonna run a
comparator chain Underground's so we can
hide the redstone down there and this is
neat like if we go to page four doing
this little pattern with the comparators
we can check it out here you see it's a
distance of four so it keeps the signal
strength even though it ran through this
whole chain of things so that's all good
we can we can keep what the lectern says
here and use it all the way over here
all right good stuff so we got our
interface figured out here now we're
gonna get to actually building the
redstone a vending machine part of this
and should go pretty quick I kind of got
it planned out already so this signal we
get from the lectern you see the first
four on right now the other four are off
that's not really useful to us we need
to be able to control like one single
device so we're gonna do a trick here we
extend this look what happens here so
it's a signal strength of four you'll
see the first three though it's on down
below here and on up above beyond that
it's off and off right there's only one
spot where it's on below and off above
and we set up a giant or like a bigger
and array here to check all eight of
them and the one that it's on below and
off above is the one that will let us
signal through so we put some torches
there some torches on top and basically
the repeater down here takes the signal
from the bottom and then we add another
set of repeaters for the top so it takes
it from here and then combines the two
together and it finds the one where it's
it's on here and off above and that's
the torch that turns on over here all
the other ones will be off so that is
pretty cool
then we're gonna use that torch to power
some sticky pistons set those on set
those up over here put some blocks above
these
oopsies and something like that and now
we're gonna add a platform here that'll
send a redstone signal into whatever
Pistons are up alright and up roll up so
just set some repeaters here with some
redstone dust and we just got this thing
done already so yeah when this gets
powered it's only gonna let the signal
through here and depending on what the
lectern said that will adjust which one
gets chosen and then we use that to
control some droppers I think we're
gonna do them like this
we'll set one up here we're gonna do two
because like if you're just sending a
signal to one of them it can kind of
take a long time to get the items out if
we have two sets of droppers it'll be
twice as quick okay so then we want to
be able to fill these droppers with our
items nice and easy so we're gonna have
one set of hoppers facing into this one
another set facing down into these ones
and we'll combine the two together and
also this is where we're gonna set up a
water stream to bring our items to us so
I made this eight blocks long on purpose
because that's as far as water will
reach and it'll go underneath and then
up a water elevator here it's the plan
and finally here what we do is we
connect the two sets of droppers
together with a couple hoppers like this
we put some chests above this is what's
gonna hold our big stash of items like
our rockets and and torches and whatever
and now check this out when we put some
items in it evenly splits them into this
dropper and this one here the lower one
so that's pretty cool and we set this up
just so that they'll be close to the
surface so we can probably just have
some trap doors or something above the
chest and easily refill it just by
walking over top here it was quite a
while ago now but it looks like it's
still here
remember when we set up this cannon we
came up with a fancy little redstone
device here this is the last piece of
our vending machine puzzle this is a
variable timer we came up with
that's let's see it shot out six ladders
that time depending on where this item
frame is rotated affects how many items
we get they'll be between two to nine
pulses at that time we got five if we
rotate it one more time it'll be four so
what we're gonna do is get rid of the
item frame and use a lectern instead and
like copy this over to our vending
machine all right guys we got it all
together here and I've been testing it
out and I keep having a problem where
the items land in between the hoppers
it's so frustrating I really hate that
change like hoppers used to pretty much
take up a full block but now items
always seem to get stuck in between them
if you're like shooting shooting them
with droppers or whatever it makes it
really hard to compact redstone now so
we got to make some changes here we
might even rip out this bottom set of
droppers just to simplify things a lot
and give it a lot of these hoppers Oh
snappers all right you know it's gone so
good so wonderful at first guys and then
we ran into the hopper issue and it went
downhill quick like it was going so
smooth before so those are like two
hours later or something crazy but we
got it all done thankfully it's all
finished now I just got to show it off
to you guys and and fill it up with the
goodies cause right now it's pretty much
empty so couple big changes here we were
gonna go down to one dropper because of
that hopper issue but it was so slow I
couldn't stand it the idea of this thing
is we want like a quick refill station
right to get our ender pearls or rockets
whatever we don't want to be waiting
around for a Minotaur or whatever to
refill so we want it to be quick so I
went from two droppers down to one
realized one was way too slow went up to
four now per item so this like we had it
before if the Pistons up sends power
into this block activates this dropper
and this one we have an observer here to
detect when this gets activated sends
power up here to the other dropper and
likewise
this detects this dropper and then this
observer detects one this detects this
and sends power here to this one alright
I made this so we can go inside to
refill them so 4 times 9 that's 36
stacks of items which is quite a bit
it'll take a while before we need to
refill so that should be okay we don't
really need a chest it would have been
nice if we could have had an auto fill
with a chest or something but it'll be
fine now the other big thing here though
is I realize that timer had some big
issues they had like a startup time
before it started activating so I had to
redesign that as well basically the
lectern comes down here for the amount
of items and goes to this comparator
which is interested track mode and this
is our button press over here goes to a
monostable to this little doohickey to
this pulsar and not gonna go super
detailed in that hopefully you
understood the way we send the button
press down below by the way is I got a
piston that pushes a redstone block
downward because there wasn't enough
space to like run a spiral of a redstone
downwards so we have to do something
fancy so over here we can choose how
many items goes from 8 to 40 is
generally I don't want more than a stack
the idea is just 3 fill because I always
keep like 1 stack of rockets on me once
deck enderpearls and we just want to top
up the stack we don't want to go beyond
that let's see let's try it out right
now we got some stone in there and I put
some dirt in for the wood just to test
it so let's go for eight stone press
that there's a little bit of delay like
it takes a couple seconds but we get it
pretty quick let's go up to the max
let's go to 40 press the button
everything is fairly quick I'm happy
with that
doo-doo-doo-doo and we got our 40 so
that's cool all right
some of these aren't accurate I found
out let's try this 129 let's see just a
weird way Oh II did get 29 okay that
that one might be accurate let's go to
25 it'll be like plus or minus one
sometimes so we have 26 instead 25 if we
do it again we'll get 24 and if we do it
again we'll get 26 again it's a little
strange it's only a couple that do that
though it I'm not entirely sure why you
have something to do with the observers
and bud powering it's time it'll be 26
again uh-huh anyways let's try switch to
a different item so we only have dirt
there for now
let's go to 15 what where'd this come
from
uh-oh do we have a an issue so we got
plus one that time plus 150 15 does this
give an item when we cycle oh oh it does
no that's really bad okay
can I fix that it's not supposed to
like if I put a block there it doesn't
happen all right hmm uh-huh
okay we figure it out why it's not
accurate as well now so it doesn't
happen normally like if I cycle normally
it doesn't shoot out blocks constantly
right what happens is we hit this we get
our items let's turn this up all right
and apparently we're bud powering one of
the droppers so when this observer
powers up here it also powers this one
but powers it right from this block so
whenever this updates again it shoots
out another item which is a little bit
annoying uh-huh
but anyways we got to stock it up with
supplies now so we need paper for
rockets let's do it we can get the bones
in the gunpowder we need from our mob
system here which still works pretty
good by the way the odd issue every now
and then with like the animals
teleporting for some reason there's a
cat in a minecart here which probably
fell from inside of it don't ask me how
but yeah I emptied this recently but
there's like is it like always lots of
stuff in here constantly refilling I
have an issue where I don't really know
what to do with all this stuff at this
point we got stacks and stacks of bones
we'll probably just put bone blocks in
that vending machine probably I said
probably twice aha we got lots of
gunpowder available this is a paper we
just grabbed so I like to make the the
triple fireworks the three gunpowder to
one paper all right so we got to get
ourselves a whole bunch of ender pearls
as well for it so we're gonna pay a
visit to the ender Enders 3.0 I actually
haven't used this in a long time I
always use the the Bateman farm so I
don't know if this is still working
let's find out I'm hoping yes
music still works a little bit loud
alright lots and referrals here this is
great this is what we want car we got
enough already actually just about oh
wow I filled up quick it does not take
long to get enderpearls oh my goodness
all right let's try get some XP here too
just to make sure it still works I think
we're good
what does this sword have what's the one
that hits multiple sweeping edge I guess
we don't have that wait a minute wait a
minute
I think it is actually working a lot
worse now there's so many falling off to
the sides what's going on these still
almost all fall in the middle look at
this the over half or missing in the
middle yeah okay that's that's a bit of
an issue and there's a lot of them on
the platform now for some reason - not
sure what what the deal is with that
there used to be just like the odd one
now there's tons all right what's the
holdup here having trouble getting to
the spot now okay I got a couple ideas
how we could fix this first off there
they're falling down a 1x1 tube which
used to be grates like we used to be
able a one-shot like 50 in a minute once
it was amazing but we might want to turn
into three by one two by three wide
that'll make it so they don't have
trouble of getting down like they're
right now and also help prevent mob
stacking from killing them but also I
wanted to sneak in if possible a couple
extra trapdoors here I think will solve
a lot of the problem somehow we got a we
got to place these
this is gonna be weird I'm curious if I
don't know if they walk through these
actually I'm curious now I just wanna
test that they didn't climb them I see
that they go through them oh yeah they
do go right through them too
okay oh that's not good that's not what
we want do not pass take a different
route oh we did it we did it guys okay
let's get this we gotta like go over now
means I should be able to do this now
yes okay we got one down so then let's
change this but they don't go this way
there we go we got it
alright now is that looking now well
they're not falling off the edges now I
think more are getting for the middle
for sure right but there's a bunch head
there just like sitting there now that
that aren't even trying to get to the
middle so if we made it a three-wide
that should solve everything and it
looks like our platform down below isn't
loaded with Enderman anymore
[Music]
well I made a couple more changes to the
farm here but overall it's really
efficient again we got no problem ok
enough XP like we we farm it faster than
we can take it in so there's not really
any points making 3 wide actually so we
won't be able to take the XP in any
faster even if we made the farm slightly
more efficient you know that's fine I
decide to get rid of all those magma
blocks because I found them pretty
annoying and put carpet down as well to
hopefully reduce teleporting although I
think we need to double stack it I'm not
quite sure about that not really having
much teleporting issues just the odd guy
here and there but yeah overall I think
we're we gave this a nice update it's
good again so I got something else I
wanted to show you guys today and I'm
not gonna lie it's not all that exciting
you know it's not glamorous it's not
it's not anything to be super proud of
or anything like that but I tell you
what guys it is importance the nether is
vital to our world it is like the veins
keeping our world alive and I spent a
lot of hours finishing up our nether
tunnel here so I just wanted to show it
off and I wanted you guys leave me a
good job' though but that's all I want
really so we started at around zero zero
and we recently upgraded our / / firm we
finished that ice farm our guardian
firms still working great so we're games
see lanterns and stuff and we even found
a way to harvest sand it's fairly quick
recently so we got like all the
materials we need to build the another
tunnel
/ / ice glass sea lanterns so I was able
to extend it all the way to our
underwater base now so maybe I'll
actually get to working on this thing
now that we can get here quickly so we
started it like zero zero our nether
tunnels 1,500 blocks along this
direction now and like a hundred blocks
on the z-coordinate 138 so I thought
that was kind of cool the only thing
we're missing is a couple rails I'm
holding
because we're low on iron at the moment
and our iron farm is not working anymore
so we urgently need to build a new one
soon that said yeah also we found those
donkeys recently we'll be able to
transport them through the nether now
which is great maybe start breeding
mules and stuff like that
alright everybody well I think it's that
time again where we need to wrap up our
episode for today
or is it no there's been one more big
thing guys today's a big big day for old
Wilson I tell you what I haven't worked
on Wilson in a long time
it is functional I have to refresh that
many times I did finish it it can just
be improved quite a bit those the
problem anyways I looked at his redstone
today and I noticed an air with it
apparently his bladder system was not
set up properly properly he has a
stomach and bladder system and
apparently the bladder system never
actually functioned so I fixed that I
figured out what was wrong so Wilson
officially can take poops it's a big day
big day
unfortunately there's no functionality
for that yet so I might hook that up
somehow have to get creative with it I
guess and then like when he poops we
want his happiness to go down uh-huh
that's the the next big thing anyways
let's get to the comment of the day it
says the cave base is still the coolest
base to this day literally years after
construction oh that's some major
flattery right there I love it I gotta
take it all in honestly though I think
this is by far the favorite base I've
ever built in Minecraft and I hate to
say it it's like a bittersweet thing
it's probably the best base I'll ever
build in Minecraft I don't think I'll
ever make something I like more than
this it's actually very simple in
construction like there's not a lot of
fancy stuff to it is this grass planks
stone you know it's easy to recreate
there's been a lot of other bases I've
seen
people recreate the style and they've
kind of thrown their own unique touch to
it and it's pretty cool to see what
people do with the same theme I have
always kind of I kind of haven't really
done a lot of construction on the man
cave I've been building more in other
parts of the world which i think is good
it gets more variety but I have also
kind of wanted to keep it expanding the
man cave I don't know if you guys would
be interested in that but like this is
where it ends right now and I've always
wanted to make this like a different
themed area over here like still keep
the grass and all that but maybe start
adding fires and lava and stuff as we
get in you're closer to bedrock like
that's lava level down there I thought
that might be cool there's a there's a
couple places we can branch off and
expand the cave if we want and even add
more redstone devices down here might be
something we do in the future no I made
it so no none of you guys can spawn
anymore where did you come from like I
was so careful light level eight seven
right there no way huh all right I gotta
fix that anyways guys hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching until next time take care have
a wonderful day bye bye
[Music]