[Music]
hey everybody how you doing today
i am just in the nether right now
working on the dual
uh blaze xp farm here
i was planning to get a lot of this done
or
at least try to before i started
recording today and then surprise you
and be like look what i did today it's
amazing
it's all done but while building this
something
weird and interesting has been happening
i put down a layer of fence gates here
to trick the mobs up into walking on
walking into the air and falling down
because they see them as
normal blocks for their pathfinding but
as you just saw there there's something
very strange happening here with the new
changes defense gates
how they can be controlled with redstone
uh this is causing them to automatically
close on their
own at random times randomly kind of
and the the issue is
normally in the game it will
randomly go through chunks and randomly
choose blocks to
update every so often i'm not gonna
give specific numbers because i don't
know off
hand but when it randomly updates one of
these
for some reason it decides to close them
because they're not being powered right
now
which is a big issue if you're doing
anything mob related with these things
like a lot of people do so
or if you're using these for conveyor
belts or any other design you have to
take that into consideration now
if that doesn't get fixed that's a
pretty big issue
uh so all of these will eventually all
close on their own because they're not
being powered
so for this what i'm gonna do to fix is
just use science and get rid of these
but just something i thought i'd point
out to you guys hopefully it gets fixed
in a
new patch
all right so the thing i was trying here
doesn't seem to be working
quite like i hoped it would this was
just
a test to see how it would function
i've been trying to set this up without
using any pistons to move
the blaze around and i i have signs
there now that's to help decrease the
time it takes them to
fall down the center and that does help
but i don't know just relying on their
pathfinding alone
to get their way through takes too long
they kind of get stuck in places
um they will eventually find their way
through but it just takes a while
so i'm trying to get them to fall down
and then go to the end of this tube and
then they would
join together and go down another tube
and then up
is what i would like to happen
but yeah they just
i don't know i have to use pistons i
guess i've been trying to avoid using
them because
for one thing they like the game a bit
um
they you have to choose one of
two negative effects if you have a
piston
and a solid block to push them
it pushes them good occasionally they
will glitch into
the solid block and then suffocate to
death
which is kind of a good thing but the
other
issue is just sometimes when they get
pushed by the solid block they take a
little bit of damage
for a split second they will take
suffocation damage as
as it pushes them
and that's why with my other blaze farm
there that they didn't all have the same
health
because some of them took damage as they
were getting pushed around
now if you were to push them with a
glass block
they would take no damage from that but
sometimes
they get stuck inside it their head and
they'll be on a
on the pressure plate at the same time
too
and they will totally jam up the system
so
there's no good way of moving these guys
around basically
which kind of sucks mine carts you can
only do one at a time
what i was thinking of maybe doing is
pushing them through my tunnel here with
the furnace minecarts but then
i did try that in creative mode and it
worked well but the problem is
you have to keep feeding it coal but it
is a good way of moving them around
long distance like a whole group of them
so yeah i'll have to adjust this
use pistons and probably have to do that
another day because that will take a
while
oh yeah and with these uh the doors and
the trapdoors don't seem to be closing
on their own but
i haven't given it a ton of time either
although if you put a block next to them
and remove it
then they'll close on their own
this door is open right now if you put a
block next to it and remove it
it'll close on its own too
all right we're back here and
i have been doing a little bit of
polishing around here
with the cave trying to
figure things out a little bit better um
so before here you would have to go up
and then back down and now i just cut a
slice out of the cliff here and just
walk straight pretty much
so probably going to
either get rid of this mushroom farm
here or move it over one block just
to make its symmetrical
this is uh
that's where the pressure plate is right
there i would like that
to be in the middle of the walkway here
and maybe in one block
not that i really use that but
it would be nice to be aligned properly
i did a little bit on the ceiling
i added this wooden stripe on this side
people never really told me if they like
it or not i i kind of like it because it
creates harmony i guess with the floor
but i would like to have these all along
the walls
wooden stripe and then another brick
stripe
sandstone stripe might be a few too many
stripes but
i don't think it looks too bad
yeah and i put some more grass over here
for now
one thing that was suggested in the
comments let me know what you think of
this as well
is uh for me to get rid of this wall
over here
so if we go down there
it's only it's only like two blocks wide
in a lot of places
and it wouldn't be that tough to get rid
of and if i do
it would open it up to the tree farm so
you would be able to see the tree farm
easily from up here that might be pretty
cool
let me know what you think of that this
ceiling will be
a little bit higher i'm going to try to
make it kind of a domish
shape to it and i
might put another brick all around this
green
ufo thing
i don't think those colors clash too
badly i haven't fixed this yet i need to
do that to
make a chamber for cows to fall into a
holding area for cows
i'll probably put that over
here somewhere maybe along with these
mobs
um let's see what else
i am eating watermelons now i've made
the switch i think
it's just so easy to get them now you
just walk in
you're refilled walk out
it's pretty cool
okay and another good suggestion i had
was to get rid of the stairs
in this slime escalator thing
and replace them with these half slabs
so i think i'll do that right now too
and then i think uh we're gonna go to
the end because uh there was a few
things i didn't try out there
and to my surprise you guys actually
like the end visit so maybe we'll do one
more
all right time for enchantment break
figured i should spend the levels before
we go to the end here
running low on picks so here we go level
wow
wow man that is the best pick i've ever
got
i think that's like the best pick you
can yet that's
awesome yes
all right i got a little bit more done
hello got a little bit more done here i
put it
some more border around the ufo to see
how it would look i think it's uh
it's pretty good i like it got some
sandstone to try it out
um let's see i put the wood border
around here to see how it would look
probably change out a little bit yet i
wouldn't mind having
a glass balcony type thing just a small
one so i can
walk and look down without uh
worrying about falling off so i'll
probably have fences around here too
i'll try to make it look a little less
square
one other thing i want to do before we
head off to the end again
to do some tests is uh
die
is uh try out some pixel art here
so i mentioned i wanted to i wanted to
do some harvest moon pixel art i tried
doing a cow face
from the old snes harvest moon could not
get the colors to look good
so i tried building a creative mode just
didn't look quite like i
hoped so i think i'm gonna do minecraft
pixel art cows
i'll probably put one over here and see
how that goes
need an eight by eight
eight by eight this wall is 13 wide
so it's not going to be symmetrical
another problem but
i will play around with it and we'll see
how it goes
alright you ready for it here it is
here's the pixel arts
looks looks pretty good um i had a
little
trouble lighting it as the one issue so
i put a wood frame around it
with glowstone every so blocks um
don't really like how the glowstone
looks i could have inset the picture one
more block but then
and like have glowstone hidden on the
inside
but then it would have been a lot harder
to see the picture i think
if it was in one more block the frame
would cover it up more so
so i think i'll leave it like that it
would be nice if i could put trapdoors
over
the glowstone to make them a little bit
less
sticking out like a sore thumb i guess
oh that's kind of cool
so i don't know if i'm going to put more
here i might but the problem is i have
uh
i didn't even think of this but i have a
tube here
which is why i didn't put it on that
wall this
is uh what i push the towels down with i
don't really need it but
i don't know
yep so that's good got pixel
arts and that is uh
the dark pine wood and then that's light
oak wood
i guess and white wool then
light gray dark gray and black
so those are the five five different
colors i used
anyway so i'm gonna get ready and we're
gonna go to the end there is at least
three or four things i want to try out
today hopefully um
so i'll get my stuff together here and
i'll set up a bed at that stronghold too
so that when i die i will be right by
the portal
okay i got a little base set up here in
the stronghold
some stuff i slept uh what's your sound
get that down so we're gonna do a few
tests again today
um again our goal is not really to beat
the dragon
yet although i've pretty sure i'll need
to to get free control
over the end but before we do that
oh you guys are annoying before we do
that we're going to do a few tests
again so a lot of people seem to
be disappointed last time i didn't try
to make another portal
in the end and also i'm trying to go
with no armor this time because last
time i went i didn't take any damage
really so we'll see how
i fare oh my
fair with no armor here
okay where is he
um why is there no boss
what the heck oh there he is
what i guess you have to get in range
before he spawns
maybe i really can't look at any of
these guys or i'm in trouble
so
yeah he's doing weird things glitching
out
i'm looking at you don't hurt me okay
he owned that enderman okay so
and now the enderman's chasing him i'm
gonna try to make a portal real quick
here
did not try this last time because i
have heard
it doesn't work so i wasn't going to try
it
but you know a lot of the times i get
wrong information so i really should
try and see with my own eyes whether or
not it works so
where is he
that's not a good sign
so yeah oh man nice lift
so no what's our brightness
doesn't seem like you can have another
portal uh although i would
think if you were to do it in mcedit
and hack in the blue boy
the portal
warped blocks that i bet you it would
work
if i was to guess
but legitimately nope
okay so that's one test done i should
get
maybe i'll try and make another one of
these storage minecarts real quick
nope not gonna happen
not at all okay
okay so this next test is one i wanted
to try last time but i forgot to
or i ran out of time or something but i
have a almost dead silk touch pick here
i'm going to try to get one of those
healing
things see if you can grab them or not
i check the wiki and then say so you
will find out here
so i'm very curious
don't look at them i do have armor on
this time
go up um go up this one
i'll try be quick
here he comes get out of here
still safe infinity bow on this guy
would be
awesome oh damn
i probably should have waited to heal
where is he
okay he's gonna try to get me from
behind
oh and he did okay here we go this might
kill me
dang it okay you can't grab them it
seems
um
great view of the place from up here
oh he's just so easy um
they really should have made it so that
you need potions to beat this guy
or to stay alive in here
like this is yeah whatever anyway
oh my chickens are still alive
i bet you can hurt them though
that's awesome they're all over the
place ah
get some yeah
okay maybe we'll try to do the minecraft
thing again oh yeah my stuff's here
okay well i'm going to
going to make a minecart storage my cart
uh put my stuff in kill myself and we'll
do the next test
so for this next test we're going to try
fishing rod
doesn't seem to work
let's keep trying try it a few more
times
come swoop down
and nope too far away that time
be creative that'd be pretty crazy if it
actually worked oh
i thought i looked at him come on
get down here oh i missed i missed
oh i think it did work there or else he
just did swoop
it looked like i pulled him down the
freaking enderman stole my dirt block
[Music]
oh i hit the dragon
okay where is he
oh world's longest boss fight
no no it's not working okay
um
oh it works on minecarts oh and it does
pull
i didn't know that that's cool
it doesn't work on the dragon okay
okay so fishing rods don't seem to work
on them uh i'm going to try one more
thing yet today
i would like to try snow golems in the
end here and see what happens but
i don't have any actually so maybe some
other time
but this next thing i want to do our y
coordinate is around
60 right now i want to see what happens
if you get all the way down
to like zero
if he will uh chase you down there or
not i'm curious to see
so i'm gonna hit him one more time
before i try this
okay this is going to be really tough to
do i'll have to
probably make several attempts at it
i would imagine
basically i got to build my way down
oh there he is and nope
yeah he got me i knew that was gonna
happen
okay i'm going to make another attempt
here
i'm just going to try to hit him one
time
if i can nope all right i'm just going
to go for it
it's doing a few blocks at a time i
think when i get down to the bottom
he'll stop
chasing me maybe
that's what i'm hoping oh i'm not
falling down fast enough
two three four i got five done oh he
just missed me
oh and he breaks the water too
nope
ah look what he did
he's not in the mood guys
not in the mood
here we go again
quicker so i'm using obsidian because he
can't break obsidian
could use endstone too but
um doesn't really matter
i got a lot of a lot of obsidian from
mining so i don't mind using it
oh is that the bottom
hmm that seemed to
[Music]
i find that hard to believe that was the
bottom already
okay this is it i'm gonna go again
and we'll find out if that's the bottom
or not i guess
it is wow that came quicker than i
thought it would
oh he broke my water so yeah this is
as low as you can get i guess
we're gonna start a new life here
skyblock survival etho style
so i'm gonna see if he will hit me down
here if he doesn't that means i can
actually build in the end
without having to kill them
which i would do for reasons i don't
understand
myself
that is pretty cool though i like this
i seem to be safe
yeah he's not coming for me down here um
which makes me wonder how high i can get
before
he will start attacking me and
destroying my stuff
let's get a little bit higher here let's
go up to 10
and just try hover here for a bit
oh he came down
see i was wondering what would happen i
thought maybe he would
fly down and somehow get messed up
if he went below zero or something i
don't know
so he will attach if you're at ten
actually what i should do is just go aft
down at the bottom for a while and see
what happens
there he is again yes i'm going to go
afk here for a bit and see if i get
knocked off
yeah yeah he did get me uh
uh it took about about two minutes or so
before he found me but
he did eventually find me and kill me so
i don't know i guess that means i have
no choice i gotta kill him
you know what else can i do height
doesn't seem to matter
distance doesn't seem to matter uh
she'll just keep breaking my stuff if i
build anything so i gotta kill he didn't
give me any choice
and i think that's what we will do maybe
next time i don't know
i'm gonna try to get a whole bunch of
potions together more storage minecarts
maybe some tnt enchanted stuff
all kinds of fun things i'm going to get
them all to the end
prepare for a big battle then i'm going
to
make a backup of my world just before i
fight them and i'll probably release it
for you guys if you want to try fight
him with all that stuff
and maybe i'll kill him several times
and just keep loading the back up i
don't know
have some fun with it that is the plan
i do have to kill him can't think of any
other way of keeping him
alive and doing what i want so
that's what we'll do but for today i'm
going to say goodbye
i'll see you guys again next time
i never did really explore this area yet
i should do that sometime
okay see ya