hello everybody this is etho and welcome
to my amazing super fantastic intro
today today I say let's let's mine some
redstone we yeah let's sleep in a bed
ah let's admire the beauty let's enjoy
the beauty let's kill a bat
ha ha ha let's put this in storage let's
melt some stuff let's chop some trees
let's enchant a pic yeah
let's share some sheep let's go
cliff-diving haha let's hug a creeper so
I guess what I'm really saying here guys
is let's play some minecraft so to begin
with today I got to give a big THANK YOU
to maybe pants that's his name
maybe pants yeah he posted top it on the
reddit explaining how to fix it that's a
sound leg issue as having especially
noticeable at the silverfish farm so
like if I walked 16 blocks away from
these guys all the sound files would
unload and it would just cause
tremendous leg I don't have that problem
anymore
or not really bad anyway I can go back
and forth there's a little bit of a
slowdown but it's not like a huge
five-second stoppage like it was before
so that's pretty cool what it is is I
had to update my Maya now what was it
you got wrote it down somewhere think
open al files yeah open al
that's the sound library that minecraft
uses and I just say we're very old so
that seemed to fix it now moving on
let's get to the let's get to the game
here I'll show you where we're at with
the village we'll follow up
I also discovered my sound audio was way
down in my mixer so I'm actually hearing
the game
everything is so so clear and loud now I
loved it because it was almost all the
way down I really had to correct my
speakers before to get it to to hear
anything so loving that so I got a track
all set up here go to the village the
village is pretty much prepared all lit
up we got a fence going all the way
around now and as far as the village
goes I don't think I'm going to adjust
it too much I want the original village
layout and feel to it I'm just trying to
restore it and keep it alive I guess I
would like to EUR to some of these
torches though so what I thought I would
try to do is you know the usual black
wool redstone lamps let's try just see
what that would look like and you're
down light it's have a few of those
around the village I think that'd be
pretty cool I might put a stone half
slab on top to you that way we can get
rid of some of these torches and it will
look better overall I would say so there
is something I'm a little worried about
with this portal because we need this
portal get the villagers from the nether
to the village these pigs they Kemp they
came from the village they went through
the portal into the nether here and I
can't get them to go back so I'm worried
the villagers aren't actually going to
be able to go through this portal for
some reason I don't know why
what happens if I hit on yeah I don't
know I must be violating some rule here
that's preventing it though but anyway I
got the lights positions all figured out
now powered so let's go through place in
our lamps I also removed a whole bunch
of the torches already so I don't know I
maybe went a little overboard with the
lights but you need them like you gotta
light the place up so they kind of have
to be fairly close to each other and the
general rule is like it I got like a
little spacing leaf there's a house
there's going to be at least two one
block spacing usually and between the
the lamps here there there's six blocks
of parts while there's a five block gap
between one two three four five there's
ever a cross section with a walkway I
got it aligned diagonally one block out
except over here this is a little bit of
a problem there overall I think it's
okay how's that looking so I did bring I
brought a whole bunch of different half
slabs I want to try out I figure we're
most likely going to go with the stone
ones but doesn't hurt to try other
things and sandstone so let's go with
regular wood first okay those are kind
of cool actually I kind of like that
sands don't know I like the light wood
better
that's kind of cool to know and still
yeah you know what actually I don't like
the stone I think we're going to go with
either that that not sure which I like
more should probably be something dark
because the littles dark if if we even
want to do that I'm not sure what do you
guys think I think we'll go with the
dark so if we do yeah okay I'm going to
finish that up and we'll try to an
aerial view of this and see what it
looks like we got to hurry it's almost
day I want to see it at night yeah hmm
what do you think what do you think what
do you think those look a little weird
actually from above yeah that's pretty
cool though
I think I don't think we'll do any more
laps that's a pretty good coverage
now I've also done a bit of work on
purifier thing again so I'll show you
that and we got to figure out what we
need to do to finish it or get it
working so let's just take a look so
these are all new you know I love my
arches so we got a whole bunch of arches
here both sides yeah mine cards they'll
come down here and we Keeler's make them
go straight or we'll have them go to the
portal here and the villagers will go
through this way is a staircase up to
the surface
oh no creeper over there by the way okay
got to finish that this I think I'm
going to put apples in not sure what
I'll do with this we can't put weakness
potions in just we'll just get shot out
yeah we got two dispensers this thing is
for the furnace minecarts there's a
button here send them out
oh you know what we could do we could
have coal in this one
yeah because we'll need coal somewhere a
lot of this is over the top and really
unnecessary but that's why I liked it so
yeah we'll have a coal dispenser and
hold an apple dispenser then let's see
so there's a couple couple things I
haven't been looking forward to adding
here because it'll be a bit messy but I
got to add something to shoot out
weakness potions so you need another
dispenser in here I can't remember
what's behind this wall yeah that's not
gonna work
mmm
we'll probably have to hide the the
weakness dispensers underground
somewhere we're kind of limited because
there's already a lot of wiring around
here and then we also want like a master
but inform to this is what we want it to
do we want we want to put them over here
by the way we want one button that will
shoot weakness potions if there is
something in these holding areas so it's
got to go through an antique check that
all the ones that have a zombie villager
in will get a weakness potion then I
also want a cart launcher button so when
we press that all the ones that have a
villager in this dispenser will shoot
out a cart and power this rail all end
up going this way that's what we got to
do we also have to finish this thing
instead of a killing thing for it
besides that we're pretty close to done
need a roof or ceiling I mean this needs
to be finished
I want it yeah you know what I want to
try with this I want to try stone slabs
on the top grab some of these and some
of these mmm
oops hot day my arch a beautiful arch
have these going all along and then
slabs I know I only need one stone slab
but I'm I'm weird like that I have to
put two looks a little weird cuz that
stairs missing mmm let's do the Wow
we cover the whole thing we'll have the
lighting glitch unless we remove the
blocks above it - mm we'll try that out
I'll work on that and also here maybe
we'll do a really sloped staircase to go
up so again we'll try the same thing
we'll have stone slabs and then we only
want to see one I think going up so you
one there
wait I'll wait that won't work
no because it will look like this oops
oops this isn't going well it'll look
weird like that
mmm let's make the wall go in one more
anyway we won't worry Tim we won't worry
too much about that right now so I'm
gonna work on finishing these does this
dispenser deal here who man I am back
you know it feels like an instant to you
guys it is an instant to you guys but to
me I've been at this for over two hours
I'd say at least two hours a ridiculous
amount of time trying to wire this thing
and got it done really happy with how it
turned out it was really tough to do
because there's so much stuff like a lot
of things to take into consideration we
got to we got to power this we got to
power these lights we got to power both
these dispensers and not together
independently we got wiring for these
trip wires we got a piston thing above
here so there's a lot to each of these
things and everything is kind of in the
way of each other so with a little bit
of ninja red stoning I met get it work
very very nicely actually so I'll show
you it actually let's go let's go here
first so this is the master panel
there's two options we've added here the
villager medicine and the villager
transport so that the villager medicine
is the thing that sends out weakness
potions to the zombie villagers that's
going to be in these dispensers here I
did manage to get at work with a second
dispenser there
and so we gotta fill those up with
weakness potions if we press this it'll
shoot out weakness potions only if
there's a mob in this area if this trip
wires down or active or whatever so it's
like a sort of self intelligent system
thanks to the wiring so this this button
I decide I would run the redstone wiring
around the outside of all of this so
let's go check that out oh please don't
be any creepers I had one down here
already yeah so this is running all
around the outside let's just start from
the beginning oh and thank goodness we
did all that redstone harvesting today
because I used a ton on this alright the
other buttons right above there goes to
this wire and it goes down here runs
along and then it branches off to this
redstone torch and this redstone here is
connected to the tripwire stuff so if
the trip wires active this redstone is
active and it goes to this redstone
torch and these two make a NAND gate
that goes up here and then I gotta get
up there I guess we'll just use that
that torch goes up to this redstone wire
this repeater and this is I have to be
very careful how I do this here because
this is the dispenser the weakness
potions are going to be in but over here
is also minecart one and dispensers are
very picky how you power them if you
don't do it right they'll shoot on
redstone updates so with the way that
goes it goes through a block to the
dispenser if I had the repeater right up
against
it would activate both of them which
would be it a no-no this also though I
don't really want this but it powers
this piston above which we don't really
want but it doesn't matter thankfully
because that this piston will be
extended if there's a mob in there so it
so it'll send power to it while it's
already extended and won't really do
anything thankfully so yeah that runs
all along here all those and it's a long
wire very long wire because it's running
on the outside and it ends right here so
there's six of these units that we have
to take care of did some framedrops okay
now the other one is the villager
transports and this will send a minecart
out of the bottom dispenser and it also
will power this track for a little while
so that the minecart will go forward and
pick up the villager and then go down
the track so we have to power two
different things with this button and we
also have to do a check if there's a
villager in there so we don't send out a
minecarts if there isn't so that gets
pretty complicated also so the buttons
right above here goes this redstone it's
stone torch and then there's this stuff
here this was the toughest part to
figure out but it's really really nice
how I got it
so this let's see where do we start from
this is the wire for the tripwire right
here you got going through some
repeaters these torches are for the
glowstone lamps above so goes to that
also sends power down here and then into
this
and this block goes to the rail power
rail above and it also branches off here
and goes to this which is the bottom
dispenser so we got two wires going here
so two conditions have to be met this
wire has to be off the trip wire has to
be active and also this one the button
press goes to this and and if both of
these wires are unpowered the torch
turns on and everything we want to
happens and that's about it that's about
it that's what I've been up to I just
learned something you guys I did not
know this if you have an angry mob
they'll actually follow you in the
minecart
that is awesome uh take that ceased oh
this is whatever I do whenever when he
pranks me she makes me feel better about
myself you know what I've been trying to
figure out is where I'm gonna put some
chests in this place and I just came up
with an idea I think what we should do
if he hits me in the back I'm gonna mad
so mad I say we need more we need more
gonna have for chess
and maybe the crafting table over there
too I think it would be good a good spot
over here I put these this these iron
bars here to kind of match this but you
know we don't need them really it's not
like you're going to fall off here yeah
let's try chess here and see what that
looks like
then we could either connect this with
that that would probably look better or
put a crafting table here because we
don't have any of those anywhere either
yeah then we can use this for storing
potions or apples or anything we need
down here minecarts Yahoo nice cool
things about up and running I don't
think we have time to try it out today I
still got to get a whole bunch of stuff
here I got it yet mine carts and
dispensers I get all these weakness
potions golden apples that kind of stuff
all all set up here I want to put I
might put like an item frame here coal
got your coal here so work on that and
then next time we'll probably be able to
see this working zombie or zombie
villagers they all go underneath and fix
it
they actually I probably won't wait a
sec let me get stone brick they convert
in three to five minutes I'm fairly
certain it that's what it is random time
between three and five minutes I'm host
found out something really cool though
that the other day looking at the game
code that there isn't
speak speak they can convert faster they
have a chance of converting faster if
there's there's iron bars or beds around
the zombie villager can shave some time
off the conversion speed so if I want to
optimize this even more I can put some
iron bars around those holding areas and
they'll convert richer which might be
cool don't know if I'll do it but that's
something else we could do
spent all this time on this already hey
me as well right
also I wanted to talk about a few things
I've been having a whole lot of youtube
trouble ever since hurricane sandy I
don't I think that's what's causing it
basically I can't watch youtube videos
anymore and I've tried a few things I've
tried updating my flash I've tried I've
been watching my internet connection I
don't think that's what's doing it seems
to be working fine I can go to like
twitch TV and everything run smooth
there but on YouTube even watching it
240p I have to buffer the videos and
they very frequently like every 5
minutes they'll get stuck and I'll have
to reload the page and refine the spot
I'm at and oh it's just the real sad
situation so I'm hoping that gets fixed
later or sooner sooner would be better
than later oh yeah how's that looking
too plain maybe
we're going to hit our head on this too
I should have brought it out like two or
three blocks
I might adjust that yet anyway
I think should get going today I had
something else to say but I forgot what
it was oh well still working on my map
and I did set blings redstone challenge
the other day I think I might upload
that before this episode so you may have
seen that already that was pretty fun
okay okay I remember what else I wanted
to talk about here there was a feature
added a really cool feature added a few
snapshots ago that I haven't really seen
anyone use yet like of the people I
watch on YouTube I haven't seen anyone
use it and I haven't used it really much
myself I've been trying to it's hard to
teach yourself to use it but it's a
really cool trick you can move your
inventory around using your your keypad
now which is really cool so if you if
you hover over an item like a slime ball
and I press one it goes in my number one
slot if I hover over flint and press
five goes in number five i press five
when i'm over the flint in number five
it does nothing if i press one they
switch so you can you can move around
your inventory a lot faster so it just
takes a little while to get used to but
I'm trying to teach forcing myself to
use it because it's a cool trick in the
game now but yeah anyway onto the
comments hello mister ethos lab I am a
longtime subscriber of yours and I think
that some new subscribers did not watch
the episode where you explained the
whole face cam thing maybe you could
take a minute of an episode to explain
the reasoning again thank you for the
great videos and have an amazing day
well thank you you too
so the facecam thing what he's referring
to is how I haven't shown my face on
YouTube and how I don't really plan to
show my face on YouTube you know a long
time ago was never an issue nobody ever
asked to see it and then I passed some
imaginary subscriber line or something
and now it's a constant annoyance type
question can I see your face when will
you show your face have you ever seen
eatos face it's a constant ah it's a
never-ending thing so my my view of it
before is I didn't really care you know
if I showed my face whatever and still I
kind of feel that way the thing is I
don't have the equipment to really show
my face like I don't have cameras like I
could possibly do it not very well
there's no real need for me to show it
though in my my opinion what I do on
YouTube has always been more about the
game and not about me so you should be
looking at what I'm doing in the game
not at me and yeah so no real need to do
it in my opinion not that I really care
although I do somewhat now the thing is
a lot of people have said they don't
want to see my face also some people
want to see it some don't so it kind of
cancels out the whole request because I
don't want to have some people see it if
they don't want to and yeah I could hide
it somewhere or warn them that I'm
showing it but you know they're going to
see it even if they don't want to if I
show it so that's one issue the other
issue is I've actually been harassed in
real life from people figuring out where
I live and getting a hold of my identity
in the past
stint it happens still and I don't want
to give out any more of my identity that
I need to really so don't want people to
know what I look like
oh hello because it that's just one more
piece of my identity I can never get
back so yeah
it's tough being stuff being a YouTube
where sometimes but overall it's really
really rewarding and enjoyable but
sometimes there's some jerks out there
so yeah anyway that's it for today guys
thanks for watching and take care have a
good day
that's what Zee still says and I just
said it to old man my bad bye bye