[Music]
oh
man i forgot about the cinematic key
slow motion camera oh yeah
it's not enabled by default anymore i
actually had to turn it on the keyboard
that's why i don't use it
anymore i don't think or i haven't used
in a long time oh i can go down the
ladder
do you see that i went down the ladder
guys
oh it's been a long time since i did a
cinematic intro and it'll probably
never happen again because it's so corny
so welcome back guys this is etho
i am in the nether uh some of you
probably know where i am i'm
like way up in the sky wait a minute
let's get let's
let's get out of this camera mode there
that's better way up in the sky
uh this is where i stand to enable my
gold form to the zombie pigmen spawning
and i've built a little contraption up
here i'm pressing all
sorts of f1 f5 keys here
okay this is the view i want so
i built a little redstone contraption up
here let me show you this real quick
uh basically uh
if i'm here i and i'm here too long
too many zombie pigmen will spawn and my
game will get
very laggy and i might not be able to
kill them if i'm here too
short not enough will spawn and i
it'll kind of be a waste of time it
won't be very efficient
so i decided to install a timer here
to precisely time how long i'm here and
then
when the time is up this piston extends
and knocks me down the hole here
and drops me down to
a place where they'll stop spawning
basically is the goal of this thing
oh yeah by the way don't forget to get
your snacks guys
i got coffee and milk chocolate here
ah so good that was my last sip
uh yeah so basically
got the hopper timer here then inside
these two droppers this is like a
counter
when i press this wood button it sends
seven pulses
to this wire this is a comparator clock
that makes
these seven items go into this dropper
and then that powers this
and it unpowers this so the piston
retracts
and also that turns on this timer this
timer can then run
and every time it it goes back and forth
it sends one pulse here
which sends items from this dropper back
into this one
so
that way this whole thing can reset a
lot
better than if it was like a straight up
10 15 minute timer sort of thing
but basically hit the button
my game is lagging a lot um
by the way maybe i'll take a few of
these items out i haven't
timed this quite right yet either
i just finished setting it up here so
it's not set for 10 minutes right now
it's set for
probably less than one but we'll get
into position this is like my aft
spot and i haven't tested these
ladders out i have some further down but
this might be
an amazing splat if it doesn't work if
the ladders don't catch me down below
i'm just gonna hit the ground
so hopefully this goes pretty quick
basically the game is lagging right now
because the zombie pigmen are going
through the portal
and the game doesn't have very good
code well it's it's not that the code is
bad but there's no
it doesn't save anything in the game to
tell where the portals are so it's got
to figure it out every time
and that is an extremely costly
operation in the game code so it lags
incredibly when i'm up here because it's
got to figure out where portals are
many times a second because there's so
many zombie pigmen going through
um should go pretty soon you see like
how the piston is
disappearing and reappearing i've
actually been up here for
probably too long
because i built the thing up here and i
haven't been down since so there might
be a ton of
zombie pigmens in the gold farm
ah that's kind of awkward isn't it
i was kind of hoping to get pushed down
by now but uh
let's go down the ladder one more time
i have maybe you guys should go read a
newspaper or something until
until this happens come on
how much longer it might go this time i
think it's going to go this time
come on come on come on
uh-oh oh it didn't go good
catch me oh they catch me good very good
that would have been
pretty sad if i lost 47 levels anyway
let's go through the portal
see what's going on over there i might
have to stop recording here if it's too
laggy
hey guy oh whoa
oh i should have got out of this f5 mode
i don't know what's going on
let's go down okay that's much better
let's push this guy off
it's like a zombie pigman laser beam i
love it
i love this new computer guys it is so
much better than my old one
my old one everything was just frozen
when i'd go through and now
it's actually animating all these zombie
pigmen and
it's pretty pretty powerful
stars are twitching what are we at
1300 i don't think it's gonna be able to
handle that though to be honest
we'll try it
i don't even know if i can press the
button i can't see the button
where's the button
oh it's on the red clay yeah i'm not
supposed to let this many spawn
i think i hit it
i love this the synchronized grumbling
yeah this isn't going to go over too
well i can tell you all that already
we'll try it
it's running so slow oh
[Music]
oh why are so many dying
that's not good did they all die
oh you know what i did i put more items
in the timer
instead of taking some out
oh well i wanted to make it so they
wouldn't die as often so i
i put items in by mistake i should have
taken them out
oh man okay well that was a bit of a
bust
where's the timer anyway
so that's what's going on with gold farm
maybe we will go
do something else here
take four of these out that was the
problem there
[Music]
okay so i decided let's work on the
library some more today
uh i i saw that it snowed
all over my red carpet here
because there's no roof so i'm changing
out
the red wool with actual red wool carpet
um i think that'll be better i'm
wondering actually now that i think of
it
if you walk on carpet does it play the
the block below it or does it play
the wool sound
oh it plays the block below it so it
sounds like i'm walking on wood now
that's cool i actually like that more
than the wool sound
aha so i'm changing all this notes
basically putting oh wait can i do it
yeah
that won't affect down there putting
spruce down and the carpet over top and
i'll be able to hide lighting below this
if i want
or if i need to i don't know if much has
changed here since last time i recorded
i know i finished up the coves
i don't think i had those done last time
so we got two of them
oh i'm missing glowstone in this one
still
okay maybe it's not quite done
that's what it's supposed to look like
so we got two of those done we
might try to hide some let some secrets
chess or something behind these
bookcases so that we can store our
enchanted books
oh yeah and i changed the pillars before
we had them a lot closer together they
were like
from here to here uh three block space
between
now it's a five yeah five block space
and i think that looks a lot better like
that
except for over here it's still just the
three which i think is fine
adds a bit of variety i'm going to try
copy this over to the other side before
we get going here
yeah because it's not built yet and then
i will be right back
there's nothing on your monitor there's
actually something there
that confused me for a while like what
is that that's that's a ufo
or something uh that's my respawn
area way up in the sky uh so i got the
the walkway down here copied it very
cool
uh let's head on up there i don't have a
pillar to end or pearl against
this will go over there
very nice so we got lots of walkway this
this second story or second floor has a
lot of walkway they don't serve much
purpose though they're more for looks
which is fine but i will make uh
some some area over here with books and
maybe tables
could be cool uh and then it's gonna
most likely dead
end here same with the other side
pretty much just doing a mirror both
sides just because it's a lot easier to
to build this because it's such a large
structure otherwise
um but as i was working on the walkways
i
decided we really need to get a
staircase
up up to here down down to the the first
floor
at the moment there's no door on the
first floor so there's no actual way to
get
down to the ground level
so we should get a staircase going i
will most likely put a door in here
somewhere though
so i figure let's do a staircase
in the middle of this so
let's see maybe we will see
one two three
could start it there
let's go one more block actually
because that way there's a one two three
four five there's a three block space
between
this and where the pillar should be so
we'll start our staircase
here and most likely let's see how this
lays out
uh probably want at least three stairs
i like to build like three by three
or odd numbers usually so
that's pretty much how i'm going to do
this i'm just going to put a 3x3
platform
up here now
i really like these t staircases too
so we're going to continue it then going
up this way
on this side and on the other side as
well
if we do three more stairs does that
take us up to the right height
no we gotta go one more i think that's
fine though
okay so now this should connect
that was actually that was really lucky
look uh if it went
just a little bit further this wouldn't
have worked we have a one block
spacing here that allowed it to work
because it goes like this
okay so that's how we're going to
connect down to the ground level
and may also make it go further out
this way and we'll have some more books
on the second floor
up over here
three four five six seven
like over have another area up here
with books could be cool
that does look neat though i like how
that looks uh the walkway
okay so let me finish this up
and we will do something else
oh this guy snuck up on me
oh run away
nope nope oh went to the right
all right getting dangerous let's end it
and there we go we got the staircase
mostly completed here
i put stairs on the back as well to make
it look
more structurally sound and
is it a t staircase or is it a y
staircase it looks like a y to me
from this angle i'm not sure if it has a
proper name
i think i think they're called t
staircases though
um so let's get some wool down and
we'll connect it over here
oh
very good uh maybe let's bring this
out at least one block
do the border let's see i got some yeah
okay do the border like this
i guess i can put that there no one will
see it nobody knows
it's not spruce like the rest of it
okay and bring this over
i'm going through so much material
building this thing
there is a lot of wood in this building
i i gotta tell you
it's crazy that sound
i keep hearing that sound you know i
never used to notice it
but like every time i start recording
that happens it seems and i
i stop and redo it because it's
it's creepy
okay get those going i think we're gonna
go
do something else though in just a bit
i had an idea for a fun little game
we could make that would be pretty
pretty easy to do
this building is not going to get any
any more
larger this way though because we've hit
the side of the cliff
it's gotten that big that we ran out of
land to build it on
so yeah might make it
come out like up to here tops i think
okay but that's pretty cool we got a lot
of paths done again today
let's go work on my mini game idea get
get it started anyway
mm-hmm so i was looking for a place to
build our mini game and to the right of
the
you've been ethod looks like a good spot
so
there's the reference on its position in
case you were wondering
boy would i love to harvest that iron
hair
what was i thinking it's so valuable
i go through these periods where like
i'll have a lot of a resource and i
won't mind wasting it
and then later it's like i'm face
palming
why did i do that i could have used that
so badly now
i actually got a ton of iron recently by
replacing
the iron in my beacon with gold uh from
the gold farm
but i do need to go caving again
sometime soon oh
it's getting night time too early
let's see do i want to do it what's
behind this hill
i want a hill to make it a little easier
to build
we need some height with it
yeah this should do okay and i also want
a bit of a flat land
in front of the hill so the mini game
we're doing
every time i record there's a creepy
noise i i tell ya
like earlier today i started recording
and it happened
like two seconds after i started
recording it's like nope
i'm redoing it and it's been happening
all day
okay so let's i might want to go even
higher yet though is the thing
so the mini game a little while ago i
talked about some
crazy safari
boat hunting game which never really
happened
uh we're doing something similar we're
going to do a boat target game
i'm not sure how high i want to go
though with it this will try this
so yeah i had this idea today it's
actually
pretty simple i've seen like a lot of
people have done this idea before
where you have a bunch of falling
targets i've mostly seen people do it
with
chickens and i was considering using
chickens for it but
we're going to use boats instead just
because they're a little easier to
create
and manage
okay so we'll do this um
the idea is we're gonna put water over
top of this flowing this way
and we will have drop can i use dropper
i think i have to use dispensers
now that i think of it i do
be right back
yeah so like i was saying we take our
dispensers
we're going to put them in the middle
here we're going to want at least
five of these five targets i believe
would be good
but we could do it as many as we want
and this should be enough space in
between them
okay so these are gonna be filled with
boats
and we can even have a buffer of boats
uh in a chest and we'll bring
bring them to the dispensers using
hoppers
and okay um we got to put
a rim i'm just mostly as
i wanted to build the whole thing out of
dirt i'm just i'm out of dirt though
pretty much so we'll have
this around it for now i'm just doing
like a temp builds
just a shell to see if this works even
because i haven't tested it yet
okay like that and then
boats are sort of two by two so we want
two block spacing
all right so there's a two block gap
here where they should be able to fall
down
and we will put signs here to hold the
water in place that we're going to put
here
although that's a bit wasteful i could
just do them let's let's run them this
way
speaking of wasteful watch me drop signs
down there
okay so that'll go along
lots of signs oh my goodness did i bring
enough
i did awesome i think i had another
stack
uh yeah so we'll get water going
all along here
and the goal will be to shoot the boats
as they fall before they make it to
the ground if they make it to the ground
they'll go through some detection system
if it's still in boat form i i lose a
points if
if or i can have hoppers down there for
example that pick up the boat
and item form and then i'll gain points
from that
so it should be pretty simple to
distinguish between a drop boat and an
actual boat entity um
let's see let's get some boats
and then i'll use a randomizer for each
of these
which will release the boats and we can
then have a
a master timer
which we can adjust to make it more or
less difficult
how can i power this let's uh
oh i don't even have cobble
all right let's do a little bit of
mining
all these poor beautiful mountains
i just want to leave her
okay let's go back
should be able to make this look nice
too when it's done uh
it's gonna look pretty ugly at the start
here though
okay that's
good this is just to test it so i put
the boat in there
see if it breaks oh it didn't break
until it hit the ground uh it didn't
even hit the wall here i thought it was
going to hit the wall
aha so we should actually try
two of these to see if they crash they
should be far enough apart but
just want to make sure
you know what this game needs to do
finally make it so you can stack boats
i mean seriously you can stack
everything else at this point
why can't you stack boats
okay
um let's kind of
do this the cheesy way and try to press
them quickly together
yeah that should be enough space between
them so
that should be pretty good i think
maybe we'll do one more boat and hop
down and see what it looks like as it
falls
this is where i need a second person to
do this for me
that should be good i i almost think i
should have built it closer this way
though because it's going to hit the
hill now
i didn't think that through anyway so
that's a little intro
to the mini game i think i'll do or i'll
work on that some other time though i
just wanted to
give you the idea see what you guys
think of it uh if you have any ideas for
it let me know before i get too far
into working on it i'll check the
comments
uh anyway speaking of comments we should
probably go read some
and we have two of them today so the
first one here says
did that bat just swim in the water
the bat went underwater
you are crazy bat you you you can't
breathe that stuff
huh scuba bat
who knew
is that normal i don't think i've ever
seen a bat go underwater like that
or is it is he gonna drown what what is
he doing
this is fascinating yeah look at that
what a crazy guy okay
i've never seen that before
that might be totally normal but i don't
think i've ever seen a bat go in the
water
like that all right so back to the
comments
uh the first one here says are you gonna
make more videos on starbound
please do i love that i love the game
and your let's plays
so i i did a few episodes of starbound
then i kind of just stopped
and i'm sorry for that if you were if
you were following the series
uh what what happened with that is they
kept rolling back the characters and the
worlds and that
and i went through playing the game like
three or four times from the start i had
to restart
i think it was at least four times i
restarted
from the beginning and i never got to
really experience
the later game because when you're
making a let's play you sort of play
slower than you would if you were just
playing
on your own is the way they tend to go
so i i don't know i didn't really get to
experience the game
too well because i just kept redoing the
beginning over and over
so i sort of lost interest with it
and from what i heard i wasn't really
convinced they weren't going to do
another rollback
soon so i'm just going to give the game
a little while and i might
pick it up again later i did really
enjoy starbound i think it's a great
game
but the rollbacks are are not very good
for
for let's playing unfortunately
but maybe later we will do a real series
on it
second one etho how did you grow
so big so fast any tips
suggestions height wise
if you mean height wise uh eat your
vegetables
get lots of protein a lot of people
don't drink milk you should drink milk
too there's lots
lots of good stuff in milk build strong
bones
make you make you big and strong yeah
if you're going for fat eat lots of fat
eat lots of sugar
if you mean channel wise i'm not really
sure to be honest there's sort of these
rules
like youtuber ruler rulers rules
uh like use thumbnails uh do lots of
collabs with big people
begged for like or not beg for likes ask
for likes
um and all those sort of things which i
didn't really do but for some reason my
channel grew big so
i don't really know what i did lots of
efforts
and and enjoy what you're doing try it
try to do something unique
too seems to help a lot
yeah i want to say thank you to you guys
as well a lot of people
really enjoyed this story i told last
last time when i was doing the comments
and some people even animated it
and did a very good job like i saw
several animations on it
it was pretty amazing so thank you for
that i really enjoyed that
thank you for watching this episode as
always hope you have a great day and i
will see you again in the next one
[Music]
bye