hey hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
one of our let's play episodes their
heads are like following me I like that
so guys another wonderful update says
come to the game we're now at 14 w 32 D
and Mojang have been busy with the
snapshot stuff again lots of new
features being added to the game which
is awesome I thought they were done
adding features and they were going to
like focus on finishing up the 1.8 patch
but no they they keep adding things
which is hey bring them on I'll take all
the features I can get some really cool
ones again I'm about to make my first
armor stand here if I can figure it out
yeah so we got colored fences we got
colored doors we have colored beacons
all the things I needed at one point of
time have come out in the game which is
awesome what am I doing here
we need sticks more sticks all right
let's do oh I can't remember now no is
it this no this this makes more sense
yeah okay armorstand
is it going to have okay it has a stone
plate on it so these are really cool
least that if they do what I think they
do I haven't tried them yet but let's
wait a sec I just want to see something
does it keep the plates of whatever one
you use like if we use a spruce slab is
it going to be a spruce slab I'm really
happy they made them like entities so
instead of just being a block these
armor stands because from what I read
you can move them around I've seen
videos of people making like little
robots which is Oh
I thought wait a second wait a second I
thought that was a thing is it not I'm
looking for nether brick sandstone stick
a sandstone one just to be sure here can
you not do this maybe it's just that one
no you can't do that I just saw the
recipe for this thing and it was like
flashing between all the different types
of slabs by just not okay never mind
let's try this thing out
we have armor put wither skeleton heads
on you but pumpkins on them see all you
have to do is click on an empty spot
that's right
and I put my pants on that is pretty
cool so you can use them for decoration
and there's lots of little tricks to
them so if I bump it does it move no it
doesn't move around can you punch it oh
that killed it they give you a double
click it it breaks right if you
right-click it pulls it off the stand I
saw something about like it even
interacts with dispensers let's try that
out
all right I have dispensers on me let's
see let's put that there and we will
automatically put on pants yeah that is
cool that is really cool
and apparently you can even put money
pick them up with minecarts
is what I read I'm just testing these
things whenever something new comes out
I like to investigate thoroughly what
you can all do with it no didn't pick it
up oh it moved oh I did get it look at
that Oh step I was just thinking of like
home alone remember when when they're
looking at the window and he's got the
the mannequin on some toy car or
something and it's going back and forth
and it looks like a person behind the
curtains dancing or something I was just
thinking about doing that minecraft with
these anyway so that is pretty cool
I like it um I've been will clean that
up later oh you got you guys fully grew
up you're not as cute anymore this guy
had a bad day where is he oh he's down
there okay I've been thinking about what
to do with these bunnies and I think we
are going to make bunny doom over here
they are going to get killed
I'm sorry guys but I need the rabbit
foots for rabbit foots rabbit feet
whichever is correct we're gonna make a
rabbit farm over here so let me get some
stuff together and we'll start building
it oh man I just tried a few more things
off-camera with these armored stands and
I think we're gonna have some fun with
them they are pretty cool like you
didn't run them over activator rails
when there to my cart and they eject and
move them with water streams and yeah
they're pretty cool I also noticed these
guys that
they make a sound just like an idle
sound is very very quiet but it's like
this little quiet chirping I don't fit
in here it's so so quiet you just barely
hear it never noticed that before
alright enough enough stalling here
let's get to it so I am going to do it's
a pretty small farm it's like the
vertical one oh I can still hear them
that chirping it's stuck in my head now
alright so this is how how we're going
to do it if we put we're gonna have like
a viewing window here whoops oh I can
already tell this is gonna go badly I
experimented with this and creative for
just a bit and seemed like it was a good
farm um okay so this block represented
where I wanted the front to be so that
means we're gonna have a hopper here
maybe Oh totally blanking what what I
did is that right let's get rid of this
then and get some logs over here that
doesn't feel right either oh man this is
why I built things off-camera but if I
do too much off-camera it's like a slip
a slide show type of thing you know you
guys don't see what happens I think I
had it like this actually yeah okay
right yeah okay
so we're gonna put a hopper below the
slab here oh we did that already
oh my goodness alright a little bit
embarrassing all right we need a chest
this is going to hold all the stuff that
we get off these guys hopper goes into
that so they're gonna sort of rest on
top of the slab here the baby guys I
guess we could put a crafting table
below the chest here as we
work that way they don't have to keep
running back and forth put that there
we're going to want some trapdoors here
as well or at least one and that goes
right here and the reason for that this
space without the trapdoor the baby
rabbits can fit through that if you put
a trap door at the top here though and
you have a half slab they can't fit
through that which is kind of cool oh I
thought they got for you for a moment
there I'm going to put a piston over
there just this little extra feature for
something I'll talk about later um we
want another dispenser I don't know if
I'm going to actually use this thing but
it's actually let's put it on the other
side just to confuse myself a little bit
more this will be for poison potions
possibly possibly let's get some logs
going up all right like this and like
this okay behind there's so many pieces
to this it takes a long time to build
okay so behind here we're going to have
another dispenser in this will be a
water bucket and this is like an
optional auto kill system if we want to
use it get rid of that um and we're
going to need some fences let's try make
the new fences too so if you don't know
the recipe for arm I think it's like
this the recipe changed but need one
more block that's the wrong type there
we go just like this ah spruce fences
that is so cool you know if there's one
thing this game cannot have too much of
its new textures new types of blocks I
think we're gonna put it right let's
just break this right here like that and
the cool thing is as a 16 gets more and
more blocks
it doesn't just increase like the
combinations you can do lint linearly
it's exponentially because every new
block you can combine with all other
existing blocks right and as more and
more get added the number of
combinations increases exponentially
which is kind of cool I guess that means
your builds can be more and more unique
all right anyway
go up like this so the big rabbits those
guys down there they're going to sit on
top of this fence here actually we might
want to not put yeah I think this wants
to be glass so that's baby rabbits they
can fall through this little space on
the left and the right of this and the
big ones cannot and we want it to go up
two blocks so that they'll try to jump
out of it even though that they can't
and I think that's pretty close to right
let's put two buttons over here and here
and we want the autocue button hooked up
so that is going to be right over here
just put a piece of redstone there so
this button goes to the dispenser click
it and that makes the water come out so
the baby rabbits when they sit on this
half slab they're going to be below the
water and then when they grow up their
heads are going to touch the water and
they'll they'll suffocate in it and then
all the drops fall on the half slab and
the hopper picks them up through the
half slab puts them in the chest
it's pretty good okay so I just did a
little bit off-camera here not too much
I added in a button here for that piston
in the back so this is a this is a
release system if they're on the half
slab and you press this they fall down
and then they're free to get out if for
some reason you want them to roam free I
don't know
could come in handy and I was wondering
maybe we need to connect them to this
fence and we also need to be able to
feed them I'm wondering if we can use
half slabs or these snow slabs for five
six seven the bunnies are so small is
the thing at six layers they can get out
you need at least seven so there's like
just a tiny little gap there I'm
actually wondering why they don't get
out here because it seems like anyway I
don't know c-can we do that we can click
the fence pretty easy there oh now I'm
stuck all right we're going to try to
get a guy in there I don't think we can
feed them through that little tiny crack
though put some stairs here maybe we'll
block this too as we do this just so
they don't get stuck where I don't want
them to be all right so we got to get a
buddy up to the top there we only need a
few breeding bunnies and the thing is if
you don't have them connect it to the
fence they are free to teleport to you
so we need to tie them down it's really
important okay I'm going to hook them to
the fence all right did that work
yeah he's connected good I'm going to
push him over there let's see if we can
get them up these ladders I put oh he's
going to give us a hard time
aren't you bunny come on oh he does
climb ladders oh oh I'll come on you
were doing so good how can I get them up
all the way maybe I'll put a few more
ladders and I'll climb up with them this
is a one time thing we don't have to
always do this ah darn mmm
spider bunny spider bunny
hey come on guy go on oh he was like up
he was all the way up almost I'm sure I
didn't do this maybe I just need a few
more blocks let's put one up there all
right come on you were so close
spider bunny make me proud oh he's up
he's up on he fell man this is a little
annoying could also just like make a
staircase or a water stream that brings
them up here let's block that let's just
do one on camera if we can come on so
close yeah we got him in so I think he's
gonna try to jump will he jump he's not
jumping kind of wanted him to jump so
it's easier to feed them maybe he needs
more places to jump to I don't know
anyway I'm gonna load a few more into
here and maybe we can try it out
AHA so we are ready to try this thing
out we have like I think I put 10 to 12
in there I lost I lost track I was
trying to count them but they're in
there they're all jumping around
whenever you relog they stop jumping and
then after a certain amount of time they
seem to just start again except for this
one guy
what is your problem bunny this one guy
just refuses to jump lazy lazy little
bunny I don't know why he's probably
being squished into the corner or
something it's good if they're jumping
because it'll be easier to feed them
otherwise it'll always try to like feed
the same guy if they're not moving
anyway let's give it a try people just
feed a couple of them Oh bunny fell down
you see that but he fell down do you
really get one from that I tried the
feed for their Oh what we only fed three
it looks like because they still had the
hearts yeah I heard the bunny fall
awesome should have two in there oh
where did bunny go so the thing is these
guys will teleport too though won't they
I just the whole release system is sort
of stupid now that I think of it because
these guys are all just gonna yeah
they're gonna teleport out of there
maybe I need to get fences to hook these
bottom guys into with leads I don't know
where did that other bunny go
I heard him fall all right let's speed
this some more I guess bunny yeah you
see him fall good
are they teleporting somewhere on me or
what
okay there's at least two in there now
let's try to hook them with a lead just
to sleep and fit through this now
they're there in there they are
definitely in there cool so if yeah we
should get a fence here but if we have
the water here right now they won't
suffocate until they grow up then then
they will in that and they will drop
their loot if you kill them and their
babies you get nothing if you
automatically kill them with the water
you will get their leather and their
their food their bunny hide bunny buddy
what's it called anyway get the food
from them you won't get the rabbit's
foot though to get the rabbit's foot
it's a rare drop you have to kill them
and you have a better chance if you use
eluting so yeah that's probably what I'm
going to be doing most of the time I'm
guessing Mysore does enough damage I
don't even need this
poison thing but we'll keep it there
just because we had the space actually
let's let's change this to let's just
wrap this around a little better
Oh invisible block hide the dispenser
you I put the trapdoor on stairs instead
of the full blocks like we started with
just because I thought it looked a
little better
alright it's cool so yeah that's the
thing I just will wait a bit for them to
grow up here oh yeah we should try this
too let's get the water out and make
sure they can fall through that when we
breed them here is there any yeah we got
a few here bunnies you see that they
fell down that's good let's go check it
do two two two they are not in the water
I still only see two where are the
bunnies going or they squish together
are they falling into ah here maybe
we'll just release this first batch just
to see if there's any hidden ones there
oh I should add oops
should I shut the water off one two
three four that one's in the half slab
hmm not too sure what happened there
all right anyway we will do another
batch after these guys and see what
happens okay i think enough time has
passed here we can try to get some more
baby rabbits some bunnies 2 2 2 2 you
may the bunnies
little squeals for got for this time oh
please tell me there's at least one more
guy in there nope can't click anymore oh
maybe we did I thought we did there at
the last second maybe not alright
anyways we got four baby bunnies now I
wonder thing is it might be hard to hook
up I added a little thing here where we
can put them on fences right away nice
and easy but I guess I can only click -
that might not work out actually oh wait
I got another one it's hard to tell when
it connects someone and when it doesn't
yeah
oops oh I did not want to do that
alright you could also use an iron
trapdoor here and then you don't have to
worry about accidentally opening it we
will come back later though I think I'm
going to try convert this room into a
bit of a carrot farm as well and try to
polish it up a bit more alright guys so
I have got a lot done on that room let's
go check it out it's pretty much done
actually might make a few minor changes
to it but here it is and we got some
bunny troubles oh we got bunnies all
over the place these guys teleports all
the time if you don't tie them down and
they're right in your face and oh I
really wish these guys didn't teleport
to you like I I understand they're a pet
but unlike the other pets you can
actually harvest them for goodies it
doesn't feel quite right but that's what
we got to do guys I'm sorry if your
bunny sensitive turn away but it's that
time this is what the farm is for oh man
why do they have to make like all these
cute animals in this game it's just not
right although I do like that sweet oh
we got a rabbit's foot look at this
awesome first rabbit's foot so yeah this
is a carrot firm I'm going to add some
pistons below this so you can press a
button and it goes up and down and drops
them all there's water hidden behind
here and here little ways I had to do
some rearranging with the horse stable
wiring because it's right next to this
actually this is the ceiling try to make
it interesting as best as I could
what else what else added a light over
here with a trapdoor and there's
lighting all along here help light up
the room and so the plants grow
I made my banner as well from mine crack
put it in here and I put one in front of
the door I didn't know you could do that
but you can put banners on doors and
then totally hides them pretty much and
this is a spruce door which looks pretty
cool I like it that's why I hid it now
it does actually look pretty cool though
but anyway it seems to work pretty
decently this will try out the auto fit
the auto killer thing just to show you
what it does takes a little while but I
have a comment picked out for today it
says Ito if you had to choose a favorite
mod from what should that mod be
favorite mod by far Terra Firma craft
Terra Firma craft is awesome having so
much fun playing that I wasn't really
expecting a whole lot out of it but it
is really really good like when I first
started playing I thought it played
maybe ten episodes worth and I'd be
bored of it but we're about we're
getting close to thirty episodes in on
that and even though I've explored most
of the content
content - it's getting late here I'm
sorry
slurring my speech I've explored much
most of the contents to Terra Firma
craft but I'm I still don't really want
to end the series because I'm having fun
with it yeah really good mod adds hours
and hours to the longevity of Minecraft
if if it's your thing but easily it adds
50 hours to the game play time but yeah
I guess it is that time again guys we're
going to end it here as I said before I
do have family visiting for a little bit
longer still um and I've been very busy
like gone all day day after day so to
make episodes has been a little
challenging just managed to sneak a
little bit of time today to make this
one but I'm going to keep trying and
hopefully in a couple days or so watch
it's like five days yet but hopefully in
a few days things will get back to
normal I might miss a couple more days
with the episodes but I hope you enjoyed
today's and I will see you again in the
next one take care bye bye