ah how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back to another episode of
our let's play series so guys we have
had a little bit of a problem here as
you can see a little bit of a technical
problem in our let's play worlds here
and I had to load a backup so I'm in the
process of rebuilding a few things we
lost and yeah it kind of sucks
I had to reform a lot of stuff and
rebuild and trying to get everything
exactly the way it was so hopefully you
guys wouldn't be able to tell a
difference between before the problem
and not we let we like pull the back to
the future here and went down an
alternate timeline so hopefully we can
get things fairly similar but yeah you
might notice like some walls being like
one block over or whatever this is the
reason I thought I would tell you yeah
so get this this is what happens you're
probably like Ito you should have made a
backup you fool that's what caused the
problem I was like hey you know it's
been a while since I made a backup I
should make a backup of our world here
and while making the backup it corrupted
my files like the way I do it is I
right-click on on my folder my city my
save world here and I will 7-zip it and
then usually move it to another hard
drive every so often I'll put it on a
thumb drive in case the hard drive
crashes and I'll even upload it very
rarely for you guys but if like there
was a fire or something I could download
it myself and we'd have an online backup
- yeah while making the the backup 7-zip
decided to not only not zip up the file
but it deleted the original files for my
world here and corrupted them so
yeah anyways I'm going to hopefully get
things as good as I can here and then we
will get to our episode for today
alright guys well I think this was the
last thing we had to do on our list to
get things back the way they were in our
world so now we can start making some
progress might look a little different
but things are pretty close I think
that's what that's the great thing about
like being able to upload videos of my
world here if I ever have a problem I
can just like look at my own videos and
figure out okay the blocks or were like
that
so I can I in pause the video and build
something like exactly just from the
video so that's that's what I ended up
doing with this worked out pretty good
so now what I want to do is fill in this
big hole here we have because right now
if anything falls in these hoppers it's
going to jam up the furnaces below and
mess up our super smelter but even if a
zombie-like was to fall into this hole
he might land on the hoppers and then
burn up in the Sun his nam be flesh
falls into the hoppers and jams up a
furnace like so that's what could happen
right now so we got to really protect
them I'm going to cover it with slabs
and then put dirt over shot so I'm
blended into the frame okay so we're
going to take a look from the distance
your guys at our terraforming job yeah I
like that so this line kind of continues
through goes around oh it's kind of hard
to see I wish I could just like stop in
midair
so that was one side of the hole over
there and other side was over here and I
think you could hardly tell there was a
problem with the terrain here now right
like if we grew grass it would look
fairly natural I think so I'm happy with
that let you get the comments on last
episode a lot of you guys did like the
design for this building the interior of
it anyways but I think we can all agree
the outside of it is nasty right we got
to do something so I know guys I know
the reason you watch me is because I'm
such a great builder right I'm
struggling with this a little
it's uh who my plan was to put four
towers in the four corners right that
would be something really simple to do
like we would put a tower here tower on
the other side that'll fill up most of
the exterior of the building and then
we'll be done just got to fill in a
little bit on the wall here right I
tried using stone brick and wood and
stuff but I tore it all down it looked
bad so now we're going with the nether
brick look I didn't want to use Brown
though because if you have nether brick
in' and like brown clay there's no
bright block for your eyes to focus on
and it just looks bad so I switched over
to magma blocks and it looks bad but I'm
gonna I'm going to keep trying here I
think once we add some details to it
it'll actually be okay my plan is we're
going to put a flame on the top of these
towers like it will have a 3x3 thing of
magma blocks up here and then we'll put
flames on top of these and hopefully try
to make it look cool right or maybe
it'll even raise it in the middle here
have the middle a little bit higher give
it some more depth alright so then this
will come up here and then over here
alright so how do we make this look
better that is the question well we got
to add some variations to it stead of it
going completely straight up we should
probably change that right that's
probably the best I can do so we're
going to roll with that and you guys are
going to like it you're going to tell me
how great it is right yeah let's try to
actually add some more stuff here too so
it's creeper no my imagination so it's
not totally plain like we'll do this do
something like that and then we got a
big flat area here let's let's throw in
some slabs or something try a little
design here and that and that okay how's
that look yeah sure looks great II so
thanks guys okay everybody so here we go
we're going to take a walk around the
building I think I got it all done now
and be gentle with your with your
criticism no critique you're gonna
critique me you're going to be nice
right yeah so this is a very different
building style than I've done before it
was actually a lot of fun to do very
dark though maybe I made it too dark
there's lots of nether brick in it you
might remember like the archway here had
some nether brick in it I changed that
to orange sandstone just to add some
more color to the building and I think
that highlights the entrance very nice
like this we've got the stairs nice and
bright Artois nice and bright you know I
love my arches and then I added a lot of
detail to the towers here there would be
over detailed but I kind of liked them
and I just copied like we have four
towers in total I just copied the design
to all of them so that's simplified the
building a lot here I just had to fill
in the wall here pretty much to finish
it up so just random nether brick
structure stuff nothing too exciting
here this side has like no orange which
is probably a mistake but like we got
the brown clay here that's being used on
the interior so I couldn't change that
unless I made the wall thicker but I
didn't want to do that either
aha and then there's this a little bit
on the back here I have to make
something random up with so decides
exactly the same we'll take a look from
from on top here too but yeah I think
our super smeltery building is done now
from a distance I think it looks okay to
like I'm okay with it look from up here
the flames look kind of cool but yeah
I'll see what you guys say about it aha
now it does stand out quite a bit
because like the area the terrain here
needs some work it's it doesn't really
go well with the green grass I think we
will do some more terraforming out here
and I didn't do anything with this
elevator yet I'm going to save that for
another day cuz like last time I tried
to work on it it took a long time and I
did not finish it and now I got to redo
it so yeah also check this out I noticed
this
while running around here I was like
wait a minute why why did my character
just go up and now I did it - now did
well what's happening here there's like
some invisible blocks here like half
slabs and I don't know what they are
we're going to figure this out together
so updating them does not make them
appear I don't remember ever placing any
slabs here which is what really confuses
me oh it's a bed oh so is this gonna be
a red bed yeah red bed lime bed okay so
the old beds get converted then okay
that's a little weird yeah I guess our
enderpearl is still here from before so
we're gonna take a little break from the
building here guys do a couple random
random fun things there's something a
building in are amplified stranger I've
been wanting to check out for a while
and now we finally have a reason to we
have ran out of flowers guys we're low
on flowers a long time ago we built a
flower farm here and we only used it
once because we got so many from it so
let's check this out I don't even
remember how it works or if it's even
going to work so I guess so you got a
hopper minecart running oh we got a
bunch of them running below these might
not work because there was a patch that
broke the hopper minecarts a while ago
we'll see I guess I never really
polished this up too well tonight oh I
think if there's any bone meal left I
think all we do got to do is flip this
lever right
yeah totally totally automatic contracts
where do they go oh there go oh my bad I
just realized the sound was really loud
so I turned it down here yeah this
flower firm doesn't work all that great
actually I noticed like the hopper
minecarts do not pick up the flowers
quick enough
like the stuff is just getting stuck up
here and the hopper mine cards are
picking up some of it but like
eventually most of this will just be
spawn right but we shut it off for maybe
it can't pick them up while it's running
you see the stuffs disappearing now yeah
I think maybe it just can't pick them up
while it's moving possibly because like
when I was running I didn't really see
any disappearing right I'm not sure how
full are these hopper minecarts I wish
we could click on them easily oh do they
unload oh they unload on this end too
okay that's where some of it might be
going then and they stay until they
empty right anyways I thought it would
be fun to check this out I totally
forgot how how it worked in everything
all right very good guys so I just
grabbed the Shanker box full flowers
here should last us for quite a while
again I use them for dyes but also just
for decoration and stuff too so another
thing I wanted to try today got the
water system working for the mushroom
farm I think haven't tested it so it
would be fun to do together so yeah each
of these dispensers has a water bucket
in and there's a wire that runs down the
middle here to the both side so there's
a dispenser on both sides with the water
bucket in an idea is like the closest
way for it to get down is one two blocks
over here while like to go over here 1 2
3 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 so it's going to flow
directly down here and not spread all
over the place I hope if it spreads all
over the place it's going to destroy
some wiring and stuff probably okay so
to turn it on
we just need to press a button over here
and this runs all the way down here and
around and we'll see how much lag this
actually causes because it's going to be
pretty crazy I think okay just get a
button and here we go yeah I think we're
good all right
uh-huh and then we'll test the water
streams to make sure they actually work
to the way we want them to is it still
going
maybe the graphics oh yeah there they go
it takes a while for the graphic stuff
update I guess that actually looks
pretty cool right I like that
okay didn't feel much lag but I guess it
wasn't drying it that's why so these are
all kind of messed up because we're
having a wiring problem still but this
one looks like it's intact properly
though so does everything go to the hole
here that's what we want um looks like
looks like it's okay make sure
everything goes there there's no dead
spot so maybe here all that's a dead
spot Oh what who knew it's getting stuck
like deaf way halfway on the block
no no oh that's really bad darn so if
they come from this side they're all
going to get jammed because I did it on
an even number instead of an odd number
that was a big mistake we can fix that
but I'll have to add more dispensers
like if the if we add a dispenser there
and one right next to it then it would
work okay well I do want to do a little
bit more with this building today so
let's get back to it here I want to do a
bit of terraforming so we're going to
get rid of the grass here like probably
a distance of about
and ten or fifteen blocks all around the
structure I'd be replaced to grasp with
coarse dirt first and then we'll try to
mix in some other things like brown
concrete maybe concrete a little bit
cool maybe some other stuff some leaves
and and all that kind of stuff then on
the border of the coarse dirt here like
like way out here we'll try to build a
stone fence all around our smeltery
building and I think that'll blend it
into the Train nicely because the way it
is right now it sticks out like a sore
thumb right it doesn't really suit it so
we have to change the terrain and blend
it together with its surroundings so
yeah we'll see how it looks after we
change it here yeah okay so this is what
I was a little bit afraid of it doesn't
look too good just on its own the coarse
dirt is not enough all right it stands
out now the whole the whole area there
not just the building so we have to
transition it a little bit better I
thought I thought it would be an issue
that's why I have the fence in mind but
we'll probably have to do a little bit
more than just a fence we're going to
try to do a cobble fence and I'm just
going to spam cobblestone all along the
border here we will mix in some some
grass and stuff some greenery with this
little bit - we're going to do it like
we did the fence over there so just
cobblestone and then going to have some
stairs
a couple stone fences maybe some mossy
we'll mix them as well and just by
making little variations and stuff it
hopefully looks pretty good we don't
want it to be too tall though like we
don't want to block up the view of the
building how does I do this before I
think I remember I think I just spammed
it right I don't think I actually
thought about it too much i think i just
banned it and it worked so we'll try do
that here let's go through and do
different layers see how it looks okay
so I've been looking at this I don't
know I'll see what you guys say about it
I think it's okay
for the most part I am second-guessing
myself though like maybe we shouldn't
have done it out of cobblestone maybe
wood would have been a better choice
because the the brownish color of wood
would have went with the nether brick
nicely and it goes with grass nicely too
because it's an earth tone but maybe
eventually like if we build more stuff
around this area that the gray
cobblestone won't really stand out as
much I don't know like for example the
way we've been doing the paths in this
area kind of looks like this over here
right so this is a great color
eventually if we connect this up to this
area like we'll probably connect this
path to like that one over there
eventually and it'll run through here
run straight through go around the wall
here between the Nexus and the super
smeltery branch to both of them and
probably keep going this way all right
once we get trees and stuff in here to
to look better but yeah I don't know
I'll see what you guys say about it we
still need to do more here though like
this is still too much of course dirt
still stands out too much one thing we
will do probably is try to mix in some
grass and maybe some leaves not too much
just a little bit okay so I'm liking
this a lot more now there's something
about putting the grass like this tall
grass on coarse dirt I just love it so
much
it makes it look really good so I'm
stabbing this throughout we got leaves
all along the fence now I'll just kind
of randomly place them through let's go
take a look from a distance here now
spend a little bit more yeah the more
details you had to build the better it
looks in the end of things I find I just
add more and more layers to it and then
it it makes it more pleasing to the eyes
somehow
all right yeah I like that more
definitely definitely much better so the
leaves they break up they get rid of
some of the great color and there's more
green so it blends in with the grass
better and it's not like one giant solid
clump of grey now so it's broken up so I
think that's that's nicer and when
you're down here these these blades of
grass make it feel like it's overgrown I
like that a lot yeah okay I'm feeling
pretty good about this build now I'm
happy with that I will do a little bit
more with it's either off-camera or with
you guys in another episode I think we
will call that for the building for
today though somebody suggested I check
out our chests here now yeah it's full
that one's whole just about totally
filled up okay that's cool we built this
pumpkin farm a long time ago and I
haven't really gotten anything out of it
like it's it's taking a really long time
for these chests to fill up not because
the farm is necessarily bad it's because
we don't spend any time in this area but
because we're building this mushroom
farm
we finally got we got some pumpkins here
so we can try to do some trading we got
two farmers here one of them this is 11
dude we don't want him we want this guy
right yeah 8 pumpkins the really nice
thing about this is you can trade up to
8 emeralds worth at a time we got 7 what
a deal with the new advancement system
is there a way to shut it off because
like everything you do gets announced
and like every snapshot it gets reset
it's going to be really annoying if
there's no way to disable that new
recipes yeah new recipes all the time -
uh-huh like every time you make a new
instance of the game you're going to get
spammed with messages non-stop wow we
did a full stack okay that's cool yeah
so there's like there's a lot of
emeralds worth of items here we're going
to cash these in alright everybody
well I think we're gonna call episode
good for today here we'll wrap up I just
want to show you the sheep farm here too
before we finish finally got all the
Sheep into place yes I just got a diam
here and it's done if you don't know
they died because like where we have the
glass here now used to be Pistons and
when they changed it so that Pistons are
solid blocks they all suffocated and I
had to replace all the sheep that took a
long time but they're finally all here
finally all grown up and we can
reinfection
once and for all where's the gray I am
sure I picked up grey wait a second
oh yeah let's get to the comment for
today guys I decided I will pick a
difficult question all right are you
ready for this this is the one you all
have been wondering about basically
where have I been
Ethan interest in this let's play then
just take a break from it man then maybe
later on you will actually begin feeling
super excited returning to its you don't
have to stop getting ideas just because
you put it on the shelf for a while all
right so a little bit of a tougher
question I have not been uploading very
much lately and I'm sorry for that don't
have a great excuse for it either
basically just didn't really feel like
recording lately and life like this
thing said I don't I really try not to
force these videos like if I'm not
feeling like recording
I don't record so sometimes there'll be
gaps and videos and like I've tried
recording in the past when I when I
don't do you liked it and it just turns
out so bad and I don't enjoy it and I
don't think you guys like those videos
as much so yeah I want to try to keep
keep things natural I did have some
stuff , like I had to finish my taxes
and I I made a big mistake I played
another game it's like I decided to take
a day off one day and play a game and
then I got hooked on it I keep doing
that and I know it's a bad idea but
I love playing other games too so yeah
that that was another issue but yeah
hopefully things will get back to it I'm
feeling a little bit more inspired to
record again so I'll try to keep it
going no promises but I'm going to try
alright
so until next episode guys thank you for
watching and I will see you again in the
next one take care bye bye
[Music]