hello
everybody this is etho and we are once
again today
playing some more let's play again today
we are some more
yeah all right so i want to address
something this is kind of important
uh it's i see it so much in the comments
now i don't really
know why but it's become a huge
controversy
and uh people are kind of fighting about
it arguing a little bit
causing drama etc etc
over over it and i don't think we should
ignore it so
the the shiny rocks uh there's been a
lot of controversy about the shiny rocks
i i put these here in my cave a few
episodes ago because i thought they look
cool
you know give it more of a cave feel
but uh they've been getting some weird
reaction
from people um i've had some people that
thought they were funny for some reason
i've had people that
were getting annoyed by by them for some
reason like
this is weird okay but there's some
people
that thought i was getting my jollies
out of
annoying people by placing these
which i know it doesn't make sense but
that's that was another kind of view
on them and also in the extremes there's
uh
there's this one guy that said he's
gonna unsubscribe to me because
i've become so full of myself like i got
so many resources in my world
i have to boast about them and show them
off in my walls
like basically that i'm not a humble guy
and you know he doesn't like that and
he's taken off
so yeah
um really they're not a big deal i just
put them for decoration i don't get what
the big
issue is so um
just gonna get rid of them and
you can see me getting rid of them i
don't have to comment about them anymore
um don't have to fight don't have to
you know you don't have to worry
everything's good everybody's happy
no more shiny rocks not a big
deal okay there wasn't even that many
it's
oh
oh man
whoa whoa whoa
dude
oh my
goodness
oh my good the comments
the comments are gone
everything's gone
it's all good
oh my goodness
wow
dude
that just happened
oh my storage room
oh did they survive yes
oh
he did this
oh man
well i'm going to load it back up
one second
man all right here's
here's the situation a few days ago
i got a new hard drive and i gave my old
one
to a friend like i got a bigger one
um it seems one of the things
i forgot to transfer over was my
minecraft
backups like all my worlds
and i've called him up and he's already
formatted it
so
no and then um
okay not too bad i i've
uploaded my world to mediafire like 10
episodes ago
right so i thought i'd just go download
it off there and
you know i might lose some progress but
at least i have my world again
and yeah apparently all people have to
do
is like report my my download for
copyright infringement or something and
they get it taken down which keeps
happening for some reason
so i don't have my mediafire download
even
anything recent so we'll have to we have
a choice to make right now
we either like
oh man sucks um like i've got my
i've got so many videos out i could
probably recreate this block
for block just by looking at the videos
and just try to repair everything that
would probably take a long time to do
obviously
the other option is to go to a really
really old backup but
i think we're going to check it out
oh man this
is why we don't mind the blue shiny
rocks everybody
okay
all right all right all right all right
i'm not a good actor we've been over
this before so let's
let's cut it here um
i did have this idea of maybe making it
last for like five episodes you know
and just like every time i go back to
the man cave i load the
blown up world and every time i'm at the
stronghold i love the proper world and
yeah anyway i had this big long thing
planned but it would
cause a lot of drama it would cause
or it would make it difficult to do
anything in my worlds for as long as i
made that last
and uh it kind of interferes with the
plan i had for today i kind of wanted to
do a
world tour today because a lot of people
have been asking for it
and this is sort of my 400k special
so thank you everybody four hundred
thousand
subs is unbelievable
and it came up so quick man that was a
big number
really appreciate all the support i get
from you guys though and i'm not just
saying that i mean it
so yeah this is my world back in episode
i do make regular backups don't worry um
i want to give you an idea i was kind of
curious too just what the cave looked
like before
because the idea with this was i was
trying to build everything to match
the general cave shape and it's
it's um it's different
um you can kind of see how stuff
progressed though
just from looking at this i guess this
is one of the first things i built i
i thought it was the mushroom farm
but no it was this and that's about as
far as
we got
tree farms over here
very cool so we're going to jump back to
the proper world and we're going to go
on a little tour of the place
and maybe i'll just describe a few
things in detail and
yeah just a relaxing episode today
oh yeah i thought this was kind of
interesting too uh this world
or this biome was a forest uh when i
first made it
i made this world in i think pre-release
the 1.9 pre-release number three i think
so the biomes were a bit different then
this was a forest this is also
pre-anvil map format um
but for some reason when i load it now
it converts it to a snow biome
even though i went through the patches
with it being
a forest still it's remained a forced so
yeah it's kind of interesting
not sure the reason behind that
there we are so everything's back to
normal the way it should be
this is our world as it is today
and yeah let's go for a world tour why
not
it's been requested for ever since i
brought the idea
back when i did the 200s
there's a lot of mobs here the 200
200 lp montage thing
um so it's a little strange for me to
give a world tour because i see
my world all the time i know exactly
where everything is and what everything
is from and
etc etc i kind of assume my subs know
that too but
really i do get a lot of new subs every
day
currently it's about 1500 or so per day
so that's a lot of people that don't
know much about
me and don't know much about my world
and
you know we want to make them feel at
home as well and it's also
sort of nostalgic to go through stuff
my world though it's not that big
um yeah i'm a little
i um
oh what's the word i fiddle fart around
a lot
in minecraft i don't get huge progress
done it seems but anyway enough blabbing
uh this was the main area where we
settled down
uh first thing we built was the creeper
face down there
and then i sort of i
mostly started developing in here
because this is where
i saw abandoned mine shaft it was the
first one i ever found in this area
and nice flat ground easy to build stuff
so
this is sort of where and straight walls
too
pretty straight walls so this made a
nice building area
we got our very very old
oh no not again i'll be right back
ah man okay sorry about that um
so yeah this melon farm i just harvested
it
uh oh and it's already grown this melon
farm i made it before the change where
mountains could grow on just soil before
you could only grow it to until soil
so that's what the back was for there
was a hole in there and it would shoot
it out so when you go in and you tilt
the soil and
put it back and yeah so that
that was one of the first things i built
as well mushroom farm over here
there this is like
as small as i could make an automated
well just about as small as i could make
an automated mushroom farm
um just made it for the kicks
um let's see what else
this thing here so you saw those two
spade responders there was
one like underneath here and there's one
over
around there um this thing used to work
it doesn't hit the moment i have to fix
it
but yeah they they come up this
staircase thing
they go up and then they fall down here
they have one hit point and
just a is the main xp farm i used for a
long long time
and i still have tons of string and
spider eyes from it
and i've upgraded it over years and
whatnot
over here we have the slime farm which
is also changed a lot
um there's a cart system here that i
need to
fix but it it's supposed to pick up
these big slimes
and then they go around a cart track
underneath
oh they come down this cartridge and
this goes all the way around
the tree farm area and you can see their
head sticking out it's
kind of a fun effect
let's see this thing here it still feels
kind of out of place but
it's just infinite water source
crafting bench oops and so forth
over here we have our
potion dispensers
there's also a hidden chest back there
and a hidden crafting table
um this thing here has
this is also one of the earlier things i
made
very proud of it i'm not going to be
able to get
in
ouch sorry we'll try it out i do have a
backup
there we go so it's a spiral piston door
our potion room over here
um storage for the potions it's all
color coded and labeled nicely
we have our workers they're the ones
that make the potions for us
occasionally i'll come in and make them
myself too
the way this thing works uh
pretty sure it was actually one of the
first of its kind like an automated
potion
system thing but the way i had it
glass bottles that'll dispense 30
and there's exactly 10 brewing stands
here
i had it timed out perfectly so i could
just make it to the end
by the time this one would be finished
but since then they've
increased the potion brewing time so i
can usually do it
a lot faster i can fill up the bottles
here
and it's everything is positioned in
such a way that i can just
barely reach the brewing stands i can
reach everything around me no problem
all the all the bottles extra bottles
they land here
so they they're easy to pick up when i'm
loading these
oops unless i throw them um
another word above is just for looks
yeah you fill that up then you get
you can select your ingredients here
that's for nether warts
and then yeah everything's labeled you
get 10 of each thing you pick and
put in the brewing stands
i'm just going to fill this up
i'm so glad they changed it so you can
shift click in these oh it's so much
nicer
all right the rest will just dump off
here so we can continue
um usually i just enter purl through
it's simpler
i'm worried about those guys escaping
always
we have the ufo cow farm which i
actually haven't used i forgot
i had it set up actually
there's a chicken farm there which i'm
probably going to kill them all soon
we've got the villagers this is project
pokemon
so these guys
these guys have not been bred these are
original villagers from
villages we found
we still need to finish this we need a
blacksmith and a priest
but they can only come from a newly
generated village basically
can't be they can't be bred to finish
that then we have emerald city behind
the doors
which i need to get to working on again
so much lag it's gonna go away
there we go emerald city work in
progress
kind of like it's big problem now is i
don't have a way of getting emerald
blocks so it's going to be hard to keep
that theme going
this is like a holding room for them
um got chests under here
some nice stairs this cow
farm so
there was a trick before or if you put
fences below
farmland you could
jump on it all you want it would never
trample that got fixed really quick
but it's still kind of functioning now
because the cows don't just randomly
jump they don't trample it
which is good so we can
control it here this
opens up the sides water flows out
harvests all the wheat
and then it all ends up over here
i'm going to take a break i i need a
drink one second
uh much better all right
let's shut this off got storage down
here
and leather there's dispensers on the
sides
for wheat seeds
uh my looting sword and
one of those
um usually i kill the cows
before i replant so it's easier
anyway that's sort of unfinished as well
there's no proper way of getting in or
out of it i have to ender pearl at the
moment
over here we have the donation tree farm
uh just a way of thanking people that
donated to help me out
oh man lag in this game needs to stop
um
seriously it's gonna stop
very good nope nope
it doesn't want to stop
ever since 1.3 man
okay anyway i'm crying about that
over here we have the actual slime farm
this is the spawning pad for
it this is a tunnel that goes all the
way to our other base the stronghold one
um
we got to move along here running low on
time i guess
see we got an elevator here that takes
us to the surface
these are kind of broken i can only make
it work by stands
just right it's kind of tough to do
uh usually i'll have to walk up that ah
man
oops
i really like how this place looks at
night i gotta say
so we have the snowflake up there
there's a portal
that takes us to another hub if we want
to use it
we got the glowing trees all around us
which have a very cool effect at night
the original glowing tree is up on that
hill this
is the abandoned mine shaft which i've
been using a lot lately actually
and lots of storage down here
mostly just stone in that um
this thing would not work anymore i
guess
i'm pretty sure it doesn't work anymore
let's try it out
because boats actually give you a boat
net well that's if you hit it
if it's being destroyed i think it still
drops sticks in that
oh no no never mind yeah so this doesn't
work anymore
uh there was a oh dana lost it there was
a
how did that work when the colored
wood first came out i built this just
for the fun of it
uh it would let you convert like jungle
wood into regular
regular blanks you know um in large
quantities
um so you would how would that work
yeah you would fill these chests up with
boats then you would break them
it's been so long since i used this
mostly the bottom ones are important you
break them all the boats
fall out and then you
right click on this causes the boats to
wash over down here and just
hold right click and all the boats go
into this thing and break and you get
the sticks and the blanks and
converts them
yep
and once that stops glowing up there the
water will shut off
and the pistons go back up all right
moving on moving on so this is mine
shaft i've shown this recently again
i've mined out everything this way
on the first row and i've started mining
this way
but let's go up again there's a few
things left in the k by the show so i'll
just cut recording for a sec
and i'll meet you back there
so i think that's everything this way
over here
we have an enchanting room
made this when enchanting first came out
it's also automated
there's uh four groups of bookshelves
that you can move up or down
to control levels of course you don't
need as many bookshelves anymore so this
doesn't work quite right
um over this way this is my favorite
part of the cave actually this area here
i've got a nice bridge this is the
furnace room
that actually makes noise when you put
items in no blocks play
there's a little wire access room back
here
which also goes for the storage room
and then there's storage for for fuel
i love the window
oh yeah also the slime elevator thing
over there
take some to that area there
oh anyway uh storage room
i like the storage room a lot and i'm
really happy with the way i organized it
actually
um i always have what i need here it
seems
a little bit of all the different blocks
fit into
six 18 chests which is pretty good
um might make a few tweaks to it if i
was to ever do it again but overall
i'm really happy with how that turned
out this is another
door thing opens a bit different than
the other one
this is where all the all the potion
ingredients are stored
and that this is a hole where they flow
down
there's a second layer to it as well
this is where the glass bottles are and
gunpowder
which needs a refill
lots of wiring involved in this project
um sheep farm i love this sheep farm
i still need to finish it sadly
uh i'm not going to demonstrate it i'm
sure you've seen it
it's one of the more recent things
and it takes a little while to do nice
stairs here
um that's about everything in this area
i think
so let's uh let's move on oh yeah
actually you know what i need i need to
end with pearls
grab a few ender pearls and we'll be on
our way
so behind the creeper face is
a little room here with a portal
wait that's for the fire charge that's
for the water
i think we're out of fire churches
maybe wait a minute how did i
how was i supposed to access the
dispenser even
oh man what have i done
all right i gotta go but get a flint and
steel i guess
one sec
well it did relight itself once the
redstone
ore stopped glowing so
maybe i press the buttons in a way i
wasn't supposed to this one
makes the portal go out this one lights
it and if you right click
the the redstone ore down there it will
turn on for a little while and then go
off on its own
and this takes us to the nether hub
which is another recent project
still under construction
this is just to make transport to other
areas in the world a lot
more convenient as we build them in the
future
currently only one side is sort of set
up
there's a selector panel to it select
our destination cart launcher
wire access back here
and
for right now i've just been running it
i hope to work on this some more soon
um gotta lay down track this track goes
to our nether fortress
where we hunt where we hunt uh wither
skeletons
also under construction
actually before we head
to the stronghold i'll show you
how do i get up again is it over here
no lost in my own world
how do i get up
um what the heck
i forgot oh there is this
there it is okay uh this takes us up to
the nether
where badness is
over this way is where most of my nether
construction has occurred
and also one of my favorite things i've
built
oh what a mess
oh that's gonna that's gonna leave a
mark
it's gonna stop
it's not gonna stop goodbye
nuts
so this is a stronghold um
dang it one sec
uh for those of you that don't know i
always play on hard
and that hasn't changed since this world
was created
i don't know if we lost anything
look at all my important stuff that's
all i care about
yeah so this way is the duo blaze farm
which is
awesome very very cool
and that's about the only thing here
actually
this is my best source of xp in this
world
or most convenient source of xp
two blaze spawners give a lot of xp
and they run it basically 100 percent
efficiency
so yep we got the
caterpillar conveyors down here
um this is the blaze farm i designed
myself
and then i made it work for this
situation so i built two of them
and tried to join them together
and it turned out pretty good took a
long time to do though
special killing chambers over here
which work really well there's a button
that's
um see which order do we do it again
it's been a while that one opens it up
so that they can
get up here so you can swim with the
lava
this one is for crusher system
that's timed just right so that it will
get them down to one hit and this is all
the timings
stuff for it up here
okay that's about it for the nether
there's
a little more but time is at the issue
here
so let all uh take it to the stronghold
next
alright so this portal takes us to the
stronghold base this is
my second main base in the world
um originally it was a stronghold i
found i have
changed it up a lot since then
um so it's got
i guess it's got two main things to it
there's a silverfish farm here
which is my ongoing struggle to perfect
um getting close though getting close
it's another one of those over the top
not really necessary for anything
things that i invented
basically what it does
there's a smooth stone generator back
here
all right and it's set up in such a way
that it can detect when a silverfish
enters
one of the smooth stone blocks and then
it's
oh it pushes it forward
and puts a new smooth stone lock in its
place so the
silver fish blocks go down this line and
they get compacted together into a big
block
and stored so that i can
later harvest them for xp something i've
the main reason i set it up though is
for mining i want to get the silverfish
uh to be able to i want to be able to
transport the silverfish to other areas
and just have them go nuts and and
destroy all the blocks and yeah
and just have fun with that there's uh
there's this up here too which i might
have to change
because i think there's stuff blocking
it now
uh it's for the lighting below
more lag that's from the silverfish i
know
so up here is the base i've been working
on very slowly
there's storage in these compartments
here
which i need to finish
and this is for
mob system stuff which i'm also working
on still
uh above let's go above i guess
so weird right now i'm blanking on how
to get out of here i just the ladder
oh the pressure of recording
yeah there's a big mob system up above
there's also
millions and millions of slimes
always now i'm gonna have to light up
the surface here
it's not something i usually do in my
worlds because i like the challenge i've
had
having mobs around you know just extra
surprise um but yeah it's affecting my
mob rates
so that's the big mob farm there
over here i'm going to cut for a sec is
the ice tray i'll show you that
very good so this is the ice tray over
here
i made this when it was changed where
you could pick ice up with silk touch
again
and it's set up in such a way that the
water freezes very quickly because it's
next to a snow block
or any solid block you can use
um and you can control that
make them go up and down
and the dispensers here create a big
infinite spring of water
which fills up the whole thing with
water whenever we mine it out
oh yeah and the reason why i'm
considering lighting up now and not
before
with these mobs it doesn't really matter
to me because i'm going to sleep and
they'll
despawn or they'll burn up in the
daylights but with slimes they
have different uh despawning rules so
they just stick around it seems
even if i'm far away uh during the day
and
yeah so that's why i'm considering
lighting up now
this is another thing i made recently
this is the
villager purifier which is not fully
done yet
um that's just about everything i guess
we gotta head to the end yet
i love it so down here is the end portal
and we just the other day made the eats
road
which is really really cool actually
i'm gonna be making more of them i think
i like it a lot
still need to do a few things with it
set up a few more
paths and also like a boat dispenser or
something would be nice
but yeah this takes us to the ender
ender
which was or it is one of the
other really good xp sources in my world
here
and i've shown that quite a few times
too but we'll just take a quick look at
it
it's a pretty long road there it is so
it's a piston pusher
system it drops them down onto that pad
and then
i look at them they come closer and i
kill them
they're all down to one hit points
so they just take a punch to kill them
they're very loud
they're very very dangerous too
but yeah that's about it for the world
tour i hope you guys enjoyed it
uh i was a little rushed through it i
gotta admit it's hard to show
everything um i don't have a whole lot
of stuff
like and some people they can build they
can build like crazy
um i'm not so good at that
i'm very indecisive about things
so something about me like all video
games i play
i try to get really good at them it's
like
i like to challenge myself to get better
and
with minecraft it's weird because it's
a sandbox game so it's not like
how do you get good at minecraft so
i guess the way i've done it or i've
tried to do i'm not saying i'm really
good at the game or anything but i have
gotten better at it
um first thing i kind of got into was
redstone stuff and making technical
things
understanding the game mechanics and
then more recently i've
been getting into pvp stuff which is
another
big aspect of the game in my opinion
i've also been trying to get better at
building
which is that's my weakest point in this
game i would say
um man there's
it amazes me some people like corrales
for example i've
been looking at some of his stuff lately
and that guy can make some
cool stuff some people just
they got the skill for it and i'm trying
to learn how
how the heck they do it
just been trying to pay attention to
tricks people do and
to make stuff look better and yeah
so i don't know with minecraft there's
always something you can improve on
and that's what keeps the fun fun that's
what keeps the game fun and fresh for me
anyway
well here we go i know everyone says
this etho but i love your videos
keep up the hard work we all appreciate
it smiley face
uh thank you very much for the nice
comment and thank you everybody for your
support
and and your nice comments too
uh you make this fun for me so we're
gonna end it with an enchantment
let's hope we get something good be
really nice if we got something good
just to leave on a positive note
game so if you could be nice
that's pretty good i'm happy with that
all right not that fortune matters on
the shovel
but it's the thought that counts all
right guys
have a good day thank you for watching
and
being great