[Music]
be a little bit uncomfortable standing
here at the moment you know wrong with
this so welcome back everybody this is
Keith oh and we are in our net the right
strip-mine remember we mined out two
blocks high all all around this area
looking for the nether rights and now
I've come back to it we're going to T&T
it up and try uncover a bit more now I
don't know where to stand how far I need
to get back
[Music]
we're talking like eight stacks of D&D
it was pretty significantly oh my
goodness now that chewed out a big area
down to bedrock in a couple places here
okay
our look in this especially for the
nether right after doing that so I can
see a couple pieces here just floating
around okay that's good that's good
another one over there got lots of
quartz exposed there's another one over
there found a few another one there yeah
yeah there's a bit around here that's
good
excellent so we got fifteen ancient
debris from that so it took about eight
stacks of TNT plus about fifty minutes
of our time to set up the TNT a mine the
debris afterwards yeah so to be honest
with you guys a couple weeks ago I
thought they were about done adding new
features to the nether update here and
they were gonna enter bug fixing and
like finishing it up but no they keep
adding more and more cool stuff to it so
I have updated again we're in twenty w15
a snapshot here with the the newest
stuff there's a new nether biome another
one the basalt and Delta's we'll
probably go check that out later today
there's new blocks new variants of
blocks we got nether brick fancy
variations we got new quartz stuff we
got set there's a new black block the
black stone which a lot of people are
excited about in like 20 different
variants of that thing which is crazy
yeah now that I've updated though we
also have some of the other features
that got added previously so the
smithing table if you guys don't know
this it's for upgrading Diamond armor to
nether right armor so I can finally do
that or tools as well I believe so I
thought I thought you could do it like
this but you can't kind of wish that was
an option like this is a way to keep
your enchantments right but if you've
already made the nether right armor it's
too late you're supposed to just put the
ingot in and there we go we got nether
rights puddle stoppers just like that
now let's try it on tools eater of
worlds and we
oh that's a crafting table that's not
gonna do it either world's can you be
upgraded yes you can
amazing for our first project this
episode guys I thought we would address
something that's also gonna be coming up
in this update I believe they're getting
rid of zero tick farms and that has some
people may be a little bit sad or
unhappy maybe even upset they especially
I think like the zero tech firms for the
bamboo you hook up bamboo to a zero tech
farm you basically have infinite free
easy fuel for your super smelters
unlimited sticks cuz you can craft
bamboo into sticks as well and it's just
really nice and easy right so I thought
we would try build like something
similar to that like an easy farm to set
up it's not too big it grows quickly and
all that kind of stuff so you can set up
big fields of bamboo but I think that's
what those people don't like doing so
instead we're gonna make a bone meal
farm the major downside of this farm
though of course is it requires bone
meal but if you have bone meal this is
gonna be probably one of the best bamboo
farms you can build we can automatically
grow bamboo using a bone meal and a
dispenser and then triggering it with
redstone which is what we're gonna be
doing in our farm and the nice thing is
if it reaches max site and you trigger
it beyond that it doesn't waste it let's
get started so I got a begin set up over
here for speed mining we're gonna be
building this near our super smelter so
you can hook it up to our fuel and I'm
gonna put it underground actually we're
gonna dig down 16 blocks here hole is
dug and we already here so let's get to
it
now I actually designed this farm for
1.50 I'm hoping it still works at 1.60
we'll find out as we do it here
we need a seven by four area so two four
six seven I always count by twos
except here I challenge my horse seven
by four I think the bamboo needs to go
right here yeah bamboo go there we gotta
get some dispensers
probably got a mommy yeah that's so it
always happens that confuses me more
than anything and we're gonna set up six
dispensers around this and now we go
crazy with the hoppers so hopper here
hopper there hopper there hopper dere
opera here hopper here hopper there
hopper there hopper here hopper here we
only really need one hopper running into
each of these dispensers but for some of
them were running too just so that the
bow meal feeds into them at the same
rate it gets used up that way we can run
the farm for longer if we want to then
we're gonna stop those barrels full of
bow meal and we're gonna have hoppers
running into all these in a nice line
our rails on top of the five hoppers
here we power it's over here and then we
have a copper mine cart that bounces
back and forth picking up I not items
bow meal out of this double chest up
here and that goes to all five of these
barrels then and down into the
dispensers for the Redstone we're gonna
run two dispensers like this for right
now but we might need to come back and
adjust that just depends on how the farm
runs here and those dispensers are being
bud power which kind of confuses me we
get that in subtract mode run it back
like this and then we have to be careful
not to lock this hopper over here so I'm
gonna run redstone like this and now
that I'll run a loop to it by the way
this is something I really like about
the barrels in the game now unlike chess
you can actually send a redstone signal
through them or put redstone dust on top
of them which makes it a lot easier to
compact certain things like what we're
doing here so that's cool fifth block up
on the bamboo we're gonna put a piece of
soul sand here for a water elevator
we're gonna install that at the very end
though so we don't wash away our
redstone and then the sixth block up
here is where we start our column of
sticky pistons we want to go up ten
blocks with these okay so we're almost
done with this we just have to run
redstone up to the column with pistons
there we do that with an observer
detecting when this redstone changes put
a piece of redstone dust on top of that
and then
run that into a block here to our first
piston and then we just do a staircase
up like this all the way to the top
listen to that music just like a zero
department loud and annoying cue also we
got the redstone done on this thing now
we just want to encase it in glass or
whatever block you want here in front of
all the Pistons we need a block and then
around the Pistons we want to surround
with blocks around the bamboo here
around our water elevator go to this
side as well and we got to build this to
the top then and then for the very top
layer here we're gonna cover over the
piston the bamboo and everything except
for the water elevator get our water in
here for the elevator and I think that's
the final step I'm gonna find out now if
I messed it up there we go all right
here we go this is the part that
actually scares me because I'm not sure
if it's gonna work or not um I got my
sound down I got it loaded up with bone
meal we're gonna want to have some
switch at the top there to turn this on
but for now do that hopefully it's
working oh it's looking good it's easy
it breaks the bamboo after it grows and
it goes right into the water column then
starts spewing out the top there let's
see how these are using up the bone meal
so that's the speed we want to see it
using it that means activating every
time that one's activating every time
this one's not activating at all that
could be because it's like reaching max
growth it's hard to tell or it could be
because of gain but powered I'm not sure
that ones are going at a good speed that
one's at a good speed so I think I think
actually this one's not running because
the other five here are throwing it
every time and it grows two blocks every
time so at five of them trigger it's
growing ten blocks to the very top there
and this doesn't need to activate them
and actually my game might start getting
laid you soon here all right let's load
her up so it's a it's gonna be quick by
the way very quick
I hope throughout our inventory we stand
right here you can see the speed that's
pretty good right well it turns out one
wasn't good enough after all I built
four of them we got four bamboozler is
put together here all red stone DUP all
loaded up with bone meal I pretty much
broke the bank on this project actually
I only got I got less than a chest full
of bone blocks left now and got through
at least two double chests into this
thing but they're gonna last a long time
like this and run for several minutes
before it runs out and whenever we run
it we're only gonna be running it for a
couple seconds probably because it
pretty much will instantly fill up our
chakra boxes look at this thing oh I can
feel the lag I can feel the leg and I
should have cleared out the inventory
first so although all the streams end up
pretty close together here so it will be
pretty easy to connect them all and then
run them to whatever we want I'm not
gonna make like a hopper collection
system for this thing though because
nothing's gonna keep up with this right
yeah this thing is actually ridiculous I
love it so much
I think it took 20 to 25 seconds to fill
up that chakra box which is pretty been
crazy for these things landing they
falling out now they're going in the
middle pretty much okay so I think this
thing I did some math on it I think it
can support about 256 furnaces running
like if this was constantly running and
the furnaces were constantly running I
think about 256 is the number which is
pretty nutty okay well I think that's
enough bamboo talk for today we're gonna
head over to our Pigman farm again today
we worked on this last episode we added
the enchanting station in here we added
some blue ice and made some other
but we were having big issues with the
big lens now I think it's all taken care
of so what I did is I cut some I don't
know you call it chasms channels into
each of the diagonals of the farm and
then I put some blue Sol torches in and
that makes the the pickling guys run
away from them and they just fall right
down those those slits we have in the
farm we also have some trapdoors lining
that so they try to walk across it you
see this rich trapdoors and it's working
really well actually like better than I
expected
there's a big limb he's taken a casual
stroll when's he gonna see the torch oh
he saw it he's freaking out he's right
in a knees down
yes I'm super happy this is working
again like this is one of the main firms
I use in my world I use it constantly
and now that gold is actually valuable
with the piglet trading it's like I
really wanted this to work again the
funniest thing just happened there's
like some new sounds in the nether that
I'm not used to yet
and I thought my stomach was growling
like in real life it sounded like my
stomach growled it's like okay I didn't
really feel that but I guess I must be
hungry
then I did it again is like wait a
second what's going on and I realized
it's actually just one of the new sounds
than the nether you get so much stuff
from these big leg eyes it's insane it's
soulless and yes gravel
yes shroom lights crying obsidian
obsidian leather magma cream fire
churches glowstone quartz it's like all
kinds of crazy stuff I didn't realize
that you can get iron from them to like
it a pretty decent amount I'm trying to
get this whole speed enchanting it books
off them so I got a level one and a
level two if I get another level two or
a level one I can make a level three
that's the max we got another level two
and a few more ones here so I think I'm
gonna combine the two twos together for
three oh it's 12 that means this is a
high level enchantment we might not be
able to put on our boots
I was only 16 really doing it okay this
is actually a bigger deal than I thought
it was so if you guys don't know soul
speed allows you to walk faster on soul
sand and soul soil and it's not like a
little bit faster it's actually
significantly faster like this is this
is pretty nice I do have a speed to
beacon where I'm at here so that's
adding to it for sure but even still
this is this is pretty cool you can't
put carpet over top of it so if you want
it to look nice that's still possible oh
we're out of food I can just feel some
of you guys silently judging me right
now it's like Oh Ethan fish what's wrong
with this guy
how old is his world it he can't afford
decent food it's because I was crafting
my golden carrots before I wasn't
actually buying them off of the
villagers I was making them and now that
we have the gold trading I don't want to
waste my gold on on food right so I'm in
the middle of breeding up a farmer
villager he's just about ready Oh does
it work on trap course it works on trap
doors okay but works on carpet works on
trap doors not on daylight sensors or
slabs though well I think I figured out
how to do my a tunnel on hermit craft
when the update comes out to space them
one block apart from each other and oh
it's a fun trip to get the ethos place
last episode I asked you guys if I
should take advantage of cheats oh here
and surprisingly just about I think
everybody said yes actually so we're
gonna cheat throw it up get all the
emeralds and I finally traded with this
guy enough we can buy the carats oh yeah
now to be honest with you guys for a
long time I felt like Sandy City was a
bit of a doom project we built one house
a long time ago and it was kind of ugly
I didn't really like it and I felt like
every other house we build after that
has to look the same as the first one
and it's gonna be nothing but a big ugly
town so I just left that one house
forever and then we got the stripped
script bark and stuff added to the game
hello creeper and now we built the
blacksmith over here and since I built
that blacksmith man it feels so much
better
just having one more building in the
city right I think this is actually
pretty nice view looking down the street
here so that's cool we're gonna do some
building today we're gonna add another
house to Sandy City and you know just a
few more and it might actually get
finished one day I think I'm gonna put a
new one over here so I was laying down
our foundation for the house here and I
got to thinking this might be a good
topic of discussion with you guys
actually like a question of the day for
you guys is this an OK way of doing the
foundation because I don't have a lot of
house building experience I'm actually
very curious what you guys will say
about this so I think the proper
technique when you're doing a foundation
is to have straight walls right but I
don't usually do that I usually will
make it like jet out a block here and
there on purpose I do that and I I do it
because I think it'll add uniqueness to
my build but I'm not sure if that's a
mistake because they makes it really
hard to tie the bill together afterwards
when the walls don't line up and stuff
but at the same time that forces me to
do some weird stuff so to finish off the
build and sometimes that can look pretty
cool the weird things I do and it I know
like this house isn't gonna be the same
as any other one I build because it's
got some unique features to it so is
that a good thing to do or not should I
be laying out a straight foundation let
me know what you guys think about that
planning on having some kind of stall in
the front here I marked that with the
planks and this is gonna be our entrance
and I'm going to probably line it with
lime for some color and then stairs on
top of that and then oak on top that
like we've been doing with the other
buildings like oak over top here Oh
snappers so check it out everybody we
got ourselves a brand new building in
Sandy City our third one oh and you just
saw our shutter system on our stall here
it closes when it turns nighttime
shutters go down we got to get a
villager in in this little area here I
did some testing and if you have a fence
with carpet on top the baby zombies are
not able to get in there even when these
are open they won't try to get the
villager inside here he seems to be
perfectly safe so I want to try get a
with the workstation in there eventually
if I put trapdoors in front of the
fences here though the baby zombies will
be able to climb up those and get in so
I just put signs in front to make it
look like it's a bit more structured um
yeah check out this place what do you
guys think I again with what we talked
about there I don't know if it looks
like cool and crazy or if it looks kind
of sloppy yeah I kind of like it though
I think it's pretty unique we got like a
back alley here we'll probably make it a
nicer path eventually some interesting
structural stuff here so I made it come
out here and get supported and then we
got like a big box up there like a tower
okay let's check out some details here
so this is a very ninja friendly
building you can easily get onto the
roof here unfortunately the daylight
sensors are bluish colour not ideal look
probably better if we use like the slabs
there spruce slabs or something but
function before aesthetics right so we
want our shutter system to close at
nighttime so that is definitely staying
in we got a pretty interesting roof here
it kind of slopes a few different
directions and meets in the middle here
we can get onto our balcony oh don't you
break down my doors man really will show
you stop doing that I hate that future I
never want to build with doors because
of that yeah you gotta found our balcony
burn to death for a little bit here we
got a Sun cover so we can relax take it
easy or growing some beet roots in our
our planter here brewing stand we got a
shelf there for some potted plants nice
view of the city from here another tulip
a little cover for when we come out so
this is uh this is one of the rooms are
upstairs this is probably gonna be like
a bedroom living area sort of thing look
out over here as well and to our berry
bushes or ninja out onto the wall you
know the view from here we got some
shutters that are open they're trying to
get me aren't they
oh did I show you here there's a real
ninja move you can get up over here jump
up jump up onto here and then you slip
the trapdoor and get up over here flip
it back down and boom we're on the roof
so we're growing a couple plants up here
as well I got string on top so the trees
won't actually grow and get down to our
floor here and then I never actually did
the interior for this main floor I
wanted to see what you guys said if you
had any suggestions and then I'll try to
incorporate them later well we're a new
terrain here you see the lava falling
down uh-huh
so before we end this episode I would
like to try find the new nether biome
the basalt deltas I haven't seen it yet
just quickly and screenshots and stuff
so let's go take a look oh that's that
all these folks they they do a lot of
damage whoa
okay wait a second wait a second good
thing we got the good carrots here whoa
I got good armor on that was insane okay
you gotta be careful yes dad crimson
forest you guys are nuts the range on
them too you kind of knock the upwards
be pretty tough those guys they are
really hard to hit without getting hit
okay so this is the new gold ore try get
some of that or chin yeah we can so
touch it yep
dude this looks so cool
so we're at 38 44 50 that's six got 12
that time I can't count anymore
Oh I was 15 that's denied oh I missed
them oh that's embarrassing oh is this
it I think we might found it yeah basalt
Delta's here we go here we go oh we got
a fortress in here too cool let's go
check this out all the little details
like the music the sound effects the
particles the fog
oh it just creates such a such a cool
atmosphere it feels like we're in a
totally foreign new area in the game
right new box okay here's a big patch of
the black stone stuff cool cool so
apparently this stuff is like
cobblestone as well you can like crack
furnaces out of them or stone tools
we got glowstone in here still oh this
is so cool okay we got a blaze spawner
over there so this is warp forest over
here we got soul sand valley over here
then we got the new basalt Delta's and I
know we're right next to the crimson
forest as well this is gonna be my dream
spot with all the biomes together and we
have a fortress yeah I think if I'm
gonna build another base it's gonna be
like right around here it's like the
dream uh-huh so do you guys remember
that feeling of the nether being maybe a
little bit underdeveloped a little empty
well I think that's gone it's like I
totally didn't for place in there now
with all the new biomes it feels really
good lots of stuff to check outs in new
mechanics I'm really happy with all the
changes Mojang have done I think the
Crimson forest is still my favorite out
of the the biomes oh the Delta one is
interesting but it's like very grey it's
like you have to build something in
there before it feels good I guess maybe
like the gray is good if you want like a
blank backdrop I guess and anything you
build is really understand
out in there so it's interesting anyways
comment of the day guys it says hey etho
how is your fitness / training going are
you still pursuing it jetpack Jan great
name yeah so the short answer to that
question is it's going very well
actually um so if you guys don't know
this story about a year and a half ago I
started working out pretty casually cuz
I was starting to feel a bit sluggish
having trouble focusing and stuff like
that if you if you don't know exercise
is more than just physical it also
improves your mental health so I I got
thinking maybe I should start working
out see what kind of effect that has
then I was just doing it very casually
like five minutes a day maybe twice a
week when I first started like I do
push-ups and that's it for the day or I
would do sit-ups and that's it for the
day and do that like twice a week which
is like nothing but I noticed big
changes just from that little amount of
activity and I wasn't pushing myself
very hard at first either I did that for
about six months it was going pretty
good I started to increase my activity a
little bit during those six months and
then summertime came around it got
really hot and I just stopped like
almost completely it got it was like
unbearable to work out in the heat so I
just I kind of gave up for a bit got
lazy with it as well but then autumn
came around and I start working out
again and then like from autumn last
year till now I've been working out
pretty regularly I even went from like
twice a week to probably five or six
times a week now but I'm still pretty
casual about it maybe work out like ten
minutes a day just at home don't go to
the gym or anything a lot of people
think you have to go to the gym to get
into shape you don't you can just start
working out at home guys you can do it
right now if you really want you just
gonna talk yourself into it I have
started doing a few activities that are
more difficult though I'm one of my
favorites that I saw like the best
results with was like I think you call
it a neutral grip like between a chin up
and pull up except I don't use like my
full grip strength I only use the tips
of my finger
it took a while before I was even able
to do one of these things
once I started doing those that man my
shoulders got big and my my arms and it
works the abs and everything pretty much
yeah so I'm trying to get into more
difficult activities because I find they
have a better results once you've been
doing it for a while yeah I definitely
definitely noticed some big improvements
of getting stronger don't quite you have
a six pack yet but there's definitely
some shape there and just overall
feeling pretty good about it so yeah I
recommend you guys try it out if you if
you can spare five minutes a day or
whatever anyways I'm gonna stop rambling
hope you guys enjoyed today's episode
thank you for watching until next time
happy yourselves a wonderful day take
care bye bye
[Music]