what is going on how's it going
everybody welcome back to another
episode of minecraft wow you know this
might not look like anything special to
you guys but and all the time I've
played this game all the years even
during the Alpha and the beta days I
have never once not once have I seen the
hostile mob cap broken look how many
zombie pigman are down there that is
insane I don't know what's going on I
did not move these guys here there's no
spawners here they just spawned I've
been afk up on that platform for 3-4
hours trying to farm up some gold and
came back to this and some other sad
news 9 of my iron golem seem to have
died in that time which is very weird
because I haven't seen them take damage
like while watching them so yeah I'm
pretty sure that's more than 70 zombie
pigmen rights it's more than 80 we've
gone far beyond the mob cap and I don't
know why did they raise it I wonder very
interesting I think what I'm gonna do
I'm gonna climb down here let them
despawn and let them respawn maybe I
just didn't notice it was higher or
something absolutely crazy okay let's go
down okay I went up and they were still
all there so I went back down waited on
the nether ceiling for five minutes
guess just died and now we're gonna
check it again so it's been 5 minutes I
actually stopped and waited for them to
de-spawn and there still seems to be
quite a few up there
don't know if that's okay it's reading
98 so that's probably about 80 which is
like the most you will see naturally
spawn yeah it's been about five minutes
and they're pretty much all back I would
say I took a screenshot of what we saw
before and put out a dot on each of
these guys heads to count them and there
was a hundred and ninety so I was like
two and a half times more just about two
and half times more than there should be
which is pretty weird pretty weird
pretty cool anyways I want to see how
much gold actually got unfortunately my
iron golem died so probably didn't get
as much as I hope for Oh are they oh it
almost all filled up okay
good thing I checked it when I did and
get you rid of all these why am I
getting uh oh you know I'm not supposed
to get gold swords in there I wonder if
one of these item filters ran out so
when the cart goes by at the start here
it picks up one item out of each of
these hoppers and that fills all its
slots but I got to keep these stocked up
oh yeah one of them ran out two of them
ran out and if the mine car has a free
slot it can pick up swords and stuff too
so get a refill these alright everybody
so the next thing we're gonna do here I
just gotta grab some redstone I need it
I love it can't get enough of it we
totally ran out last episode was not
able to finish that nether hub project
so it's gonna grab a little bit here go
finish that up and we'll check it out in
just a second
all right I'll see you there there we go
did that work hopefully that's good
enough I was like take 50 on this stupid
spin guys I couldn't I couldn't get it
to work my mouse kept sticking in my my
cursor was going up and down when I
stranded the spin anyways here we are in
the nether I finished up the redstone
circuitry here so it does a full loop
now let me just give you a quick
demonstration so this lever turns the
power on this one controls
system that allows the signal to pass
through or not goes all the way around
oh look at that
so cool if we retract the piston then
the signal can't get through so these
all just turn off but what that allows
us to do if I ever get sick of the
pattern or whatever we got our light
show here I can always change it up we
can kind of program it in so if we turn
the power on if we want like a quick
pulse do something like that and then
only a couple lights turn on and you
have didn't even have several signals
going around at the same time oh I did
that wrong I'm still learning okay this
has to be there we have to keep it like
that
okay unpowered this is a little bit more
to do than I thought but yeah we didn't
have like several lights going around if
we want or just one we can have a really
long one really short pulse whatever we
want is pretty much possible and then to
clear it we just pulled that lever and
it all gets reset that's pretty cool I
think what I'm gonna do have a quick
pulse yes okay there we go that'll be
our light show for right now if I want I
can change it later just kind of keeps
going around and around it's not causing
too much leg either so let's that's
pretty good I think I like it
okay we're kind of zipping around our
world here today all over the place
sorry about that but I did want to stop
by the Nexus here really quick just to
point out something I was having trouble
with item elevator here right in the
comments you guys told me what the
problem is and it is something I did not
realize with these item elevators
apparently there's a speed limit to them
did you know that I didn't know that you
cannot just like have a long ice like a
long chain of ice here and have the
items go full-speed into it you have to
slow it down before it enters elevator
like you guys said three blocks before
slow it down otherwise items might shoot
out like I was having trouble with which
I had no idea no idea you also
said I should close this up here to like
make this a solid 3x3 so won't jump out
of the corners or anything like that I
think it's good on that side all right
so hopefully that'll fix the trouble I
was having with this and you know what
this made me realize I had trouble with
these item elevators before and I didn't
realize it in the end
oh is that okay yeah I think that's okay
in the end I was having trouble with the
thing that dispensed our ender pearls I
was losing about half the ender pearls I
had no idea why I bet you it's because
my item elevators messed up there so I
just want to go check that out again
we're zipping all around our world today
but to the end is where we're heading
next
okay so this is the item elevator I bet
you I bet you that's the problem with it
the one down here careful careful
careful yeah this see I got this long
straightaway again I could not figure
out where the ender pearls were going I
don't think I slowed it down here either
no I didn't yes we have answers answers
to our problems I think that'll do it
right should do the trick now let me
very carefully I thought I use gray
glass here I guess it was blue I'm in
very carefully tried to make the 3x3
just in case that matters too okay you
guys said just to do it around the
bottom all right all right so let's get
out of here
but anyways guys let's get started on a
project for today shall we yes yes what
are we gonna do what's the plan well you
know what I realized we've been doing a
lot of redstone projects lately like a
lot of them we haven't done a lot of
building lately so I kind of felt like
doing some building today and we're
gonna maybe build something over here we
got this big empty field got a couple
trees here but nothing else really a
little while ago we built this fence you
guy said you liked it
this path needs a bit of work yet but
with this fence you thought it would
look better if we had maybe some breaks
in it like a gate for example somewhere
would probably be nice so I was thinking
we could build a couple houses or
buildings in this area here and then
might have the path branch off through
the fence come out this way I have a bed
right over there I use that bed all the
time it's just kind of sitting out in
the open if we build some houses here
maybe we can throw the bed inside there
and have a couple other things here too
would be cool ah first place I'm going
to build is maybe over here we have a
nice flat spot pretty open and I was
going to build a blacksmith all right
that's our plan we'll see how this goes
if it goes well we might build more more
buildings here so we could have like an
inn and salon or a bar or something like
that there's a lot of options for for
little village but we'll start with a
blacksmith and first off most important
piece is the furnace try to decide how
much space we need you know I don't know
how big the building's going to be I
don't want it to be too too crazy big
but if it does end up big I don't want
it to like encroach on the fence there
and our farm so maybe we'll try move it
a little bit this way and just don't
want it to close this tree we just kind
of want to snuggle snuggle it in here if
we can all right yes it's probably a
decent spot so I'm gonna start with the
furnace brought some netherrack let's do
something like this light it on fire
and nothing too crazy we'll just do a
little one all right I think possibly
we're going to be getting the snapshots
this week guys and I am pretty excited
about that
been waiting a long time for it a long
long time as I've you probably I can't
wait to see the changes
and explore the end content and all that
stuff should be fun alright so maybe
we'll just do something like this and
build up the back a little bit here
let's let's try two different things
here we'll try with the stare at this
height so like this oh it's nighttime
good thing I got that bed right bias I
use that all the time like seriously
it's insane
alright that's kind of cool or we could
lower by one do something like this
maybe is that good
alright building isn't exactly my
specialty oh that's that that's actually
pretty good looking too now I'm never a
hard time choosing alright maybe then
what we'll do is build this out and we
do actually let's not put this right
here let's maybe move this forward one
because I don't want it to line up with
the chimney alright and then every three
spots I like to work with odd numbers do
something like that we're just going to
build a covering over top this area too
and this will be like kinda outside but
with a covering they'll feel pretty open
I hope alright get another one over here
and just put back a little fence here I
brought some spruce fences that could do
something like this
running along alright get rid of all
these rocks I don't really like these
rocks you know I tried it out and after
living with it for a little while I
don't like them too much should should
should do something different with it I
think alright then we will do more
fences like this and build this up
alright give me a little bit of time to
build off camera here we will try
actually I'm going to build a roof over
this because it'll probably take a
little while okay guys I think I got the
shape of the roof figure it out here I
just
realize something though it's quite
possible it's low enough to catch fire
that's my only concern but we will have
to see because I was thinking we could
have a beam over here running down the
middle is that far enough because what
does it do it goes one I think that's my
answer
yeah that's not gonna work is it darn it
what if I put stone here cuz I don't
really want it to be a super high
ceiling as a thing I'm just going to put
stone in those two spots because it goes
1 2 3 4 5 I think this can still catch
fire can it I think that's the limit
it's got to go one higher yeah I think
so I'm going to leave it for a sec just
to be sure dope very cool so we got our
blacksmith covering area out by the
furnace it's not quite done I don't know
what to do here what do we do it kind of
messed up my pattern I had going on so
gonna do something special on that end I
guess don't know like I tried to add
some detail to this thing I put some
beams across here I don't know if that
was a good idea or not it makes it a
little bit more closed feeling a little
bit more square but it does make
structural reasoning right it makes
sense like I also put beams across this
way too
and from a distance it looks pretty
decent I would say you might want to do
a couple more things to it but from from
the kind of diagonal side angle over
here I think that looks pretty good like
that's that's what we're going to see
most often as we go down this path
that's that's a view we get something
like that so yeah that's all right so
the idea is we're going to have a path
probably somewhere around here and it'll
connect to this building
I like this go around to blacksmith area
should we do gravel here gravel or or
dirt
I'm not sure I did bring gravel with us
and andesite try mix up some some stuff
I also brought puzzle as a possibility
we'll try gravel first so but basically
I'm gonna have a rough ground ass type
of area and I want the house like
there's going to be a house - like a
building - this I want the front
entrance to be right around here is the
plan and it'll it'll go like this and
make an L they'll go down along this way
is the plan so it's probably going to go
into our field here a little bit but I
think that's fine
what I also want to do had an idea if
the house is going to be over here let's
make a basement for it like a cellar or
or something some sort of underground
type of thing to it we'll start that
over here okay
so we're gonna have some stairs going
down I think that's good we'll try it
like this like this it'll go down into
our basement just a little area could
make some fig barrels or something under
there and make it look like a wine
cellar is an idea or we could have I
don't know something crazy
some random contraption underneath would
be cool to something with character so
we got our furnace we're gonna need an
anvil of course
so could put that over here you need
water
right I got a quench the blades there I
think this guy that works here is going
to be a minecart blacksmith which I know
is not a thing but in Minecraft is not
that many things made out of iron so
maybe he's going to make mine carts and
minecart tracks will decorate the
outside with a few of those grab some
water
could do a cauldron with water or we
could just make a basin out of blocks
you know what I mean like have um like a
three-wide thing you know what cauldrons
probably better yes so the house is
gonna go like right here I think so
go there kind of come out like this go
forward a bit just kind of get a rough
idea of my shape all right and probably
about this wide or so going down this
way
Oh snappers it's coming together guys
it's starting to take shape here
actually having a lot of fun with this I
don't you know I don't do a lot of
building especially not houses like this
but I should it's fun it's a nice
strange so what I did I decide to do the
front like this gave it a porch so you
got to go up a block to get into the
front door yes still no house here
unfortunately this is like the feeling
to the cellar area dark creepy basement
which I like a lot we're not going to
put a door on it or anything we'll just
keep it open like this and maybe have
another way of getting to it from inside
the house would make sense but we might
not either we'll see um yeah starting to
come together here feels good
of course it's going to look a lot
better once we go through for a final
run-through and just add more detail
like like this like bushes and stuff
it's the detail that really makes a
build stand out and you might be
thinking etho you messed up boy there's
no windows no windows well we could
maybe put some tiny windows here but you
know what I realized
guys I thought ahead without even
thinking about it
the Sun rises in the East sets in the
West so that makes that the south which
means this side of the house is actually
on the No
earth so there wouldn't really be any
windows here ah so we're going to put
the big windows on the other side of the
house especially since yeah it's not
going to have as much character as the
front side probably so throw windows on
that side will be good and yeah it's
going to continue on with it a little
bit more here
very good we got a couple more things
done on the place here guys let me show
you this is our street view first off so
this is an angle we're going to see the
building from most often as we go down
this path here
I think that's alright and if we go down
here now we got leaves along the path
here
I think that's adds a nice touch to it
through a bush in the corner there put
some coal by the the furnaces like a
smelting material or charcoal or
whatever it is and totally forgot about
armorstands you know I don't use these
too often I forget about them but yeah
kind of makes sense for a blacksmith
right
put some gold armor on that then if we
go actually let's look on the left here
so I I put in a garden area here didn't
really plant anything yet but I did
bring some seeds and stuff so we'll
probably have a couple rows of oh no we
can't do that I forgot about that okay
we're going to plant flowers here yeah
flowers not - not carrots and potatoes
totally forgot you can't put trap doors
on tilled soil come on trample how hard
is it to trample I don't think I can
because that's that's there all right
let's grab these I'll put them back
later put it in a few windows spots here
this is inside just put down some birch
wood flooring nothing too fancy I really
like this for flooring the birch wood I
think it looks good I liked having a
nice bright floor
um south side of the building is where
the the wheat field is so didn't really
do much back here gonna fill this area
with wheat as well and this fence is
really annoying oh come on oh I can do
it from here easy there we go now on
this side I decide to try to do
something here
you know people stack wood outside their
houses and they have a covering for it
usually tried to make like some some
staff logs here drying out and we'll
probably put a fireplace inside kind of
works that you really need the cracks
between the logs over to look good right
it doesn't quite work in Minecraft but
yeah anyways that is our our blacksmith
building so far I think it turned out
pretty good oh yeah yeah please remove
shoes guys now you might not know this
but like I I visited this the u.s. quite
a few times I noticed there people tend
not to take off their shoes in buildings
in Canada that's considered pretty rude
if you don't take off your shoes on you
when you visit someone's house so yeah
please remove shoes before you enter
kind of a cultural difference suggest
although it varies between families I'm
sure anyways I had a lot of fun with
this today I think we're going to wrap
things up here though I didn't quite
finish it didn't build the basement yet
or anything it's a big building takes
quite a bit of time but comment I picked
out for today it says heyy
so do you ever get angry when playing
the games mmm I think he means get like
get angry while playing games in general
ah you know what not usually not usually
pretty much never actually you know when
I play video games and I think this
should be true for anybody but you
should do it for enjoyment you shouldn't
do it
like usually people get angry in
competitive games like when things
things don't go their way um you're
taking it too seriously then in my
opinion if you get angry playing a video
game you're you're taking it the wrong
way
you should be playing to have fun and if
you're not having fun you shouldn't be
playing it is my opinion so sometimes I
do get frustrated like games have
glitches and stuff but not usually angry
if something frustrates me with a
specific game I'll I'll usually just
stop playing it because there's
something wrong with it type of thing
but yeah like games that fun games are
probably the best form of entertainment
in my opinion one of the best way better
than TV I would say anyways thank you
for watching guys hope you have a
wonderful day take care bye bye