[Music]
ah
man okay so as writing my minecarts back
to the nether hub rights and there was a
zombie pigmen on the track so i panic
because he i bounced into him the
minecart was starting to go the wrong
way
so i panicked and instantly hit like
shift and
a whole bunch of other buttons one of
those was q
i threw my sword on the ground and
i'm like chasing after my minecart as it
goes back
a thousand blocks that way or whatever
caught up to it got the mine cart go
back to pick up my sword and it is
gone
yep one of these fools stole it
oh no and i just lost sight of him he
was right here he was like right there
my good sword
did he really just vanish no he couldn't
have
it's one of you right
i should not have stopped to explain the
story it wasn't even a good story
oh
did he fall down no i'll look for him
one sec
oh you sneaky little guy man he found a
cave here
all right so this problem is i also lost
my boots today i accidentally let them
break
at most we will be able to take two hits
from these guys probably
so we have to be very careful here
[Music]
when we make our escape
see can we get through here oh this is
not going to end well is it
they're going to be forever mad at me
too
let's go straight up is that is that a
plan
[Music]
oh man i'm so scared no they're they're
still on wandering up there i just saw
their feet we need them all to fall in
this hole because there's no way out of
it
come on guys i hear you up there
block it block it block it we're fine
we're good
okay that's my escape i'm getting out
[Music]
go go go go go go go go
yeah they all landed in there awesome so
i think we can get out of here
we gotta get to there and then go down
the rail
you guys mad at me we cool we bros
they seem fine
yeah they're cool all right not too bad
all right so let's do some enchanting
here guys i got a few levels to spend
i was just out at the wither skeleton
farm accidentally let my boots break so
kind of want to get depth strider again
no
let's try again oh do i want blast
protection i'll take it if it's got
depth strider oh that's terrible
one more try yes
oh and it's just that seriously
okay that's not bad though as long as i
have some way of getting it i'm happy
because i can probably combine
even the ones i'm wearing with that
and get that strider let's see what it
would cost
yeah i could do that if i want um
okay so we got that i'm also curious if
i'll be able to repair my sword again
here this is like
at least the third time i've repaired it
i think
let's check that out oh this guy i came
upstairs here and there was a piece of
gunpowder here i think he killed a
creeper
in my base which has me a little
concerned
because i don't remember killing a
creeper up there
all right sword that's yes that's how
you make a sword okay
there we go it's been a long day oh i
can do it
maybe i only repaired it once then twice
okay that's good still has some life in
it
um today i i asked last episode what we
should do
what would be your preferred project we
work on today
check through the comments actually lots
of different things were suggested
but i think the main one
was the nexus and probably the second
main thing
was what we're going to work on first
here
that's right we are going to be working
on wilson the library
haha sorry wilson fans it was close it
was very close
but i think the library fans had you
outnumbered by just a little bit in the
comments
so yeah we're going to work on the
library today also known as the bane of
my existence
but uh we're gonna do it we're gonna get
it done
the only condition i have
is that we're gonna destroy it i'm
tearing this sucker down
that's right library finished
no no if we're going to do this i want
to do it right
i don't want to keep working on this
piece of junk
so if you had some attachment to it take
one last look
uh we're going to redo it from scratch
we're going to make it cool we're going
to do it right
and we're going to try to do it in a
similar style though so if you did like
the style
don't worry we should get something kind
of similar
but when i started this i didn't really
have a clear plan in mind
and kept working on it with no clear
plan in mind and it just kind of turned
into
meh so
now i have a lot of ideas and i want to
i want to make something really cool
here so
let me tear this baby down um i would
tnt the whole thing except i do want to
save like a lot of these blocks like the
carpets and
the bookshelves there's some redstone
stuff in here some quartz
don't really want to blow that stuff up
all right we are very close to getting
ready to build again here
just doing the last little bit of
demolition
i've been tearing this thing down for
over an hour it's taken so long
such a huge place or was
is the key word there um
we're going to build something of a
similar size though i think
can i not light stairs on fire i guess
not
uh-huh but uh yeah i'm gonna just
finish tearing the rest this down and we
would get to it here
i'm going to use some tnt on these
windows because they are
real pain to uh deal with
all right good
yeah it turns out these dark oak stairs
do not
burn the regular ones do
these ones don't and i don't think
spruce would but we'll see
oh spruce does burn yeah spruce burns
maybe it's just the new ones like the
dark oak and attitude never got added to
the list or something
yeah so we finally got it torn down we
can get the building
oh i've been looking forward to this
let's do it
so i'm gonna have to do a lot of
building off-camera i think but we'll
start together here
what is this hole in the ground i did
not fill this in
no i just dug this actually this is
where we're going to start the building
this is what i'm going to call the
enchanting pit
it's going to be a key feature of the
library i think
and i just placed this here this is
where i wanted to align the enchanting
table
right over here okay so back wall is
gonna go
somewhere around the edge of the
mountain i'll just kind of explain
things as i build here and
anything repetitive i'll do off camera
but uh
trying to line it up so the back of the
building is going to be here
we're going to build it kind of from the
middle outward we're going to
inside first not the exterior
that was the mistake i made last time if
you're building something with a lot of
function in minecraft do not
build the exterior first build it inside
out because you will have trouble
otherwise right
so i'm just going to set up an
enchanting station here
perfect for the library right
bookshelves nice
so this is the design i usually use when
i do
enchanting because that's 15 bookshelves
right it's five plus five plus
oh math wait no that doesn't add up
here let's try and chant something i'm
sure i use this design every time
uh let's put this thing in let's see if
it goes up to level 30.
oh it does okay five plus five
five on the bottom oh i'm well over whoa
whoa i think i went one
too far out is what i did all right
there we go enchanting is hard okay
i think we'll do that and then i usually
throw an
ender chest which i just placed let's
get this back
right in the middle and i want to set up
like an
anvil dispenser type of thing here so
maybe we'll build up the bookshelves a
bit more
try to make it more fancy
we will put um
should we put anvils like over here-ish
tell you what let's put some bookshelves
behind there
get rid of this garbage
uh maybe yeah let's do this i'm gonna
put like a shelf
here and then anvils on top of that
and change the ground out here with
something like oak we're gonna build
mostly out of wood on this project i
think we'll use
dark oak for any pillars we'll use
spruce wood
the planks for the general ground
and then this oak wood for anywhere we
really want to highlight
on the ground it's a little bit brighter
let's throw crafting table in the back
here we'll probably need it
okay good tell you what let's
actually change this out to a
spruce slab
oh man okay this is going to
take a long time i think to build
yeah okay i just want to do this with
you guys so i want to
anvil up there and then we're going to
put a bunch of anvils on top i tested
this out in creative they don't
really take damage usually when you
are just dropping them one block like
that
so i think we can do that and
i don't want to see the other anvils
though so we got to put like a block
right there to hide it so that's the
height of our enchanting area
that we gotta try to work out here
huh ah yeah
i'm starting to get a good feeling about
this i think that's pretty nice
i want this to be really
detailed this is a high focus area right
here
so we want to make it as fancy as we can
and i don't like how this is starting to
look kind of flat here so i have a plan
we're going to do kind of like what we
did
before with the library where we had
those railings
with like the fences we're gonna put one
of those up here
sort of so you gotta bring this out more
give it more 3d
depth to it and
yeah let's let's add a well
maybe not wait a sec let's look at this
again
that does look cool right that adds a
little bit more to it
uh let's do it like this let's add
slabs here oh it's getting pretty high
though
no you missed you failed
i want it right right there good
yeah that's that's like the build limit
right there
and then fences on top
so this will be like the floor up here
at this height here
and then you can look down into the
enchanting pit from up there
um yeah i think that's cool maybe we'll
even make this
come out more
how's that does that make it better yeah
i think so
gives it a more like it's trying to give
you a hug
feel i guess i don't know um
i'm gonna add some spruce around here
i'm gonna do some more building off
camera here in just a sec i just wanted
to do
a bit more with you and let's let's try
to make this
fancier too instead of all flat let's
put stairs here instead
maybe we will do it towards the
enchanting table other way other way
yeah like this okay
just to add a little more detail to it
and then we'll put spruce underneath
here
aha all right well it is coming together
here pretty nicely i think
liking where we're going uh we're going
to go do something else pretty soon here
i just want to do a little bit more
building
i feel like i'm on a roll right now i
don't want to stop
um i went and got the banners that we
have at the rabbit farm and copied them
just for looks got an
enchanted oh enchanted bottle up there
and i'm gonna put an armor stand well i
have one there but i want to
dress it up with some armor too just as
a decorative thing
now anywhere i need to fill space this
is really cool all i have to do is put
bookshelves
that's the nice thing about building a
library if you don't know what to put
somewhere just put bookshelves you can
never have too many
uh so i got those here got a light there
it's gonna put carpets
i don't know if i want to use red carpet
i might use
not all just red carpet like we might do
gray
over there because we don't really want
it to stand out
yeah i don't like that standing out so i
might make that gray
um what else what else
i think next what i want to add i had a
hard time deciding
um where to put the staircase to get up
out of this pit
i was either going to put in the front
here but i think we'll have two on the
side and
and the reason for that i'll explain in
just a little while
but uh yeah i think we'll make it go in
like that and we'll run these beams all
the way up to the ceiling and use them
to look like a support beam for the
ceiling
oh i turned my sound up oops
i was uh i took a break and did some
other minecraft stuff for a while
um but now i'm back into it all right
uh yeah we'll put stairs here
oh i don't have any stairs i put them in
the chest
there we go where should we start them
should we start them like right there or
should we start them a little
further maybe here we will see we will
find
out and then
i kind of want the stairs to go like all
the way up to this level here so we'll
have another staircase going up here
have not decided what to put in these
spots i'll either put like a
door here to go into a secret area type
of thing
or i was considering putting water here
like a little water fountain
and then have a pool of water uh like
that goes like this
kind of but i'm not sure
okay guys so i did go with the water i
tried it out here you will have to let
me know if you like it
and i did some leaves and organic stuff
around it too made like a little pond
um makes perfect sense right
every library i've gone to has a water
fountain in it somewhere
yeah helps to moisturize the books so
that
you don't get paper cuts yeah perfect
sense okay
um put in the staircase added some more
banners here i'm gonna probably change
this to a different banner
design than that one just for some
variation
but it'll be something colorful
hopefully got the stairs going up
and then we will have some sort of floor
area here baby zombie
um pretty happy with how much i got done
here though all right and then
this is a curved area with a like a
balcony thing check out the view from up
here this is what i wanted
like this is what i was initially
planning for like a little
raised section so that you can look down
in the pit and
and get a nice view of everything i
think that's cool and i'm gonna have
half slabs
i think at this level too so that uh
i like this so that like the fence still
stops you here but you
you get a nice view otherwise you're
like down like this and it kind of
blocks the view a bit more
and if you want this way you can jump
over it too
which i probably will do all the time
instead of using the stairs
but yeah this area here the reason i
wanted this
we are going for function big time with
this build
so we got the enchanting station here i
also want
a dispenser type thing for each of the
different types of
book enchantments because we're going to
have a
storage for all the enchanted books we
get and i counted
there are 25 enchantments in the game
right now so
one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven
twelve i counted wrong somewhere i think
oh wait maybe not
here let's get rid of that leaf maybe
we'll have to do it like that so that's
i believe and then if you do it again
it'll be 26 so we might do this
if we can pull it off i would love this
because then
it's like i'll have signs in the middle
saying what each of the buttons does and
like i might hit this button and it will
call an unbreaking three book and
either have an item elevator somewhere
that brings it to us
or like a slime block launcher or
something we'll
it'll deliver the book right here though
like right here
so that we can get any book we want for
enchanting
and also have some storage thing for
putting the books we get enchanted that
we get from enchanting
into bulk storage somewhere i don't know
i got lots of plans with this place we
also need a spot for all these
librarians
we're probably going to get at least a
dozen of them maybe more
um we also need a spot for the comment
of the day
and kind of wanted to build like a
little bank fault
maybe if i'm ambitious i will build an
armory
and tool station as well because that
kind of goes hand in hand with the
enchanting
but we'll see how much space this all
takes
but yeah that is the start of the new
library let me know what you guys think
about that if you have any ideas
okay so i decided let's pay the village
a little visit
here in particular there's one guy
i've had him stashed away for a little
while
because i wasn't sure if i wanted to
like really keep them
this guy here he's actually pretty
amazing now that i've
like looked into it more so he's a tool
smith
uh we're gonna move him over to project
pokemon and keep him there
so that nothing happens to him but uh
basically
he has a pick enchantment here
for 12 emeralds that's the cheapest you
can get it
and it's efficiency three unbreaking
three which is just about the best you
can get
um what it does is it randomizes between
a level five and level 19 enchantment
and this is pretty much a level 19
enchantment
and a very lucky one at that so
the best you can get is efficiency three
unbreaking three
and silk touch one so it's not quite
perfect but it's
it's almost perfect so i want to i want
to keep this guy
um little guy get out of there
we don't want you you're not special
okay so i think i'm gonna just make a
portal for him it's probably the easiest
all right i'm gonna take this out too
i'll have to rebuild this
great so as soon as i break this i'm
gonna light it
because he's gonna run i'm sure
or not i thought he would have ran
go into the portal please
come on you've been trapped for so long
he's not gonna go is he
all right so he went through the portal
here and i am right above project
pokemon right now i set up another
nether portal here and i fenced off this
area so that
we can get him where he needs to go in
peace we got to drop him down
right here so
i don't think he's quite ready to go yet
though i gotta wait a while
for his uh portal cool down to wear off
oh he did go okay cool this must have
been loaded while i was in overworld
then
all right and
he is
oh i thought he wasn't here for a second
i got worried
all right you oh he's in danger
oh man you gotta go right here guys i'll
put that there for you
to help you out all right
i need him to move this that
actually isn't perfectly safe because if
a zombie goes up to his fence he can
kill him
um they're busy though
i got another villager underground there
i really want to punch this guy because
he's not gonna
yeah i'm doing it he's not going to
leave that fence
all right sorry sorry there we go
and broken door
all right this is where we had the
corrupted chunk before
it should be fixed though
[Music]
all right let's replace the door
and there we go cool
so he should be safe and sound i'm gonna
relog just to make sure we don't have
the corrupted chunk issue
all right but yeah he is there
yep i tried re-lodging everything is
good he didn't corrupt the chunk or
anything crazy
like the other villager did that was
there um
we have three here now we gotta get more
but in due time oh no
no why
he's not getting hurt did i forget a
slime block or something there
oh man
darn it um
why is this one not working
it does retract oh how can we look at
what's wrong there okay it's over here
he is there
there's a slime block there
oh here we go i bet you that was doing
it
let's try again the slime block was
sticking to that
oh actually let's leave it there one
more time just so we can get them all in
the same place
ah it doesn't matter actually
doesn't matter
there we go
you know what i got some water there too
i just realized
oh i need a water budget now this is
going terribly i just wanted to trade
with this guy
and there we go
okay i think i can reach it there we go
everything is good
so this guy is really cool he's got the
great pick it's cheap 12 emeralds that's
nothing
let's buy two of them i just want to try
something if we were to combine these we
would get efficiency for unbreaking
three how many levels is that going to
cost
because we could straight up by
efficiency for unbreaking three for
24 emeralds there and 10 levels
okay all right that's interesting
the other great thing about this though
i think you need
it's either efficiency two or efficiency
three i think it's two
once you get that oh i disabled this so
that we can move them
uh once you get that you can insta mine
netherrack i believe
so this is a great nether pick
oh no
today while i was moving that guy it
looks like four villagers found the
portal
and i have disabled it so i don't think
they're going back
um let's not go that way that's where
the guardian guy is
yeah let's go out here just to try it
out yeah efficiency three on breaking
three
should be able to tear up netherrack
yeah
that's great if like i want to do
[Music]
uh more work on the wither skeleton farm
okay where did you come from
i think i left a guy in the nether
before and he must have found his way
here
weaponsmith oh and i haven't traded with
them even
all right sorry guy i will do it just to
see what it unlocks
it's a bit wasteful okay
oh he wants more emeralds though knocked
back
one i think after this one you'll unlock
his good trade
right and
we have oh that's pretty good i think
silk touch one efficiency three
unbreaking threes knock back one smite
three hmm
i'm gonna keep them here keep them safe
just in case i want to
move them here let me let me push you a
little bit more
good anyways guys that is going to do it
for today's episode i do have a comment
picked out
and i figured i should answer this one
because i have a lot of people asking me
about it
and you probably want answers so here we
go uh it says what happened to terra
firma craft you have not done an episode
in a long time
that is true that is very true so lately
my schedule has been pretty busy i've
i've been finding it difficult to do
everything i need to
to record everything and tara
hermancraft was one of those
series that was taking the longest so i
decided just to put it on hold for a
while
uh we were approaching the end of it
i may release a few episodes of it yet
but no promises
um but yeah i do still want to beat my
or achieve my goal in that whether or
not i release episodes on me doing that
we will see uh but maybe
if things if i can find some time i'll
do it and if i'm in the mood
also people asking about crash landing
that is still going on
we got fly boys now uh we got minecraft
my single player
and maybe the odd thing here and there
so it's a lot of stuff and i kind of
need to
thin it out a bit which is why
terraformer craft has
taken the back seat for right now anyway
uh
but yeah that's it guys thank you for
watching hope you enjoyed it
i'll see you again in the next one bye
bye
[Music]