[Music]
uh
oh
okay okay enough of that these guys
teleported here
and one thing led to another and that's
our intro for today
um let's get a real song going
so i'm working at expanding this area
here so we can start
working on the storage room i got some
tnt ready
uh i'm very limited on my tnt supply
that was a problem
all those signs
ah i want it in
oh well yeah so i just blew up a big
ring all around
we're going to continue expanding here
i'll clean this up
and i'll get back to you
yeah the wolves in this patch are just
so broken
like for some reason they're standing
now and i can't
make them sit uh and they don't move
either
so really they're sitting but it appears
like they're standing but i can't switch
them
to make them stand even though it looks
like they're standing
yeah i set up a second layer of tnt
we'll make it go off
and i don't know if you can tell or not
but i have
i'm on the minecraft server right now
believe it or not
this is going to be a test to see if the
audio from that gets picked up
i have gotten into the habit of having
two
instances of minecraft running so if i'm
digging stuff out like this and setting
mundane
or doing mundane tasks if i'm doing that
quite often now i'll have minecraft
running
two instances of it one on the minecraft
server
just afk at the blaze farm so you might
be able to hear blaze
i'm not hearing any sound from
this instance of minecraft i can't hear
this tnt
so hopefully it's getting recorded
and i've been enchanting stuff like
crazy
and i do the same when i'm on my track
sometimes i'll just after
my blaze farm in single player here
it's just a nice way of being there
without
actually being there because sometimes
trouble can happen if you afk
had a mob system
um anyway
i'll keep working at this and i'll get
back to you
out of torches
sorry guys uh i just rewatched that
video and you can
totally hear the blaze sounds in it so
uh i'll have to turn the game sound down
if i ever do that again
you probably were all confused had no
idea what was going on
um the single player didn't have any
game sounds i think because i
plugged in my headset or unplugged it or
something
which sometimes
really messes up my computer sounds like
i'll have to restart the minecraft
sounds or
firefox will just randomly crash on me
which is a bit annoying but what can you
do
and i know you're going to say use
chrome
i've considered it i might one day but
not not now
i have to be in the right mindset just
try a new browser
um yeah so i did a whole bunch of caving
just now i took a break from this
and tried to light up some caves around
here to speed up the mob system
this is what we got nice run and
plus 66 redstone blocks
what
that was uh anti-productive
let's try it this way so let's see what
we get with this
i don't know about you guys but a lot of
times when i play minecraft i'll have a
youtube video going on in the background
and like i was just caving for example
and you'll hear
the people in the video caving as well
so you got their mob sounds plus your
mob sounds combined
and you you don't know what's going on
like
you might hear a zombie and just
freak out and look all around you and
and there's nothing and then
in the video you see it's on their
screen
or you might hear a creeper sizzle and
you think
nothing of it because you don't see any
around you so
you just assume it's happening in the
video and then
right behind you you know gets you by
surprise
it happens to me a lot um and i'm really
bad for it too like
i'll be in the nether and i'll hear a
creeper sizzle and i just assume
it's on my end and i'll freak out and
turn around and
yeah there's no creepers in the nether
so i got this set up for another tnt
ring
where i have another tnt ring set up
which will set off in
just a little bit here i'm going to put
the stuff in the chest and then i'll be
back
uh we got a total of 414 redstone dust
from that by the way
which works out to an average of
6.27 per ore
with fortune 3 from that test
uh let us do this
this place is getting bigger
we're down to our last 20 to 30 tnt
though so i don't know how much more we
can clear out today
than apple each of these has a leaf
block underneath
which people ask a lot about is just to
it has a very low blast resistance so
i don't know so it's
speak speak how do i want to work this
it does more damage to there's another
apple there
does more damage to the blocks below
than say if you were to have
a piece of cobblestone blow would you ah
sorry i was angry there you go
you'll be fine you'll be fine
yeah he still loves me
all right very good very good we have a
lot of space cleared out now we can
we got some room to work here which is
good
um something i want to show you for
those of you making mob systems
the way i'm going about lighting up the
caves like that's what i need to do i
have to light up all the caves around
here
this is the center point of the mob
system i need to go at least
128 blocks all around the center point
but i plan on going a little further
than that as well because that
because we'll be moving around this area
so we need to go
further to make up for that the further
we
stand from that center point um
so i'll show you how i oh
i'll show you how i've been going about
lighting up the caves like
there's a major tape this way which i
have all lit up i couldn't find any more
dark spots so
at this point what i do is i go 100
blocks diagonally from the mob system
in in four directions so
so our x is like negative 463 and our z
is 851 or so add and subtract 100 to all
those numbers
go to that spot those four four points
and uh i'll meet you there at one of
them
okay so you can see the mob tower over
there that big snow tower that's our mob
system and that is our center point
so i went around that area as much as i
could looking for
caves lighting them up i can't really
find any more at this point so
it feels like i'm done all the taping i
need to do but i can tell by the mob
rates
it's still very slow so if you're making
a mob system you got to remember to
check the edges
of your of your radius so
i've gone 100 blocks on the negative
x and plus 100 on z to this point here
and i'll do the same
for over there there and diagonally that
way
and now this is where the controversy
begins
i make an x-ray machine at these points
and also one
in the center so usually i'll make five
total
to scan all the caves
and
i'm not telling you to use an x-ray
machine you can if you want
if you don't mind using it this is just
the method i
i go about lighting up today's um
the reason it's a sensitive issue is
because a little while ago i mentioned i
do not like
sand duplicators and a lot of people
oh right there i got a cave a lot of
people tore into me about it
that i ha i'm some sort of a hypocrite
because i
i don't approve of the sand duplication
but i approve of the x-ray machine
you can see that's where i have all lit
up so i got a lot of work to do around
around this area it's all dark for the
most part
so i'll just briefly talk about that
um in minecraft you should do
whatever you whoa
i don't i think that's natural i don't
think i dug that out
yeah do whatever you think is fun
right i play survival mode because i
enjoy the extra elements it adds to the
game
such as resource collection so that's
that's the reason i don't want to use
sand generators because
they will wreck my fun there's a tape
here too
um but now if we go into x-ray machines
i'm not using it like obviously there's
right and wrong ways of using it you
would not want to go to
like a pvp server and use that to find
people's bases that would be
just wrong but in this case i feel it's
okay
it doesn't bother me because i'm just
looking for needles and haste
haystacks basically i don't want to do
that because it would be very
frustrating and it doesn't
really get me any benefits except saving
me
time and frustration that's the key we
saw
so that's my reasoning behind the x-ray
machine don't use it if you don't think
it's right
you can use sand duplicators if you
think it's okay
doesn't bother me just don't try to get
me to use one because i don't want to
which i get hundreds of comments every
time
i say or i do something involving sand
people tell me
just use a sand generator and that bugs
me
uh but anyway it's gonna be out of the
game soon i'll be happy
so again i did some more caving there at
that spot we were just at
i found seven more stacks of redstone
and i got three stacks of iron a stack
of gold
then i went and did some enchanting i
just got this pick which is
amazing and now we gotta enchant the
shovel
which is not so amazing
all right so let's head back to the
storage room area and we will start
figuring out our layout
all right uh where to get started
how do you start a big project
well yes one thing i'd like to do first
of all is figure out
the size of this room as it is right now
so let's see
negative 485. i'm just gonna write this
down
just to give give us an idea of how big
we want this when it's all done
because this is starting to feel like
the the size
of the room i would want maybe a little
bit bigger yet
and over here negative 4
46 so that's about 40 bucks on x
and 8 35 it's about
40 blocks on zed so this room's roughly
40 by 40
right now i probably
want to go at least a 50 by 50 room or
bigger
um and this is going to be our
centerpiece this
these emp units in the middle uh
i felt like what i wanted to do like i
don't have this all planned out
all that well just sort of in my head i
should figure out some details like
maybe plan it out in a paint program or
something
as we get into this but for the center
what i figure i wanted to do was
have have it raised off the ground a bit
like two blocks up or something
from the ground in our storage room
um and then create a platform we can
walk around
in the center as well and i was going to
do that in the shape of an
octagon so
at this distance here it feels about
right we have the whole thing in frame
and that is one two three four blocks so
we want our walkway
to be at least four blocks wide
so i'm just gonna cut this
out
and we'll see how this goes
i'm not i'm not the best at big builds i
haven't done
anything major in this game yet
um although recently i've been more
inspired to to attempt bigger projects
although this this really isn't a huge
build it's just
bigger than what i'm used to
yeah if we did a straight across there i
think that diagonal would be too far
so let's go another block
um how would that do
that is not good let's make this go one
more
put this back
yeah that's that's about the size of the
octagon i'd want
so then this would be our path and we'll
have
a small staircase at each of these sides
to get up it
up the two block height let's pick this
up
it's working much better now now that i
did all that shaving today
go over here oh yeah uh but i still got
a lot to do with that
so
i'll i'll cut more of this out and i'll
get back to you
yeah so what i've been doing now is i've
just been uh cutting out this octagon
shape
um just to see how it'll look when it's
all done and then we'll replace the
stone with wood or something else
a different material if it looks good
um last episode maybe i'll just touch on
this a bit
uh last episode i devoted to the mob
sorting
and we
we didn't really figure out anything
definite last episode and
i got a bunch of feedback from you guys
thank you very much for that
um lots of lots and lots of different
suggestions were sent my way
uh i did not see anything
definite though like out of all the
suggestions i didn't see anything like
yes that will work for sure and i didn't
come up with anything like that on my
own
either so i still don't know exactly
what i'm doing although
i did get some good suggestions which
i'll have to look into further
um so first of all with the idea of
using
their pathfinding to separate them using
villagers to get to separate zombies and
the ocelots to separate the creepers
there's a a definite problem with that
method
if like you need to give them at least
one block that they
will walk onto to get to the villager
for example
and if there's that one block there
there's a chance any other mob will also
go to that one block
so it you can't get it to 100 percent i
don't think there's any way
of making it work for sure properly
um then there's also captain walnut's
method of using snowmen
which does seem to work really well and
by the way there was a lot of confusion
about this last episode
dm77 uses captain walnut's
snowman design so when i when i
referenced
captain walnut i also meant dot dem's
mob system they're the same thing or his
mob sorting system
um the problem with the snowman
is getting them you got to give them a
target to shoot at right
uh the way i saw captain walnut had his
setup he was using
spiders which i do not have spawning
in my system at all spiders and endermen
don't spawn in there
so i need a different target i'll either
have to use
zombies creepers or
skeletons if i use that method
and that is a big problem because as far
as i know
it's very difficult to make a snowman
shoot at a skeleton
and without him getting killed instantly
like it's within a second of them
shooting a skeleton they're dead
usually skeletons
they don't mess around as soon as they
are angry they attack that there's no
like whoa
there's no five second wait or anything
it's instant
that they'll shoot back and just kill
the snowman
and the snowman won't even shoot at
their legs
so if i supply
a different type of mob there's a good
chance a skeleton is going to get chosen
and the skeleton's just going to kill
the snowman if if
i use them i don't know
don't know what to do about that i saw
in
i don't know if like if captain walnut
had a trick to it i saw
he had like an iron fence maybe where
the snowman was but it was really hard
to see in the video
maybe he's using that as a way because
in his older system he was using zombies
as a target
but it to me it looked like he was just
placing the zombies using mob eggs
not that they were actually put there by
the system itself
but i could be wrong on that
anyway that's that's the concern about
the snowman method
another good idea that was suggested was
just to use
oh yeah and about the creeper thing the
creepers will only run away from
the ocelots if they have a lot of
possible places to run
to and if you give them a lot of
possible places to run to
there's a very very good chance a
skeleton or something will go that way
as well
because they have a lot of possible
chances of choosing that direction
but another really good idea i got
suggested was that i
um use iron golems to separate
skeletons from creepers and use
villagers to separate the zombies
it doesn't matter so much if a
if a skeleton or creeper gets mixed in
with the zombies for what i have planned
it won't cause any serious problems so
uh that could work i'll have to look
into that some more
and just the idea is to use the momentum
of the iron golem hitting the skeleton
to launch them into a separate stream
than the creepers so that's
that's the best idea i think out there
yet for what i want to do and that's
what i'm going to research some more and
probably use
unless i can figure out how to do the
snowman thing properly
anyway let's take a look at this how are
we looking
[Music]
what do you guys think of the shape
yeah i think that'll be okay uh how's it
gonna look from up higher
so on these edges is where the the
chests are going to be all on the
outside
uh it's probably going to be several
layers as well not just like
at ground level here it's going to go up
vertically
a bit so we'll be looking down at this
as well
yeah i think that's okay so
um maybe i'll try outline it with wood
and set up some stairs
and we'll see how it looks
hmm what to do what to do this is the
part of the build where i need to make a
lot of important decisions
and then stick with them be happy with
them because
they'll be tough to change later so
one thing i think will really bug me
with this if i keep it like this
with the two block thing is i can't see
the mob drops in the emp units which
would really suck so i should
at the very least raise this floor up
half a block
and then i would be able to see him
um if we go up another if we go up a
full block
might even be better although then the
center
isn't as highlighted so that's one thing
i'll probably do and uh i want you guys
feedback on all
on all of this so i'm going to bring up
a few things here
um the other thing we got to figure out
is what type of
blocks should we use with this build
a general trick i see among builders is
to keep
within two or three main type of blocks
in your builds otherwise it tends to get
over complicated looking or over
your eyes don't know what to focus on
if you don't use enough types it looks
really plain
so probably keep it down to three main
block types
or three main block colors or whatever
i tend to prefer i guess you'd call them
earth tones so
i i like the look of the wood i like the
look of
grass blocks the green i like the look
of
sandstone um
personally that's that's my preference
um
that's a lot like what we did at the
other base though so if
if we went that path we we would be
getting into
repeats here with my style most likely
which may or may not be a good thing
i'll i'll get your feedback on that
i know a lot of people like the look of
the other bass i i do myself
but if we do the same thing it might not
be very interesting to do it again you
know
another thing around here like if i use
grass this is the color we're gonna have
i'm okay with that color that looks good
but there's also
river biome here it's the same color
if we go over here we got swampland
though and i don't like swampland grass
you know in this game i've never really
been tempted to use a texture pack or
anything
except for maybe faithful the faithful
texture pack
but the thing that has always really
tempted me is to change
my grass texture file
the grass colors because i do not like
how
most the grass in this game doesn't look
green they really needed to make it
like they should have done it like how
terraria does it with the different
grass seeds and you could
have different colors of grass and
difference in like
multiple biomes you know in my opinion
like instead of it being linked to the
biome code it should be
just different types of grass like like
how you can have mycelium
in different biomes that would have been
cool if they did that way instead that
way we could choose what grass we want
where
um but anyway
got to figure out what blocks we're
going to use got to figure out
uh what shape and how we're going to do
everything here so just
leave me your feedback i'll take you
into consideration
um what i was planning to do here
uh do like a half slab staircase up to
the center
it won't be as big of a staircase if we
only go up one block or whatever
uh and then i was going to have wood
outlining it
with fences above above the logs here
um not necessarily this color like we
might use dark wood or
or something completely different
depending on what you guys see
but that was my idea originally
with this and then planks or something
for the floor here um
or actually if we do the grass thing it
would probably be grass
if we keep it like the other base over
here
anyway get me your feedback i'm gonna
get going for today
thank you for watching everybody and i
will see you again
next time take care