[Music]
hello everyone this is
etho and today today is a very good day
today's uh
a happy day it's a special day do you
know what today is
do you know what today is today is the
500 000 subscriber special day ah
oh yeah man 500 000 subscribers
unbelievable why are so many people
watching me i still have not figured
that out
uh yeah today's 500
thousand 500 000 subscribers special day
which is a very good day indeed uh
first of all i want to say thank you to
everybody that's been
watching me and that's been supporting
me some of you have been doing it for a
very long time and i
appreciate it don't fall down that hole
and uh got newcomers lots of newcomers
as well so welcome everybody
uh i hope you have a good time watching
my videos
uh yeah i don't know what to say i'm
i'm just really happy thank you everyone
uh so in honor of the 500 000 subscribe
why am i having a hard time saying that
500 000 subscribers special day just
rolls off the tongue a little too
quickly uh
in honor of that i thought it would be
cool
to well everything kind of worked out
pretty perfectly for this we got
fireworks in the game now
uh everybody likes fireworks pretty much
everybody
uh you know i wasn't too excited about
them at first but when i tried them out
myself
i really enjoyed them so i i want to put
on a firework show
for the 500k special and it kind of goes
in memory of the old world where we
would uh launch fireworks every
subscriber special
using canons that was the closest thing
we could get to fireworks now we
actually have fireworks so
yeah and i've been wanting to do a fun
project too for a long time so
this is perfect absolutely perfect so
i'm trying to
whoop trying to work that out uh to
begin with here
as far as what we need to get this going
we need gunpowder lots and lots of
gunpowder
i have a little bit i don't think i have
enough
uh we need paper for the rockets as well
got lots of that from our giant reed
farm
and we need the special items to get the
special fireworks like uh
what was it diamonds
we need we need uh
fire charges i know is one i think gold
nuggets
that kind of stuff i'm pretty pretty
well covered on that the one thing i'm a
little concerned
about is dyes though we also need dyes
and i have
some stuff some colors i have lots like
i got lots of whites i've got lots of
blues and what's going on here i'm just
i'm just left clicking is that new
you just click and it goes into your oh
that must be a new feature i didn't know
that
now it's not working i was just left
clicking it now it's maybe that was a
glitch i don't know
i'm confused anyway yeah i'm working on
getting the dies i got pretty much
everything i need
yellow and red colors i need
green i have no cactus farm or anything
so that one's gonna be tough i don't
have brown
and yeah i don't know if i'm gonna
bother getting brown browns not a color
people
people don't want to see brown fireworks
i don't think so i'm not too worried
about that but green i definitely want
to get some green
uh so yeah let's try to get our act
together here
uh i'll show you show you as this comes
together i guess
all right so i think i got our yellow
and red dye situation sorted out here
and
and that goes for orange and pink and
all the other sub colors too
that you make with red and yellow so
i came to use my greenhouse and it
didn't work i guess they fixed it like
before you could just go into a dark
room
when you break the grass and the flowers
they all pop off
so that's a i think i use this once for
getting yellow flowers or something
i don't know how well you can see but
now it's like you can't
plant grass and flowers if it's dark so
you need light
but if it's light then they don't uproot
so you have to make it dark
[Applause]
and even if you make a dart that doesn't
instantly uproot it takes time
for an update or if you hit it then
it'll do it but
yeah so what i did is quickly
and very ugly put this together
i got a wire that runs underneath
to to the center
it would work better if i did the whole
thing underneath but this is good enough
um that runs to the center then i got
this
monostable thing it's this
clock running very quick clock makes a
piston extend and retract as quick as
possible and that controls our lighting
if uh this is not covered
so it's going light and dark light dark
if you have
uh any issues with pulsating lights
maybe close your eyes for a little bit
all right oh man it's also very laggy
but this works this works
now i just spam right click
and uh this controls the lighting
and then it also sends that pulse down
and
down below this this area right below
the ground here and that causes the
update to make it
pop off
so yeah die situation is under control
see that pulsing down there
okay now we are here getting our our
paper
for the fireworks
i love this reed farm
that's like how it looks when you're
down here it's like you can't see
anything in front of you there's so many
okay that should be enough
and i started just a little very basic
cactus farm here eventually in my world
i'm going to build a proper cactus farm
and a proper
flower farm and all that so today's just
really
quick and basic ways of doing it
okay so we're gonna have to wait a
little bit for our cactuses to grow
before we can start making our fireworks
uh i'm gonna fill you in on the plan the
plan for the fireworks show because we
got a few things to consider
if you remember if you remember the old
fireworks setup we had i always had a
problem where i
wasn't able to really add variety to it
you know it was always the same
same sequence of canons going off
and it was very hard to to change it up
you know so
if you saw it once you saw it every time
you know
even though i launched it like five
times or six times throughout the
subscriber specials it always looked the
same
but i i would try to add a few new
canons to it every time to change things
up a little bit
and i plan on doing that with this one
we're setting up now too we're going to
continue to expand it
all the time and launch it every
subscriber special
um now i do want it to be random though
i want variety so it'll be a different
show every time
so the cool thing is we can launch
fireworks out of dispensers and
dispensers have nine slots it'll shoot
one out randomly so we can have nine
different colors of fireworks for nine
different types
and it will randomly choose between each
one as it's launching so that's awesome
that's built in and the fireworks
themselves there's so much variety with
them
so again awesome
but as far as the launch
sequence i said that word lot launch
sequence not lunch launch sync with
sequence why am i having trouble
speaking launch
sequence yes uh
as far as the launch sequence goes
uh we want the timing to be random if
possible
but we want to be able to control it
also so there's a bit of trouble with
that like you can do randomness in
minecraft a few different ways
very easy ways with chickens
walking on pressure plates and stuff but
i
i tried that on creative and it didn't
didn't do
what i wanted the chickens say stop
moving and they stand around so
i didn't think that would work too well
there's a random
randomizer i made a long time ago that i
never used
this is glitching out isn't it it's icon
back when i did the firecracker prank on
beef vintage beef on the minecraft
server
i made up a little randomizer thing so
i'll show you that
it is a little bit flawed unfortunately
but for this
purpose what for what we're doing it's
actually
uh it's gonna work out pretty good i
think
so i'm kind of going by memory here i
think i had
ring of netherrack
and that's on top then there's going to
be
two bud switches with this thing um
let's see i'm trying to remember i think
i had a regular piston
and then a sticky piston
and our goal is to make a fire appear
right here so that when a fire appears
this piston extends and puts it out
and this one extends and triggers a
redstone signal so to do that we're
going to want a
torch there some kind of block
um
the bud switch we got a power diagonally
so there's gonna
actually yeah that's right i had the
wool
up above in the middle here
oop this wool blocks very very important
so if that redstone is powered above
these become bud switches
uh so let's then run this up
i think we need to invert it as well
oh it's fun doing redstone on camera
isn't it um
oh you know what i think i did it like
this i think i had we need a repeater in
here too
otherwise the delay is not going to be
long enough yeah and then it just runs
to that
i think that's what i did
yeah so now let's just try this if
if this gets an update
nope
what did i do wrong
oh there we go
all right i have to update this one not
this one okay
so that's our basic gist of it here and
then we're going to put
glass around here so we can see
i guess actually we don't need a glass
block there whatever
put one there we have to cover every
single side of this wool block so that
it doesn't burn
because fire needs an air block to
spread so we want to
get rid of that and then there
we're going to leave it exposed to air
at the bottom though and that's where
it's going to catch fire
and light this netherrack
okay we'll just do that i think that's
okay then we can put a dispenser
on top this is what's going to launch
the fireworks
um put it there and we'll put some
blocks in
just so we can see it working i think
this is all good to go
uh if i remember right i have a flint
and steel
in one of these there we go
okay so now i'm gonna light this well i
gotta have i gotta fix this don't i
oh yeah i can fix it but i didn't nope
not by doing that
there we go just do it quick enough okay
so i think it's all ready to go
there's a redstone dust on top the wool
so that'll prevent it from burning on
the top
so let's light it up actually i don't
need that there
like this
now the more fire you have the quicker
this is gonna happen so if we have eight
around it
it should happen oh it's glitched out
why is it glitched out
because i updated it with the fire see
if we can
oh i missed the spot
on there goes there goes the wool block
darn it
this thing's really good guys trust me i
just need to
i need to fix it here
once we have it built i can copy it
pretty easy
okay what's messed up now
gotta retract that let's uh
oh
oh it's burning on the inside no it's
gonna burn the wall block again
stop stop update quick quick
now we lost it
uh okay i'm gonna fix this one sec this
is a disaster
yeah i looked this thing over i was
trying to figure out why i couldn't get
this to retract
and as far as i can tell it should i
think it's glitched out because you can
see the arm
is both retracted and extended so i
think i just gotta
break it and fix it that way
i think
i didn't think uh
that would be a problem though to be
honest
oh i got the fire inside darn what am i
doing
ah which one do i update i know i can
fix it just by
ah
what am i doing wrong here
oh man that burnt fast oh
you know it is i think that had to be
extended for this to
fix itself let's try this
oh let's try this
there we go fixed finally
why was that so hard okay so now it's
gonna send these random pulses
oh it's broken again what the heck
maybe i gotta extend the repeater
okay i'm to get this thing working
properly then i'll i'll start recording
again
yeah i think i found the problem here
this was not expected i guess it's a
directional thing
i i built it facing a different
direction it seems to work
oh activity put out the fire first
because this one the piston always
glitches out
it's really annoying
oop all right so let's get this going
that's fine it's fine
uh this one's working pretty good though
no problem
so far
yeah glitched out again look at that i
don't know why it's glitching out it's
not like i'm
sending it a rapid pulse or anything
like that it's uh it's pretty normal
i would think
yeah because it's got to go through all
this wiring before it retracts right
it's not like i'm doing anything crazy
here
there's a delay in everything i don't
know
but yeah it'll shoot off one rocket
every time it goes
now with this setup though eventually
even if it's running properly like this
eventually this wool block is going to
burn
because there's like a two second or not
to say to tick delay
from for the piston to extend and in
that time it's possible the wool block
can burn
it's very unlikely and for what we're
doing
it doesn't really matter too much
if it does burn up because we're going
to
be making a backup of the fireworks show
and then loading
the backup afterwards again so we get
all the fireworks back
in our dispensers um
and all the wool blocks that burn we'll
be back too
so i think it'll be good
it'll be good uh they're used i think
the way i set this up originally i think
i used a crafting table
somewhere and crafting tables for the
longest time
they would cause fire to spread but they
didn't actually burn
now same with like wooden pressure
plates and stuff
uh they would cause fire to spread but
they wouldn't burn now i think they
fixed that in the game
because i don't know i tried it out
before and it would not
like fire should or it used to spread to
those blocks there
but i can't do it to happen now
well i've tried reloading minecraft and
that didn't fix the problem and the
piston is still glitching out
i checked and it's not intersecting any
chunk boundaries
either except maybe vertically it is
but so is this one you would think they
would be affected the same if that was
the problem
um not a clue so i'll just have to be
careful when i build these i build them
facing the right way
and there's one other issue
uh so the way i plan on on doing the
wiring
i'm going to like
in general when i'm doing stuff in my
world this is piston is going to be
extended at all times
so that this will block or this thing is
not running you know
but then when i want to start the
fireworks show up i'm going to send i'm
going to have a master switch that
turns all these machines on by
retracting the
piston there and then it can go
but when i do that
when i initially retract it it's going
to
cause one firework to go off from each
dispenser
if i do it like this i might be able to
i haven't tried this but if maybe if i
invert this
i i'm not really i really haven't
thought this out or anything
but usually if something's not working
i'll try invert it
and see if that fixes it
maybe if i invert this i won't have that
problem
but it might cause new problems we don't
know
still only shooting one that's good
okay let's try this uh when we turn it
off it shoots one
okay yeah that's what we're gonna do i
think gotta make sure we invert it one
more time
still working good okay
aha awesome i think we're gonna have the
best color
our green dyes in our fireworks show
i'm gonna plant another set of the cacti
here too
because i want to make sure we have
enough uh i think this first
fireworks show is going to be a little
bit wimpy though sadly because i
i hate to say it but most of my
gunpowder converted to tnt form already
so i only have six stacks i'll probably
try to get some more before we do this
but
yeah if you if you do the math well i've
done the math already
if we average for gunpowder per firework
that's not
very many actually let me do it again
yeah it's only going to be like 96
fireworks or so
so not going to be the most impressive
thing to begin with
but we will keep building it and i'm not
going to do it just subscriber specials
any kind of special we do or
if we just want to do something fun
every now and then i'll
probably make this thing go off
fireworks show go off i mean
and maybe improve it before i do that
um but yeah we're going to do it
over at our pond there so i'm going to
start setting it up we'll probably do
maybe at least 10 of those randomizer
things we set up there
and put them in the water
oh boy okay this is a very important
decision time for me
because what i decide is either going to
work out
pretty good or it's going to not work
out well
and take an unbelievable amount of my
time up
because i want to put the fireworks show
in this lake
right i want them to shoot out from the
bottom of the lake
and come up i think that'll look cool
i want to spread them out as much as i
can like i said though for this first
launch it's going to be a little wimpy
we're only going to have like 10
little things set up eventually though i
want the whole lake
full full of those machines we'll do our
best to spread them out this first time
but
the way i think i should do it start
like dig down and cut out
a grid pattern every five blocks of part
will space the machines they only take a
three
by four so i could put them
well no that's about as tight as i would
want them i guess
so every every five blocks will have a
line for redstone
that will go to all the machines in the
lake
i have to decide how deep down i'm gonna
dig though
because yeah water and redstone they
are a pain to mix and i'm going to be
digging below the lake
the lake has sands in quite a few places
it's pretty good though there's actually
a lot of soil i'm happy to see that
but if i dig too close to
the bottom of the lake the sand is going
to fall and the water is going to pour
on my redstone so i have to go
down i think i'm going to go
15 blocks below this level maybe
it's really hard to know for sure it's
the deepest right there
there's also all these like caves
uh in in the water here like look over
here there's a cave right here
so i'm gonna have to deal with these two
unexplored even um
hey get out of here
yeah i think i'm gonna go 15 bucks or so
yeah uh that's what i'll do
and i'll let you know how how happy i am
later with my decision
yeah there's a lot of work involved to
this so i think for this first launch
i'm only going to dig
up to about x200
so our fireworks show our first one the
whole whole thing is going to happen in
this area of the lake
only and later we'll expand out further
and i figured out my positioning i think
it's going to be about i think it's 14
blocks maybe
maybe 13 but i'm going by
fives it's really important i go by
fives here
when i'm figuring this out
so this tunnel starts at uh at z360
this one is at 355. this one's at 350.
this main tunnel here is at three
all right negative 245 x our y
is at 50. um
so this is gonna make it a lot easier
when i'm figuring out where
i need to go because i'll probably have
to go
in the lake here and dig down to place
my dispensers and stuff
out after i finish setting up the
machine down below
so that'll just make it easier to find
stuff
oh this is not what i wanted to see
a huge cave system underneath
okay this is getting pretty close to
ready what i'm doing now
is just connecting the dispensers to the
things and this is how i'm doing it i
got
all my positions marked down on paper i
only set up nine of these things
um but we we probably don't have enough
fireworks to film anyway so
i think that's good enough for today i
really gotta get to bed here it's
getting so late
this project is
very very time consuming
but it's okay it's okay it's gonna be
cool when it's all done
but yeah i've been working pretty much
all day on this
can't wait to see it though it's going
to be cool
break the ladder got the pumpkin as a
marker
in case i have trouble finding it later
uh i'll take you down below again
i think that was it yeah that was the
ninth one um
down below i got so much to do yet
though it's crazy
uh let's see
i see you oh where's my sword
where's my sword
okay let's not go down there uh yeah
i got these set up down here shows the
purple wool
i gotta get my sword ready there's a lot
of guys down here
um and what we just connected to is
right above this block
yeah it should be good i gotta get my
foot in steel
and start lighting these getting them
ready
i actually know what i gotta do is
connect to all these
redstone things so i have to run a line
for each of these paths
it's going to be it's going to be
like a thousand redstone probably or
something crazy
but i'm going to do that now
yeah and i just sort of spaced them out
as well as i could
with these first nine
actually doing the redstone here went
really quick i'm pretty happy with that
oh doesn't make it all the way
okay redstone is
pretty much done here i just gotta
connect it all to
the main switch over here
uh oh yeah we gotta light the fires
light the fires for each of these things
and then put the fireworks in and i
think we're good to go
but i gotta make the fireworks first hmm
you can probably tell my voice i'm
getting tired oh man
i think i can do it though within an
hour if i can do it within an hour i can
finish
today
oh we're lighting her up now oh yeah
we could even like if it's not fast
enough still we could put another layer
of fire below this
and have like 16 fires it'll be twice as
quick
but you know i think it's going to be
good like this
all right very cool
that one gotta be careful i don't burn
see this is gonna be really bad if water
pours now because not only is it gonna
wreck the redstone it's gonna take out
the fire
uh those guys are still chilling
tempted to mess with them but at the
same time i don't wanna
stay up any later than i need to
so we'll leave them be uh
this is actually pretty fitting though
if you think about it we're lighting the
fireworks with fire
in a way right
um this one and this one
oh no
why did it pulse again that was
it's weird working yeah it's good
okay i should have made it where i could
fill the dispensers from below here
that might have been better i could
still change it if i really want
oh i made a little bit of a mistake here
i guess this is supposed to be
extended when we start it otherwise it's
not going to work so i have to change
these again
yeah like that so otherwise it won't
retract which is a problem
i've been waiting for this this is where
things get fun guys we are going to
start
mixing i got everything laid out
pretty nice sadly i don't have time to
get more gunpowder so it's
again it's going to be a bit wimpy this
first first go here but
we'll improve it later um
i'm gonna make mostly simple rockets i
think this first time
so it'll go the gunpowder will go a
little further that way
but yeah let's get this going i'm gonna
make i think
eight of each color is the big basic
stars you know
i think actually you know what i i've
been wondering
like i think they stack but i don't know
how
how many you can stack you know what i
mean
uh let's try this out
that's a low flying
9 10 11 12 13 14 16
16 and a stack that's crazy
does it go more i i don't want more but
i'm curious now how
we'll do 17.
that's pretty cool man i can fit a lot
of these in each dispenser
17 even wow oh man
yeah i don't want to that's too many
though i don't want to do
more than that but i'll probably make
eight of each
each color just a basic level one
flight uh basic explosion i guess
uh so that that'll be 16 times eight how
many is that
it's not going to use all my gunpowder
16 times eight
it's going to use two stacks of it darn
yeah it's a good start though i'm gonna
do it
oh you know what it was actually 16
times eight times
two because each of them needs two
gunpowder for
eight of the basic rockets for each
color
but yeah i mean i made those and i made
a few
other fancy ones
this one used eight diamonds i think
it's gonna be cool
uh so i'm gonna start distributing these
through our dispensers i'm gonna put
two stacks for each and that's
yeah it's not they're not even going to
become close to full so
lots of room for improvement here
i got to find them all good thing i
wrote down the coordinates
man i can't believe i got it done today
guys i got all the fireworks in place
it's all ready to go here just gotta
flip the switch basically and
we get ourselves a nice little firework
show
ah but yeah thank you for watching
everybody i will see you again
next time take care
thanks for all your support and
everything
just kidding what kind of monster do you
think i
am pull something like that no i'm
already here
let's let's check out the show man i'm
excited
i want to see what it does now take it
with a grain of salt though it's
it's probably going to be a little bit
slow there's not as many
firework dispensers as i'd like and
there's not as many fireworks as i'd
like and all that
but you know what something i thought
about too i could probably change the
speed of this thing by adjusting the
difficulty
because it's based on fire spread so
that's kind of cool but yeah hopefully
this is good
let's check it out all good firework
shows need
a good music track in the background
best song
um don't have a launch
system set up really so i'm just gonna
place down a torch
and get up there real quick
oh it's going dig it
oh that's so cool
oh yeah i am happy oh that was neat
ugly brown one
oh i like that one there
[Music]
that one's really cool too i gotta make
more of these fancy ones man they're
really awesome
[Music]
oh i don't even know what that was
it had a crackle to it though
[Music]
i like that one i gotta make more of
those
must be gray another ugly brown
[Music]
okay this turned out really good i'm
happy
slowing down i think it ran out
there's probably a few left but not many
[Music]
yeah that was cool guys okay let's get
to
our comment reading fireworks are so
cool
you got that straight
oh man
[Music]
oh i'm gonna have fun with this project
i'm gonna keep working on it guys
don't worry we get more fancy stuff in
lots more fireworks
but i'm really happy with just this
little setup even that is cool
great addition to the game good job
mojang
[Music]
you know i don't think i we saw any of
the green ones those are the first ones
[Music]
oh stinking brown why did i put the
brown there
it's the ugliest one right up in front
[Music]
another one anyway we don't want to see
any more brown
i think we're done for today guys thanks
for your support honestly
i really appreciate it you guys don't
know how much you guys
help me out with this youtube stuff
and uh i hope you keep on watching and
keep enjoying the videos
i have fun doing this
okay here's just a quick follow-up on
our fireworks show i
came down to inspect what happened
because it seemed like it slowed down
actually and yeah the wolf got on fire
what i did before the show is i i ended
up
extending this repeater because
this torch was flickering too quickly
for the dispenser it wasn't shooting the
fireworks so i had to
extend the the pulse length on this wire
and because of that the wool burnt a lot
faster
so it ended the show quickly there
should be at least twice as many
fireworks
actually so what i think i got to do is
move
the dispenser from here to here
and this repeater will make the torch
stay on long enough to activate the
dispenser i think
but yeah that's it was still pretty
successful for first launch i'd say
i enjoyed it i hope you did too as far
as world download goes i was
really trying to get it done today but
it is honestly
past 4 a.m right now i got to go to bed
so next episode for sure i'm gonna
make a real effort on it and uh next
episode i'll have the world download for
you guys
so please be patient just a little bit
longer
all right that was a good day
have a good night take care