[Music]
oh that's so awesome
whoops i was at my gold farm i was like
why am i not getting any gold where are
all the pigmen
go through the portal
why are they going through the portal
why so many this is perfect man we got
the lightning and
gajillion zombie pigmen
randomly
walking through the portal for some
reason
why are they
i am so confused why is there so many
pigment around here
what happened
okay i get these ones probably came here
because
they went back through the portal from
the library
how did they
i was just up at the gold farm for a
while and i don't know
i don't get it there's no portal up here
pretty sure
oh we got chickens huh
yeah i don't get it
well anyway uh this opportunity is too
perfect to throw away how often
do you see an unexpected horde of zombie
pigmen
on top of a mountain ah not too often
so i have this stupid uncontrollable
urge to
make them mad at me and then have them
chase me off the mountain
because i have something they don't have
not a brain it's feather falling boots
yes they don't have feather falling
boots
so i think they'll just die
but uh all right i want them to fall off
over here
if we can it's a nice cliff over here
i should survive that myself
i think they're starting to disappear
actually i should do this quickly
okay um
how do i well i'm thinking about it too
much
just oh maybe not enough i just killed
myself
darn it oh and i spawned here
i forgot my bed was here
hey guys you forgive me
you forgive me right where did i throw i
think i went this way
yeah there's my stuff
i got my boots follow me
oh you cheaters
darn it all right i'm going back
no i'm not i'm dead oh i lived thank you
feather folly
yes i killed one
this was stupid i wanted them to fall
off of there
oh darn it i guess i'm not done here
um for some reason these guys are mad at
me too
oh that was some lag little cheater
i think i will
nope no arrows
yeah give me a minute
oh look at this resourcefulness i had
feathers on me i had
gravel we can make we can make arrows
how about that
it's all good don't be mad
oh look at that we got a sword
uh-huh i think we just about got them
all
i'm kind of curious why these guys were
mad because i didn't anger them in the
nether it's like one of the angry guys
went through
and told all the other guys about me
[Music]
i bet if we go through again there's
gonna be some
more angry guys for some reason
okay we're good i think we're all good
so there has been some developments in
minecraft and as
a lot of you guys have probably seen uh
zombie baby zombies can ride chickens
and it is amazing
it's awesome um
turns out though also zombie baby zombie
pigmen
can ride chickens and they spawn in the
nether
and guess what my mob system spawns tons
of them that's why there's
chickens all over the place here because
the zombie pigmen despawn
this is supposed to work by killing them
from fall damage
but these guys they just float down
they land on the track and then they get
in the way of this minecart thing going
around and around
and clog up everything so they are
a problem um as cool as they are
they are a problem we have to redo some
of this stuff and i have an idea
um using portals like we just saw with
all the zombie pigmen coming out in the
overworld rather than
killing the mobs here in the nether and
and dropping them down this this thing
this didn't really work either by the
way because they
they would despawn as they were falling
and they would usually despawn before
they hit the ground so i kind of had to
redo this anyway
so my new plan with the gold farm
we're going to try to set up a bunch of
portals like big long
short portals and then have the zombie
pigmen just walk through
and on the other side in the overworld
that is where we will store them and
then kill them with a looting sword and
we'll get even more gold from them
so yeah that's what we're going to try
to do
how effective is it going to be we will
find out i guess
but i'm going to get a ton of obsidian
together here
and start setting this up
because i'm having the time of my life
minding obsidian
this is way less fun than it looks
and it doesn't look very fun
this was full of lava up to that point i
got
just about four stacks we're gonna need
a lot for the portals
having the time of my life mining
obsidian
oh no oh
and that's why you start from the top
and work your way down
i didn't take very long i got tired of
mining obsidian but we do have five
stacks here
and before before i forget i wanted to
show you guys this too this is one of
those things i would
pretty easily forget but i changed the
walls here
and some of you might like it some of
you might not i'm not sure
um i didn't do the whole thing yet but
in particular this wall
always bugged me it looked really plain
so i
i put the cracked and the mossy stuff in
i tried not to overdo it
i might have put a little too much but i
think it looks okay
gives it more of a cave feel i find
breaks up the wall because it was just
plain stone before
i haven't done up to here kind of wanted
to see what you guys thought of that
um but yeah we're gonna go back to the
gold farm
let's go back very quickly
so gonna need some sort of pusher system
too
to get them into the portal i'm setting
up and if this all goes well again this
is experimental too
i haven't uh haven't really done a mob
farm like this before that used portals
um but if this goes well i'm going to
try set up a mob farm like just a
regular mob farm that does this
by the man cave as well um
and send like creepers and stuff into
the nether so
working the other way
um yes so i guess
let's maybe just do one or two of these
first to make sure it works
i'm gonna have to get rid of a lot of
this stuff
so the lowest spawning pad is right
there
um so maybe
let's plan to put like a portal here and
move all the mobs
to the left um
all right so i brought stone brick so
they would fall
let's see they need at least a two block
high clearance to get underneath
all right so i think i think that means
our ground is going to be here
so half of them like the right side is
going to land there and then we're going
to go
down a little bit more have another
layer
probably i think at that
level
so they'll fall down and then they'll
get pushed one more time when they're
down here to the left and that should
put them into a portal right here um
so we need pistons lots and lots of
pistons what a surprise
i've gone through so many pistons making
this dumb thing
um
see i'm going to use sticky pistons i'm
not using string
like tripwire for this one i'm just
going to use pressure plates i think
so that they can individually fire
uh instead of like the tripwire setup we
got there where the whole row fires
and i guess
it's gonna be a very simple nope not
there
right there i think
yeah just trying to remember how to do
this
okay so pissed in there block in front
um here let's let's change this up for
right now so we can get up here easy
i'm gonna have a whole row of pressure
plates stone pressure plates here then
we're gonna activate the pistons
and we just need to send power
into there so we can do
we can do like redstone oh careful
redstone and then repeater and alternate
them all the way down
so let me get to that
[Music]
it's literally at eight
and those gas i don't think have gotten
any quieter
they're still so loud oh uh anyway
so there is eight of these these
sections
this took 32 pistons which is a it's a
little bit it's not terrible
um this isn't even totally necessary
what i'm doing here i'm
i'm forcing them to enter the portal
though instead of relying on their
pathfinding
by doing it this way and i just noticed
as well
if we put the redstone there it's going
to activate the piston below it
so we might not be able to cheap out
yeah i don't think we can cheap out oh
so
see before we put the blocks on let's do
the repeaters
so glad i have lots of redstone now
i would have just dreaded doing this
otherwise it's the iron though
um everybody tells me to make a witch
farm in my world i haven't found a
like a witch hut yet to be honest
and with my amplified terrain it's going
to be even harder
unless i change it back specifically for
that which i don't think i'm gonna do
because i do enjoy taping
although i do the speed mining thing now
so
hmm i don't know
i haven't used as much iron lately
now the next thing this is the part i
really don't want to mess up because
this is
not going to be fun um but i think the
portal goes
right here this is the base of it
i'm going to have to try to set this up
as well where i can disable the portal
otherwise it's going to interfere with
my portal network
system
so only when i'm at the gold farm i want
this working
come up and then probably just do a too
high portal would be fine
i hope see
i think that's okay we can come back
very good i've never made a portal
this big before
all right i brought in flint and steel
let's make sure it works
i thought that would have worked what
did i do wrong
ah darn it uh i might go check creative
really quick because uh maybe it needs
to be taller
i'm not sure
okay i'm back let's give this a try
need to be one block taller so three
tall
so yes the idea is they will fall down
and this forces them right into the
portal
so they should instantly pretty much
teleport into there took us to the
snowflake
just gonna take me back oh it did
oh because it's up high that's why i'm
not gonna be able to leave here
because they uh oh oh
i'm having some pretty bad leg spikes
i think because of 174 i'm not sure
what's causing it but yeah that looks
like that's gonna work so that
is fantastic uh i'm gonna set up a few
more of them
maybe and we will try it out
and then we gotta set up like a killing
system on the other side
or or at least some way of storing them
so we can see what happens
the the main issue with this setup
though is i have to be
very careful i don't um
let too many zombie pigmen through the
portal and not take care of them
otherwise i will
i'll have thousands in no time they they
spawn pretty quick
uh in this whole thing
oh yeah check that out uh i did half of
it
we're gonna try out this half first it's
gonna not be running at full speed as if
we did the whole thing but i just want
to make sure
let me change all these to two um
now that i see that i'm glad i saw that
the the pist the piston left a block
behind it looks like it glitched out
but if these are two it shouldn't do
that
um
darn it all right give me one sec
okay so we got that fixed top and bottom
all set at two
and oh my goodness there's a lot of
these guys starting to show up even
though i'm like within the area they're
still spawning somehow
um but yeah we're gonna light these
portals up
we're going to go on the ceiling
bye-bye
i've heard if you have too much portal
blocks you get
lag um
yeah we'll have to just see what happens
here i only did half because
this is either going to be really
awesome or really a
big waste of time i think so i don't
want to waste the other half
of my time if it is a a failure
we got it we got it we did it um
gonna go up on the ceiling and just sit
there for a little bit and then
i'm gonna come back down go through the
portal and we should
possibly see
although this portal goes to a different
place
doesn't go to the snowflake that could
be a problem
huh
all right second thought i gotta disable
that snowflake portal i think
because this takes us to the library
hey
all right everyone so here we are on top
of the nether ceiling up at the very
tippy tippy top of my world at y230
um some stuff is happening i can tell
you that for sure
i am getting lag
uh which makes me want to get down here
from here very quickly
but uh like i'm having like blocks come
back
and stuff like it's almost like server
lag
so things are definitely going through
the portal and they
are causing a lot of lag
that's all i know so far i've been up
here maybe a minute or two it hasn't
been long at all
i feel we should go check it just in
case i'm doing something
very wrong to my world i took out the
library portal instead of the snowflake
one so we should
meet up with the pigmen here
oh it created a new portal
huh
okay darn it test is invalid
ah
why would it make a new ah whatever i'll
figure it out
um that's probably not a good thing
i was here to get the coordinates for
for uh portals
um there was some gold on the ground
below
he's not real okay
stuff happened some stuff definitely
happened uh
mostly guys would have despawned though
as soon as i came
within range oh and brought us back here
good all right so i'm going to move the
portal on the ceiling
to try to get it to line up with the
snowflake and then we will try it again
this is the time guys i think it's gonna
work this time portals are aligned
world is lagging it's been i think three
minutes
i've been up here and you look at the
numbers the entity count it like
it changes and then it freezes i think
that's lag every time it freezes like
that
because it should just be changing
constantly
i think we will find out
oh man oh the ender pearls
did you see the ender pearl like it's
trajectory it was like going back in
time and forward back in time
um hopefully
i'm not overdoing things here
[Music]
awesome oh my goodness
entity count 300
that's with it working at half speed
three minutes
what am i doing
yes it works this is way better than
what we had before
um so we need a containment
chamber for these guys some way to kill
them
we'll probably use poison potions i'm
guessing to get them down to half health
and then we'll throw an instant health
potion and have our looting sword
equipped so we'll get the
loot without wasting our sword
durability i wonder how many fell
off
oh man i got that stupid idea again
tell you what this time
how far down is it hey guys
oh that that's a pretty far jump oh
oh man you are you're one of the good
ones
probably shouldn't have done that that's
going to give me a lot of trouble now
because they didn't all fall down oh
yeah there is
there is gold for days down here
i like it okay cool
well um i'm going to go back into the
nether maybe take the other
portal because i don't want to go back
up there
oh man are they mad
[Music]
oh yeah they're still mad they're mad
they can't get out of there for sure
right or maybe it was just that guy
because they all bunched up
as soon as i hit him
they're bringing reinforcements
you know i didn't even check the room
i'm in if there's any zombie pigmen
there sometimes is
ugh i turned the sound back up and i
regret it now
[Music]
oh boy they're going through this is
terrible
it's causing so much lag
i'm very excited about this though this
is gonna work out
awesome why uh
is that lag causing that some of those
repeaters are still on
oh yeah that was like okay
this is gonna rival my enderman farm
honestly guys like
because i'm going to get xp from it now
and at the rates that they collect it is
going to be
crazy i'm going to try to get the other
four of these done
and we will try it out one more time
before we end this episode
well i just got owned by this guy
i came through the portal and he just
like hit me 10 times
all at once it was crazy
oh i got my stuff good
it just appeared that was weird
anything fall down i think i'm good
yeah it's very strange i went through
and i thought it was zombie pigmen at
first but it was just a zombie that went
through
um and he got a bunch of cheap shots in
on me uh still working at building that
i needed some more stone so let me get
back to it
all right guys let me let me let me tell
you what's going on here i'm having
yet another problem and i don't quite
understand this one
i finished setting up the gold farm and
i'm anxiously
awaiting testing it i think it's going
to be awesome
but when i went to test the portals like
when i went through
um some of them worked some of them
took me off way out like negative 400
x and and created a new portal out there
instead of
connecting with one of my existing ones
here
so i've tried to center
a portal as best as i can on the whole
farm
this is where it should go
um this is the same y-coordinate same
y-shape as this is y 105.
it's one block higher than it should be
um
i think most of these it's gonna work
here we can try this out
yeah okay it took us back here that's
what we want
um some of them were not connecting with
the snowflake which is why i decided
to move it but even with this
in the right place if i go to the
portals in the corners
like the corner of the portals as far
away as i can
like this this is the very corner
and when we go through
x negative 32 zed 28
it just it creates a new portal for some
reason
which is weird it's very weird because i
was under the impression
that as long as you've got a portal in
the overworld here within a thousand
24 blocks it should connect with it
which
that one definitely is
very strange very strange but i think
i'm going to try this out
even with this problem i'm not sure what
this is going to do
maybe it's going to create like
thousands of portals all over my world
as the zombie pigmen go through we will
find out
okay guys this is it this is our final
test for this episode
i have been up here for five minutes
i've been timing it
uh with the full farm complete
and i made a backup before i did this
just in case i
i did wrong oh man ender pearl
it's not going down
some of the problems i've been having
with minecraft today might not
necessarily be
minecraft's fault i got a warning
message on my computer that my
performance was slow
so it might just be time for a reboot or
something i'm not sure
but the the portal lag is definitely
real that is definitely a minecraft
thing
because i'm sending so many guys through
the portal
anyway let's see what happened here um
didn't fix the portal situation so some
of the zombie pigmen probably got split
up
oh and they've been dying too there's
gold in the water
i'm not hitting them this time you can't
make me
i like it that is so cool
so i i wonder if like if i go explore my
world now if i'm going to find all these
random portals
in places because they they decide to
create new ones
or or what happened there exactly
yep okay so
the farm is working much better now um
it's not as automatic as it used to be
but
look at the numbers guys look at the
numbers we can do amazing things with
this
um it's going to be an xp farm now as
well
and we can use looting with it so all in
all i think the changes have been
way better
i really want to hit them let's pull her
up one more time
uh next episode though we will probably
work on the killing chamber
i don't think that's going to be too
tough to do and
maybe i'll figure out what's going on
with the portals
i went to the man cave to get a book for
the comment for today and when i came
back there was still a bunch of these
guys here
even though i was gone for at least a
minute oh
and i just threw it away how about we
read it
so this is a big comment it actually
helped me out quite a bit because it
answered
what was going on with my village it
says you may have not
actually made an endless breeding
village the thing about villagers is
that it doesn't register a village as a
real member
villager as a real member of the village
until they are
adult villagers that that's the key
right there
for example imagine that 15 villagers is
supposed to be your max
if you have 10 villagers some of them
will start breeding so let's say every
set of two breeds
we now have five child villagers plus
the original ten however
the village will still only count ten
villagers therefore it is possible for
those villagers to breed yet again
before the children grow up
also even if some of them grow up let's
say that all
have except for the 15th villager all of
those new
adult villagers will now be willing to
breed meaning if all of the villagers
were to breed again we would have yet
another seven child villagers meaning
you could very possibly get
around 22 villagers in a village that
was meant to have a max of 15.
that i think that's exactly what
happened because i have about 22
villagers in the village
all grown up and they stopped breeding
so
that's why it went over the limit of 15
and there was no need to panic
um you gotta really watch if you do make
an
infinite village breeder that you keep
an eye on it otherwise you might
have a situation like what you saw out
here with the zombie pigmen
except imagine leaving that for five or
six times longer
and you might not um
be able to play in your world anymore
unless you go to mcedit
but yes that is the end of our episode
of run i hope you enjoyed it
and and liked it it was a
very i actually really enjoyed what we
did today
uh even though we spent most time in the
nether um
i was really happy to see the gold farm
worked as well as it
is as it does now and i'm looking
forward to finishing it
now that it's working so good so great
so well
that's the one so well okay guys
thanks for watching bye
you