[Music]
hello again everybody this is Ethel
welcome back I've been doing a whole
time of Shaving since last episode like
just constant many many hours of it
trying to get the mob system going good
and I'm starting to see some
improvements I'm gonna go do some more
caving pretty quick here I just wanted
to enchant this pic with my teeming
levels excellent awesome ah yes that's
great I'm gonna take that with me much
better than this one yeah I'm getting
lots of resources it's too bad I don't
really need them or at least there's no
urgent need for them in my LP minecraft
server Joe and I would love this stuff
like believe this like I'm loaded
absolutely loaded with everything but
you know down the road I might need it
for something cool let the stuff smelt
and back to gaming I also made a cool
discovery which we'll get to pretty
quick here yeah while I was caving I
found this a stronghold wall and I
thought I went through the entire
stronghold but this place looks dark so
somehow I missed this oh maybe not yeah
I must have maybe I'm not sure oh let's
just see how big of an area it is I
don't know if I put these here or what
the deal is got him whoa there's a
little bit here it's almost like it's
not connected to the other part of it or
something for me to have missed it
yeah because it's dead ends there and
I'm surprised I didn't see it when I was
doing the x-ray thing I only found it
like it just happened to stumble into it
yeah that's it just this little pocket
somehow got separated huh
very weird and another good eveing run
we are really getting this place lit up
now like there's a mob system compared
to last time there is not nearly as much
darkness around this is this is one spot
I need to go to yet and there's a little
pocket there maybe a little bit of
darkness there but I'm not really seeing
many caves anymore that need to be lit
up which is a good sign and I went
through the mountains and I got a lot of
that lit up like the tunnels in them
that are hard to find but yeah it's
going pretty good
[Music]
and level 30 again let's do a shovel Wow
man alive that's great all right
everybody so a project I wanted to do
today is something on this thing here
it's good the way it is but I feel like
we can improve it some like if you want
to trade with these guys you know 15
pork chops assuming I had pork chops I'd
have to run all the way to my storage
room then I'll run all the way back to
get the next trade going you know or or
even like this guy with the paper
trading usually i I've just been putting
the paper I get in random chests I find
on the way like like in these or like
stuffs game disorganized so what I want
to do is put in some hidden chests
around here for the trading and just
keep cheap paper and them and other
other things I can trade with these guys
in the chests so I thought over here in
these these spots would work really no
way down the hole better be careful
while we're working okay so we're gonna
have to tear up a whole bunch of floor
and stuff here it's okay
and hopefully we got enough space so one
thing I want to do is have a light in
here so I brought these I kind of
planned this out before
put redstone here and we're gonna have a
pressure plate above on the wood here
wooden pressure plates it'll go to
that's and we want I'm gonna have like a
stair like that and this is why we want
to enter pearls on this all the time
okay we want the start to pull back one
block that way
so we need oh and it just transforms
great we want a piston over here and
transform back and we need it to be
powered by default so oh we hit
something over there what is this
nothing jittery fingers this okay now if
that retracts will pull the stair back
and we want to use a stair so we can put
a chest right underneath here not sure
how this is gonna work yeah I want I
want a double chest like this and a lamp
underneath so it'll shoot light out
through it make it look nice and Peter
goes to the redstone torch that should
be it let's just try this out so
get this going oh I heard it sound like
a creeper there for a second so now I
think this should work
oh that's nice
that's real nice very cool that's what I
love about this wood border I didn't
hike pressure plates and pistons and
stuff in it OOP glitch so I'm going to
do that there there there and there for
sure and it would be cool to hide maybe
enderchest I brought along as well have
one of those hidden here and if possible
crafting table too so I'm gonna get to
this and add a few more in yeah this is
gonna be a really nice addition to have
around here a lot less running around
that's for sure doo doo doo sweet ooh so
for this last one I'm gonna put a
crafting bench instead you know light
block there and crafting table I always
mix those up ever since terraria you
know I always can't keep it straight
wait wait yeah that's right those are
stairs I modified this part a little bit
also
that's and three more of these and I
think we're good to go here all set all
right checked it out that's a really
cool effect in Dorchester this is my
first official enderchest that's not in
a temporary place awesome
okay oh yeah one more thing I should
probably get rid of glass if I'm doing
trading so it's going to maybe do this
instead whoa whoops just four down here
got an egg yeah I'm all out of steak too
I died when I was kami fell in lava lost
a bunch of stuff including my food
all right what was they doing this yeah
how does that look the other option is
to do from above or iron bars then you
can't really see their face though okay
I'm gonna leave it like this for now
have the iron bars at the bottom holds
it in you can see their face still
pretty good these two have been staring
at each other for a long time a very
long time and also I started moving
paper here sweet alright it's moving on
I've been working up here at the potion
room storage thing so remember I said I
want it to mirror that half arch on this
side of the door well I discovered that
wasn't gonna work because the wall came
out to here before like the stone brick
lining and the stone wall was right
there so I juggled some of the wiring
around in here and compressed it and now
I'm able to move the wall not just one
block in which is what this would be but
two whole blocks in so I move the wall
from here to there so I should be able
to mimic that and that's what I'm gonna
do now
I got it mirrored and it looks pretty
good I'm happy with it
check it out yep and then I added this
another arch here then I just need to
connect that to this somehow and we will
be done with the arches this whole area
will be connected together nicely every
section has arches and then here will be
open no more arches in this room so
yep starting to figure things out to
finalize things grasp going here wood
over there this is where I've been
keeping the comic books for now until we
build the library still not sure some
people suggest that I should put it in
Emerald City which I might but I also
found a pretty cool floating island
somewhere which I might want to put it
as well yeah it would change just would
you see that one OOP that one leg though
is this hang out in midair so we have to
do something about that now what I do
want to check out is what's behind here
because we might be able to put another
room or something depending on how much
space we have well we'll definitely do
something but I just want to see how far
we can go before we run into something
I've built if we run into something I
built okay there we go
that is the cave spider staircase let's
just check that make sure it's in
working order yeah it should be fine
there's a sign right there oh there's
the other one okay just wanted to make
sure I didn't take the sign off somehow
yeah we could have a pretty big room
over here by the looks of it that's some
sorts maybe a bedroom or something
although I did oh all right I can take
this out I moved the wall one block and
then it's like you know I can move this
another one so I did it again that's why
it's so sick there
but yeah you get the idea that's pretty
good
what I'm thinking of doing is this the
mushroom farm the stairs go in like that
at the top what if we ate man even
harvested the mushrooms there's a lot of
slime chunks in my area here did not
come from the slime farm yeah like I
sink a mirror stairs like this somehow
and then I have a column like that maybe
and then put something in between maybe
okay I did a few more things here this
kind of works I like this how it shapes
upward like that then we could have some
lighting either if we can make it work
without it burning anything we could put
lava somewhere behind there and try and
make it look good we'll leave it like
that for today though
then I added this thing which doesn't
look too great from this side but we
could cover up a lot of that with stone
like that square put some stone in front
but on this side it looks really good
and it mirrors that one got a nice
lookout up here and then the space
between that one and that one is exactly
the same as this arch here so I could
just copy that too
which is what I might try see that what
happens to be changed do that and we'll
just lay out the shape really quickly
here so an idea I have guys something I
would like to be added something I would
like to add it to the game intense
I like caving a lot I've been doing a
lot of it lately
lately they improved it quite a bit in
my opinion by adding or adding the
feature where you get XP from mining
ores something else I would like to see
though to make G be more challenging and
more rewarding maybe they have all this
new stuff with spawners like all these
new perimeters or they didn't add potion
effects to the mobs when they spawn and
all that I think it'd be cool if like
dungeons had a chance of being special
dungeons like that spawn mobs that are
more difficult than usual maybe like a 1
and 1/4 chance of it being a special
spawner of course what I would really
like is if they made super dungeons I
had lots of spawners but in vanilla that
could easily be exploited so they would
have to deal with that somehow if if
they were to yeah more challenging
gaming please that's what I would like
and maybe do that sure why not
how's it look from here yeah I think
that's what we're gonna do guys got to
figure it out what do you see when you
look at this I was looking at it and
that's a smile that's one eye if we'd
had another one there it would be a big
smiley face I don't know if we'll do
that but I just noticed that that would
be pretty funny okay so I did some more
up here I just changed things up I got
these running across now and did some
stuff with this I almost wonder if I
should use it in the type of wood like
the dark wood or something for the top
here but overall I think it looks pretty
good
I started clearing out this room
whatever we're gonna put here I'm not
sure yet but it's another space we can
use yeah so I think that one's pretty
good I was gonna do something I can't
remember now mmm well I don't have a
whole lot of time I don't have a whole
lot of time left for today but maybe
we'll just poke into this village really
quick I love that yeah let's go to the
village I thought I was gonna run to the
Redstone wiring for the door oh boy is
it over there
but I never did when I was doing that
chest stuff oh hello
hmm hmm pretty sure these guys won't
hurt villagers secrecy it's the zombies
and other mobs inadvertently they can't
like skeletons could accidentally shoot
one or a creeper could blow up in the
air one just making sure they're still
here this guy's stuck in there I don't
see any villagers ask me a little bit
worried they down here it's at least one
down here I'm pretty sure one oh boy
where's the other guy there he is
sometimes he likes to go for walks
that's allowed
so as like in the comments on what water
fountain feature type thing we should
use and everybody sort of said something
different so I think we'll go with this
one think slightly more people said this
one but it was really hard to tell a lot
of people said to go ahead and just do
the piston thing as well so that's what
I'm gonna do now
hey I want I want to get him out of
there yes I'll I'm gonna put pistons
here punch holes in the ceiling maybe
fill that one back up and that way we
can put doors down here and they'll
think they're actually outside doors
okay I got a hole punched right there we
got a skylight that comes all the way
down to in front of the doors here
shines for the Pistons
we have this guy down here and when I
shut the water off he pretty much
instantly bolted to the doors so it
seems like they're working but I'm
keeping an eye on him
he hasn't gone out gone through them
since he's gone through them
he hasn't come back through them since
he went into them I should say or
however you want to say it so he's he's
inside I'm pretty sure where he thinks
he's inside I'm guessing when it turns
day it's still night time but when it
turns day he'll probably come through
and I'm just working down here to
keeping an eye on what he does it looks
like it's turning day now so let's see
what he does if you'll come through the
doors he hasn't gone through them all
night which is good yeah that's that's
looking pretty day out I don't know he's
staring off into space or something I
think when I get them together again
they'll start breeding
come on it's definitely d yep mmm that
other guy came through I don't what this
guy is doing
and oh you know what it looks like he's
doing it he's like great against the
wall it's almost like he's trying to get
back up there
wait come on man just go through the
doors oh he's so close
yeah I think we got a problem guys dang
it's okay we're learning things about
them how they work don't understand why
he doesn't think it's day or why that's
not a valid door oh they found each
other how are they breeding but I saw
hearts
No
hmm yeah I don't really know what's
going on it seemed like it was working
but now this doesn't want to go through
about 30 seconds to a minute later they
both came through the door no he's
trying to go back and succeeds dang yeah
I got a really rethink this whole thing
because I I can foresee a lot of
problems with it and that's all we're
gonna do for today guys I have a comment
here I picked out it's actually one I
really like it's something I've been
meaning to talk about heyyyyy so just
wondering how you feel about using the
snapshots in your LP I think that
decoration items would work for you like
for arrows with the frames or with
sorting hope you read this beam yeah you
know what I've been really tempted to
use the snapshots in in the let's play
before I was avoiding it completely
because I didn't want to spoil the
patches you know but you know what
happened I saw so many videos about the
features and saw everybody doing stuff
with the features that were coming on
the snapshots by the time it actually
came out like six months they were
developing 1.3 or whatever whatever it
was by the time it actually came out a
lot of it was already spoiled so yeah I
don't mind waiting a few weeks for a
patch but if you gotta wait months and
months and months chances are a lot of
its gonna be wrecked anyway so as long
as long as the patch is not super buddy
I think I may consider doing it soon one
thing that worries me about that though
is like some people may avoid watching
my let's play because that then I could
potentially be spoiling spoiling the
patch or the snapshots for the
so I don't know it's a tough decision I
would like to but there's pros and pros
and cons to it I'm not sure what you
guys would think of it in general but
yeah good question well have a great day
everybody see you later
[Music]