[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and we're back again to the guys
with another let's play episode checking
out the 1.14 update some more just
barely scratched the surface on this
thing so far we got a lot to check out I
thought we would do one of the more
subtle features here and we would we
would take a look at it and give our
course fruit firm and a major update so
if you don't know the way we currently
harvest this thing it takes about 10
minutes or so it's actually quite
time-consuming basically I run along the
top of the wood here and try to knock
off the seeds and every plant usually
has like five seeds to it on average
right we gotta get at least one off of
each plant so that we can we'll have
enough to regrow um and I just kind of
run along here and get as many as I can
as quickly as I can to because I only
got 5 minutes before they start the
spawning so that's the way we used to do
it but now in 1.14 they made a very
subtle but very awesome change where you
can knock the seeds off of course roots
using a bow or even a trident it looks
like which is really cool I like that a
lot
I did try with like snow balls and eggs
and and what are they the the charges
the fire charges those don't work none
of these work it has to be I think you
lose the bow or a trident
or probably the crossbow and I it looks
like it even works if you do it from a
dispenser so if we plant this down shoot
it with an arrow it pops off so that's
cool so what we want to do is try to add
some way of automatically harvesting the
seeds off of our course fruits plants
here and also yeah there's one more
thing I wanted to check out you know
that trick where you can let's get our
tried and equipped you know that trick
where you're you're trying can kind of
hover around I wanted to try that out so
if we throw it
get our arrows there so it can't return
it in our inventory we don't have enough
space for it so it just kind of hovers
around us it's kind of curious what
happens if we run near our course fruit
see if it if it knocks anything off or
hits anything doesn't look like it
really does anything hmm
that could have been cool too if you
just like run through here and it would
with like ten tridents hovering around
you and you could harvest everything now
I don't think that's that's gonna work
okay
let's go with the redstone method then
okay I just thought of a stupid game you
can play with all at roie's here it's
kind of like golf where you try to get a
hole-in-one basically except you're the
ball and if you miss you'll probably die
all right so the idea is you try to go
headfirst oh I missed it you go like
headfirst down into a 2x2 hole or
something then see if you can make it
without hitting the ground let's try one
more time it's really hard to aim
actually
Oh nope so I think maybe gotta go more
like you gotta be higher up maybe I'll
get it don't you guys worry don't you
worry oh that was close there's got to
be a trick to this right
Oh oh that was so close like I can get
within two blocks of it almost every
time it's a there's a 4x4 I think I
could do it
almost every time it's just two by two
though huh oh and it still killed me
what I hit the water oh I just I just
didn't slow me down enough all right you
guys might be wondering like what does
this have to do with the course fruit
farm we got to stop by here just to get
some sea lanterns this is our guardian
farm lots of lots of goodies here we're
gonna grab probably two stacks maybe
three okay so first step of our upgrade
here we're gonna replace all these
glowstone lamps we have along the wood
here with C lanterns so that we don't
have to have this leaver
sticking out all right good stuff so now
we're gonna add our mechanism to our
farm and I think we could do it pretty
simply actually the plan is just to have
some dispensers running along these wood
beams and we'll fill them up with arrows
and just shoot them straight up and they
should land on the seeds down below it
and this will work pretty good with our
existing farm actually it just so
happens between each of these we have a
one two three four five block space and
I think when you shoot an arrow out of a
dispenser like this it will travel
horizontally like up to two or three
blocks so it kind of works out like it
should reach to about the middle from
here and then on this one will reach to
like the middle over here as well so
it'll cover most of the area pretty sure
cuz when it shoots out of this dispenser
it's gonna have a random angle to it
most of them are gonna land toward the
center but the odd one's gonna go off
and if it hits a seed that's gonna cause
it to break off aha so we'll probably
have to shoot quite a few arrows though
like you see how far that one traveled
probably have to have quite a few arrows
flying here so the plan is we'll
probably put these every two blocks like
so we got to have some way
filling them with arrows and activating
them as well so the plan is have hoppers
running between each of these so that if
we put the arrows and hoppers they'll go
into the dispenser and then we'll just
run some rails over top and doesn't
matter where we put them yes we probably
want that it's the activator rail over
the dispenser I'm guessing the Spencer's
are able to shoot through rails and then
they'll power the power rails as well
when the cart goes over top okay
everybody so this is a little bit later
now I had to stop and and go do some
mining we were totally out of redstone
again what else is new rights so we got
some more redstone a little bit more
iron for hoppers and we got this pretty
much all set up now we're about to test
the doubts so I did it a little bit
different because the detector rails on
top where they were was either powering
the hopper or the dispenser and was
either not letting the arrows travel
through or the dispenser was being bud
powered or it just didn't work let's
leave it at that it didn't work so I
split the systems so we got the rails to
deliver the arrows and then we have
redstone running underneath to activate
the dispensers and we have full control
over both that way and then we're gonna
have a reservoir of arrows in these
chests and probably oh I am NOT as ready
as I thought I was I shouldn't have
started recording I thought I had the
Opera mic guards on me there there
uh-huh you know I try to I try to make
things run smoothly whenever I can but
it doesn't always work okay let's go
back up yeah so the plan is get these
going underneath they should fill up
pretty quick with the arrows yeah look
at that
that's great they should also fill these
dispensers pretty quickly I believe so
we got to get five different lines going
all right and we'll have to let this run
every so often just to refill the
dispensers but it probably doesn't need
to happen
all the time okay so let's go over here
now slip that switch so let's see the
first pass how many arrows just one one
in there oh I was hoping for more should
be pretty good now I think we'll shut
this off so what are they ants we're at
40 okay so 40 arrows per dispenser I'm
guessing we only need like 15 maybe 20
to do a harvest but we'll see here cuz a
lot of the arrows are gonna miss like
they're not gonna hit the seeds every
time but they only need to hit one from
each plant really to be successful with
this so yeah we set up a pulsar down
here and let's just try to do like 10 at
first and kind of see how my seeds get
knocked off wow that happened quickly
all these smokes okay that was pretty
cool oh yeah that was only 10 Wow okay
there's a lot of arrows that just got
shot I'm seeing lots of seeds that are
that are on the ground a lot of them got
knocked off so yeah probably only 15 to
20 I'm guessing let's let it run a
little bit longer and then we'll do a
harvest I feel like that's about 50
night yeah so I was 15 exactly okay
so now we're gonna hit the button how
many we got in here
let's take these all out so it doesn't
mess up with our results we'll hit the
button it's gonna cause a lot of leg
because now we have so many entities on
the ground too and I think they get
washed by water so oh maybe they don't
no okay they all stayed in place just
the ones that were on the course fruit
plants you could hear them them dropping
uh-huh alright kill this fool and there
goes the water and the seeds should
start funneling up here are you able to
shoot whoa okay
did you hit that one over there
yeah he hit over here and knocked the
seat off okay so you can use the
skeletons and stuff to knock them off
too if you want pretty much anything
that shoots arrows okay let's go to bed
here we're gonna check this thing out it
looks like we need like two and a half
stacks to replant I'm just gonna replant
here and we got just about two and a
half stacks with those 15 arrows shot so
we probably want to go to 20 to 25 per
harvest actually arrows from each
dispenser also we got a couple problems
with this thing and this is filling up
with coarse fruits so I think our item
filters got messed up and probably got
to do with a couple repairs on this this
system can't so that's the coarse fruit
one oh yeah so this is supposed to be
for coarse flowers somehow the 18 we had
in here got removed so got a deal with
that and let's actually head over to our
smelting area to see if it's making
torpor or if that elevator is still
broken I can't remember so basically we
send all the course fruit over to this
building which is where it's supposed to
get smelted in the basement here oh
they're not running oh okay we have
problems all right
this farms kind of busted a little bit
it looks like I think it's the elevator
we put an elevator in this thing and I'm
guessing it doesn't work anymore all
right
what kind of elevator it's the old is it
a redstone this one oh no it's this
wonky one still I thought I ripped this
thing out and replaced it I guess not
okay so this is like a really weird
elevator that probably doesn't work at
all anymore so we can we just got to
replace this with a bubble stream yeah
so that old elevator it worked by
sending items through blocks which isn't
really a thing you can do anymore so we
ripped out all that redstone that you
saw there that huge contraption and it's
just been replaced with the bubble
stream
which is so much simpler let's test it
out
so of course fruits supposed to go in
and up yep looks good all right and I
think I know what happened with item
filters we're using one of these old
styles which I try not to do anymore I
don't know why I built one here
but the issue if you only have like 18
items in here and it fills up entirely
like if it goes to 64 this signal
travels three blocks so one two three
and it'll activate the one next to it so
this item filter caused this one to
shoot out all the items and I think
that's why it broke before so what we
want to do is just expand this to be one
block longer uh-huh yeah so this is a
pretty common trick I'm sure a lot of
you guys already know about it but just
in case you don't if you're a little bit
newer to redstone by expanding the item
filter here it makes it a bit bigger
which we don't like like this is a bit
of a trade off it gets a bit bigger and
we also have to keep 41 items in here
instead of just 18 so that costs a
little bit more as well but the benefit
is like if this fills up to a full stack
we never have to worry about it
affecting the item filter next to it
because it can't go beyond a full stack
and add a full stack it can only travel
through blocks that would need to travel
for to reach the one next to it which is
impossible but it's important to note we
have to get rid of these ones in our
filter because otherwise we could have
up to five stacks in here we need an
item in there a garbage item that will
never go into the hoppers so that it's
safe so now at most you can only have
one stack course fruit in here at a time
all right everybody good stuff good
stuff so we're about done with this
project I'd say we got it fixed up the
item filters the elevators are working
now from what I can tell
and we even upgraded it with the new
system for not gonna the seeds off
that's gonna save a lot of time in the
long run because we use quite a bit of
perper on our nether tunnels actually
and one thing I'm going to add
off-camera here before we're done with
it is just a long delay one of these
things to the start of the Pulsar there
so what this is going to do
is so I don't have to time how long to
pull the lever for I'll just have to
press a button and then it'll shoot
exactly 21 arrows so when we did 15
arrows there we almost got enough seeds
back
it's a replant it was just a little bit
shy so if we shoot an extra six I'm
pretty sure we'll get enough Plus
probably a little bit extra
all right everybody so we're gonna check
out another cool thing that's been added
in 1.14 again kind of a subtle change
but it's got big implications here tea
and tea now drops all the blocks when it
blows something up so I'm doing some
testing here like look how much sand we
got from that that's amazing that's
awesome
and of course in order to make TNT you
need sand and gunpowder so in the past
it wasn't really efficient or I don't
think it was at least to use TNT to mine
sand it was just a lot quicker to use a
shovel but now I've blown up five other
pieces besides this just to give an idea
of how much we're getting and I've been
trying to do it kind of on a flat area
of sand so the first time I did it we
got 20 sandstone 64 and 1820 sandstone
the second time 64 and 21 64 and 47 64
and 41 6447 6451 so we're kind of
getting pretty close to close averages
here now that's just been like laying
tnt down on a flat surface like so and
then lighting it that's kind of the
easiest way to place it there's another
way we can do it though which will
probably yield more sands but takes more
set-up time
yeah so the other method we can do this
is we can dig a little bit of a hole
before we place down the TNT and drop it
down that way we can take advantage of
the top part of the explosion along with
the bottom will be more of a sphere that
gets blown up it seems like we do get
more blocks doing it this way but I
don't think it's worth the extra time it
takes to dig the hole we also get a lot
more sandstone and cobblestone in this
method which generally you don't want
you just kind of just want the sand
right I've done a couple explosions now
to kind of compare so this was our first
test we're roughly getting about a
hundred sand per explosion give or take
right this is the results from this new
method of digging hole we get pretty
much the same amount of sand sometimes
though we get quite a bit more like over
two stacks sandstone over here
sandstone over here the rest is sand so
we're getting pretty much 100 sand as
well but we're getting a lot more
sandstone about 140 blocks compared to
like 110 we get this way so is it worth
it probably not I think just placing on
the surface is a lot easier is it worth
it is it efficient way of getting sand
for making more TNT I think so I think
this is gonna be the new thing so how do
we do it quickly
I just just like this just keeping your
offhand and switch it maybe
Oh Oh try not to blow yourself up guy
get into a habit okay let's run through
here and kind of see what we got yeah so
the ones that we blow up on the surface
they only go like three or four blocks
deep in general which kind of makes it
easy as well because we can go from like
this hole to this one a lot easier it's
not much of a climb while that other
method was making holes that were like
six or seven blocks deep which are kind
of hard to traverse so we're getting
like a hundred or more sand per TNT
that's enough to make 25 TNT per TNT
right so something that might be worth
checking out we can be a bit more
liberal with our TNT use and do like
chaos cannons that might actually be a
thing if we can get the TNT to spread
out enough it won't blow up the sand
that other TNT creates hopefully let's
get out of here I'm guessing you only
wanted like a few blocks above the
surface that looks like it's spread out
pretty good
yeah look at all the sand no good at all
so that might be a faster way of like
covering an area
either way though this is gonna be cool
I really like this change one of the
things I dreaded a lot before was like
collecting sand for glass and concrete
sand more TNT you know now there's a
method that seems to be quicker and is
actually fun because we can use TNT to
do it so I like that so that's a great
combo and let's check out one more thing
here this is something I've wanted to do
for a long time use TNT in the tree farm
last time I tried this though it could
almost blow up a five by five by five
area but we lost so many blocks that I
just never ended up doing it but now
this probably is a great way of doing a
tree farm actually so the idea is we'd
probably drop the TNT from a dispenser
above down into the middle use pistons
to get them all into this position I
should we set up some sand or some dirt
just to see if it blasts this
because ideally you'd like to have the
Pistons here that don't get destroyed
but that might not be possible it's
curious it'll go up the dirt okay we got
sand underneath so that'll give us an
idea as well all right
so and that blows up okay so it doesn't
do the edges did it blow up any of the
dirts this is fine on the side fine on
this side fine on this side yeah so it's
pretty exact actually which is good
looks like it doesn't get this row here
though well it took one out one piece
out over here one piece out over there
yeah if I remember right I did this test
like at least 20 times in the past and
it never would blow up the dirt on the
edges but let's do it again now in 114
and make sure it's still consistent I
think it always leaves like a 3d cube
though after the explosion all the dirts
fine still that's great and very similar
results on this explosion so that's
mining about 70 blocks roughly per TNT
which is not bad like that is a lot of
wood that would take so long to mine
with your axe 70 blocks oh boy okay this
is actually a pretty big deal so long
and gone are the days of chopping wood
everybody new tree farms are gonna be
amazing in 114 so we're actually on the
build one right now I guess I went into
creative to play around with it for a
bit and came up with what I think is a
pretty awesome idea actually so I got to
thinking why bother
like making a whole bunch of piston
conveyor systems and whatnot to push the
logs around why don't we just make a
pattern like this and grow spruce trees
or jungle trees or something right for
2x2 trees and then leave the middle
hollow if possible and this is where we
drop the TNT down
so I played around with it for a bit and
I figured out if we go up one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
counting time with ease oh all right you
guys ready 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20
21 22 23 24 25 26 guys okay so I'm going
to show you how to build this tree farm
you go up 26 blocks and then you start
making your platforms this is where
we're gonna be dropping the TNT down so
you want to keep that open yeah so keep
in mind the spacing matters quite a bit
with this so 26 dirt blocks below us and
then the clay here's our 27th and at 27
is where we start with our pistons so
all along this side all the way up we're
gonna have pistons and then on this side
we're gonna have dispensers with the TNT
in starting one block above the piston
all right and then there's just a simple
pattern we got to do all the repeaters
we place here we set to four all right
and then we snake our way up the tower
here so we go like this repeater into
redstone into another repeater set that
to four and then I guess we go up again
and then we go back so wire wire had
right place this yes we'll do this okay
no that's not right I know what I'm
doing everybody don't you worry don't
you worry double repeater four one two
three four all right so now we are at
our next dispenser and I just leave a
block there too
okay and then somehow I built this and
creative what like where I could fly
around so it's much different now try to
do it without being able to fly a little
bit harder okay then that goes to here
and we do the same pattern for go up
and then redstone repeater and go back
and forth back and forth with this all
the way up we go up six dispensers and
six Pistons uh-huh so this is what it
looks like when one side is done which
is zig and zag zig and zag all are all
the way up here six dispenser is high
and then with the Pistons we do the
exact same thing except mirrored on the
other side so again we go like this
except where the dispenser is we put a
block and there should be the piston
below it okay and then we go over here
repeater we just copy what we have over
here basically go up and over all right
redstone dust and hopefully you get the
idea cuz we're not gonna build the whole
thing on camera here I'll take too long
and then our piston needs to go right
here I haven't quite figured out how to
place it I guess let's go over like this
no it's still faced up well if we place
it like right in the corner there we go
that we figured it out okay so the block
goes above rights done up here repeaters
all set to 4 all the way up okay so we
got both sides done now and they're
basically a mirrors of each other so now
the way this works the piston is gonna
be extended and then this shoots the TNT
on top of the piston head which holds it
for a short amount of time and then
releases it now we got to make sure the
TNT stays centered though so we need to
have blocks on the sides here as well
which can be anything I'm gonna use
glass for this I guess I'll stack all
the way up so that no TNT shoots
sideways here mm-hmm
so we've pretty much got the the main
core of this tree farm working that's
all we're going to do today like there's
a lot of extra features we could add to
make this nicer but I'll just show you
the the basic idea to it today cuz we're
almost out of time so we want to invert
the signal here and we need five
Peters I think we can get rid of this
put redstone dust there instead set all
these to four oops redstone dust there
to connect them and then leave this one
at one I guess I think that's the right
timing will make sure here though and
that's all all the redstone stuff you
need for this really we'll throw a lever
here for controlling it so the idea is
when we pull this lever it's gonna
activate the TNT dispensers and then
like 20 ticks later the Pistons retract
and it drops the TNT down one after
another starting from the bottom to the
top and now that that's done I think
we're about ready to try it out here so
let's let's do that we gotta grow some
trees so we'll go with spruce saplings
for this test so we do something like
this and the nice thing is the way these
trees are positioned we never have to
worry about like this tree merging with
this one
like sometimes that happens when you do
a four by four tree area but should be
perfectly fine with this so you grow
that this one and again like there's
lots of cool things you'd add for this
dispensers with bonemeal in to
automatically grow them one big thing
with this that's gonna be really
important though we have to fly to the
top of it or go to the top of it and
shear out the middle we got to remove
the core so that the TNT is free to drop
down because it's gonna be full of
leaves all the way so probably set up
like a bubble stream elevator next to
this that brings us to the top we share
our way down and then put like a button
down here to activate it ideally but we
don't have that setup nut right now this
is just the rough thing so we got to fly
up there to pull that lever so it's not
fancy at all but it should work I think
I put TNT in all of these and it's gonna
use 60 per harvest so hopefully I do
anything wrong hopefully we don't blow
it up
that go from a distance to check it out
so it starts from the bottom and works
its way up and you see that a little
timing between its to allow all the
drops to fall down without getting blown
up by the TNT because if you it went
boom boom boom boom boom
most of the drops would get exploded but
this gives it time to fall with the
gravity and I guess let's see what we
get here now it doesn't do a perfect job
either but it's pretty close
let's throw away our saplings too
because I'm curious about that we need
at least 16 we're pretty good here a
little bit more up there some fell in
the middle we could set up a system for
automatically picking up the stuff like
maybe the hopper minecart or something
underneath running there's a few leaves
left over that will despawn over time if
we leave them and you'll have a few
pieces of wood left over and midair
that's perfectly fine as well we'll
still be able to grow the next set of
trees and they'll just grow through
whatever's left that didn't get cleared
out so we got just about four stacks of
wood there and 18 saplings so that's
that's good to go probably set up some
Pistons to move these last couple pieces
of logs that don't get moved right but
we can just chop them away - it's fine
and get started on the next batch and
yeah that's kind of the idea behind it I
think it's gonna be really cool
really convenient really quick and like
the great thing about this is you could
set this up pretty quickly in a new
world like it only costs a few stacks of
redstone right there's hardly any
Pistons in it so it's not gonna use a
whole bunch of iron you just need a
source of TNT though it's kind of the
problem
all right and we go for the next round
sometimes the trees are taller than
other times as well this time if they
weren't quite as tall so we didn't get
as much wood oh we're fine and you'll
notice none of the dirt got blown off
that's really important so all this
puzzles still here
all right everybody well I think we'll
have to wrap up for today's episode I'll
try getting the more done on that tree
farm for next time though we'll check
out some extra features try to make it a
little nicer to use but for now we're
gonna read the comment of the day in the
finish up here it says hey etho are you
doing okay for some reason your voice
doesn't make you sound like you're in
the greatest shape if you're in any
trouble I hope you get better soon if
not well then sorry for misinterpreting
uh-huh I appreciate the concern I really
do honestly I actually not to brag or
anything I don't want to sound braggy
but I feel like I got pretty lucky in
life as far as health goes never really
had any serious health problems and even
like stuff that could have happened from
accidents like breaking a bone or or
getting ran over or something like that
that's never happened to me I haven't
had any serious health problems from
stupidity either so yeah
the only real issue I have is a slight
allergy to pop and that's it like I'll
get nosebleeds if I didn't drink a lot
of pop also knowing this soda to some of
you other than that though doing pretty
good I resumed the exercise thing I kind
of fell out of it during last summer but
managed to pick it up I'm doing chin-ups
it ups push ups lifting weights and
stuff and feeling pretty good for a
while there I thought maybe I was gonna
start gaining weight but that kind of
got under control I haven't gained any
weight I'm not it
no no chubbs added to the etho only
thing is that I think I could improve is
I
you used to do like a lot of biking and
tennis and stuff and I don't do that
anymore I hardly move because I'm in my
chair all day so if I was that asked to
run somewhere I would get winded so fast
so that's something I should probably
think about doing more of but yeah
that's kind of kind of where I'm at
right now
thank you for your concern again I
encourage everybody to get into exercise
if you haven't I've mentioned this
before not only does it improve your
physical well-being it is great for your
mental well-being as well like you feel
better and have more energy and stuff
when you exercise too so it's it's
definitely worth doing and I definitely
encourage people to get into it or to
resume it if you've kind of gotten lazy
like I did at some point get back into
it you can do it alright so hopefully
you guys enjoyed today's episode thank
you for watching as always and I'll see
you in the next one take care have a
good day bye bye
[Music]