[Music]
hello hello
everybody go get your snacks welcome to
another episode i like chocolate
and um i wanted to show you this cool
trick i figured out the other day
with beacons so you know
like i had a barrier here before i'm
changing changing it around
but you know if you have a solid block
above the beam
it gets disabled right
um there is this really neat thing you
can do though
it's more of a visual pleasing thing
than anything
but i i wanted to see what it would look
like if you had one of these above a
beacon
because they're very similar in size the
beam and
the cobblestone wall and it i think it
has a really cool effect
and i'll probably do this a lot if i
ever set up beacons
just because i like it so much
but yeah check that out
i don't know i think it's cool you can
even like uh
create patterns in it like you can have
one missing
every second block or something if you
have several beams next to each other
you can do other
other patterns as well um
really good for underground bases like
if you have a beacon underground
but you don't want to see an opening in
the sky
you can do something like this i'm just
going to put this where the other
beacons are supposed to go
do something like this and
have
like blocks around here
creeper check we're good
so the beacon ground will look like that
to make it come up
and i'll probably do this on the
minecraft server with my
beacon setup it looks really cool if you
have like glass
like three high glass i can see the beam
through it
and go up
top it off with another one of these
and then like to have your ceiling
up there
i don't know i thought it was cool i
wanted to share it
and it doesn't look as good as i hoped
with the the mossy walls though
the mossy cobblestone walls looks a
little strange
but yeah anyway
well i couldn't just leave at that so i
messed with that some more and now we
have a
fairly big structure for our beacon to
protect it
and to emphasize it some more
i don't know i think it's pretty cool i
like it
it'll look a lot better when we get
three more beams in there though
so dark so spooky we are down in the
mines again today
because i've added 50 new names so i
thought it'd be nice to go through these
as a way of saying thanks to the people
that have donated
i do really appreciate it
and actually this is maybe a good time
to bring up a topic
um very serious in nature
um i may have mentioned this before but
lately like the past few months i've
been under some pretty bad hardships
um i've been it's it's been tough
uh it's actually affected me emotionally
pretty bad too
but that has all changed thanks to these
minds
uh today finally
i actually went through them started
mining them out
and now i have like over 10 stacks of
redstone dust again which is just
awesome i can i can do stuff again
uh i've just been working with nothing
really for the longest time
every little scrap i could get i've used
up
and it's pretty much just squeezing
redstone out of
like out of stones like every little
morsel i could get
and barely getting by so
thanks for the minds guys they have
helped out a lot
and at this level like at y 12 with
their eyes
that's ideal for getting redstone that's
the main reason i'm using these mines
actually
you also get a lot of blue shiny rocks
but the redstone
is the ticket you find it constantly
like you see it more than iron or
anything else
which is great so i can
hopefully get to doing stuff with it
again
it's really not it's really hard not
having redstone on minecraft i have so
much of it because people keep giving it
to me
i'm actually going to be using a lot of
that up too though pretty soon
on a project
i think we're about through all right
that's
it so thank you everyone i still have i
think
over 50 names to go and uh
gotta gotta work at finishing these
okay let's let's head back up to the
surface and
actually we might go to the end today
i've been meaning to fix up the enderman
farm
so here we are at the ender ender and i
want to do some work around here today
let's first do an enchantment
and it is absolutely garbage um
yeah so i want to make some improvements
around here i never did really finish
this
um and there's a few problems with it
so one of the big problems is this
island here
actually we're going to tear it down
today
wow he actually grabbed the block from
it
yeah when i made that island i didn't
really know how far enderman could
teleport
and they can teleport 32 blocks
apparently so they can go from this pad
up there and when that happens
i have fewer mobs in my enderman trap
and that is a very bad thing
so we should really get rid of this
thing
yeah it's not many but a few mobs do end
up here and the longer i stay
around this area the more that actually
do teleport
did they remove all the soil or was it
always stone
i can't remember how i left this i know
they've
they've removed a lot of the soil i
think it was stone on top
yeah this was all soil over here that's
all gone
crazy uh this is solid stone
i have tnt in the ender chest i'm gonna
rig this up to blow
and then i'll remove the rest with my
tools
um we may still do the island thing but
i'm not really too excited about it at
the moment
if we do we'll definitely build it
further away though
okay so let me set this up and we'll
have some fun
i'm digging this out to place my tnt
pockets and it is a really weird feeling
being in here like we're in the end
digging out stone that i've placed
myself
and it's it's pretty big like this is a
big island
i don't know it just seems strange being
up in the air
oh i had a really strong urge to walk
forward for some reason
um yeah i think i'm just gonna
do it like this and we'll see what
happens
ah what is this joke's on you man you're
actually helping me out this time
um okay i think we're ready to go here
island be gone
whoo oh yeah
very cool
um did this get missed not yet did
uh it's actually not that thick anymore
i i was expecting more land to be left
almost fell out of the world oh
come on come on
nope
all right yeah so i'm going to finish
tearing this down
and then we will try to work on a few
other things here
this is the end of the island a little
bit left to go
i've been trying to figure out how to
get down and finish
tearing it down i think this is probably
the best place just jump down there
and i might be able to reach still
yep cool all right that's one thing down
i am going to have to move this platform
too i want to get rid of this
and rebuild a proper enchanting station
and proper storage
um let's see what else
i do want to get rid of these these uh
fences
they don't really do anything for me
because i don't stand here when i kill
them
i'm always at this end
and they get stuck behind these and can
be angry
at me and sometimes like i'll start
walking on my bridge not knowing
there's a few stuck behind these fences
trying to get me
and they'll teleport and kill me so
they're actually
kind of dangerous i want to get rid of
those
um i think i'm going to replace this
ground
with grass just so it looks nicer
there's no color in the end so
if we can get some green or other colors
in here will look better
well i got about half of it torn up now
um
this is a very big job though and these
guys are making it tougher
it's 40 by 40. so i gotta
remove about 25 stacks of stone
and then place 25 stacks of dirt
plus whatever these guys steal which is
a lot actually and they're in my way
and yeah
pretty frustrating um
so i'm gonna start using glowstone
instead of
torches as well oops try to make it look
better
but yeah lots to go here
all right i know how to deal with them
now if they're in my way i luckily
had one of these on me and it's helping
out a lot
i'm pretty sure they can't steal blocks
if it's on flat ground
like if i fill this totally in i don't
think they can pick them up it's only if
they can grab the side of it like this
but like blocks over here they can't
take
but i am watching for it so far
hasn't happened
all right
look at these guys man just about every
one of them took one
it's insane and now i gotta clean them
up too
oh man these guys
it's all right they don't seem to be
picking up uh the ones i just laid down
which is good
although that has me worried over here
oh maybe one was over here unable to
reach
the outer edge i don't have to watch it
for a bit
uh yeah so go do the other half here and
put in some lighting
glowstone pattern of some sort
i get that a lot where it makes the
noise but i didn't actually anger any of
them
it's like if you look at them but
not at the crotch sometimes it does that
uh it's weird anyway
well next up we are placing the grass
and
it should spread pretty good we got the
lights in place i
put the glowstone every fifth block it's
more than what's needed
but it will keep this place nice and
bright
and yeah you can definitely see they're
taken from the edges so i'll need
another block
uh all along here that they can't take
so maybe cobblestone um
other than that it's looking pretty good
seems like a lot of enderman doesn't it
there it is some nice green pastures for
them to graze on
uh looks a lot better i think
it's quite the change though it's gonna
take some time to get used to but i do
like it more
it's a lot easier to see them too uh
when it was gray before uh there wasn't
as much contrast and
you know when they get a little bit
further away from your view
the ones in the back can be hard to see
so with the green
they stand out a lot more
i do want to try put a cobblestone fence
around it yet
i think that would be pretty good and i
don't think it'll affect it
negatively in any way
because they shouldn't teleport behind
the fence
i might grab some mossy stuff too and
try work that in
i removed the outer edge a little bit
and i brought this up
so now i don't think they can steal the
grass at all
that's pretty good that's so scary
jump at that oh
[Music]
it's like being on the edge of a
building and trying to jump
over the rail it's like it looks like
you can but i don't think you
actually can
oh that scared me i don't know why
okay i think i trust it i'm gonna do a
full on trust test here
all right we're good um
yeah i think that'll be pretty good
that way i don't accidentally walk off
either i've been known to do that a few
times
i don't have a whole lot of time left
for today so we're gonna have to
finish this up but yeah i got to move
this platform back
we want it at least 32 blocks away from
where they drop down here i want to set
up a proper killing
area for these guys as well this this
fence isn't working for me anymore um
with the s p emulation now they can
actually hit me when i'm under here
uh somehow they like they glitch
into me um
actually one thing i'm wondering about
these cobblestone walls they shouldn't
be able to
jump over them so if i
use them i might not even need a roof
yeah interesting
that's one possibility
um but yeah instead of doing a fence
even if i do
put a protection over my head i'll use
water like i'll i'll put ice down and
melt it so i'll have floating water
above my head
so they won't be able to attack me
and they won't be able to teleport on
top of the fence because that's what's
happening with this a lot with me
uh they go up there sometimes they'll be
aggro so when i
when i poke out of here they'll all
attack me which is pretty freaky
or if i forget to go out and i start
walking this way
they'll knock me off this walkway which
has happened
many many times so we don't want a fence
like that at all
okay i did talk about wanting to set up
an eats road for this as well
because as as is right now i'm still
watching this stupid obsidian path i
don't have any
minecart track to get out here so it's
like a
two to three hundred block walk every
time
um kind of sucks
maybe for the rest of this episode we'll
just quickly check a few things with
eats i haven't messed with it in a long
time
i have no idea if it works at all
anymore
there always seems to be a way to get it
to work though so
yeah you know what before we leave this
place uh there's actually something i
want to do um
a lot of my new subscribers are confused
by this whole thing
like why why can't i kill him when i'm
holding a steak
why is this steak doing so much damage
um yeah if you didn't see the older
episodes there's a whole thing up there
and uh it's an ender it's called the
ender ender it's a trap
pistons push them when they spawn and
they fall down to here
onto this platform which is
um what was it oh i forget how far the
fall was i think it was
43 block fall gets them down to half a
heart so i can
punch him to death
oh yeah uh back when we fought the ender
dragon
we set up these snowmen and they're
still here
but constantly
okay i don't have much time to play
around with this i'll probably
try to figure it out some more later i
mainly just want to see
if the easy loader concept still works
for getting the boats on the road um
it's been so long how do we do that so
we'll do the standard road the two
block one like this
just wanna see if the boats will break
or not
and then ladders
whoa i've never heard that sound before
that's weird
huh anyway uh easy loader easy loader
how do we do that again
i think i used water's gotta come
see water comes
actually i had a different design for it
didn't i
i'm thinking back way way back to the
old design i think the new one
or the newer one
struggling to remember
did i have water here that went like
like that maybe
we'll try it blocks above build our
boats
oh the number of boats i went through
trying to figure all that out
back when it was tough to get wood so
many hours
cutting down trees
okay that's a good sign i did not put
any water down the lane though
so we'll do that one by one
that was weird it's like i placed the
water in the wrong spot and it corrected
itself
okay
um that thing tree is in my way
right so we need we'll put water here
get out of here and we will put one
over here
oh
i think it's working
just make sure the water's flowing
straight at the end here
well that's good news yeah i would like
to have a
eats road set up somewhere in my world
just for the coolness factor i think it
i think it still works actually looks
like it's going really quick too
because they did speed up boats like
it's not
quite the same as it used to be oh that
was weird i wasn't
it's kind of along this side i think
that's not right yeah i'll have to set
up a big
scale test on this
but it almost seems like it's not going
straight
anyway i don't have time to mess with
this today for for a long time
so let's go read the comments and
call it an end for today
well i saw this comment and i just had
to pick it uh
short and sweet you know i've never once
heard etho asked to like his video or
sub
after doing an episode only youtuber i
know that doesn't
oh i could go on a very long rant about
this topic
um well first of all why i don't do it
it always annoyed me on youtube when
people ask for likes
especially like the more attention
someone gives to
asking for them the more it annoys me
but i understand why people do it it
helps out their videos
but in particular when i first started
in youtube there was a certain
minecrafter i started watching and i was
just
just getting into his videos um
was kind of starting to get hooked and
then he was doing this thing though
where
he would spend five to ten minutes
basically a whole video
uh asking people begging people to like
his video
try to get as many likes as you can on
it um
it's a we're doing this together you're
we're
we're we're gonna be a a big happy group
type of thing really it's a selfish
action asking for likes
um and oh man i could talk for hours
about this
liking a video helps out a youtuber
plain and simple
the more likes on a video the more
attention it gets
in this in the recommendation
list so asking for likes would help me
out
but it's kind of a pet peeve of mine to
a degree
i i have been tempted to ask for him i'm
not gonna lie
and who knows maybe one day i will
um in fact when you
become a youtube partner one of the
things that suggests
for success is that you ask people to
like your videos
but the whole concept is kind of stupid
in my opinion because
if everybody asked to like their videos
it would change
nothing every video would get the same
number of likes
extra and it would get no
extra promotion over another video
because they would all get more likes
in a way though i'm i'm helping them
abuse a system by not asking for likes
because
my video doesn't get the extra attention
so it doesn't get
the extra likes and extra focus in the
search engines or the
recommendation list or whatever anyway
it's a pet peeve of mine that's why i
don't do it but who knows maybe one day
i will because it does help
yeah not today all right guys
have a good day take care thanks for
watching
you