man it is pouring rain out there it just
won't let up we've been stuck here
forever now ever gonna get free you know
what don't take this personally but I'm
not really enjoying my time here with
you you know you're just not very much
fun it's the truth
really you don't talk you tell me a joke
or something out you know just forget
just just sit here well we made it back
to HQ finally today we're going to be
we're going to try do a bit of building
get some get some stuff built for a
change and you can see I've done a
little bit of work in the Bandon
mineshaft it looks a lot more open now
doesn't it what I've been doing is I've
been removing the fences and the and the
blocks above spider webs all that stuff
and after you do that it really starts
open the place up there there's usually
only a one or two wide we'll all like
look at look over here this path here
and this one here there's only a to wide
wall so I've been ripping some of those
out and after you do that it really
makes a lot of space so let's turn it
out pretty good last episode we found
this very big square area and I felt I
needed to build something here but I
wasn't really sure what I wanted to do
and in the comments I got two main
suggestions one was to either make it
like an animal farm like a fenced off
area to hold them and the other one was
to make a wheat farm so today we're
going to build both of them here in the
same area I have
a fun idea for an animal farm I want to
try out it's not going to be super
efficient or anything and not quite
automatic but it'll be a good first farm
and it should be fun something I want to
try build and we'll also build a wheat
farm so let's get to work here okay so
the dimensions I'm looking for are 13 by
13 for the farm and this thing right now
is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 by 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 11 12
that's odd it's not a square so 11 by 12
I need to make it 13 by 13 and the other
thing I want to do is do it a little bit
deeper will probably go five or six
blocks down as well so I'm going to work
on that and I will see you when it's
done
Wow look at that doesn't look like much
does it
but that took a while and this is what I
got from it lots of lots and lots of
cobble and some dirt which is good but I
tell you I sure am missing my T and D
used to be so easy clearing out areas
like that I think I got to go down
another block or so and then I'll be
happy with it and then we'll get started
here you'll see what I'm building look
at this guy you stole one of my grass
blocks that little bugger give it back
you mutt felting yeah you're not so
tough come down and fight like a man
oh what a pansy
yeah he's not he's not going to do it so
I think our preparations are about made
here we can get started I want to do
some experiments first so just to try
out a few things that I'm not sure about
I believe it or not I've never made an
automated wheat farm before I've always
just done the standard harvest it
yourself
plant it yourself deal even in the last
world I never made one I never got
around to it so it's kind of new to me
the one we're going to make here is not
going to be overly complex it's just
going to be push a button releases water
to harvest the wheat and delivers it to
us and that's about it we could make
something more complicated if we use a
bud switch to detect the wheat growth
but I should brought more water with me
but we're not going to do anything like
that now what I want to check out first
here is if water will destroy farmland
because I'm going to use it to harvest
the wheat and it'll be a big problem if
I have to refill the soil every time and
this is probably common knowledge but I
just want to see it for my own eyes
I checked the wiki on information on
wheat farming some things I need to keep
in mind we needs to be light level 9 or
higher to grow farmland to be destroyed
in four ways and water was not listed as
one of them so I'm guessing it will not
get destroyed here so I'm going to watch
it for a sec though just to make sure
it's just looking like this and then I
looked up
oh man I was close this guy use a sneaky
one so glad I looked up okay so the
water flowing over the farm line did not
seem to wreck it it's perfect I'll
probably have pistons on the left here
and the right with water flowing out to
a middle lane all the wheat and seeds
will get pushed into the middle with
water flowing to a collection points
over here or something that will deliver
the goods to me now the other thing I
want to try out this is this is the
awesome thing this is one of the reasons
I'm building this weird weird eel here
so you guys suggested I use this area to
either make a wheat farm or passive mob
farm so I I wanted to combine the two
now normally that's not possible because
people actually put up fences to keep
animals out of their farm and I'm going
to put them the two together so people
would normally call me an idiot for that
but I got an awesome tip from a guy
called Astro astronomical the other day
he told me something really cool if you
put fences underneath your farmland like
that then animals or players won't be
able to trample the crops walking on it
normally and that is just that's a great
tip so thank you astronomical I hope I
said your name right shoutouts to you
I'm sure a lot of people are going to
like that one
it might get patched eventually though
we'll see but I will abuse it for now
because I like it and you see if you get
rid of one of these fences
you know it doesn't take long for it to
get destroyed usually there it goes so
it does work he said it does not work
with the nether fences though so keep
that in mind if you do it I'm not really
recommending you do it but I just want
to do it because it's kind of ironic
okay and this farm is going to be mostly
for cows that's the main crop I want to
grow here cows and wheat so we got
everything figured out pretty much we
shall get started the first thing I'm
going to do here is I'm going to use all
the fences I got from the Bandon
mineshaft and I'm going to lay them down
this area on both sides here I'll leave
this middle clear though that's where
our water stream is going to be where
they join together so I'll do this and
I'll see you in a second
good good very good okay some reason I
feels like I'm pouring concrete here or
something and I just set up all my rebar
so it reminds me of okay anyway so we
get the fences down I never really
explained why that trick works basically
fences count as one and a half blocks as
I'm sure you know so if we're on the
stone here you can see our y-coordinate
is thirty point six two or so if we go
up on the fence it raises to thirty one
point one two so that's a block and a
half and I believe I'm not entirely sure
but I believe tilled soil is lower than
one block I think it's like a 7/8 or
fifteen sixteenths of a block or
something so it's lower too and somehow
instead of walking on the block you're
kind of walking on the fence instead of
on the tilled soil so that's why it
doesn't get destroyed is my theory I
don't know if
sure anyway next thing I'm going to do
is place down soil fill it in till it's
I'll have to hide water somewhere to
dehydrate it I could probably do that
underneath the fences or on the sides
I'll probably do the sides yeah and also
if we have water in the middle here
it'll help hydrate the soil as well so
I'll do that and we will be back
actually looking at my y-coordinate here
it seems tilled soil is no different in
height than regular blocks you see it
doesn't change when I walk on this stone
uh-huh okay soils down next thing we got
to do got to get away for the animals to
come down here from the surface so I'm
calling this the front this is left
right and we'll call this the back I'm
going to rig up a thing for the animals
come down from the surface we'll just
have a how should we do it well we could
probably just punch a hole through here
there goes my pick found some iron sweet
and we'll just dig a hole straight up to
the surface we'll put a water break in
here so the animals can fall down safely
and then they'll be in our farm yeah so
I'll work on that just give me a minute
again okay I think I mean a little head
of myself I should probably figure out
the water currents for the wheat farm
first so to hydrate the thing I believe
I can do it with just four water source
blocks so I'm going to stick them down
here underneath the fences out of sight
and that should work on I'm hoping that
works
let's see please get hydrated it's been
a while it's been a long time since I
made a wheat farm the ones hydrated that
might be from here though yeah I messed
up a bit here
I guess the water will hydrate basically
a nine by nine square or four blocks
away from itself so one two three four
and also diagonally one two three four
so up to here for this one block but it
only will hydrates if it's on the same
level like these distilled soils on the
same level as this water block or if the
water block is one higher than it
doesn't seem to work if it's lower or if
it's two blocks high or it doesn't work
either
so that's going to change things a
little bit here it means I'll have to
have water my water stream here going
all the time I wanted to check to shut
that off with pistons but I just I have
to have it going all the time now and it
will go down here oh and we have our
fences there too darn
hmm well that water there will hydrate
your Center no problem and we'll have
water on the outside take care of the
rest like these should be fine I'm just
worried if I have a water stream here
that drops might get lost in the fences
below there that's my only concern right
now ah it's okay we'll make it work that
flows there we throw items in course
that's messing up the stream the plan
will be I'll have to have a separator
between these two so that the cows don't
fall down I'll either use fences glass
panes or the iron bars probably I'm
thinking glass panes will probably look
the best oops so this will allow items
to fall down to the stream below without
the mobs falling through and it seems
like
seems to be fine that should work should
work okay so last pains down the middle
the advantage of using in the pains or
the bars iron bars is you'll be able to
jump over it and so little mobs fences
you can't unless you do a shift jump
well that might not work anymore huh so
you could ship jump maybe I'm doing it
wrong anyway so I'll clean this up a bit
and then that will be back alright let's
decide glass panes or iron bars which
looks better iron and jump over it not
too bad or glass panes I guess they
don't join together hmm
I like them both but I think I'll go
with iron bars unless you guys have a
preference yeah okay I'll do iron bars
for now yeah
okay so drops should be fine like this
collection point will be down there
I'll have lighting in the sides sorry in
the sides I'll try to use lava if I can
for lighting I never figured out the
lighting if I have lava over here let's
say we have lab over here
that's one are now 15 14 13 12 11 10 9 8
dance that's not enough so we'll have to
have see I should have thought this farm
out a little bit better before I started
it is now we're running into all these
problems hmm well I don't know what to
do we'll figure it out
well one thing I could do is use a fence
and then place torches on top of it and
it would light up the center pretty good
but I don't want to use torches really
because one of my goals down here was to
eventually replace all these torches
with lava or some other cool lighting
yeah so I was thinking one thing I could
do is put a fence down the middle here
instead and place torches all along it
and that would take care of the lighting
for the middle but I don't really want
to do that because one of my goals down
in this cave system is eventually to use
only lava for lighting lava maybe
glowstone and the the pumpkins but no
torches is my ultimate goal in the end
so probably won't do that another thing
I could do is like punch a hole down
here place lava then glass above or
something and that would light up an
area of about 5 by 5 that's a
possibility ah I don't know I'll think
about it some more I'm working on the
water flood system right now and as
always if you guys have suggestions let
me know I'm thinking for the water
I'll have Pistons on their side like
this ok and then water all along here
above the arms so that when they're
extended the water will be sitting still
and when they're open like they're right
now it will fall down and flow out
towards the fence and I'll have wire
above the cobble here control that and
we will need to have a barrier along
here I just found out that you can't
make the mossy stone bricks anymore they
took that trick out so there's no way of
producing them only find them
unfortunately because that's what I
wanted to use those the mossy stone
bricks hmm how does I want to see how
sandstone looked with these things we'll
table that for now okay
yes this is very good okay do the other
side
I'll be back uh-huh okay this is what I
did we got lava on the other side of the
Pistons
okay so lay that light through so at the
pistons are 14 then here's 13 12 11 10 9
so that'll light that will allow the
weak to grow up to here and then that
leaves 1 2 3 blocks yet unlit from the
sides we can light up most of it except
for maybe it's either 1 or 3 blocks that
won't be lit unless we put something in
the middle here
so that's pretty good
the other thing I've done underneath the
pistons I got water all along and that
will hydrate these last two blocks that
weren't hydrated before that that this
doesn't take care of so that'll pretty
much take care of although the hydrating
for us and the other thing I need to do
yet is add put this back
and then we'll have water all along here
on the piston arms maybe I'll do it
later though I got creeper just a little
while ago when I blew up like five
Pistons a little upset about that
because I lost five redstone from that
and five iron oh well okay
yes now look at this guy look at this
guy take it head-on like that well I'm
going to end the episode here today I'll
we'll finish this up next time hopefully
because it's getting late here again I'm
going to start doing my episodes earlier
so that I don't have this problem always
otherwise I start rushing it at the end
and then we'll see how this turns out so
okay I'll see you again next time thank
you for watching