hello hello everyone welcome all of you
you happy people you sad people you
funny people you boring people you
awesome people you grammar nazis
actually no grammar nazis get out of
here nobody likes you but yeah welcome
back to another episode what I would
like to do today is work on the mob
system some more it's amazing how many
people thought I had a cat in real life
just because of that guy they're
constantly meowing
it is very realistic that meow I gotta
say I bet you they got it off of a real
cat in fact but yeah so what I would
like to do with this thing
is eventually build like a command
central room where I can control all the
things it does from a single a single
room so like all the different options
so one thing we can do with our mob
system is turn it on and off we have a
lighting system built in so that's one
one feature we want to control we have
this thing here which switches between
Auto killing the mobs and sending them
to this order so that's a second option
and then it's really up to us we're
still in the middle of making this thing
so we have to figure that out what else
do we want to include with our mob
system well let's see I want to do that
bomb factory thing our ultimate goal is
to make an automatic wood harvesting
system also a cobble harvesting system
would be nice so those are two options
to get them into the bomb factory though
we can either send the creepers and
skeletons direct but we might also want
to use the bomb factory as a record
factory because it's basically the same
set up all we have to do instead though
is get the creepers down to one hit
before we send them to it and then
they'll get one shot killed by the
skeleton so we got some figuring out to
do here but basically let's let's start
messing around with stuff here so this
is where the creepers fall down here
zombies their skeletons is there I think
what we should do is try to position
them all like like three tubes that we
can actually interact with down there
somewhere so let's let's go down here
the fall and then we want them to get
moved a little bit which way I guess we
would have to move them maybe the hmm
let's make them go this way
okay so we'll have water here you can
even put that there just so that we
remember water will push creepers over
here and we'll make them go maybe one
block away from that make it bend around
and go here okay
skeletons they fall into this swing and
then we'll have a water stream push them
out that way and zombies they fall in
there let's make them just come out over
this way like so and then I guess we're
getting close to our auto thing
hmm how do we want to do this because
we're gonna need a lot of space to build
other stuff too let's just think this
through oh there we go
everything's gone it's fine it's
happened before I'm sure okay
that's that's one way we could do it
okay
here's the thing I stopped a moment just
to plan this and think it through a
little bit better as many of you pointed
out before there's absolutely no points
no point whatsoever to sorting mobs and
then automatically killing them and
you're much better off automatically
killing mobs and then sorting their loot
using hoppers and that kind of stuff so
our goal with this is not to kill them
at this point what we want to do ideally
is get them down to 1 hit kill right the
reason we would want to do that is to
get XP from them or to get like if
they're wearing it armor of some sort we
can possibly get that off of them also I
would like to set up a thing where
zombies and skeletons automatically get
killed but creepers stay alive in
stockpile somewhere so that we can use a
looting sword on them and get more
gunpowder if if we want this this is
kind of something fancy we could do the
issue I'm running into now is space we
really don't have a lot of space to work
at the moment I thought of making a
water elevator and then dropping them
down just the right height so that they
would be one hit away from death but as
you can see we have a lot of glass and
stuff above here that's not actually
possible
so I just wanted to create it for a
second and I thought of another way we
could do this instead of using fall
damage to get them down to one-hit kill
we could do something like this yeah so
we just stepped into a creative world
for a moment here I just want to show
you how to get them down to a one-hit
kill or how I planted with the system
this actually gets them down to two
punches to kill them not just one but in
the sorting system they take a little
bit of fall damage like half a Hertz so
I think they will be down to a one punch
kill and we want to get them down to
ground level without taking any more
fall damage and we will hook up one of
these lava budget things to each of the
the mob things so one for the zombies
one for the skeletons and one for the
creepers and then I'll just I'll be able
to hit a button you know I'll get them
all down to one hit I hope and we might
just do the record firm down at ground
level too because the way I plan on
doing the tubes skeletons will be like
just right here so if we get just one
skeleton in there now we could set up in
a way where this where this is open and
this is open and we get a skeleton
that's not burning to death get out of
here like so and if we go to game-mode 0
Oh is he dropping they're not dropping
records huh I'll Ariel okay
maybe there but yeah that might be an
easier way of doing the Oh you didn't
die or maybe you did I'm confused I
think this will work okay though
like that's pretty simple and then I
don't really plan on using a record firm
all that often so I don't need anything
super fancy okay so it's gonna be
zombies skeleton creeper all right
they'll fall down here there we go
let's go down the land right there
so we're gonna have we're gonna have a
wall of like tubes for them over here
the way I plan on doing this is we'll
have like this is all getting torn out
this stuff here I don't have to worry
about that but there'll be a wall over
here like that kind of wraps around us I
think would look cool and we'll be able
to see zombies skeletons creepers and
we'll also be able to get around to the
other side and see them falling over
here I think and we should probably set
up where we can kill these guys too
because I think the ones that have armor
on have a chance of surviving but we're
gonna have the dispensers like over here
here and here with lava in and we'll
have a button on the side we can press
and and a piston thing to open up so the
skeletons can see us if we're standing
like right here to get records from them
well that's the general plan for what
happens to some moms after they go
through this order I will add if if it's
not too tough I'm gonna add Auto killers
for each of them individually - like if
we want creepers to stockpile for
example we need to automatically kill
the zombies and the skeletons and then
we'll get like up to 80 creepers into
one - which would be pretty cool so if
that's not tough too tough to do I'll do
that but the other thing we gotta do is
route the mobs to our bomb factory which
I want to build over here because
there's a lot of space by the way the
nice thing about having our sort of our
standing area right there is that's
exactly where I want to be to get the
silverfish firm working like that's
that's where we want to be to activate
the mob spawner for the silverfish
now now to get the mobs to go this way
we have to create junctions we don't
need the zombies for anything so they
they're free to go that way and and
we're done with them but the skeletons
they're gonna have to go this way and
same with the creepers to get the
skeletons out is going to be tough
because they're sandwiched between both
of them I think we'll have to change the
route on the zombies to make it easier
let's maybe go like this and then over
here
and I will try that so lock that back up
come up this way and wrap around like
that all right it's all sealed can I do
this dad that gives us like an extra
block to work with the skeletons if if
we make a piston come up right here then
the water will flow another way or the
mobs will fall another way if like for
example we remove over here just going
to pick this up for a sec they go this
way and we get them out of here yeah I
think we can we just have to route the
creepers a little different too but
that's what we'll do we'll have our
water source here piston right below
this and one right below there and we'll
alternate depending on which way we want
them to go well it doesn't seem like I
can get the skeletons out with the way
it's set up currently so what we're
going to do is move this whole zombie
chain one more block over to the left so
villager and trapdoors and everything
we're gonna move one block to the left
and that will give us enough space to
squeeze the skeletons out of there I
think yeah
in the meantime I have prepared a very
special clip for you guys I went teaming
I never recorded myself caving but I I
wanted to try something a little weird
it turned out pretty cool though and it
was really challenging I think you guys
will enjoy this this is my quest to get
redstone
oh yeah I had a ton of fun doing that
guys that was incredible what I had was
doing is f5 perspective + f8 go caving
like that it is insane like you cannot
turn to react or anything or or see what
you're doing it's it adds a whole new
level of challenge to caving I'll tell
you that I think I'm gonna try it again
in the future because I I think I know
how to record that a bit better so it's
not as jerky as it was but that was cool
so this is pretty close to done now
let's just head on down a little further
takes a lot of space to do this mob
system stuff this will be our first
Junction here for the skeletons and then
the creeper one I think I'll put right
here will make it branch to the right
and to the left I just made this but put
that and that's sticky pistons oh let me
play some it's being stubborn no try
again last last attempt yes and there we
go perfect okay so what we can do I
don't have forehead stone that's what we
got to do I think is just
have a block here redstone torch right
there and we will put I don't know that
won't work can't ever it's don't that's
there mmm anyway I I think we've worked
on this way too long today you guys are
probably getting sick of it so we're
gonna we're gonna put an end to that
actually I think we used up all the time
I have for today so let's go read the
comments and we'll call it an end we got
a lot done though it's good to comments
picked out for today first comment says
etho following the trend of PC gaming in
the comments I was wondering if you have
ever played Starcraft or Starcraft 2
since you have played PC games for so
long
surely you have at least played the
first games I'm not fantastic when it
comes to online multiplayer but this
story is incredible
I have played both of them and I do own
both of them actually I haven't played
them very much though like I enjoyed I
enjoyed playing them but I find they get
repetitive pretty quick doing the
single-player stuff and I've tried
playing multiplayer
I enjoyed that to an extent but I found
it very very stressful like it's not a
casual game at all you can't just sit
back and relax and play it's not that
I'm super into casual games I like games
that have a lot of depth to them as well
but I don't know it's just very
stressful very stressful you gotta move
quick and think quick and the general
feeling I get from people that play it
is they don't play it to have fun they
play it to to win to prove they're
better than each other and that kind of
thing which isn't really my my type of
thing but they're they're good games
second comments ethos start a knotted
survival please no no it's not gonna
happen I'm sorry okay guys that's all
for today thanks for watching bye bye