[Music]
hello hello
as everybody doing today you get your
snacks
go get your snacks okay
so we're gonna do a follow-up on that
timer today got it installed I think it
is working now so I'll give you a quick
run-through of it or I'll try to I've
got two buttons now this one turns it on
this one turns it off nice and simple
after you turn it on it will shut off
automatically on its own after an hour
so if I go afk after an hour the spiders
will stop spawning
so that they don't build up to the point
where they cause extreme lag in my game
or possibly even crash it that was the
whole point of this
so haven't really tested it yet
um spawning so after an hour should shut
off on its own is the idea and you know
the wirings gonna be really good because
I put a lot of thought into this right
no oh it's a disaster back here because
yeah when I built the prototype I should
have built the whole thing the buttons
and everything but I didn't some things
turned out different than I was
expecting and I ended up just doing a
patch job down here so everything's a
mess because you need to add a few
things I didn't realize alright so I'm
gonna try my best to explain the wire
setup here I won't go into super detail
you can check out last episode if you
want more information about this timer
concept and everything but this is the
way I set this up so this wire here is
connected to all the pressure plates and
everything it's always on when the timer
is running
and it's always off when the timer is
not running so if this this wire is on
that means we want the spiders spawning
so it's dark in there that's what we
want so I could have connected that
directly to the lighting system but if I
did that I would have no way of
controlling like being able to turn the
spawning off like if the timer's running
unless I use the lever to override it or
something but then I have to play around
with flipping it and stuff like that and
I wanted to use buttons just because
they're a little bit fancier but the
thing is if I use buttons I need this
combo here I have an RS nor latch over
here and also an and eats and eats
connected to the arsenal' inside of it
and this wire is connected to the other
torch so this basically controls whether
or not we let this current to pass
through so this is the override to
shedding this spawning off if we want it
off okay and a lot of people were
wondering why I don't just took this
last torch hops like this is the first
dispenser here it's activated by this
torch below this is the first one that
goes along ooh that's six of the
dispensers then it wraps around and goes
to this other side and it makes its way
back and that's the full 12 dispensers
for the hour timer
I can't just hook up this torch to the
RS nor latch because if I do that we
have an issue where this no longer
becomes resettable correctly so for
example if 40 minutes were to pass our
spider eyes would make it up to
something like around here right
and say I was a PK for those 40 minutes
I come back I decided I'm gonna kill the
spiders then I hit the on button to
reset the timer for a full hour and then
this dispenser shoots out the item but
what's gonna happen is we would still
have that other spider eye over here and
in 20 minutes they would make it to the
end and the spider thing would get shut
off in 20 minutes instead of the hour
like we want so that's the whole point
behind having to use this mean wire here
and not just connecting the last one
just to get it resettable and yeah I
think that's all I'm gonna say for now
I'll probably be putting on my world up
for download again soon I'm thinking
episode 150 so you can check this out in
more detail if you want at episode 150
people were suggesting I should kill the
dragon at 150 so I think that's what
I'll do and I'll release the world
before I say world before I hope I did I
might have said episode I'll release the
world at 150 before I kill the dragon is
the plan I might also hook up noteblocks
to this timer thing so every five
minutes a no block will get triggered
and play a different tune the different
note blocks from each other so that I
can tell how far along it is in the
timing yeah I had a lot of fun building
this too because so much stuff in the
way this is a panel right here and right
behind that is the spider elevator so
that was in the way I have to build
around it and then over here is the
slime escalator thing so right above
here where it's dripping is where the
slimes go by and also right below like
over here there's also where the slimes
are so I kind of built it in between the
two layers
oops
which was fun and I also wanted to try
keep it away from the slime chambers
here because we're probably going to do
something with them yet so dance is the
timer and I think we're gonna start on
today's project I said I had a even
fancier timer that we're gonna build for
the blaze farm so we'll start that I
think it's actually gonna be smaller and
better than this one this one ended up
being a lot bigger than I expected
I think this other one is gonna be a lot
cooler so we're gonna get ready and we
will start building it oh yeah one more
thing I wanted to mention really quick
about this timer I got it set up for the
full hour right now but if I ever decide
I want to make it shorter it should be
pretty easy to do all I have to do is
remove the items from the last
dispensers and then I think it'll
shorten it five minutes each one I
remove them from and it's also what the
these levers were about by all the
dispensers I don't know if this will
work or not but I think I might be able
to override them just by sending power
to it instead of removing the items but
I haven't tried so I don't know for sure
all right so I think we're ready to
start building our fancy timer here once
again we're gonna build a prototype
first so that we can make sure we get
the wiring all nice and clean when we
build the actual thing at the blaze farm
and if we have to figure things out
which I'm sure we'll need to because
this is uh this is actually a pretty
complicated thing I took a look at it
again and it's gonna be it's gonna be a
challenge if we have to modify it we'll
have space to work outside here instead
of having to dig through netherrack and
stuff to make more space for us to test
things out when we actually build it
okay so let's begin this is the first
thing we're building here is the blocks
whopper so this is the most difficult
part of the build and lucky for us it's
actually been built before I have in my
creative world and I took a look at it
so I have it fresh in mind and we just
basically have to copy it over here and
then once we do that we have to modify
it to modify the blocks whopper into a
timer and that's gonna be the tough part
so this is like the GUI for the timer
the graphical interface got buttons here
pressing this button will subtract the
time by 5 minutes and pressing this one
will increase it by 5 minutes that's the
plan for that below here I took a look
at the redstone on this thing and I
don't even understand it I don't know if
I knew what I was doing when I built it
but I sure don't know how it works now
it's really really weird got an
efficiency for shovel pretty nice okay
so I have a block here yeah so a new
patch is coming out soon looks very cool
lots of changes too they've really been
working hard at that got the AI changes
and I saw there's gonna be lamps and
stuff lamps I really liked how they
implemented them too it's a flight
glowstone but if it's only it's only
light if it's powered which is cool I
liked how there's no particles or
anything not a big fan of light that
emits particles and I am avoiding
torches in the cave yeah yeah we got the
AI we got
new map heights new map format that's
pretty cool I like Choa it's gonna be a
lot more efficient so stuff should load
faster and multiplayer and all that
which is good those kinds of changes are
drastically needed I'm kind of sad
though about one thing and I've been
thinking about this a lot lately mcedit
is no longer supported which is really
sad for me because I've been working on
the map a lot lately the CTM map I've
actually come kind of addicted to
working on it people have been wondering
why I haven't been releasing tutorials
and stuff it's because most of the
creative stuff and new stuff I've been
making is in the CPM map and I don't
want to spoil the things I've made so I
think I counted right here oh we need
regular Pistons dang it hmm yeah so one
two three four five six
I need Pistons there okay I'll be right
back
okay I'm back yeah the CPM map is going
very well but I still have a lot left to
do on it so don't expect it anytime soon
when you see it you'll kind of
understand why it's taking me so long
there's a lot of very complicated things
going into it and each of those takes a
very long time to make even though I'm
pretty quick at making most things still
have to tweak them and make sure they
work for such a small small part of the
map it takes a long time to work out but
I can hardly wait to see how people
react to some of the things I put into
it which is why I've become very
addicted to working on it what are we
missing here
but yeah I'm kind of sad about them see
other thing because now I don't know
what I should do if I should wait on
working on my map or I don't know
because I need it
I really do I
I could probably continue it but then I
just can't take advantage of the the new
height of maps I'll just have to stick
with the 128 block limit or something
okay what are we doing here so let's see
here these are what do you call
monostable circuits these things here
and here this controls this piston which
pushes a block oh into our excuse me out
into our interface here and the only
thing we have to do now is hook up these
to our Pistons and that's gonna be tough
so I will do that off-camera and I'll
see you in a few more minutes that
wasn't too bad I took a screenshot of
the one I had built already and just
copied that went really quick this is
the wiring here just give you an
overview first and then maybe I'll
explain it more later so this is all
just to control the Pistons all this
wire I added it's it's pretty crazy I
don't think I've ever seen it without
the blocks in like what the Pistons do
so the there's supposed to be 12 blocks
at the bottom row here and 12 at the top
row for 24 total if you press the left
button they're supposed to cycle
counterclockwise and if you press the
right button they're supposed to kick
cycle clockwise all right this is what
happens when you press the left one
pistons go crazy on the left side and
also on the right side all so all eight
go at once and same if you do the right
one they all kind of spaz out like that
all due to the fancy redstone that
doesn't make much sense so I'm gonna put
blocks in here and hopefully it works
this like I said this is a very weird
setup I have for it and I'm hoping
there's no like directional issues or
anything like that that's gonna prevent
it from working this blocks whopper I
made originally back when 1.8 was being
developed when I said goodbye to my old
world what I was doing is I was trying
to make something really fancy for my
for a new storage room when I started my
LP up again and the idea was I would
have 12 different blocks to select from
with the blocks whopper and I could
cycle through them with these buttons
and then when I picked one I wanted I
would press a button and then they would
fall from dispensers above that was kind
of the idea I had for the storage room
but it just cycled too slow so let's see
if it works even it's going the wrong
way
not be going right hmm I might have made
a mistake somewhere okay I'll have to
play around with this and hopefully fix
it okay this is frustrating it's it's
built exactly the same as the original
one I had but it's behaving differently
so I think it's a directional thing our
F is one here I'm gonna go to the
creative world where I have the original
just to show you how it's supposed to
work and I want to check what direction
I have it built there the issue is the
fancy redstone thing over here it's
because the input to share the same wire
so I'll have to separate them but that
means I'll probably have to space some
things out to make it work
so anyway let's go to the creative world
okay here we are in the creative world
this is where this is original and I
built a few months ago the one that
actually works and oddly enough it's it
built at the same direction f1 but for
some reason even though it's exactly the
same it behaves properly unlike the
other one so this is what's supposed to
do
you can cycle left or right use your
block and just to prove it to you the
redstone is exactly the same over here
it's at least the inputs still joined
together but yeah oh well I will adjust
the other one and hopefully get it
working well I don't know what to do
here
I think today's episode is gonna be a
bit of a flop because this stupid thing
doesn't want to work just doesn't like
me today for some reason um I'm having
just enough not enough space to work and
if I I make that adjustment here so that
these wires are separate and becomes
very difficult to attach to this torch
here in the middle and if I use
repeaters or any other sort of delay it
just doesn't want to work anymore so
this doesn't work with repeaters and I
had to move these a loop had to move
these over one block each just to make
this work and this doesn't work so I
kind of need the space over here to hook
up to convert this into a memory thing
ah so yeah I'm a little frustrated with
all this and just to show if I get rid
of the effect where it pops out which I
really like it does work but for some
reason it's I came and get out of here
perk or it's not popped out will cycle
it's going the wrong way though for some
reason seems to be jammed now there we
go
this really buggy for some reason I
don't know the original worked fine
I think I'm to get this working I have
to get rid of these vertical Pistons I
have to lay everything out horizontally
because the piston glitches are I'm sure
having an effect on this oh well I think
I've messed around with this enough
today I'll do I'll go over the idea
behind behind this with you though
before we end this that's what this
rainbow wool here is for each of these
was gonna represent visually represent
five minutes so this would be like zero
minutes this would be 5 10 15 20 all the
way up to I think 55 and I could either
add or subtract the minutes using these
buttons this would subtract this would
add and I was gonna have a memory
convert this into a memory system by
making one of the visual entries
glowstone block or glass block so one of
these would have to be glass or
glowstone and then I'd have so even
though this is 24 blocks here I'd only
have 12 different ones so two of them
would be copies
yeah I can't even show it with you with
this but basically if you send power
into a glass block it doesn't look let
power through unlike the other blocks so
that way you could detect what one
you're on which one is number zero or
zero time you would hook that up to the
spawning light system and then you would
also have a timer system as when these
dispensers one dispenser and every every
five minutes it would subtract five
minutes from this so it would be
equivalent to pressing this left button
so it would have allowed me to freely
control the time on the thing because I
could add or subtract the time as the
timer's running and when I would do that
the five minutes would reset on the
dispenser and yeah I had it pretty much
all figured out but I was expecting this
to work and it's just not working today
or for me so I'm going to take a break
from this today I will an episode here
and I might scrap this project and so I
how I feel about it next time I start
recording okay I'll see you guys next
time thanks for watching