[Music]
don't worry everybody everything is good
in life once again the llama Vader 2.0
is now ready for business life will
continue we can all sleep easy oh my
goodness uh-huh it's like a typewriter
uh-huh I had a little surprise here I'm
gonna show you guys that in case you
haven't seen it yet I wanted to test it
out with a couple of there
types of dirt blocks here - so how you
guys doing today hopefully you're having
a wonderful day today last episode in
the let's play series we mostly just
checked out how the 1.13 updates gonna
affect our let's play World rights and
today what I want to do is actually have
some fun with it we're gonna check out
the new features a bit more maybe plan
out some ideas for our a hundred or base
here and just kind of have fun trying
out the new new us not snapshot release
aha so I got a big surprise I grew a
spruce tree here let's try it out maybe
with just a single one first off cuz I
don't know if that that does it no so
it's got to be the double tall's right
double falls all right here we go guys
are you ready for this have you seen
this BAM
so the the double tall or 2x2 spruce
trees change the ground to a puzzle now
it looks like it changed the dirt the
grass but not the farmland not the not
the path box and probably not the
mycelium either all right let's try over
here again yeah not the mycelium either
that's that's pretty interesting that
means puzzle is a renewable resource now
and if you want to make like a mega
taiga biome anywheres it's really easy
because you just got a girl a few trees
here and there right and it'll change
out most of the grounds yeah so it's
grass
dirts and I guess course turd - cuz it
got switched over there uh-huh and it's
only one thick - yes I've been getting a
lot of really cool surprises playing the
update here because usually when a new
update comes out I've played all the
snapshots in the let's play world for
months and I've seen all the change logs
we couldn't really play the snapshots
with this update so I just kind of
skipped it and I skipped I think quite a
few of the change logs because I'm I'm
finding all kinds of surprises here this
is another one apparently there is a new
Block in the game kind of the pumpkins
the pumpkins changed guys so what's
special about them you might ask well
we're gonna find out you can probably
tell already so the old pumpkins always
had the faces but the new ones they
don't have faces on which is kind of
cool alright cuz a lot of people didn't
like that you couldn't choose oh you can
place some in midair
has that always been a thing cuz I know
that was a problem for a long time okay
so I just checked out the wiki page on
it and apparently the placing in midair
just happened in this update because I
know from experience placing these ones
I had to put a block underneath each of
them and then remove it when I made this
tunnel a long time ago I used to use
pumpkins a lot for lighting before like
villagers treated glowstone and stuff ha
so that's pretty cool got a couple
things here we could try out with this
so yeah you can place them in midair the
wiki page said if you want to get the
carve pumpkins apparently you just use
shears on them and it gives you seeds
can you double shear probably not very
that would be crazy
no just one get like two faces on it
nope uh-huh
and I grabbed some snow here see if we
can use these pumpkins nope
so we got to use the carved ones then
alright aha
if we shear this guy you have witch
witch face do you have okay you have the
pumpkin face
we shear him he doesn't drop the pumpkin
I think he's supposed to write but if I
sure you now nothing else happens okay
can I put a pumpkin on you know hey he's
pushing me he's pushing me around get
out of here intricity okay I got some
iron as well for iron golems see if it's
any difference and nope can't use that
as expected so it's got to be these ones
huh yeah oh we got an achievements or
advanced into whatever I'm gonna say
achievements forever I think I'll never
change and I want to try out with
dispensers too because you can equip you
equipped pumpkins on your heads before
with the face ones so you can do it with
the faceless ones so take off the helmet
let's try it with a face one yeah let's
try faceless no okay so they are they're
quite different then aha another pretty
relevant thing here you can make the
jack-o'-lanterns with the carved ones
but obviously not with the regular ones
got another surprise here they are just
everywhere aren't they apparently you
get the snow slabs now if I think you
have a silk touch shovel and I checked
the wiki page on this and it didn't have
anything about it so I think this is a
pretty obscure change all the redstone
guys redstone is super laggy in this
update for some reason you might see
some frame dropping
in this episode I'm not sure um yeah
let's go over here because we tried this
I think last episode was just a regular
shovel and we get the snowballs but silk
touch is the slabs oh and they did a
good job on it too it depends on how
many are in the in the block here so I
think this one's six you break it you
get six back Oh
maybe was five yeah 5 this is 6 11 now
and this one 7 so we should have 18 yeah
alright everybody so I thought next
up here we would check out the water
mechanics in a bit more detail because I
know some of you that watch me don't
play the game anymore right and it would
be good if you guys know how it works so
that when we do stuff it with it in the
future it's not like well why is it
doing that you know also I think there's
a lot of confusion about the way the
water works because of maybe some of the
snapshots that work differently before
like when I was building the ice farm a
lot of you said that the water was gonna
pass through the trap doors which I
don't think is right right we'll find
out here let's let's try some stuff out
so as as we saw before items float in
water now so they don't drag along the
bottom that's kind of key if we place
like a ladder here yeah so you can still
have blocks like this with air spaces
right but if you want to turn them into
water blocks actually ladders might not
be one of them
oh no they are they are you place the
water bucket in it right so that's
that's a really cool way of doing it you
can have it both ways that way this is
good for me too though cuz I I don't
know how the water works either I saw a
lot of like reddit posts about it and I
think some of those some of those things
don't work anymore like that worked in
the snapshots so I guess the way it
works is if you have a water source
block and you place a block that to me
water logged in it's like a trapdoor it
automatically gets water logged same
with the ladder same with stairs same
with slabs so that's good if you're
building underwater like an underwater
base you don't have to place a water
bucket into the block every single time
you do it right also so like flowing
water doesn't go into a water laga Bowl
block like this right but if a situation
rises where a water source would be
created in it like that then it then
they'll spread there which is kind of
interesting so in our case with like the
the ice farm we have a row of trapdoors
kind of like this right and
let's grab some water here I should have
set this up earlier yeah so we have like
water sources all along one side here
right they won't spread to the trapdoors
until we place it here because then a
water source block can be created here
because we got one there and one here
and then one can be made here and it
makes a chain reaction chain reactions
do occur within water long blocks so
that's kind of key as well before in the
snapshots you could you could actually
move water in waterlogged blocks like if
you had water and a slab like this and
he moved it upwards then it would it
would spread out on the ground here
right but I guess they changed it so it
just gets deleted the water same was
over here you can hide water like behind
a wall before and then move it
but now the water just disappears one
thing that's really nice is no matter
how high above the hopper and entity is
it always gets picked up by the hopper
below here which is really cool so you
don't have to worry about items flowing
over hoppers in in water streams and
another thing I noticed here this is
something I would like to change is if
you try to place a water bucket in a
waterlogged block oh it worked
doesn't work with all of them that's
interesting wait a minute what so I
didn't work with trapdoors right no I
can't place this down here my you here
my right mouse button clicking like
crazy there can't place it there can't
place it there do you place it in in
ladders for some reason though huh oh
man I am so crushed right now I thought
I thought for sure this is a feature I
saw on the red that people were placing
rails underwater and like making
underwater minecart systems but I don't
know if it was in the snapshots I saw on
the wiki page just now that's it's a
feature in the bedrock edition of the
game so hopefully it comes out in the
Java version
cuz I think that would be really cool I
wanted to use that at our underwater
base but guess it's not a thing you know
it might be okay actually we're gonna
we're gonna try it out your underwater
but also notice this I guess because my
world was made before 1.13 none of the
water got updated to the new light
levels so anytime I place like a block
underwater it updates and I hate it when
I say things and then they don't come
true maybe I gotta have a block with
light lighting in actually how does that
work
oh that now it did so if there's
lighting nearby and then I place a block
it updates interesting okay so we're
gonna try to get the minecarts working
on the water here still it should be
pretty good
as long as our heads above or in the
water it'll be cool alright so I think
what we got to do is this that like a
row of of trapdoors or something which
by the way we have new trapdoors all six
wood colors I really like that spruce
ones I think are everybody's favorites
very good for building so now that we
did that these are these trapdoors are
waterlogged rights
oh yeah the blocks aren't floating so
where we're standing in air right now
it's good that's what I want and then I
think you just got to put the rails down
here why did that work
shouldn't it be air underneath here
because I place the trapdoors first and
then I mind it out mm-hmm you know I
thought I tried this and it didn't work
so I guess this is another really
important thing if you have a
waterlogged block it will spread the
flowing water out of it
for some reason I thought that wasn't
true here let's so that's what's
happening because it's flowing downwards
pretty sure there's water down here
right yeah so it flows underneath it too
so those items weren't floating because
there was a downward current I think
this is worth worth noting as well so if
we throw an item in the water of course
it floats right if we have a downward
currents it sinks it doesn't try to
float and even if we just like gradually
very slightly toss it in the water like
that it'll go down always right but if
we slide it in like this then it'll
float so just that little that little
oomph of entering the water is enough to
drag it under one source block here aha
anyways I want I want underwater
minecarts guys I don't know if we're
gonna get them I'm trying with ice now
just to see if we can choose the effect
right of course this is really cool too
we can sprint underwater and if we do we
start swimming alright I look pretty
cool zoom oh here's oh you can't catch
me I'm too fast
uh-huh anyways I'm using a shovel
knock-back works underwater too that's
that's cool so we didn't swim into like
one one called spaces here like we do
with the lighter wings right can we do
that without seems like we stay we stay
in the crawling mode let's let's try
without because I actually haven't seen
that so if we oh yeah so we don't need
to light your wings to get into one tall
spaces anymore and then one once we're
in that one tall space we stay in it
uh-huh so what I want to try this block
the Sun is see if we can cheese the
effect make it feel like we're
underwater even though we're not
technically oh I guess that doesn't work
because I'm I got to enter this while
not not swimming
why does ice hurt you now hmm all the
Lightning disappeared
now that's nighttime uh you're not gonna
drown are you you cheated the system oh
he did he did okay it takes him a second
to find me again afterwards and he kept
the armor - that's interesting they do a
thing yeah look at that so they change
from the desert zombies to regular
zombies with a loud noise and then they
change to the drowned zombies after that
it like resets I think their air -
you're coming you're coming under with
me come on Kevin
oh he ejected you checked it off the
chicken when I tried to pull him under
ah okay I guess that doesn't work then
hey he's fine he's perfectly fine but
then if I remove this yeah they do burn
in the they do burn in daylight and they
go right for the water huh so even if
he's in the shade
he'll prioritize going to the water
first even if he burns oh yeah so it's a
little bit strange to get it set up but
I did get it working here so we got
waterlogged trapdoors above us you see
they're dripping down and stuff for the
very first time in survival minecraft we
can have kind of underwater rails where
our heads actually in the water so this
is the view it's a little close to the
ground it would be nice if we were up a
block higher yes yes but this is as good
as we're gonna get it I think
uh-huh it's kind of cool right think I
might I might use it the base still
uh-huh so let's go let's go over here
and try some things out so trapdoors
they have a special ability I believe
where the water will flow down when it's
open and then it stops when it's closed
right I tried some stuff with sponges
too just to see if we could like break
the system or something so if we place a
sponge here it doesn't quite reach all
the way to the top if we place it one
block higher and it absorbs the whole
thing so sponges will pull the water out
of waterlogged blocks too so we get
ourselves a trap door with water in it
right then we put the lily pad on top
and a piece of sand on top of that and
we're gonna absorb the water with a
sponge what's gonna happen to a lily pad
what's gonna happen to the sand you guys
know here we go huh so lily pad pops off
it doesn't disappear and the sand
doesn't float it actually falls where do
you think that slime team from it's just
a little baby slime cube drifting across
the water here okay and a creeper
apparently too I'm at like a chunk
corrupted area here I just started
coming out of the cheese
what a bully man he pushed me into the
water
uh-huh so I think guys for the next
episode the plan is we're gonna go look
for the new ocean biomes and try figure
out where we're gonna set up our base
right and look for the the nice corals
and the nice water right now we're in
the swamp here I'll tell you kind of my
rough idea for the base though like what
I plan on doing so I don't want to just
build a room underwater what I actually
want to do is live under the water right
so and we'll probably have some some
rooms underwater with airs air spaces in
and that kind of stuff too because we
can't grow like wheat under water for
example we'll need to build rooms for
certain things but as much as possible
we're gonna try actually live where
we're drowning right so of course we got
to contend with the the air bubble
situation I'm sure there's lots of ways
around that though I think sugarcane is
not water luggable right now so you can
still do this trick right I think also I
would like to play with the air bubble
stuff a bit too today if we have time
we're running a little bit long time but
I think these refill your air bubbles -
all right yeah they do they do okay so
you could have they're really cool too
by the way I think this is the coolest
thing added in the patch because
obviously you make elevators and all
kinds of cool stuff with them you can
have stations like this where you refill
- all right that works out or we could
just have a downward current probably
right I guess it hurts you know uh-huh
so soul sand makes you go up and the
magma makes you go down this way this
work is so cool
and it shoots see with a lot of force
like you actually hop out of the water
when it when it shoots you out so like
if we're gonna live underwater we're
gonna try to adapt to living underwater
as much as possible right and that
includes things like our animal farms if
we're living underwater the sheep have
to live underwater - all right so I want
to try something here I'm gonna drown
this guy but I want to try to keep him
alive so I think oh there's a dolphin
here I think if we do something like
this hopefully he gets air from the
bubble stream oh maybe not I don't know
well let's attach a fence to this is
that gonna kill the bubble screen but
let's make sure you get some air before
we chill I kind of want to like hold the
guys down maybe like that and try try to
give them air but it's probably
something I'm enough to play around with
let's see how long he'll stay like that
without dying and maybe we have like
like redstone controls for turning the
air on and off every so often so they
don't drown but I'm not sure I think
Leeds might still break off right like
when you leave the chunks he seems okay
though like that this might work I think
you should be dead by now if you didn't
have the bubble streams I don't know
what we're gonna have to play around
with it I think it could be a lot of fun
though yeah he's hanging in there I
think it's good it's a good idea so
that's how you do like underwater animal
farms and just have like two of them
side by side you can breed them and then
the baby one will probably float to the
surface and you can play bits cows you
can send it to
a killing room or something right and
just keep the parents but anyways guys I
think we'll wrap up here actually
we'll put around with this stuff more in
the next episode I am sure I've been
doing a lot of long videos lately like
30 40 minutes I I think it's better I do
like 20 to 30 minute videos though so I
gotta get back into that habit and just
make more of them I think this is a
better way of doing it so here's the
comment of the day it says are you going
to be playing on hermit crafts so hermit
craft season six just started guys I am
a Hermits kind of an inactive one but I
do play with some of the Hermit sinful
crafts here's the thing about this I
thought I'd mention it because a lot of
people are wondering this if it was just
me if it was up to me I probably would
usually my attitude has always been like
if I think I'll have fun doing something
I'll do it do it for as long as I want
as long as long as I'm having fun and
then stop when I when I'm not but I have
noticed a trend in the comments and it's
not just one person it is a few people
which mean there's means there's
probably some truth behind it right a
lot of times when a series ends I don't
actually announce it ends I just stopped
playing cuz you know I don't plan to end
the series it just kind of happens right
and I did that pretty badly with the
hermit craft series like I think I
played three seasons of it and none of
them got beyond 30 episodes and as a
result I've gotten a reputation now
where I end series all the time like
even when I played fool craft when I
stir that up most of the comments were
like well not most but some were like
well I can't wait till this ends on
episode three and it's just it's really
discouraging to see that kind of stuff
right so I'm kind of feeling like maybe
I shouldn't do something if I know and
can't commit to it and hermit crafts one
of those things were I I could have some
fun playing it for a while but I doubt
I'll get beyond episode 50 right
because there's more support for the LP
series year than the hermit craft one
always and I have always had trouble
like playing - vanilla series even like
with mine crack it was it was a struggle
always so I don't know I don't know what
to do guys honestly yeah the thing is
keep this in mind like just about every
series I do doesn't have an official
ending so I do have to end them
eventually right the one time I did
announce that a series was ending was I
think I think with the crack pack and I
got a lot of flack for that episode like
the final episode so it's like it's bad
if I do tell you and it's bad if I don't
tell you so I just don't know what to do
it's it's just dad yeah anyways that's
that's my thoughts on the matter I don't
know if I'm playing or not so yeah there
there we go anyways hopefully you
enjoyed the episode thank you for
watching as always and I'll see you in
the next one take care bye bye
[Music]