well hello everybody this is etho and if
you're wondering what's going on here
in my last legendary episode I mentioned
that I accidentally logged into my LP
world here with version 1.7 point 3 and
yeah so if you ever wondered what
happens when you down raid your world
and enter a world that you've played the
new patches and this is what happens it
it's a lot worse than I was expecting
all the new blocks disappear pretty much
um oops uh yeah so let's let's take a
look around and see all the damage I
kind of thought maybe they would have
built something into the game where it
just replaces where it replaces no thing
any unknown blocks with the stone blocks
or something as a placeholder since it
doesn't know how to deal with them but
nope it just totally gets rid of them or
replaces them with air oh yeah I have no
food either because spider eyes weren't
in vit invented yet
awesome that's fine that's kind of
interesting um what happens if you place
a block next to the side that tilled it
okay um I don't why this is kind of fun
for me you would think I'd be in horror
right now but I'm not potion room like I
said the floor caught on fire before
from this lava here but I have safeties
for that now it's the door
floating signs Wow it's just crazy yeah
that's a potion room should we try out
the door there we go um chess turn black
get careful around here what else could
we check out I guess there's a bunch of
stuff over here for the most part this
looks ok except for all the stone brick
is gone so the redstone wires is
floating here what else what else yeah
all the tests s the tickets are gone of
course that's kind of like all I was
expecting I thought they might disappear
but that was it but yeah just wrecks
everything creeper face is totally gone
there's that chunk err I don't know what
that's about
it's kind of a weird let's see what else
do we have
let's check out the enchanting room at a
chunk here who would have known floor is
gone chanting tables gone all my XP was
gone when I logged in that still works
cuz I built on sandstone alright yeah
anyway uh slime farm
it's working that's good so I would be
pretty upset about this except lucky me
just by coincidence
I made backup last episode in the middle
of the episode even which is just
perfect timing for backup
pretty much usually it takes something
like this to kick me into making backups
more frequently so I got my chicken the
butt here and it didn't really hurt me
too bad so that's awesome
no all the cows died you awesome okay
anyway I'm going to load my backup and
hopefully everything is pretty much ok
I'll have to recover some of the stuff
we've done but should take too long oh
nice move that is good run back ok plus
two like two points for that one two two
like 200 all right there was my IQ
points oh never mind I can't jump into
the lava because of the water glitch so
I tried awesome
backup is loaded okay not bad really I
can live with this just lost the water
streams and the lighting in the ceiling
but I can probably fix that in a second
amazing no time at all the water smells
are back and the lighting is back no
real harm done so that's excellent
of course the lesson to all this is I
need to make backups more often I have
to learn the hard way sometimes I
usually I do it every three episodes or
so I'll make a backup but I should do it
more often especially if I'm switching
my versions I had no idea it would be
that bad and not just me guys you should
make backups too if you don't know how
to do it on Windows you go to your run
command find your minecraft folder you
can get there pressing the Windows key +
R or go under your Start menu the
windows key is usually between ctrl +
alt on your keyboard yeah go to your run
commands and type in M data with the
percent signs in between then look for
the folder minecraft is what it probably
should be with the dot in front it's
probably the top on the list go to saves
and in the saves folder is should be all
your worlds you can copy them or I like
to 7-zip mine so they're all in one file
and one archive copy it to put it
somewhere else on your hard drive or
upload it to the internet somewhere for
you to access if your hard drive crashes
or something like that
make that UPS it's good if you're on a
Mac don't ask me because you'll probably
just get a snide remark like I don't
know there's only so much you can do
with the potato anyway make backups
that's the point today though we are
going to go to the end start getting
ready here and I will see you in a
little bit
oh and also I'll probably hunt some
under eyes for what you McCall it's the
ender pearls to make the ender eyes got
that reversed right on okay we got our
ender pearls we can make in your eyes we
got plenty and like I said yes we're
going to go to the end our mission
though is not to kill the Ender Dragon
like you might expect you will probably
do that sometime soon but not today I
mainly want to go there just to
experience it whoa my camera just
glittered I blip there there what
happened that was weird
um
yeah I just want to experience it
because I haven't been there before not
even in creative mode I've only seen
people when I first came out I saw a lot
of people going there in creative mode
and fighting the dragon and that was it
type thing I want to go there just to
experience it and just to see what is
possible there that's the main goal here
so I'm getting together kind of a care
package of all these different things to
try out we're going to try grow a wheat
for example we're going to try grow
Reed's mushrooms watermelon got bones
are going to need saplings um gut I
brought some grass that I got with silk
touch and some dirt and I have some um
no I don't need cobble no I'm gonna try
place water and lava there oh we got
even more Wow one thing I'm wondering
about in the videos I saw now I don't
know where my blaze powder is in the
videos I saw the ender dragon was
destroying stuff and I know that they
don't destroy obsidian I'm just worried
if I start placing stuff in the end that
it's going to destroyed when they fly
through it so I'm going to try two
things this might not be true of course
I don't know I haven't been there I'm
going to try two things here I'm going
to bring wood four chests to store my
stuff in once I get there and I will
also bring a storage minecart just oops
there we go just entities might behave
differently so if chests get destroyed
there's a chance minecarts with the
chest in will not I don't know not sure
what happens since I'm going there to
die basically I'm gonna get rid of all
my good tools here and just bring an
iron junk I'll get new iron armor
um all so I'll finish getting my care
package together here and then we'll
head out so I'm all ready to start my
adventure here I don't really know how
things are going to turn out this is
what I'm going to try bring with me got
slow sand nether wart seeds Reed's
that rhymes saplings I just don't really
need these whatever two water buckets a
lava bucket mushrooms eggs I'm going to
try hopefully hatch a chicken there I
don't know got saplings again grass
blocks iron well you can see yeah so
I'll probably lose all that stuff too
it's my guess and hopefully I can do
stuff there without the ender dragon
annoying the heck out of me we'll find
out so I do not remember the position of
that stronghold we found so I'll have to
think I'm just going to do it like this
again and follow where it goes we'll
probably end up with a new stronghold
I'm not sure and here we go it's it's
fun time
okay so this is kind of frustrating I
was following those ender eyes and
eventually it got to the point where I
would throw one up it would go sixteen
blocks one way I'd go there throw it
again it'll go 16 blocks back and it
just was it just kept ping-pong in me
back and forth without really
pinpointing a spot I I don't know if
that's a glitch or what but when I dug
down in that area I didn't find anything
so no new stronghold I had to look up
the coordinates of this one again in my
older video found it awesome
I guess we'll just go through this
portal alright um oh boy these guys are
annoying that is the truth
okay let's try put these in without game
push into the lava here so you need one
for each of these it's kind of like a
locking system go all the way around
this is exciting I don't know what to
expect
hopefully that ender dragon will leave
me alone for a bit so I can
do my experiments and stuff and have
have fun before he kills me what I think
I'll hmm get some come get something
yeah oh that was a mistake like that
punch very good reason why I set him on
fire originally okay it stops that I
gotta burn them hey what was I saying
yeah I I think I'm going to get my eggs
ready just in case
it's battle right away I'll just check
them and get blocks ready and I've
created a backup just in case something
glitchy happens here while generating a
new world you never know okay okay
since you're being insistent I'll let
you push me in here we go guys Oh baby
Oh boss fight right away okay doesn't
look like the best place to be can we
mind this stuff yes we can't awesome
I should probably dig my way up here
there's Enderman I don't see this yeah
well let's get up here take a look
around
whoa whoa what happened there
is that that the dragon area we'll take
a look around do you even do any damage
I don't think you did whoa I push me a
little bit there oh you get out of here
oh man he really pushes you to get away
from the edge then that could be that
can be pretty bad
is this world I wonder if it's like
infinite or if it's a set sighs don't do
me like that whoa whoa whoa yeah I gotta
really watch that dragon because he
doesn't really do damage and pushing me
around and thank you
here comes Jim whack oh I'm not really
impressed with his ability to take a hit
there ya go be careful not to look at
these guys I'm gonna throw my chicken
eggs once he passes by here's a fly
straight does he are you why is he mad
at me oh we got a chicken awesome can we
get two oh you know I like the last 30
or 40 eggs I've thrown I didn't get a
chance and then I just threw two two in
a row there that was oh sweet
five five chickens six chickens awesome
okay so we can't have chickens stop
looking at these guys do you like all is
it brought a better summer babies I've
heard if you tower up like three blocks
they can't get but no not really
trying to be cheap here maybe I should
just my sound leave me alone hey what
else is it really annoying can't do
anything today would try to water water
works infinite spring awesome oh you can
destroy it what I'm saying to my
chickens we can destroy the water really
so I guess if I really want to do
anything here I have to look ready first
it seems what are you guys doing hey
that's disappointing
alright guys so I'm just saying you can
just do everything like the normal world
but it just gets destroyed by this jerk
this is what it seems
I will let's see if you'll break this
come on I'm right here the other
question oh yeah that's what else I'm
going to try
if I if I build a obsidian house or
something well I will stop be safe
inside at home okay let's try that out
the house give us a little bit of quiet
so he doesn't hurt you when he touches
you or what
whenever the dragon runs into me doesn't
seem to damage me just pushes me all
right first house in the end right here
super-sized okay what else should we do
here let's get some grass grow on it see
how that goes
we're gonna lose all this stuff anyway
we might as well have fun with it slow
down it's all going to get destroyed I
know it especially not a bad color that
is going to be brown not really that
tough of a guy okay um oh that's what I
want to do I want my oh yeah let's cross
some trees let's do it
light those let's get some light stuff
actually looks a pretty color when you
light it up to you just on a tap did
some bonemeal trees look good and he
hasn't destroyed anything yet
incoming there goes no damage
not much of a fight going on here I want
to get my storage minecart work in here
- you need track how do you make a track
so close yeah so we got a kill that's
all it comes down to maybe we'll explore
here and see if it's an infinite world
or not I don't know got it just need
that to place it and hopefully he can't
destroy it maybe I'll just put the stuff
in it
okay and let's go take a look around
will you destroy that that's the
question where do you go capillaries
come on can you destroy my mind cards
yeah I'm looking forward to seeing what
that AI programmer does with this game
okay you didn't destroy us I'm pretty
sure he he was in range here
yeah the minecart track is actually gone
but all our duties are still here that's
good to know
grass is spreading take a look around
that means our chickens probably won't
die either which is really nice and get
more eggs from them and I well you
should be able to make wheat farms and
stuff once you kill the dragon I like
places like the nether and the end
because they're kind of like a skyblock
survival to me you start with nothing
and then it's up to you to make it
awesome kind of with your limited
resources and so it's almost like you're
the ant in corruption that's how I feel
anyway it's kind of a fun challenge to
make it cool even though there's nothing
really here seems to be just an island
yeah just an island those things are
healing him it doesn't seem to hurt me
for some reason these guys leave me
alone around hard this is pretty
pathetic as far as challenge goes I
think what I'm gonna do when we actually
do fight the dragon I think I'm just
going to try to kill them with TNT I
don't have a lot of arrows saved up so I
think that's what we'll do and probably
won't even try to get rid of those
things
just do one big TNT blast on them
if we can I thought this is a little
exciting dragon won't even throw there
we go
it was weird though because I'm pretty
sure he hit me right when I got there
but after that he was just pushing me
around that was it well anyway that was
our end journey I hope you enjoyed it
even though sorry it is it is what it is
and I could have been a little more
excited too I guess but that was my
reaction to it kind of whatever I'm
sometime will probably kill the dragon
and then establish something there cuz I
don't think he comes back I think once
he kill him that's it he drops egg and
then the egg doesn't do anything you can
go through the portal back to the world
once he kill them and and yeah when you
return I don't there's going to be
another one but I think each stronghold
has one ender dragon from what I've read
so that's the way it works I'm pretty
sure from what I've read and from what
I've experienced here it seems to make
sense because it's not an infinite world
it's just like a big island okay I'm
going to hide here anyway
thanks for watching guys