hey everyone this is Ethel welcome back
it's playtime get your snacks and let's
go here haven't been using the cow farm
much lately because I don't have a
renewable source of wheat I still have
watch let's go check I still have a big
reserve of it but I can't get anymore
once it's out til I make a wheat farm
again yeah I got a pretty good supply
here but I've just been eating spider
eyes because I like them I got to get
rid of them otherwise I'm just gonna
have to toss them or something I don't
know
this cave area is coming together pretty
good I'll probably fix this UFO thing
people say in the new snapshot releases
that I'll be able to get the farm
working again like the wheat farm part
of this I don't know if that's true
though because I think if the cows are
jumping up and down like they do
I think that'll still trample the
farmland even though they can walk on it
safely I think jumping on it will
trample it from what I've heard so
probably still won't work but probably
fix this UFO up and on the walls here
you know how they're all messed up right
now I plan on bringing some pixel art
from Harvest Moon this nest version
probably have a picture of corn and a
tomato when it was planning I'll see how
it looks the cave area is really coming
together now this part of it I will be
moving this thing because it's bugging
me a lot I have to move it one block to
the right and then two blocks this way
to get it where I want it sorry I didn't
gesture there did I two blocks this way
there we go okay I did do some changes
to the potion room I liked it a lot more
now got rid of the lapis before this was
iron and this was the lapis now I have
nether brick and this is iron blocks
looks a whole lot better my opinion but
I'm still going to make some adjustments
in here yet again over here
this was iron before and this was lapis
and now switch the iron with nether
brick and the lapis with iron blocks and
I really liked it this used to be
sandstone now it's nether brick if I do
keep the black wool it matches with the
black wall a lot better but this wood
has to go or I think it should anyway
I'll probably just use stone bricks for
the rest of this it'll kind of match the
rest of my team that way too and I had a
fire here actually that's why this is
like this but it put itself out
thankfully I didn't see it happening I
just walked here one time and it was oh
boy part of it burnt down
I still haven't closed this area off oh
yeah and as was suggested by I think two
people in the comments of last episode I
set up a spike pad than here to align
myself so now I don't have to look at my
feet where I'm standing I can just walk
up or run up and I'll be in position
automatically and I can hit all the
buttons I can get all the potion stands
her brewing stands when I walk away they
go down and it doesn't really wreck the
pixel-art floor like I was afraid of
I still haven't put the wool behind the
chest but I have figured out which
pieces I'm using and that's supposed to
room as of now oh yeah one other thing
come on come on
I used the nether brick stairs for where
these signs are I think it looks better
than just using solid blocks gives it
some depth
but yeah it'll be something above here
and then I'll connect to the top might
try sticks and flowers or something up
above or maybe trees just something
ornamental all right project for today
what are we doing oh actually you know
one more thing I should show you I've
been doing a lot of enchanting lately a
lot of mining and a lot of enchanting I
got so much stuff again hello
redstone supplies backup got lots of
iron a whole lot of shiny rocks the blue
kind um oops yeah so that's pretty good
you've been doing enchanting every time
I enchant a diamond pick I did fortune
three I got four of them now so that's
awesome but I don't think I'm going to
mmm like I don't think I'm going to use
them just for fortune I think I'm just
going to use this one as a mining pick
because I want to efficiency one and I
just can't get it when I do the
enchanting and for the project today
we're going to be doing a slime farm is
what I'd like to do I'm going to set it
up right over here going to be a copy of
this station so we'll have one of these
things right like over here and he'll
it'll match a wall pretty good and
there's a slime chunk just few blocks
further that way the rumor I've heard
I forgot to drink on swiftness potions
running around like an idiot hear the
rumor I heard that slimes will spawn at
level 40 or below from what I can tell
that's true because I've seen slimes
spawn at like level 39 or 40 in my world
and no higher so it's probably true down
here this is where my mind is this is
where I've been getting all the diamonds
and stuff from and I've got it inspired
a little bit by vex and it is 3 by 3
system here just to give the corridors a
nice feel and then I'll do branch
fighting and I'll probably be using
these for rail tracks these 3x3
corridors alright guys I think we're
ready to start building the faceplate
here so let's tear down this wall we're
going to try copy this one exactly or
close to exactly this is going to be a
problem though because I want to put
glowstone here and that will let light
into the cave spider thing so I'll have
to place some blocks here which will
slightly decrease the spawning rates of
the spiders but very minimal effect we
need to do that to block the light and
then going to put another brick in the
back
that so it's very similar to that one um
put our iron bar
I brought a button with me so we'll set
up that piston pusher thing I think it
went back there think so
and then there was redstone above there
oops
get aerial cover that up let's check it
works okay so then we'll have let's see
this leaver turns the spiders on or off
so we'll we'll have one here as well
turn slimes on or off the slime fern on
or off we'll probably have to flood the
pads to do that hopefully we can figure
something out
we're going to be dropping little slimes
onto the iron bar here we'll probably
have another lever to control whether we
kill them with the drop or if they just
collect here so that we can kill them
ourselves for a little bit of XP the
mini slimes they only drop one XP while
regular mobs like the spiders they drop
five so it's not a huge way of getting
XP but there'll be lots of them
I just to do our class thing like we did
there so and we'll just drop them down
here okay so now that we should work on
the spawning pads and then hook it up to
here spawning pads are going to take a
long time be a lot of digging but we'll
see how it goes yes I use this slime
finder app website it's basically a
calculator that that runs an algorithm
to find all the possible slime chunks in
your map and this is one of the slime
chunks here which I have just finished
hollowing out it started at negative 3 o
4 for X and 192 for Z and then it gets
greater so goes 16 blocks Gaiden that's
how I hold it out the space and I'm just
waiting to see if slimes actually do so
in here so give me a minute and we will
figure that out well so much for a few
minutes that was a few hours and we only
got one slime in that time good news I
was able to get a new pic efficiency for
I'm breaking three that's what I want
wanted a good pic that will last a long
time efficiency five would have been
perfect but not greedy I'll probably
actually have to hold off building this
slime from today because there's just
not enough I know about these guys I
have to figure some things out like this
guy is trying to get to that corner for
some reason I've been watching them for
a few minutes here and he's constantly
trying to hop to that corner I'm over 16
blocks away from him now so he doesn't
see me I'm curious I let him track me
and then get 16 blocks away if he's
going to return to that same corner and
why is he going to that corner no he's
still tracking me darn
the other thing originally I was
thinking I would just have small slimes
here split them down at the spawning
area and then have them come up a ladder
or something and drop them down here
it's thinking of having multiple levels
of the slime farm now I'm kind of
thinking I'll try to get the big slimes
here too and just have one level
possibly like I said I have to figure
out what I'm doing here so is he
tracking me or what's he doing I should
dig through let's see let's count the
blocks 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 16
should be out of range what's he gonna
do so now he's favoring that corner so I
don't know why they do that
tinnie attack me in here I don't think
you can it's only if they can get up to
your head
another theory people have is that maybe
like these guys can spawn anywhere from
level 14 below but maybe at the higher
levels their spawning rate is decreased
like this ground could actually probably
go up to more blocks so my head's at
forty point six instead but maybe it
forty point six the spawning rates a lot
lower than if you're at like level ten
or something I did catch this guy - I
don't know where he came from so I don't
know I'll figure something is out had an
idea for like a rough comparison we
could make for the spawning rates of the
different levels for slime farms so
before I was waiting for slimes to spawn
in that other farm I made sure this one
is clear - so there was no slimes in
here we got one or two up at that other
one there they're both about the same
size at this one is two levels and
there's three there are three slimes
here so I don't really see any
difference in this bonding rates for the
different levels so I think it's about
equal no matter what the level is just
from this rough comparison this isn't a
very scientific way of figuring it out
but
it's good enough for me because this is
two levels there were three sign here
the other on the head was one level with
one slime
so yeah it's about the same that of
course there's going to be small
differences but if there was like 20
slides in here obviously the height
level would matter and this is a why 13
and this is why 9 okay so I think I
figure out what I want to do here I'm
going to remove three blocks up in this
square I have then I'll probably fill in
two blocks so this area everything you
see here I'll probably have to fill in
again which sucks but that's probably
the best thing to do and then I'm going
to put three wide water canals all the
way around the 16 by 16 chunk they will
funnel the slimes to this corner here
and then I'll have a staircase water
system to bring the slimes up to this
area here something that will carry the
the big slimes and medium slimes and the
little slimes up to this point here
and I'll probably modify this faceplate
somehow quite a bit I don't know exactly
what I'm doing and then we will take it
from there and see how it works that the
thing is there's this annoying thing
about mob systems now if the mobs
passive mobs and hostile mobs will only
move around if you're within 40 blocks
of them so if I dig a slime farm near
bedrock it's not going to work it's not
they're not going to be able to get
transported up to here because it'll
probably be too far away
because if we go 40 blocks down then
they're out of range they won't move and
there's no way they'll find their way up
here the other thing is sorry I keep
wandering around here other thing is if
we're standing here oops this is going
to be a problem
the mobs the slimes will have to be 24
blocks away from us to spawn and our Y
our Z coordinate is about let's say 170
it's 170 and our slime chunk is just
over here what do we at 192 Ella that'll
actually work that's about 22 blocks we
need them to be 24 blocks or further to
spawn so that will actually work no no
problem there might be a little bit of
area where they won't spawn because of
that but that's only if we're right up
front there for like a tower potion room
or something it's not a problem okay
so I'll play around with it some more
and I'll see you shortly
I got it done went really quick this
pick is great made the job go really
fast and it's got a lot of life left to
it so really happy about that
this spawning pad for the slimes is
sixteen by sixteen in size we've got a
three high clearance here our
y-coordinate is at forty point six so
before I advance this project any
further I just want to make sure they
can spawn at that height level so before
I do the water canals I want to make
sure that we'll probably end this
project here for today just so I can
monitor it then we will have the three
wide canals here they'll be able to move
the big slimes around
there's a two-block drop right now and
they'll bring the slimes to this corner
here when it's all done I am going to
block this area off so if any slime
spawn in here they'll stay in here I'll
be able to check they won't be able to
wander away or anything and when I said
40 blocks but before that number I guess
that's not really the actual number it's
just approximate so don't take that as
the actual number for how far mobs can
be before they stop moving I don't know
what the actual number is um what else
what else I hope I aligned this properly
this is really hard to explain it's
confusing but so our X is at 288 and
ours that is it 192 both those numbers
you can divide by 16 that's how big a
chunk is 16 by 16 and you'll get a whole
number now the other thing is if you go
to this corner like down here 304 and
208 you can also divide those by 16 and
you'll get a whole number so how do you
know where it should be one block
shorter I think the way you're supposed
to do it is the way I have it here where
the lower number is where you start so
192 gets bigger as you go that way and
288 the absolute number gets bigger as
you go this way so I think that's how
you do it and so it ends at an odd
number 303 and then over here I believe
is the next chunk I think that's how it
works I could be wrong I hope I'm not
yeah that's this for today
I'll check the time and if we have some
time left we'll do something else the
episodes being a little bit long but
we're gonna we're going to go exploring
for
maybe five minutes or so see what how
far we can get in five minutes
I actually don't do a whole lot of
exploring off-camera I've kind of been
saving it for for the show because I
want you guys to see the world too so
that you can get an idea of the bearings
and all that but what I'm really looking
for is a snow biome I also want to check
out the mountains around here because
they're pretty amazing it would be
really nice to find a village just for
kicks
what else did I want to find stronghold
to put to knee tenderize for that which
I probably could get enough of now but
yes snow biome is the big thing that a
giant floating island I think it is yeah
it is whole Wow
yeah that's huge Wow
Fox stupid chicken okay that's pretty
awesome we're not really looking we're
not going to let you the mountains today
too much just want to focus on finding a
snow biome because then we'll get snow
blocks we'll get this ocean pine trees
get snow blocks we'll get we'll be able
to make snow golems I'll get these fancy
trees with dark wood and all that which
is important although I guess you don't
need a snow biome for that this is where
I can get them - what else did I want oh
yeah another big reason I want to find a
snow biome is some people are saying
silk touch does work on Ice in 1.0 so a
lot of people are saying it doesn't a
lot of people are saying it does I have
to see it with my own eyes because I
can't trust anybody when so many people
are saying different things because what
it could be is that you can't place ice
blocks in the nether I think that was
removed but it's possible some people
are confused that maybe maybe you still
can get ice blocks just mere zit grass
really green here
oh hello nice for me I'm really afraid
it's just going to hit the ocean time
for spider eye snack another thing I
want to talk about not going to be
double O the other day and as many of
you know I have a lot of trouble getting
my videos approved for ads on YouTube
and b-double had a really interesting
thing to say that may be reason I'm
having trouble is because there's a show
on YouTube called let's play minecraft
like an actual show and he said that
maybe when I upload my let's play videos
that YouTube automatic filtering or
whatever detects that maybe I'm
uploading or reposting whoever's show
that is that I'm reposting their videos
and it gets flagged and has to go
through a longer approval process maybe
this is a huge desert really flat
yeah so this is my plan I'm going to try
upload my let's play videos under a
different name and see if that has an
effect on the approval time because I
notice when I post legendary episodes
that yet approved a lot faster this is
very strange so I think I'm going to
title it Etha plays minecraft as my
let's play instead of let's play
minecraft and see if that works better
if you guys have a better idea for a
name let me know otherwise it's going to
be ether plays minecraft from now on for
my let's play alright so well ocean I
should probably head back because it's
half day and that was probably three to
five minutes what is that is that stone
yeah yeah I'm going to head back there's
one last really important thing we need
to do before we end this episode we get
all these wonderful baby trees tons of
new donors again guys so let's go
through the names starting with this one
on the way back from exploring there is
like nothing but desert so if we go
exploring again we should go a different
direction we would like to find a snow
biome or something but wasn't too lucky
there
those mountains were cool though another
thing I'm going to be putting my world
up for download again so check the video
description hopefully I remember I'm
uploading it right now actually but
sometimes I forget to put in the link
and that will be that
so many people so many donations so many
kind people um what else what else I
think I'm out of things to say those
five minutes of watching took it out of
me but if I stall just a little bit
longer we'll be done all right there we
go that's everybody thanks guys the tree
farm is full so I don't know I guess I
have to extend it again oh this is
pretty
a lot of hall space here so it won't be
too bad or I might just start a new tree
farm somewhere else I don't know what to
do this one's getting huge huge huge
huge amazing okay guys thank you for
watching see you next time