[Music]
haha hello everybody this is etho
welcome back guys we are we are in the
village of love oh but this is so sad
that one loves that one but they the
world is keeping them apart they can
never be together
what is this you go inside or go outside
don't you can't do both
it just looks wrong you can do both
apparently but you shouldn't so yeah we
are at the village here I was gonna grab
some villagers for the puppy farm we
built last time but also I want to do a
little experiment here because this is
something I don't actually know the
answer to you cannot name adult
villagers in single-player you can in
multiplayer if you have someone trade
with them and then you click on them
let's do derpy you can name baby
villagers in a single player I don't
know if they keep the name when they
grow up though so we are going to just
try that out
although oh man all my babies are
escaping wait a second okay you have a
little okay uh-oh we have a leak in the
village how are they getting there
probably wandering off and dying out
here - mmm okay I tell you what I'm
gonna block this off is I don't really
want them running around outside the
village like this is cuz there's zombies
out here - okay this should be fine now
okay so I'm gonna start moving these
guys to the poppy farm I think we need
ten of them and I got the portal set up
you gotta lure them to the portals
though hopefully that works oh now he's
doing it again
now once they start they just they don't
stop oh my goodness that spot free candy
anybody this is maybe not the best place
to do this oh hey you want free candy
yeah over here free candy free candy
get over here terrible spot for this
they all seem to hang around this area
mostly hi there let me let me show you
to my portal here
aha I kind of lost track here but I
think we got close to 10 through so
let's go check it out it should be in
the main nether hub hey guys one two
three four five six seven eight nine ten
wow I got it right Wow okay I was not
expecting that
because I I think I only count seven or
eight a couple must have ran in on their
own I gotta wait for you guys to go
through all right derpy I got a bad
feeling about this
get out of there guys if you grow up you
are going to die they love these little
tiny oh good they can't get up that one
okay go through the portal
Oh derpy grew up yes and he kept the
name tag cool so now we know you can
name them in single-player if you name
them when they're babies all right here
we go last one now they're gonna be
running around the snowflake hopefully
they don't knock each other off oh no
are they breeding I saw hearts guys
please don't do that here yeah they are
trying to darn it how do I get them up
there see the lazy way is to use ladders
which I like I like the lazy way I think
they made a baby unreal
they're going crazy with all these doors
around hopefully that doesn't keep
happening hey little guy you are brand
new to this world and you're gonna be
trapped forever and it's gonna be
wonderful
alright come on if I guide them up the
ladder hopefully he will step on block
there now he should path find his way
into the trap and to here I think oh my
goodness what a troll he went through
the door okay I you got me I didn't
think of that one ah oh man it was a
nightmare trying to get them in those
cages not not that it was tough to get
them in those if the problem was a few
of them ran off the snowflake and I kept
like giving more villagers here and they
kept running off the snowflake and dying
and just it took forever but we got
enough now I might get rid of a few of
these doors we don't need this many
doors apparently cuz some of these they
kept breeding and now we have like five
in them we only need like ten up your
total so it seems to be working though I
went
speed mining I went speed mining for a
little bit I'm trying to get redstone
for the Nexus project and when I came
back you see it down there oh man yeah
it seems to work okay so there was two
or three here when I left and then when
I came back I was like whoa there was
tons because ooh this is in my spawn
chunks and I sort of built it here on
purpose because of that so these guys
keep being made even when I'm off doing
other things in my world here which is
cool I kind of wanted to set this up in
such a way that I could fight them every
so often cuz I never really fight iron
golems I thought it might be fun if we
set up something with that yeah I think
he's mad at me they pack a punch till
these guys are you mad oh you're not mad
why aren't you mad at me
ah I kind of stinks I just because maybe
they're not at the village they don't
care anymore that's too bad
oh man he's got a lot of health okay so
I think I know what's going on here I
actually have very little experience
with iron golems I thought they would
stick to the middle here maybe not now
they're trying to like wander everywhere
but not really they are I think they're
patrolling right now yeah it looks like
they're patrolling so they're still
staying by this water stream that's the
center of the village there I don't
really need to hold them
I think they'll stay at this area on
their own and if I get them far enough
away from the village I think they will
fight me it might might yes I guess
we'll find out here so I'm gonna
I'm gonna try get one away from from
there and then I'm gonna punch it and
we'll see if he tries to beat me up
gotta get at least 30 or I think maybe
sixty four blocks away from the village
maybe further all right if I unli you do
you try to run back no he seems good
yeah yeah there we go yeah so if he's if
he's away from the village he will beat
me up for sure okay okay all right why I
want to fight him I don't know this is a
dumb idea I can't I don't think I didn't
hit him without him hitting me actually
only I can okay Oh
now if we get a bunch of them we can
have some real fun okay creepers are
still blowing these guys up right by my
chest oh man we can't have them
free-roaming it's not gonna work
they are dead lately this is pathetic
they don't even know how to fight these
guys
zombie we'll hit them ten times before
they fight back one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten
oh come on fight back there we go bunch
of pushovers
oh no no no ah you didn't just do it
they got me so this is how they sort of
arrived from the farm they just slowly
Coast down the water and I dug the hole
little deeper now so they should pile up
all in this one spot we need a better
killing chamber though for sure for sure
because tnt and manually killing them is
not the way to go and the wiki says
looting doesn't work on on these guys
like you don't get extra puppies or iron
from them this is what we got from all
those which isn't as much as I hoped
it's not really all that much but if it
runs all the time and it's automatic
it'll add up for sure what do we have
another one coming down oh yeah look at
that that was pretty quick
very cool let's make sure he stacks with
the other one they seem to come down
center of the streams I got of the four
blocks so they should stack pretty good
yeah that's good
kyoool the ice cube is done again
finished freezing let's go harvest that
I because I've been this area for why I
can see it's it's all done up there ah
yeah here we go
love that sounds so much I'm gonna go
from the top down this time
because it didn't work out so good last
time when I just cut into the middle
alright everybody so I'm gonna give you
guys a Nexus updates where we're at with
the project so if you don't know what
the Nexus is it's a giant storage room
that we're gonna be building in the near
future last episode we kind of put
together the shopping list and now I
have like an actual nexus fund over here
that we're gonna start building up of
all these items most things are gonna be
pretty easy
yet the one that's gonna be tough is
redstone the chest of chests and ice
glass and the iron really and I'm sure
we're gonna need lots of other stuff
besides this but just a rough estimate
of some basic stuff so that's the chest
of chest it's kind of a third floor now
that's ice one now that's old awful did
some speed mining today Furley an hour I
think I only got six stacks I was hoping
for more so that one might actually take
a while to finish and then this is our
rusty iron supply that's like the dirty
iron we're getting from the iron
I mean puppy farm over here and that's
not all oh yeah one thing I want you
guys to kind of help me plan this a
little bit should I build the storage
room like as a above-ground building or
should I dig a hole and build it
underground let me know what you would
prefer and then I'll take that into mind
when I'm designing it so today I also
put together this second book here which
we'll take a quick look at this is to
help me plan out the Nexus and like what
I want to store there and try organize
stuff into categories so I got like the
category names at the top here and then
maybe the list of items that we would
put in there and at the bottom here is
the total count for all the items in
that list so there's there's lots of the
spelling mistakes here and and other
mistakes so deep that in mind got dirt
wood I don't plan on storing every
single item in the game like I don't
want to store fence gates for example
because I don't really use those too
often
so I don't have them in the would list
here or like doors I pretty much make
that stuff on the spot when I need it
and then I don't store it you got sand
glass wool lots of odd blocks here some
of these are not where they should be
like I think courts should be moved to
where is it the ores category maybe it's
kind of hard to categorize everything in
a good way here like for example
redstone there's redstone ore and
redstone dust and that I also think that
should go under the ores but then I have
this redstone category and I would like
it under there too so when I build the
storage room I think the way to do it is
to have the Redstone group and the ores
group next to each other and then put
redstone in the middle between the two
that way it kind of falls under both and
yeah anyway so I added up all these
numbers of the things I think I'll store
I'm probably missing a few things from
this list though but it adds up to three
hundred and thirty items and with the
storage room I'm trying to keep it at
256 items maximum that is for technical
reasons
that's for material collection reasons
and also like lag reasons because if you
get too many hoppers going in the game
I'm gonna have like an auto sorting
system for example and with the design
I'm planning it's gonna be at least
three hoppers per item so that's gonna
be 750 some hoppers if you're not
careful you can get a lot of leg and I
have to really plan this out I'm not
gonna be building it by the man cave
because then this area would become
unplayable probably I have to pick
somewhere far away where it's well not
far away but it has to be unloaded these
two areas yeah so just some stuff in
mind also with the system I'm making
there's there's a gonna be some binary
stuff with it so I want it at 256 or
less so that I don't need an extra bit
which will make more sense later so I
think what we'll do
glass wool clay and dyes these are like
the rainbow items these add a lot to the
account I think we should have a special
area separate for those if we add up the
numbers from all these it's like 99 or
something so if we had a special spot
for them we would get our countdown to
231 which should work out okay cuz
that's under 256 okay guys so we are
going to move on to something else here
let me tell you my plan for a while now
I wanted to do some major above ground
changes like nuts like look at this if
we look around we got the planes biome
here there's nothing special about this
area it's just you can start any world
and you'll see the same thing just empty
planes over there we got empty deserts
nothing special and that's pretty much
what a lot of the of my world is on the
surface it's not special and I want it
to be special like I've done things I've
done the river there that's all man-made
I tried converting a desert into some
weird jungle thing a long time ago might
want to tear that down eventually I
don't know but I thought it would be
cool if we started doing like biome
enhancement around the place like for
example we got these planes let's plant
some wheat fields maybe we will put some
random custom trees every so often maybe
some boulders on the ground maybe we
could add some like buildings like
windmills and stuff maybe little houses
like as we work on an area for a while
maybe we can start adding more and more
to it and like start adding buildings
just for the looks of it I don't know I
think that would be kind of cool though
then like for swamp biome so you could
build some dead tree look
stuff mountains we could have like
glaciers and snow overhangs and I don't
know [ __ ] I just want to do some some
cool stuff like that though just so our
world is a little nicer because we spend
a lot of time in the man cave and that
looks pretty cool I'm happy with that
but I also spend a lot of time
above-ground and there's nothing I
really like about the above-ground - too
much except for that the you've been a
filled thing we've done a few things but
not as much as I would like so anyway
I'm gonna plant some wheat fields here
as the first step and then I'll be back
in a sec all right so we got a little
bit done here it's coming along it's
actually a lot it just doesn't look like
much it takes a long time oh man oh man
but I think we should keep doing it I
I'm excited about this so it's a lot of
wheat it's a crazy amount of wheat
honestly I'm not gonna do the whole
Plains biome like a wheat field but just
just a little bit of it I think and then
the idea is we're gonna add more and
more detail as we continue on here so we
we have the wheats right then we'll add
like paths through it we'll add maybe
boulders I want it to try maybe having
some piles of hay every so often let's
see what that looks like
let's see where should we put one I'm
wondering though I like it mobs fall
down are they gonna trample this one of
my concerns maybe not okay maybe we will
put there's like gaps in this - I'm not
sure pressure make it solid wheats or if
it looks better with little patches
missing I'm not sure I don't know where
to put it
I don't know where to put this let's try
make a little pile any add like
scarecrows or who knows what there's
there's lots of little details we can
add to this all right do that okay be a
pretty big pile okay
let's just see what one would look like
and then I think I'm gonna try make some
custom trees here oh yeah that's cool
it's not much but if you had like lots
of little piles every to hear it every
here and there oh man it's happening
guys right here right now
look at this Oh can't stop it I'm doing
it I'm making a tractor I looked up some
tractor designs and I kind of mixed a
few of them together and came up with my
own here it's nothing fancy it's not
that great it's kind of simplistic but I
think it'll work
so you do that then great glass for the
cabin cabins probably a little too big
but it doesn't matter too much anyway
so do that and then what did i do i
think i had cobble here for the exhaust
brought some cobwebs i got from the mine
shafts you can get cobwebs in survival
if you have silk touch on your shears I
always have people tell me I cheat when
I do this it's legit I swear all right
let's do that kind of make it look like
a smoke trail that's going four ways
here
maybe we'll put another one here yeah
little details there's lots of different
things you can do okay what else should
we do with this uh ladders I'm gonna put
some ladders in the front you know I
I had to look this up I've never made an
iron trapdoor before when I went to make
it I was just like whoa oh yeah wait
what do you do do you put the trapdoor
in the middle and then like do this or
something that I just fumbled around for
a bit it's actually chase you don't know
I had no clue how to do it I had to look
it up it's kind of expensive actually
mm-hmm
do a few more I think I need all these I
guess oh and it's night time let's go to
sleep kind of looks like a tractor right
that chapman is huge
oh man but if I make it smaller it's
gonna look dumb too I think you kind of
have to have like two and a half or
something I don't know like this is
three blocks two would be too small I
think that's cute and I'm gonna add a
trailer on the back with some hay in it
all right well I think we had a pretty
good start to our biome enhancement
project here working on the plains it's
fun watching the wheat you can see it
change constantly
if you if you're still so you have some
hay bales I didn't get around to adding
trees or boulders or scarecrows or paths
or anything like that but maybe later as
I feel like working on it of course we
got our tractor added the trailer on the
back with the hay pretty cool pretty
cool it's good to go look from this side
maybe I will try and make the Taman
smaller to does it need to be smaller it
does I don't know if it's gonna look
good though I'll try it no no I like it
more the other way yeah that just looks
really weird
although wait what if we I don't this
makes sense but we just do that no no
not quite right
anyway I learned something new today -
check this out so apparently this course
dirt you make this with dirt and gravel
mix them together if you hold this stuff
it turns to regular dirt and then if you
go it again it turns to cultivated
uh-huh I didn't know that that's pretty
cool yeah so that is actually kind of a
big deal because that means you can
convert to gravel into dirt one to one
now in vanilla minecraft as he may get
for coarse dirts only costs two dirt to
do that you pop those down and now you
have four dirts
ah-ha-ah-ha kind of important if you're
doing like a skyblock survival type of
map where you're limited on resources
I'm sure a lot of maps are gonna take
advantage of that in the future kind of
cool I like it anyway here is the
comment for today
it says etho what is your biggest pet
peeve mine is people chewing with their
mouths open or talking with food in
their mouth it drives me insane that is
just rude terrible bad manners keep up
the good work I'm gonna say bad drivers
bad drivers drive me crazy specifically
drivers that are not paying attention to
what they're doing I can't even tell you
how many times I get stuck behind
somebody in a one lane road in a 60 zone
or something and they're doing 40 and
you just gotta wait and it's so
frustrating because I'm usually late for
things too I'm bad for that and when you
get stuck doing 40 when you should be
doing 60 and then the guy behind you
starts starts tailgating you because
you're going slow oh it's just a perfect
storm oh I don't have road rage I don't
but I do get irritated all right so
that's gonna do it for today's episode
guys I hope you enjoyed it if you have
any feedback or any suggestions like
with the biome enhancement if you have
ideas for little details we can add to
that or if you have something to say
about the Nexus project feel free to
leave a comment I will hopefully see it
because I do read the comments let's go
check out our iron golems - really quick
here oh so many mobs to me it almost
seemed like they stopped spawning I've
been checking it every so often and it
seems to always be the same amount
yeah 33 again I wonder what's up with
that oh no one's coming down right now
okay okay you must be working still hmm
alright so yeah thanks for watching guys
I hope you have a good day and I will
see you again in the next episode
okay
[Music]