[Music]
hello hello everybody this is etho
and welcome back thank you for joining
me again
we're about to try this thing out this
is the gate for the silverfish
to hold them until we're ready for them
to come out of the turtle
uh should do the trick
so that they'll fall into this little
pit thing here
um then like we'll be coming up here
they'll follow us they'll follow us
they'll get to the top there then
they'll fall down
and they'll be stuck until we get to
over here
let them out and then they'll start
following us and we have to take them to
everywhere
to wherever we want them to go and i've
also done a few other improvements i've
made this
three wide now instead of two wide and
i've
installed some ceiling lighting in it
which looks
pretty good originally i was gonna use
the glowing pumpkins but they do not
look good
at all when you have like half of it
showing like that
on one side um
so yeah we're going to try this out i
got some silverfish ready
i'm going to do a few last minute
preparations here as well i want to
make sure we get them there safely this
time so i might
cover in some of this water we got like
a river here
or make a bridge or something because we
they seem to have trouble crossing the
water
and i don't want anything to go wrong
here
um so oh yeah i'll show you one thing
with the slow sand too
um i talked about maybe putting a slow
sand down
like like here for example
um because the water pushed me slightly
faster than the silverfish can walk
so i thought i might be able to do that
but it does not work
it slows me down but the problem is
silver fish is
not slow sand not silver fish
slow sand is slightly lower than a
normal block so you can't go up a half
step
then so sadly that that idea did not
work
yeah so we got them up to the surface
but we lost a lot of them on the way we
only got about 50 here
which is not the greatest rates it's
about 5
8 made it here oh man it's getting dark
okay we gotta move we gotta move
so i might look into making a mob evader
for these guys
uh but we'll try this out see how many
we can actually get there all the way
crossing this river is going to be one
of the toughest parts
of this whole trip
because it's this is bad this river it's
a very sharp cliff
with cactus around so they're just
begging to die here
come on make it up i can't really linger
around
fool
yeah we just lost a ton there down to
just trying to i'm trying to wait around
so that they can find me again
okay on to the destination the nice
thing is they kind of push you the way
you want to go
like i'm not pressing anything they'll
just push me whichever whichever way i
was last walking
usually we've still got about
35 or so oh don't go into the water
and that's where we're going where that
light is right there
i lost another one
we made it guys yay don't die don't die
don't die
what a trip
i mean we get we got roughly 30 so less
than half of what we originally started
with
not the best rates okay
let's watch them do their thing
and this is all just for fun really
so they'll go into the blocks that
renews their health every time they do
that as well um
and if we could get a lot here we could
have a huge mining army
all right and all the other guys that
didn't make it they despawned because we
went too far away from them
there we go
so you hit them causes them to break the
blocks
then you pull her back up
if you can
they do want to kill me yeah they're not
going to let me
there we go and then they'll reenter
blocks
but with such a small number it's not
going to do do much to the landscape but
if you get hundreds
it could potentially be a very amazing
digging tool
oh i'm too close
but anyway it's an idea i'll keep
working at it and uh
we're gonna go do something else now
let's let's see what i want to do
um let's go
we're going to work on the nether hub
idea
so we're going to go to the original
spawn and we're going to build
i want to try to build a garden or
something for the portal something
nice looking around it so we'll go do
that
get started
okay then here we are this is around
spawn
natural spawn in the world i don't know
how this project's going to turn out
i've never done anything like this
before
but i want to have another hub in this
world to get me around quicker
based off of the one we have on the
minecraft server
and the way that works there's a main
a main portal in the nether hub and then
there's also main portal
in the overworld which on the minecraft
server is in
the the first original spawn city
uh in this world i plan on putting it
around here because this is
at natural spawn so that that makes the
most sense to me in case
like if i break my bed and kill myself
i'll end up here
so i want to be near quick travel
if that ever happens um
so i'm going to kill myself just to find
the exact location of natural spawn
i need another chest i already slept in
the bed there
so no long running back and forth like
last time
it doesn't sound like i lit up this
place very well does it
i might not have explored this ravine
okay so try to kill myself
if i can not enough no
i saw a skeleton down here
um water works too
yes i should have i should have brought
some lava with me
hello chicken jumping up and down
oh leave that score the blaze farm guys
oh my goodness that is amazing
oh i'm an idiot i didn't break the wait
why did i bring up i don't need a bed
wow oh there's got to be some lava
it's got to be lava around here
or mobs or something
right okay well i'll kill myself again
i'm gonna
maybe pill her up somewhere so i can do
a far enough jump to kill myself as well
oh he's having a good time okay now
we'll
spawn at natural spawn right
there
okay um
let's go back to our chest we'll grab
some blocks and we'll
mimic having a portal down
and kill ourselves again and see if we
end up
there or if it'll put us somewhere else
okay this is mimicking a quad portal
imagine there's a portal here
here here and here and natural spawn i
think was over here okay
uh we're gonna see if we still spawn
there
now that we have those blocks nearby
oh come on no
oh good it's not retaining at least
yes
nope that did not work okay it moved us
um so we won't be able to put a portal
directly um
in the or we won't have our natural
spawn rate in the middle that it won't
let us
which is okay that's okay because i
don't really want to put the portal
so close to my uh mine shaft here either
for what i haven't for what i have
planned it's going to take up a lot of
space and it will cut into the mountain
if i put it there so maybe we'll just
have the portal around
here so
i don't know i'm a little worried about
wrecking the natural landscape
with this project oh
because uh what i did is i looked for a
complicate
or not complicated but a more complex
shape
to do to use for the floor and have the
portal in the middle
and i did a search for snowflake
patterns
and that came up with a lot of really
cool shapes and i want to put that on
the
ground and make make a garden or
something in that shape
and have the portal in the middle type
thing
and when i resize the image it's about
42 by 42 total
so if the portals here will go 21 blocks
that way that way
that way that way type thing
so this would be a nice central spot but
i
just don't want to wreck every the
natural that you know
kind of curious if i destroy this these
blocks i put down
if i'll i'll spawn there again or if my
spawn
permanently move from doing this
so the ground was up one more two
right here
right there so let's kill herself again
oops sorry tree
i did bring a bed for a reason now i can
skip the knight while i'm working on
this
sometimes it gets in the way
okay will we end up in that square there
or will we be in a new spot
we are in the new spot so maybe you can
actually
move your natural spawn little by little
by obstructing it
interesting
i just had an interesting idea rather
than building my
portal area down here and wrecking all
the trees and the natural look
i'm going to build it up in the sky
possibly
um and then that will give us a nice
overview area
of this cool looking terrain you know
uh and then just have like a boat
elevator to get up or something
that's that seems like a better idea to
me
and it will link up to the nether nicer
as well it'll probably end up in the
ceiling that way
so that's the plan i'm fill her up with
leaves
and make a portal up in the air and just
see what happens
with that idea i don't know
yeah this makes for a great view look at
my world
that's awesome so maybe i'll put it
let's go a little higher maybe the view
gets better
i'm worried about going above the clouds
though that you won't be able to see as
much
yeah i think i'll do it just below the
clouds
pretty cool okay i'll put a portal down
and i'll get back to you
now i believe this portal is going to
take me to my normal
nether portal in order to make it
connect to this one i have to build it
in the nether
but we'll try it out
oh no we're somewhere new
how high up are we why 88 this is a
different spot different portal
it's probably close to the other one
though
yeah there's the there's the tree that i
planted
there's the other portal right there get
lost guest
right there so if we go through this one
or is it going to take us
oh please tell me i'm not lost oh no
there it is this is a good spot for it
to be as well
it's it's sort of enclosed but not
totally
so i'll be able to work here without gas
shooting
awesome
okay this is this is working out great i
don't know how the garden idea is going
to work out now that it's in the air
i'm just going to lay out the shape with
leaves as best as i can
the problem is i am doing this off of a
resized image
that i got off of google images
and the original wasn't exactly square
either so i'm gonna have to sort of make
this up as i go along
actual i think i've heard before that
snowflake
patterns are based on fractals
i'm not sure if that's true but yeah
there's definite
definitely some interesting patterns out
there if you
are looking for cool patterns to put
into minecraft i would recommend
checking out snowflakes
sweet okay
there we go guys that is one quarter of
the snowflake complete
what do you think of it i'm liking the
pattern a lot so far it turned out
better
than i was expecting like converting it
down to minecraft blockiness i think it
looks good
a lot of the finer detail was lost in
this and i am using my judgment a lot
when deciding you know if it's a
if it's a solid pixel or not because
the image i'm looking at has a lot of
alpha transparency to it
and it's also rotated about five degrees
so it's not
at a right angle and there's a lot of
it's not like white and black when i'm
copying it there's a lot of gray to it
and i have to decide if i should make
that gray a
pixel or not and i think it turned out
so
turned out good so far as far as the
leaves go i don't think we're going to
keep
leaves i was originally planning on
doing a garden theme to this with
flowers and leaves and grass and
trees maybe but we're doing this up in
the air now and also
we're in a swamp and all the grass and
that would be dark green which doesn't
uh you know it doesn't say life like a
garden does
type thing so instead i am
planning to do ice since it's a
snowflake we should
we should build it out of ice i think
but we'll have to wait till 1.3 to do
that
and then i'll come back here and put ice
below
all these leaves and get rid of the
leaves
because all we're really doing is
building a platform in the sky
and that would look pretty good but if
you have other ideas like
different blocks or whatever let me know
um
i'm going to get back to work here
and i don't know if i said this already
but instead of copying the image i'm
going from
for the rest of these sections the rest
of the quadrants i'm just going to
take a screenshot of this and then
mirror it to the right
and to and down and then in that
quadrant over there as well
that way it will be perfectly
symmetrical and instead of going by this
image which
is not because it's rotated and
and resized and up to my judgment type
thing
this this is set in stone if i copy it
from this so that's what i'm going to do
yeah that view is incredible isn't it
now that i have a nice overview of the
area it's it's really
pushing me to want to improve the
terrain around here some more
um like with these mountains i want to
plant some more trees like
i think that looks really cool that
jungle tree i planted there
have a few more of those around would
really spice up the mountain
look and also the swamp i got some
glowing trees but we could
definitely use a few more
and deserts uh you can't really do much
with deserts
they just look plain
but i don't know anyway the snowflake is
complete
this is what it looks like from above
today we're just doing the shape we're
not we're not completing it
unfortunately
i would like to but we're going to wait
to 1.3 for the ice i think
it's going to look a lot better than
leaves
and we should maybe put lighting up here
as well if we do ice we'll have to be
careful
with the lighting um
but yeah double check the portal make
sure it still works
and i'll show you from down below from
down below is where it
really looks cool
portal is good very good
and
okay so in the middle of this portal i
put water
it's going to be a way to get up with
boats and also
safe way to get down for right now
anyway
um you ready for it
you can see i've been i've tested it
already i have some boat debris
here is the snowflake all complete
and i'm happy with the way it turned out
very happy i think it looks awesome
there's a few things that are not
quite right about it not that i
think we need to change them and by the
way one of the reasons i picked this
snowflake pattern there were
there were actually many snowflake
patterns i i really liked when i looked
for them
i picked this one in particular because
we have creeper faces in its
sort of eyes and the mouth
six of them or no
one two three yeah six of them uh
but with the way i got the setup i can
tell did not
do it quite perfect like
if you look from from this one here
the eyes are identical
and the mouth is identical if you look
on one of these
diagonal ones not
not right but
i think it looks good could maybe use
one
leaf block there
but overall it's pretty good especially
if he counts
the number of blocks in the eyes like
that one there
is two by fours at eight and then
there's two blocks there that's ten
and then two by two that's 14 blocks of
space
and in this one is three
and then two by three it's 9
11. so 14 and that one 11 in that one so
they're not
identical for sure that's quite a
difference
but i think it looks good
and it'll look a lot better when it's
ice and it the second attempt on this i
might also try to make a
three-dimensional look to it so it
starts
i think it'd look cool if it was sort of
cone shape so at the very edges it would
be one thick and as it
gets towards the middle it gets thicker
and thicker
and then also have ice surrounding this
water so we can have a proper
boat elevator with walls do uh
was it a four by four square tube
of ice all the way up that would be cool
with lighting
placed correctly
uh especially if you go out of ways
it looks pretty crazy i like that a lot
i think it's cool and we got a great
viewing station
up there check out the terrain which is
something i have not had in my world
chicken oh i wonder how long he's been
down there
oh yeah okay
let's go let's go further further away
i think that's cool if you guys have any
ideas on
improvements let me know um
let's see let's go um
just thinking of something i might do
[Music]
just wasting time now either do it or
don't do it
i'll i'll cut the segment here and try
recording another one
and i might toss it or keep it depending
how it turns out
all right so there's something i want to
talk to you guys about topic is
seamless textures this is information
you might already know but it's
something i found
very interesting i learned this trick a
few years ago
when i was trying to make some tiles for
a video game
the problem i was having and i will use
that
is if you try to like say your goal is
to make
an eight by eight square tile or
something
um you can draw your texture on that
it'll look good and everything
but then if you take that eight byte
tile and put it side by side
it's not going to join together very
well you're going to have a line between
the 8x8 tiles but with a seamless
texture
it seems to they they join together very
nicely
and there's a trick to making them
and and the bigger the tile you make the
more noticeable the line is and also
the more difficult it is to create a
pattern that joins together
so the trick you can
we're gonna make an eight by eight
seamless texture here
to do that you do a four by four
quadrants
so we can place blocks however we want
here
and obviously when you actually make the
texture you or the
the tile pattern you want to try make
something that looks good
but we're just randomly putting down
blocks in this case okay so there is our
four by four
now we can make a seamless texture
simply by
mirroring this seamless eight by eight
texture by mirroring this four by four
to the right and to the left so
and this is the same trick i used in
making that
that thing up there
even though i wasn't really going for a
seamless texture because i don't plan on
putting
those side by side and also that's a
circle and this works with
squares and i think rectangles as well
what are we doing here just trying to
copy this
okay
just should start with the planks first
and i'll continue this and we'll see how
it looks
okay guys so this is the seamless
texture we got from that 4x4 pattern
i'm going to take this tile and put
another one right next to it and we'll
see how nicely it joins together with
this one
and there we go so that's a really easy
way of making an interesting floor
pattern or whatever you
you want to do they join together very
nicely that's where the line is right
there
and it works on large scale and with
many different types of blocks so if you
didn't know that trick i hope you
found it interesting at least it's
pretty pretty basic
really um
anyway that's the end of this episode
thanks for watching everybody
and we'll see you again next time