[Music]
hey how's it going everyone
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play series
to begin with today guys we're going to
be doing something weird
something very strange we're going to be
exploiting a bug in the game
this is actually been in the game for
quite a while now
and i've always wanted to do like
something
with it but i'm worried if i do a big
elaborate build
revolving around it it's going to get
patched and then i'm going to have a
broken thing in my world
but also i didn't really understand it
too well today i got a better idea of
how it works
because sometimes it would work for me
and sometimes i it wouldn't and i didn't
understand why
but effectively it allows you to
teleport anywhere in your world
very quickly which is very cool
well not anywhere in your world but if
you set up the portals properly
basically anywhere you want um so it's a
portal glitch
let's let's demonstrate first look at
our coordinates xyz we're at minus 62
and 524 it uh approximately divides by
eights
i'm still not quite sure about that
though but if i throw an ender pearl
through here
we go to minus 29 and 89 so it's not
always dividing by eight
which is a little weird you tell you can
tell i've done this before
got a ladder to escape so what it's
doing
you throw the ender pearl through the
portal and
it it divides the coordinates of the
ender pearl by eight
like it would when it goes to the nether
except it doesn't actually go to the
nether
teleports in the overworld and then if
that chunk is loaded
or if the ender pearl stays loaded long
enough then it will
collide with something and you'll
teleport and the flip side to this guys
if we're in the nether here instead of
dividing by eights
or eight-ish it multiplies by eight-ish
so if we're at 90 minus 90 and minus 374
we should go to roughly eight times that
oh again you got to kind of get the
ender pearl throw just right too though
otherwise you'll hit though oh
oh he went through um
there we go that works
and you can tell i've done that before
too
whoa whoa
nelly i just fell to my death
yeah be careful about digging straight
down after you do that apparently
fortress big fortress
all right guys so we are over at the
amplified base now we're gonna see if we
can use this portal trick
creeper blast to our advantage
uh we're gonna see if we can get a quick
way back home
using it how hard is it to actually link
up the coordinates and stuff that's what
we're trying to figure out so we're
gonna set up a brand new portal here
uh we're gonna throw it into the left
block every time let's plan for that
let's see if we can get it to take us
somewhere yeah we went somewhere
underground that's good kind of
so we're minus nine and
minus six thirty six okay sounds like i
heard a pig
so we're not all the way back home what
we would do now is set up another
portal and that'll take us pretty much
the rest of the way
back to zero zero okay
all right let's see if this is broken
there might be some repercussions to
doing this guys don't do it in your
world
bugs can actually be bad sometimes
yeah that's weird
that is really weird um
i don't think this was here before
i'm just saying some some odd things
have happened
okay that might be why my gold firm had
so much portal trouble too
because i've done this a long time ago
maybe i broke the portals
i don't know and if we
actually i think we gotta fly it don't
we
let's see if we fly this way am i gonna
teleport eventually
is that what that's what happened last
time
let's see if it happens this time
yep oh man that's that's weird
that is some weird stuff happening so i
think some of the ender pearls actually
went through this portal
and then when the chunk loaded again it
teleported me there
and now if we go through again
let's look at our coordinates this time
so we're at minus 45
minus 5085.
there we go i wonder if it duplicates
the ender pearls
kind of wondering if that's what's
happening now
okay do it again
come on
i can't figure out the distance though
there we go perfect okay so that takes
us to here minus 45 and -107
we're pretty much oh i think i can take
off from the water
ah it's too much too much work uh that
takes us pretty much home now
we are right over here
so that's pretty cool
oh yeah i found this guy by the way
remember how we lost the creeper
he somehow made his way over to this
boat
and uh he's fine he's all good let's try
out the portal once more here
and see if it's still glitched out if it
is i'm gonna try reload my game and see
if that fixes it
still glitched out yep still glitched
out
okay so the world has been reloaded the
game has been reloaded
let's see if it's still messed up
i'm really hoping it's not it's not
oh so it was saving it a memory
somewhere
but it didn't actually have a permanent
effect on my world that's good
that is very good but anyways i'm gonna
play around with that a little bit more
probably and hopefully
figure out some of the finer details to
it the thing i learned about it today
though
sometimes when you throw the ender pearl
through the portal
it doesn't actually teleport you and
that happens
i'm pretty sure because when the ender
pro goes through
it loads the chunk but only for a short
amount of time so if it's like in an
open air
area and the ender pearl has to fly
several seconds for that
to hit something it's going to unload
the chunk before that happens
so you need to put the portals in like
an area with a lot of blocks around
i'm guessing is what i understand now
anyways
our goal for today guys we're trying to
build a super smell tree we looked into
this last time
and it's actually a pretty complicated
thing to do here
so if we if we put the items in
the chest the hopper minecart pulls them
out super fast
but then the problem comes up is how do
we distribute
the items from the that hopper mine cart
here
because if we put them into a normal
hopper it's slow
uh if we put like eight hopper minecarts
underneath this chest
how do you separate the hopper minecarts
then cause they're all together you know
and how do you do
how do you separate them quickly you
can't really
the other problem is hopper mine carts
are kind of broken
in my opinion they can't
so here's here's some bad game design or
it's a bug or something
like regular hoppers can pull items out
of a chest and they can
put items into a chest they have a pull
and
push or pull and puts mechanic to them
hopper minecarts can only pull items
they can't put anything
into the chest the only reason why this
hopper
got items is because it pulled it out of
the hopper mine cart
if we didn't have hoppers you could not
unload hopper mine carts
all right guys so let's get started on
our super smelter here i've decided to
put it across from the nexus we're going
to
line it up in the middle here and the
first thing we got to do is dig a hole
let's dig a hole uh most of the smeltery
stuff is going to be underground
i figure we'll need to go down eight
blocks
and oh there's redstone there oh i think
that was from the end reporter
yes yes it was
that's fine yes
how far down are we one two three four
five
six oh we're actually pretty close here
maybe we'll shave off a little bit more
all right it's very good we got
ourselves a hold that here
now i'm going to put down a layer of
wooden planks
i'm trying something different here
usually when i do redstone
i dig out the bare minimum and then keep
expanding as i need more space this way
we're gonna have lots plenty of space
we'll be able to look around and
walk around our redstone build as we
build it
and it'll look nicer more pleasant
because we have a beautiful wood floor
aha i'm learning guys i'm learning how
to play this game
and there we go guys cool so let's see
if we can design this together
i have a rough idea of what i'm doing
but i haven't worked out all the details
to this build yet so that's
that's the fun part but uh basically on
the ground here
i want a rail line to pick up items out
of the furnaces so they'll be
hopper mine carts at this level there'll
be
furnaces at this level and to put the
items into the furnace we'll have a
hopper
here um we got to figure out the heights
to all these things
because this we're building this in
reverse which makes it complicated
and then there'll be another hopper mine
cart running over top of that
all right so then we'll fill it at this
level
yeah okay so i marked out our center
here
and we're going to try to build this
together
in case you guys want to copy it i want
you to see how i do it
if you don't know as a youtuber it's
very difficult to build in minecraft
while talking the only way i can do it
personally
is if i create like a rough outline in
memory
in my memory my brain instead of using
short-term memory
for what i want to say it's a
complicated process guys
so i've i got a rough idea of what i
want to build here and a rough idea of
what i want to say basically
uh so what we're trying to do is build a
super fast furnace array here
and i've decided we're going to split 64
furnaces into eight groups so there's
gonna be eight groups of eight furnaces
each of the groups will have one hopper
mine carts for
delivering the items into the furnace
one hopper minecart for
filling it with fuel and another hopper
minecart for
picking up items so three total
for a grand total of twenty four three
times eight
twenty four it's a lot of hopper mine
carts
i didn't realize realize that until just
now
uh but there'll be a track running up
across here
with one hopper mine carts there'll be
another track
running across here with another one and
the key here to making this super fast
guys is we're going to be using
a splitter in the middle here um this is
a
technical thing i've never built before
but if you need
super fast piping this might be
something you want to use
let's see oh i might have got the
positions wrong here
let's see how would this work we would
want to come out
two blocks on this side probably
it's like we have an odd odd center odd
number center but
it's actually an even build so it's
gonna be a bit confusing
um i think
i think there's gonna be some blocks
down here the track's actually going to
go all the way up to here you need a
block next to the track
so that when it gets powered it'll
actually make the minecart move
all right and the other key to this is
we're going to have a
fern not a furnace a hopper filling the
mine cart
but as we saw hoppers are slow
so we need to make
many hoppers and distribute the load
among
all of them is the plan so what we got
to do is
something like this i think we'll mirror
it on this side as well oops
don't do that and then there's going to
be two
double chests here so i think which way
i think we want them this way
and then trap chest so we can place it
next to that
so the most hop or the
the maximum number of hoppers you can
put under a double chest is
two regular hoppers right so
that allows two items to be pulled out
at a time here instead of just one
so that makes it a little bit faster and
then we do that over here too
um let's see
but now in order to supply two items at
a time we need to connect two hoppers to
this
chest as well so to do that we're gonna
have one hopper here
one hopper there two total goes into two
down here
and we'll do that likewise two to this
one
and we do something like that okay
then we copy that again over here
and now that we've mirrored it this is
what it looks like so the whole point
of all this here pretty much is just to
create some distance
between the hoppers at the top there
like that hopper there
kind of just corresponds to that one
there that one there to that one there
that to that that to that that to that
the reason we want some distance between
these hoppers is so we can control them
hopper mine carts easily down there
uh if the eight harbor minecarts were
underneath these eight hoppers at the
top
how would we ever launch them we need
the blocks next to the hopper minecarts
to launch them right so
just makes it a lot easier to deal with
them and now what we're gonna do we're
gonna hop
on here and put in our splitter
main system thing so hopper mine cart
here we're gonna use two in total
and i believe these are four times
faster at picking up
items than regular hoppers i'm pretty
sure anyways
so this works out beautifully because
each hopper minecarts is going to go
into four regular hoppers
like so and then
what we want to do is put a chest above
these a double chest
to again uh speed it up here
so i think we're going to put it right
here right
got to be careful how i nudge these so
above this one we're gonna have one side
of the chest
and then above this one the other side
of it
all right so the contents of this chest
should get split
using these hopper minecarts into
the eight hoppers we have down there
let's try it out
so if we put in a stack of stone bricks
you see how fast that empties too it's
so cool
so this should get eights no no
no okay these are not positioned
properly
which one's wrong
so that got 16 that got 16 okay so they
all went to this side
let's reposition this so this one for
some reason
must be too far away
or is it because there's a block over
top does that matter
i don't think it does yeah that was
faster right
yeah that was pretty fast so now eight
in each of these
right yep looks good
all right so this will give you a better
idea of what we have to do here so that
that line there is for the fuel that's
for the items items
fuel fuel items items fuel is the way i
got this arranged
um this is where the floor of the
smeltery building is gonna be where we
are here so if we wanna smelt something
all we gotta do is look down
put in the chest and then it'll go into
the furnaces very quickly hopefully
is what we're trying to do let's check
out the speed of this by the way
now as we said before the only way to
unload a hopper minecart is with regular
hoppers right so we're limited by the
hopper speed still
so if we put 64 in here
it still has that slow filling time on
this unfortunately
but we got to wait for it to get eight
items at at the very least i think
then we will send these hopper mine
carts off they'll run down this line
drop off one item to each of the
furnaces
and then bounce back to get pick up some
more items if they have 16 items in
they will drop off one item on the
return trip as well
which is fine as well um
yeah and then hopper mine carts will
drop
off fuel into these and then this one
over here will pick up the items so i
i smelted one thing here yeah you see
it's got some cracks stone in there
so if we send off the mine carts
they were silent that was weird you see
it picked up the
the crack stone put it in here um then
press this one to send them back
oh yeah and another cool thing about
this extra stuff we added here is it
gives us a lot of storage space because
we got four double chests over there
we can't just uh for example hook up a
hopper to this chest here
because then we're limited by the speed
of the hopper right so
they would funnel down way too slow
and you could only actually smelt like
one double chest of things
by doing it this way we
basically have storage for five double
chests plus all the hopper space and
and stuff like that so um the only
limiting factor to it is you got to wait
for the items to get out of this chest
before you can put more
more in but that happens very quickly i
don't think it's going to be a problem
and since we're dropping the items off
here to be smelted we probably want to
pick them up here
after they've been smelted too would be
ideal probably
two or three double chests here maybe
use hoppers then i'm not sure
maybe not maybe not maybe we don't let's
just plan for one double chest and then
we'll try to improve it if we can
so to get the items up here i think
we're going to use dropper elevators
not water streams because they're
they're more reliable
and i think we can make them work faster
too
so from here where the minecart drops
the stuff off that's been smelted
where did that go it's in here
um i clicked on the wrong thing
yeah that'll go into here and then we
want to set up a dropper here i would
say and
here and then start a line of droppers
going down like this
and likewise on the other side they'll
be dropper oh
over here i hope you guys aren't too
bored by this
um we've been doing a lot of building
lately and some people have called me
out on it's like man you never do
technical builds anymore etho
so yeah today's a technical build day
i know it's not everybody's cup of tea
but yeah so this part of the build is a
little bit of a challenge as well
because we're gonna have to deal with a
whole bunch of items all at once so when
these
make their return they're going to start
dropping off eight
blocks that'll go into this dropper at
each of these stations eight of them in
total right
so we gotta send 64 items through the
droppers
very quickly that's why i want to double
up have like two
two chains of them uh i think that'll
help it out for one thing
and we'll all we gotta do i think is run
a redstone line like that across
and also make sure they reach these over
here
so that do something like that gotta
make sure it doesn't connect to the
wires up there so this is gonna get very
cramped in here
there'll be blocks running along there
that should be good
actually i think we may have just
created a bottleneck here i'm not sure
uh let's let's try this out because we
have eight
droppers converging into two that's bad
news
that is bad news that's a traffic jam so
when this would
return the items it'll drop off eight
blocks into each of these droppers
so we're gonna simulate that here we got
eight in each of these and when we flip
this uh comparator clock on
let's see how long it takes to unload
all this
and
stop that's several seconds
several seconds um
maybe we changed some of these
like we could have four item elevators
so eight down to four it's still a
little bit of a bottleneck but it won't
be as bad
change this to go this way
you know on second thought here this
quad elevator might be a little bit
overkill
it'll shave two or three seconds off of
our overall smelting time like if we're
doing one stack of items that would be
nice
but if we're doing a whole bunch of
items like a chest full it's not going
to really affect
the smelting time by very much honestly
um
because it takes items 10 seconds to
smelt in a furnace so as long as we get
the items out of the furnace
up the elevator into the the storage
chest within those 10 seconds
it shouldn't be much of a problem so we
could probably get away with even one
item elevator but i might try to do two
or even four i'm not sure yet here is
the comment for today guys we're gonna
wrap up here it says
how is your headset situation now is it
better
or still a mess it is still a mess guys
it is a disaster i tell ya i've tried
i think five to ten different headsets
now some of them i can't return to the
stores
they've all been terrible absolutely
terrible
uh i even bought one very good
microphone i bought an at2035 that's a
xlr microphone with an audio interface
and i've even downloaded software for it
so i can fine-tune my audio frequencies
in my voice
i want to sound more or less high pitch
and all that kind of stuff
but uh just couldn't get it to sound
very good i think maybe there's a
problem with my
my audio card in my computer here and
hopefully when i get a new computer it's
going to work
but i'm not sure and i don't want to
throw money at the situation
so until then i'm still using my
my two garbage they're not garbage the
microphone is awesome in the gt
330s or gx330s what i don't know what
they're called
um but the frame is broken on them i've
super glued them back together which
worked very good actually
um the padding on the the earphones has
fallen off so i've put kleenex around
them
and it looks very funny but it works
keeps my my ears comfortable and also
sometimes the speakers quit working but
if i adjust the volume on them they work
again
and and also the mute doesn't work and
yeah it's a bad situation but
it's a discontinued headset so i just
can't buy more of them either
which sucks anyways hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode guys we'll try
to continue this another time
it's a bit of a bigger build but thank
you for watching
until next time take care bye-bye