hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series how you doin what is
down this tunnel ok good at that ends I
was hearing all kinds of mob sounds in
here had to light it up it was really
annoying me alright let's get out of
here so I have heard your plea I've
heard your cries I know what you guys
want from me we're gonna do a tear um
checking out the comments on the world
tour episode there was one complaint
something we forgot to do I didn't
forget to do it I just didn't want to do
it because I knew it would take a lot of
time and by the way don't make statues
of yourselves guys honestly if you do it
in real life you got pigeons that come
by and they poop on your shoulders if
you do it in Minecraft Enderman come by
look at this you stole my zipper it's a
piece of my zipper missing there I just
noticed oh man yeah I did
you guys wanted to see what was behind
the diamond door uh we never checked
that out in our world tour it's because
and I tell you what guys it takes so
long to get in here I really didn't want
to do it whoever designed this door is
an idiot I gotta say that does it take
so long every time I want to go through
here you know what we don't have time
for this
no no we're gonna do it we're going to
do it we're going to wait otherwise you
get you're going to be upset come on
oh it jammed so to begin with you're
guys we're going to do a little bit of
adventuring last episode of course we
built this system here for getting water
out of sponges and then filling up water
bottles with the water buckets we get
from the sponges ideas we're trying to
make a
them for brewing potions in the nether I
got that all set up we're gonna check it
out in a second here but first uh we
kind of got to get some more sponges
because I only got like maybe 30 or so
so we're going to go look for a water
temple here and if memory serves me
right I have found two in our world here
one of them was by the mushroom island
and I think another one was over this
way which we got an elder Guardian out
of but I don't think we got the sponges
out of it but I don't quite remember it
was so long ago also I kind of kind of
amusing the bow flying now I still
haven't got mending though so I can't do
it for very long
I need mending on my armor my wings my
bow and until then my stuff's gonna
break pretty quickly if I do this for
too long
all right was it over here this is where
I remember it thought the wings would be
nice for this Oh cuz we can we can see
in the water here pretty easily
I remember being by like a tall mountain
or something oh that's what I was
thinking of this here this is the island
we blew up that one time when I was
trying to move my spine oh and that is
the fortress I think this is the one we
want or a temple guardian temple I
always say fortress all right so we're
going in we are going in and just to
begin with here I am going to do regen
I'm going to do water breathing this
better be the right one I'm gonna be sad
invisibility
oh there's another there's another
temple up there you see that way in the
distance there yeah this is the one okay
this is the one we got the elder
Guardian out of but we did not like get
the sponges or anything and there's
still two our elder Guardians here and I
have found the front entrance finally
all right let's go inside do a little
bit of exploring ouch man we're taking a
beating so we got to kill the elder
Guardian so easy to get lost in these
things looks like we go this way and
then maybe up let's go up here yeah this
is a big room good those look like
blocks I've placed in the past oh here
he is alright I am going to kill these
guys
what elder Guardian is enough trouble
for me that one we got in the windmill
was very tough to get there I don't want
to horse around with more of them
alright that's one down we got to find
one more and we also got to find the
sponge room treasures oh man taking lots
of damage off these guys how's my armor
holding out looks okay ah yes there's a
ways of going up right when you walk in
the temple I always miss those oh and I
got them blocked off apparently that's
the portal we used it to move the elder
Guardian a long long time ago which
worked really well you just build a
portal in here and you can move the
elder Guardians without having to break
blocks or anything
there is Oh oh right I never walked down
here
okay okay let's finish this up and then
we'll go get that other Guardian temple
oh okay no no no no no no keep running
around keep running around you do that
they can't get you oh I almost died
we gotta be we can't just rush this guy
I guess I did not have my regen potions
on my bar here okay let's use one this
guy's pretty tough got him whoo-hoo so
that's all three Guardians down at this
temple but there is no sponge room
there's just this loot box which I
wouldn't mind checking out but before I
raid that since we have two minutes of
mining fatigue I think I'm going to head
over to this other temple nearby
we'll go loot that one go go go go go
all right out there following me so I
don't know I must have missed this
temple
yeah there's Guardians elder Guardians
here oh that's sweet so now I know we're
three three of these are in my world and
very lost here each one of these
generates differently from the the other
one from the other one from others as
far as I know so sometimes I think
there's zero sponge room sometimes
there's one I think sometimes there's
two hoping we get lucky because I think
that last one either I rated it earlier
or it didn't have any sponge rooms or I
didn't find them I'm pretty sure I went
everywhere this one has a lot of dead
ends like go down there and it's just a
dead end all right um keep on moving I
think my potions are about to wear off
again is that where we came up I'm lost
already
oh this is a loot room good oh there's
actually what maybe I have it in here
then oh that's really weird I place
stone and gravel I guess I just don't
remember I don't think I killed anything
in here though okay let's heal up got'em
sleet's another sponge that's three oh
hello hello there
aha this is the top of the temple and
I'm out of night-vision just about out
of all our potions here so should be
dark all right that should be that was
the third one right or was that the
second we killed two killed two more
there must be one more here then all
right
he's down that was last dude we are just
about out of potions hmm yeah I am not
finding any sponge rooms yeah I gotta
say guys too so that's two temples two
temples and no sponge rooms this is not
going well either I cleared them in the
past and I don't remember or they just
didn't generates but I've gone through
both temples pretty thoroughly so I
don't think this is gonna work we might
have to go find another one okay check
this out guys this is pretty cool I was
flying around and I got elder Guardian
right mining fatigue three so I'm
looking around in this water trying to
find the temple I don't see it this is
the border like where the amplified
terrain comes into existence this is the
old stuff here I think the plains here
got a big wall so I'm looking around for
this temple where is this temple where
is this temple I'm hearing the guardians
like their laser beams guess where they
are you go on the river here there's
this crazy slits it to go down and then
the temple hidden below this big
landmass here it's pretty cool oh that
looks like the front entrance there
no let's just look at my coordinates in
case I die so I'll never find the spot
again
I don't know about this so it's gonna be
hard to get in here all out of my
potions now so you're really gonna dodge
these lasers whoa swim through the beams
don't get it don't get to it okay we're
in once you're inside it's pretty safe
but what just getting through that
entrance is the most dangerous part and
we got it back to here so I can get
water or air
all right he almost got me
sponge room yeah
ah yes finally get the gold
whoa we're home yes
all right mission success we got 35 wet
sponges eight dry sponges 16 gold blocks
from that expedition check this out
aha all right very cool so we got some
sponges and now guys I think we're gonna
go check out the nether brewing system
that we got built here we designed most
of it last episode oh you you're gonna
make me hit you aren't you can I get
this without hitting them oh this is
gonna get nasty maybe we leave the
nether now all right we're going up the
tunnel here so maybe it won't be a
problem we'll see it's one more guy well
we got a check we gotta try out the gold
farm today - I updated - 1.94 which is
supposed to fix some of the leg issues
that I was having I think but we will
see yeah let's go down our tunnel here
I'd built the nether brewing system over
at the dual blades farm I thought that
would be a good spot for it because we
got a bit of space to fill here um I've
been working on the tunnel it's still
very unfinished but this is sort of the
design I'm going for I think it looks
pretty decent actually I know not
everybody likes these purpura blocks but
personally I think they're really nice
and I like the mixed with yellow like
sandstone or similar to what we have at
our nether hub that the purple and and
yellow mixture at the nether hub we did
purple wall and sandstone here we have
purple blocks in sandstone but anyways
let's go ahead and try out some of the
stuff we got built here all of this is
untested I like to include you guys for
the very first test usually so you can
watch me fail let's see let's do let's
do 20 20 wet sponges and ideas you drop
Moff here we did all this last episode
so it should be pretty clear put that in
there and it should not work excellent
it's going so smooth
did I forget some redstone or do I have
to activate this once before it will
work maybe got a little access here with
the iron door too which is nice in case
we have problems I think maybe I was
supposed to activate this once before I
do that and then it works every time we
have a button there we go I think we can
put a button on here and that'll trigger
everything I hope I hope I hope yeah
okay so it's got the sticks in there
we got the empty bucket waiting to go in
and now I think it'll go continuously
right ah watch a comparator oh it did
light up it did light up okay so why is
it not working then oh it is now I
didn't change anything well now it works
okay whatever alright so that is part
one of our nether brewing system here we
get the water buckets from the wet
sponges and those end up in here the
reason I built this so high up is
because that way I don't have to do a
item elevator here just it funnels in
perfectly into this dropper this way
I've got the double chests here that's
storing up more water buckets um doesn't
look quite level with our Sun although
unfortunately it's a little higher than
I would like but also I should probably
put an iron trapdoor here or something
because eventually I'm going to want to
take these dry sponges out of here and
we need access to that too so I think
this is actually a good height for it
yeah there we go I think that looks good
now I'm happy with that
so we got a button for the trapdoor over
here it's a little bit off on the side
but it works you can click that in and
look into the hopper here then pull the
sponges out and I figured out why this
and work the first two times the first
time you got to press that button just
to get the sticks and the buckets ready
they're supposed to be waiting in there
for the sponge so then we click this
gets it going it didn't work the second
time because we also need one bucket in
here one water bucket before it will
activate the comparator somebody said I
could probably just lengthen this
repeater so no buckets get stuck here
but I tried doing that and it doesn't
work it throws off the timing on the
whole system and it doesn't do the loop
that after that so I'm going to leave it
like that
and first part of this is done it's it's
pretty simple just drop off the sponges
and press the button I like it doesn't
really take our time
oops we just have to wait for it to do
its thing so this is part two of the
machine now this is the water bottle
filling machine so we take our water
buckets that we get from the wet sponges
stand over here hold right click press
q' q q q all while holding right click
some of you guys like on red in that you
suggested some some pretty good methods
for this as well i decide to go with one
we did last episode just because i was
lazy and I saw those afterwards um but
yeah there's definitely a lot of
different ways you could do this
some of something to keep in mind though
is cauldron mechanics have changed in
1.9 so what might work in 1.8 you might
not necessarily work in 1.9 I'm pretty
happy with this I think this is good
yeah so you would empty out all the
water the water but or the water bottles
they go down oh and by the way I could
have hooked up some item elevators to
take the water the empty buckets out of
here and put them back into our sponge
machine but it just didn't seem worth it
I just put a trapdoor no I'll manually
move them same with these empty bottles
I'll just grab them put them in here
manually ok so part three of the system
is probably the most important part of
the whole thing the actual brewing
system I decided to put down over there
so that I could avoid using item
elevators for the most part with the
system and it might look a little
familiar to you this is actually a
brewing system I designed about a year
ago I have a tutorial for it if you're
interested
umm decide to build a here so we could
try it out in 1.9 make sure it still
works which I believe it does to begin
with this is the confusing part I was
looking at the comments for this system
and like a lot of people were like oh it
doesn't work it doesn't work you wasted
my time uh yeah let's let's just double
check I think the thing you got to do is
when it has awkward potions here the
very first time you use it you also have
another have to have another nether
warts in right before you turn it on so
up is on down is off if we're going to
make instant damage to potions for our
blaze farm that's what we use to kill
them what we got to do is to make them
damage to the two parts you need
glowstone oh that scared me this is
another fortress so we get random blazes
in and wither skeletons every so often
magma cubes kind of annoying all right
so that that does the two part we want
splash potions so we use gunpowder
fermented spider I'd changes it from a
poison potion into a damage post potion
every potion needs nether wart and the
main ingredient goes here so since we're
making instant damage you need spider
eyes if we
make speed potions we put sugar in here
or fire resistance into a magma cream
every potion type has one main
ingredient and that's what the spot here
is for alright and it's easy to change
out so what we do now is just flip the
switch and it should get water bottles
go in then then this turns into awkward
potions and I believe the spider is
supposed to follow next yeah it did
spider I and now it's going to go to
what okay that's a glow stone now so I
think it's going yeah so it's a fully
automatic brewing system and it's super
simple super simple let me just show you
back here one more time again there is a
tutorial for this so if you want the
water bottles go in here and there's
very little redstone it's just a little
couple pieces over here and one main
line over here and that's it this
heavily uses the game mechanics to make
the whole thing run um there's no like
clocks or anything it's it's intelligent
it knows what what it's doing and some
people are saying it even works if their
server legs so that's good to hear
ah so that's our brewing system I think
we're we're good to go now finish it
does take a lot of time though that's
the thing I like about the chaining ones
that we have in the the big brewing room
okay that's switched out good but what
puts water bottles in so this is going
to be nether wart and then does it
switch to spider eyes again it should
right or is it going to give us two
nether warts I might have made a mistake
building this lets the sea please work
please work please work it's good okay
good ah okay so let's move on guys let's
try out the gold farm now I'm very
curious I'm really hoping this works now
if it doesn't I'm probably going to have
to build a new one gold farm number
three light the portals this took a
long time before and it seems to still
take quite a bit of time not as long as
it was before though okay that's good
Hales little a lot faster this time the
problem was once we get near the top of
the nether the game totally would freeze
before like this exactly like this ah
yeah
so I'm right-clicking but I can't go
into that minecart it's not because it's
too far away it's because my game is
totally shut down pretty much can I
bring up my pie chart it doesn't show
like a lot of tick leg though the purple
one there okay I think it is actually
working I think I just can't teleport
until that last minecart for some reason
I'm gonna have to try figure that out
but let that maze I'll be Pigman have
spawned here I was only up there for
like a minute at most um you're supposed
to shut this portal off first before
using the gold farm wrong button I think
yeah so we shut that off we got to get
out of here and enter from the gold farm
this is a very bad idea I gotta get out
of here it worked
whoo I'm still like really practicing my
take off with a bow I think the trick is
if you guys are trying to learn how to
do this too you want to look up slightly
like you don't want your cursor
flatlined like at this level you want it
up like this so if you do hit yourself
with an arrow you really get some
altitude then if you're engaged with
your wings oops
try again oh you got a shoot and then
press spacebar twice my spacebar seems
to be all gone ah my spacebar seems to
be maybe not the best because a lot of
times I press it and it doesn't actually
work I'm finding Oh also I'm not sure if
you can take off from the water I have
haven't practiced that yet oh yeah you
see what you see how that worked there
so as soon as I hit myself with air I
just like shot shot up because I was
lifting looting up slightly so it makes
it really easy to take off if you do it
right I just haven't practiced enough
yet there we go there we go you see how
much altitude I got with just like one
arrow there so you got to look up right
after you shoot yourself pour those
slits okay this has got to be messed up
so you can't enter Pro when you're in a
minecart I think that's what was
confusing me right so if I leave the mic
I've left the minecart right as I threw
that and then I was able to get up here
it doesn't seem like I'm lagging but
let's just double check so when we press
this good items are flowing yeah those
look like they're flowing into a good
speed I've been up here for a little
while I think as soon as that goes to
zero it's going to push me yeah
I'm getting stuck on something here what
is going on last minecart is definitely
messed up though yeah the ladders not
supposed to be on that side I don't
think hmm anyways let's go down and just
double-check the farm is working so what
we've got to do is we go down and then
we go to the portal that's on top of the
nether ceiling sit further down kind of
hard I don't like these minecart
elevators anymore I kind of want to get
rid of this but I'm worried they're
going to fix that piston trick
with the translocation oh yeah so now we
go through here and this should take us
to the top of the gold farm we go down
the elevator and there should be lots
and lots of zombie pigman there's none
here uh-oh entities say three hundred
thirty that seems kind of high I wonder
if they're off somewhere else
mmm-hmm
that is the problem with this gold farm
they can go to any portal pretty much if
I'm not controlling them
what portal would they have gone to I
wonder
most of them I keep off oh there is a
portal here Oh hmm there is a chance
they went through this I'm gonna have to
look more into this later I guess but
the zombie pigmen we're not letting the
game so there's hope for the farm okay
guys so let's get to the comment of the
day for today we're gonna wrap up the
episode it says hey etho what happened
with the ark survival evolved series I
very lights the PvP series and the
normal series and keep doing the great
videos uh yeah so with the are Co not
server we played on there for quite a
while had a lot of fun with it it was a
very good series for sure vegan for my
channel it was one of my favorite games
and it did very well over time though I
was I don't know I kind of got bored a
little bit doing the PvE player versa
environment thing we were like on
episode 40 or 50 we pretty much did
everything in the game and a lot of
other guys kind of slowed down playing
on the server on the are cannot server
so then I decide let's try out the PvP
thing which was a lot of fun it was a
real pain to edit those videos though
like we were playing
six or eight hours and getting one video
out of it
so it wasn't really great turnover but I
was having a lot of fun with it so I I
kept doing it then like after the fourth
episode we had trouble scheduling
because there's four different people
that haven't some of them have jobs and
I'm busy and and they're busy so we
missed like two weeks in a row that we
weren't able to record together and then
this server got a wipe so all the
structures got deleted I believe so I
decided yeah probably best just leave
that series even though I was enjoying
it um it was just taken a lot of time
and really the viewership on it died off
tremendously compared to what it was
once getting so felt like a good time to
end it might in the future get back into
it just because it's a game I really
enjoy but not guaranteed yeah I don't
know anyways hope you enjoyed today's
episode guys thank you ever so much for
watching hope you enjoyed it and I'll
see you again in the next one take care
bye bye
you