[Music]
wait a minute
they killed the blacksmith again
i'm not doing it guys i promise i am not
doing it
the light is off again and the door is
open
keep in mind you gotta flip a lever
to change the light
somehow this lever is getting flipped
and the door is opening
and it's not me something
super strange is going on here
okay down to the last blacksmith
this time let's change things
because if we just drop him down here
flip the light close the door i don't
think he's gonna live to be honest
we have case studies now and it it
didn't turn out too good for the other
ones
uh let's change out this glitch door
we're gonna put a real door here
for starters
all right oh oh dark oak
hmm actually if i break this does it
give me the door
well it did darn it
you not in the mood for you right now
if i'm lucky i might be able to grab
that door and get back up
[Applause]
watch his throat come on no it's not
gonna work
oh it might this time though it might
this time
nope
man all right first things first
we're putting glass over top his head
oh it's not gonna let me
here let's put it let's put it right
there i think i got a sign here yeah i
do
all right we got glass above there
we're gonna put glass here and there
should be no way for
anything to ever get in there and kill
him
right all right
that's that's what we're gonna go with
i'm gonna go back up there i'm gonna
replace the door
i i better do it with you guys because i
have a feeling something strange is
going to happen again
uh see let's just do it really quick
we're back here put the door down we got
two doors from that i guess the bottom
half and the top path split and it gave
us one for each
okay
that's weird the door's on the different
side compared to that one one's the
right that one's to the right
this one's to the left okay
anyway so this is how i'm leaving it
right now
if the light turns off again and the
door opens i have
no clue there's no clue what's going on
so everyone here's what i think we
should do today i really want to build
a new ice tray or a new ice farm because
our big one here unfortunately
is not gonna work anymore it's it's done
it's finished
vignato it is it is broken beyond repair
because this is a tiger biome they made
a change
where tiger biomes no longer get snow
like this like
if i break the snow it's gone it's not
going to come back when it
when it rains or snows anymore
and also water doesn't freeze to ice
in tiger biomes at least at ground level
i think maybe if you go higher up they
will
it will but i never tested that um
so yeah i i can't just fix this it's
done
so we need a new ice farm i'm running
really low on ice and it's one of those
things i use a fair bit of
so let's get to that today i just like
doing this it looks so cool
oh man
yeah so we're gonna build it out by the
man cave actually because
mountains uh they get snow and water
freezes on
on them like at the high altitude which
they didn't do that before which is why
i built this one out here
long ago because this was the only snow
biome i had
but i can build it right by the man tave
now which is kind of cool actually
so let's get to it
so that was bunny number two and he
teleported into a cactus so
rest in peace bunny number two you
lasted longer than bunny one
i'm impressed
all right guys so i found a spot here up
in the mountains
i think we're gonna build the ice farm
just over here
there's like this a decent size flat
spot for us to work in
i think i'm gonna go for about a 16 by
16 area
for the for the ice farm shouldn't take
up a lot of space
i tried pouring water on the ground too
and making sure it turns to ice and it
does
which is very good same with up here
and in relation to the man cave the man
cave is just
over there you can see the bridge got
the snowflake there the mob system there
so it's not too far away i'm hoping
uh the ice farm will be able to run
automatically while we're in the man
cave because with that other one
i would have to like dig a hole and hide
in it for 30 minutes for the ice to be
made and
it was kind of annoying i would like to
just like
be able to come here and harvest it
without having to wait
i think i used to have water here and it
froze
yeah i like specially shaped this so it
would flow nicely down too
oh and it froze again darn it i'm gonna
put a torch here
yeah yeah i want that back
it's supposed to be water there it looks
like it's coming off the top of the
mountain that way
and filling the lake down below there uh
so i'm going to lay down
words words i'm gonna lay some
groundwork
to the project uh gotta do a bit of
digging and
preparation and then we'll start
building it
excellent we are ready to go here so
let's get to building the thing
and as i place down some rails here i'm
going to try to tell you about the
design
that i came up with so
i wanted to make an ice farm where the
ice gets pushed
upward like it so it looks like it's
growing out of the ground and then when
you harvest it
you have like no machinery or stuff
beside you or in in the way in any form
it's just coming out of the ground
and i i want to make like a giant ice
cube
that grows out of the ground um
and i think we are going to be able to
do it here so
it's tough to do that though because
let's see which way do we want to start
i think we're going to start this way
so it'll go left and zigzag right left
right
it's tough to make a like a vertical ice
farm though because
you need the water exposed to the sky
for to create ice if you don't have that
it doesn't
um so it can't the way i'm doing it i'm
going to make it push it sideways and
then push it upward
um and we're going to cheat
quite a bit here on the redstone instead
of using redstone we're going to be
using detector rails
oh you know what i need i didn't grab
regular rails are you kidding
oh preparation
well done let me let me lay down the
rails basically i'm just
filling in detector rails all along the
pad here
and it's going to zigzag throughout the
whole thing
yeah it'll look something like this when
i get all the rails down
pretty much exactly like that all right
let's try it out
so the detector rails here are a 10 by
10 area
so it's a hundred uh i can make it
bigger if i want it or smaller it
doesn't really matter
i think up to 24 blocks maybe a little
less
although my card slows down quite a bit
maybe 10 blocks is
pretty close to the limit it has to be
able to make it all the way across
from the power rails without any gaps
all right so that's good uh next up
we're gonna be
put putting down a layer of pistons over
top all of these
these uh detector rails like this
and these are what are going to push the
ice blocks up
and i'm only going to do a few here
because otherwise it could take a while
i don't think i have enough pistons on
me even all right
so pretend i did the whole thing next
up let's see how does this work
i hope i figured this all out right
um
[Music]
i feel like something's wrong here
let's see i have some sideways pistons
are supposed to place i think they go
along
here but then these are in the way
hmm
hmm you know what we might need to put
the sideways ones the other direction
then
so this way i didn't really want to do
it that way but it's fine
nothing wrong with that all right and
then
some more pistons down here
yeah this is right this is definitely
right
um so we'll have them going all along
like so you know what my internet is
down and i'm so sad
i'm steve right now ah
there's there's few things in life that
get me anxious or aggravated
but when when the power goes down or the
internet goes down i just feel
like ah just drives me crazy
because so much of what i do involves
both of those
and if i can't do those things it's like
um and i can live without computers
without the internet
and all that for for quite a while but
the thing is
the fact that it could come up at any
time just
just like or the fact i don't know when
it's going to come back up
is what really bugs me if i knew a time
or what's what's wrong or anything like
that
not a problem but i don't and that's
what makes me anxious
so i don't know when you guys are going
to see this episode
i was able to get a little bit of
internet today by tethering my phone
to my computer but for some reason that
stopped working as well
just randomly no clue why
still have data on it but it just
stopped
it's really annoying i went too far here
those out all right
uh let me get down the rest of these
pistons and then we'll start placing the
water
so we're actually almost done here we
just have to work out a few more details
with this build
uh let's put the water down though so
the water
this is why i like ice too by the way
it's it's portable water
it's so easy to place instead of like
carrying water buckets all over the
place
this is so much better uh we're gonna
have
water all below these pistons like this
source
blocks the stuff below the pistons won't
freeze because they don't have a view to
the sky
um then we'll want to put a few blocks
over top these edge ones
so that even if like we don't want these
to turn to ice here
so if these blocks all disappear
with this setup it'll be able to
recreate
the water i'll just show you
all right
yep not a problem not a problem good
so now we need to
let's see we're going to need to get
some more detector rails going along
beside these pistons here
let's get these down that's what
that's what will activate them going
sideways and we'll probably want at
least two power rails on
both ends to make sure it can get all
the way across
like this let me show you the
cart too what it does it's pretty cool
so if we get this thing going
oh let's get out of here quickly we're
missing it
aha so normally it's pretty tough to
wire
pistons like when they're in a big panel
like this
going upward uh so i figured i'd just
use detector rails it's much easier
and it looks kind of cool so i think
that's good
watch this this should activate yeah
those go up
very good it recreated the water oh it's
going back
i don't know if i want this thing
running like all the time like the cart
i don't know if it needs to
i don't know those are just part of the
details we have to figure out yet
but uh if we make the cart come up here
uh this should work out pretty good
actually
can this curve no needs more space
oh is there gonna be enough space i
don't think there is
let's see let's just try it so if this
goes up
can we put a oh i think it just worked
out actually look at this
nice very nice so then i'll go down here
and then we gotta send it
back to there so maybe we'll just have a
side
rail going here so it doesn't have to go
through the whole middle thing again
it'll just go right back to the start
okay let me show you how i did the rails
so the cart's going this way then i
added this rail
to make it go back to the beginning uh
originally i had i had it going all the
way through here
and it just went around really nice and
clean but
it didn't work out right because we want
these lower pistons to activate first
and then these ones
right after them and if we make it go
just around here
and the carts go in this direction then
these ones all get activated and then
it activates the bottom ones so it's in
reverse
we want to make sure these get activate
first then these so i had to do like a
figure eight thing here
it goes down activates those bottom ones
there
and then it comes up around goes this
direction
goes down here and that comes out over
here
it like goes around and then it goes oh
i'm getting all turned around and then
it goes right left right left right left
all the way down to there
back up and around down
oh it's it's a little confusing but it
works
so all right i think it works i haven't
tried it yet
so let's give it a try make sure it does
work
i just want to start it right here this
is kind of the beginning
okay they get pushed sideways
no darn it i forgot about that problem
i don't want to move this block because
it's keeping the water in place there i
actually
let it uh leak out and erect all my
rails and i had to replace them
i i'll have to move this back one more i
guess
right i think i can no i can't because i
got this here now ah
um
[Music]
darn why did it have to do that
oh you know what i could do i could just
put a sign here as well
right yeah let's do that that's that's
way nicer i'm just going to put that
there for now
get rid of this block all together
and see sine
sine sine sine sine no crafting table
whoa
just fell off the mountain we're good
we're good
uh yeah i'll just put a sign here i
think is okay
get rid of replace the water
and
[Music]
uh i i don't need to make this curve to
the left and then back around anymore
either
right oh yes i do i do oops
uh okay here we go
just about got it there we are let's try
it one more time
and please work please work
yay so pushes those up it pushes them
sideways
and pushes them up oh it'll do it on
the next trip i guess on this trip these
ones will get pushed up though
um so a big thing we got to watch for
here is how long it takes to do a cycle
as well like is this ice going to be
frozen
by the time it gets back or should we
make it wait a while
looks like we only have three ice blocks
there currently
or four
all right these ones are gonna go up now
oh oh i didn't put a cover over it
so i didn't create the water properly
okay
that was confusing
ah torches oops
so it's gonna make this is another thing
i'm not sure about it's gonna make these
side ones
like a vertical column all the way up
first and then it's gonna be the next
row
all the way up and next roll next row
not roll
oh man more torch problems oh and i
wrecked the rails again
dang it
stupid torches just wrecked my day
all right i'm gonna fix this this will
take a while uh
torches are gone rails are backed in
place let's try it out again let's just
watch it for a bit
see what it does make sure it's all okay
before we cover it up because i'm gonna
hide most these pistons
yeah it's looking good looking good
there's gonna be a layer of ice
one thick right above the whole middle
thing
so the idea isn't that you harvest all
the ice just
but there'll be one layer you don't
harvest that you walk on and
and it'll help make it look better and
and work better
because i'm going to be putting blocks
over top like these pistons these rails
all flush with the ground is how i
designed it that's why we wanted these
detector rails along
the side of this instead of blowers or
above it or something
yeah so it looks like it's going
yeah and i'm gonna try and make it out
of prismarine blocks i think
because they're new and it's nice to use
new blocks always
still good yeah still good
oh i should have checked how many ice
blocks there were
see i think we had three here
huh all right i'm gonna let it run for a
while while i uh
start working on the looks of the area a
little bit more
and we'll see what happens with it well
i didn't get very far
i ran out of the prismarine blocks very
very quickly
they're actually pretty expensive when
you think about it because it's like
eight
prismarine one ink sac for the dark ones
and it's
nine for the bricks and four for the
cobble
it goes really quickly you need you need
a lot of it to really build anything
large scale
but i afk here for about 20 minutes just
to make sure
it all works okay and it seems like it's
fine i wanted to
make sure it starts the next column
without any problems and it has
so that's cool looks pretty neat
actually i like it
i might harvest some of this ice and
just put down the floor
of ice that it's supposed to have after
the first harvest just so you can see
what it looks like
when it's when it's done properly
so there we go we got an ice floor in
the middle this is what it's supposed to
look like
and we would harvest everything from
this block up
uh when whenever we want to uh so it's
gonna create a giant 10 by 10 by
10 cube of ice here which is a thousand
blocks
15 stacks of ice per harvest
which is pretty good it looks like it's
going to fill up pretty quick too like
probably only
four or five hours of running if i was
to guess
which is way more ice than i use so i'll
probably shut it off
every so often as i get the ice so it's
not running all the time
but yeah pretty cool pretty cool this is
the last of the ice 34 blocks but we
will have more soon
thanks to this thing
all right everyone i figured out the
mystery to
the three dead blacksmiths
and it's it's a story without a happy
ending unfortunately this
this really stinks turns out
like i came here again again the
blacksmith was gone the glass was gone
lever was reset door was open it was a
broken half door again
turns out this is a corrupted chunk
where the blacksmith was ah
that stinks that really stinks
that means what it's doing it can read
the chunk okay but it can't save to that
chunk anymore
um which is not something i've ever had
happened to me before in a world
so you can place blocks in that chunk
and it's okay right but as soon as you
leave the area in it or shut down the
world
this chunk unloads and when it tries to
reload it since it wasn't able to save
it
it it uh returns to whatever it was
when it corrupted so
let me demonstrate uh
here look over here where it says chunk
0 13 10 that's the position
the in the in is the chunk number
so we're at negative 20 here
negative 20 is okay negative 19
2 8 is the corrupted chunk
so anything put in there is going to
disappear when this area
unloads so i'm just going to exit out
go back in
and all those blocks are gone so that
really stinks i don't know
really what to do with that uh
it could be a result of the snapshots or
it could
just be it corrupted a long time ago and
i never noticed because
i haven't changed anything in this area
in a long long time
and i think that's what it is actually i
don't think it is the snapshots like i
thought it might be the glitched
outdoors up there
that messed it up but the priest had a
glitched outdoor too
and that didn't cause any problems um
so it's not that it's something else
that happened probably a long time ago
that i just never caught
uh anyway here is the comment for today
guys we're gonna have to end the episode
there is no comment because i don't have
internet
i can't i can't go find a comment
unfortunately this is the first time
this has happened
um yeah really really stinks i'm now
over 12 hours without internet i'm not
sure if i'm gonna survive
tonight guys i don't know
if i do i'll see you in the next episode
but uh
it's gonna be rough these are dark days
for me
very dark and
if you're watching this most likely i
worked something out
hopefully it came back up uh if not
i i am going to attempt to upload this
through my phone if i can get that
working so that's another reason i want
to
end it right away because it's gonna
take at least 12 hours to upload
and it's yeah 0.2 upload on my phone
plan it's not great that's a quarter of
my bad internet already so
yeah ah thanks for watching guys i'll
see you in the next episode
bye bye