hey how's it going yeah I'm talking to
you how's it going what's going on
what's new how's the family you guys
remember that old intro okay we're here
working on the egg farm some more found
out it's not going to work
like I wanted it to I'll tell you why so
first of all actually I'm going to run
I think the wiring down here so we'll
have this covered up so we just run some
redstone to the right of this block and
we can get it to go down down here
somewhat somehow to these Pistons the
reason this isn't quite working right
like the idea was to keep the chickens
inside of the glass block all the time
so that when they would lay an egg it
would shoot up the top but when they lay
an egg it has like the sideways velocity
to it so if it's moving slightly to the
left for example it'll go upwards but it
will keep going to the left through
however many blocks you have in front of
it so even if this was like five blocks
thick this wall it would just keep
moving through those blocks and
eventually it would like move like that
all the way up nope but if the egg is
standing still when the glass block hits
it it goes straight up that's important
we got to nullify its velocity before we
put it inside a block otherwise it's
going to go random directions because
they they lay the eggs in random
directions
oh boy so yeah I think what we'll end up
doing did it make it all the way up no
where did it go yeah we're going to have
to try figure a few things out here but
I'll probably just set up a pressure
plate up here and when we go over that
it'll make a piston extend down there
and the eggs will go straight up
hopefully to where we want them to go
whatever that egg went there's an egg
out here there's one egg over there so
one of these chickens laid an egg and it
shot out to the left and eventually just
fell out here I just alright so I'm
going to try make a few adjustments here
and we'll see how that works okay let's
try this out guys we have the lever all
wired all right let's go down still
don't have a nice way of getting down
this is okay though so I put the piston
holy that was a loud one put the piston
down in the middle instead of pushing
the eggs from the sides because I think
if you push them from the sides they get
a sideways velocity as they rise and
will not go up straight so I think this
works out better we're actually going to
try this out yeah let's throw in Wow
is it just me or is that really loud for
some reason I think we had 27
27 dirt okay so the wire it runs all the
way down here and to it over there so
let's go up we'll flip that lever and
see if we get all our dirts or some of
its lost or what happens exactly oh
let's go let's go
that is some storm I tell you oh yeah
also worst noise ever
okay so much noise here we go should we
go we'll try it watch as it comes up we
probably won't be able to see anything
if it comes up it didn't come up yeah
they it oh I didn't think it would be
this hard to transport items what's
wrong
let's go down again I want to get this
right before we put the chickens in
otherwise we're gonna have to kill them
all okay
well they're gone where did they go
where they keep disappearing too I
wonder maybe we'll find them in the wire
track somewhere oh yeah we just picked
them up hmm so I think they were up
there somehow they still didn't go up
Straits that's not good mmm well I think
let's just try this out a few times and
see if we can spot a hole let's cut the
stuff escaping to or something I don't
know where it's going
fill that in okay it went up should be
going straight up I don't know why we
got it again right from there okay
let's try it again see if it does it
again I think that was the same spot as
before yeah you see it you see it
because I have a hole here from the
Redstone I guess yeah hmm okay I can fix
this okay I got that plugged let's try
it again
and fill it and now hopefully hopefully
it's at the top otherwise I don't know
what to do and I'm running out of ideas
I thought it was just going to be really
simple to do this but there's more to it
than I expected
hey you don't steal any blocks okay I
don't trust them
no they're still not here hmm
there's another hole over there it looks
like it might be doing going to that I
should try go and just seal this all up
let's see if we pick it up when we go by
yeah look that's what it is okay so it's
got to be solid that's the trick and it
might shoot into these stairs I should
change these maybe okay where you at die
and hit him he's going to teleport yeah
how do you take damage I hate it when
these guys steal my grass blocks and
he's gone okay
holes are sealed its wired let's try it
come on make it up make it up it didn't
make it oh it did make it where was it
I must have been in the stair hmm okay I
got rid of all those chests and also the
stairs it's all solid and I also
replaced the lever with the pressure
plates and change the wiring up a little
bit so let's try it out again I think
it'll work
come on come on yes finally great okay
so we can load it up with chickens I
think and should be good now this is the
wiring path whew
got one repeater in to extend it OOP
and it comes all the way down so now to
get the chickens in
I wanted to do a few other fancy things
but maybe I'll do this another day yeah
just to get the chickens in it's kind of
take them up like 20 minutes to grow and
another five minutes to lay eggs so
it'll probably take too long to do this
episode but we'll load them up Wow
not the best okay we got one at least
from that sorry chicken I always feel
bad when you have to whip them in their
face after they hatch I think we got two
from that one egg oh yeah gonna be great
guys a terrible noise good last stack I
got I'm not sure we might be able to
breed them somehow through the glass
okay because this all has to be solid
I think otherwise it will find a way to
escape on its way up and there's about
18 or so in there that works okay good
all right you know what I think we
should work on this for a little bit
today too you remember remember the
river we made not too long ago I want to
add some trees along the sides of it I
don't know the poor squid know he's in
the water oh he didn't deserve to die
why did he die Oh
that was weird yeah let's let's put
trees alongside the river this sandy
part I think I'm going to switch out -
we'll put some soil here all along maybe
just make it come out four or five
blocks from the water and then we'll
leave it as sand see how that goes huh
so I'll switch this over I'll get back
to you and we'll plant some trees it's
some bone meal and just see how it looks
I would like I would like the trees that
vines on to that kind of overhang in the
water that guy really wants me can't
have me there we go I got a whole bunch
of it replaced over there in this big
section here let's try get some trees
down and see how it looks I think let's
put them about the third block from the
water so here does have to be perfect
actually it's better if it's not okay
and hopefully we'll get a few big ones
at least I wonder if that might be too
close together let's just see what that
looks like and over there and they're
all little ones so far oh there we go
let's see what that looks like from the
water that's kind of cool yeah I like
that so we'll do that all along here
just trying to make this prettier a lot
of people are saying I should replace
that remember that overhang also with
stone and I might end up doing that too
just so it looks more natural
I changed a lot of the stone with dirt
that try keep it uniform looking but
yeah probably look better with stone
after all and we'll make it go let's
make it go all the way to the water yeah
sure whoa right in the face
you're going to achieve over there mr.
zombie villager I still haven't been
back to the village since we did that
maybe we will try it for that next
episode I'll maybe just hang around
there for a little while and see if they
start breeding in that okay how's that
going yeah it's pretty good the desert
trees are really yellow I got these
vines too should put a few of those
around oh it believes just died there
you see that and the grass drover time
very good I forgot there's a whole
ravine down here too is actually really
dangerous let's go check this out one
sec I don't know if I ever went down
here we're getting owned good get out of
here school yeah okay yeah I've never
been down here hey how's it going um um
don't do it whoo
see what I did there you see that I'll
do it to you too oh okay enough goofing
around
we could have trees down there and over
there we might not put any on top though
and we could have them go around have
some over here just to make it feel more
enclosed and then this goes to the
overhang the clip is pretty steep here
so we'll probably skip this area
although maybe maybe we could sneak one
in here or two yeah okay that's cool big
tree let's try yet another one over here
yeah that's working you guys think too
many trees maybe here oh no I think
that's awesome yeah I like that a lot
actually and let's try to get one more
tree here if we can we'll replace this
and see if we can sneak another tree in
here right there ah so it does use the
bonemeal up even if it doesn't grow
that's pretty cool
if we get some vines it's going to look
nice and I may even change these the
glowing trees
all right s going to be good
yes so today guys the day I'm recording
this anyway I upload the first episode
of don't starve and I just want to give
a big THANK YOU to get to you guys for
you know being pretty nice in the
comments it's always a little
nerve-wracking uploading something
different and I I appreciate it when you
guys are nice and give good feedback I
recorded a whole bunch of episodes of it
yesterday actually and at the time I
wasn't really thinking oh yeah you know
what people might not like this I just
did it and today before I read the
comments it's like oh you know what I
forgot some people might be mean because
it's not my draft but yeah actually
people were really nice in the comments
I did get a few instant dislikes like
maybe 100 or so I think that from people
I didn't give it a chance but overall
those that did they were really nice in
the comments
there was Anna or at least I didn't see
a whole lot of negative in the comments
which is always a good feeling so thank
you guys
with that though it's it's only going to
be a one time series I think so when I
die in it that's probably going to be
the end I still haven't died I am NOT
going to tell you how many episodes I've
recorded though so but yeah once we die
or if the game gets repetitive that's
going to be the end and we probably
won't have any more of that on YouTube
I'm a one day stream it if I get into
streaming but for YouTube that's
probably that's probably going to be a
short 10 episode or so series depending
on how long I last so I hope you guys
enjoy it
how is just going let's take a boat ride
let's see what we've done here and then
we'll probably get going I need to get
to bed here recording late again tonight
I don't like recording late I haven't
recorded late in a long time actually
I've been pretty good about that but
I've had a busy week so my schedules a
little bit off oh this is nice
oh load world load that good trees all
the way out here yeah I did some of
these I still need to grow can we reach
come on yes
ooh that's the overhang so this is what
we should replace with stone the top
part at least and having a party over
there yeah let's go let's go for a
proper boat ride through this thing yeah
I'm going to try add some vines I'll
probably grow some grass and flowers on
the outside too which is nice so oh yeah
nice overhead canopy got a bunch of
trees there
oh no no whoo I want to add maybe a few
more over there it's a little bear I
just want it to feel very lush lush
Riverside oh I gotta grow those those
are looking good those are our vines are
already growing that's cool oh those
trees we might want to get a few closer
don't hit the boat No
ah we almost made it all the way through
yeah that's nice I like it
so if we had some lights in the trees to
some glowing trees it's going to look
really good and then with this area I'm
sure what we should do here I really
like that waterfall
I should add some more waterfalls on
that mountain look look he's in the
water he's not oh boy they suffocate
when they're on land now but seriously
he was in the water still one piece of
sand is bugging me here there we go much
better okay guys let's go read the
comments and see what people have to say
for today yeah I picked a question out
of the comments it's a good question
mine the grammar though it's it's pretty
bad
hey etho I have a question you don't
gonna stop with your let's play soon do
you um yeah oh boy I think you've asked
me if I'm ever going to stop my let's
play and the answer is I have no
intention to I'll probably keep it going
as long as I'm making videos even if
minecraft views drop significantly I'll
probably still keep up with it and same
goes with minecraft server as long as my
track servers around and I'm on it I
will probably keep making episodes of it
big those are pretty similar to my let's
play actually except there's a bit of a
group dynamic to it different things
happen from other people and I like to
try to incorporate that when I can
another one he stole a grass block thank
I but yeah I really enjoy my let's play
series and I I want to keep it going as
long as they can and you know as a side
question that might come up
I plan on
keeping this world also for as long as I
can I don't think I need to switch it
and less land generation drastically
changes and I can't get it for some
reason in this world but I don't think
that's a problem so that's gonna do it
for today guys have a good day and thank
you for watching
night time song