[Music]
hello everybody this is ethos
thank you for joining me again i hope
you have your snacks ready
uh what we're going to do today to start
off with
i'm going to make i'm going to make one
of these
oh yeah and
i was going by the cow farm
the other day and i really want to fix
it
um i was staring at it for a while and
it's
it's easy to fix i just need to do it so
let's
take care of that um
it is possible to turn this back into a
wheat farm now
um first for those of you that are
newish
i'll go over the history of this cow
farm
thing here when i first built it
you see how we have fences underneath
all of these
[Music]
when i first built it it was when
uh walking over farmland would trample
any crops you had to always sneak over
it
that got changed but during that time
there was this
glitch in the game where if you had a
fence below the farmland
you would not trample the crop
no matter how much you jumped on it or
how much you ran on it
didn't matter it was always good that
got fixed and
this used to be a wheat farm actually we
should try out the water
make sure it still works used to be a
wheat farm
and then i had to get rid of that
feature
when they fixed the fence trick we still
have the water systems ready
um but then they changed another thing
where they made it so cows only jumped
uh if they're climbing up something like
if they're trying to get over this fence
he'll jump over
it but if they're just walking around
they won't jump
and i've been watching them and that's
definitely true so
we we can convert this back to
a wheat farm as well if we put some
fences
in between keep them from jumping
so if they can't make it over they won't
try
of course they all hey no you can't make
it over
stop trying stop trying
[Music]
uh maybe if we do the whole thing
they'll stop hey squid
what are you doing in here uh i do sort
of have uh
just blew in the mic sorry i do have a
bit of a chicken farm here
i've been throwing eggs in here for so
long
and i never ever get chickens from the
eggs i don't know why
out of like the 40 or 50 eggs i've
thrown in there i've gotten two chickens
just bad luck
okay yeah there
now they should stop jumping let's let's
hop out of here
did not mean to go up here
everybody's behaving
yeah so now we can switch this back to
wheat farm i'm gonna get rid of this too
i never liked the
the pumpkins in this i think when i
built it is when
actually i wonder if i can
i don't know if we can put a lamp there
and power it
when i built this i think it was before
i went to the nether
yeah i don't see how i could power that
well we can switch these ones for sure
the lighting is just right in the sweet
farm as well
so these ones in the middle are very
important
do that and that
yeah okay so i'll see you guys back in a
little bit
once i plant this a nice feel the wheat
here
what's wrong with this picture what what
is not
right just randomly out of the blue
i was just in the wheat field i come up
here and there's a creeper just
right behind me i don't know where he
came from
exactly i see he fell down there though
the farmland's trampled
um very close call though
so another thing i want to add to this
is uh some
dispensers maybe outside here
one for for this one
for i got a looting sword
be nice to have that there
maybe dispensers for wheat and for seeds
as well
not not really to dispense them more
more just to hold them like a chest
but i'll put buttons next to them anyway
are we just having a party down here
aren't we now we got an enderman
trampled another crop
oh you're mad i'm mad
dude not cool
oh man that sound it's getting to me
it's driving me crazy
gotta get out of here i did do i put
some dispensers
in the sides two there and two on this
side
i also put buttons above
there's some note blocks in the back
which we'll cover up
each one a different instrument to help
me
memorize by sound which one is which
and that's about it for that
excellent so we got that feature
repaired the wheat
farm is back in action and uh looks
pretty cool
um it's gonna come in handy as well
because my
my wheat supply my stockpile has come to
an end so this is very timely
and we need the wheat to feed the cows
and my steak supply is also coming to an
end
so it's good we did this today
and also you know what like as patches
come out in this game stuff gets broken
it's just part of it and if if you don't
repair that stuff
it keeps building up in your world and
you have more and more things that don't
work
slime's not moving minecart's broken
what's going on
no speaking of not working
what's going on here
[Applause]
there's a baby slime there
um hopefully i'll get through here
oh i did it okay
[Applause]
interesting you know what it was i was
killing slimes before and
um a tiny one
got into the big slime area and i think
that
messed things up
[Applause]
but yeah if you don't
if you don't fix stuff in your world
eventually it just keeps building up and
building up and
it gets to you it bugs you and that's
one of the problems i had with the old
lp
world i just kept having more and stuff
more and more stuff break and it got to
the point where over 50 percent
of the stuff in the world wasn't going
to work anymore
hmm okay one second here
okay so it would be a real shame if we
did all this with the wheat farm and we
didn't fix
the ufo as well so let's check this out
and see what we need to do
to finish it
okay because i built this if you
remember i built this
and my world got corrupted and
everything i did to it got
erased when i loaded the back up
and i haven't fixed it since
so i have to i got to fill this up
with water another layer at least
and
[Music]
i'll probably i'll just do this really
simple i'm gonna
what am i gonna do gonna make the water
flow
to here and then
see if we can make the shot
oh beautiful make the water go this way
and then we'll
have a a hole that comes down around
here
and we'll drop the cows right like where
this torch is
right in the center and that'll give us
something we can put lighting around
here as well because
i haven't been able to hide the lighting
all that well and we
if we have something in the middle of
this fence to break it up
we can hide some extra lighting around
here
yeah so that's what i'll do um give me a
moment while i work on this
and i'll get back to you
all right we are up here we're going to
start putting some water down
um that creeper from before he came from
this hole right there by the glowstone
there's a hole that goes all the way up
to the surface and there's a water
stream
uh converging converging can
coming together at that hole it's meant
for the cows in case we ever have to
reload this
but occasionally a mob will make its way
down
and since i've been up here i've had two
mobs come down
they're they're finding me we got a
skeleton waiting for us there
and there's some zombie flesh from a
zombie that fell down
just floating right there
but what i'll do with this we're gonna
put
leaves along here
and then put water next to them
and we should put a infinite spring
somewhere too
yeah right there
so we gotta go all the way along got to
place every single water source there's
no shortcut to that
because there's no there's no ground
below to make a infinite water source
and i'll be back when i'm done that
okay i got the second water layer done
uh we need
the water fairly thick because if i
remember right before
sometimes the cow would the cows would
fall through if it wasn't thick enough
like before they would start swimming
they would come up and they'd just fall
down through
this is where we will stand for the ufo
um put a rim around this we're going to
try to make the water go
this way different than we did it before
so i got a row of water in the back i
gotta make it spread now
which i can do by
doing that to make it go out
okay and then that will only go eight
blocks is the thing so
starts there one two three
four five six
seven eight so the water is going to end
right about there
and we need to make it go further yet so
i'm going to try
this out we'll have an iron bar
stretching along here
could also use signs for this but i'm
going to try an iron bar
and then
one layer up have another one i don't
know if a cow will fit through that
that's what i'm trying to do um
i know a player can fit through this no
problem um
because this will actually wait a minute
wait a minute
i'm not careful the cows might get
underneath here and drown
hmm well anyway we'll have to play
around with this a bit i'm sure
but if a towel will fit up through here
i can put
another water source
right on top of this fence here and make
it go further
okay well i'm going to show you how this
is intended
to work uh i'm a towel right now pretend
i'm a cow
i'm a cow i'm a cow i'm a cow
uh they'll hit this uh iron bar i'm
expecting they're gonna
swim up and then fall down and i think
that will
allow them to go underneath and then
they'll try to swim up again
because they're only going to be half in
this air space and half in the water
still so
they should still continue to swim
assuming they can fit between the two
iron bars
and then there's water streams at both
ends which
will pull them to the middle here and
then we'll make them go
this way with the one
one block wide water stream so
what what we're trying to do essentially
here is to get
all the channels that come up in this
nine by nine area down to a one
wide water stream
which is easier said than done so i did
get a fishing rod we're gonna try it out
it's been a long time since i fished for
cows so
don't know how good my technique is to
be
first try no he's not jumping up and
down enough
interesting let's try one more
maybe in a different spot
we'll do something different
okay that is not working
oh oh he made it
he's too fat though why are you so fat
ah okay they cannot fit through that
could also move this back
no we can't
so i think what it comes down to is i
have to use the signs all across here
a little bit less professional looking
but that's what we'll do or fence gates
or something
he's not drowning is he she
why aren't you drowning where are you
getting your air from
i guess it's she must be far enough into
this
iron bar that she's not considered to be
in water
[Music]
i was going to do the fence gates but it
wouldn't let me place them against the
ceiling i think you need
a block underneath or something so i
just went with signs
we're gonna try this out we're gonna put
water in the two sides and see what
happens
these cows
go go go
they should come to the middle
there he is okay
and he is stuck on she
whatever it is stuck on a block all
right
oh i see so there was a block missing up
there
um so that'll work it's a little messy
looking i'd never
plan on coming up here um
should be able to clean it up quite a
bit yet though
all right i'll tell you a fun way of
harvesting wheat
in case you didn't know this um
fall on it from like a mile up
gives you a good feeling
okay let's do our first harvest here
it's pretty much all grown
i've been falling occasionally and we
got a few missing
from that
awesome look at him dance
getting a lot of like from that i forgot
about that
very nice
[Applause]
[Music]
so yeah it holds a lot of wheat what was
it got over two stacks of wheat from
that
[Music]
oh
oh when they're jumping in the water
they trample all the ground that sucks
all right uh there's a few changes here
i know i said i wouldn't need to come up
here and it wouldn't matter what it
would look like
but really if i want to use it if i want
to use the ufo
feature and go fishing for the cows for
fun
um i need to come up here to get into it
or that would be the most convenient way
so i also need to punch a hole
oh that creeper scared me um i gotta get
a
gotta have a way of getting in and out
so i'm gonna get down there i just will
just
maybe change this and yes i know i have
shears on me but
i'm sometimes afraid of using them that
i'll take out more than one block
because they they harvest the leaves
really quick
so yeah we'll do that we'll put a ladder
here
and this will be our way in and out
can we get back out yes okay the nice
thing about this
cows are fatter than the player they
cannot fit
between this ladder like in this block
they're too fat
while we can so
works rest doesn't work for them there's
no chance of them swimming up that
this is the water path
basically they'll get flung up into
this huge block of water thing
just holding the space bar
they'll get pulled along here then
there's a
there's a it's higher here
and that will align them into the center
even though
the fence gates won't do that the the
leaves here will
and the water stream ends perfectly
right
here so this is what where they'll get
dropped
hey whoa what is with all the creepers
man
and that thing's busted again come on
what is going on today this is crazy
never have much mob trouble
okay he was low on health too
i'm assuming he came down here again
it's because i'm close to the surface
and they're tracking me
and finding their way down here
[Applause]
what it probably is i think they're
spawning in there
and messing up the carts
ah because i thought i fixed that there
might also be a cart stuck on the track
somewhere from that last disaster
uh oh yeah let's try this out make sure
the channels get dropped down
random xp orb floating there from the
creeper
yes where we go down get our fishing
line
and let's go fishing so again this
is just for fun this project
wow got him right in the center
[Music]
bye-bye so we need a tube down below
there to hold them
and possibly some other stuff but i'm
not going to worry about that too much
right now
one of the weirdest water streams i've
ever done doesn't matter if it takes
them a long time just
as long as they get there
all right so that works yeah this is one
of the weirdest water streams i've ever
done
because i used iron bars and leaves
yeah okay
so the tube what should we do for the
tube
i do want lighting around the base of it
to help light up this
area get rid of this torch it's like the
last well there's a few around here
still
some one of the last few though that we
need to get rid of
and if we have a fence
here and one here they won't be able to
jump
over that i could just do fences
hmm
yeah i might just do fences that would
be real simple then we don't have to
have a
ugly tube although that um
okay i'll think about it i'll think
about it
yeah we'll do fences for now and later
we might change it to something else
but we'll try the these out for a while
now
let's put
let's put wood around here
and this will probably get changed too
i'll work out the finer details to this
another day i got to go to bed um
we'll put a glow stone or a lamp or
something there
let's try this out one last time and
call it a day
okay and also up here i might put
probably most likely we'll put
dispensers
in over here or something instead and
change this to stone
and in the dispensers put fishing rods
and
other things i might need
okay
wow whoa that was a weird that was a
weird one
you gotta wait a few seconds after you
hook them
um i don't think they will ever get
underneath the iron
bars the reason is because it they get
pulled towards you
um so even if they were directly below
the iron bars they won't get pulled
straight up i don't think they will get
pulled
slightly towards me and it should be
okay
how did i get out of here before
okay ender pearls i'll have to make a
way to get up here properly
random grass
huh interesting
and we have a cow there awesome
yeah so we'll we'll work out the finer
details later i'll probably do most of
that off camera
and then show you uh i'll make the room
up there nice
as well get a path for us to go up and
down
cow it doesn't move it stays in the
center that's cool too
but yeah that's it for today it's nice
to get this up and working again
thanks for watching everybody i'll see
you again next time
[Music]
you