hello hello how's it going everyone this
is Keith oh and welcome back guys to our
let's play world how you doing I am
doing pretty gassy no I'm doing fine
doing great I've been working on our
blaze farm here just been adding more
purple and yellow and trying to finish
it up trying to make it look good or
weird or whatever it is so added a few
more details to it since last episode
and I've started working on a tunnel
here to get to it and I'm trying to
figure out how I want to do the sides
and that kind of stuff on it right now
but a very big change has happened to
this game guys as a lot of you probably
saw hey what's your problem man get out
my face there was a big update to the
game they added gliders and they
reworked the boats and I am very excited
about that I want to I want to try that
outs so what we're gonna have to do I
found out the hard way guys like I had
some big plans for today I went from the
nether here to the overworld and when I
went through the portal the nether
portal I started I spawned underground
and was suffocating to death so I dug
myself out of the mountain and then I
went from the overworld back to the
nether here and I just fell into a giant
pool of lava so it's like ok portals the
nether portals aren't working properly
in this update I was like okay I'm just
gonna skip going into the nether
altogether we'll just go straight to the
end because to get the new glider guys
that's where it is you have to get to
that end ship you know where the beacon
was before well they got rid of that
beacon and now there's an item frame
there that has the glider wings in so
it's gonna go try get those and go
through the end portal fall into the
void so I've had I've had a little bit
of trouble getting going here but I want
to play around with them so what we'll
have to do is go into
creative world I guess since survival is
kind of kind of broken with that update
currently till they fix it so I'm going
to generate an amplified world and we'll
just goof around with gliders and maybe
plan out what we're going to build in
our world to use them okay so here we go
into the amplified world whoo all right
everybody so welcome to an amplified
world with the new glider wings these
are the Electra so they're called so
that is it's like the shell on a beetle
you know like a ladybug when they lift
up their shell and then the wings come
out that's that's what the light rawr
whoo-hoo and they are so cool oh there's
a village over here so I thought maybe
it'd be fun just to play around with
them a little bit to start with see what
we can do you kind of get used to how
they work so I've been reading on the
reddit some some information about them
to just see what people have been doing
with them
it sounds like they can go about ten
blocks every one block you go downward
here and since we're in creative we're
doing cheats Oh wrong way wrong way no
oh that's the way we roll okay yeah if
you fly perfectly horizontal like with
your angle at about zero or zero right
right here you can go pretty far pretty
pretty quickly as well if you go
downward though you get like a speed
boosting then you can do like a swoop up
kind of like in Super Mario 64 with the
wind cap and I seem to do like a leg
kicking move when I run out of speed and
then you start drifting downward if you
go perfectly straight up to you oh yeah
you fall darn it oh man that was brutal
I just watched that back I didn't land
on my feet guys I landed on my head it's
like a neck breaking landing it was
great I want
try the few things here so leaping
potion I want to see if that's enough to
get you airborne because normally you
can't just jump in and float oh uh it
seems to start but yeah you don't go
very far
yeah you see I'm just pressing spacebar
right now and I'm moving forward a
little bit it's like the gliding just
initiates but you still need somewhat of
a cliff to go anywhere with it aha
so no quick travel on flatland okay I
was wondering about that and let's see
oh yeah so the wings they have a
durability to them they have 432 and you
can apparently repair them they just go
is it there like a chess piece right
you can apparently repair them
infinitely I don't know if that's true
or not let's let's use them again and I
think it's like every second you fly
your ability goes down by one from what
I read okay let's try it again so it was
one the first time oh that didn't I
think we flew for a second there didn't
we maybe it's not a second maybe you got
a travel certain number of blocks this
is really hard because I don't have you
know I did want to play around at the
end of pearls deal if this is a good
opportunity whew
didn't you throw one while gliding oh
you can yes oh this is gonna be so
awesome
feather falling is a definite must now
though okay now they probably took some
durability it's double check see if it's
still one level to repair it has 426 oh
it's two levels now I don't know hmm
I'll have to look into that a bit more
I wanted to see though if you can put
unbreaking on these like that's getting
more expensive for every time you repair
them I hope they don't like become
unrepairable because you
can't craft them you have to find them
in there they're hard to find okay so if
you put thorns on is that possible no no
thorns even though it's a chess piece
protection for is a no unbreaking 3 all
you can do on breaking though in
survival mode that's great really happy
about that so the last longer at least
Hey
all right cool so let's let's let's play
around some more something I saw on
reddit that a lot of people are doing is
like cave diving and flying through
little openings and stuff I want to see
if we can do a bit of that ok I found a
pretty good challenge here and we'll see
if we didn't do it our first step is to
get into that opening there and then we
I think we got to go down into the left
and then it gets really crazy so we'll
see if we can do it here I don't know if
we can fly this far ok so just nice nice
gliding to begin with nothing crazy oh
oh actually might I make it oh I'm in
the wrong view what am i doing oh where
is it is it down here yeah it's down
here it's down here ok swoop down and
then whoop and then what and then to the
right and then do the left oh yes we did
it now we just need a cave to go down is
it we run over here no oh wait wait
no oh all right so challenge number two
guys I just had an idea
let's try make a sky Road okay so it's
an inverted sky road instead of going on
top of it you go underneath it and this
would serve instead of a launching
mechanic so if you didn't want to do a
slime block launcher or TNT blasting you
into space I don't know why you wouldn't
want to do that but if you want to try
something else an idea is as you lose
altitude throw an enderpearl
up and then you regain it right and you
can potentially travel forever this way
if this works I haven't tried it yet
this is our maiden voyage ok you ready
let's get into the cool
we'll do the camera mode here so I'm
gonna have to do this when I want to
throw the Pearl okay whoo I don't know
how far I can go let's let's just start
easy oh well uh a kind of works with
practice you know you could probably do
it pretty good see if we can go farther
oh yeah
still doubts still counts the end of
this is four hundred blocks we've
traveled the only thing is my uh my
health is going down Oh was that a Miss
no I hit - Wow
I just thought an endermite falling to
its death that's awesome
Oh oh yeah I got it I got it oh I felt
it too further though I think although
I'm lagging maybe that'll help no I
think that's going into the water
definitely possible though
so now we answer the question we've all
been wondering can you glide while
riding a pig off a cliff we must find
out the answer right piggy okay
game-mode 0
I think riding pigs might be broken
right now yeah I had trouble with the
horses too I wasn't able to tame horses
for some reason so there's a couple
issues in this current snapshot but
maybe we can just push him off the cliff
should be about the same thing right
all right piggy here we go and whoa no
you can not glide while riding an entity
it looks like okay here's what I want to
try next so I want to see P and flies
through these trip wires right without
landing and see if the slime block will
give you a boost again you know while
you're still in midair so without
landing fly through it get launched up
let's try it this should be a pretty
good runway if this works you can just
like do a loop and just go forever right
oh do i I don't have my wings oh darn it
yeah one sec man I just had a big
flashback to the whole like feed the
beast Oh jump out the window
oh I forgot my jet pack is flat people
are going to be doing that in vanilla
minecraft now it's like every week
people are gonna be posting oh I jumped
out of my treehouse forgot my wings cuz
you gotta you have to take them off to
fix them right people will forget it put
them back on calling it now it's gonna
happen all the time okay here we go I
don't know it's gonna take some practice
to get good at these two Oh totally
missed it let's try again I like the way
they implemented them though that
actually takes a bit of skill to fly
them like controlled it's not like a
static speed you can adjust it and set
up courses and obstacles if you want
it's good
be a real fun thing I wonder from going
through them or did I write my bad at
lining it up it looked like that was
right to me but you can kind of go
through tripwires too as a problem ah
delays too long
yeah you move fast and I should test the
speed too I haven't done that yet yeah
let's set it to one okay here we go
again I think the trick is we got to
really slow down oh let's get low and
then slow I missed it I missed it
yeah oh this is so difficult I can't do
it one more time come on it is so
difficult to hit this little target I
hope I get really good with these wings
I'm gonna practice you know enderpearls
were hard at first but now everybody's
really good at them um okay we got it
that time but again delays wrong oh no
oh yeah I think I did that right but it
likes stop me then actually push me up
hmm I landed instead of actually getting
launched at all which is kind of weird
ow oh I did it oh my goodness yes it is
possible
oh that's awesome
you have to be going fairly fast though
it is so hard to do that was like my
30th or 40th attempt already but the
idea is if you can get a refresh you
don't actually have to land and it's the
landing that messes you up because once
you land you have to go through the
whole downward and then horizontal where
you lose about five to ten blocks of
height but if you're just going
horizontal at full speed like that you
just keep cruising now to take it to the
next level I want to try chain multiple
of them together so I'm just going to
try to do two because my pilot's skills
kind of suck right now but these are the
same heights and you should be able to
space um pretty far apart I don't know
the right distance or anything yet it'll
be a bit of a trial and error sort of
thing but I'm gonna try do two now so
wish me luck there we go that's the
secret you didn't you just need more
surface area oh I think I landed on that
though because I saw the walking
animation ah this is killing me guys I
know there's a trick to it I know there
is I just can't figure out what it is
see this that's what's happening to me
now I'm getting stuck on it
I think increasing the size of the
launcher is actually not a good thing
I'm guessing it's like it's figuring out
that I'm hanging the side of a slime
block instead now and that stops me oh
went through and the tripwires seem to
not activate a lot of the times which is
another big problem so I don't know if I
can do this consistently
ah what I went too fast I don't know um
now a few times I did seem to get it to
work I believe I was moving upwards
slightly at a pretty decent speed ah oh
yeah I think that might have counted
actually I felt like we slowed down a
lot though it's hard to say okay one
more time and slightly move upwards now
I got stuck on it hmm
well anyways I'll practice that some
more later maybe you guys know what I'm
doing wrong you let me know but I wanted
to check out what happens when you go
through lava and water as well so let's
let's see this and then drink a fire
resistant potion to stop you um-hmm yeah
it slows you down okay then you got to
do the freefall again so it's like like
you're starting over I believe yeah
really slows you down you seem to keep
some horizontal momentum so it's not
terrible but it does slow you down quite
a bit
mmm project ice runway doesn't seem to
work either the idea was that if you use
ice you might keep some of your
horizontal momentum so even if you land
it doesn't slow you down too much but I
keep getting stuck on the slime box and
I'm not sure what the deal is with that
and you'll get rid of all the delay see
if that does anything and now I can't
get it to work alright so the flying is
very cool I like it a lot can't wait to
play around with it more in our survival
world but I wanted to try out the boats
today as well so let's get to that all
six different color
Oh baby
dark oak oh that's not bad either
I like the birch one hi they all look
pretty good actually even the jungle
wood I don't mind the jungle wood
vacation looks really cool though huh
if you want to be fancy I think it
teaches way to go so I think they
changed the recipe some something odd
happened in my LP world like for one
thing I found a bunch of sticks and and
planks on the ground like some boats
exploded and I don't know where that
came from
but it just found it a few places and
shovel is it oh that's not it okay so
what it is the different colors of wood
don't work currently they'll probably
come out soon but in survival all you
can do with the the 41b is oak ya 41b
uh-huh anyways let's try these out I
have not wrote in them once yet so this
is my first time since the change let's
see how it how it works I know whoa why
am I going did I play some backwards
okay turn it around so you press a and D
now a this will happen when I press a
this is what happens when I press T so
it controls one paddle at a time let's
go into this view I guess and there
seems to be a limit to how fast you can
press into if you hold both together oh
you can pick up entities too yeah that's
awesome oh it is a little bit confusing
because I want to go right when I press
D and that makes me go left ah I don't
think a little while to get used to but
you can just hold them down a and D
together and then you go straight look
around a zero as you're rowing it's kind
of nice the boat is very slow right now
but I'm guessing they're going to change
that because I saw so
complaints I can't imagine they will
leave it like this because yet is even
slower than I expected someone said
though that they they go the same speed
maybe I'm just not let's play around
with the timing of the paddles maybe
there is a trick to it oh man whoa you
can turn pretty fast okay here we go
and actually pressing the button
together I think it's the same speed
right I'll try a few different speeds
you can probably hear me press some
button through the mic slower slower
maybe now slower makes a girl slower
there's they did in a good way though
where you don't just spam like the
faster you spam the faster you go
because that would be really annoying
there's there's a limit to how fast you
can press it it's more important that
you're consistent but it's also nice you
just hold it down and go I don't know if
that's the fastest you can go with it
but I can't get it any quicker really
uh-huh okay let's try to maneuver the
river see if that's possible it seems
like once I start turning I lose all my
momentum though just kind of bad like I
would like to just gradually turn here
while still going fast but I can't yeah
that's an issue very easy to control
right now though because it's so slow
but I'm sure they're gonna they're going
to buff up the speed and make it a
little bit tighter controls it's a it's
a cool change oh I like that just needs
a little bit more improvement so if we
got an entity in the boat how do we get
rid of them if we hold shift I I get out
okay I have to actually break it
can I break it oh yeah that got him out
okay so you're pretty much always going
to have a squid with you it seems
because they like to hang out on the
surface unless you get a chicken
come on chicken gonna get you ah ha oh
and they they get in your way too now
that's crazy okay so as far as I know
there's no way to break the boats by
ramming it to the side of the hill yeah
didn't break good what if we shoot it is
it like minecarts and stuff I imagine it
still is let's go to game mode one get
our bow let's try shoot the chicken
first
now you can yeah one shot broke it
yep they don't break it's wonderful
alright everyone so we're gonna wrap up
our episode here for today had some some
good fun with the gliders I didn't want
to stop I I did that stupid run like a
hundred times at least I just want to
keep playing with it and see what else
is possible because there's so there's
so many ideas and and just fun things
you can do not necessarily practical
things just a lot of fun goofy things
you can do with the colliders anyways
we'll hopefully be able to play around
with them in our world to your next
episode if they fix that portal bug
which I'm sure they will and then we can
start setting up some cool stuff here
but anyways here is the comment for
today it says etho how about doing
another terraformer craft series with
shaders okay so I brought this one up
because lately in my comments I'm seeing
a lot of people mentioned Terra Firma
crafts like almost every video so I
think maybe this might be the time we do
another reboot of the series um I've
been thinking about what to play and I
was considering either doing Starbound
Terra Firma craft maybe sky saga I was
hoping to check out and a couple other
ideas I had but let me know what you
think about Terra Firma craft I probably
won't do it with the shaders if we do
though because even though I like them
and a lot of you guys did there was a
lot of people that really hated them so
just to keep it open for more people
probably know shaders this time also I
had trouble recording with them just
because they killed my framerate uh-huh
alright well I hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode have a wonderful day and
I'll see you in the next one take care
bye bye
you