hello hello how's it going everybody
this is
etho and welcome back guys how you doing
today
hope you're having a good day where are
we right now you might be wondering it's
kind of obvious isn't it this is not
where I come to cry or anything like
that it's not no I just dug this up this
is right behind the mob system as you
probably guessed I got to be really
careful around this too I think because
I don't think there's any way to get
these mushroom blocks anymore right
because you can only get brown and red
mushrooms you can't get these these old
ones anymore I don't think so as we work
here today we've got to be very careful
no creepers blow it up and I don't hit
it with a pic or something like that but
the goal for today we are going to do do
that arena idea I thought about it some
more I looked at some of your comments
and I am pretty excited for it I think
it's going to turn out pretty good I
hope we will see I guess as we work on
it here okay so the very first step to
this we got to get in there probably I
made like a little platform to work off
of here but we'll probably want to do is
just like go up a little bit maybe a bit
more so we have a bit of room to work
here and what we'll do yeah maybe at
this level here we're going to have some
sticky pistons that come out is it too
dark for you guys let me turn on the
torch sticky pistons will come out and
the mobs will land on the floor that
pops out of the wall here and then we
also want to release some water on the
ground we're making here so that they
don't die when they hit it right and
we'll wash them off this way and they'll
fall down into a holding area probably
maybe we'll make them bunch up a little
bit too
and yeah I was thinking about it there's
actually a lot of flexibility with this
whole arena idea I've never made an
arena before well I should have maybe to
be careful how I phrase that I've made a
verina's or attempted to make arenas and
then servers always seem to get reset
for some reason I've never made a mob
arena before I should say so this is
going to be a fun challenge but yeah
like we can adjust the difficulty of it
the difficulty of it based on like what
Armour we're wearing
how many mobs we send through you know
we can give mobs armor we can buff them
with potions we can debuff ourselves
with potions you know what weapons were
using there's a lot of flexibility with
it and I think we can make it more or
less challenging depending on what we
want I'll use planks just so I know it's
a different block here all right so this
will pop out land on that above this
we're going to put dispensers with water
buckets I guess I don't know if I want
to do it all the way along I don't think
that's necessary let me figure out
exactly what water pattern we need here
they'll have to go in the very edges for
sure though
all right guys very good so we have the
first part of this done let me just show
you what I built up here and how it
works can I make it yes we made it good
so this is basically just a switching
system so that the mobs will either go
to the mob system and die or they'll
gets routed over to the right here into
the arena so that we can actually use
them to fight against basically you hear
them all they are right now just blocked
by the stone in the ceiling here I got
to remove that and let them free somehow
let me just show you how this works
before I do that though otherwise they
will fall into the water and then
root to the middle here and fall down
into another holding cell that we
haven't built yet but yeah we got a
button here press it once picks up the
water and the Pistons retract you see I
got a whole line of signs there as well
so the water doesn't have to flow all
the way to the bottom and just stops it
from updating press it again water comes
out and the Pistons extends so it's
pretty cool so the drop or not the
droppers the dispensers they take two
pulses to activate but the Pistons only
need like an on/off right so that's that
was a bit tricky I had to make a t
flip-flop here and right now the block
is out if we press it it pulls it back
Pistons retracts press it again and they
extend because it goes forward so it's
fairly simple and then I got another
wire running up here to the dispensers
dispensers are really annoying - I gotta
say I it's not enough that I was
powering them like I had this wired a
little different before I was actually
powering the dispensers but they weren't
activating I had to like power them and
give them a block update for them to
work so that's what the repeaters are
for just make a block updates and I
guess I gotta let these guys free this
will be fun Oh careful
all the while I don't want those
mushroom blocks to break on me oh that's
freaky
oh all right so we're gonna have a lot
of mobs here like it's not an issue for
sure don't shoot the creepers
oh I'm not I'm not gonna take that
chance actually if they shoot the
creepers I get it here they're going to
blow up down there whether I like it or
not oh man okay we got them all right so
that's good
I'm not going to switch this again until
I tune for until we get the holding cell
set up in the arena here so that's what
I'm going to work on next
actually let's figure out the shape of
the arena I was figuring might want to
do like a 21 block circle in diameter
maybe we'll just try lay that out a bit
let's move this over one two three four
five I'm going to leave a little bit of
space between this and the mushrooms and
I'll probably want to just put a layer a
stone here so if that creeper does blow
up they won't get rekt okay tell you
what guys you know what we're gonna do
we're gonna take a moment just just you
and me right now hey how's it going
today is a very special day guys very
special for you that's right
today is life-changing for you you know
why because I'm going to teach you a
very special joke today this is a lot
like the that's what she said
type a joke like that style it's a
different joke though this one is three
words and like that's what she said you
got to it's not a joke you go tell to
somebody okay it's a very unique joke in
that you have to wait for people or the
right circumstances to use it okay so
this is how it works you're with your
friends or your family grow maybe you
want to do it with on strangers whatever
whatever you like you walked into a
restaurant for example
and it's a new restaurant you've never
been to it you open the doors you go in
and there's a pretty good chance someone
in your group is gonna say oh oh
something smells good and then all you
gotta say is I just farted
and that's it boom you got them
they've already admitted to liking the
smell of your farts okay Oh something
smells good I just farted it's very
simple very effective and they say it
was such such joy in such satisfaction
Oh something smells good that when you
do that it's like a roller coaster you
take them from the top and you drop them
and yes is it is wonderful there you go
life-changing day for you use it use it
wisely my friends all right
this doesn't feel like I'm doing this
right I looked at a circle generator
site before I started this and I thought
the circle looked a little bit different
for some reason so I think I got the
dimensions wrong this is about the size
for our arena though I think that's good
we don't want it too big if you make
them too big what happens is you can
just like run around the edges and the
mobs can never catch up to you and I
want to try avoid that at this range we
can't really run away from skeletons
because I think they can shoot 16 blocks
this is a little bit bigger than that
but it would be pretty hard to avoid
getting totally hit you know that's
something they should change with this
game I feel like if they tried to change
things a while ago like the difficulty
scaled depending if you were on easy
medium or hard right they should make it
as you go from easy medium hard
the mobs get faster and if you're on hot
on hard like zombies are actually faster
than you so you can't run away um I
think that would be
that would actually make the game hard
like the mobs would be something you
can't just avoid them so I got a
question for you guys today what is your
least favorite thing to do in Minecraft
I asked you that because guess what I'm
doing right now my least favorite thing
I am mining some obsidian nether quartz
hunting is pretty low on my list but I
think this is even worse because it's so
boring oh my goodness
anyway so I'm gonna leave here I think
I'm up to about three stacks I hope not
quite darn it
let's let's see if that's enough
hopefully it is have I ever shown you
this I think I have this is my this is
the way my obsidian farm works what you
do you go through the portal here it's
on my timer so it closes behind you and
then when you go through again it'll
create a new portal and every time you
do that you get a new portal just bust
it and you get obsidian very cool I like
it
I've used it a lot actually but I for
some reason don't have my haste beacon
here I must have moved it just been
annoying so the what is the obsidian for
we're going to use it on the arena as
you could probably guess we're going to
try line the walls with it so if there's
creeper explosions and stuff we don't
have to worry too much so let's head on
back I did work out so what was wrong
with the circle not that it's actually a
circle this is minecraft yes I know oh
let me show you this - I never showed
you this so to get to the arena we're
probably going to have to go through
here they'll be like an intersection or
something and one of the branches will
go off this way there's some ravine here
and that is part of the potion farm over
there that's about it was there I'm
seeing it cobblestone there I'm
wondering if that's a spawner I don't
think it was
but yeah here is our circle so what I'm
going to do probably is just like have a
veneer in front of this maybe put the
city in here so you can't actually see
it but if a block gets blown up it's
only gonna be one thick you know but I
don't want to make the whole thing out
of obsidian because it looks terrible ah
that hurts one more block I didn't have
to mine all right
and then at each of these edges here
each of these it's probably where we're
going to release the mobs so we'll have
four four points to do that somehow we
have to get them to those spots evenly
if possible like where they fill up
evenly not exactly sure how to do that
so I couldn't wait guys we're gonna do a
fight already it I just want to try it
out I want to get an idea of how fast
they fill up the chamber here and and
how difficult is that kind of stuff so I
did make a release chamber this is it
and I think this is gonna work out
pretty good actually
I was gonna have like Pistons retract
from the ground at first or or fence
gates or something but like if I use
fence dude skeletons might shoot over
top of it at me or if I have Pistons
that retract downward or upward baby
zombies are going to fit through the one
tall gap er I don't know this this is
good here like when it's sideways is it
nothing can get you until you release it
and very simple so that's the way we're
doing it let's get up here and start
wait wait wait it's not closed is it
let's close it I haven't decided how
we're doing our arena fight yet there's
lots of different ways like we could do
it in waves where they sort of build up
for a while and then we we release all
the mobs and maybe as waves progress
through we we release more and more or
they get stronger that type of thing
we could do like a survival mode where I
try to kill as many as I tend before I
die and get like a point for each one we
could do like a Time Attack how many I
can kill on a certain amount of time
there's lots of different ways I haven't
decided which way we're doing it we're
gonna probably have a control room
somewhere is it nighttime now
I think it's nighttime guys or maybe
because I'm up higher here they're not
spawning now yeah we'll have a control
room that's where that button is going
to be so that we can turn the switch on
and off oh and I never put the water up
oh and I never close that I'm supposed
to put water there oops
think we're safe maybe it's not
nighttime I don't know I think it's
because I was up high they stopped
spawning
yeah but if we do a control room type of
thing we might be able to make several
different game modes and control it
there depending on what we want to do
alright so they're not moving in there
very quickly are they and it's
definitely not night I think they just
stopped spawning when I went up maybe
they're trying to get out all right
let's just let these guys out and see
what it's like
they all have armor is possibly not the
greatest first test oh and they're going
to be running around if we got creepers
that are about to explode forgot about
that okay I have pretty good armor on is
the thing and I get sword so if we tone
this down a bit it's going to be really
difficult can't already okay guys so
we're going to try this one more time I
waited a bit too long there's more mobs
there than I want but we'll see what
happens I guess what I really want to
test out now though is having some
obstacles on the course like some walls
to hide behind and use strategically so
we got a few of those and we'll just see
how that affects things later we'll
probably add traps and stuff to this -
like where maybe there's lava pits or or
maybe dispensers that shoots damage
potions out somewhere that heal the mobs
but kill me we'll see I made some stone
swords probably not the best in this
battle because there's more but I just
want to see how it goes whoa
probably shouldn't turn my back I missed
what happened when they got released
there oh this is no I'm switching to my
stone so all right I'm out of here
there's too many mobs too many mobs okay
oh oh please tell me that didn't blow up
twice I had a feeling it was too many
umm it was too many guys it was too many
I'm hoping I didn't blow up my stuff now
I'm a little scared I did try to put
some stuff in the chest like the
obsidian so I wouldn't lose that but my
tools my boots of the traveler I had
those on me okay they should be despond
says far away
they blew up my bed - I think our stuff
will be okay because the bed was pretty
far away okay they're not all gone oh
and I can't close it
look secret ability oh okay
let's let's close this and um oh he's
got my sword
well at least it won't be spawn now I'm
gonna just run in refresh and probably
die here
no don't Bluff oh oh come on this isn't
fair
guys I gotta figure out how to kill
myself I spawned in the ravine alright
this works and yeah see we got to treat
this like a super hostile map right now
you don't just keep running in and dying
you got to equip up and and take it on
properly here oh man they're in the
tunnel even just one please tell me
there's this one hate stuff is fine we
might have lost like a shovel or
something in that but for the most part
I think we did okay
that there should be a guy with my sword
around here
wonder where he went hmm where did he go
did you saw it that guy definitely took
my sword Dave got the boots of the
traveler we got my axe and power drill
and my shovel even we just got to find
the sword that's the only thing missing
did he figure out how to get out of here
I wonder I'm gonna be really sad if that
sword is gone oh you can try to hide my
friend but you you will be found got it
I think yeah we got it sweet well I
don't want any more of that guys so
we're tearing it down that's it
project failed no that might have looked
like a J oughta quest you guys I get
that it's pretty crazy but that was a
very effective test actually I could
tell from that even if there was only 20
mobs I think we would get overwhelmed
pretty much the same so what we got to
do is make it bigger I'm not so worried
about making it bigger now I think it'll
be okay we're gonna make it 30 blocks
this was about 20 we're gonna bump it up
to 30 if that's still not big enough
what I'm going to do is maybe start
adding a second layer to it like
vertically and I think that'll be okay
I really regret placing this obsidian
now because I had to tear it all down
um but yeah I think this is going to be
fun I think it's a good little arena and
once we polish it up we'll have a lot
more control over it the thing is I
don't want to lose the fight because I
got overwhelmed like that I want to lose
because I got whittled down type of
thing you know like I make mistakes I
take some damage not like
a million mobs and we can't do anything
about it that's not the way I want this
to work okay so check out guys I dug out
some more space here and we now have a
31 block diameter circle this feels
about right I don't think I would want
to any bigger so will well bounce the
game around this around the size I think
it's good while I was digging I did run
into something unfortunately this is the
tunnel from the man cave to the old
stronghold base and this you know out of
everything I've built in the man cave
this has probably been the most useless
I use it very little the idea was to to
build this sited woops move animals
between the two bases easily and if I
ever for some reason lost my nether
portal I could use it to but never
happened I never use it so it's not a
big deal if we just bump it to the left
a little bit put a bend in it or
something it's a low priority thing so
we won't worry about it too much but
anyways guys I think we're going to get
to the comment of the day for today
this one says maybe you could hold
different mobs in different cages and
the ability to give them strength etc
and your and give you slowness etc then
when you start it it blocks you in until
you have 20 rotten flesh or ten arrows
etc that's a lot of etc I think it would
be really cool and keep it keep it up
with the awesomely epic videos I'll
thank you very much I like this idea of
like getting locked in until you feed
something a certain number of rotten
flesh sure certain a number of mob drops
maybe we could use that for like rounds
if we're doing waves like maybe round
one lasts until I get 10 zombie flesh
feed it into a thing and then when we do
that we get a moment break and it'll
start storing up mobs again and
in that break we get maybe a reward like
some food or some arrows or health
potion that falls from the ceiling and
helps us to survive a bit longer for the
next wave and as we go through the waves
that keeps happening maybe we need more
each wave or something or the rewards
get less I don't know somehow we have to
have a tipping balance where it becomes
more and more difficult too but I like
that I think that's a cool idea I don't
think there's really much benefit to
separating the mobs I like them sort of
random and of course I like the potion
idea I think we'll do that too
now I was considering using pressure
plates maybe like once we have because
you can use these that detect I'm a mob
czar I think yeah the gold ones detect
up to 15 so I'm just one guy so that
only goes one signal if we have more
mobs oh I didn't know that that's
interesting you see what it's doing here
it only counts the statues one item I
think yeah it'll go up to two until they
combine but if we have a different item
they'll go up to two I didn't know that
I never use these these are like the
most useless thing in the game so that's
interesting but each of the mobs will be
separate so I think it will work for
them if we somehow incorporate this
which we might but anyway anyways guys I
hope you enjoyed today's episode a
little bit of a different style today I
like to sort of change things up a
little bit every now and then so let me
know what you thought of it today
and I'll see you again in the next one
take care have a good day bye bye
you