oh this is exciting
you guys know what day it is it is
update day today finally actually it was
yesterday but I had a sore throat and I
still have a sore throat but and I guess
by the time you watch this video it's
probably a few days ago but anyways
today for me is update day oh yeah so
we're gonna be we're gonna be updating
to 1.13 the ocean update three guys in
our let's play world what do we do
before every update though what is the
key we make a backup that's right back
up your worlds guys because I don't
think there's any going back once you
update to one point thirteen you can't
downgrade because there's a new world
formats in one point thirteen so if you
have any issues yeah you should have
made a backup just saying okay here we
go oh look at this this is kind of cool
small little feature but they actually
changed for the title screen so we got
like an ocean scrolling background now
what we got to do here for our let's
play world
we're gonna go to edits they added the
ability to optimize his world here so
what this does is it oh it tells us this
will attempt to optimize your world by
making sure all that is stored in the
most recent the game format this can
take a very long time depending on your
world once done your world may play
faster but will no longer be compatible
with older versions of the game are you
sure you wish to proceed even if we
didn't do this it wouldn't be compatible
with older versions yeah I know what I'm
doing alright so basically it goes
through the whole world and converts it
over to the new format instead of doing
it as we explore so hopefully things
aren't as laggy as we play here and it's
gonna take a bit of time so I'll be back
in a bit uh-huh so you know with this
part of that big guys you you might be
like oh I want to play what's this sucks
I gotta wait so long just think of it as
an intermission sort of thing like go
take a bathroom break make yourself some
tea some coffee I just got myself some
he-here maybe you're one of those hot
chocolate minorities out there or apple
cider 's you know whatever floats your
boat just get your get your snacks get
your drinks you know get settled in
because you're gonna be playing for
hours and it gives you plenty of time to
do that
still got I still got lots of time here
well we are in guys it's finished we're
on 1.13 officially now so let's do this
right
if you don't know whenever a new update
comes out what I like to do just for
like an episode or two is this goof
around a bit check out the new mechanics
see how old mechanics have changed I do
intend on building an ocean base here
soon but that's probably gonna be in a
few episodes so what's the best way of
seeing how mechanics have changed it's
by checking out everything that's broken
right so what I like to do is just ya
can't you can't use mushroom blocks
anymore as fuel I like to just go test
things out and see if they work anymore
and figure out what we need to do to fix
them if possible and did the denote
bucks play I don't even notice oh yeah
they did I got my sound really quite
apparently oh yeah it should be it yeah
we go there we go so we'll test out a
few things together here one of the
things that always scares me is the
pop-up sheep farm anything involving
water and this update is gonna be
terrifying and this involves water and
life
if the water fails it kills the Sheep
like if it if it lingers and they don't
go down or something they're gonna all
drown oh there's a float now wait a
minute that was weird okay I think it's
still still about the same though
different effect like they float up now
before I think they would kind of stay
in place interesting this is work
I think that's working the collection
system and their pearls are fine can the
door open door still opens door still
closes okay we're on a good good track
here I specifically saw one comment that
said my mini firms are gonna be broken
in the man cave we have like three or
four of them so it seems you can't plant
crops in dark spots anymore which is
what we use to harvest them so yeah
oh these are in blue now the text these
are still white is it to stall all named
items
I guess that's cool yeah so if we want
to make mini firms from now on we needed
an another way of harvesting them
besides darkness then check out the
cactus farm here you'll just kind of
float in there you know you're supposed
to sink now you're supposed to sink now
there you go okay oh you strapped - oh
he did like a swirl down the down the
tube there okay let's see any cactus
falling oh there goes one did it fall
down I think it did
Oh oh no it's still there it's still
there okay so yeah items float on water
now so the tried true and tested cat
this farm from the Alpha days is finally
broken wah wah or we just gotta get rid
of the rim here one or the other if we
want to try fix it all good so this mini
farm should be broken can't plant
anything yeah so we're gonna be seeing a
lot of stuff that's broken here but keep
in mind we have hundreds of things built
in the world so don't get all like doom
and gloom on me here until I start going
doom and gloom okay guys so this one's
gonna be broken - yeah it uses darkness
as well this is another mini farm we
have but this one I think should be fine
cuz this one the first ones we made
which still use pistons to harvest yep
still good still good old plastic still
works this is an interesting one so this
uses water and it has mushrooms in
darkness do you think the mushrooms died
is the water gonna push them properly
let's find out on this episode we'll
have Ethos let's play worlds we've
discovered new recipes oh goodie I just
finished learning all the recipes now
gonna learn them all again at 1.13 oh
joy
hmm Oh weird they fell through well I
think they're from a higher level though
oh yeah there's gunpowder up here too
huh
so there should be like slabs over the
water here celebs don't shoot out
is it worth fixing I think I will it's
it's a simple thing to change oh I know
what's wrong oh this is interesting so
look at the items here they're like
bouncing back and forth now they're on
this side kind of weird it looked like a
block was missing here is like why is a
block missing wait a second and then I
realized the glow stones over here they
changed it so water is more transparent
now so before it would like knock out
three levels of lights but the problem
is with underwater bases they looked
really dark so they made water basically
like any other block and as a result I
think this glow stone from here melted
the ice that was here which didn't do
that before it cuz is underwater let's
check out the cow farm here this uses
water so it has a chance of being broken
where's the switch over here Oh looking
good I mean this didn't work before but
I'm still gonna try it could you imagine
if like everything breaks but the each
road starts working again for some
reason now it's it's a sunken boat you
can't hop in it still good
oh maybe it's just some if it's on a
certain tick then they all pop off
hop on again that time it popped
okay interesting I'm sure there's a way
to still get this to work I wonder that
might mean that the rails are finally
fixed because this has bothered me for a
long time so before if you try to to
move this rail and the block at the same
time it would always pop off but as we
saw with the grass there the blocks are
moving but the grass wasn't popping off
okay I thought they they fixed the
glitch er there made something nicer
yeah even on the retraction what if we
do it like this
nope I am so happy guys one of my big
concerns with the update was they were
not gonna change the water and it didn't
matter like all the new features they
add to the underwater it would still
look terrible but they actually changed
the water so we don't have the ugly deep
blue stuff anymore it's still pretty
blue but it's it's definitely more
transparent and I think it looks a lot
better and it depends on what biome
you're into so this is forest but I
noticed like even looking through the
waterfall here you can see the torches
on the other side so but it's not like
super bright or anything either so I
think that's cool I think it has a nice
effect like even over here I think this
looks better over here now with the new
water color I did like light this for
the darker water with it not being able
to pass light through as well before so
you really notice like glowstone
underneath it so that should probably be
changed under water you got the cool
sounds right it's crystal clear alright
it still can look dark though like the
ground looks start here but our visions
not really blocked by the darkness of
the water or anything so I like that I
think it's a good a good trade-off the
river here it did update by the way so
any water blocks that you made with ice
and thawed and then we're like floating
those all have
updated there's no way around it so the
river we've we went a long time without
accidentally updating its or having some
plants spread and causing a tough date I
went without using frost Walker boots
for so long because I was afraid this
river was gonna update but it finally
has I don't think it's too bad right we
hardly see it anyways and as a result I
can finally wear frost Walker and not
worry about triggering this so that's
good
the vine farm oh you guys are worried
about the lion farm aren't you it still
works guys it still works
ah yeah we got a brown mushroom the mini
mushroom farm is still in business guys
so I had another comment saying that the
nether wart farms can be broken like the
water the water system I'm not really
sure why so I guess let's just do a
harvest and see what happens oh that
looks really different doesn't it the
swamp water color oh I guess they're
gonna gather in the middle but they
should drop right oh yeah well we done
before the water disappears and then I
have water streams there so I wonder if
that's gonna be an issue it's gonna go
into the collection system is this still
on the timer or is it not retracting Oh
oh they made it to the collection system
so they're going in there
oh is this a really long time so I guess
I got it timed for like talent you
staked another work to to get through
the middle before but now that they
float on the water and don't drag along
the soul sand the timing on there can be
shortened by a lot oh man
I'm scared this is a doom and gloom
situation guys if the lava Vader doesn't
work I'm gonna scream doom and gloom
everything is over let's play world is
dead I'll just edit that out of the
video oh man really I did not expect
that wait a minute why is it that well I
got all the Pistons not going at all oh
did you gain weight is that the problem
you can't push you up anymore oh I know
what it is I know it is no clocks are
moved by slime blocks now right so I
gotta change these that's simple that's
an easy fix
wait a minute I guess I missed this one
you get the mushroom stems now oh that's
so cool we got a new block in the game I
had no idea oh I love that I love this
texture a lot I'm gonna be using that a
lot I'm sure I just testing out the
mushroom firm it's still good
oh and it gets better guys we have the
interior texture again too so if you put
two of these side-by-side and then break
one of them it keeps the texture now
that's that's a great way of doing it
and it works on the stems too Oh what
like it I like it we can still crawl
with the lighter wings back to the
mushrooms look at the underside of the
brown ones I think they used to always
be brown right now we got the inside
texture form just a subtle thing also
look how close this texture is to oak
wood it's weird for some of these things
I know they're different I'm just not
quite sure how like I know this is
different is that they added sounds to
the harvesting or something I'm not sure
still works the same but the the effect
when they get harvested is different
there
kind of some bubbles down there mm-hmm
no water with this farm so I'm assuming
it's fine still oh yeah they're all
falling through Oh cuz the note blocks
are getting moved Oh didn't realize I
use note blocks on that small change
nothing big oh I did something the
generator storix what about the farm oh
yeah
silverfish farm still works as far as
the farm itself
good right yeah I'm actually pretty
curious about this one cuz I tried it in
one of the snapshots and it didn't work
they like shot through the sand
it still doesn't work okay it doesn't
chew through the sand though it just
doesn't like the sand it's shooting
fireballs at the bottom of the sandwich
that's scared me which would ignite the
top right but I guess that's not a thing
anymore oh they're here they're here
finally yes I've been trying not to
sleep because I want to see them
the Phantom's guys we got phantoms one
two I see two of them
these killed us in that one series
hardcore Hermits or whatever and I just
wanted to see like how do you actually
deal with them because I still don't
know oh forget about them it's the other
moms that are me trouble here oh look at
them all do you see that he went like
straight up after he hit me boom what
helps they're not really like targeting
me too much here he comes here he comes
maybe slowly eventually okay he hit me
and then he slowly retreated
those two are duking it out now there's
more phantoms the longer you wait though
right like the more nights you don't
sleep
hey you wonder if I can chase him like
in the air oh that hurt oh oh I can't
get him he said he's on fire he's
burning you see that oh he died what
that's not because it turned day is it
oh no there's another guy he's still
here so that one did actually die Oh
Oh nope nope it's all good it's all good
he's on fire too though
it's weird they make this sound like
they're right by you even though they're
not
oh he's burning in the daylight don't
you do it so so far I'm actually pretty
happy guys I was really worried about
what I was gonna find going around the
world here today and so far like most of
stuff there's quite a few things broken
but most of them is just like change a
couple blocks or add a couple blocks
it's less than an hour two's work
probably for everything we found so far
with the exception of the mini firms
those are broken but we'll probably
disagree redesign the new one anyways
now the one thing I am very worried
about is the Nexus cuz the water streams
are broken here that's something that
could potentially take quite a quite a
while to fix oh boy do we do we try or
do we forget the Nexus exists we better
try I don't know if I have a spot for
these in there actually we'll see what
happens now I hear I'm I hear I'm where
they going
okay there you're going up there let's
go check it out see what's happening
here
looking good so far that's what they're
supposed to do I think the next
potential area where it could break is
over here where they fall down I think
it's fine guys whoo yeah look at the
swamp water it's so much more clear you
can see the sand and dirt so easily
through it now it does look good though
I think I like it all right you still
got the blue patches where it's a little
bit deeper so it's pretty cool so the
super smelter I don't think it's broken
but of course as we saw we can't use
mushroom blocks as the
you all anymore so we'll have to switch
over to planks or something instead
which means I gotta empty all the fuel
out of the furnaces which will probably
take me 5-10 minutes to do another kind
of annoying thing but it's not a big
deal looks like we still got pumpkins
flowing down there that's a good sign
now we just finished this farm I didn't
know that the mushroom boxing was gonna
be changed right
I think this farm will still work its
usefulness though is another question
it's not nearly as useful if we can't
use it for fuel but we can still
manufacture brown mushroom blocks and I
guess this texture - and the stems and
yeah the brown mushrooms like it for
fermented spider eyes and stuff so it's
got some value still but I won't need to
use it as much as before probably first
to grow the one thing that could be
broken here is the collection system
let's give that a shot so they all flow
to the middle and they do go down that's
good still fine then oh here comes the
clay does it get picked up I think it
got picked up
yeah it's getting picked up just making
sure with the Nexus that the hoppers are
actually grabbing the items - and it
looks like they're clays going into here
like it's supposed to
[Applause]
okay so the firework system still works
the same but it is a lot more laggy that
used to be I'm getting like really low
framerate right now from the redstone
running below yeah so maybe I'll mention
that as well as far as like optimization
goes I think I'm getting a slightly
lower frame rate than 1.12 but there's
no jitters or anything which is which is
good
no like choppy frame rates and I think
at night time I've noticed the tick rate
might be a bit low maybe from some issue
with the pet the mob pathfinding but I'm
not sure but overall it's not too bad
not too bad and is this is just the
release after the game release usually
they have a couple more batches and they
optimize things further so I'm not too
worried about that
last farm for us to try out here I think
is the core Street farm ooh big leg
that's normal it's normal are the items
gonna overshoot the water they're gonna
get stuck I'm not sure they do move like
so much faster
I like that like when you're harvesting
things now normally it has to drag your
grip across the ground but now it's just
like super fast on all the firms yeah
it's fine it's all good
all right everybody so that's probably
all the troubleshooting we need to do
here I did some off-camera as well of
course in like the the mob systems fine
and most other things probably miss some
stuff but overall I'm very happy with
the results I expected a lot worse to be
honest and yeah it's not gonna take me
long to fix things so I'm happy about
that usually like I I do the snapshots
in the let's play world but this update
I had to wait for it to finish so we're
like getting it all at once here and
unfortunately like all the
troubleshooting is taking up most
episode so I'm gonna try get another
episode out soon where we actually play
with the new features like we didn't do
anything with bubble streams today or
anything that's gonna be in the next one
try find an ocean biome but there is one
thing we can test really quicker that is
pretty excited about I saw in the patch
notes that like zombies in that they
synced in water and they they turn into
drowned mobs right but apparently the
undead horses also sink in the water so
I'm really hoping they made it where you
can ride horses underwater would be so
cool oh did I hop off I hopped off okay
she sinks really slow but you can ride
them you can actually ride them
underwater oh my goodness this has been
my dream forever
we got sufferings in the game definitely
gonna be using this he's kind of slow
though isn't he mm-hmm
it just kind of floats there though he
doesn't sink down very fast like I'm am
I on the ground yet no if I'm on the
ground now I am here the clippity-clop
so we got a zombie down here still not
drowning I can't tell I thought the
bubbles are all gone but maybe what is
happening like I'm not drowning is it
cuz I'm on the horse or is there still
one left there I see the last one poppin
I think maybe yeah I'm drowning now okay
interesting alright I think that's
really cool oh he converted do they swim
to their the swimming animation nope
nope just us okay yeah and I haven't I
actually haven't seen the new
enchantments like the is it vorpal or or
Riptide or something so I'm pretty
excited about that I think it's like you
throw the weapon and you go with it if I
understand that right
but I haven't seen it so lots of stuff I
want to check out should be a lot of fun
anyways guys that's gonna do it for
today's episode how did your World's
Fair that's my question to you did you
just start a new world or did you keep
your old one if you kept your old one
did you have a lot of stuff break let me
know in the comments I'm curious but as
far as our comment of the day this was
by far the most common suggestion
because we were working on the ice farm
last time and will continue that don't
worry very soon here but it says echo
for the ice farm you could use something
like an armor stand with frost Walker
boots to really speed up the freezing
process the number one like suggestion
guys I'm gonna show you is the yeah so
we got silk touch rights the thing is
frost Walker ice is different than
normal ice you can't actually harvest it
it just disappears and then though the
waters gone there it can reflect Ordo so
it's a good idea right but unfortunately
it doesn't work okay this should work
now right I've done this like once when
they came out but I haven't done it
since yeah it's the motion it's the
motion that does it haha we got a fish
you just spawned in the water guys and
you get fish when you kill them oh man
that's so cool
cook salmon anyways that's gonna do it
for today guys we'll put the new stuff
in the next one hope you enjoyed today's
episode regardless though and until then
thanks for watching hope you have a
wonderful day take care bye bye
you
[Music]