hello everybody this is etho and we are
in the end rites now guys something very
bad is probably about to happen how do I
explain this some a very odd situation
has occurred you see this this pillar
where my mouse is is highlighting right
now that is a gravel pillar I was on top
of that looking at all the Enderman one
of them decided to take a block out of
that pillar which caused a chain
reaction where all the gravel blocks
fell down and since I was at the top
there I fell down as well but I glitched
into the block on the side and started
falling down basically I am on my way
down to the ground now with every
Enderman in the world and mad at me
let's see what happens I think you see
the gravels propagating up there okay
are they chasing me are they chasing me
they are definitely chasing me okay so
what I'm gonna have to do since I can't
fight them I did bring water we'll try
we'll try survive here I don't think the
water oh man did they grab the horse
fruit no that what the water hit the
course fruit doesn't happen yeah the
water doesn't da grow them anymore is
the other problem so this has gotten
quite interesting not exactly sure what
to do here this is terrifying no okay I
ended up just killing them off with the
sword here it took a little bit of time
but wasn't too bad hey you stand on the
last guy got him alright let me show you
what I saw when I pillar it up it was
pretty cool actually
okay it's starting to happen so you see
the Enderman quickly spawning in and D
spawning as we
higher up here is there in the automatic
despawn range now some of them
oh no we're totally out of it okay let's
go down a little bit more we want
something to stick around yeah they're
starting to stick around at the bottom
there so then what you do you look at
them all which is pretty easy to do
that's it it's really weird it's like
you got all these black dots like trying
to attack this tower it's kind of cool
all right guys so I thought today it
might be a good idea to do a channel
updates let you guys know what's going
on as we go look around for a fortress
here and I've never tried like flying
around the end with the lighter wings so
we'll see how this goes
hopefully we find a fortress pretty
quick here and we can go explore it but
yeah a lot of you guys have been
wondering where is TFC where's modded
minecraft what's going on and I figure I
should probably fill you in so this has
been a bit of a rough week for me to be
honest
had a little bit of trouble I first it
started with me trying to record Terra
Firma craft and that did not go so well
I recorded like half an episode decided
to scrap it I wasn't happy with how it
turned out and honestly I think we
should probably and that series which
don't really like saying cuz it was it
was going well and I know a lot of you
guys still liked watching it was getting
good views and all that but as as the
series goes on it becomes harder and
harder because we're kind of at the
endgame now and I've had trouble
recording last few episodes this last
one in particular did not go well oh why
how did I jump like that that was crazy
yeah didn't go so well because I didn't
really know what to do in it so I
decided to do some building I'm trying
to build the house and it didn't turn
out very well I spent like hours
gathering resources and tried building a
house didn't like how it looked I wanted
to tear it down and then if I tore it
down I was
back at the beginning like what I do for
this episode I try build a house again
dry my di look better
the problem was there's not really a lot
of building options in Terra Firma craft
like not a lot of different blocks
there's no automation either like you
can there's not really Pistons so as far
as N gamed terraformer craft it's not
the greatest I would rather like play
vanilla or modded there's a lot of
metalworking stuff but that gets pretty
pretty boring and if I just kept playing
it would get very repetitive so I think
I think it's a good idea to end that
unfortunately
moving on then I tried recording a
modded episode and that once again had
technical problems if you followed me on
Twitter you would have saw that got it
fixed up today though I direwolf got me
into contact with the guy that's in
charge of forestry he helped me out
figuring out what I needed to update to
get it all working and it seems to be
good now
alright guys I found a fortress these
things are so rare Oh
like I had to go to 3,000 before I got
one it's very important we don't die
here and we need to get a spare set of
wings that's the main reason we came
here in case I do die eventually I don't
want to oh hey why was that chest popped
or let me go down please yeah they
popped the chests somehow uh yeah but
you guys the other thing that happened
this week is I got tonsillitis it only
lasted for like three days oh so it
wasn't too bad actually but yeah I
wasn't really able to record during that
it's very difficult to like talk and
swallow when you have tonsillitis oh
this is not how it's supposed to work
this this chest is popped - what that's
got to be a glitch right all the chests
or pops all right let's fly on over to
that boat and get get our wings I guess
I would very much like to find like a
mending book as well mending and frost
Walker I still need oh man - sure
actually
all right let's check this baby out got
the bruise stand with the instant health
may as well take that and what is ours
our prize here let's good sound soak
touch efficiency three all right
oh no books oh wait wait that has has
frost Walker on oh yes success I've
wanted that for so long
finally got some it goes up to frost
Walker three though right
mmm we'll have to try those out it's a
bird it's a plane no it's eat so flying
high in the sky it's so alright guys so
I must have mixed up my coordinates or
something and positive and negatives are
probably wrong I can't find the portal
to go back to the main island so we're
gonna attempt the best jump we're gonna
fly off this way the main island should
be this direction about seven hundred
blocks diagonally right definitely
should be doable let's see if we can
make it we are flying we're not fine
that's how you check okay good this is
so freaky though cuz we can't see a
thing but at zero zero should be the
main island oh oh we oh I was looking
way too far down just about went a
little bit too low yeah that's one way
of getting back if you can't find the
portal if you get lost or mixed up if
you know if you fly you don't make
bridges and stuff so you lose landmarks
you make it a bit tricky too
find your way if you didn't keep track
of your coordinates properly like I did
there all right but we're back we got a
spare set of wings and the frost
Walker's okay so the good news is we
actually did get mending as well the bad
news is it's on the Iron Boots oh and a
waist I'm gonna I'm gonna keep them
though it might they might be pretty
decent actually that's my first time
getting mending and frost Walker I've
never even tried for us to Walker in
creative yet so I I just let's give it a
try here I've seen some videos of it
though yeah and then it's it starts
melting or is it melting or breaking
because it has like cracks in it right
whoa
so how small does oh it actually all
disappears oh so you need the motion and
you can't swim apparently did you not
jump out of the water with them oh you
can you can there is that because I have
my wings on these are about to break by
the way I better fix them okay if you go
in yeah you can jump up if you don't
have the wings on so it's the wings that
we're giving me trouble there oh and if
you jump yeah then you fall in the water
okay yeah let's let's try out a couple
mechanics here guys I'm wondering how
some things work like the lily pads oh
it doesn't turn to ice I thought it did
okay wait there's a when you go on lily
pads you go up a block a little bit
don't you yeah we're at sixty three
point zero then you go up to point zero
nine three really the other thing I want
to try is does it work with boats can we
have our super speedboats ah darn it's
because the boats still do that thing
where they they move fast on ice
I just not though I told somebody in the
comments you could but it it looks like
the effect is canceled when you're in
the boats oh so you have to be above the
water is what it looks like
and when you're in a boat you're a
little bit below yeah we're at sixty two
point zero seven and on the ground here
we're at 63 so you have to be at 63 to
trigger the effect it looks like or
higher right because if we're on a lily
pad it still works too right can we
place lily pads on this ice you can't
okay I see I thought I saw pictures
where the lily pads were frozen like
that boat whoa what's happening when I
placed one of those lily pads it broke
somehow okay here's what we're trying to
do though we're gonna move around on
these lily pads and see if it makes the
ice cuz we're a little bit above sixty
three point zero right I'm curious I
don't know it still has the effect so if
we're above by a bit it still works yeah
so check this out guys I wanted to see
exactly how the frost Walker works so I
got some snow slabs from the man cave
there pay attention to our height here
so we're it's sixty 3.875 we're still in
the sixty three block range right
it creates ice if we go up one more slab
into the sixty-four then it stops so
it's the full range from 63 to to less
than 64 that it creates ice if we go
down below the water and also drop down
to sixty two point eight seven five and
no longer creates the ice because we're
below the water so you got to be at the
water height or above it's no more than
a block all right I want to see now what
happens if we put a boat on here let's
grab our boat okay since you sink down a
little bit in the boat yeah
think it's working right did it just
make that nicer was that there before oh
it's not working I don't think it's
working
no darn it so maybe it just doesn't work
in a boat I guess that makes sense right
it's Frost Walker not frost Rider all
right let's try place rails on this now
it can't place rails of any kind
oh no yeah it doesn't look like it
okay I thought maybe you could create
floating rails nah doesn't look like it
though I also wanted to try the
armorstand thing apparently you can put
the boots on the armor stand and it
still activates the effect did it just
eat my boots or oh I put them on how do
you do you have to shift you know I
never use armor stands yeah you got a
shift okay and then you gotta make it
move
yeah you got me to move okay so that
works what happens if we put this armor
stand in a boat well good I missed do
you not oh yeah you got to push it into
it when you're not in the boat right
yeah mom
oh you can't I pick up farmer stands in
a boat you might not be able to okay so
it seems like the effect is triggered
whenever you walk into a new block so
right now if you look at our Zed we're
at seven seven seven point eight seven
zero we can move around within this
block nothing happens it's not till we
cross the border into the next block so
we're at point nine and then new block
automatically triggers of the effect
okay so I found out a few more things
here so we can't freeze water if if
there's water or ice above it so we
infuse this top one but we can't freeze
the one below it even if we go on the
proper level to do it and the flowing
water doesn't freeze it
either also I did not realize this but
the light level matters with this frozen
ice frozen ice with this new special ice
so because it's nighttime now it doesn't
saw it it stays frozen like this until
the Sun comes up or if we put down like
a torch or something some other light
source then it'll start melting it or
breaking it
I think it's breaking it it's not
actually melting it right oh man you
guys have to be really careful though if
you do this if you switch all the water
to this special ice when day comes it's
gonna leg your server or your game
incredibly because it all has to thaw
out and update at the same time oh this
is gonna be bad oh no I'm fine it
happens all the time so I have some bad
news if you guys thought a frost Walker
is a great way of getting rid of
unwanted water like this pond here if I
want to remove it let's turn it to ice
and then you can break it nice and easy
right no unfortunately not it has a much
longer breaking time than normal ice you
can't instant break it's this is
efficiency 5 with haste to the fastest
you can get so no easy easy to make
Guardian farms or anything you still
have to remove the water the hard way
now probably one of the coolest things
you can do with the frost Walker
enchantment is activate redstone devices
so I want to show you guys how you can
how you can go about doing that I'm
gonna try a cup a switch to our gate
here probably the best place to put the
water is in the middle so I decided to
put it underneath the wood on this side
so right at this block is what I want to
freeze this is a double check if there's
water there let's put on our frost
walkers I think I double-checked frost
Walker 2 is the maximum according to the
wiki will it activates
you got to walk right up to it though it
looks like mmm oh yeah and that's the
other thing if we do this we probably
want to put glowstone next to it
otherwise it won't melt you know yeah
this is in such a dark spot that it's
not melting uh-huh all right let's try
this again so if we walk up to the gate
like this
yeah it doesn't activate we have we
would have to be in the middle and it's
only when I walked into this block here
unless I'm closer on this side mmm the
range is actually not that great is it I
could put it underneath this block that
would probably work a lot better but it
won't work so well before coming from
the other side unless I put one under
here too okay on second thought there's
redstone right underneath this pillar
that's not gonna work so well I'm gonna
just put it in the middle here just to
show you guys how to do this if you if
you want to hook one of these up
basically you want to put in a T flip or
I'm a t bud switch it's a bud switch
that's a T flip-flop basically and
they're pretty simple to build a
redstone dust down here sticky piston
redstone block okay
and then what do we do guys I'm
forgetting I think you gotta go redstone
torch then over here and then a repeater
goes in here somewhere I build a lot of
things off of memory and that's not
always the best thing is my memory sucks
yeah I think you do it like that okay so
then you put your repeater here now any
time this this piston gets an updates it
switches alright so when the water
freezes it extends and when it unfreezes
and retract so it's a complete cycle
sort of thing get our water over here
and now I'm gonna hook up
a wire from this to our main starting
device here I think I got to connect it
to this wire over here and then it
triggers all this stuff over here all
right all right so check it out guys we
got it all installed so now when we walk
up the water freezes you do have to get
kind of close if I had more space for
redstone I would have done a little bit
nicer but it does work so the gate opens
I made the wire run underneath here to
the hopper timer up there basically it
goes up with a torch over there seems to
do the trick
and whoa I did one of those crazy jumps
again so yeah I got to figure out how to
do those Lister really needs I've been
practicing but I can't quite figure it
out it's like it's not like when you hit
the ground is it Oh
because you can actually trigger the
glider wings if you just fall one block
like that but I can't get it to do one
of those weird hops afterwards yeah I
don't know maybe you got a hit space
rate as he hit the ground oh that was
crazy
I think that was this a normal jump
though they looked it looked weird cuz
of our our perspective whoa
I don't know there's some trick to it
yeah I'm gonna seal this up and
oh I made a mistake
it does not freeze if any block is over
it's right not just water all that sucks
okay well Dern aha sorry about that guys
a little bit of an oversight on my parts
that's why we were doing that testing
before to figure out the mechanics and I
I still miss some things apparently so I
moved it over to behind this pillar and
we have air above it now that's what you
need you need air above the water test
it out it'll make it easier to activate
it from the side it should still be
possible to activate it from this side
too I would think if we stand in that
corner but it's not a not a perfect
thing I mostly did this just to show you
guys how to do it though if you want to
activate things with frost Walker it's a
bit trickier to hide it than I thought
though because you need that air block
but still still possible one thing I'm
gonna have to be very very careful about
guys is this river here I can't wear
frost Walker anywhere near it because
it'll cause it to update and then it's
gg there's no way of like recreating
this now which is what the comment of
the day is about so let me let me get to
that we're gonna wrap it up here for
today it says etho if you're going to
play in 1.9 I thought you might find
some of these more obscure changes
interesting especially that any floating
water sources in your world might be
ruined
aha so there's a i I've seen this
comment a few times I thought maybe I'd
clear up a misconception about it so now
when you when when ice thaws you used to
be able to have like floating water
sources in the world
yeah that where frost Walker these fries
by the way they don't thaw out because
there's no lighting nearby to do it but
yeah you can't create floating water
anymore it automatically updates now
when it's Oz out but that only applies
to walk to ice that you melt now so any
pre-existing floating water I have in my
world is fine it's perfectly fine ice
like I have that floating water bridge
at the amplified base that is still
there that did not get updated but I
can't recreate that or I can't recreate
this river now because that mechanic is
gone so if this ever updates I can't I
can't fix it so let's try not to ever
mess with this uh-huh
all right guys I'm gonna say goodbye to
you for today thank you for watching
have a wonderful day and I'll see you in
the next one
oh yeah and give me ideas for the next
project we do because we finished up
that tree firm we're open to work on
something else now so what do you want
me to work on next let me know all right
take care bye bye