[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back once again to
another episode of the let's play series
so today we are starting off in the
swamp here because I had the idea I
wanted to try build a mushroom house so
here it is over here guys
I finally got enough nether wart block
saved up we could actually build some
more here just to build this I think
took seven or eight harvests a tower
another word farm that big farm we built
like these blocks are so hard to get cuz
they're nine nether word each oh yeah
you can't uncraft them either anyway so
this is the the house I came up with I
thought of course the reason you guys
watch me is for my interior design you
come here for the tips and tricks right
so let's get to it
I don't think I've actually ever
interior designed anything in this
series before so this should be fun what
I want to do let's do exterior first
actually I wanted to put some red glass
windows on this thing is this a tiny
little house here I thought I'd try
build has a fun little challenge I think
it turned out okay though just needs the
finishing touches and then it's done
here alright so I'm gonna put windows
there windows here oh yeah one more
window up there I think that's it
alright yeah that looks pretty cool
alright I like that I like that's okay
so I think we're gonna go down a block
just so we get a little bit more space
now I know every single one of you
watching have made this mistake in your
life before it's like you build your
mushroom house and you think oh we're in
the swamp it's dark it's spooky I need
to use dark wood flooring wrong this is
why you watch the interior decorating
master this is your house this is where
you go to get away from the swamp you
want it nice and inviting plus the house
is white you should use a color clothes
and matching with that white color
what a better choice than Birchwood
here's another key thing people miss
about their home it doesn't matter how
wonderful and beautiful you make it look
after a long day of killing slimes out
in the swamp when you return to your
home at nights you are going to hate it
absolutely hate it unless you have
something to do in your home you need
activities as well so what better
activity what could be more relaxing
than sitting sitting down and reading a
book enjoying a story
maybe clipping the the branches off your
bonsai tree or what other activities we
have got to be something in this box
brewing yes of course maybe making
yourself a cup of tea or something yes
wonderful I got one last final tip for
you guys to finish up our interior
decorating series here but this is
probably the best advice you will ever
hear in your life
fireplace uh-huh every small cozy home
needs a cozy fireplace it makes sense
right seems obvious but let me tell you
something a lot of people they're gonna
be like Etha what are you crazy you
barely have room to sit down in that
house and you want to add a giant
fireplace to it but they don't see the
value in it let me tell you something as
nice as your home is eventually you're
gonna want to upgrade right you want you
go you're gonna want something bigger
and random house fires are very hard to
explain to insurance companies but a
house with a fireplace in well accidents
happen free upgrade that's right okay so
no dragon there we go light our fire I
don't know if this will actually burn
something let's let's count this one
two three four I think this wood might
catch on fire up there I can get rid of
this torch and just for good insurance
here let's put a carpet right by the
fire yeah we don't actually want the
place to burn down just yet but just
when we want to upgrade so until then we
can just play some string up here
because it's not flammable I think we
need three more pieces yeah three more
pieces so if we do this I don't think
that'll burn now because it travels one
two three four blocks above one block
below and one block all around so I
think that's fireproof now although that
looks kind of dumb doesn't it maybe I
should use something else anyways so
this is just about done we got ourselves
an upstairs here I think it's very nice
it's very nice we can get some pictures
in and we don't really have room for a
closet or anything so I think I'll just
do that and we'll call it good here all
right I put one picture downstairs here
and we're pretty much out of space so
we're gonna call that good I'm happy
with that okay so this should be
interesting
I got something kind of prepped here
while building the mushroom houses
trying to think what should we do with
our swamp biome how can we make it look
better because we're doing that biome
enhancement thing where we take our
biomes our swamp our desert our plains
and forests and stuff and try to make
them look cooler than their defaults and
with a swamp here like we've done the
mushroom thing we've just added a
mushroom house I think those are cool I
would like to add a few more mushrooms
to this and I thought like even if we
add mushrooms and change out the ground
and add some decorations it's still
gonna feel pretty empty I think so I'm
gonna try something a little bit more
crazy here I would like to have like 30
custom trees 20 blocks tall and
spreading throughout the whole biome
here but good luck building 30 custom
trees and survival right there's no way
the copy trees
so I'm gonna try a cheese method here
which will still take quite a bit of
time but I think it should be
interesting I want to make a fake canopy
that looks like a real canopy if you
know what I mean so birch trees they
they are 5 by 5's right so we want to
place them every 4 blocks here I got to
think of a better way of counting maybe
can I use the f3 would that make this
easier so we're at 23 1 2 3 4 5 it would
be every 5 right yeah so 28 whenever
it's at 3 or 8 on the x-coordinate
that's when I place a sapling that makes
that easy ok so basically all I'm gonna
do is plant the bunch of saplings up
here and I'm gonna let them grow
naturally if any don't grow I'll come by
with some bonemeal and that'll be our
first step to this if it ends up looking
terrible I did make a backup before I
started this so we can just undo any
changes if this really doesn't look good
afterwards cuz I'm not really sure how
it's gonna turn out here all right and I
think when I start the next row here I
don't know if I'll put them like
side-by-side with each other that would
be easier but I think I'll try staggered
them instead so let's start instead of
starting like right here maybe let's
like move it over a couple blocks that's
it at 0 and 5 ok so some time has passed
here and our trees have grown for the
most part there's still a couple missing
and as you can see it's pretty much
fills up the whole whole area there's
just the odd block between the trees
that I need to fill in and as I suspect
it it doesn't really look super super
good just yet right so there's gonna be
several steps to doing this and we're
just doing it on a small section to try
it and if it looks good here then we'll
like expand on this about 2 or 3 maybe 4
times but basically what I got to do now
is go
through this chop down the trees and I'm
ascared of of chopping down too much any
that didn't grow I got a bone meal and
you can see they kind of grow at various
Heights too so it's gonna hopefully let
make it look a bit more staggered be
good okay so check it out so this is
what it looks like now that we've
removed the the tree trunks kind of the
nighttime a view of it right now let's
go to sleep
yes let's sleep oh you know I got to
show you this in the house let's not
sleep out there the bed here is really
glitched out it's kind of funny if we
sleep in here ba boom ba boom ba boom
[Laughter]
I think it's cuz there's a half slab
over the over the top of the head I'm
not sure alright so this is the daytime
look pretty cool so we got to fill in
the gaps next year I did most the trees
where I just removed one of the the logs
like flush with the leaves but then in
some places I tried removing two and it
started leaving these big giant gaps a
bunch of the leaves despawned so
probably best just to remove one like if
we go to a tree here I'll try show you
what I mean hello maybe not alright it's
so freaky working here there's so many
mobs that spawn alright so if we just
remove one we we kind of do that but if
we remove two and you're placed to a
whole bunch of the leaves will despawn
so it's it's better just to do one I
think alright so this is what it looks
like from the sky here the top view of
it's a little bit funny looking I would
say so my next step here is to fill it
in like I said but we're gonna do some
other stuff as well so I'm gonna I think
it's gonna be easiest to do it from on
top here to fill in the gaps I'll try to
do that looks like there's gonna be a
few quite a few to fill in but then
another thing I'm gonna try to do here
if we want to give it that spooky swamp
feeling we got to block out the lights
so I'm gonna have to cover all this over
with some some sort of block and I think
clay will closely match the leaf color
here so basically I got to make sure no
light can pass through here and then
that's gonna look funny from the top
view as well so then you got to add
another layer or two of leaves on top of
this as well so check this out I forgot
that the leaves are actually gonna block
out the skylights like they with just a
few leaves you don't notice it but when
you get a bunch of them together and I
filled in the gaps now it's like
completely dark underneath there it's a
it's a CPM map oh oh oh we almost blew
up there I'm gonna run through here and
light it up thing is I don't need to put
the clay blocks above the leaves but I'm
still going to I think just because I
don't like seeing the blue through them
like that this the blue sky I think it's
better we cover them still hmm
this is where I start calculating time
and stuff so I covered up some of this
of course it takes a long time placing
the blocks to do this but it took just
to do this little section that's eight
stacks of clay and we're gonna need at
least 24 maybe thirty two stacks total
for this section but we're I want to
expand this like probably three times
the size as well so it's gonna be well I
can't even count 72 stacks of clay plus
we got a cover over this with leaves
again I was thinking about using
concrete powder but I'm not sure I liked
it as much it would be cheap I could get
this easily so that would be the nice
thing about it let's maybe just do a
small section here just to see if it
makes much of a difference all right so
that's the clay over there I like that
way more than just having the blue sky
showing for sure can we really see much
of a difference between that and the
concrete over there no you can't really
yeah I'm gonna switch over then because
this is dirt and gravel right you can
tell I haven't used concrete powder all
that much so it's actually for gravel
and for sand and not dirt and the dye
and I think collecting clays a lot
easier than concrete powder actually
because like sands at all various
different levels and stuff it's kind of
annoying to collect in the desert and
it's only like paper-thin but if you go
to the Mesa it's like solid solid clay
instead of a beacon really easy oh I am
so tired now guys I've been at this for
hours now just non-stop block placing
thousands and thousands of blocks but
check it out it's it's pretty good right
so I did expand it a lot I don't think
I'm gonna make it any bigger though you
can see it goes all the way around there
I think that's gonna be the final size
of it I I like that there's still lots
of stuff we can do with it but I'm I'm
getting tuckered out here as you can see
I didn't put the leaves overtop the clay
there I'm gonna save that for another
day I did do a little section there just
something an idea of what it'll look
like that's just one block thickness on
the leaves there and I think that looks
fine as is and another nice thing about
the clay here I realize is it acts as a
barrier like if you just have leaves
solid leaves they're transparent blocks
so if you're on fancy graphics
everything needs to be rendered
including the ground below but this kind
of acts as a shield so it should
increase our frame rate quite a bit
having this year which is I think is
cool
I guess let's go down and check it out
right so where do we get down here let's
go over here and alright here it is guys
this is how it looks right now again
like I said I would like to do some more
with it
I got rid of all the the scaffolding and
stuff because for what I want to do next
I need to lower the staff holding like
three blocks or so is just too close to
the leaves I can't work with that but
even as it is right now by staggering
the trees it creates a pretty cool
pattern it's a it's like wavy it's not
square which is good that's I was hoping
for so I think it is fine like it is
right now but something I would possibly
like to consider doing in the future
it's just that hanging leaves sort of
thing I like to do so just rough it up a
bit so it's not flat stuff and now have
leaves drooping down you can see if I'm
too close to the top here I can't really
work I got to go down like six blocks or
so the other big thing we should do with
this by the way is we need to create
like parts of custom trees that go up
and connect to the canopy just the wood
part of the tree we don't have to do
anything with the leaves I don't think
which is the most time-consuming part of
making a custom tree I would say but
just have it attached in a few places so
it doesn't look like the canopies
floating like it is right now and
that'll make it a lot better plus it'll
add some more structures in the swamp
down below here the other thing I'm
going to try to do here though is I'm
now that we're done building for today I
think get rid of all the torches and
then we're gonna play with the lighting
to see if we can get a cool atmosphere
this is how I would like to keep it to
be honest like it's darken areas and
brighten other areas where the light can
seep through around the mushrooms and
stuff we got some glowing trees in here
still so that's bright around those but
the mobs are just such a problem so we
either have to do hidden lighting or I
think I'll go up into the canopy and
make up a couple spots where the light
can get through
because this is like we can't ever enter
there during the day as it is right now
so that's useless all right so let's go
check it out now I punched about I think
seven holes into the canopy which live
it up quite a bit and I also put a few
torches on the ground which we can
replace with fancier lights later I just
have them there is like possible places
for like a mushroom light or something
like that
so let's walk through here let's see how
quickly it takes the mobs to respawn and
also how the atmosphere feels now that's
a bit brighter it's okay like there's
still light in dark spots right I like
that feels okay I put one hole right
above the center of this thing so the
nether wart farm should stay bright
during the day as well not nearly as
many mobs that's good because he could
barely walk through here before but if
we're in the area for a long time
they'll still respawn it's actually
quite a bit better like there's only
maybe ten mobs around right now which is
pretty good so like there are dark spots
like that maybe we could put path blocks
there or some other block where they
can't spawn on that way we can keep it
dark and have the atmosphere feeling to
it but anyways guys articular are gonna
have to wrap up the episode here for
today I don't like to end it quite so
early normally but I am so tired now
like unbelievably and I'm starting to
get the symptoms I don't know if it's
just like a me thing or if it's normal
but I don't really feel tired when I get
tired like I can stay up for days and
not have that feeling like I can't keep
my eyes open
like I have no trouble staying awake but
I get symptoms when I get tired my voice
gets raspy my eyes get really dry I have
this really annoying thing that started
where underneath my left eye like just
underneath it I get this burning
sensation that lasts all day until I go
to bed basically and I don't think
that's normal it drives me crazy it's
and it's only the left eye not the right
one is that weird or the other people
have that - I'm not sure anyways here is
the common
today it says etho was looking at your
computer specs on your About section on
your channel was wondering if you have
updated any of your PC recently I cannot
show my f3 anymore without people making
fun of my my specs
like seriously I am overdue for a
computer upgrade I still have the gtx
770 and you can see my my processor
there
I think the processor is decent though
right like I have never had issues with
the processor it's just the graphics
card that really needs an upgrade the
problem is like I always buy my
computers from a store I like doing it
that way I have built them before as
well but I find I don't like that as
much it usually ends up costing more I
find it takes time you got to order the
parts or find the parts and I usually
have problems too after after a while
blue screens maybe not anymore maybe
computers are just better now I'm not
sure but the thing is so many of you are
building your own computers that they
don't really sell good gaming computers
in stores anymore so I've looked at I
can't find like anything I have to build
one I think this time around or just
upgrade my graphics card maybe is
another idea but I'm not sure like if I
upgrade from a 770 to like a 1080 are
they the same size or do I need a
different motherboard for it I'm not
sure how that works actually
anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
Sora is a bit shorter but that's gonna
do it for today thanks for watching take
care bye bye
[Music]