[Music]
greetings everybody this is etho
and i see a squid has trampled our crops
a squid right there
so he must have fell from above uh
i did clean up this room a little bit
smoothed out the walls put some pumpkin
lighting here
it's a little bit more uniform and
whatnot
um so that's that's all done
there's did not really make a proper way
of getting in but i can get in and out
through
here with ender pearls real easy
so that's that's probably the way i'll
do it
um tried this out it's working okay
there's a few cows roaming around there
from before before i had this
fence here and i guess we could do a
harvest
harvest time again
uh today i'm mostly planning on doing
stuff around
uh the other base the stronghold base i
gotta do some stuff with the the mob
system
and maybe some stuff with the storage
room we'll see
but that's where we're gonna head to
right now
all right everybody so here is the deal
uh a few months ago
somebody left the comment in one of my
videos with a challenge for me
an engineering challenge in the game uh
or design challenge whatever you want to
call it
to do something involving mobs
and the guy got a lot of flack for it a
lot of people told him it was impossible
uh it's a stupid idea but i love the
idea and i've been planning on building
it
ever since i read that comment um and
i've also seen
a few other people make attempts at it
and have done some pretty cool things
with ideas well
but about two three weeks ago i took a
shot at it
in creative mode and figured out the
most difficult parts of making it work
so i'm not going to tell you what it is
yet
i don't know if you guys like that if
i'm sick when i'm secretive about things
but
i kind of like you to figure it out as
we go along so
i keep you thinking but i don't if you
don't like that let me know
um but we're gonna we gotta lean towards
that direction
towards making that project and before
we can do it we need to make
a few improvements to this mob system we
need to make
most importantly we need a mob separator
which is something we're going to play
around with today we'll probably go over
to creative world
and and do some experiments there
when i made this i had it with this
project in mind and i thought it was
going to be real easy to make a mob
separator because you just need
villagers to separate zombies you need
ocelots to separate creepers
and then you're left with skeletons and
you can easily divide them up that way
but apparently there's other problems
involved so we're going to go to a
creative world and just see how it works
we'll we'll create a little mock-up of
the idea
yeah so i loaded up a creative world i
had
and i think this was a creative world i
made in 1.3 because i was right by
one of these villages and there's no
stairs on the roofs
got dark spots where they were check
this mountain out
that's pretty cool too
but yeah we're gonna do some mob tests
here it's gonna take a lot of trial and
error to figure it out
and little by little we will figure out
what we need to do to make a mob
separator
the the issue the main issue i think
uh with this idea at the moment
is that the ocelots will randomly
teleport like dogs and the dogs and the
cats they randomly teleports
when they're not supposed to with the
1.2.5 patch
so i think that's the main issue
but we'll we'll see if we can if we have
any other problems so
we're going to pretend the mob system is
right above here mobs are falling down
into here
safely
so if we spawn a creeper
you will just go to the end so let's see
what happens if we were to put
a villager here i guess
just a lot of trial and error to figure
out their behavior
maybe move it back a bit more
and i have seen other uh separators
of course there's my really old one i
made that one's
never been very practical though i saw
somebody make one using snowmen that was
pretty cool but
it was very large also so
i'm gonna have to keep this as simple as
possible
okay let's get a sign to hold the water
sign yes actually we don't need one
okay so what will the zombie do now
okay he tried to go but he couldn't
that time he made it
okay
so i put a cover over top here so that
uh the sunlight won't affect their
pathfinding we don't want that happening
also i said uh creeper instead of zombie
before
i know i know you don't need to correct
me i know the difference
sometimes i say the wrong thing though
um
so the main issue right now is we can't
reliably make them go follow the
villager so we could either try
widen this or what i want to do first
is raise this water stream up one block
and see how that affects things so it's
going to put signs all along
bottom then we'll put the water on top
of them
because this forces them to have their
head right against the ceiling so
there's no
there's no gap we'll also have to put a
sign here probably
water doesn't feel that way
okay now let's see what happens here
actually let's raise this up a bit too
okay single
you got it no problem
no still had trouble
hmm maybe i should try slow sand
curious to see what that will do
that's a creeper that's a creeper
okay there
well now that their heads against the
ceiling they're probably not on the slow
stand look how fast they're going
through
so i'll undo that and try again
uh let's try it again here
water's down again
nothing
nope can't see the villager now
weird
yeah slow sand does nothing because
they're swimming up anyway
yeah i changed something here so they
can't see the villager anymore they're
making
no attempt to get them
i'm guessing it's because i put this top
on
here
let's try that
there we go that one block was doing it
yeah he tried but wasn't able to go in
but at least he tried
i'm curious if it was just the one block
or
if it's other blocks too
let's cover up everything except that
one
see what happens
yeah just the one block weird
okay what i want to try then is
um half slabs we're the half slabs
come on come on
okay we'll put a half slab
there he tried to run
why would you run into the zombie
[Laughter]
oh man that's weird okay we'll put the
villager behind that
and see what happens
okay i've been running them through here
a few times and there's some interesting
stuff
at me i also punched a hole here
now so they can fall down because that's
the other thing we need to have some way
of getting them into
another stream
but what has me really interested is
they do this little hop here
when they get out of the water i want to
see what happens if we get rid of that
blocked yet
tries to go this way that's weird
okay what happens if we put water above
there
because we got to build this with the
thought in mind that we're going to have
a lot of mobs going through here too
not just one at a time
oh that updated the water so it flew
down there
yeah i tried out the water idea but
didn't really work
all the mobs went up it so
what we should try to do now is increase
visibility because
by the time the zombies see the villager
they're
they're like over here and then they
start going towards them and
then they try to swim back but they
can't usually
so we will cut out over here
so they'll see them one block in advance
but still not be able to go
this is simpler if you can keep it down
to one wide tube
even though we sort of need a two wide
one here we just don't want them to be
able to walk
in the two wide area so if we do that
how's this look
so now they should be able to see the
villager from here
right maybe we'll get rid of one more
block there
whoa that must have fell
yeah we'll we'll do this
that and that let's see what happens
oh yeah saw him way earlier
yeah that's the key there
oh nope didn't make it still not good
so we may have to make this wider after
all at least
one block
yeah that's what we'll do so we'll
take it out there do something like that
and then have them converge into one
wide
stream if possible
even with those changes it's still not
working 100
and i'm starting to see why
there's two major factors that
determine whether or not they make it in
or not
he won't make it
[Music]
he will
so what it is first of all if we go in
here
um if you look at our z coordinate you
see it's at .69
or 0.7 basically um if we go to the
right side it's at point three
so there's a point what is it point four
yeah point four blocks leeway where we
can move around here if they're right
against this left wall
they have to travel 0.4 blocks to get
out of the stream
or to get to this wall so there's a
little bit of leeway there which
influences them but the main thing is
uh their rotation because they have to
turn around before they start walking
towards the villager
so pay attention to their rotation that
guy made it because he was almost
looking at the villager that guy was all
the way turned around like he was like
this
he had to go like this and then by the
time he turned around
it was too late so basically
it comes down to us needing to give them
more time
he won't make it he will
he will he will
he won't that's weird how they do that
too like he was
i think like this it would have been
quicker for him to turn this way but he
turns
to his right and it's a long
like over 180 degree turn he does there
um so he won't make it
what i'm gonna do is take out another
block i don't think we actually
need it too wide i don't think that has
any influence
um i might extend this water stream to
give us some more space to work with
seemed to take him a while
yeah i think that's helping he'll make
it
he'll make it he'll make it i want one
that's turned around
oh did no they didn't make it i think
they were in their way
i'll have to rewatch it they i think
they were in their way and that's why
they didn't make it but
maybe not
i rewatched that and i spotted the
problem
the way i had it set up i had
two blocks wide line of sight to the
villager for the zombie
and a one wide block walkway to get to
them
uh i noticed the zombies did not
actually start turning around
until they came to the one wide walkway
though the line of sight didn't really
do anything
so since it was only one wide it didn't
give them enough time to turn around
and go into it i've changed this back to
the two wide thing
and that should work out just fine now
i'm used to the old mob ai you know
where path
or a direct line of sight was really
important to them but i don't think that
matters so much anymore or at all
possibly um because they
they figure things out differently now
but as it is right now we're still going
to have the problem
do you know why
after everything we've learned today do
you know why it's still not working
100 that guy will go in
that guy will go in
he'll go in
he'll go in he won't
why won't he go in
do you know it's because it's still only
registering as a one wide block way
because we have this block
over top now it will work 100 percent
i think i hope
see he had to do a major turnaround
there and he still made it with plenty
of time to spare
uh now what i want to see is how other
mobs will react to this
if they will attempt to walk that way
because if they do
this is all for nothing we want them to
go straight
he went straight
so i'm gonna send probably hundreds of
creepers through here oh he's attempting
to go
and see if any of them try to walk this
way
yeah i've been sending them through and
i've seen a couple attempt it
it's rare but it does happen and the
longer the stretch before
the villager the more likely it's going
to happen because they'll have more
time to see that path
oh there he goes see
ding guy so
to stop that from happening we need to
make it so they don't
their pathfinding can't see this as a
viable path
uh which we can do by lowering the
ground
by four four blocks so
that they would get fall damage if they
did
the question is if the zombies will
still attempt to go that way after we do
that
which is what we'll have to check out
yeah there's no floor there now let's
see if they'll kamikaze to try to get
the villager
no they don't that is a major problem
huh
yeah that competes things a lot i'll
have to mess with this a bit
and see if we can figure something out
well um no major breakthrough yet
i've been learning a few new things but
nothing
nothing 100 unfortunately i
uh i checked out that video again the
other mobs order i saw
it's by captain walnut and he uses
snowmen to do it
he's trying to spot any tricks he might
have been using that i'm
overlooking but nothing stood out
it's just because he's using snowmen
they are guaranteed to walk
towards the snowmen when they're agro
which i don't have the luxury of with
this method
although with what i want to build i
don't think i can have them aggro at a
snowman i think it'll mess up the
the plans i have so i have to do it this
way
and i think i think the way i'm doing it
here is okay
i just can't get it to 100 percent
because if if
a zombie can go there a creeper can go
there or a skeleton
can go there just unlikely they will but
it's
it's always going to be possible um
unless i figure out some trick i'm
not realizing like for the most part
it's okay
what i could do is have another setup
like this and it will
decrease the chances even more like it
right now it's probably one in thirty
one and forty
chance that they'll go in where they're
not supposed to
if i was to have another of these it
would be like one in thirty times one
and thirty a very very
small number getting messed up
which should be okay for most of the
things i want to do
like we haven't had one go there yet if
we go use a zombie he'll go there every
time
this is a new trick i figured out you
know how we have to have the block open
above here the downside of that
is it slows them down and causes jams in
the streams
because they it takes them a while to
move from here but we can have
trapdoors apparently have them down and
they still view it as an empty block
but they're not able to jump up when
they enter here so
they just smoothly move through like we
want
nice and quick get them out of the way
and then i just have a stream up in the
air like this so that helps to pull them
out as well
get them out of the way quick
uh but i think i'm gonna mess up or mess
with
the creeper separation now
i'm fairly happy with this as it is so
we gotta
try do something with ocelots
gonna figure out how big they are first
what's their size
uh they're taller than half a block but
shorter than one
they won't go through there
and it seems like the creeper can see
them if that just the top of their head
is poking out like this too
they take off
and it seems like the creepers won't see
them
if they're enclosed like this they don't
run
you can try
they take off oh that's a cat that's not
what i want
come back here
there's a reason they run ah yeah
um no what i want to see is if a creeper
will take off
even though the line of sight isn't
there
nope nope
nope nope that guy did
line of sight is important with this
he took off right when he got about here
okay
what we want to do here is make the
zombies go to the right
skeletons go straight and then creepers
go to the left so we're gonna
make a duplicate of this on the other
side
but the difference is zombies are
attracted to the villager while
creepers are repelled by the ocelots so
we don't put the ocelot on the other
side we need it
over here by the villager so i'm going
to try to put him
right here diagonally
and then open this up
so they have a line of sight i'll clean
this up
and just put our villager or not a
villager ocelot
right over here
oh boy well there's another problem now
these cats don't do a very good job
at what they're supposed to do most the
time
the creepers don't even notice them
i've tried positioning the ocelot in
many different ways
it doesn't matter
like they have a direct line of sight
that time where
they went when they do go they want to
fight the current as well for some
reason
you can see the ocelots right there
direct line
i think i know why it's happening
there's no real good solution to it
zombies still work
here let's sleep and i'll show you what
i found out here
um if we have
let's go way up here it's doing a little
test
if we put an ocelot on here
and a creeper right next to him
they don't run right
like they don't see the cat
they just killed the cat well you live
but
they owned them um
they will run occasionally
haven't seen it happen yet but they
should
there he goes lost another cat
the creepers seem to need a lot of space
for them to run
because if you do it where there's a lot
of ground around
i think the creepers run right away
over here they have a very small amount
of space to
to work with so if they they have to
pick
a spot to run to and there's very little
choices
so most of the time their pathfinding
cancels out
because they don't pick a valid spot
when they check a big area but if
there's lots of valid spots then they
run
all right guys that's all we're gonna do
with this today uh
episodes getting pretty long if you have
ideas
let me know in the comments and i'll
check them out
and i'll also keep working at this off
camera
hopefully figure something better out
um but that's it thanks for watching i
hope you enjoyed it
and i will see you again next time
[Music]