[Music]
greetings everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode of our let's play series
how you doing today uh check this out i
got something to show you here
so listen very carefully
when i do this
you probably don't really hear anything
right maybe
maybe a little bit but not much uh
here's a problem i i've had with
minecraft for many
many years now whenever i go to record
i have to plug my headset in right
and then minecraft does not update its
audio like it doesn't switch over to the
headset
it keeps playing the game sound through
my speakers
so you might hear it through my speakers
right now just barely
which uh is a big problem for me so for
the longest time i would just like
restart the game
to get it to play through my headset
which was pretty annoying
then i found out eventually that you
could just press f3s
to restart the sound engine in minecraft
but in 1.9 or 1.10
i can't remember which one it was they
actually removed that so i was back to
restarting my game
now here is the big thing guys if you
have this problem too where it's not
switching
to your headset or whatever audio device
you want when you plug it in
i have found out there is actually a way
of doing it still if you look at this
f3t reload resource packs
if we press that game freezes for a
little bit
resource packs were reloaded and now you
should be able to hear it
very clearly so yeah that that reloads
it
so that's that's awesome uh anyways
i am uh collecting some resources here i
have a big
building project in mind for today guys
it's gonna be incredible it's gonna be
amazing
uh let's get to it here
[Applause]
[Music]
job's done all right very cool guys so
we got it done here i
really didn't think we'd be able to get
this done this episode this is a big
project but there we go it's beautiful
it's wonderful let me give you guys a
tour so you go inside
uh you know you can furnish it however
you want if you guys want a tutorial on
this build
uh just let me know in the comments i
might rig it up for you
it does it is quite a big build though
so be prepared if you do attempt it
got a window at the top there
very cool i like it
very practical sod roof you know keeps
the rain out we got a chimney
what more could you want in life really
that didn't work
uh oh no no
hmm you know what you want to know
something crazy
i just checked and even after we did all
that building
uh it seems like there's still some time
left for this episode
so i guess uh let's let's do another
project here
we're over at the nexus good old never
done nexus here
and uh i think we'll try to make a
building for it today if we can
as it is right now it's functional we
have a face plates we can operate it
every time i use it i'm worried a
creeper is going to sneak up behind me
so let's try to enclose this area if we
can
right now i've decided to move the ender
porter here
this was a little bit buggy we might get
into fixing that later i think some
people have
actually working designs so i might just
copy one of those later
but right now it's in the way so we're
going to move it here
um and yeah let's talk a little bit
about the building here
so i decided to go for like a white and
light blue
look i don't want to use a cyan clay
anymore
it's it's dull right it's not it's not
very nice
um and especially for like the buttons
there
those are the main part of the room
really these buttons here we really want
them to stand out
so i've been playing around with color
schemes a little bit at first i was
thinking of using emeralds
for behind the buttons because they they
really stand out
and i like green a lot
but uh like
lime clay and that a lot of people it's
kind of hard to use it in a way that
it's gonna look nice that everybody
likes you know so
i think blue is a little easier to pull
off so instead of using emeralds behind
these buttons we're gonna use
diamonds blue shiny rocks they're
they actually look pretty decent here um
i think
so let's see how hard is this gonna be
to change
looks like we just got some redstone
torches back here so we'll pull these
out
get rid of the clay the ugly gray clay i
actually like the cyan clay a lot it's
just not
ideal for this build so yeah we'll get
rid of it here
gotta be very careful i don't destroy
important wiring here or i'll waste an
hour trying to
figure out how to build it again uh
there was something here that i
destroyed
was it just a pillar oh it was a
it was a stair here okay yeah so check
this out
get some buttons i don't know why i made
more buttons i had all the buttons on me
and tada
those really stand out i like that so
we're going to go with that
very nice very nice okay so to be honest
i'm not super confident about my
color scheme here or the building
decisions i made but we'll see how it
looks
uh once we get it all done uh for the
border
like all around here i've decided to use
light blue clay
as our main building block and then for
the floor the bulk of the floor
clay oh we had so much clay left over
from that big build i decided yeah let's
let's try it out here
uh it actually has a bit of a bluish
tinge
to it so it might not be terrible
we'll see like this is one of those
building blocks people don't use very
often
but i kind of think they go together
right
and hopefully hopefully the texture is
not terrible it kind of reminds me like
of concrete you know
interesting okay okay i'm not
sold on it just yet uh before we decide
with the floor though let's actually
work on the walls and the roof
and then it might blend better because
i'm gonna be adding more blue and stuff
uh oh yeah and by the way like every
time
we do something with the nexus
somebody's like ito what's the nexus
it's a giant storage room with automatic
item sorting and item retrieval so right
now i need some
court stairs actually so court stairs
have the code 6e
to request them we press 6
actually i think it's reversed right now
6 e
and hopefully we get court stairs so
this should request
16 of them i think uh yeah let's work on
the walls though here
it does take a moment to arrive oh and
there's some garbage in there
so very important we want to connect to
the tunnels we have over there that's
where the items are actually stored
uh there there's no real reason to go
there
but it's built you know i want some way
of connecting there anyway
um let's go ahead and sleep here real
quick
so yeah i think i'm going to put a a
passageway over here on both sides one
over here one over there
did they arrive okay i don't think there
was 16 in the system we got 15.
so yeah i wanted to try put those over
here
all right and the great news is bone
blocks are a thing now so
i don't have to go mine for a bajillion
courts
to finish up this project we're going to
switch over to using bone blocks and
this middle is kind of the feature of
the room so it'll be a bit brighter
and stand out so i think this is going
to work out pretty good actually
so i think we'll do this
maybe come out one more and then we'll
leave a
three or five wide passage let's leave a
five i think
and then do something like that so the
passageway will be over here
uh so let's get rid of this then
start making the border go this way like
that
this will be clay
f zero haha
great game classic game you know i think
that might have been the first racing
game i ever played actually
i remember blowing up in it a lot uh
so this is starting to feel pretty good
i'm liking it
i'm gonna try to do the roof now uh
let's see
my plan is to do like an arch because
because you know me i like my arches so
probably yeah probably about that shape
there
uh do i got some dirt on me yeah let's
let's fill her up here
f zero is sea lanterns by the way i
don't i don't know what's up with these
buttons i'm getting like random amounts
of
stuff it's not 16 i got 25 there somehow
i was gonna put those down here get a
little light in
into the situation and you can see i did
like an ether door over there
uh which will up open up to the
passageways
all right do the same on that side i'll
do that off camera
and let's go up here and try to mark
this out
so maybe
um there's some wire there let's start
on this side because it's blocked a
little bit more yeah maybe we'll do
something like
this go up two
and then maybe two again
and then fill in the middle
let's see how let's see how this works
out i find building episodes a little
bit tricky
it's like and now i'm going to place
this block over here
and this block over here i'm not exactly
sure a good way of doing them you know
it's i'm more use more used to logical
stuff
instead of actually building but
building is good
is this uh oh it is the middle okay
good so that works out to five
and then we'll do two and then
two more and then maybe we'll switch
over to one
oh i fall down how does that work out
so this would go here
bring that out here
yeah so i'm gonna i'm gonna bring this
out a bit more
um maybe span quite a distance here
actually
and see what that looks like okay so
check it out guys
got a bit of an arch here i do really
like the shape of this
i think that's good but uh
you know there's a lot of white in this
build which i think is fine
but we gotta set a limit somewhere right
if we do this
and i haven't even gone as far as i want
with it it's gonna be so much white
so let's try to mix in some blue uh with
this i was thinking about doing a line
uh with a pattern like a line going all
the way across here
so probably five wide thing
either this pattern
something like that or we'll do
this one
or my other idea is to do this
what do i mean you'll see what i mean in
a second i'm gonna try this one out
first though and just see what it looks
like here
okay let's check this out i did all
three patterns we'll pick our favorites
[Music]
oh
i think i'm gonna go with the middle one
it's this cleaner
right yeah
very cool guys so there we go we got our
line running down the roof
uh i never know what to do with roofs
i'm not good at building roofs but
i am actually pretty happy with this i
think it's okay uh you can see i got it
lined up with the door so it should help
to make the building feel symmetrical
to a certain degree uh you'll see what i
did here too i'm so i did another arch
like this it kind of transitions
from an arch going this way to an arch
going this way
because i love arches uh got lots of
arches
and i filled in there i just did a
little design thing
oh uh one second
the great thing about working on a
storage room is you have all your items
here ready to go you don't have to run
around
constantly looking for stuff
cool that's good and
yeah i think this is good for the first
part of the building we're going to
create a separation here now
uh we still need to add a lot of stuff
like a bed
a nether portal i want to add in a rail
system
for delivering items to the nexus i want
to add in
maybe some sort of a lighter launcher
and
all kinds of crazy stuff so this is
going to be a very big room
to help it not feel quite so plain we're
gonna
create a separation here try to split it
up a bit add some variety
one second while i sleep once again okay
here we go
so this is what i want to do uh i like
to add vertical height to my builds
whenever i can so we're going to go up
two blocks
see how this looks two blocks up i think
it looks pretty cool
compared to flat on the ground so
let's build like a wall here
yeah just to too high wall
like so and i'll be able to hide some
lighting in here too probably which will
help us out because
like this is good during the day but at
night time i'm not so
sure where we're gonna hide the lights
it's gonna be
not fully lit up at the moment for sure
so we'll do that and then i want to add
a staircase system here
so um
three wide three wide
yeah let's do that okay we'll take this
out oh not all of it
do that and do
that and
where the clay over here switch that out
and maybe yeah let's get rid of the
slabs here
we'll put in a sea lantern here for
lighting
and maybe one in the middle here
because i'm very worried how i'm going
to hide this lighting and there's that
big area in the middle here
uh i kind of got carried away with the
size of the floor
you don't want things spread out too
much in minecraft because then you can't
light it
is the problem and i got carried away
here
okay do that
cool okay
um should we make this come out one more
and this go in
yeah i like that
so um building break
you know that wither that was loose in
our world yeah he's still here
we should take care of him here today if
we can find him
he's pretty sneaky though he's hiding in
the trees somewhere
somewhere oh
hey buddy please don't kill me
please don't kill me
he's gonna kill me isn't he
i really wish i didn't go in the water
oh yeah i'm so dead
is it me or whether it's like crazy
difficult now
oh no he's he's a ninja
where did he go mr chicken
i think we found him
oh yeah he bumped me too okay
so got a diamond chest plate on this
time see if that helps
out at all seems to be helping a lot
yeah don't don't wear elijah wings
during a weather fight
it's cool and all but it doesn't work
very good
and he's down nice nether star
gonna be able yet another beacon with
that
oh snap check this out
they actually have their own custom
sound effects now so mojang added them
that's cool
they have a hurt sound
yeah they they have custom hurt sounds
custom death sounds that's cool
what you doing down here
all right we got a beacon again i had to
steal these ones
because i had a shortage so it's good to
get them back
ace 2 and speed 2 are my preferred
so guys this is what the room looks like
now it's uh basically all done this part
of it anyway we still got the
the other part to work on here i want to
see what you guys say about this
first though let me know what you think
of it if you have any suggestions for it
uh we got lighting here here here
on the sides i hid some under the chests
over here but i don't think it's going
to light up the middle here
this spot in this spot i think are too
dark at night time
unfortunately so need to figure out what
to do about that too
but otherwise i think it's good here uh
something
i'm going to do oh yeah the door's not
set up yet
so you're going to come out here it's
going to take a left over here
you got to figure out how to split it so
it goes down and
up um but there'll be probably be some
sort of a tunnel
leading up to here uh surprise surprise
can you believe this turns out if you
have holes in your top floor
it's actually a pretty bad design choice
because you constantly fall down
so i brought some glass over here i'm
going to fill these in
because i do i do go up here every now
and then and i often fall through and it
bugs me
so let's do this decide to go for light
gray glass it's pretty close in color to
the quartz
and let's see what that looks like from
below
yeah i think that's fine we'll go with
that
okay so let's figure out this tunnel
here a little bit uh if we go through
the door
uh i found out the very center of the
the storage room up ahead is actually
right down here
[Music]
portal's so loud so yeah we will uh
probably have some sort of a door frame
here as well
kind of even that out you come out here
and then on this side we have
all this wiring right and i think that
looks pretty cool
so we're going to leave that visible
we're going to clean up we're going to
get rid of the grass
and all that kind of stuff but we'll
leave the wire visible and that will
kind of make up
one of the walls on this other side
though
um i was thinking about adding a window
at first then it's like well
you got this giant hill in the way even
if we bold those this hill
further out here there's just some trees
there's not really much of a view this
way
so we should make some solid wall on
this side as well
and since it's a nexus here i had an
idea
i've been wanting to use somewhere we'll
see if it looks any good or not
i want to try to make a circuit board
wall
something that resembles a real life
circuit board
pcb so this is kind of the color we're
going to go for
dark green and then
actual circuits like the wiring is going
to be the lime
clay there and i want to try build like
electronic components on the circuit
board and just see if it looks any good
or not
we'll have to make them pretty small
because it's minecraft i don't really
have a lot of uh
freedom here so let's say we want to
make a
a processor a microprocessor or
something
microprocessor microchip i mean what am
i saying so it could
look like oh not bone blocks i want to
use the
the quartz pillars yeah
yeah these so a microchip might look
something like
this man that's huge
i thought this was going to be small but
nope
um so as you walk
by you can't really see the details
though
it might not work so good on a wall
maybe it'd be better on a flat ground
like for a floor um
see a capacitor could be
something like this
nah it's too big and clunky isn't it
darn
i was gonna try like draw lines like
going from
from the components together i thought
it would look cool but
it's gonna be way too big i think
in this case we need it further away
for it to look good and probably not
sideways
all right guys well it is getting a
little bit late here for me so we're
going to wrap up the episode
for today but let's do the comments
which says
hey etho challenge change your minecraft
language to
danish and try to pronounce some of the
items in your inventory
love your videos
you're going to regret that let's do it
how do you change your language language
uh what do you say danish
hi where's danish
dansk dutch
uh which one's danish
it's got to be one of those three right
this is a much harder challenge than i
expected i don't know if it's dutch land
or this one
we'll go for that one
celebrity
stock ah that's an easy one i can do
that one
hellblast glass to phil
feckl really fackle
uh bruce steen
diamond text i think i did that one
ender purely
steak oh that's that's my kind of thing
uh
diamonds shoot worth
did i
i succeed this is the last one we got
enough
aha i speak perfect danish or whatever
language this is
stinkol wrote another ziggler
perfect it kind of sounds like german
for a second there
anyways guys hope you enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching
i was going to do a harvest but i don't
remember where the button is
is it over here no it's not over there
no it is over here what am i talking
about
ah let's do it thanks for watching guys
hope you enjoyed it
until next time take care bye bye