hey hey how's it going everybody this is
Ethan welcome back to another episode a
very slippery slide a wonderful intro we
have here guys I've shown this before
this is the ice spike biomes in our
world looks very cool this is one of my
favorites biomes in the game now look at
these crazy ice spikes we get they go
all the way up but yeah I've kind of
shown this before I was in the middle of
a ice run here I was collecting some ice
and I saw something that I never noticed
before I was like out over here it turns
out there is more to this biome and I
never saw it before like not even very
far from here I thought it's it ended
because we've looked around here but it
turns out I just barely caught an eye of
its still can't see it oh yeah yeah we
can see there's a nice spike up over the
over there so it seems to continue
actually so I thought it would be cool
to go check it out see if there's any
cool scenery over here as well so I want
to give you guys a big thank you man
that the response on last episode was
amazing I could not believe like I
didn't expect that at all but you guys
are so nice and supportive in the
comments it was it was really cool very
encouraging oh yeah we got a little bit
of the overhang going on here too even a
lot of people that don't normally
comment like that made the effort to say
something in the comments something nice
and supportive so that was really cool
oh yeah look at this starting to get a
little more hilly over here Oh
if it's not quite as nice of scenery
over here I think this is where I'll
actually collect the ice from because
that other spot is really cool and I
hate to destroy it but I have been this
one's more kind of more closed in it's
hard to get a good good feel of the
place I think that's about it though I
don't know if there's any more this way
seems like the biome switched
yeah we're in cold taiga here let's
maybe just go up on the hill if we can I
think we're getting a little bit of lag
it's generating new terrain yeah I think
that's about it this is the border oh
wait it might continue on over there I
might go check that out oh yeah look at
this view this is pretty cool from up
here and it does keep going a little bit
it seems so let's go check this out over
over the mountain because it might
continue on the other side keep going so
giant drop here and that is about it
yeah that's that's the border there
uh-huh anyway
pretty cool I thought I would show that
what about over this way it seems to end
over here too
so not much more here just a little bit
and kablamo or something here we are
many hours into the future I think I've
worked like five or six hours on this
stupid thing today one big final push on
the Nexus to get the guts of it done so
that we can move on to other parts of
the project and I am still not finished
I only need like 30 more minutes or so
but I am seriously out of the time that
I can work on on this off-camera but I'm
happy to say all the redstone is
complete on here finally all the hoppers
are in place all the chests are in place
I did the lower water stream that's what
you see here it's just the upper water
screen that we need to finish and then
all this interior stuff is done it is
done
I had one water leak over here
accidentally washed away some redstone I
tried to fix it I hope I did it right
the thing that scares me most with this
project is things are not gonna work
like I have to be so careful when I'm
building this that I do it exactly right
because if you know one repeater is set
to a slightly different delay or one
redstone dust is missing I'm going to
have one the crazy time trying to find
all the problems when I actually get it
working so that that water spill has me
a little scared but anyway I am done
working on this for today pretty much so
let me let me tell you a few things
about it first off got all this stuff
done all the guts all the leg causing
stuff and I'm still getting 120 frames
per second if we do a shift f3 What's it
telling us the tick tick delay is a
pretty important one that's that's what
hoppers effects and if you get a high
tick on your on your game that's when
the Sun and the moon start jumping and
you can't open chests quickly but so far
you know I can hardly tell the
difference that we have anything it's
instant look at this the Sun is not
jumping which I'm very happy about so
this this structure everything we've
built here is not too bad in terms of
lag which I was really worried about
with this project I thought I was gonna
build it and then it's I'll never want
to go near it because it will light me
like crazy so that's good I have one
really sneaky project to do though after
the guts here which I'm not looking
forward to for each of the items all 256
items I have to go to the hoppers and I
have a hard time getting around here
still
that's what enderpearls are for at each
of these hoppers I need to program
it's an item filter I need to program
what item goes into each of these and
basically I have to do something like
this remove one and then put the item
there that we want it to be these have
to be a junk filler item so we can't
just use glass we have to I think what
we'll do let's try this out I think I'll
use cobblestone
do we have a stack of cobblestone
there's got to be tons of cobblestone in
here or answer yeah I'm gonna try to
name this I'm pretty sure this works
though we will name our filler product
filler oh so clever
all right so normal cobblestone
shouldn't stack with that I'm pretty
sure let's grab some of that before I
forget it
there we go so if I want to store let's
say stone bricks in one of these I would
have to let me up here I'm losing it
okay there we go I would have to put the
filler in what was it I have to get up
to 17 and then the item I actually want
to store at this place so let's say well
I said another or a stone brick right so
I'd do that and now if I put regular
cobble on here it shouldn't go in the
hopper right yeah bounced off that's
good if we have filler and though
that'll go yeah that went in okay oh
wait a minute what is it supposed to be
18 I think it's supposed to be 18 right
I didn't mess that up
it's not 17 18 yeah that's that's the
number so then we would have that and
then whatever item goes there uh-huh I
gotta do that for each and every one of
these we made that book before we
started this project of how I want to
organize it roughly so I'll be using
that to decide what to put where but
that is a project for another day I
think oh yeah one other thing we should
try out here let's make sure when we put
a
don't break in here it doesn't mess up
the order of this stuff
okay so just went right through it adds
one and the one in there goes away which
is awesome
that has to be whoops I have to make
sure the item is in the first spot
though cuz if it's it's in the back I
think this will go first right ooh yeah
see that stacks the baton this one goes
away so we don't want to do it that way
that goes first item we're sorting and
then the filler okay all right so
something else I worked on today that I
wanted to show you is the pyramid over
here or the ziggurats whatever it's
actually called I'm not sure I've been
corrected on it though it's just a
stretcher though I'm not actually trying
to copy anything specific so it is what
it is and I got I got all the walls up
basically there's no detail to it though
this is what it looks like just plain
Plain Jane
raw and simple and I think it looks
pretty good even as it is I like that
more than the giant red cube or the the
Snow Mountain thing I think seems to fit
a little bit better and it will look
better when we get the rest of details
in on it whoa all right so guys the next
thing we're gonna do here I played
around with an idea for a new mini farm
one of these things I actually use this
a lot one of the problems it has though
is I can only use it for about five to
ten minutes like the idea is you afk
here and just hold right click put
something heavy on your mouse and you'll
automatically climb some crops and
whatever but it only can run for about
five to ten minutes then your inventory
fills up and stuff starts and spawning
on the ground this new design will
automatically pick up stuff and I have
an issue I I can't throw things away I
just can't and one of the problems I'm
thinking I'm finding is I get all kinds
of mob drops from this thing and I just
keep stashing them in this
and it's it's starting to get a little
crazy so we got tons and tons of bones
that I got to get rid of I just can't I
can't stand throw the way I gotta use
them so we are going to build the new
one over here and I'll show you how to
do it okay so I think we'll put it in
the orange house here kind of up and out
of the way let's put it now let's put in
this corner here it's got to go in a
corner alright so you need three
dispensers for the bonemeal so do dis
dis and dis this over here is where the
soil will go for the crop and I didn't
bring any with me for some reason and
then the pressure plates to activate the
whole thing is here this will activate
the clock that makes it run put a
comparator down over here let's take out
a little bit more of this wall so this
one's not gonna use a piston this one
harvests a crop using darkness which is
kind of cool it's a little bit quieter
see I think we do that and then go up
here perhaps maybe not I forget how this
goes I think that maybe a repeater was
here yeah I think that's right and then
you go up like this and we got to run
wire to all three of the dispensers hey
you hey that's where the crops go get
out of there crazy guy alright goes up
to over here and we got a run one to
this this dispenser here too so let's
put a slab here let's do a crafting
table going alright and just let's make
a stand out of this hey these guys man
get out of here trying to work made you
go up and then to that I guess I think
that works like that okay
and I believe actually let's lower this
by one and then have a repeater go to
here it's got to be set to three and
when this power is this block here I
actually no no that doesn't work what am
i doing I think it's gotta go like this
actually just wire and then the dirt
blocks here and when power goes to this
redstone wire it updates the dirt block
and that causes it to uproot the wheat
right so this is this is a repeater we
got to set to three then yeah so I think
that works all right turn this to
subtraction mode and oh you know what's
wrong try to figure out what's wrong
with this stupid thing this is a slab
it's not a full block let's get a full
block there so we can actually send some
power through it all right all right so
we're gonna put some water over here or
somewhere where it'll hydrate the soil
hide it over here is good
all right and now to actually collect
the stuff that drops what we'll do is
we'll dig down I don't know what is that
what is that from is that gonna be in
the way hopefully not so we'll have a
hopper going to the side and track and
then a hopper minecarts I hope there's
enough space here did this work oh yeah
I think it's good so I'll pick up items
through this block so if we throw stuff
on here it goes through through the
block into the hopper minecarts then we
until this and I think we're pretty much
good to go we got some bone meal in here
all right put a block there so now one
last thing in order to make it dark what
we'll do is put a slab upside down slab
like that that makes
totally darked in the space but we can
still interact with it
and is it working yeah it's working cool
so that's pretty much all there is to it
runs fairly quickly uh-huh so I'm gonna
also add in some extra storage here for
each of these for bone meal and then
some chests down below to pick up the
drops okay so there it is guys it's
basically finished these guys like to
walk on it though which is a bit
annoying get away I added an extra
dispenser and it doesn't do anything
it's just to bounce out the look that we
got extra storage up here lots of
bonemeal very good and I added some
storage down below which we'll check out
in the second but yeah let's let's try
this out so oh I tried to throw it down
there it didn't work they go that time
no it did hear you you take that alright
so if I have an inventory full of stuff
we can see it'll actually go into into
the storage down below see we're getting
wheats we are getting wheat every time
right or did I mess that up
it's hard to tell I think we are okay
yeah and none of its going in my
inventory it's all going down below and
I'm still able to get seeds from this so
so I don't run out that's why we want to
be able to stand right next to it but if
there's no room in my inventory Oh goes
down to the infant inventory below so
that's good and if we go check it I just
made it in this room over here do we got
five double chests plenty of space and
it goes there what what happened here
there's two two invisible blocks
how's the chest okay I was looking for
the students like where's all my
sandstone now I want some sandstone hey
you get out of here
alright guys so I don't have a lot of
time left to record today I gotta upload
this pretty soon but I just want to try
one more idea we got all this open
desert over here right all this space I
kind of want to fill it with something
so I'm considering building a mini
village of some sort here lots of little
houses that don't really do anything
they're kind of just there to look good
I guess and I'm wondering how difficult
that would be so I'm just building a a
sample house to see how tricky it is so
I just threw this together very quickly
this will be a roof to it
flat roof nice and simple and then so
something I've seen people do is you put
stone slabs around the top then or I'll
spruce wood so we'll try that out and
then we'll add windows and stuff to it
as well and see if it looks half decent
if it does maybe we will be able to
build the city alright so far it looks
terrible
let's pretend the how the door goes here
alright
chisel that away we would want a window
maybe here mmm another one there sure
and we could do a spruce the fence type
of window should we have another one
here this side looks pretty plain and
let's do this sure I'm like putting very
little thought into this I'm just sort
of doing it and seeing how bad it will
be alright so far it looks kind of
crummy it's a simple house but it's the
details that would make it so maybe with
practice I could get better yeah
aha how about now guys what do you think
of it now
I spent some more time adding details
and I think it looks quite a bit better
it has a bit more color to it it's the
details that are gonna make the houses
look good so we need ideas of stuff to
add to the outside but do you think it's
good enough for a village because we
would need to make lots of little houses
like this and have roads and fountains
and trees and whatever stuff like it
kind of cool this is the interior would
probably add some stuff and inside - I
don't know I kind of want to build that
the village quickly - those I don't know
how much time I should spend on each
house but anyway let me know if you like
it if you do we'll probably go on with
that idea but yeah that's going to do it
for today guys
hopefully I sounded better today I'm
pretty much all over the cold finally
that really messed me up like I haven't
been that sick and so long so yeah sorry
for the lack of videos lately I'm hoping
things get back to normal now that it's
gone
and here is the comment I picked up for
today it says personally I think the
modded series will be very good it gives
you the freedom of single-player and
allows you to do more and more with it
yeah I cannot wait for this good luck
etho I am so excited for this modded
series you have no idea I've been
waiting weeks to play it's because I put
together the pack myself and and that
has made me very excited for it I picked
out all the mods I configured everything
the way I want it and have total control
over everything and I am just I've just
been waiting to finally experience what
I've what I've put together and I am
recording an episode of it later today
so that's gonna be the next Minecraft
video so hopefully you guys enjoyed the
new series I'm hoping it's gonna be a
long long-term views on my channel yeah
we'll see how things go
anyway that's it for today thank you for
watching everybody have a wonderful day
and I'll see you in the next episode bye
bye