well hello everybody this is etho
welcome back guys thank you for joining
me again today get out of here guys here
we are we are here this is where we are
right over here where is here I will
tell you where here is this is a very
special place I have looked like an hour
for this place we are standing right now
it's about 500 blocks south of our
stronghold base maybe six or seven
hundred blocks so what is so special
about the spot
well you may have noticed there are some
water temples here is one over there
there's one out over there these are
these are water temples we have not been
to yet so that's pretty cool and there's
some light in the water there too I'm
guessing it's a lava pool but I kind of
want to go check that out but that has
nothing to do with why this place is
special the reason I was looking for
this spot this is like an island out in
the middle of an ocean you got desert
over here there's only a little bit of
grass outside of this area that I'll
have to take care of but I want to build
a passive mob farm right over here aha
and and yeah so that's our our little
project for today the reason I want to
build a passive mob farm I have found
out I always had this assumption that
you could only spawn horses in once in
your world like when you load a new
chunk that's when you get your horses
and there's no chance of getting any
more unless you go to new world turns
out that is not true I found out today
you have to you just have to kill all
the passive mobs in the area and there's
a chance to get horses Oh guardians are
getting out here so this is a Plains
biome which is important if I tell all
these sheep and cows here we should get
horses so if we can kind of automate
that somehow
we can spawn a lot of horses and I'll be
able to get donkeys again in my world
because right now I don't have any
uh-huh
so probably the easiest way to deal with
things though is to sort of limit how
much grass area we have and also to
flatten things out so that's what we're
going to do here and I am so lazy I'm
not even going to dig a hole for the TNT
I'm just gonna TNT a hole for more TNT
that's right amazing because usually it
takes like two or three minutes just to
dig a hole for all the tea and tea I
place I'm finally at the point in my
world here where I got more TNT than I
know what to do with it so any chance I
can use it the same timer to have fun
yes let's take it so I use two stacks
and I guess this is going to be our
explosion platform it's a little bit
risky but we will try it here we go whew
that was actually more contained than I
thought it would be nice Wow look at
that
okay well this should be a little bit
more fun I use the rest of D&D there's
four stacks hopefully this does a lot
No
we're good
ooh right in the face man
uh yeah a little bit more I am going to
have to get a beacon over here though it
looks like okay so I decided rather than
trying to flatten the whole island today
I'm feeling a little bit lazy we're just
going to remove all the grass which I'm
just about done just got this little
part left and then I'm going to go and
remove some of that other dress outside
of this island and then we'll try it out
all right so we can move on to the next
step here all the grass has been removed
from this island I have removed all the
grass over there and a bit of the grass
over there you can see I made a line so
hopefully it doesn't spread but I think
an Enderman might just like grab a grass
block from over there and Transplant it
there and then I got a big problem I
have to take care of so all the dirt
really needs to be removed anyway so we
are going to where's my chests over here
we're just going to put down a grass
platform and see if anything spawns so
it's pretty simple
see this is all sunflower Plains yes it
is maybe add we'll just build a platform
right over here and then we'll step away
from it and we will see if anything
spawns on it and how long it takes for
something to spawn and that should give
us a pretty good idea of what we need to
do well guys we have a little bit of a
problem here possibly it's been a little
while couple minutes anyway and we have
not got a single mob yet and I've went
around the cylon that went around there
and over there there's no animals around
except for my horse one horse that
Island I removed all the grass on this
should be the only grass in the area
we're over 24 blocks away and
respond no you know what it is guys I
got to figure it out now it's a spawn
chunks any animals in our spawn chunks
count towards the total population cap
before it stops spawning them so that
means this is our spawn right here you
got the compass out true spawn right
right at this point if we go over top
compass flips around uh-huh
so this complicates things extremely
because well we do have these chickens
here right for example because of these
guys that guy just took up one spawning
space from what we built out over there
so I could kill them the thing is even
if I get the population cap down it's
just going to spawn more because it's
all grass here right so I would have to
put like 15 chickens in each of the four
corners around the spawn chunks so that
when I'm standing here it won't spawn
any new ones or I could try to get rid
of all the grass which is not something
I'm gonna do here
all right everybody so let me tell you
what I have found out in the end of all
this rather than then showing you all
the painful fails that happened on the
way basically to summarize the month the
passive mob farm is not going to work
there's absolutely no way to make it
work as it turns out we are in a super
flat world right now you see we got some
sheep we got some cows this is true
spawn we're at we're where we are at
right now I did some tests with squids
and bats to see if they would affect the
weather or not the other passive mobs
would spawn turns out they are on their
own separate thing bats and squid do not
affect like cows and that spawning at
all if we do a
kill everything but bats bats are still
here and we got some sheep that just
respond right over there that killed all
other mobs in the world you can see a
nice long list of them cows sheep
chickens rabbits etc if we do it again
we might see some horses in there yeah I
got some horses rabbits respawn aha
so this is what I did before I start the
episode this is what gave me the the
hope that I could get this working today
but then there was another layer to the
whole thing besides the spawn chunks
affecting that the mob count and let's
go to another world so it turns out even
if we can deal with the spawn chunk
issue with mobs being loaded there from
my man team like I got my cow farm I
have my rabbit farm horse stables all
that stuff is loaded all the time by the
spawn chunks even if we were to somehow
deal with that or move the spawn chunks
we have another problem where it's
extremely rare to get any passive mobs
to spawn in a normal world since I last
died let's check the list this is where
I died last we got bats squid we got cow
cow cow cow cow pig chicken that's not
too bad actually it was like seven or
eight spawned if we do it again compared
to a super flat world it's way slower
though that's because there's a lot more
land I'm assuming more chunks to deal
with and it has to go through all those
chunks instead of just one layer type of
thing anyway so even with these
thousands and thousands of blocks of
grass it's extremely slow to get any
passive mobs to spawn if we were to cut
it down to only a couple hundred blocks
like I was planning it's basically not
going to happen but anyways guys I guess
we'll do something else here now I
always debate like should I just
cut out my fails from the episodes or
should I include them like today what we
just did was basically a waste of time
is like well should I pretend like that
never happened and just do something
else sometimes I do cut them out
sometimes I don't today I decide not to
just because we did a lot of terraform
you it might be a little hard to explain
that later if I ever show that island
it's like what happened to that island
it's got a hole in it and how did you
find those those the water temples or
something later on so yeah and we
learned a bunch of stuff today or I did
anyway so the mob system is filling up
last I checked
lots of gunpowder I've been using the
bones through wheats arrows whenever we
play oppa lately oh yeah this is just
about full let's get that out of there
also have a bunch of stuff whoops
stored up in here I've just been
dropping it off
gunpowder arrows I thought I have
another chest too gunpowder is not we're
going to head over to the village for
just a second I saw that always looks
looks buddy it's like a giant villager
block head thing perfectly square there
should be a villager head block it looks
really good doesn't it it's kind of like
clay Harding play um I locked one guy in
there and I just say all have been
falling down into this little one by one
just I'll let him out I came here once
it's like what happened all my villagers
they're all gone and then I saw that
they were in this little area there was
a librarian here that we could trade
with see if he's got anything new to
offer
where's the paper gonna have to trade up
the zombie flesh
um librarian librarian where is he
it's probably inside somewhere there's
actually a lot of villagers here yeah
this is a guy let's turn him down music
okay so do a couple trades and this guy
he's taking all my money here
he will not unlock the new trade we got
yet one more unlocked for the final book
then we'll check them all come on yeah
he took all my paper already all right
you know what I'm just gonna I'm gonna
give them all hopefully that unlocks it
there we go finally so the first one is
knocked back one for 18 that's terrible
then the second one is look at the see
one for 16 that is also terrible Oh
power five for 37 a little bit pricey
but a cool trade we have a potentially
good clarity he's got 36 for the rotten
flesh let's see if we can get four on
the redstone we want for redstone to
lapis to redstone to lapis nope he's no
good alright that's it for the paper
trade you better unlock your new one oh
my goodness I hate this guy we got a new
new library in here you will not unlock
his trades though so I've used up the
glass trade and the paper trade now I
just need to unlock one more so I guess
I have to buy big bookshelves gonna buy
two there we go finally so he's got a
leer 3 for 32 that's kind of expensive
oh he has what what else did he get
debts strider - 431 punch - eyes kind of
junky
there's a lot of really bad villagers
right now so we're just gonna we're just
gonna get rid of them open style so
maybe we'll go check out one of these
temples today - lets go - this closer
one I got a strategy on how to capture
the elder Guardian that I want to try
out here so this should be pretty fun
we got depth Strider we got night vision
we got water breathing you got speed
potions regen there should be oh there
he is
you didn't scare me this time potion
good we should be able to zip through
this thing whoa
the entrance is right here I believe oh
yeah look at this so much easier I also
want to look around for sponges because
you can only get them from the temples
let's see all right so they all have a
different layout apparently oh hey hey
no no don't hurt okay let's go over here
this run through this thing it's amazing
so much better than the first time we
went exploring one of these all right oh
don't tell me it's a dead end
yeah it's a dead end okay I get lost so
easy I'm going to be leaving markers I
think oh hello there he is alright I
wasn't expecting to find one so soon so
the plan is invisibility potions Oh am i
filling these up with water
oops invisibility potions if we take off
our armor I don't think we can be seen
or else I'm going to get one shotted
here I don't know if he if he hurts you
if you touch him I hope not
so you can capture these guys with the
minecarts for sure and he is big isn't
he
this guy might not be good actually
because he's a little bit too trapped in
here how tall is he is he okay he's not
he's only two blocks or three blocks
maybe yeah so he's about oh oh no don't
run away don't run away I could
potentially like empty all the water out
of this room pretty easily with these
all right yeah I've got air pockets now
I wanted to make a portal to transport
them into the nether but I don't think
I'll be able to set one up big enough in
this room all right well let's try it
anyway we will see if we can build a
portal
he's just bigger than I thought he was
is the problem so we might be able to
fit them through but it's not looking
the greatest put that there that there
this here and then if we slime block the
middle we might be able to light it
although hmm it's so tough because we
can't uh ooh
he took damage
it's tough because we can't break blocks
normally we unless you're using these
slime blocks oh there we go today maybe
if we do don't can't break it like that
you know what I got to do I got to get
rid of all the water around it that's
right and make sure it doesn't reek
reate it slope maybe this is a nightmare
um don't think it's gonna work no
there's still water here darn it um what
to do what to do what if we do it like
this and I go inside with it and then we
do this here we go here we go this might
work okay now I can probably light it
break ourselves out see a minecart idea
looking easier that then what I'm doing
here possibly so now I want to see if I
can push him into it so I'm going to set
up a couple blocks alongside it and kind
of shove them oh did work yes oh man all
right what are we doing on invisibility
we're still good let's go through and
see where he ended up oh man that is
awesome
all right so we got him to the nether
now if we want to move them he can
either jump around himself or a lot of
that hurt or we could move them with a
minecart
darn I can't break it Oh guys you know
what we got to try here the normal
Guardians they bounce like crazy on
slime blocks I want to see if he does
too can I place it I don't know if he's
jumping high enough oh he's just jumping
a little bit short okay yeah let's try a
half slab just to get him a little bit
higher up should be able to place this
right right right yeah there we go
oops I didn't want to place too okay now
I should be able to put this down oh he
had a bounce Oh
sometimes he bounces yeah he's bouncing
good kids
OOP sorry guy sorry um maybe we will do
something fun with that because I have a
feeling he's going to be able to bounce
like 10 to 15 blocks up like the normal
Guardians do if we set this up right
okay so I got no mining fatigue right
now I brought some milk I want to see
just how annoying it would be to have
this guy in our nether okay there it is
I'm going to drink the milk and we'll
see how long it is before we get another
one of those in the meantime I'm going
to try to change this up so he has more
freedom to bounce or more space to
bounce so I'm going to dig out above
them so far hasn't kicked back in that's
good where is he he's probably oh yeah
he's right there I gotta shut the portal
off I brought some water to do that and
I'm just gonna make him a little thing
for him to bounce up here looks like
he's like two by two by two so it's not
too bad actually it hasn't come back on
so it probably only comes on every
minute or two I don't know we will see
I wasn't able to put the port alot with
waterside his broke it and replaced the
Citian we are ready to try this out now
see if he can bounce really high like
the other Guardians and he seems to kick
in the mining fatigue every minute and
that oh there we go again
which is what the wiki page says - all
right so I'm gonna get a ladder ready oh
no no no no no no no no no don't you
dare don't you dare you're my pet you're
supposed to love me okay so let's get
the slime block there and with one
doesn't seem to bounce too much
- come on bounce oh there goes Oh nobody
takes damage oh man okay okay stop stop
stop I don't want you to die yeah he
definitely bounces but the whole damage
taking might be an issue how could we
deal with that is there any way we could
deal with it let's try it again here but
this time we will aim to get all four
slime blocks down not just two and see
if he'll be okay and I got them healed
that just kicked in very good so I'm
gonna get rid of one of these slabs
place this down oh whoa whoa place it
place it place it place it place it
place it there we go and we take the
slab out oh don't don't die before I
finish this oh oh oh
don't die don't die see still taking
damage got all four down oh man yeah I
think he might be okay now yeah that
might be might have been the trick let's
could take a look how high can he jump
um is he hitting his head or H&E go even
higher I wonder
all right let's uh try get up there is
he hitting his head I think he is
actually hitting his head still so he
can jump even higher possibly oh he
kicked in again yeah he seems fine now
though like he's not taking damage
that's cool let's do another one of
these in us let's make sure we don't get
trapped up here good yeah I'm gonna take
out some more and apparently I've dug a
top tunnel here and I had no idea okay
let's take out these because he might
even be stronger than the regular
Guardians like you might be able to jump
even higher than them oh that might be
it there yeah that's it holy smokes so
that could be a fun little display for
them if we have a long tube that he's
jumping up and down in and we can get a
bunch of them through if we want
whoo oh yeah he's perfectly fine that's
cool all right guys let's get to the
comments for today I picked out two the
first one says ethos and by have you
played any MOBA games such as dota or
League of Legends if so what do you
think about them I used to play the
Warcraft 3 custom games and I believe
that's where dota originated from so I
have played the original dota from
Warcraft 3 it got to the point where
about half the games hosted where dota
it was super popular but I never liked
it I always bugged me because people all
the people were playing that instead of
other games which I thought were better
uh-huh and that's about it
I haven't tried the new ones I haven't
tried League of Legends or any of that
just they don't really appeal to me
based on my past experience
so what's your favorite pasta dish I
like cheese filled pasta so I like like
tortellini I like ravioli and that kind
of stuff I would say is my favorite and
I prefer tomato-based sauces over cream
based sauces uh-huh
all right guys that is going to do it
for today thank you for watching and
hope you enjoyed and I will see you
again in the next one
why do I keep getting butchers it's like
all I get is butchers what is up with
that seriously like 50% of the villagers
I get are butchers alright anyway see
you guys thanks for watching bye bye