[Music]
a-hole all right guys this is it the new
Minecraft 1.14 update is out
oh we have lots of new stuff to check
out lots of new things to see and a hits
us right away here as soon as I log in
BAM new texture pack in Minecraft 1.14
what do we think about this guys hmm I
don't know eyes I haven't looked around
the world yet I kind of wanted to do it
with you guys I just logged in pretty
much into the world and there's
definitely some very notable differences
like we've we've been like always kind
of against texture packs in this but now
for the first time in the official game
we have one forced upon us like I logged
in with the new textures so they like
want us to use them it wasn't like an
extra choice I could choose from
thankfully though if we want to go back
it has they have given us the option if
we go to resource packs we just add in
the programmer art the classic look of
Minecraft toss that over to the right
here we got new loading screens now
which is really nice and we go back to
the normal looking minecraft so I kind
of want to go around and just look at
some of the textures we got to fix
something in the mind in the man cave
here as well so we can do that together
but let's just kind of we're going to go
to the whole episode in this new texture
pack I'll kind of give you some of my
initial thoughts on this I don't like
the planks okay the planks are kind of
the the big deal breaker here because
the man cave is loaded with planks but a
lot of the other blocks
I don't think look that bad like I
preferred this new smooth stone it's a
little bit rounder a little bit softer
there's a lot of other blocks like soul
Sam looks a little smoother you know I
like the glowstone lamps the glass guy's
glass has improved quite a bit they
remove some of the streaks in it so it's
a lot more transparent now and I
definitely prefer
that yeah let's go let's go take a
little look around you'll notice like we
can see through leaves now which I don't
like I'm thinking like we either stick
with the old go with the new or we mix
the two together I kind of thinking
about mixing the two like what I like
from each one and putting it together
here's here's the big thing you know
first big change with Minecraft 1.14
it's actually a small change but it has
big implications to our world
oh I didn't see Mike over here what's
going on you'll notice it's dark over
here now so we should fix this right
away before we have some bad accidents
no Manatee pistons no longer our
transparent blocks so this was a trick
we did long ago in our worlds hide
lighting we hid glowstone or probably
yeah it's pumpkins actually because I
was so cheap at the time I didn't have
glow stone I use pumpkins to light up
our paths and that's not a thing anymore
so enchanting tables aren't transparent
anymore pistons we got a crafting table
here I think that's a new sound actually
I've heard that one before so is that
actually so this actually works they're
transparent they made slabs transparent
which is weird because I feel like
they're gonna change that again in the
future like this is the easy fix just
doing that well I know in a future patch
that's not gonna work right well
actually maybe maybe it is still dark
with it let's check our lighting light
level seven okay so these aren't
transparent whoops okay
undo undo we might have to go for
trapdoors then just as a temporary fix
for today but we just can't have this
place overrun with bobs you know
got figured out what the leg is old it's
bad kitty
Bad Kitty this is like what I don't know
what I did with this farm but it's so
laggy there's something wrong with the
redstone in that thing oh I just did the
kitty get off the pressure plates I not
intentional honestly so the trap doors
don't look better than the Pistons for
sure well I'll probably try to do is
hide some lighting and the leaves above
and then get rid of get rid of all these
on on the ground but this is just the
fix for today so we don't get overrun by
creepers and stuff in here yeah we got
we got mobs all over the place guys
there's a creeper there up there
things are gettin a ste oh snap how are
we doing over here this area is fine
okay okay what about over here yeah so I
think the cats they stand up like when
you get attacked and then they go places
you don't want them to go like on on the
pressure plates okay we got a dark spot
up here I started making a list as well
by the way so if we decide to mix the
two texture packs together these are the
ugly blocks that we'll probably want to
replace in my opinion but I want to see
what you guys say about the whole idea
before we do anything let's actually
check out the ugly brick thing how does
brick look in this texture pack ooh nice
thing about this is we're eating free
Pistons you know the ugly brick thing
did it think you could get worse but I
think it got worse we might we might be
adding a bricks to the list here
yeah this is nice too by the way they
change books so now you can actually
like you have a cursory you move around
and edit
instead of only being able to edit the
into the page which was super annoying
before if you ever had to change
something in your book oh yeah there's a
piston yeah this was always a dark spot
in the cave like right over here I never
could figure out a way to hide lighting
that reached up to that point also with
the slabs it looks like they do let
light through if it makes sense like if
we have that little gap there then it
lets light through through the half slab
area which is pretty cool that's a nice
way of doing it all right it's very good
very good so we lit up most of the cave
now you have adverted disaster and we
can get to some of the some of the fun
stuff I did decide to add melons to the
list as well
I don't know that yellow is not it's not
doing it for me it's pretty stripey
so I decided to add those and I think
that where we might want to change the
bark like if we do a mixed pack this new
barks not bad but I think the original
is slightly better uh-huh yeah this
place is lit up again all right cool so
let's head over to the village that's
the big major thing with this update
yeah so many changes with villages and
villagers and stuff a lot of really cool
changes I think they overall made some
amazing additions to the game with this
update not a lot not a lot of stuff I
was upset about or sad about said maybe
maybe some of the texture pack stuff
yeah I'm not I'm not liking this brick
even really telling this room I think
the original was better for sure the
stone I think the original stone was
better - let's put a let's put a stone
question mark I'll see what you guys say
about that one and let's head on over so
I think our villages our villagers are
going to be the new type right yeah they
got their hats awesome okay so we got
with a new villager system I'm wondering
if they're gonna keep their old trades
or if we're getting brand new villagers
holy smokes all right some stuff this at
me you know you got mad
oh well what's happening here I know
they can get mad at each other now this
guy he's like no no not you you're a bum
you don't even have a job yet so if they
have this brown coat like this and they
don't have the coin purse that means
they're unemployed it's a bum of the
village he needs a work station to get a
profession if we try to trade with him
you kind of just shakes his head no I
don't got anything trade with you but
these guys they all have trades and I
think they're gonna they're gonna keep
their originals because he's fully
unlocked here he's a master so they have
different ranks like journey man master
this guy doesn't have an XP bar I guess
let's check this guy over here this was
my mending trade guy with the dragon
head
I love how is his head bobbles with the
dragon and on oh that's great okay do
you still have the mending trade you do
okay so they keep their old trades
okay let's actually head over to our
project Pokemon over here I'm kind of
curious about this because if you guys
remember they've actually redone the
trade system for villagers once already
in the game and any original villagers
you had kept their original trades plus
the new ones got stacked on top of that
and I'm just curious to see you know if
that's all still good here and yeah it
looks like that definitely still applies
so this is one of our special chibi
villagers you see he's got like two
paper trades and one written book for
one emerald you can't get that anymore
that's like super teeny so these are all
still good which is cool it looks like
he's a master though so we probably
won't get any new trades trading with
this guy I think he's maxed out already
by some bookshelf and we're out of money
here yeah I don't think he's gonna get
anything new unlocked we'll probably go
exploring them a little bit here and
check out more things with the villagers
but first off I just want
look at the sandstone so here's our
here's our before the original oh okay
as a pretty big change isn't it uh-huh
so new sand stones a little bit more
Brown I don't think it's that bad
actually it's uh it's one of those
things where I think we don't like
change our initial reaction to change is
always like oh I don't like that why
don't you just keep the way it was
originally but after a while of using
something you get used to it and then
you're kind of like I guess this this
new thing was actually better than the
old I kind of think it's like that with
some of these things like it's really
jarring looking at this right now but I
think we could get used to it and maybe
even liked it more because I've always
wished sandstone was a bit more Brown
I'm gonna get you I'm gonna get you what
I tell you so something that's worth
mentioning in this update I think
they've made some major performance
improvements like a lie a lot of times
when you guys see my frame rate you're
like wow itto get an upgrade already but
honestly it's the manty the mancave is
extremely laggy for anybody if you were
to load up my world and you'd go to the
man cave you'd be like what is going on
in here it's it's pretty bad but with
this updates like normally it goes down
to maybe 30 FPS if you look at the top
left there where it's 60 65 it jumped up
to 90 it kind of goes by 30 or intervals
so if you can do 90 plus it'll go up to
90 if it's 60 plus it'll it'll go to 60
kind of thing
so normally we're getting around like 60
over here probably and we're getting 90
now so that's pretty major things are
loading a lot quicker like when you when
you change resource packs and stuff that
happens so much faster if you exit the
game and stuff that happens quicker one
thing I did notice though while flying
around
I don't think slowed faster I think
they're slower for whatever reason like
we're getting a lot of invisible chunks
normally this was able to keep up like
in the last update everything would kind
of load as you go
so hopefully that gets taken care of in
future minor patches but anyways guys I
think we're gonna go do some exploring
now so we're actually twelve thousand
thirteen thousand blocks out now in
brand-new terrain and we're gonna start
looking for some of the new features
with with the update here I thought this
area was pretty cool though this has
nothing to do with update it just looks
really cool
anything with a no we're hanging like
this is super super awesome
it's got like these pillars holding the
sand up I like this area a lot actually
okay let's look at the map in case we
ever want to come back here or our
coordinates but we're gonna we're gonna
keep going here whew alright look at
this we got ourselves a tundra biome and
I can see them right away here as soon
as we walked into this place so many
berries what are they called again sweet
berries yeah sweet berries uh-huh oh
yeah so these things are spiky if you
didn't know
looks like our armor I didn't notice
that yes our armor protects us from the
poking if we take this off its gonna
hurt a lot I think yeah we took half a
heart that's it doesn't hurt as much as
I thought
but you take the damage very quickly
actually
and it probably causes durability damage
right so we're at 350 for 352 yeah so
that goes down pretty quick every hit
and I'm assuming we plant these yeah so
we put the berries down it it makes a
new plant if you break the plants you
don't get any berries so I just you
should first them by right clicking not
by killing them like I've been doing
uh-huh so what do you guys think what's
your opinion panda's verse foxes who
wins I gotta say I think I like the Fox
is a lot more the pandas are cool though
don't get me wrong the pandas are really
cool I'm really excited about the foxes
I think they look super cute and I love
I love the functionality that they got
too so I'm hoping we can find some here
oh so cool
hey guy hey oh he went to sleep the
naptime oh yeah
so these guys they are they'll run away
from you like they're so scared but if
you shift it's kind of like the Ocelot
thing where they'll they'll kind of
ignore you they don't hear you get right
up to him you can feed them these sweet
berries I think he might be a friend no
now he still runs away still runs away
okay alright foofy I'm gonna take a
quick nap here do you do you on the bed
like the kitties do I just not okay okay
he doesn't care about the bed so I'm
gonna take it
no foofy no food give it back so yeah
they can pick up items in their mouth
which is pretty pretty awesome and then
to get it back you have to like give
them something they prefer yeah oh you
took the meat so you get our bed back
apparently you didn't give them like
swords and stuff too and they can use it
for fighting and it'll actually boost
their damage like incredibly which is
cool ah this this might be the end of
Luffy though we're gonna try to take
them back home cuz I don't know if they
spawn naturally in Tundras or if you
have to like find them and it's like a
one time spawn thing but we want to kind
of go south to the west this way oh you
just ate the meat I don't know this
trick still works but before we were
allowed to we were allowed to grab oh I
think you dropped oh dear
oh man okay I did it wrong ah floofy
Luffy dang it used to be able to use one
firework without the lead detaching I
think I might have done it wrong though
I was hoping we could fly him to the
ocean I think he dropped down
oh snap okay we found one we found one I
can't believe it
this is great so this is an illegitimate
I don't wanna I don't want to trigger
the thing or anything like that I just
want to I just want to get idea of
what's kind of operation they got going
on here as a great position for it so I
got the very top of a mountain where
they got view of the whole terrain
around them uh-huh so we got that nearby
that's cool so I found something else
nearby here - I had this this kind of
crazy idea by the way I couldn't find
floofy I think something happened to
foofy and there were no other flew fees
in that area so we kind of just moved on
here to the plains I had this idea maybe
we try to create like an outpost today
like we'll settle down in a village and
like build it up and and live there for
a while and then when we feel we got it
in a good position will trigger one of
the raids and watch it get destroyed or
try to defend it at the very least I
think that could be a fun thing I don't
know if we'll do all that in this
episode but I thought we would start
getting settled in a little bit although
I'm kind of lost now our Elijah wing is
about to break as well as the thing I
only brought the one pair we actually
don't have enough to your ability to get
home so we're kind of stranded out here
pretty quickly we got to settle down
there is oh man I should have marked the
coordinates there's a village I saw that
it was pretty cool nearby I think it was
this way I don't remember the swamp
being here though oh we got time to
renew your body too okay we might be
able to find more flue fees this Tundra
oh it's wooded mountain I think that's
different
no oh man okay I didn't find the village
I was looking for and we have lost our
wings okay we got a bit of a decision
here now so I stumbled across another
village the one I saw originally was
really cool it's like up in the
mountains and you know we would have had
to build bridges and stuff to connect
the parts together but this is more of a
plain-jane old village out in the plains
you know on flat land the thing is
though I can't find that other village
I know it's nearby I just can't find it
for the life of me and our Elijah wings
are worn out so I think this will have
to do this will be harder to defend in a
raid though like if it's up in the
mountains I don't think the the raid
pathfinding is gonna work too well but
if it's on like flat land like this it's
gonna be a bit of a challenge for us so
are they fighting
uh-huh but this is a new village so you
can tell we got like different pathing
and stuff it's not the perfectly
straights boring villages like we used
to have we got updated houses and stuff
which is pretty cool as hay bales
hanging outs they look much nicer now
and we got work stations so this is for
I think cleric the brewing stand it's
actually kind of interesting like those
generates in the overworld now you don't
have to go to the nether to find broom
stands oh and we got the Bell here okay
let's ring the bell and see how many how
many guys we get here we got some wolves
nearby and we even have some bones so
let's let's get started on like oh the
golems over there too let's get started
on like taenia some animals and stuff so
yeah I kind of want to like get some
animals here I want to make some farms I
want to fortify it and then trigger the
raid basically and hopefully expand the
population because we might only have
two people is what it's looking like we
got a farm here a couple little houses
nothing too crazy
that's the plain old bed in there got
our villager okay so he wants he wants
carrots and he'll sell us bread let's
trigger the bread already so I want to
try I want to try to get these guys
breeding and I'm assuming you still need
to trade with them to get them to breed
together all right we got our work cut
out for us here so we have a nitwit as
its taking a census of our village the
farmer is our main guy we got to make
sure he doesn't die
we got nitwit we have a farmer and I
think we just have a cleric and that's
it three villagers this place is going
down but we're gonna try yeah we're
gonna try build it up we'll see how this
goes what's the cleric trade oh he's
gone he was in here before it's so hard
to find these oh I was at that Oh so we
have two cleric buildings I see okay
what's our wings at 14 yeah he's in here
okay and he's he's gonna buy zombie
flesh so at night time I'm gonna have to
hunt zombies and try collect enough so
that we can trade but during the daytime
here we're gonna start getting to work
and trying to make improvements to our
village first step here we got a free of
a golem so that he can actually help out
if things go south so I think he's kind
of trapped in here let's check the crops
see if we actually have any carrots I
can't tell with the texture path
actually I think this is beetroot
beetroot seeds that's gotta be wheats
got potatoes just regular weeds oh we do
have carrots okay so all the bomyeo we
get here we're gonna use to grow carrots
to begin with so we can do the trade so
that we can start getting new villagers
maybe let's go one two three something
like this all right we're gonna put some
sneaky water over here all right very
good very good so we just set up like a
little carrot farm outside the
blacksmith probably put a fence gate
there get some shears here
oh look at that the the golem came out
of his little hidey-hole oh he wants to
go back though oh wait a second let's
let's block this off so he can't go back
that way yeah okay you you go to work
guy so in the village here we got some
trees like in the middle of the path
from some reason so we're gonna chop
these down that doesn't make sense to me
this one maybe now I'm gonna give her
this one to Guerra the trees we're gonna
share some leaves and basically we're
trying to put work into this village you
know and build it up from nothing and
feel satisfaction in that and then light
destroy it is the dream alright
share these leaves so it's kind of cool
how they got this they got like one path
going this way and the other one going
this way so I thought we would put the
leaves kind of in the middle here
instead have like a little separator and
then we can hide some lighting
underneath that if we want to plant down
a couple of our sweet berries I don't
know about this that farmer has been on
the roof for quite a while and I think
he's either stuck up there or he's
contemplating life for something does
this do anything
I thought the Bell was supposed to call
them to like the center of the village
is that not what it does this guy went
to check out our carrot for him and he's
like trapped in there now he doesn't
know how to get out I think he was
trying to go that way and the fence got
in his way
now he has no idea what to do start
breeding up our our wolf population to
defend the village and us when the raid
happens
I spent the night hunting mobs and now I
think we have enough zombie flesh where
we can trigger this guy's trade a few
times so then hopefully these two will
start breeding together so we got a
trade with them and they need to have
beds and there's a lot of beds in this
village so they should have enough I
think but we'll make a few more just in
case something something's gotta happen
right I've traded with both of you oh no
they just they looked into each other's
eyes they they had a moment and then
they just walked off cuz the Sun is
setting no all right I guess they're not
quite ready to breed let's let's fear
the sheep that came with the village
here we'll start making more beds maybe
they need more beds I don't know there's
probably like well there's a fence gate
okay cool
probably at least like seven eight beds
in this village I would think but maybe
that's not enough alright so we haven't
checked out the blacksmith here yet
either like what kind of goodies we got
with it that guy went back into that
spot I don't know why it's kind of
annoying so I guess this doesn't have an
anvil anymore on the outside you got a
grind wheel instead or a repair and
disenchant ER so you can no longer
combine tools together to repair them
you have to use this thing and you can
also remove enchantments off of gear you
yet so I got this off of like a skeleton
or something it's got feather falling so
we can choose to remove the feather
falling and Chapman Thanh it's and when
we do that we get a little bit XP
actually which is pretty cool that's the
neat little thing so you can repair
things there and you can disenchant
things inside we got some bread okay we
oh we got a saddle that's actually great
because there's a lot of horses around
here and I wasn't able to check them out
so I like that it looks like the blast
blacksmith doesn't have a bed so we'll
add one in here
gotta get our bed population up put one
in here I think I'm gonna give her this
ladder that that guy that went on the
roof he got stuck up there so enough of
them shenanigans okay
the village is starting to take a little
bit of shape here and it needs a lot of
work but we're not doing anything super
crazy either we just kind of want to get
it a little bit more presentable you
know so yeah with all the new villagers
they all have like their own work
station we haven't really checked out
too many of these so he's the farmers
they get this composter you can throw I
don't you put leaves in oh yeah you
can't see you you put leaves in here
kind of fills up with the podzol and
that turns to bone meal and and you get
yet you in turn like seeds and garbage
into bone meal basically which is pretty
cool this is also where they have to
come to restock like after you trade
with them in order to reset the trades
they have to go to each of their own
workstations so that the farmer comes to
this thing the cleric goes to is brewing
stand and that resets I think once or
twice a day which is pretty cool uh-huh
and if we have like unemployed villagers
we need to set up workstations
unoccupied ones I believe that they will
go to and choose a profession basically
oh yeah and check this out this is
pretty cool so he he wants to buy
carrots off of us right so if we hold up
a carrots I think he holds up an emerald
yeah so he'll show that that's what
he'll give us in return if we unselect
the carrot then it goes away which is
awesome so this guy's getting pretty
close to the point where he might level
up actually he'll do it at the next
stage so also I want to point this out
because he's a Novus right now that's
like the lowest drink he just has
like an iron coin first there or silver
one or whatever you went in the
composter look at that alright and now
if he upgrades though he should get a
better coin purse
so did you level up and it unlocks the
new trades yeah so you see it went from
iron to like bronze now he's an
apprentice we got new trades and he'll
buy pumpkins from us and he'll give us
apples okay
basically you're gonna keep doing the
carrot trade with him and I'm gonna
trade some emeralds with the other guy
so that we can hopefully trigger them to
breed one two three okay that should be
enough to level up this is gonna go from
iron to bronze right where are you going
where are you going no come back no now
we went back inside okay did you level
up you need one more trade alright now
he leveled up yeah he's got bronze cool
so now he'll take gold for emeralds or
we can buy a single lapis for an emerald
ouch that's a little bit nasty come on
guys you can do it
you can do it uh-huh uh-huh oh there's a
guy up there I never even knew that wait
a second wait a second do we have
another villager like we have the nitwit
as well that green coat one but who is
this guys it's our blacksmith he's been
trapped up here the whole time
oh he's unemployed okay that's
interesting well uh you I'm gonna let
down I think there's any houses up there
or anything he's he's been there the
whole time right oh man okay that that
wasn't smart guy I would have let you
down you have to go that route okay well
we just got a new villager oh and did he
just
transform because he's got an eyepatch
and stuff now anyways guys I think we're
gonna have to wrap up our episode here
for today and next time we'll spend a
little bit more time in this village and
then will trigger the raid and probably
head back and start doing some more
technical things with the new updates or
checking out new contents but I thought
this would be a fun little goofy thing
because I kind of I'm kind of curious
like how hard it is to start up a
village now that it's changed then with
the new system yeah anyways let's get to
it here so the comment of the day it
says etho have you ever needed to know
something about your own base and
instead of checking it directly in
Minecraft you Google it's let's say you
are doing redstone in a very cramped
space and you need to remember how you
did certain circuits in another part of
your base so you just google it instead
of go and check it for yourself
haha I have actually done that a few
times like I'll check the video
especially for coordinates and stuff
sometimes
I'll have no idea and I'll remember I
showed it in a video in the past or
something and all
I'll get the coordinates that way uh
generally though if I want to see how
something is built it's a lot easier to
do it in the world than to see the video
which is unfortunate for you guys so
what I do we're getting out of your
villager talk to you later I'm actually
surprised I've shown this before several
times and none of you have asked about
this world this is the world I've had
for a very long time so this is planning
LP okay it's different from our regular
LP it's basically our LP world copied a
long time ago and I've just been using
it as like a creative worlds and every
now and then like it's way behind our
current LP world bye bye probably two
three years at least I think but like
whenever I have an idea for a project or
something usually I do the creative work
in here and I'll just do like a little
whatever there's lots of little random
garbage gizmos all over the place that
don't really do anything you can see the
start of our
mastermind game here and some of the the
technical things like I'll go into this
world and work it out because the
redstone is free here and stuff you know
it's easy to to build things when you're
in creative and then if I ever need to
check something that I've built in the
past I can just go into spectator mode
and like check out something I've made
before but yeah this place is just
littered with all kinds of random things
some of them that got built some of them
that never got built sore that aren't
really refined in this world there's
lots of lots of crazy gizmos you can see
I'm having really bad chunk loading
issues uh-huh maybe someday maybe
someday this will get built I'll just
goof around with random stuff here I
think this was part of the Simon Says
game the hexadecimal dakota or something
this was an alternate version of the
super smelter that i decided to go with
a different version and yeah I've done
like building building things I've
played around with I tried prismarine at
some point with the Sandy City here and
I didn't really like it tried a bunch of
different colors here and yeah basically
if I need to goof around in the world in
our LP worlds or if I need to check
something I'll come here most of the
time a lot time it is beneficial to go
look at a youtube video though uh-huh
anyways guys that's it for today hope
you enjoyed it thanks for watching until
next time take care have a wonderful day
bye bye
[Music]