[Music]
greetings everybody and welcome back to
another
episode that's right another
not another or another
another episode yeah
so i've been i've been working up here i
got the lights installed i'll show you
that before i
fill it in it's night time right now uh
we got our light sensor down there
right right there and it goes to these
lights and then they go further to these
lights and
it's a very subtle indicator but it
should do the trick
fill it in
and we are good i also did one other
special thing with this and
i'm pretty happy with it so
let's skip ahead to day i think it works
i haven't tried it yet but i'm pretty
sure it does
and we'll be able to see difference
between the darkness now
and when it gets lit up during the day
so
here we go let's get our sound up
oh one ladder left
whoa that's pretty loud all right so
this is what it looks like at night it's
pretty dark
go to sleep
beautiful morning
[Laughter]
isn't that awesome oh i love that so
much
so i have a morning song that plays now
every morning
and uh that was it i'll go show you that
uh it took me probably two hours to do
or so
uh to figure out how to tune it and also
actually put it in where is that
oh it's right there
all right yeah down here where i got the
note blocks
uh there's 27 note blocks in total
and i got them pretty condensed i didn't
put any of the chords of the song
in that is uh oh what's that song called
morning mood is what's called so
let's play it one more time while we're
down here
oh it's pretty cool so nice addition to
the cave i think
i would like to have a nighttime song
too maybe
but i don't know what to pick for that
if you guys have suggestions please let
me know and if you can
and tune it for me too oh that would be
awesome
because i suck at it it took me so long
to get this one
working i it was a little frustrating
like i went on
youtube to try find a nice song to play
and it's like nobody tells you how to
to tune anything so
finally i just got frustrated and picked
the song on my own
figured out how to tune it
actually you know what i don't want to
be that guy either so
what i'm going to do is i'm going to put
the instructions on
on how to tune this in a notebook and
then i'll show it to you
so just give me a minute or two here and
i'll get that done
all right guys here it is this is the
notebook uh with the song in it if you
want to copy the song and use it in your
own minecraft world
uh this is how i did it it might not be
correct i'm not an expert on this
i also skipped doing the chords because
it would have taken more space
and i didn't know how to because it goes
through
several octaves that you can't do in
minecraft
um well you probably can i just don't
know how
and also this is just the intro of the
song i didn't do the whole song
so morning mood 27 notebox in total
and the way i laid this out this tells
you which number of noteblock it is
the first number here uh this
then this next thing here is how long of
a delay before that note
so before it since this is a first note
there is no delay
and then the second number here is the
number of
of right clicks you do on the note block
to get that tuning
and this is actual notes b g sharp
f sharp
and oh yeah and if you want to see how
to do it just pause the video
so page one page two page three
and i hope you enjoy so i'm gonna store
this down here in case for some reason
i accidentally dig into it or creeper
blows it up or something like that i'll
have a reference still
as well let's just put it here
and yeah if you have an idea for a
nighttime song please let me know
uh maybe a lullaby or something of that
nature
or maybe there's a better song yes i
don't know
all right uh the moon is going down
sun is coming up i just want to make
sure it works if it
it happens normally not just when i
sleep in the bed
i'll talk about the plan for today uh i
was going to build something
and then show it to you oh
it's morning
yeah that's a pretty good time for it to
trigger i'd say
oh yeah you know what i want to do today
let's head on over here i want to
mess around with the automatic brewing
stuff
uh but i'm not doing a full-blown
potion room i just want to make a speed
potion
dispenser thing that automatically
refills itself
like this thing here i don't use this
thing all that often to be honest and
the reason
is because i know when i use it i have
to refill it and
even even though i have the potions here
just the fact that i have to constantly
refill it
kind of bugs me but the idea with this
is you just walk in
and then you get potioned for six
minutes
although speed two is over compensating
for it
so yeah that's that's kind of the plan
for today and i was going to build it
and then show it to you and then it's
like
you know what that's not what that's not
what i'm about
i don't build stuff and then show it
that's a bad habit
uh at least i think
viewers would rather watch me build it
and overcome the problems i
have when building it and see how i
design it and that
that kind of thing so that's what we're
going to do today i got stuff ready to
go here you can make hoppers
in vanilla oh man
where is it chest
and stone is all it takes yeah i heard a
rumor
well i heard from somebody that you
can't and i just
i didn't think to check myself uh so
last episode i thought you couldn't make
them but you can
good news that means we can actually
have fun with them today
so let's get it going here let's get
building
designing and all that fun stuff
whenever i make something involving
redstone
this is the first step i always do i
always work on
i have no idea how much space we need uh
i always work on
like the face plate or the the look of
it first
figure out where i want stuff positioned
that the player has to interact with not
necessarily what block
colors i'm using and all that but their
actual positions
does matter quite a bit so we'll have a
little
entrance thing like we have downstairs
we'll put our dispenser at head level
again
there's a like i do have this somewhat
planned out but once we get to the
actual
automating and stuff i have no clue i
just know the look
i want to start out with here um
so yeah walk up step on pressure plates
get potion
um so the next idea i had
try to take the that block out
and we will
wait wait we need a hopper that's what
we need
get our hopper
and we're gonna try put one right there
i can't remember if they fixed it where
if stuff lands on the rim does it go in
now
or is that still not fixed
i think it might be fixed
come on rim throw it over here
this will tell us yeah okay it seems to
be fixed
so we'll have a hopper there and
we need a way of entering water bottles
into our system because there i don't
think there's any way of automating that
process we still have to feed it water
bottles
so i thought it would be cool to
do something like this have a water
stream
an infinite spring here
grab one of these and we'll use this to
fill up our water bottles
and it also doubles in function we have
an infinite spring
wherever we build this which you can
never have too many of those let's be
honest
uh so i think we'll do this and then
when somebody wants to fill up their
water bottles
should work out okay i know if they
right click on the hopper
it'll bring up the hopper
wait why does it have oh cause i was
throwing stuff at it that's right
um all right so if my inventory is full
of stuff
if it's full of water bottles or
anything uh when i
when i fill it up with water it's just
gonna fly out
and then we want that to go into the
hopper oh it looked like it didn't land
on the rim actually
or it might be full yeah it's probably
full yeah
okay so that's that's how we're gonna do
a quick refill for this thing when it
runs out of water bottles
uh hopefully if we can get stuff to work
that way as far as like for speed
potions we need
we need to give it another wart we need
to give it sugar
oh and redstone yeah we need redstone
and then gun powder so there's four
stages to brewing
all right and to get those
uh where we need them i think it would
be best just to have chests
i know there are ways of automatically
sorting things i've seen a few
but just for simplicity i'm going to
skip that all and just have chess
showing uh
maybe we'll try put them here
one for each unique item
get one more alright so one of those
will be
oh yeah and i brought these for that to
you
and that will tell us what items goes
where
there's going to be a lot to this isn't
there get out of here wool i don't watch
you
no i want my minecart
you know what i'm still dealing with the
hard to use
inventory it's getting fixed from what
i've heard
which is good so hard to move stuff
around
i feel like bwo slow fingers here
oh uh so yeah nether warts
sugar then redstone gunpowder so when we
when we load this we'll just put stuff
in manually
uh we might have indicator lights to
show if it runs out i don't know
that might make things too complicated
though
so i would like these to be easy to set
up in various places not like a big
thing to build
all right and then another wall here or
something
okay that's a pretty good look
oh yeah and we would want one for the
actual speed potion we could probably
put that right on the dispenser
or above
okay so that's the first thing now what
we got to figure out
how do the brewing stands actually work
because i haven't
i haven't tried that yet uh i have
i think i've heard that there's no
intelligence to the hopper
oh yeah these are wood aren't they yeah
weird um
okay we'll get one down make it
face the brewing stand then we'll throw
some items in and see what it does
okay is it if we throw it stone is it
gonna put it in
oh maybe there is a tail engine
intelligence to it
ah i grabbed the glass bottles i swear
okay if we throw glass bottles
they disappear
where'd my glass bottle go
are they actually disappearing
what wait no i'm missing
six aren't i
i had 49. now let's just go oh
they're going in oh right because the
first item
there yeah right if the first item can't
go in the next one won't go either
hey hey
just casually taking the stroll
all right um
although if the chest is there
um well yeah if we have a hopper there
that'll hold it
properly the water okay
so there does seem to be some actual
intelligence to it that's good news
um
with the setup it would be better if we
have four
brewing stands total instead of just
like trying to
get get to awkward potions and saying
them back to one brewing stand and
then getting speed potions and sending
them back and then doing the redstone
instead of doing that all in one
if we have it going in four it'll
probably be simpler and
it will make the brewing faster because
we only have to wait for one stage
instead of all
four um
i'm not sure for the glass the water
bottles
since they don't stack we should have at
least three double chests
full or for them um
hmm okay i'm going to stop for a second
just think a bit here
actually before we get any further here
what we really need to figure out
is uh how they these brewing stands
interact with the hoppers because
i've heard they just always eject
stuff into the hopper
you can't actually put that in the slot
that's interesting or in that slot
they must have changed that um
yeah so i just got taken out so that
means we're gonna have to do some timing
stuff
to make sure that doesn't happen i think
the way people have been doing that
or dealing with that from what i've seen
is they've been
they have like a storage minecarts that
will only stay there for so long
and then leave
and only be there at certain times i
think that's what we have to do
and just time it right i need another
chest
can't make a chest in that window oh and
it's night time
perfect opportunity to hear the morning
song again
oh what was that i think that's a
particle effect
morningstar
oh you know what i did i slept before it
switched to night
ah no morning song
so sad you know what i'm i am a little
concerned though
about that like i know in my old world
like with a storage room
hey uh the zelda tune that would always
play
eventually like over time i was starting
to get a little
annoyed with that to be honest not like
not always but
sometimes when i'd hear that it would
kind of bug me so i'm hoping that
doesn't happen with this
so far it's it puts a smile on my face
every time
okay so i think if we do this
glass bottle i grab the glass bottle i
think if we do this
yeah it only puts it in when the
minecraft goes there
that shouldn't be too hard to time
uh the other thing we got to do before
we get any further here we go to
wire up our dispenser i think and sort
of plan things around that
uh that might be a bit tricky with the
water
and not being able to see where i am
oops oh darn it
ah one second i think i'll just do this
off camera
i might do it like this wiring have the
redstone dust below
that points into
this block with one torch then it goes
up to another torch
and up and up like that i could have ran
the redstone torch right here
where this block is but then the water
would have flowed into it so i have to
go one block
out oops problem with doing that though
is now the hopper
is going to have to go to one of these
sides instead of
yeah because this is the block here with
the redstone torch on
all right so i had to rip this up a
little bit i was having some trouble i
finally figure out how to place a hopper
the direction you want though
uh what it is is it it connects to
whatever block
your cursor is facing so right now i'm
facing this side of the block
so it will connect to that block if i'm
facing
the grass when i place it it'll go down
towards the grass
and i was struggling with that a little
bit but now i understand
okay that still works uh what we got to
do
actually let's put a block here we're
going to run a second hopper
because and
yeah one here oops
there because uh we there's gonna be
water above here and we can't really run
rail
uh if there's water above we better go
to sleep
now we're gonna hear the warning song i
demand it
give me the morning song right now
all right back to work um
yeah so we'll have our water back in uh
we gotta do some more testing i think
to see how the brewing stands interact
with the hoppers there's a few things
that
oops still still need to figure out here
all right just want to double check this
if i have like a stack of nether wart in
here is it going to
pump it through oh the whole stack all
at once
interesting that's a little scary
hmm
why is the pump so fast
i thought
oh boy i thought it would pump one at a
time at least
it went the whole thing
okay so it goes to the hopper instantly
but then it goes to
minecart one at a time uh
that's a bit scary we might have to fill
the hopper up with stuff to stop that
or just fill in the oh yeah we might
just have to fill in the last uh
four slots or something to stop that
with something you can't
use well i don't know
all right i'll think about that next
thing gotta figure out will a hopper
pick stuff
up if there's a rail over top from the
mine carts
so we will
we'll do this oops
run a rail line over top
and a block and do we have another chest
no let's just use a dispenser
okay so stuff we put in here
is this empty yeah stuff we put in here
should hopefully go into that dispenser
go go man
awesome okay that might be a good way of
doing the brewing stands have like
brewing stand hopper then to the left
have a rail line
then then hopper
brewing stand and
yeah i might do a staircase shape if we
do that
hmm i wonder if there's a better way
uh i've been thinking about this and i'm
pretty sure
we have to have the brewing stand on top
of a hopper the problem is
then it's always pulling the potions and
stuff out
so i think we have to jam it up with
stuff
and have one spot with whatever it
normally brews
and then just time it right
so that's the cart is only there
actually let's try something here too
uh wait what i want to try
oh yeah i want to see what order they
enter the cart is it going to be
water bottle water bottle water bottle
water bottle or is it going to be water
bottle combo couple cup a cup of water
bottle water bottle you know what i mean
let's check that out
hello minecarts did they go to the
oh they went down yeah
okay water bottle first that's good news
i i think next update they're probably
going to change it where
the hopper will work off of red a
redstone signal or at least i hope they
do because
uh it's really hard to control it if you
if you can't use redstone like how long
you want it to be on for
it's a work in progress so i'm sure
they'll do something to make it better
but what i'm doing now got that filled
up
there's three potions so when this
finishes
somehow we have to tell the cart it's
done and it's going to come
and hopefully only pick up three potions
here
if it picks up less that's fine we can
adjust it so that it stays longer
if it picks up more than three though i
don't know how to make it
quicker to be honest oh
oh it only picked up one okay
so we need to slow it down
uh the easiest way of me to figure out
the timing is probably just do something
like this
set up a chest hopper another chest put
items in
and then i go to my recording software
afterwards and take
and count how long it takes for three
three items to leave here
and i should have my exact time needed
and i just did that and it looks like
each item
moves through the hopper at a rate of 1
every 0.35 seconds
so just about a third of a second so
three items is probably going to be
one second or 1.05 seconds
or in repeater language
somewhere between
that and that i think
however curt travel time also adds that
delay so i just have
i have like two seconds worth of delay
there and i have the hopper with
some stuff in we can see and adjust it
pretty easily just by doing this
seeing how much it picks up from that so
we got six
let's shorten this a little bit
see what it takes next time
three okay that's what we want three is
the number we want can we repeat that
three
four oh that's bad
uh it's inconsistent uh let's
let's shorten that one more tick
try it again
three
four hmm
why so inconsistent
uh shorten it one more
well you know it's probably possible
then
get the in between i would
think
oh i might press that button too soon
four again no way
all right whoops well that's gonna mess
everything up
darn it uh one more timing thing i want
to figure out
is how long it takes to actually brew
stuff that's pretty important
is there anything in there let's just
fill this up
so let's brew let's brew some potions
here and i'll time it
this is i guess we'll just brew two
because that's all the bottles we have
okay and
here it goes so i'm gonna go back to my
editing software and just check how long
this takes i think it's the same for
every
like no matter what you're brewing
um we got to figure out how we're going
to activate everything as a problem
oh why'd the cart just move that was
weird
okay so that's what we got or that's
what we needed
uh to act or to time things
properly i think what we have to do is
have one of these
this will tell us how many things are in
a brewing stand
well we'll just steal these we're always
going to be doing three though
so it'll put out a redstone signal based
on how many items are in it
so if there's only one item it goes
three blocks if there's
two
seven seven blocks uh we'll
have to invert that i think
right i don't know uh and if there's
three things in we want it to turn on
maybe it wants all
no
we have to subtract okay that's on now
one item turns it off hmm
i don't know if that's really what we
want i guess i could probably work too
i don't know all right so based on that
we can tell if we need
to make stuff happen and
when we make stuff happen we have to
figure out how long
in between making stuff happen so i'm
gonna check the editing
well it looks like it takes potions 20
seconds to brew
each each stage here so four stages
that's 80 seconds to brew a batch
of speed potions uh
this thing here i think i got this
timing correct now
so there's there's some blocks in there
i i changed it to 11
11 seems to be the trick number i
haven't seen it fail yet
there's three
six
nine so it's going up by three every
time pretty consistently it looks like
12.
so this is good i'm glad this works
it's very simple too
and all this is doing is acting as a
control to turn the hopper on and off so
it'll go
from it'll go through the cart and down
into this one
when we want it to 7
30 let's just go all the way make sure
i've done i've done a bunch of testing
before this too and i haven't seen a
fail
that's good that's going to be our
unloader i'm pretty sure
i have done a lot of rethinking here
though
it might like it looks like it's gonna
be extremely complicated
having four brewing stands so we should
probably switch to one
and yeah i wasn't really thinking about
this right
uh if we if we have our bottles
first and then we give
nether warts and then we give
our sugar and a redstone
this stuff going
what the heck oh it's stacking okay
sugar redstone gunpowder
oh it's going through
well maybe i'm not overthinking oh yeah
because the slots will all be full
so they'll go into this one at a time so
when it finishes with the netherward
there'll be a slot open for the sugar to
go in then they'll take the sugar out
and the hopper will act as our buffer
it'll do it one by one
bedtime
oh no it wasn't quite night time again i
did it again
uh also we can't have the chest like
this we have to have a hopper underneath
chest to take items out
that's a rule and i think it would be
better to use dispensers here
instead oh my gun powder
precious gunpowder what did i just throw
away
uh have four dispensers here facing
this way
with our items in so we'll still be able
to interact
with it on this side doesn't look quite
as good
as the chess i have to say but it'll
work better
and then we'll have redstone we'll
probably have to get rid of our infinite
spring too i hate to say
then have a water stream here which will
take
take the items to our brewing stand
hopper
and we'll just time these so that they
go out in the right order we'll also
have to have one for
the water bottles which will get fired
first
that will go to our brewing stand hopper
and then the plan i have with that
i was messing around with it here
uh basically this is kind of cool
this isn't going to brew but if we have
we have our order here
sugar redstone gunpowder we have a
comparator here
um let's just get rid of this
oh darn i should have showed you this
first darn
ah so much junk so hard to move items
around
so if there's only three items in here
the signal only reaches this far
so it doesn't go to this block here if
we have a fourth item like the
netherward in here
it will go all the way and
when stuff is brewing
it'll go all the way and
what i plan to do once this finishes
this nether wart
right right um if you look closely at
the end of this wire while i'm in the
window here
it's going to pulse once once this
finishes the netherwood's going to
disappear it's going to open up a free
slot for a moment a brief moment
and the gunpowder goes in i don't know
if you saw but it pulsed there
and what i plan on you doing is using
that little pulse
and a redstone locking counter
thing so uh i don't have the setup
though i
unfortunately but you can use locking
repeaters as a good counter you send a
quick pulse
to this line here then you lock it
so that the signal can't get through and
every time you pulse it it'll go through
one more repeater
until it finally makes it out the end
and when it gets to here
it's going to automatically
restarts the process of shooting out
water bottles
and then the ingredients
and it will restart everything if
it'll do a check as well if there's
enough water bottles in the chest we'll
use a comparator for that
then it will do all that stuff otherwise
we'll have to restart it with a button
that's my concept thing is
there might be a new patch tomorrow i'm
not sure what the plan is with that
uh and for all i know hoppers are
probably going to change
so i and the episode's getting longer so
i think we're just going to leave it at
this for today i have the concept
figured out it's just a matter of doing
it
oh it's daytime i can tell look at that
the light is on it's amazing uh just one
really really quick comment for today
because i went a little
longer than i should people ask why i
don't like making long episodes it's
because people
in general don't have long attention
spans especially when i'm doing redstone
so today i probably board a few people
i'm sorry
uh but this guy asks you can smelt with
blaze rods oh my goodness
yes you can i picked this one out
because his name had blazing
i thought that was kind of ironic uh
yeah you can smell it with blaze rods
you can spelt with coal
charcoal even things like sticks
saplings
fences all sorts of crazy stuff
crafting benches it's actually
surprising i see this a lot actually
people don't know you can smell with
blaze rods so
it's actually a common common unknown
fact
about minecraft okay thanks for watching
guys have a good day
bye
[Music]
you