hello everybody
whoo welcome back this is e though and
try something a little different today
I'm recording in the morning oh yes I am
as shocked as you I usually record in
the evenings because I I find that's
what I'm the most awake in the day but
I'm trying the morning I might have a
bit of a raspy voice
it is almost afternoon now it should be
gone I find when I wake up in the
morning I feel really tired I have pink
eyes for the at least 15 minutes and
then like they get auxin oxygenated
oxygenated that's a word yeah and they
turn white after a couple minutes of
being awake and raspy voice sometimes
I'm stuffed up in the morning but I find
when I record in the evening sometimes
stuff comes up during the day and it
prevents me from it so got to stay on
top of it get a head of recording that
way I don't miss days like like I did
yesterday and I wasn't happy about that
so to start off with today we're gonna
try oh finally got something we're gonna
try something a little different so get
ready for this when I when I meet
someone new and I'm getting to know them
and you know we're having conversation
what not I have a bunch of questions I
really really enjoy asking people
because you're almost guaranteed to get
an interesting or entertaining response
from people so I'm going to try ask you
guys one of these questions and just see
what happens so feel free to leave your
response in the comments and if there's
a good ones
I might even mention the next episode
and entertain people with your story
so one of the questions I like to ask
people is what was your most
physically painful experience in life
now keep in mind though your most
painful experience isn't necessarily the
same as your your worst injury that's
another question I like to ask people
ooh just what injury of your stands out
as being the most painful I guess and
it's a really fun question to ask people
because you never know what kind of
response are you going to get and
usually there's a good story that goes
along with it this thing is going off
way too quick by the way we're just
watching it right now I tweaked it to
slow it down but it still seems like The
Fountains going off too often but for me
I'll give you an example of how this
works when I was younger I was given a
pogo stick as a present sort of
unexpectedly ah did I break my I did
break it darn it I never used the pogo
stick before but I learned actually had
a lot of fun was that pogo stick but it
got to the point where I had no trouble
staying on it anymore I I mastered like
keeping my balance on it then I started
moving on to like tricks and stuff try
do some more entertaining things with
the pogo stick like I could do no hands
or just one foot on the pogo stick and
use it backwards that kind of stuff and
then I got to the point where I would
jump off of things with it and try climb
things with it um so one day I was above
concrete like as I jump it on concrete
with it and there was this wheel ramp
and the wheel ramp you drive your car on
that and it brings it up like a foot at
you chin get underneath to change the
oil real quick but you know what I'm
talking about so I decide I'm going to
jump up that with my pogo stick and then
jump off the end of it and drop down
like a foot with it and as I'm jumping
up this thing it musta caught one of the
knobs on it that the tire grips on and
it pushes it out from below me and my
pogo stick goes backward
right when I'm at the peak of the jump
and I come I drop down I think probably
three or four feet land right on my
knees like right on my knees I didn't
catch myself with my hands or anything
just landed straight down on concrete on
both my knees right on the funny bone on
both of them you know how you have the
funny bone right below your kneecap or
beside your kneecap landed right on that
for both legs and man that hurts so bad
I couldn't even cry I was just so
focused on the pain and I couldn't walk
for at least five minutes and I had to
be carried it so that was my most
painful experience feel free to leave
yours in the comments and I look forward
to reading them all right but anyway
let's get to it here I really feel like
doing something with villagers today so
I returned to the lost village here I
can't remember what we called this thing
even but we had three houses we had the
blue one yellow one and I believe
there's a green okay got the green one
here looks like tree grew that's awesome
I think I had a sapling in the bed there
that works okay so a long time ago I
look it even goes went through the wall
on this side a long time ago we worked
on this and didn't really do anything on
it since I had two villagers for some
reason they never did anything though
they didn't populate the village at all
might not be enough doors got one two
three four five six seven that's enough
for two there's another one and I'd
leave I don't think I put extra doors in
the blue house
No okay might try put some more doors in
there and then also the yellow one I
think there's a ton of doors in here oh
my here zombie I've no idea what
happened to the villagers either they
either got zombie or they took off down
some cave somewhere seven doors there so
this village should handle I would say
at least four or five villagers but
that's it
I bet that's one of them where is that
is that below oh look at this okay no it
wasn't them there's that unexplored cave
here interesting anyway so what we're
going to do to start off with we're
going to try to start this village again
and just see what happens
sprint um so if you remember I made like
a zombie purifier up over here just go
down here oh oh I have a couple in here
already cool okay that'll speed things
up um but yeah there's a zombie spawner
here they'll spawn in each of these
things then I can
weakness and Golden Apple them and then
remember how I released them
I had a switch for it or if I just broke
the thing must have just broke it you're
free
you gotta get trades that's not bad coal
for emeralds okay
so I'm going to go ahead and do that and
try to get them to the village okay look
at this I was going to light up that
cave it's one of the last teams around
probably so this is loaded with monsters
and this comes pouring out at me as soon
as I go into it like oh boy
so many guys that it creeper I think
that was Muslim oh well that was smart
target for some reason oh no here he is
I thought I could hit the creeper twice
before blew up no not my stuff I bet
this sword has knocked back on it though
there that time I blocked oh man
okay everything's fine get out of this
cave quick cuz this is not safe
heal up make sure I got everything
doesn't have knocked back it does that's
probably what threw me off alright good
good oh wow we got pretty lucky here
look at all these guys these are all
possible future candidates for our
villager positions and I see a lot of
potential in them I gotta say they might
not look very smart they might not know
how to tuck in their shirts but I think
we can make something of these guys you
you sir live live die live live live all
right we got five very good
let me initiate the training I just
oh that this is more than I wanted
actually I only wanted like two or three
since we had to to start with and one
more guy now I expect you guys become
librarians blacksmith or priests
anything else is unacceptable
know that alright I'll give you time to
complete your training and then let's
get a move on it I don't know what's
going on with this guy he came up he
came up to here and started looking up
at me and he won't go away like he's
been there for over a minute now I feel
like I'm on that judge chair and he's
begging for his life for something maybe
if I walk away he'll leave a but we're
gonna do the running of the bowls
oh you better go guy this is for real
now you better go the right way - I'm
running seriously I just he's locked in
on me I moved back far enough he'll go
after the villager you might hurt him
though what I've never seen a zombie hug
a villager like that let's go guys come
on he's just pushing them oh it's so
bizarre oh oh they're trying to get
they're trying to escape hold him back
guard hold them back no darn it oh one
got knocked down and he missed the water
somehow all right you're the last one
how about I just push you down
can I now he's freaking out
Geronimo oh you did the angry face or
angry emotion I hope you forgive me
all right guys find your home very good
make a village they like this house okay
very good so there is one two three four
five six seven in this one house Wow
okay so the guy I hit over here he's
still trading with me that's good so now
I'm going to go through the village and
just try to add more doors I guess
pretty sure I can just add another row
of doors here or several rows and also
put some in that blue house and just see
what they do with that stop it just stop
it please
I really regret my decision here I don't
know we got to stop them from doing this
it's really annoying you go by them they
stop I'm gonna get rid of this world of
doors I added not sure if they started
doing that because I added that or if
they we do it regardless okay they stop
if you get rid of them two rows of doors
no good problem I'm having those they
don't want to leave this house I also
have a zombie infiltration had like five
zombies running through here already and
I think we lost one or two villagers
added in some doors in this one this is
technically like outside of the house
and the cave area here is inside the
house if that makes sense it's it's like
reversed and I think that's what's
giving me a lot of trouble trying to
turn this into a real village
stop playing with the doors
what are we down to we got five man I
think we lost you already come on man
this is brutal I am having so much
trouble all five of those villagers died
while seven total they all died i
recreated summon and brought them down
here so we got two in this house least
there was two yeah there's still two and
I crapped another one down there but the
villa or the zombies they can get here
from pretty much anywhere it seems I
like blocked everything off and they're
still finding their way and I borrowed
everything off like this and and now I'm
having the little zombies come by and
they're getting through my barriers and
oh some nightmare I have no idea where
that zombie came from mmm anyway so I
made some changes here I I moved the
sunlight to over here so now this is
like inside the house and everything
over here should be outside including
the cave I think when the cave was
considered inside they don't really go
around exploring so now that I reversed
it again it should work I hope so I'm
going to remove this right now they're
inside it's daytime they should probably
go exploring I think come on guys go
explore the world can't spend all day
inside it's not good for you that's it
okay so he's outside will he go through
the other door here or is he gonna stay
in this area still
okay it took a little while but they did
you outside this is very good news
very good oh I feel like my children are
running around on a road right now and
they're gonna kill themselves oh oh
let's not let's not bother them why how
did that want to get down here even is
that one of the ones I thought died
rejected
that's weird they don't move very quick
when they have the hearts on them okay
um that might be because you can't reach
a door actually you might be glitching
out um he's finding his way back up they
have not went into the other houses yet
unfortunately they're near them they're
really close you could go guys this
house this house is amazing just go
inside take a look yeah
the hearts are a good sign though I I
wasn't expecting that
um so I'm just gonna watch him for a bit
and see what happens I guess and while
while I wait I'm going to start building
another house here might help them to
connect to these other houses easier if
we have one a little closer I suppose um
so we're doing a diagnol red house here
and I think we'll have let's see let's
go get some doors real quick here make a
few doors probably just to like so
you know I haven't used it all with this
village is any stained glass I wonder
fish get into using that to see it
doesn't matter which way the doors are
these aren't actually important doors or
just doors wonder if I could do that hmm
and maybe we will put a window here and
one over here yeah we'll try that out oh
they went back inside darn it I think
something's going to happen though that
was that was very positive the hearts
that was that's a good sign
Oh what it wasn't that guy that had the
hearts before this is like he's like
he's rocking out right now is going up
and down up come on we're so close I
think they see it as a village now which
is really important before they didn't
yeah reject it again okay now they're
just messing with me go inside the house
you're so close you're looking through
the door crying out loud no he's not
doing it nope look at that so mean so
mean this is really weird actually
it's nighttime but they're not going
back inside it's like they can't find
the house you can do it you're really
close
that's very weird I'll come on nothing's
happened yet they keep getting the
hearts though which is definitely a good
sign I've released the third villager -
I was thinking I might improve the
chances that I had teased over there
maybe nope let me let me leave weird
another villager go he must have found
his way back into the teeth they will
not go in these houses though yeah I'm
not sure what's up with that very
strange I wonder if there's like a limit
tie my doors he'll go through when
they're outside anyway so yeah I'm
working on this house it's a little
strange but I'll come on quit teasing
make it happen oh did you see that they
that one had hearts then that one had
hearts and now he's got hearts again aha
we did it yes oh it's a real village now
I am happy finally no idea how long that
took and they will probably die to
zombies but this is a good sign
very good so let's get more doors going
around here yeah this house we will do
the glowstone thing like all the other
houses have like so get some windows
going I got to get some of that puzzle
too I would like to use that for these
flowerbeds because they keep growing
grass but I haven't found it yet in my
world here very cool we're gonna have a
lot of villagers in here if we can get
more of these houses going
excellent
all right
how's that I just it'll do mm-hmm oh yes
we got another one
aha Red House is taken off look at this
we got one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve more doors
that's enough for four more villagers
fantastic and I don't know if they see
this is a house yet I pushed this guy in
open the door and then closed it on him
so I kind of forced them into this house
and I hope that worked I don't know no
he left it it is daytime now so he's off
exploring yep
we have done it I am so happy now it's
nighttime they went inside the blue
house village is expanding red house is
done excellent I'm feeling good about
this so if we can get this as an actual
working village we can start doing like
fun fun stuff where they automatically
trigger things pretty soon here I think
which is the main focus of this village
like we want them to automatically go in
mine carts and then go places and and
harvest crops or whatever all on their
own
is is the goal of this by taking
advantage of their their AI tracking
this might stand out too much it's a
colorful village so we want colors so I
think the orange stairs is actually a
good thing and then we'll do the dark
ok everybody so when I left that village
was looking pretty good I think we were
up to five villagers maybe six even um
so it's growing and there's plenty of
room for it to grow yet hopefully when
we return all all the villagers are
still there I had one more zombie leak
before I left that I sealed up and
hopefully that was the last one
otherwise they might all be gone when I
return again and at least it's set up
now that if I put villagers in it should
work it wasn't working when we started
today but anyway comment time here we go
comment number one the only one says
heyy so when are you gonna get around to
fixing up all your machines at the
updates and stuff have messed up it
smiley face so that's what I've been
doing for quite a few episodes now I've
been trying to get things working again
and working on a lot of older projects
too what do you guys think of that are
you ready to see new stuff or you
enjoying me like finishing up things so
currently by the way storage room works
furnace room works the sheep farm that
was one of the last big things I had to
fix and that works now this room is good
everything back here works
this little ender pearl thing works no
problem um still haven't done that but
these stairs work all these stairs work
yes mushroom farm works this thing is
really old the really old stuff didn't
break I find for some reason like my
watermelon and pumpkin farm not a
problem still works we fix the spider
thing now we kind of took care of the
slime farm so it's not so annoying
although this is pretty much empty all
the time just because I can't stand that
hopping sound anymore it just drives me
crazy
I've heard it for so long in my world
here it's nuts the UFO we kind of
figured that out
this brewing room it's all good still
need to finish this but it's not exactly
broken all those things work just going
through the world here fix the map and
finished it's this farm still fine so
honestly guys I think I've got
everything repaired that we had here
that was kind of soso kind of broken um
snow farm works my mini farm here this
still works accidentally when I was
working on the snow from last episode I
accidentally dug into here and wrecked
all the redstone but I fixed that up I
didn't show that on camera um yeah but
things are going good in the world I
would say Wilson Wilson still isn't
working very very very very close to it
though
fountain works this I think still works
it just needs a refill
um it has arrows it just needs a
apparently than another rack ran out of
there and go ahead and fill it actually
oops I got tons of cobblestone I don't
mind oh and I'm gonna activate it once
ah anyway things are going pretty good
my my man cave here I'm pretty happy
this still works elevator works this
mushroom farm I don't like it works
though and this all this is all good in
here too so yeah that is where we're at
in my world let me know if you want to
see me projects or if you're enjoying
the old ones still and I might decide
what we do next based on that but that's
going to be it for today guys I hope you
enjoyed this episode and I will see you
again next time bye bye
Oh