hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back oh he's gone on he left a left a
nasty little thing behind no how are you
guys doing today uh I have a little bit
of a headache today myself unfortunately
I don't know I think I I waited a little
too long without eating I had supper
like an hour too late and got a little
bit of a headache so I tried laying down
for little bits that didn't really help
and then I thought hey I'll have some
coffee because sometimes when I have
coffee I don't know I think the caffeine
rush kicks in and I feel a lot better in
sometimes my headache goes away so I had
some coffee
and while I was having my coffee I
thought well maybe my blood sugar just
got a little bit low so I had some
chocolates get my sugar sugar up get a
big kick and now I'm crazy energetic I
am all over the place no don't worry I'm
in control still but I do have a
headache hopefully it'll go away though
honestly I would feel a lot better
though if I could just find another
ocelot in my world here I have I've went
back to the jungles I've looked around I
have waited around I've killed all the
other animals around my jungles to try
to get another one to spawn nothing and
today what I would like to do is try to
finish finish up this mob system get it
working because I'm I'm really curious
to see how it'll do no no what on earth
ah was that the puppy where did they go
I I had I think I had two wolves here
well I had one in here ah man I think we
lost the puppy that's not cool
Oh No
all right anyway poor little puppy we
are going to head over to one more
jungle there's one I haven't checked and
hopefully we'll get one they're out by
my Mesa biome it's a little ways away
but hopefully that'll do the trick we'll
get some ocelots and then we'll try to
fill this thing up and maybe as as I
wait for the for the cats to breed and
all that we might work on the outside of
this - Here I am on the road again there
I go looking for a jungle biome found
one let's check it out please be an
ocelot please be an ocelot this is
actually not a very big one is it hmm
let's take a quick look around I have
one back-up plan if we don't find one
here I can't think of anywhere else
I have jungle biomes and like I've cut
down trees guys I've cut down trees made
sure there was lots of grass and still
none spawned oh come on
don't do this to me I don't want
chickens get out of here chickens want
ocelots new new ocelots no more jungles
we're gonna have to go with Plan B after
all I have one one tame cat in this
world he's kind of locked up at the
moment but we're out of options this is
just getting ridiculous so we're gonna
go with that oh yeah check this out
today here I'm going to break this
portal we're gonna get rid of this
portal over here yeah anyway oh why did
I place that I thought I only had one
obsidian on me
at 28 all right yeah we're gonna have a
new portal here in the center of the
room we're going to keep this area the
same I do like this nether hub looks
even though this idea this rail cart
function isn't really too good anymore
with the way the games changed but we're
going to keep it just for the looks I
think and yeah I'm going to try to get
some horses in this main hub area though
as well and maybe eventually I'm going
to try make something to have these
stairs retract down like this and have
it flush with the floor normally might
be kind of cool
no no oh he just died in this leaf
because I couldn't get him to sit down
cuz he was running away from me ah well
darn I don't know what to do now we kind
of need these guys and I can't get any
oh man I can't believe that just
happened I really don't like you guys
I'm just saying just saying give me so
much trouble ah let's see if this guy
runs from me or not oh I can't click
them can't click this one he won't sit
up oh boy I think we gotta go this way
okay looking for more jungles some
people ask me like sometimes how long
does it take me to record an LP episode
and obviously it varies but usually it
takes oh don't do that usually takes at
least six hours sometimes eight and a
lot of it is just like running around
dealing with this kind of stuff like
honestly too
ocelots so far I've spent probably about
four hours which is just ridiculous
honestly and all my attempts have failed
now that was the closest I've gotten so
crazy and a big problem with it right
now is that they're kind of get up there
they're bugged out at the moment like
Pat's site they'll just randomly
teleport as we saw and into blocks and
suffocate so I really shouldn't be doing
this right now like trying to get this
mop system working but I don't I just
kind of want to do it I want to get it
done and I think we're generating new
terrain here which is why we're we're
skipping like this so I'm going to stop
recording mmm turns out that was new
terrain area I thought I went that
direction before but it's not I don't
really want to go generate a bunch of
new trainer oops oh now don't don't do
it it's my good horse my good horse okay
he's fine
I'm burning down the jungle so that will
hopefully get a lot of grass showing so
that we'll get some Ocelot spotting and
then I'm gonna I'm just gonna wait and
hopefully my horse doesn't run into the
flames I kind of wanted to be on him so
that wouldn't happen oh snap oh I'm so
happy right now oh my goodness we got
one to spawn just like the fourth or
fifth day here so much time burnt down
the jungle I've killed like 50 mobs like
pigs and and sheep and cows that
patrolled this jungle so many times
hoping one would spawn we finally got
one and he's gonna find some way to kill
himself
I'm guessing where is he get out of the
leaf blocks
come here I am not messing around
anymore got to adjust that right
distance and then they'll turn around
and then they'll turn around come on
come on
look fish delicious fish seriously
because he's in the grass he can't see
me
there we go there we go ah yes we did it
whoo-hoo this is the greatest
achievement of my life all right we got
a he's fine as long as he's sitting it
when he's up and running around he can
teleport into something that will kill
him so the thing is once I get movin
here I can't stop moving until I get
where I need to be word my horse cool
there it is so hopefully we have a safe
journey all right I'll see you guys
hopefully back at the stronghold with
good news so we're gonna have to stand
this guy up this one cannot stand I'm
going to use a lead just so there's no
chances oh can I not do that can I not
do mate make up the baby
yeah don't day we gotta sit this one
down
we're sit oh man this is a disaster now
fish fish we get the baby over here -
where's the baby let's all go to this
corner everybody this corner
yeah yeah okay okay oh that one was
coming this way then he he stopped the
baby is down here oops I healed them
darn it okay he's good
I'm gonna have to move him now I'm
worried when he grows up he's gonna die
there um this guy stay away from the
equipment's away
and yeah whoo that was complicated let's
get this guy's safe oh he's so cute
all right now I'm gonna wait and rinse
and repeats a few times and then I'll
I'll move them out of here I'm taking no
chances still all right so things are
going pretty good now I'm just in the
middle of getting these guys in place
not working i bred like 20 cats and 20
wolves we've lost a few but overall it's
going pretty good
um this is what I'm doing with the
wolves
all rights and then their place there
then the cat goes on top and this is
little tricky to do not too bad I will
say like I'm doing this mob system as an
experiment to see how how effective it
is it's very simple to set up the mom
system like to build all the spawning
pads in this to get the yet the wolves
in the GAT so is insane that is what
takes forever so if you don't have
wolves and you don't have cats you might
want to try a different design is all I
can say all right did were you up there
I don't know weird things are happening
to kind of with the wolves and that I've
had a few randomly teleports which is
something we're going to be keeping an
eye on too as we do this like while
they're sitting that they will teleport
to me so I'm hoping that doesn't happen
because then they'll get teleported out
of their places and I won't be able to
keep this thing running all right that's
one layer done cool all right everyone
so we are ready to go here we're going
to fire it up and see what it does we're
probably not going to get super great
rates because I got dark areas around
here still but I'll try to get rid of
those later
we also
don't have hours are a villager in place
so that zombies aren't going to be
attracted to that currently I'm trying
to decide also I want your input on this
what should we do with the outside of
this building because I don't want to
leave it just like this it's a giant
cube of blandness currently I was
considering tried to convert it into a
penguin like from feed the beasts like
have orange feet and the fat body and in
the head and some wings on the side I
don't know if it's the right shape those
chestal it's a little bit fat is what
I'm concerned about
you must have spawned in there I still
have the torches in but there's probably
a few dark spots all right so let's go
on up okay hopefully and pull this off
very good so all the guys are seem like
they're staying in place which is also
very good some people are asking about
the half slabs here again these are to
prevent spiders from spawning in here I
especially don't want spiders spawning
because they will knock these guys off
of their their pedestals they need to
stay put
although the dog is trapped there no
matter what he can't get out but the cat
can be knocked around the two tall mobs
they won't shouldn't be able to knock
him down the way I got the setup so
that's good and the top half of the dog
is showing so he can still path find to
the skeletons with this setup
he only cannot see in this this this
this and this spot up close here like if
there's a skeleton here he it won't run
away from the dog until it moves to like
over here so keep that in mind with this
I could get them in a better spot if I
made it three tall but I don't think
it's really worth it okay but yeah these
are to stop the spiders from spawning
somebody suggested
I just want to point this out they
suggested I put fences here so that
there would be more air blocks like
above this fence is an air block if we
do it this way and the more air blocks
you have like level here the quicker
your spawn rate is going to be like
having these walls these blocks on the
walls at this level is going to decrease
it so um you know ideally I should try
to remove those but I don't really care
and same with these slabs each of these
will reduce the spawn rates because it
takes away in air space at this at this
height here um so this seems like a good
idea this does not stop spiders from
spawning though like they won't spawn on
top of the fence but if they try to
spawn like here they're going to do that
3 by 3 check like all around and they're
not going to get stopped by anything
because this is considered air still so
yeah that does not work also having a
half slab like on the ceiling instead of
on the ground doesn't work either
spiders will still spawn if you do that
so I just wanted to point that out it's
a good suggestion though but it just
doesn't work alright let's get it going
oh I should have known that was gonna
happen
let's go back up so this is six layers
six layers and what is it it's like a 13
by 7 each of these things - because it's
lapped in each of the the wolf areas
whatever in total it it comes out -
let's see I got on my calculator here
1092 spawning spaces oh but I never
calculate these so there's nine that
don't count here should I do that real
quick
9 times 12 108 thousand 92 - 180
so the total is 984 for this thing I've
got setup there's six layers at 12 dogs
12 cats they were a pain to get
especially the cats they were paying to
get me place
we'll see how it goes though mmm
got a creeper in there I went to go
sleep in the bed because it was
nighttime some guys must have spawned Oh
No try to get this going I ran out of a
heart in clay so I wasn't able to finish
this I was too lazy to go get some more
all right this should be good
killed our first two mobs already I have
signs over there and the mobs they fall
down we got another guy he's got a torch
all right fall down oh yeah those are
zombies so the zombies aren't really
going to fall down until you get the
villager in place um it is daytime yeah
things are happening that's good that's
a good sign
that's very good actually that is not
too bad again I have dark caves around
so I wasn't really expecting much
although it has kind of stopped now hmm
now here we go yet got some skeletons
awesome zombie yeah even though there is
no really there's no villager there yet
attracting them they will still like
wander around and they'll fall down
that's not bad not too bad
in fact there's one area in particular
we might head over to light up now that
I know is going to be affecting this
quite a bit also one downside of running
this is I'm going to have a lot more
slimes in my cave and those also will
decrease the rate of this thing think
too bad though yeah it's not super fast
but it's it's not terrible all right
cool mm-hmm under the snow flake there's
always tons of mobs always we should
light it up
this will help things out it's actually
a pretty big area that's dark ah all
right awesome
this as worried there I thought I might
die actually hey where'd he go
what happened was he in the water I was
wondering where the creeper way he must
have been in here and I didn't see him
I'm very confused nothing blew up so you
had to have been in the water okay so I
did Kandice start setting up a room here
a little while ago again we're putting
like the collection area for this thing
over here we're also possibly going to
experiment with that setting something
up in the nether with this knob system
but we'll worry about that later
Oh give me give me everything except the
best stuff there I'm done with that for
right now this gunpowder cool so I set
this up in a way I planned it this way I
wanted a instead of converging all the
mobs into a one by one tube like I
usually do I wanted like a waterfall
kind of effect like where you can watch
and cascade down and I might also want
to extend this up higher
so you can see it better so I'm going to
have hoppers running down here
those will converge to to a single
hopper into the middle so that is right
over here get these going like this I
will collect all the drops I'm hoping I
didn't really check but I'm hoping this
is a far enough drop for it to kill the
witches too I haven't seen one fall yet
so I don't know otherwise they're gonna
get stuck in this it seems like most the
mobs that are spotting with armored
dying though so that's a good sign
it's like at least thirty two blocks
might be about forty block drop so
that's it's pretty far alright so we got
that and then right now I'm a glass
viewing window or should we do this
cuz oh no really
I just said while he even survived a hit
two hits what does he got on this thing
well he had four pieces but Wow
protection three feather falling for
unbreaking 3 I am keeping these that is
insane I don't know if we actually need
glass is it better what do you guys
think should we have glass here or is it
better without it because they're not
gonna not really gonna affect me right
like they always die when they fall
except for that zombie but we can make
it so he can't leave the room if we're
worried about it although I think some
of these drops are falling out like
these bones and these arrows huh
I'm not sure the hopper is getting most
of it we might need a window loan anyway
let me know what you think it's probably
going to be it so let's do the common
thing where did you come from I picked
out one comment for today so let's check
it out here it says hey etho I have a
question are you interested in doing
live streams if you are I would like a
live stream in your LP world in which
you do like a big progress on a
time-consuming project also maybe a Q&A
session on a live stream awesome work on
the videos I love to enjoy them every
day thank you very much
all right so live streams I have tried
live streaming in the past a few times
and I've never really gone into it as a
problem not out of lack of desire I do
really like I find I really enjoy
watching the other mine crackers when
they do a live stream especially if it's
like an out of the ordinary thing for
them I will usually try to join in and I
I enjoy it so I do see the appeal of
live streaming and I've often wanted to
do it myself
but there's a couple issues one of them
a big one is my Internet's I can pretty
much only deliver the lowest quality
possible on Twitch and is barely um it
when I do live stream second problem I
found I'm not very good at live
streaming I can't I don't think I can
keep people entertained that long I'm
not very charismatic um which is kind of
why I do a lot of cuts in my videos
because I I kind of lose energy and I
just stop talking if I go for too long
the other thing third thing is time live
streaming can take quite a bit of time
out of the day especially if it's done
regularly and I find with my episodes
the response I get from you guys usually
is in proportion to the amount of
I might spent on an episode so if I
record something and don't put much time
into it usually I don't get a good
response from you guys I find so I would
rather spend time making better episodes
usually but for fun maybe eventually
I'll do more live streaming we'll see
how it goes but nothing super bland yet
anyway that is it for today guys thank
you for watching and I will see you
again next time