hello hello everyone
ESO here how you guys doing today I hope
you got your snacks ready I got mine
here ready to go something I've been
meaning to do is polish up the cave area
a bit because the way it is right now is
is it's not very nice we need stairs I'm
jumping around all over the place
random blocks everywhere I'm going to
make it look better so I sort of started
working on that over around this corner
here and I before I could really do
anything now I had to deal with these
cave spider spawners because I I left
them pretty much unfinished and I need
to decide what to do so I got something
set up here I spent a few hours on this
trying to figure out their behavior and
all that and I got it working really
good actually it's pretty pretty awesome
so I was going to do an on camera but I
figured it would take a long time and it
it did so we'll just go through it
quickly this is my spiral spider
elevator here yeah so there's a there's
two spawners here we got them both
working one of them is underneath here
right over there and it brings the
spiders into this elevator the problem I
was having before the main issue with
these cave spiders is that they would
track you and then they wouldn't
necessarily go where you wanted them to
go they would fight water streams in
that so I wanted to come up with a
guaranteed way of dealing with them
because I don't like having any dead
zones or paths finding problems when I
do this mob stuff and and this is pretty
much the solution to it I got it figured
out figured out a few tricks with cave
spiders that work
yeah so they all collect here they're
one-hit kill because they drop 15 blocks
and these guys go up there's also so we
just went right over top the other
spider spawner here these spiders they
go to an elevator behind this wall can't
really show it to you because it's
closed up but that's what happens these
ones they join in with that elevator it
dropped some 15 blocks onto a fence post
oh I do have a view up here cool yeah
you can sorta see the elevator here it's
going up and around spiraling up and
then the very top oh maybe I'll poke my
head in just for you guys I hate to do
it because I'll probably get attacked
here why do I have that in there they
fall down here yeah you got me one at a
time too so that there's no spiders
underneath to get in the way of them
taking fall damage I'm gonna die here
I gotta go sometimes you guys can get
you through blocks it's really unfair
okay give me one moment the good thing
is I actually do have a working on off
switch for these spawners now so I got
shut off we can look inside safely
without the spiders jumping all over us
okay so let's pillar up here I'll show
you the drop area yeah okay so
this is a stream that pushes them down
see the block is coming towards us
there's a sign here and above there is
this water block this is to drown them
in case they decide to start climbing up
here and they somehow make it all the
way to the top I don't want them jamming
spiders from falling down here so that's
a safety I don't think that actually
happens though from what I can tell but
just in case it's a little bit of a
safety they fall down 15 blocks on to
the fence post here there's that one one
high gap I guess for them to fit through
so they don't climb I think I added that
recently then they fall down to that
second chamber and that's this is really
annoying I might not be able to get out
of here come on come on
yeah they fall into another chamber here
this is just so that they're out of the
way for more spiders to fall onto the
fence post otherwise they might land on
each other and take no fall damage which
is an issue and then they fall into this
three block area and I got I played
around with this a bit and I think a
three block area is best for them to the
be in I'm able to hit them or reach all
the way to the top there if they try to
climb when you hit them they'll they'll
touch this water scream and they'll fall
back down instead of a staying at the
top usually which is good because if
they're if they're at the top here then
spiders aren't able to flow in like
while you're killing them which will
plug up the drop area and then when more
spiders fall in they might not take fall
damage which is an issue yep and so they
they always take 15 blocks fall damage
that's being carefully controlled so I
don't have to use a stone sword to kill
them anymore I can use my fists it's
regulated properly
and the other thing the reason I'm doing
the elevator like this I played around
with a whole bunch of different ways of
doing it I tried having solid water
source blocks in a one by one area for
them to swim up they don't like to swim
properly like normal mobs they can
actually go down solid water source
blocks somehow like without swimming if
they're tracking you then I tried using
ladders for them to climb up that didn't
work out all that well then I tried just
having them climb on their own like if
they'd get bunched together but that
seems to depend on if they're tracking
you if like you know if you have bunch
of spiders in a one by one area like
this sometimes they'll start climbing up
and then they'll climb up to the top and
stay there
I had like a water stream at the top to
push him when they did that over to the
side and then fall down but that didn't
work unless I was that near the thing
for them to to start climbing if they're
on their own they won't climb unless
they're tracking you so I settled with
this thing it's a little bit big and a
little bit slow but it's guaranteed to
get them up regardless of where you're
standing it'll take them up and they
won't drown in it they can't get stuck
in it so it's it's a good compromise and
I left I made this area here glass
because I want to have a little clicking
area see it in action just just for
looks I'll probably put a stone wall or
something in front with a little viewing
area yeah so this area here still needs
to be cleaned up quite a bit like the
ceiling needs to be raised and walls and
all that stuff I just wanted to show you
this before I started covering
everything even more so like like this
wiring here I got wiring running all
around the spawner area I'll show you
how the lighting works to shut it on or
to shut it that bad back turn it on or
off
let's just hop down here this is inside
of the spawner area 8x8 room you can see
we got pistons on up one on each side
with a with a glowing pumpkin there you
can use glowstone or a torch or
something when that lever outside there
is switched these Pistons extend which
block that which allows the spiders to
spawn again and then you can see he's
fighting the water current that's right
it's trying to avoid with this thing
although not totally avoidable due to
the positioning of this but as long as
I'm on the opposite side of this wall
they'll they'll go this towards this
direction and they'll go on top of these
stairs here this is the trick this is
the trick I wanted to point out if the
spiders have an air block above the
water stream they're able to fight
against it like you just saw but if they
have a solid block above the water
stream then they are not able to fight
against it if they're tracking you so
this is what I came up with I got a roll
of stairs you could do this on all four
sides really and it should work
regardless of where you're standing I
just have on one side because that's I
don't know I might I might add it to all
four sides but got a water stream
pushing them on top the stairs there
with these signs holding the water in
place could use vents gates as well
spiders oops will you push it onto the
stairs and then the screen will push
them this way they won't be able to
fight the current and they get sucked up
to this area here which is a bit
complicated this is the start of the
elevator right here but you'll notice I
have this is the water source
right there so kind of zigzags too over
there the reason for that is when the
spiders get pushed onto these stairs
they're only going to be about half on
the step they won't be right against
this wall here so if you have a solid
block where this stair is oops if that's
solid blocks they're going to be
somewhere around this position here
between the two blocks they'll run into
the wall and they'll they'll get stuck
so you need to have two stairs here
OOP that was a weird positioning I liked
how you can get your stairs back now
when you when you break them it's not
going to let me put it in the right spot
is it come on there we go yeah so if
they're in between here and you have the
stream going it's going that way and
then zigzags it'll suck them up they
have a block over top they won't be able
to fight the current all the way up the
elevator they'll they have a block over
top except where the signs are and it
seems to work okay got a sign on a sign
here to hold this water in place and
that's that's how that all works so I
did that with both of them and yeah no
problem so far so the plan for the rest
of this episode is just to kind of clean
this area up a little bit better we need
to add some more features as well I want
to add a lever here somewhere I'm not
sure which side to turn the Steve spider
spawning on or off so that they're not
annoying us if we don't need them to be
at the moment the wiring is the two
spawners have isolated wiring this is a
lever for one of them it goes around and
I believe that piston is right here yeah
so
so this is how this works redstone
wiring powers this block which powers
the piston which is adjacent to it and
we extend the wiring using a repeater
here powers this block this wire pulls
the current through that block and
continues on here again there's a piston
right behind this wood block get a
little viewing area here for looking at
the poor little spiders as they go with
up the elevator okay so we need to
connect this wiring with the with this
wiring over here so you goes all the way
around and hook up a lever so we can get
control both of them
it'll be pretty simple to connect the
two together this this looks like a
really good spot here to do it I'm going
to change things around a little bit
though move this repeater step we'll
have wire there so you can either pull
power through a block if you have the
repeater on this side or you can put
power through the block if you have it
on the other side so let's go over there
we're just going to switch that if we
can get in there okay so instead of that
we will have the repeater here and that
will send power to the wire on the other
side yeah okay and then we can just pull
this down right here and we'll switch
this repeater so yeah we could either
put the repeater here or we could put it
on this side doesn't matter this is fine
I guess I'll get rid of this second
lever since we don't need it anymore
you can see it's steam powered all the
way around now the reason I'm sending
power through block like this is just to
keep the wiring all at the same height
instead of going over top to this
pumpkin because I can't put wiring on a
pumpkin so it seems like a good place to
put the repeaters
okay the next issue we have you probably
saw it already but like if you kill the
spiders here some of the drops are going
to land on this iron bar yeah and
there's one flaw with this as I'm
hitting them like that they will be up
at the water stream so that might cause
one or two not to take the fall damage
because they're blocking the area but
yeah you see how the string is getting
stuck on this bar here we could either
could either put a piston behind there
to push it off or we could use a water
screen to push it off I'm not sure what
we'll do the switch to turn the spawners
on or off I think maybe putting on here
a quiz okay
yeah we should be able to take power
from over here on that side and then
maybe we'll have a button here we can
press to push these items on somehow
this side is clear yeah it's okay
that's what we'll do we'll have a button
here and maybe some glowstone polite the
area cool thing I noticed ever since the
recent patches I'm not getting Enderman
down in my cave here which is cool
because before they were teleporting
down all the time which is annoying
moving blocks around had me a little
worried they were going to cause
problems on future but hopefully that's
not a problem anymore okay so that I was
going to say something else but I can't
remember now so I got a I got a path
here for the wire it's it's really
simple just goes down here I added this
little bit and then it connects to our
loop which goes around and then it goes
to that other loop where we connected
and it goes around the other spawner so
this will take care of it all try it out
yep this one's powered and is this other
one powered yes it is
so we have our switch on or off there
let's hook up our our piston I think
I'll use a piston I'm gonna try just
stick it in the back here like right
over here
wrong way oh and we can't get it out now
there okay
put all that back there and if we put
the button right here we could probably
just put a wire over here and that'll be
very very simple and hidden which is
nice let's try it out though
get some light on the area I'm going to
throw some blocks on the bar hi shad
really get some spiders in here because
that might push them through the glass
or something crazy yeah works like that
I'm gonna get some spiders Oh make sure
it doesn't do anything dangerous oh and
I maybe I'll replace this with nether X
or nether nether brick so we can see the
button clear cuz right now it's it's the
same colors the back
yeah so this is one of the problems I'm
having with this still they are tracking
me if I'm on the other side of that wall
just because of where the spawner is I
couldn't really avoid that so even if
this is covered they're still tracking
me so basically I I just have to be on
the other side of a imaginary line here
I'm over here it's fine it works a lot
better than it did before where I was
doing that stare trick down there they
really weren't cooperating because
before I would pretty much have to be in
the corner for it to work and and now I
can just be somewhere on the sides does
it matter
and same with same with that one there
the way of their position there was no
way I could get them to all go into one
stream together from the two spawners
without them tracking me enough and not
oh what am I saying
disobeying the water streams they were
disobeying the water streams before but
now it works which is important I got
the nether brick on the other side here
not sure where I'm going to put the
glowstone
and maybe I'll put signs below your Adam
will figure it out pretty happy with
this let's try out the piston though see
what it goes yeah it's fine even if even
if it does add it won't crush the mob's
piston piston arms you can't stuff I
think the mobs and they're not getting
pushed through the glass which is what I
was worried about so all in all I'm
pretty happy with this yeah so it's nice
to have that more finished up now this
is really good it works better than the
other spider system a lot of people are
wondering where that is so maybe I'll
just run there directly here to show you
this area here needs to be cleaned up a
lot I can rip this out too now that's
from the old system ax is messing around
with get to the other cape spider system
you just goes through the tree farm here
and I believe we went too far it gets in
here somewhere let's run down the tunnel
and right over here it's kind of I got
I'll clean up this area too eventually
in time this is it
lots of lots of pics here some of these
are actually pretty good movies working
dude I just got another fortune 3
diamond pic is awesome nothing else on
it though
3 soon I'll be able to enchant something
else and level 39 here with our cave
system no we really need to pick out a
theme like a wave like a block selection
type thing for the ground I would like
to have grass like I've been doing but
maybe have some sort of a walkway to of
another block like maybe maybe the stone
bricks for the walls of the cave that's
a problem I have right now I want
everything to be stone bricks and it
just doesn't we need more variety how do
we work it in these nether bricks go
great with them though I like as play
around here maybe using them for my
ceilings that's why I've been doing in
my custom map and it looks awesome
stone brick walls another brick ceiling
and need to mix some sandstone with
another brick and it looks even better
so let me know what you think of that I
also really like using wood planks and
leaves and stuff
Wood maybe we can mix that in somehow
I'm not sure for this cave area though
I'd like to kind of keep the shape of it
like instead of squaring everything out
that kind of want to keep the shape and
just smooth it out a bit like dad paths
and that kind of thing but I want the
natural look of the cave I'm not sure
how it would look if I replaced like
these walls and stuff with stone bricks
with this exact same shape type thing
and maybe nether brick for the ceiling
that might look a little strange it's
hard to tell do you guys have any ideas
what should I do
I'm really bad at picking out blocks
to make it look good that's the thing
that I really think people should get
into more make tutorials on how to make
things pleasing looking like there's so
many tutorials on how to build technical
things but I would like to see tutorials
on how to build aesthetically pleasing
things tricks to it you know I think
that's all that common and it would help
me out a lot I think a lot of people
learn that stuff when they play
multiplayer they kind of pick up tricks
that other people do and it adds to
their variety with me though it's like
plain boring stone brick walls
everywhere I need I need more variety
here but I'll think about it give me
your feedback what should I do
what do you think would look good so far
I like how it looks but yeah I don't
want big empty walls like this anyway
I'll probably mix in some lab lighting
in these walls because I want to hear it
all these torches clean out this area
I'll probably get rid of this big chunk
here like a path I might rip this out
and put a path down here somewhere this
area really needs to be leveled out and
cleaned up stupid Enderman
I don't know when that happened but he
brought a grass block down I'll probably
switch that to grass too doesn't matter
now and I'll clean this up some more
this door here is for a wire room like a
way of getting down to the wire because
this will all be covered eventually so
it would be nice to have some type of
access although I might move where that
door is
might start adding some paths here like
I was thinking maybe bricks or or stone
bricks or something do a path this is
pretty common oh we need to do I don't
have what I need for this I need some
half slabs
we'll just see how it looks small sample
here that holes all over the place
and I just fell in it darn it okay I got
to fill this