hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys let's
do a
do a 360 here that doesn't look so
smooth
hope you guys got your snacks ready for
today today is going to be a weird
episode a little
out of the ordinary i hope you like it
regardless
but we're gonna go take a trip down
memory lane today everybody and we gotta
be quick about it too because we got a
lot to see
i will save you princess you're welcome
okay so what we're gonna be doing
is we're gonna check out some of my old
worlds
in minecraft the ones i've had i had
before this
this main world that we've been in for
the last like 200 250 episodes
um i've had three main worlds before
this
one of them you guys have seen a lot of
but the two before that
i haven't shown around too much and i
thought it might be cool to check those
out because i haven't seen them
in about two years myself
and
it was back in a simpler time of
minecraft and i'm gonna
try uh try downgrade to alpha and beta
versions of minecraft
as we check these out too because when i
when i loaded up one of them in
particular there was tons of chunk
errors
it did not converts too well to our
crazy future minecraft world we live in
now so
i guess hopefully there's not too much
technical problems today
but uh we're gonna go check them out
let's go into our portal
and i'll see you on the other side
well here we go we we've been launched
back into time here
man i was getting 5 000 frames per
second on this menu screen
that's like a that's like a record for
me
uh okay so i had to rename the world to
world
one for it to show up here hopefully i
don't know it says zero
0.0 that's not a good sign
i might have updated it to beta
uh like a different world format
oh snap oh snap
probably a chunk here i'm guessing i
can't imagine i
started underground before
this looks very alpha though
it's not too bad it's not as dark as i
remembered it
uh oh
oh you have to hold f3 you can't just
press it right why
51 okay maybe
maybe we are underground for some reason
old cobble texture
oh yeah wait what was our position i
have no idea where i am in the world i
didn't check this out beforehand
we might just have to kill ourselves
here and hopefully get back to wherever
i
i had my buildings
hopefully this turns out well i don't
know how how this is going to record
and all that whoa
whoa
this this looks so different than so
dark holy
okay i don't know where i am though
i don't recognize anything
wow
okay yeah i think we're just gonna kill
kill ourselves and hopefully find some
civilization here in this world
oh uh oh i pressed i something bad
happened
alrighty then so that uh that ended
pretty badly actually
um i think uh i loaded the world in a
newer version of minecraft that had a
different file format
and so when we started moving around
there it was creating new world and was
trying to save stuff and i think it
freaked out because
every time i started up it was crashing
so
yeah uh luckily
being a good record keeper like i am i
have uh
i have a bunch of saves that are just
like world one world two world three
world four world five i have
no idea which which is the right world
for
for what but uh
we're going uh we're going ancient
minecraft fishing right now
to see what's on these
okay here we go yeah this is it
i don't know this might be an older
version of the one i released
to the public though i'm not sure
um does this look familiar
uh huh we just built this
oh what does it say sewer axis okay i
thought maybe i put something clever
there
let's go down this is how it's supposed
to look
right here oh man
render distance far uh
let's turn the music down a little bit
we'll get it going though if
if it's if it uh starts playing 3d
is this still an option i can't i can't
remember if that's still an option if
or if they took that out i
do not recommend it ever though
oh yeah here it goes so this is where
the cactus firm went
uh let's go exploring oh and you
remember when the cactus
look how big the cactus drops are it was
like an
error in the code for some reason it was
the only object that was like
the size of a normal block almost it's
so huge
it does this little zigzag thing you'll
notice no
signs or anything to hold the water i
figured this out exactly so the water
would travel eight blocks
oh although i did use a ladder here i
must have
must have got smart about it and this is
my very first
storage room right here oh yeah
oh i'm steve
oh the glowstone okay so this is post
nether
it's good to know let's see what kind of
stuff i had
these chests aren't making any sound oh
because we're an alpha that's right
the yeah they didn't add chest noises
until
like 1.8 or something
i i can't even remember now when they
did the sound update is when that
was put in
slabs very curious oh
oh weird is that the stair texture
what are these
yeah that's a stair texture that looks
really strange
i don't even remember when they changed
that to be honest
i must not have noticed when they did
yeah wood stairs
i like snooping i'm very curious what i
had at this time
although this is going to take forever i
don't think i really
stored anything here i this is like one
of the later things i've built in the
world
and then well oh i remember that that
air too
if you uh
sometimes you would get running and you
couldn't stop until you pressed escape
oh we got some pork here we better grab
this because we'll probably take damage
oh that's weird you hover it over and it
goes underneath the sand
had some sugar chain lots of cactus
for some reason when i got into this
game
i thought tattus was like the most cool
and technical block in the whole game
because if you
if you placed a block beside it it would
automatically break it was like the only
block in the game
oh here we go got lots of stuff in here
oh yeah no shift clicking what am i
doing it's like the only block in the
game where you could remotely uh
cause it to break uh by like
updating beside it i don't know for some
reason i was fascinated with it so i was
always
i always had like cactus farms and
ah come on
yep here it is so this
this is where i started in the world
this this room here
um for those of you that don't know
i'm very bad at making roofs in the game
a big reason for that is i've always
lived underground
this was a side of a hill basically so
this is like a hill
this whole place my starter house here
and i just hollowed it out like i i dug
inside the hill
hollowed out this room uh and then kind
of expanded from here
let's see over this way is my furnace
room
i think i tried to fill all these with
fuel
most of them look empty though maybe not
oh my goodness let me out
i liked how i had redstone on me as as
last thing in my inventory when i exited
the world here
records lots of food
okay here we go 19 diamonds
pretty good oh i actually had clay i
don't believe it
all right so for those of you that don't
know
the very first thing i ever wired with
redstone was these doors right here this
is the very first time i use redstone on
anything
these double doors it's my very first
redstone project
let's check it out
i am curious i think i broke some of it
just there
that looks pretty efficient do i have
torches i do
i'm going to try to try to make sure i
use torches as we go here
putting redstone on sand great idea
oh i'm still trying to shift click
things
this is fun for me i hope it's fun for
you guys i love uh
i love checking out my old stuff here
all right let's get some more lights
i spent a good like two hours on this
on this redstone project so i guess the
pressure plates are above here
and there i think there's one pressure
plate above that block and that one
and it comes to here repeaters
we didn't have repeaters back then so uh
you have to use like redstone torches
like this
anyway i got it working it took me a few
hours but i figured it out might not be
the most efficient thing
oh it's night time i don't think we
should record at night
i think that's a bad idea
yeah i think i'll i'll be right back i
don't know i can't remember i don't
think beds were in the game
at this point so i probably can't sleep
this away either
ah good times good times
you just hang out in this room and play
cat over and over
no uh i did play chat a lot though
look at all this food actually let's
take bread i think bread is better than
uncooked
pork this uncooked pork is only good for
one and a half hearts i just found out
yeah so you'll notice i had no sword in
my inventory too
because i used to
used to play with mobs on when i first
started this world nope
the grinder is working
cactus grinder yeah but
after a while i kind of got fed up with
the mobs and i uh
i used i played on peaceful for a lot a
lot of the time
um it wasn't until i started doing
youtube videos that i actually
switched to playing with mobs on again
because i figured
it'd make my videos a little more
entertaining than playing on peaceful
mode
oh the mod behavior is so much different
too you see how skeletons strafe to the
left
and they'll they'll just like randomly
jump
there's three fire things on them
instead of one big one
oh it's so so cool to see all this again
uh i got a fountain here i was actually
pretty proud of this gazebo i built
i think this looks pretty good even
still it looks pretty good i think
probably the nicest thing i've built in
the world
even though it's not very big oh we got
a well
um remember how
fire was eternal if it was on on wood
like that
oh you know what i had a cactus farm
before
this one even i totally forgot
oh man
oh and i tried to do that but i i messed
it up the dimensions are wrong i bet
yeah i think that's what it was so then
i like
planned it out and made the the proper
one over there
and i'm guessing i don't know what the
story is with this i think i was
fascinated with half slabs here
just wanted to like make a pyramid out
of them i guess
oh there's a portal
this is probably the first the portal i
ever made over
here pretty sure
there's another one in the house too we
should probably go to the house
i kind of want to check out the nether
cannot remember
if i ever did build anything in the
nether
during the nether building terrain
that's probably not a good sign maybe i
didn't
oh yeah we got things oh wow i got rails
and everything in here
oh yeah and it's uh the minecart physics
still work that's awesome
got a tree in here
so dark i'm sorry we won't spend too
long
so how does this work again i think i
have to
is this an automated thing oh it is it's
on a pressure plate yes
oh look at this i i don't even remember
doing this
nice fires
wazira
i don't know how to get out of the
minecart do i right click or what
oh snap i'm scared oh there goes my card
yeah i definitely used to play on
peaceful
there's absolutely no protection against
gas
i don't remember having other areas in
this world
so i can't imagine what i i made another
portal to
this is taking a very long time guys i
don't know
i might record like two or three
episodes
in a row of me doing this and i'll
upload them
pretty close together so that hopefully
you guys don't feel like you got cheated
out of a normal episode
uh if i if i do too many of these in a
row
there's nothing out here man
you see how the mobs just like randomly
jump
looks so cool um
yeah i don't think i built anything here
i really wish i could run so slow
let's check up here
no i don't think there's anything out
here all right i'm gonna head back
i'm gonna cut here speed speed things up
a bit
another is so scary we got no protection
against
yes i'm walking right over a lava pool
i want to see where this goes to if it
goes anywhere
because i can't remember
building anywhere out from my main base
there
this is like the latest version of alpha
2 by the way
when i made this world originally it was
the lime green grass
at this point in the alphas it looks
like we had the different biomes
actually looks pretty good though
nothing out here either why why on earth
did i make those portals
i don't understand oh there's snow here
let's just take a look at this terrain
pretty cool oh we gotta
overhang over there
is that a treat yeah that's a tree i
thought maybe i built something there
cool cool all right we're gonna head
back to the main house
all right i gotta do it guys i have to
do it
i'm so dead oh they're chasing me
how fast are they i don't know if
they're running yet actually
oh yeah they're running they're running
pretty good will they be able to get up
here
not if i do that
oh cheated death i'm happy about that
i believe in this version they dropped
cooked steak
instead of like gold gold nuggets and
zombie flesh
zombie flesh wasn't in the game zombies
would drop feathers
wait where am i is this
uh oh no
i'm lost this isn't the right place
maybe i should have died
i don't know how to get back now
so i think death is my only option here
i can't find my way back
this is zero zero more or less and uh
it's new terrain so i don't know where
where to go
um by new terrain i mean it's a desert
biome and biomes didn't exist by my
house my main house
oh what
okay i know where this is i don't know
how well you can see i lost my torches
this thing here pretty important to my
channel this is uh
this is where i first started learning
about the boat dispensers
i was trying to come up with a water
pattern where
the boats wouldn't break in it when i
placed them
and this is like a holding cell for a
boat
i thought i was safe in here and then
this creeper opens the door and he's
like hello
hey oh he sees me
could you go away please
i'm re-equipping leave me alone
all right it's almost day i'm just
waiting a little bit and then we'll
record again here
oh man
and the finisher all right so i think
now let's let's take an actual tour of
the house it's
it's the main part of the world um so
this is like the front right here
i built these stairs along the side
viewing window out here so you could
look out at the at the water but then i
kind of blocked it off
later and we go up here
spent a long time on on this little
spiral
thing i got here took me a while to
figure out how to do this
for some reason and uh
it's pretty nice up here actually i was
really into
like nature and trees and and and grass
and and green things you know
nothing nothing like i am today no
um so i have like trees all along the
walls here
kind of give it cover make it feel
hey how's it going you're not so uh
you're not so secretive
actually you make a lot of noise on that
grass
these guys are vicious so and they're
very unpredictable the mobs
like the they'll be like swimming out in
the ocean and stuff they don't care if
they go off land
oh look at this they're all over oh man
there's lots around
i guess it is pretty dark though
don't kill me i made some arrows
i have to do it spam it
yeah lots of windows another viewing
area out over here oh this is a better
view of the water i guess
and of course i wanted to be able to see
the cactus farm
inside spent a long time trying to
figure out how i could
place this dirt so so that the flower
wouldn't uproot because if it's too dark
they
they would pop off the soil and i found
just the right light level where it
would uh
work inside i think i even added this
glass above here just so that this
flower could uh
be inside the house here um
we got a wool white wool and stone slab
floor design going on in here stone
slabs change
color quite a bit just because there's
dark spots it's kind of interesting
actually
how that looks uh did not furnish the
place
out over here we have a balcony
it's pretty nice that was like supposed
to be some compass tower
that i never finished over there there's
like north
east southwest spelled in spelled out in
torches
if we go down ouch
this is it's like my favorite
place over here wait let's go up the
stairs
oh yeah you can get around here too i
hear the creepers coming
more double doors over here yeah they
found me
they're they were pretty smart back then
if they smelt you they would find you so
the boat dispenser i don't know if it's
gonna work
i think it did take a few seconds this
is where it would come up
oh yeah it still works well it should
because we're in alpha right
um boats are actually incredibly slow
for some reason i thought they were
quicker
oh and if you go into uh one of these
section things i don't know if you can
get out
barely got out there was
did i have a boat returned i can't
remember
i don't remember if i made a boat return
i wonder where this goes
is this to my basement oh it is to my
basement okay maybe we'll go here
so i had like a water slide in the
basement of my
house here oh what was that that looked
like a ravine almost
oh yeah oh this is awesome
all right let's hop out and a big thing
in the past
like this wasn't common because we
didn't have silk dutch or anything but
there was this giant topic on the
minecraft forums about how to get grass
down and
uh like underground so i did that in
this world here and i got grass
uh way down underground i guess it's
only y44 but
i thought that was pretty cool you would
have to staircase it down and this is
actually the staircase
over here
fully intact actually and you'd have to
wait for it to grow from the surface
down
all the way took forever um
yeah over here we have an underground
tree farm
pretty cool we got one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve
trees uh at this point in the game there
was only one tree type the oak trees
and oops got some storage chests here i
like to use
wheat for uh decorations a lot in the
past
and there's like lights above here to
kind of
give it that glow
thought there was a chest there i guess
it's gone
and then to leave the basement that's
the storage room up there that we saw
earlier
to leave the basement what is this
why is there glass here
that's kind of random there's a few
glass blocks there for some reason
i guess that was so i could figure out
where the center was
got another water slide thing here
hopefully this works
oh yeah that boat launching mechanic i
love it
that's like one of the things i miss the
most about uh old boat mechanics
how how you could get launched up in the
water real quick it was so cool
all right i think the lava there is what
i used to break my boats on actually
this thing here um if we go down we can
go check out the boat dispenser
oh it's a water ladder darn it can i get
out of here
oh i can it works yes
oh that's sweet i didn't think i had any
of those in this world
ouch man i just took damage
and this here is the boat dispenser room
i'm gonna put lights down just because
it's pretty dark
uh these are all the holding cells
i think there was a button where i could
call it
from down here to where was that extra
boats here
i did i did the pot lights throughout
this whole thing
up in the ceiling
was there not a
huh maybe i
does this let's try to press this
that might be for the mine cart
yeah it doesn't do anything oh we can do
this
oh maybe we can't i thought it would
make all the doors open i guess not
um what does this button do
let's go investigate whoa okay there's
uh
skeletons in the carts
oh snap holy
they ain't messing around
yeah that's why the cart doesn't work i
get it
thing guys two skeletons and they're in
both the carts
i wonder why i didn't have any lights oh
because i played on peaceful
that makes sense so they stopped my
minecarts here i guess
i don't know i can't remember how to get
them going again
i think if i break it and just place it
here it should work
yeah cool cool
all right let me try did i do it i did
it
oh there's a there's redstone there
did it stop yeah it stopped hmm
all right i don't know exactly what's
going on
that time it worked
this was the first minecart thing i ever
made this was just to get to the other
end of this room because it's a pretty
long room
and if you waited on there another one
would send you back
oh where are we going i guess i was
supposed to hop off
oh man let me out
cool computer room over here
basically a bunch of redstone wire
redstone repeaters that go to each of
the doors
and this redstone wire runs all the way
up to the surface to
a giant staircase thing
you know what i i'm just realizing this
now but i must have hated torches back
then too because i had
i had pot lights throughout this whole
thing and i'm noticing like a lot of
places i
i use pot lights instead of torches just
so i
i wouldn't see the torch you know
try to make it a little fancier water
ladder back up
pretty cool um
here let's go take our our water slide
oh no is it dark
i think it's getting dark this is one of
the later things i added in the world
too
giant water slide goes up to
the build limit which was 128 at that
time
and uh it was actually pretty quick
though
can i go in f5 mode yeah f5 mode works
oh you can't do the forward-facing
camera though
this goes quite a ways and it goes over
to my giant tree farm over here
huge drop
you go way underwater it's pretty cool
uh when you break the boats there's no
way to get the boat back it always would
break into the planks and sticks
yeah this is a giant tree farm area
pretty cool and then the back i had
another one of those
water slide things over here and i guess
i should stop recording again because
it's night time
you dirty little guy he found his way in
is he trapped in the doors now
he got darn it
good thing i have a backup i didn't
think you'd be able to see me
all right let's continue with our tour
uh let's go
let's see so that door takes us down
here this is an under underwater
minecart rail line that i built which
was a huge pain
back then to build underwater there's no
efficiency tools or
aqua breathing or anything like that and
it was dark as can be
um staircase also brings brings us up
back to our main
patio i guess you would call it there's
a secret room over here
which for some reason is not where i
hide my diamonds and stuff
back over in our our house here there's
a staircase that goes this way
i don't remember where this one went oh
it doesn't go anywhere
right this takes us to our storage room
if we go in there
uh my nether portal's up here
oh yeah and the wheat i forgot about
this the sugarcane farm
i actually did this up so that the sugar
cane goes to the storage room too
it like follows a crazy water
water path
yeah there's water everywhere somehow it
makes its way to the storage room
i can't remember how i did it
um all right if we go
further oh yeah okay
stairs go up this way some doors here
this is like my zen garden area we got a
nice fountain in the middle
a wheat field trees all around the top
here to give us nice cover
give it a nature feel there is couches
here and a viewing window
on both sides um
the ladder here to this patio i guess or
balcony whatever
and yeah so that's about it for the
house
maybe quickly we'll go check out that
underwater rail line
and i think that'll be about it i can't
remember what it goes
to if anything
see can ride this down to the storage
room too
yeah it's really neat to see all this
again a lot of this stuff i forgot about
i don't know if this is going to work oh
it does cool
yeah underwater minecart tunnel
took forever to make
oh oh i don't remember that
i guess it goes underground wow this is
really long actually
i see a minecart up there that must be
the end
oh oh that was a fancy uh that was a
two-way booster thing i remember that
oh wait oh i know what this is i think
yeah
okay so this doesn't actually go
anywhere
this was like going to be a bridge here
but i never finished it oh yeah and you
don't die if you
if you're in a mine cart or a boat at
this point in minecraft
i think i was going to build in this
area but i never got around to it i
started a new world
um which we might check out next episode
if i do another one of these
so i guess let's go back to
the man cave and wrap this up
so we made it back guys and uh that was
a lot of fun i actually
i had tons of fun doing that i hope you
guys enjoyed it too
i know it's it may it might be a little
weird because
that was more my world than your guys's
so
it might not have been as nostalgic for
you as it was for me but still it's cool
to see
like alpha minecraft even um
because i haven't seen that in years or
or experienced it myself i should say
if you're wondering how i did that by
the way you can select your version
in the minecraft launcher you can select
older versions like alpha versions and
beta versions
but you got to be really careful when
you do it that you back up your worlds
and stuff
otherwise you might make a mistake and
and lose all your stuff so make sure
you're careful when you do it
um but that's that's about it for today
uh we're gonna do the comments here in
this i picked out one here that says
don't change worlds the one you're in
now
is so cool i like the idea of going into
the amplified terrain though
i remember the last time you got a new
world you didn't have any resources to
do
anything i remember that too man
actually uh i was really frustrated
because when i made my new world there
was like all these new
uh like survival themed
uh things coming out in in the patches
like enchanting and and uh
i think potions came out too when i
started this world
yeah although i did make a cool potion
room but uh
yeah i wanted to do to make like all
these farms and stuff and i just didn't
have the supplies to do it
so that was that's a good point it made
for boring vid
viewing keep up the good work so
yeah last episode i kind of uh talked
about the subject of starting a new
world i wanted to feel out what you guys
thought of it
and i was looking at some of the
comments and uh
it's not like 80 percent want this and
want this it was pretty uh actually
pretty evenly spaced like
about a third of the people wanted me to
start a new world third wanted to
just go off into amplified terrain or
whatever maybe start
in a new area and third just want me to
keep it
and and keep doing stuff around here and
finish up projects
so yeah the bulk of the
the bulk of you guys seem to want me to
to keep it though which
which is good because i'm not quite
ready to say goodbye to to this world
and there's no real reason to either
we're better off just going to a new
area
um so
and i do want to point out too like a
lot of people when i ask
like what should we do today or what
should i build or
or should we start a new world a lot of
people will say it's your world etho you
can do whatever you want
which is true but
like you guys spend a lot of time
watching my videos
so i don't feel it's only my world
i kind of want to do what you guys want
because
you're in putting your time into this
whole thing too so it's partially yours
as well
and i want i want it to be a good
experience for everybody
um so with that said if you do have
ideas for builds or things you want
want to see me do leave a comment i do
check the comments still
and uh i guess that's about it for today
though
and uh next episode i think we will do
do that tour one more time and then
after that we'll probably get back to
regular uh
what we regularly do in our our let's
play here
uh this is just like a for a fun
change and uh it's actually really easy
to record that because it's just walking
around so i can record another one
really quickly here so yeah that's going
to be it for today thank you for
watching guys and i'll see you again in
the next one
bye bye
you