hey everyone it's been a while since we
last did an enchantment so let's start
out the episode here with the 42 and
it's pretty mediocre but it's going to
be a great episode don't let that get
you down okay that last one is a bit of
a bus so we're going to try again 43
this time dang it man okay I am
determined to get a good pick to start
off this episode so we're going to do
one more one last one this is going to
be good 144 ah don't get me wrong I do
like these ones I just go through them
so quick I want efficiency for
unbreaking 3 that's the goal but ah
it'll do alright I know something we can
do to make up for the so-so pics this is
going to be good oh I've been wanting to
do this for a long long time first stack
of TNT in the LP before this the most
I've ever had it any time is usually
make like 20 or so I think was my most
and pretty soon we're going to be
rolling in this stuff oh yeah and
something I want to try out maybe to
start off with is some vertical chain
drilling with TNT let's see let's go
over here it's a fine art to master I
don't know I think I've experimented
with it before but basically we got to
remove all this stone here we don't need
it so I'm going to go to the top and I
will see you soon
okay so this is right below the mob
system y59 here we got a dig straight
down and try all out all the blocks
below us here um
man I just whizzed by when they come
down I'm gonna try do a 5x5 area I don't
know probably have to remove a few of
them by hand but we'll see how this goes
so I have water ready and enderpearls
I'm going to dig straight down so if we
fall in lava should be able to hear it
there we go
actually that's not that much it's not
as far as I thought it was going to be
oh yeah
so I know I've done this before and if
you remember my 50k specialty can't
cannon run one how the pit explodes
towards the end of it of the run
basically what I was doing is it was two
snow blocks at TNT then two snow blocks
then the TNT we're going to use let's
see how should we do this we want each
TNT to try blow up blow out a 5 by 5 by
5 area so the TNT should explode at this
height so maybe we will drill out a 3x3
by hand and see how this goes
first of all this probably is not going
to work very good because I'm just
winging it really all right do that
I guess I'll put the TNT here I don't
know yeah yeah go up see what what
should this be I just want to get this
exact so for future reference I'll be
able to do a lot quicker once I have it
figured out I'm going to go up one I
guess I guess this is the next spot we
would drill out and I'm curious to see
what kind of explosion this will do and
if it will chain or not all right so the
next one would go here repeat the
pattern as many times as you want and
see what happens so I'll finish the rest
and we will try it out yeah so this
chain is only three T it's not much of a
chain really but if it doesn't work well
we don't want it to keep going anyway so
I guess we'll just put we'll use a lever
and let's see we're using leaves because
they have a blast resistance of one so
leaves and snow or two block sets are
extremely easy to break with TNT we
might have to choose a block that has a
higher resistance nope no distance is
too great it just can't can't do it it'd
blow up it blew out the five by five
pretty good though of course we have to
take out a three by three but the amount
of blocks compared to if you did not do
that is quite a bit more I think yeah so
it doesn't chain but it's not bad
one more we'll stay on it this time it's
quite a bit of land so let me figure out
how many blocks that actually blows up
on average okay so for that set up it
mines out about 85 to 90 blocks per TNT
which is a pretty good but in order to
get that effect we actually need to mine
out twenty nine blocks ourselves in
addition and there is some remnants in
the five by five by five area usually
looks like about seven eight or nine
blocks give or take a few
so that's pretty good it does not chain
no in order to get it to chain we
probably have to move or space the TNT
one block closer or else get rid of some
of the leaves in between which isn't
really an option because we need them to
pillar up so because idea is you dig
down then you pillar up with your TNT
space properly and and whatnot you're
going to try another setup now a
different one chirps ah let's see we
will dig down again you know I'm taking
the iron I hit the blow it up and this
time we have soil we're just going to
interfere but well okay so this time I
want to try let's see we will do let's
just get this here for now get some
light so you guys can see the TNT will
explode at this height again I'm just
going to mine out four blocks like that
so the TNT will explode where my head's
at ideally
and we will see how this works
see we go what would it be spaced closer
then yeah would hmm what am I doing here
um okay well let's try space at three
blocks apart so again we'll put another
one here and just see what gets left
over one two dig dig dig dig leaf TNT
leaf leaf beat and tea kind of made a
mess here just for the sake of testing
we'll fill it in the soil is going to
interfere there feels wrong to place
blocks when our goal is to get rid of
blocks okay so I think we had four that
time in that chain see what happens
see fill chain yeah it's gaining now
looks like it to go quite a few blocks
let's go down get some light again yeah
so it comes close to a 5x5 but it leaves
a lot more residue in the corners and
obviously doesn't do doesn't do as good
of a job and it cost more TNT because we
had to use for for pretty much the same
amount of space but it's a lot easier to
do a lot less to my notes uh-huh
okay one more chain mining experiment
here I kind of forgot that the center of
the mob system is not centered with this
room down here the center of the mob
systems right where that tube is there
so I'd set up another test here let's go
up oh that looked really weird very very
weird yeah so we were down there we're
going to do a horizontal chain mining
thing same setup as before I think they
will chain pretty good because they're
only one two three four blocks apart no
five blocks apart and TNT is usually
pretty good at that range ahaha still
glad I have TT again I've missed it so
much
alright so I only set up a few few
chambers and I don't really want to
leave this is the part where I blow up
okay we're going to do another
experiment here we're going to block in
the corner and see if we die maybe we'll
go in two blocks how about that okay
dented it then bounced this way too
great yeah we're fine very nice
good chain good chain not a whole lot of
residue left either which is very good
that might become my new standard when
I'm mining out a large area because
before I was doing what was it three by
four high area and I would dig one one
wide by two high tunnel for myself and
space the TNT every five blocks like
that I think is what I was doing before
this new method though there's a lot
more efficient although it does require
more manual digging setting it up let's
do it again
TNT is awesome Oh failed chain Oh field
mob system oh lava pool nuts oh dang
that better not leak down I think it's
okay yeah there's no holes there mm-hmm
alright would blew up the leaves
alright let's fix this was good we'll
replace this with glass or ice when it's
all done but just for now and again last
one for today might fall
no word
oh yeah gotta close that off again I'll
check it in just a sec okay
there was a lava pool here I filled in
there's only one deep and that lab over
up there
I think it's contained for now very good
okay so we got a lot of land cleared
using about half a stack of TNT it's
good all right so I'll get rid of this
bottom layer yet I wanted to keep that
so I had I would have something to stand
on and we will see how it looks
yeah so we got a lot of land cleared
here today a lot of space I put in some
glass tubes just to get a feel for how
it'll be when it's all done but it's
very dark up up high there so you can't
really see much with the way it is right
now this room is going to be pretty tall
pretty high up is what I'm planning
because we're going to be extending out
these walls all four of them this way
this way this way in this way and it'll
be a fairly big room the centerpiece is
only going to be a small part of it I
think but right below the mob system
we're going to have the mob sorter which
will split the mobs into the three tubes
here if we have it on and then right
below that will probably have a ceiling
so it's not going to be quite that high
up but it'll probably be maybe now
between five and ten blocks lower we'll
have another ceiling and that will be
the fancier looking one for this room
and yeah this mom systems actually
working a lot better than I was
expecting it to considering I haven't
really made an effort to light up the
caves yet so excited to see how it'll be
when it's all done now I was messing
around with cleaning up this area a
little bit I put in stone on the floor
instead of having random blocks
everywhere and might change this with
something else yet I don't know does
have a cool texture to it but it's just
really bright considering everything
sandstone and yes I finally did the
ceiling in this room so this is the
pattern I went with and the corners it's
a white with the black middle the sides
are black with the white middle and then
the very center one is white with a
black middle again so kind of cool
pattern I like it and if we go on top if
we can go on top it's a huge mess here I
plan on cleaning this up I flattened out
this part too
so now we have a nice flat level walkway
where we can take a look at the wiring
and make any changes we might need to in
the future so that's pretty nice as well
and these are the holes that let the
sunlight down to the Pistons and to
through the glass here and lights up
this room really nice okay so one more
thing I wanted to try do today is figure
out what we're going to put behind these
four by four tile things here colored
wool was a suggestion by many so I have
three colors on me right now I want to
try black white lime I would like to
also try orange and maybe yellow and see
how they look behind these tiles I don't
have orange and yellow at the moment
though so we'll have to farm some but
this will be our test subject let's say
we'll do white first I should have
grabbed I'm going to make some shears
too now that I think of it it's white so
where's my stairs
okay have his white look not bad
kind of reminds me of those paper
Japanese doors somehow kind of cool um
shears okay should I stop recording I
always I don't know I always debate when
I should stop recording you know because
I don't want it to be boring very rarely
will you see me get items from my chest
because I don't know where stuff is
usually and it's not exactly the most
exciting thing but just this time for a
change and okay I was hoping to play on
the minecraft server tonight a little
bit so I'm probably in this episode soon
I haven't been on there very much lately
and I've been wanting to finish those
blaze traps with the with the water all
right black
that's kind of cool ooh
yeah I do like black um other questions
maybe I should do some one color and
some another one and have it alternate
but I don't you know what this room is
really really busy as it is this is like
the most whoa thing I've ever made a
Minecraft like so many different colors
so many different shapes probably should
just keep this at least this one thing
simple not a whole bunch of different
colors is it problem with having a busy
room like this is your eyes don't really
know what to look at because there's so
much crazy stuff going on so it can
actually be a bad thing but I do like
this place don't get me wrong
green nope not going to do green it's my
favorite color but in this case it just
does not work okay and that's all I have
on me so I'm going to farm some yellow
and orange wool and I'll be back ah dang
creepers okay so I made a 7x7
grass room here and this is how I'm
going to get the colored wool basically
if you plant bonemeal in the very center
it should well maybe you need a bigger
room because this grass appeared outside
so maybe it needs to be bigger
some reason I thought 7x7 was the right
number and an update what technical
problems there we go
so if you the way they I think people
used to do this in the past is they
would cause block updates next to the
grass and it would pop off like that but
generally just
spamming right-click in the darkroom
works to get all these flowers around
occasionally you'll get a piece of grass
in your face we can easily break it but
if you want to get fancy
bring out the redstone this is good for
today though like that and we are foals
so that's a quick way of getting flowers
and colored dye and we will make our
orange and yellow wool ok let's try
yellow first orange is one that I think
is going to look pretty good so that's
why we're doing it last but I think so
far black is my favorite yeah don't like
yellow it's not going to be yellow
that's for sure
so black is in first place right now
then probably white and then green then
yellow is how I would rank it but last
one orange although I never really did
like this color of orange for the wool I
wish it was not so creamsicle like and a
little bit more Orange
and no no I think I like that a little
bit more than the yellow but black is
the winner in my book
so I will convert all these to black and
see how it looks
mm-hmm yes yes very good very good I
like it I did the layer below too
we can't really see it though because we
got all the silverfish blocks from that
last disaster which I haven't cleared
out yet but yeah looks good I like it so
I think I will say goodbye for today I'm
going to go in here thank you for
watching and I will see you again
sometime other than now bye
you