[Music]
can't get me
can't get oh oh man that scared me
oh
so yes hello everybody this is etho
and i am in the nether once again having
some fun here
a new snapshot 37a have upgraded
they fixed with their skeletons so they
spawn in the existing
fortresses like like i had hoped
and they're actually fairly common
fairly common i found a few so far we
also have blaze spawning all over the
place now they're
those are really common but you see them
more than
pigmen they didn't come from there they
were naturally spawned there
so yeah i have gotten two withers
skeleton skulls
so far one more and we can
summon the wither the big guy
which is something i haven't done yet or
seen myself
but yeah i'm i'm here i've been
exploring
i might put up some video of me
exploring this place but this is
um i realized that this is the
fortress we checked out last time and
it's actually
pretty ideal for making a mob farm which
is one of
wow which is what i'm considering doing
here
still still trying to decide exactly how
i want to do that
easy guys easy
run lawn food i'm gonna have to head
back soon
but yeah if you these guys would leave
me alone for a bit
this fortress oh you know what let's
just
let's just scram here for a second
this fortress
there we go this fortress is rates
like in the middle of a lava lake almost
so it's a really good place to make a
mob
farm i would have to take out some some
nether
rack well a lot of the rack whoa
but yeah it wouldn't uh it would work
pretty good right off the bat i like
well i'm stumbling real bad today
i've been to a few nether fortresses and
this one gives a lot
of uh spawns like lots of pigment around
lots of blaze around you can see one up
there
lots of wither skeletons here so high
spawn rights already
and it would be a good place for one
okay guys i'm going to run you through
my little plan
with the mob system in the nether here
it's not definite or anything i just
thought of it within the last 30 minutes
or so so it's
probably gonna change too uh but the
main goal is
of course to summon the wither skeletons
or not summon them but spawn them
in the mob system so that we can get
their skulls
so that we can summon the wither boss
and then
and then get their stars and be able to
make beacons so it's that
it's a big long chain of events we got
to do
to do all i'm
trying to figure out exactly the rules
with with their skeletons where they
spawn
how they spawn um some of their
movements and
stuff like that and i've got most of it
figured out
uh one thing i'm doing right now though
with these torches i'm trying to figure
out if
light level matters uh with all the
other nether
mobs it doesn't so you would think it
went with them
but ever since i put these torches up i
haven't seen
one near them so
nothing's definite yet but that's one
thing i'm watching out for right now
just kind of running back and forth
and looking um
one thing i did figure out though is
they can spawn in a two block high
area and i stumbled across this by
chance
i had i had one spawned like that
and his head was stuck in the ceiling
and he wasn't able
to move so even though they can spawn in
a two block high area their collision
box seems to be
bigger and they can't actually get out
of it so
that's interesting that means i can have
a too high spawning area
and they wouldn't be able to chase after
me i could have them stuck there
so that's one thing i'm thinking about
doing
with whatever i build my mob system out
of i'll
probably want to avoid using this nether
brick because
it's really dark and it sucks for
youtube so i would probably pick
cobblestone stone brick or stone slabs
the white ones
those look pretty good in the nether
and i would want to build it out
above the lava lake here not in this
part with all the land
because these wither skeletons they
share their mob count with
the gas the zombie pigmen the blaze the
magma cubes
so if they're spawning outside of my
trap
like these guys are um
it's gonna lower my rates ideally i
would want to blow everything up
outside of my traps so that they
couldn't spawn because
the nether is just full of holes like
that and
in the ceiling there's holes everywhere
underground
it's really hard to get them all unless
you just blow
everything up but i don't really plan on
doing that so this is
a good spot oh
i did not mean to jump there that scared
me
this is a good spot because most of the
work is done for us already with this
lava lake
um so i
yeah i'm gonna probably just level the
fortress
and build rooms out of like cobble
or something uh two blocks high
might set up minecart tracks and that in
it to increase my mobility
or i might rely on speed potions to get
around quick
um as far as killing them goes to get
the mob drops i think we have to kill
them ourselves
so i'm not not going to do anything
fancy with that
it's basically going to be just a room
see them go kill them type thing
what else what else the wither skeletons
as far as i've understood they spawn
only in other fortresses but you can
kind of expand them like where they
spawn
within the fortress by
building within a chunk that has part of
a fortress in so
oh
there we go um well i get four blocks
of the fortress is in a chunk we can we
can build
into the whole chunk because it counts
the whole chunk type thing
type thing is my favorite phrase at the
moment um
you can expand it that way and when it
tries to spawn the wither skeletons it
checks that chunk
but it also checks a bounding box around
the fortress which i think extends seven
blocks
above the path i don't know exactly how
that works like if
like if it checks from the highest point
in the fortress and draws a huge
like rectangle around the whole fortress
hello
or or what the deal is exactly
or how far that guy did a lot of damage
oh wait no only two hearts we're good
oh they do hurt pretty bad
so yeah i gotta figure a few things out
yet but sometime i'd like to start this
soon
sometime soon i'd like to start this i
mean
i don't know if i'm gonna do it today i
just need one more of these and then i
can
have some fun
well i've returned home to feed our
lovely companions here they're going to
eat me alive most likely
it's my last test and then i'm out of
ideas again
i've moved the portal over further
and then i'll i'll i'll let you know all
the things i've tried to make this work
it's a glitch by the way it's not like
i'm doing this wrong
it's it's a glitch that i can't even
duplicate
in a new world like yeah it's
still doing it i have no idea why
i'm gonna die i'm gonna die i'm gonna
die
you're gonna eat me don't do it
look what they do they've killed me a
few times doing that
i've learned it well i've got armor on
this time
but it just like kills my boots
oh wow i was like they had like this
durability
before that now it's all the way down
that sucks
ah so moving the portal didn't work i've
tried orientation
orienting or oh what's
what's wrong with me orienting
i can't say the word is it orienting
whatever changing the direction the
portal is facing
before it was going this way i've
changed it to this way
still doesn't work i've done it on this
side and also on the nether side i've
tried
changing the direction
i have tried adding a lip to the bottom
having no lip
i've tried making it flat here having a
cup below
i've had blocks on one side of the
portal blocking it and i've had it open
like this
i've had it uh
very claustrophobic in here now i have
it really open
i've tried getting rid of all other
nether portals within this area that
might be interfering for some weird
reason
i have tried having the silverfish aggro
at me or not aggro at me
um what else have i done there's been a
lot of things i've tried and nothing
is fixing this then if i go create a new
world
it's like no problem at all so i don't
get what the deal is oh yeah
that's one thing else i tried i created
a new world
and had the portal like i have in my
world here down low
at about y8 and
the nether portal up like where it is in
my world here
and it it worked perfectly fine just not
in this world for some reason so i don't
really know what the deal is
i'm out ideas
okay so i think one of the new things
with this 37a
snapshot is you get xp for fishing i
just want to see how much you get
and how it gives it to you like if it
creates xp orbs or
or how it happens but
i'm not having much success here
come on it's always when you blink
whoop don't think
oh it was bobbing i saw it bobbing
that's weird sometimes it goes up and
down without the bubbles
that time it had the bubbles and i
didn't get anything
oh oh come on can't tell if it's like
glitchiness or if it's
there we go oh and i did get a few orbs
but
not much xp but it's nice a nice
addition
because really you need a lot of reasons
to fish because it's so boring
well you teleport to me hey hey get out
of here my dog teleports me again and
today he has the yellow collar
like he's supposed to
you just really want to be on the shot
don't you
also i thought i was going to kill a
zombie here but it was a zombie villager
i took a shot at him and
my stupid dog finished him off i
couldn't stop him
so i don't know what the deal was with
that i didn't think there was any
villagers left here
don't know where he came from
huh found another one
maybe they spawn near villages
and hmm i should try to cure him
and see what happens
oh he almost got me but i got him
trapped he did not cooperate
i walked around the area looking for
more and when i came back here he
despawned
so very interesting
i guess you got to carry this stuff with
you otherwise there's no chance of
curing them
all right we're going to do an
enchantment and for a change i'm doing a
bow
for good reason
and it's just pretty basic it's all
right it'll do
all right guys this is going to be fun
i'm looking forward to this
i wasn't planning on doing it this
episode but i did get
all three skulls we can summon the
wither
this is gonna be my battleground i don't
care if it gets destroyed it's my sand
quarry
um and i'm i'm really looking forward to
this
if i sound stuffed up i got a little bit
of uh
of a stuff up going on in my nose
um
yeah so i have not seen
anyone fight this guy in vanilla yet i'm
really excited i don't know how much
damage he does or how crazy it's going
to be
this is what i brought with me
decent gear i got ender pearls
got that power 4 bow sharpness 4 with
knock back
and i brought some potions along
so yeah let's have some fun here
oh boy yeah
yeah here we go
okay i think we got a little bit of time
before he
actually i think i'm gonna get away from
him if i remember right
maybe i'll wait for that oh
one heart man he's right in my face i
thought he's gonna
be like the dragon or something
dude
okay okay whoa
oh i might not be prepared
dude i think that's killing me quicker
with the regen
is it
oh my goodness he's owning me
i can't get away from him even with the
speed potion
dude no
no why can't i get away
go go go
he's not hitting me is he
he's training on my health no it's that
stupid regen i think it's killing me
maybe i don't know
oh yeah i don't know
that was weird get out of here man get
and he like fully recovered from that
too
oh oh
whoa
dang man this guy's tough
[Music]
um i don't know if i can kill him he's
gonna get me
wow
[Applause]
oh i did not expect that i don't know
oh that kind of sucks i wanted his star
so bad
i'm gonna go check that out to see if
he's still there or not
man
i'll have to re-watch that video but it
almost felt like when i took the
when i took the regen potion uh i
started losing health quicker
but i don't know definitely need better
gear though that was crazy
dude it's nighttime great
um what the heck
that is a squid i don't have time to
stop but that is hilarious
dude he's still alive
i should have brought some stone to like
build a fortification
i wonder if i can get to my stuff i
don't know where my stuff was
wow he did damage
if i don't kill him he's going to wreck
my world
wow was i up here
or was i don't want to go near him if i
didn't die there
how was it up here i don't know where i
died
oh i'm starving dang
must have been where he is there
yeah dang
what i should have did is ender pearled
away when he was right on me there
so i could recover but i didn't think of
it at the time
where is he at
did it get darker
or red it looks like kind of red out now
oh oh oh don't pull up my stuff
oh you jerk face
okay that's it
i am going to
i think i'm out of range or that so my
stuff won't be spawned
but i gotta like get a super suit on
right now
get prepared get potions again and
try to get my stuff back before he blows
it all up
or despawns
here's what i did i went to the blaze
farm and i got
a set of armor protection four
protection three
protection four uh diamond armor it'll
max me out
highest armor defense i can get in the
game
i've got potions ready speed 2
to start out with my main goal
my main goal is to keep them from
destroying anything in my world he's
getting really close
to being out of that desert which i
don't want second goal is to get my
stuff back
third goal is to kill him and get his
star
um i also got some other good stuff i
got
one of these and i got this
um this and check this out
amazing best helmet in the game i've
tried getting respiration and aqua
affinity together before and i've never
managed to but just without even trying
i got it plus protection 4 so that is
awesome
all right so i think i'm good to go oh
yeah and this is crazy
uh while i was at the blaze farm i saw
one wither skeleton
the whole time
and i got another skull from him so
already onto
getting another three going here
all right here we go rescue mission
drink that that's and
oh i should have drank the strength oh
well
get these going just about night again
it might be easier to fight him at night
if he's attacking other mobs
okay drink speed two
toss it i want to make sure my inventory
is pretty full
or i mean empty so i can pick up my
stuff because i had a lot of stuff on me
gotta move
okay it should be around here this is a
power four bow by the way
i had one more it's gotta be
up and around here somewhere i think
over there
there he is i saw him
um don't oh he's blowing up my stuff
no don't wreck it my boots
oh all my good stuff
okay i think we got most of it
let's just check one more time
arrows it's okay he's
barely hurting us now i think we're
gonna be able to take him
i'll have to check what survived later
i think the regen was okay actually
after watching the video back
but it's hard to tell all right buddy
you are a dead man oh no
he got me in a hole
[Music]
use ender pearls this time
i think i'm full health yeah i'm doing
good
he's got nothing on me
i don't like how he's right in your face
i kind of thought
like it's really annoying
it's not exactly hard to miss him either
oh yeah okay now he's in uh i have to
actually hit him with my sword now that
he's going like that
i think he's doing more damage
but still still nothing with this armor
huge whoa
did i get him
with her two did i get him
i didn't see the star drop
maybe he doesn't always drop it
he like blew up at the end there and
shot me into the air
okay well next time i do that i'm gonna
be a little more careful
about it i might have to do it at the
end or something
because that was crazy look at all the
damage he's done
yeah i don't think i got the star now
i'm going to watch a video back see if
he actually dropped one or not
because i didn't see
i ran all the way around here in the
desert looking for it and i did not find
one so i don't think he dropped one or
it might have exploded somehow
didn't get a star too bad but there's
always next time
um also i lost it looks like i lost my
pick
i think i had a shovel i lost and
my sword i actually found the sword just
about to pick it up i was five blocks
away and it despawned
i hate when that happens i
did pretty good though i got my stick
back i got my bow
got my boots and
yeah not too bad that was fun i really
enjoyed that actually
and i'm glad i was able to do it before
i saw someone else do it
and so if i spoiled it for you but it
was your choice to watch
all right
okay here's the comment i picked for
today hey etho
can you explain the whole eternal thing
why do you say it funny
i presume it's some sort of a joke that
i missed right
yeah it's it's an inside joke i'm trying
to think exactly how it happened
but i think it was i was editing
a kaiser cavern episode where he said it
that day
and then later in the day i also
recorded an lp
episode where i was building the
silverfish farm tunnel
and in honor of good i named it the
turtle
and i didn't really hear anything from
him about that
uh i think he missed it
and then randomly like weeks later
months later i we were playing vinyl
fantasy
and i said turn all again and the goo
just kind of freaked out and when did i
ever say eternal
and it just i don't know it made me
laugh so
yeah it's an inside joke
well that's it for today guys i'm going
to get going here thanks for watching
and i'll see you next time