[Music]
hey what's up everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode of our let's play
series i have noticed a new a new change
in the game
something bad for me uh there is some
silverfish getting stuck in here now
that we use this thing often but you see
between the half slabs there
i guess i can fit into that space now
although they're not or maybe they're
only spawning in it because they're not
actually trying to go
through it
which is kind of interesting but that
never used to happen like they would
never spawn
in those areas there actually that guy's
inside the glass
no he's not in the glass is he
almost looks like he's inside that glass
block above the spawner
maybe he's trapped behind it i can't
quite tell but yeah anyways guys
i have noticed my stash of ender pearls
is running dry just about out of them
so i probably should not
uh wait any longer
we gotta fix this enderman farm the
ender ender 2.0 before it's too late
so we're gonna head over there i keep
putting it off because i know it's gonna
be a lot of work but today's the day
i thought we'd just go check it out
together and and see what the situation
is
so all the string disappeared in the uh
the piston pushers i got to replace that
i brought bunch with me here
once this thing gets working again
though i'll be able to use a sword and i
should be able to
kill them all with one swing instead of
using the
the tnt explosion mechanic we had before
uh it'll be a lot simpler now but yeah i
i don't know how tricky this is gonna be
i think the
best thing to do is probably to go to
the very top and like
fall down one layer at a time and and
place the string that way maybe
i should have brought some blocks with
me ah
this little stack up here
how high does this thing go oh here we
go here we go
127 okay so what goes uh below 128
was my original design with it i'm gonna
put a torch at the top
here's the problem though we have
enderman stuck in here at and
as i'm working on this i have to deal
with them i think
i should be able to hop down one layer
at a time
uh replace the string
like so
all right that's connected
how am i going to do this without
looking at them all the time
i already messed up oh man well as long
as he doesn't teleport to me
oh and i misplaced that
where's that extra one i placed i can't
see it now oh there it is
okay so this row is done so then i
should just like hop down
do the next one so yeah it shouldn't be
too bad
awesome so i got all this string
replaced guys our enderman farm is
working once again
and it actually wasn't too difficult to
do that if an enderman got in my way
there's a trick you can do with them
if you look down
i don't think there's any way for them
to get angry at you
even if you walk through them so that's
pretty good you even have a pretty good
amount of leeway like i think you can
walk like this
even but if you go a little bit
higher what is the range
that's the range right there you don't
want to aim your cursor
any higher than that uh but yeah now
that it's all done check this out so
we can use the sword to get the splash
damage
so when we attack one it it seems to
attack like a three by three area
which is pretty sweet so it does the
full damage of the sword to one target
and then i think like half a heart to
all the ones around it
and if you have looting on your sword
you do get the looting effect on the
ones you kill with splash damage too
which is cool
but uh yeah unfortunately this
this enderman farm wasn't designed for
this so there's more spread out than i
would like to take advantage of this
trick
if you guys build one nowadays you want
to try to get them all into a 3x3 area
so you can take full advantage of it but
it's pretty good even
even like this i would say
oh man we're getting tons of levels
already
all right so maybe i'll
enchant a couple of books here real
quick and then take off so i did some
work on the
uh oh what was it the tunnel
oh i don't want that the tunnel in the
nether so we're going to go check that
out and also i'm going to go fix that
silverfish farm i'm going to fill in
those spaces so they don't spawn
uh between the slabs oh that's a good
one
right powerful oh it's just powerful and
power four
all right
there we go
[Music]
yep so check it out guys this is the
design i went for with our
nether tunnel i worked a bunch more on
it and is just about done i
ran out of iron and glass blocks and
burper blocks and
and everything pretty much but it's it's
almost
all the way to the end now so yeah i i
think it looks
decent i'm i'm happy with it i don't
like the way the rails look
particularly but i did that to stop the
zombie pigmen from spawning i
came came across something that
surprised me a little bit i'll show you
real quick
see this take off pick up the layer here
oops
okay gotta be careful i don't break the
ice yeah i thought when i was making
this originally that i could just put
slabs on both sides like i usually do so
you do like
slabs over here slaps over here and that
you would get the
uh slippery effect on the boat still
through the slab because it applies to
the player like
to your guy you see i'm kind of sliding
around on the
the slabs here so the ice effect is
still triggered
but if you do it with a boat
oh it's not going to let me place it is
it all right
yeah it's it's just like normal ground
you don't get the slippery effect
the speed effect from the ice and i
tried it with carpet and a few other
things so if you want to stop zombie big
man from spawning
you i don't know what you could use
besides rails if there is anything even
but they don't spawn on rails anymore so
i decided to go with that
i don't know if if buttons stop it i
need to look into the spawning mechanics
a bit more
uh because they've changed a lot
yeah rails are for sure safe to use to
stop the spawning
let's go for a bit of a ride here
i went for a pretty simple design
nothing too crazy just so that would be
a little bit faster to build
still took many many hours though i
gotta say like
if you if you have to go a thousand
blocks in another even a simple design
like this is going to take you at least
three hours there's no way of doing it
any faster i don't think
because for for every
here let's slow down for a sec oh every
let's see one block you go forward you
have to re
remove all the netherrack in this space
for example so
probably have to remove at least you
know 15
20 25 blocks right for your tunnel every
block so if you're going a thousand
blocks
that's 25 000. that's a lot of
netherrack
there's a lot of netherrack and then you
gotta place the blocks
and collect the materials to do it so
you got three blocks on this side three
three three that's twelve
even with the simple design if you put
blocks in the corner that's sixteen
times that by a thousand this tunnel's
actually fifteen hundred blocks long
though so
it's a lot of blocks you have to like
deal with
and there's only so fast you can place
them so
yeah if you do another tunnel design i
suggest you go simple don't do anything
too crazy i've learned the hard way
that it's just not worth it whoa
if you smack the boat with your sword it
just goes flying
that was weird you know what else is
weird look at this so if you go up the
stairs
sometimes it happens i think it depends
on just how he lines up with the stairs
but he does this like jitter jitter
climb
and sometimes it's smooth like that
second second set was smooth there
uh-huh all right so guys it happened
again
something terrible oh we even did it
over there
yes there's a tiny staircase there uh
while building that nether tunnel
i needed a whole bunch of burper blocks
right so i used the coarse fruit farm
quite a bit and when i went to use it i
got a little bit of a surprise
we weren't getting any coarse fruit from
it like we made a system
to totally automate it like a collect
well not totally but it collects
the it breaks the plant collects all the
the drops together and then auto smelts
it right
when i went to use it though that did
not happen so it turns out
i totally forgot but we actually used an
item elevator
in our design for this thing there's a
tiny little spot here
we have to go up like five blocks you
know
not a big deal with old elevator design
but now we need
we need something else so guess what i
still don't know how to make an item
elevator
i looked at some tutorials it seems like
the most common way of doing it
is with two trap doors um
one i i think you guys know what i'm
talking about one trapdoor makes items
go up and the other one acts as a gate
so the other items can't get through
but in minecraft one of my favorite
things to do is problem solving
try to figure out something to do and
then figure out how to do it so
i had uh a moment where i was thinking
outside the box what's another way of
doing item elevators
and i might have come up with a good
idea here
we're gonna try to figure it out
together let's see
let's find a flatter spot to try this
looks like it all fully grew again um
just about there's a couple white ones
still
some of them grow very fast and some of
them take quite a while they stay
super short like look at these this
one's only
two blocks tall other ones are like
fully grown i don't know why it's
it varies so much alright
yeah so let's do this here's the idea
we are going to
[Music]
have our column of glass right i want to
have a sticky piston
push the items up and i meant to silk
touch that but somehow i switched out
my silk touch pick all right the block
will come up
and here is the great
idea i hope we're gonna use a dropper
to shoot the items down
and hopefully get around the whole like
timing issues with water streams and all
that kind of stuff
so we can activate this dropper through
the wall here and we can
also check if there's any items in it
pretty easily using a comparator so if
we have a comparator
here if there's anything in here
we can find out and then we can tell it
to shoot the item out then make the
piston activate and it'll shoot the item
up
right and the really cool thing about
doing it this way
let's let's build this up just a little
bit taller so we can check it out and
it's full glory here
all right it's like a rocket elevator
it's super fast
you'll see what i mean in a second let's
put a
couple blocks in here oh yeah and to get
items into this dropper
i think we want to use a hopper like so
so you would have like your
your water stream drop the items off
into this hopper here
like you would have your ice stream
going into it
they'll go into the dropper use the
comparator to check it check when
there's items in there if there are
items in there make a clock runs
that shoots items out of here
this is being complicated shoots an item
out
or several and then activate the
piston over here
i can't make a lever no oh man
tell you what let's do it like this
and i'm totally missed it but yeah
something like that
um oops yeah let's put the glass blocks
back
fill it in properly i really need a
lever for here
and make a button okay let's do a button
that's better
alright so shoot an item out it goes
into that space there and then when this
gets activated
it shoots it out the top super quickly
which is awesome
and even like flies through the air so
you could have it
an item elevator that's invisible
basically it'll shoot the item up
through the air
and then you can catch it at the top
there um
what i'm gonna have to do is figure out
exactly how to time all this stuff
because we need to make sure the items
aren't moving after they get shot out of
the dropper they need to settle
that's why we're shooting them down so
that it
has that velocity to go downwards so
they'll settle to the block there
quicker than if we were to shoot it
sideways or something
you know all right
okay so yeah this may or may not be a
good item elevator in the end of this
i'm not sure
i'm designing it as we go here i realize
though the biggest flaw it's gonna have
is the time it takes for the items to
shoot out of the dropper and settle
so that they stop moving on top of the
block there and then it's gonna take
two redstone ticks for the piston to
extend
and retract so in total that might be
like
four redstone ticks if i was to guess
which doesn't sound like much
in that time you can shoot two items
from the dropper but that's time
where we have to stop this so if we're
doing one item
at a time it will take a very long time
between each item
so i think we're gonna have to do do it
in batches and then trigger
the piston so we might use a circuit
like this
to do that this is kind of kind of cool
basically we got two comparators here to
give it a
a thing you see how the signal slowly
disappears there
oh it's got to be a pulse though i think
yeah so it slowly fades away in that
time
we loop this comparator back to itself
and that activates the comparator clock
which will shoot items out of the
dropper as quick as possible
and then when it stops that's one will
probably trigger the piston so i think
we could even do something like a
redstone torch here
to figure out when it's done let's try
this again
oh it does flash actually hmm
maybe we put it over here
stays off and when it's done it turns on
so when it goes on it would trigger the
piston
well i don't know what to tell you guys
i thought i had something really cool
here
a very nice eloquent redstone circuit
that did pulse it did pulse but this did
not change
uh i have discovered some
inconsistencies with redstone doing this
all right and that works exactly like i
want this one works
right
sometimes it doesn't sometimes it does
weird things
what time it works yeah if you look at
this though
you see the shape of the redstone so at
the bottom left we have redstone
top left and top middle right and bottom
right
if we go over here that's exactly what i
did i i'm
there's no way i did any any different
right bottom left
top left top top middle right and bottom
right
it's the exact same thing this is the
comparator that was switched
i don't know and even if we get rid of
this thing and we use a lever
like we have down there
like look at this this comparator is
stuck on right now
it's being powered even though it's not
powered i don't i don't get what's going
on
in this world and this redstone dust is
not getting powered by it
that's got to be a visual glitch right
so confused lever
redstone compared to redstone lever
redstone compared to redstone
block subtraction comparator redstone
redstone redstone redstone redstone
guys if you know what's wrong
please let me know i do not understand
this and it's very frustrating i was
trying to avoid using a hopper clock
i wanted to try to make this simple but
that's out the window now i think
aha so guys i replaced that comparator
gizmo with a hopper clock over there
and as you can see it looks pretty
complicated
uh that was the advantage of the
comparative thing it looks simple you
know
now we got all this all this mess there
but it does seem to work pretty good
let's try it out so we throw that into
our hoppers
which are now funneling into the dropper
and with our timing gizmo we now
receive fat dice in midair
so it shoots it up at us which is a
really cool effect
quite a distance too actually isn't it
now i don't know how consistent this is
like it seems
good yeah we got all 59 back
let's try it one more time i'm worried
that's the thing if i make my
if i use my own design i have to worry
about losing items
like if there's a problem with this i
really need to
find it before i switch over to using
this
oh oh that's because we were too far
away though
uh-huh okay it's looking good looks like
we missed one block there but it did go
up straight
we were just too far away to grab it 44
58 plus the one down there
aha cool so that's that's quite a
distance one two three four five
six seven eight nine about ten blocks i
would say that shoots it
which is cool here i'll show you it
working down low here
it looks really neat
it shoots items into the empty space the
void space
and it stops for a brief moment there
and then the piston extends up
and however many items you wanted to
shoot you can adjust with the hopper
clock which is
cool kind of kind of a neat effect to it
it definitely has some cons compared to
the other
item elevator designs i've seen like
most of them
can handle a continuous stream this
cannot it has to pause
and also you're limited
how fast you can inject items into the
dropper
by the speed of the hoppers you could
set up another
thing of hoppers on this side but how do
you get
the items to go into both sets of
hoppers i'm not sure
this is our little setup here it's got
some
eight blocks in there for right now so
if there's
items in here it unlocks the hopper
clock this torch goes off
which allows us to run these are both
sticky pistons
and then if there's no items in here
this comparator is off so this the
comparator clock here doesn't run
but when this hopper clock is running
this turns on
which allows the comparator clock to run
which
makes it shoot items out of the dropper
and also it goes down here
to our piston oops
yeah over here so every cycle with the
hopper clock
there's a brief moment where
there's no items in here like eight
items here
flow slowly into this one right and then
there'll be eight items in here then
they flow
out and there'll be a brief moment where
there'll be none
in here and that's the start of the next
cycle basically
in that moment we we make this piston
extend up
so we take advantage of it and
yeah kind of cool
okay guys so right now we are over at
the purper farm
on the auto smelting line here so i
replaced that
item elevator we tore out with this new
one we designed
and this will be a good test just to try
it out see if it works if we lose the
odd purper block i don't mind
this this is a bit overkill for this i
think
unfortunately we're not taking advantage
of the item shooting
oh it actually shot over to the side hmm
i don't know
that was odd okay well we'll try it out
so where do they come up they come up
right here this will be
where the ice stream continues so we can
then put a block over top if we don't
want it
shooting up through the land like we
have it currently
that should stop it let's uh let's throw
a couple items in again just to try that
all right and it should be good to go i
would say
see if anything flies out no it stopped
it's good
and one more time no that was everything
okay so i didn't adjust how many items
shoot it at a time
by how many items i put in the hopper
clock there by the way so we could have
it do a full stack at a time or whatever
yeah so to try it out we're just going
to do a quick harvest here at the perper
farm
or coarse fruit farm it's easy to mix
the two up
it starts out as coarse fruit and then
it becomes purper
all right so just doing the final couple
breaks
then we'll go activate it you know the
nice thing about this too now that we
got a elytra wings i can just fly down
right to the button and
activate it oh feel that lag
feel that leg oh please render though it
looks so amazing watching this thing
all right here comes all the course
fruits and the seeds and stuff
getting washed down into item streams
and hoppers and stuff
all right i do notice quite a few land
on the sides here maybe i should do
something about that
not like a crazy amount like we have 10
and 16. let's run around and just see
what we get here
but it is a little bit and sometimes
they get trapped in the stairs here even
yeah not too bad like i could uh
get rid of these stairs and put block
full blocks there instead
i did that for uh decorative looks
oh yeah and over on the very end here
especially
it's not quite uh it's overhanging too
far
or the the plants they grow too far over
i should say
all right anyways i'm rambling let's go
check this out so we got
maybe like 15 or 20 of each there
so it's shooting items down the item
stream
all right and
it goes quite a ways actually so let's
go let's walk above the ground here
that was some wasted ender pearls i
moved one block every one i used there
alright and oh that's not a good sign
ah man they're all over the place
why is it not working now
what
i'm confused now
it seemed really good
huh
well let this be a lesson guys sometimes
you can waste a lot of time making
something out of redstone and then it
doesn't work
even though it looks good do i have
something
is it because maybe this isn't built up
all the way
like it's actually shooting through the
glass here even
i don't know
oh still going through the glass
maybe we need like
two box airspace to stop it yeah
one isn't enough it's traveling too fast
it'll actually shoot through it
okay
ah no they're still shooting sideways
though
ah really
it seems to be stopping a lot more now
yeah yeah it's quite a bit better now
that i made this change
having that extra air space above it
just gives it more time to slow down
and
okay okay i think we got it guys
uh might want to even remove this one
here
it needs that extra air space so that it
can stop uh and if it doesn't stop
it shoots through the glass kind of
sideways it seems
i think i'm still watching it
oh it's still happening though hmm
i think the the piston need might need
to wait a bit longer before it activates
all right anyways i think we'll uh
have to call the episode here guys let's
do the comment of the day the finish up
the comment of the day for today says
eso are you going to play stardew valley
i would really love to see you play this
and i'm sure many other people would
too so i have played
a lot of stardew valley in my whatever
free time i can find i've actually
played it more
than i should i am uh addicted to that
game
so those of you that don't know i'm a
huge
huge harvest moon fan like the old snes
nintendo 64 and back to nature for the
playstation versions those are
my favorite of the the games and i
played them a lot when i was younger
um stardew valley is very similar to
that
it's actually maybe even better i would
say
so of course i'm i'm a big fan of
stardew valley
um even before minecraft on my channel i
posted harvest moon videos without
talking in them
and those have since been deleted um
i do have a play through a very very old
very cringe
cringy harvest moon playthrough for like
10 episodes or something then i quit it
oh where are my seeds did they not go
through yet
seeds seeds
where are my seeds
what oh does this
does this use an item elevator two wait
a second
oh no
how do i get the seeds i can't even
remember
um well darn we might have lost them all
one second we have a crisis here guys
ah they're supposed to be in this chest
there's none in the chest here
how do they get up here is it an item
elevator it
is no
ah i don't want to build another one
i'm gonna have to look for a better
design than what we built today i don't
trust it
to be honest um
yeah i'll have to look into it a bit
more i was hoping to make something very
simple and i think i could have with
if those comparators worked like i
thought they would but yeah
anyways we're gonna have to wrap it up
here for today
so thank you guys for watching hope you
enjoyed it
oh yeah and the reason why stardew
valley
isn't the best for my youtube channel is
because
every day in that game is about 10
minutes long or so at most you might get
two days per video
you have to play it for hundreds of days
that's
that's many many episodes
and it would take a very long time to
get through a playthrough of that game
it's a better game for streaming
than for youtube and because of that i
don't think i'm gonna do it
even though i would love to like that is
that would be a very fun thing to play
on the channel
but it's just i would have to end it
at an arbitrary time you know so
people wouldn't be happy when i would
end it and yeah
anyways thanks for watching guys hope
you enjoyed it have a wonderful day
take care bye