hello everybody this is etho how are you
guys doing today uh I've been doing fine
just been doing just fine like
definitely didn't get a whole lot sicker
after my last episode because I I said I
wouldn't
I've been messed up these last few days
guys I'm so sorry I haven't put any
videos out this is actually my first
time trying to record since my last
episode and you can probably tell I'm
not all all the way back yet my voice is
a little crummy and there might be a few
cuts in this video if I edit out
coughing and stuff we'll see how it goes
hopefully I can do a whole episode here
though so yeah I figured let's let's
start a building project here because I
want to talk a bit so before that let me
introduce the building project so we're
going to do the fishing shack over here
and I looked up some some videos not
videos images on Google for like what a
fishing shack actually looks like
because I wasn't I wasn't sure if
they're actually a real thing I just
called it that and it turns out they are
a real thing what a surprise and they're
pretty much what you would expect it's a
shack basically but from the images I
saw they vary quite a bit you most of
them are pretty small though a lot of
the ones I saw were very old and rustic
looking kind of worn out and like almost
falling down this made out of wood most
of them and some of them were built in
the water some of them were built like
half in the water half on land so I'm
totally on land right next to the water
and yeah but pretty much all of them had
a dock around them so I think that's
what we'll do we'll try build it like
half in the water or at least maybe
mostly in the water and then part on
land and yeah so let's let's get it
going here
so my apologies guys it's been a good
three days since I've been able to
record here actually let's figure out
where I want to line this up and I still
feel pretty crummy this last month has
actually been probably the worst in my
whole YouTube thing in terms of like
unexpected things coming up and making
it so I can't record and the number of
videos I've been putting out lately is
pretty crummy so my apologies for that
that's not like that's not going to be
like a routine thing is just a very bad
set of unexpected events happening that
is kind of put my channel in a debt and
a slump I guess but that's not going to
be characteristic of it I'm going to get
back to making videos like I used to
which wasn't very many I tried aim for
quality over quantity but still I looked
it up actually and like last month I put
out 22 videos the month before that I
put out 36 so there's definitely been a
drop and like two weeks of that was
because my internet went out
unexpectedly I'm just like setting up
the dock here by the way made fashion
set up the dock first maybe I should
figure out where the cabin should go
yeah I think so maybe so I would like it
to line up with this like these three
blocks maybe we'll start it around here
I would like it to be at least one block
out of the water so this work wait why
would get over here oh you know what I
didn't know I do have an axe what a
surprise
yeah so I had identical trees for the
coffee I had a internet outage for two
weeks and I had family visiting for a
week which I knew about
that wasn't unexpected but I was
planning on getting ahead before that
happened and then nope internet outage
occurred right before it and then I
wasn't able to get anything any
recording done like I planned
all right so entrance to the building is
going to go here and then the week after
my family left I get sick
so just been crummy set of events that
have been happening but things should
start getting back to normal again from
this point on I think okay we're going
to try make them mostly out of wood here
too by the way I think the door is going
to go here and I'm going to try
something with stairs for this build
let's see we'll do it like this yes but
even though I haven't put out a lot of
videos I do want to say thank you to all
of you you've been supporting me well
still with what few videos I've been
putting out most my like single-player
and multiplayer videos gets over 300,000
views still which is awesome and plenty
of likes and and feedback from you guys
like comments and that so I do really
appreciate you guys sticking with me and
being loyal even though I've been kind
of slacking a bit I do really appreciate
it though and hopefully things will get
back to normal more so again so yeah
I've been the last three days have been
the worst like I got the flu
I really wasn't expecting you at the flu
usually like not too many people get the
flu where I live in or at least I don't
usually get the flu in the summer in
Canada I'm guessing probably in other
parts of the world though there's a the
winter flu is the big thing that gets
people usually like 60 to 70 percent of
people I would say get the winter flu
which I actually usually avoid getting
it now I used to always get it every
year
even though like I've never really taken
flu shots for it and surprise surprise I
used to get it all the time
but even though I don't take flu shots
still I've kind of stopped getting the
winter flu ever since I had one really
bad experience probably the worst time
I've ever gotten sick this is among one
of the worst times I've gotten sick I
usually don't get this sick cut because
I had like a fever and chills and queasy
stomach it's very rare I gets queasy
stomach anymore I haven't um what's a
nice way of putting it I haven't there's
no nice way of putting I haven't vomited
in like close to 10 years now so it I
have a pretty tough stomach and I
usually don't feel like I don't get it
upset stomachs too often ever since that
time I got really sick which um should I
explain what happened there my worst
experience getting sick I won't go into
too much detail but basically I threw up
because I know a lot of people don't
like to hear this kind of stuff but I
threw up with quite a bit of it
intensity one time where it was coming
out of my mouth and nose at the same
time for about 30 seconds and with a
great amount of psi so we'll leave it at
that
and ever since then I haven't vomited um
like I think my body was like I'm sorry
I overreacted I shouldn't have done that
to you I'll never do it again
let's be friends again and it's been
good ever since then let's see
how's that looking I kind of like that I
want to get some doors down here yeah I
had like a headache and sore throat nose
is running like crazy
I had like coughing spells where I would
cough for three hours and blah blah blah
blah blah everybody gets sick it sucks
and I'm just glad I'm kind of starting
to feel a lot better now which is good
like I think I'm on the road to recovery
at least I can actually talk again which
is nice
and I want to put a door here then we'll
get so this is what I want to do with
the stairs and the walls like something
like this kind of make it look a little
rougher than it probably should be and
do you want to do that for all the walls
oh I got more stairs good oops I wonder
how this would look we did it like the
whole way up and like that
hmm and if we were to I brought some
pains with me I kind of want to have
some windows too if we put a window in
no no that doesn't work okay um maybe
we'll just flip these these upper stairs
like so yeah I'm feeling a lot better so
it's good to be back and I hope you guys
didn't miss me too much
feels good to to be back
whoo-hoo all right enough of the dreary
sick doc I think let's talk about
positive things today's going to be more
of a relaxed and talky episode by the
way if you couldn't tell already
it's I just mostly wanted to let you
guys know what's been going on and give
you an update and it's it's the easiest
thing for me to record in the state I'm
into and they're they're nice once in a
while I think so that's good maybe
before we do the walls let's make sure
we're happy with the positioning of the
building because we might have to move
this whole thing if we don't like it
it's actually it's really big isn't it
like considering its small but it's
really big at the same time just because
this is a small area actually let's work
on the dock so for the dock I was
thinking we'll make it out of birch just
to give a little more variety in the
color I kind of like to work with odd
numbers so let's go three just we'll
make this all birch and I'm going to put
torches on outside for just now okay
here's another really important thing I
want to tell you guys I'm actually using
minecraft 1.6.2 so after last episode we
tried out the new snapshot we went
exploring all that I decided to load my
back up before we went exploring I was
going to continue using the snapshot
but good thing we loaded that back up
because it turns out trying to think
here uh let's see
ah was a terrible time to stop talking
sorry turns out in that first snapshot
that was released if if we went
exploring and like went to the nether
and all that and loaded the nether
structures and that they would be lost
forever like they wouldn't be saved as
structures in the game like there was no
support for that with that snapshot so
they would stop spawning with her
skeletons and blazes and that kind of
thing if we if we did that so what I
have to do in one point six point three
here is go around my world load up all
the nether fortresses and I don't have
any witch farms in my world I don't
think I never found one that's actually
let's go out a little bit further like
this this will be like my tiny peer over
here for fishing and then we'll have
posts on both sides of this I'm I don't
know villages are affected by it either
I don't think it would really matter
because you know even if they were if
the file got saved and properly or
something the villages would just
recreate themselves I think because they
still they still have all everything all
the blocks are there to make you the
village again so pretty sure they're not
an issue with that I want this to go up
further
so yeah that's going to be a job so I
got to go about a thousand blocks out my
nether and go all over so that I can
keep my nether structures and then when
I do that I'm going to update to the
snapshots because I kind of would like
to like even for this I want to try out
the fishing and stuff so I've got to get
on that and I want to build my gold farm
too very soon I was actually going to do
that next but then I got sick so we'll
probably do it after this episode
let's use let's try use fences and we
might put something underneath them
we'll just see what this looks like make
that go to there we'll bring the birch
out a little further I got to work out a
roof - I'm really bad at doing rooms in
this game I don't do them too often okay
how about we go here like that and
they're pretty excited about this
snapshot though and all the changes
there's some been some great stuff for
mapmakers and it's you know there's been
a lot of great changes format makers
lately and it's like ah so many cool
things I would like to play around with
but I can't because like I don't use
command blocks in my single-player world
here or on mine crack or anywhere so
these are all new features awesome
features coming out that I don't get a
have any fun with so while I was sick
here I started working on that that
arena you know the mat making series I
was doing I kind of got back into that a
little bit and I'm hopefully gonna try
finish that I know I keep saying it but
I would really like to finish that so
that I can start using some of this map
making targeted stuff in the game
because it seems like it's a lot of fun
maybe let's take a look from the outside
just to see where we're at
oh it's so big hmm it's it's fine though
it you can still see the water
underneath I think that's important - it
looks like it's above the water at least
um we'll definitely need to take out
more of this stone though to make it
look like it's not filling up the whole
area I'm going to work on this a bit
off-camera though just so we can get get
it done this episode and maybe we'll do
something else because I'm actually
feeling pretty good I think I could do a
bit more
awesome alright drum roll eat those
fishing shack completes almost complete
let's take a look at it I'll give you
the Grand Tour I'm pretty happy with it
it's I think it's nice and cozy actually
this is the money shot from over here I
think well maybe not I'm not sure what
angle I like the most for looking at it
maybe like this I kind of wish maybe I
should get rid of some of this stone and
open it up more so we can see it from
that angle but even like this is okay -
ah all right let's go inside though
front door
come inside there's a grand total of
let's see three times five times four
about 2,000 square feet amazing so we
can store all kinds of fishing poles
fish bait fishes fishies you know maybe
if we get a record catch or something we
can frame it in here and I don't know we
got a little bit of space to work with
here though I actually had one idea I
can't believe I'm going to do this for
what we can do inside there I'm on a big
cauldron chick ever since working on the
nether hub on the minecraft server and I
like never used cauldrons because I
think they're absolutely useless but you
know I had an idea of how we could use
one in here where do I want to put it
yeah we'll put it in this corner okay I
was thinking let's see how can we do
this let's do this for right now
I'm going to put a hopper cauldron fill
the cauldron up to two to do and this is
where I wish I had three buckets or no I
think it only takes one doesn't it yeah
that's right three buckets no one bucket
I'm still
still really loopy excuse me and this is
going to be like our fish budget so when
we catch fish we can throw them in here
and they'll they'll keep until we have
to skin them is the idea yeah yeah pixel
it picks it up good good cool I got some
glowstone for lighting there is one
concern with the way I did this you can
still see the glowstone from the top I
did it's it's a lame roof but I think
it's okay because it's such a small
building I think it's okay I did the
crummy roof like I usually do but didn't
see the ghosts on both sides if we cover
this though just go up for a second I
almost think we should leave it exposed
because if we tap if we cap it off with
something like that it gets really dark
up here because then there's no lighting
but I'm not sure of course I want
feedback on this if you think there's
something I improve let me know well out
this door we have our our nice little
dock in one of the pictures I saw of
fishing shacks they had like an overhang
over over the dock which is to keep the
rain off when you're fishing I guess and
I kind of liked how that look so I
decide to do it from here
for here too and we have the dark wood
over top we have the regular wood along
the sides like the stairs going around
and then underneath it we have birch
wood so three different colors all all
mixed into one
pretty cool fences going up to it and
one why should one or two other things I
was considering maybe we should line the
bottom with something like that I'm
wondering maybe darker would be better
because we don't really want to focus on
it and that matches with these more so
possibly should we do that
one issue with that though is I liked
being able to see the water from this
side so we have to remove more dirts so
that we could still see it get this
going
alright how's that look from up here now
mmm I'll work on it how about that I
could spend I could spend an hour on
that little detail probably but yeah
pretty cool oh yeah the other thing I
was thinking about doing these so all
the pictures I saw I don't think many of
them actually had windows like fishing
shacks I think most of them were just
like solid wood I kind of do want to
keep the windows oh but I was thinking
maybe it would be better if we made them
a little more cheaper ronald woody maybe
we should use fences instead let's just
see what that looks like that zombie I
keep hearing that zombie I I'm worried
he's kind of close actually you know I
like the panes more so we'll stick with
the panes and I guess let's try it out
eatos fishing shack whoa mouse is all
over the place this is actually the
fishing rod we enchanted last episode my
very first one but it lost the Lear two
enchantment because we downgraded to one
point six point three ah it might still
have the data saved though so when we
upgrade like it might just not be yes it
might just not be displayed on it so
when we upgrade it might be back pretty
cool though I like it so we got to do
some more terraforming around here
whoo-hoo we got two that was actually
pretty quick
and we will store those for later cool
cool I'm going to add some item frames
and we'll probably try to get all four
of the different types of fish up on the
walls somewhere and some fishing rods on
the walls and just decorate it a little
bit more but that is the fishing shack
alright everyone so I guess we'll
actually probably end let the soda
around here these these talking ones the
time goes so quick it's unbelievable
compared to when I do all the cuts and
stuff but don't worry will we get back
to our regular routine pretty quick here
I mostly just wanted to give you an
update today of what's going on one
thing though we're going to do before we
end it this guy here I asked for
suggestions on what we should call them
and I look through them and then when I
saw this one I knew that's what it had
to be I'd even look at the rest because
I knew none could top it because it was
just so good so sorry if you suggested
one that doesn't get used but this one
can't be topped just can't all right but
we got to change its color color to blue
very good very good in Naruto which is
where my skin is from this is Kakashi um
he has a dog and that dog's name well he
has like nine dogs but his main dog the
talking dog that wears a blue vest is
called that's what I get this right PA
que que un I think it's I haven't I
haven't heard the name in a long time I
think it's I guess in English it would
be packing that javi right who can ah
someone will correct me um that's how
you spell it though so we're gonna call
him that because it's most fitting I
could think of
ooh I think it spookin actually see it's
Japanese so it's it's not how it sounds
in English
and he stood up when I named him and
he's stuck in the fence I didn't put him
in that fence you got in there himself
somehow well he actually listens to me
today that's good
all right let's head back over the
fishing thing I'll show you what it's at
right now I did a little more to it and
then we will read our comments actually
we'll do it right now
ESO have you ever went camping or went
on an adventure to somewhere interesting
oh I have I have I've actually travelled
quite a bit in my life most I haven't
been out of Canada and the United States
so like I haven't been to Mexico or
Europe or anything like that but I've
gone camping quite a few times to the
west of Canada we have the Rocky
Mountains which are absolutely beautiful
and there's so much to see there and
they're actually really fun too because
there's a lot of things you can do there
like it's not just sightseeing there's
also like shopping if you go to Banff in
jasper there's a lot of shops and stuff
although it's mostly from souvenir
touristy junk but there's some unique
stuff to see like like there's one thing
I really liked is that I think it was in
Banff there's a rock store that has AM
rights and AM rights is like specific to
that region it's a rare fossil that
looks very cool it's like rainbow
coloured and stuff and you probably
wouldn't see that too many other places
in the world and they have a lot of
other cool like rocks and jewelry not
that I'm too interested in that stuff
but still need to see there's also Hot
Springs and you know you can go canoeing
and there's horseback riding cetera et
cetera but specifically camping probably
my best camping experience one time with
my family we like got all our gear like
our tents and our food and everything we
needed four nights clothes and and stuff
and we
I had to carry like 50 pounds up a
mountain
ten miles very steep mountain very rough
terrain and at the top of it we set up
camp there was like room for three tents
or so I don't think there was fire pits
but there was an outhouse up there it's
not like a campground it officially like
you didn't pay for it or anything it's
just a little bit was set up there where
you could set up a camp if you wanted
and pitch the tents and like we cooked
on the kerosene stove that we brought up
and you have to bring your own light
lighting up and that kind of stuff you
also have to really watch out for bears
so we like at night we had to tie up our
food and you know as a real camping
experience and we pitched our tents
underneath the waterfall
that was really cool then we hiked down
the next day ten miles and my feet got
all swollen and it hurt really bad and I
think I found out that I talked about
this a couple episodes ago how I can
make my feet go like like backwards some
people replied to me and said that's
actually a like a medical problem it's
like oh dang my bones are out of
alignment and my feet apparently and
that might be why like my feet swell up
when I'm on them for a long time I don't
know yeah
so uh that was probably the most pain my
feet I've ever been in now because it's
like hiked 20 miles with a lot of weight
on them and on the way down I had to
cool my feet in the river because they
were so swollen but it was really fun
it's an experience a great experience
but anyway that's all guys hope you
enjoyed I will see you again next time
hope please sounding a lot clearer and
better and happier bye bye
you