[Music]
hey hey
welcome back everybody this is etho how
are you guys doing today
uh we are back here in our single player
let's play world
that doesn't sound right does it our
single player let's play world
you know what let's let's not even think
about that uh yeah we are back
um let's see what do i press this button
it's labeled it shouldn't be so
confusing
the water but it means water comes down
and i always i always get mixed up still
press that um so yeah guys
i have just updated to the latest
snapshot i am
kind of curious about this because
let's grab our buddy here
oh no oh
oh no i have i have ignored my dog for
so long he no longer cooperates
come on guy like i'm right-clicking him
he won't stand up i had trouble with
this guy before didn't i
i forgot about that
uh maybe i should re-log he he won't
cooperate do you wanna
you want some food will you listen now
you gonna come no there's been changes
with dogs and apparently
i can't show you because my dog is kind
of dumb or disobedient or something
come on guy tried re-lodging
nope try to lead can't attach it to him
i've tried bones he won't accept them
he just wants to stay at home like he
doesn't want to go outside at all
uh what else could i do i could try
throwing some water at him i guess
and it's gone why do item frames do that
it's like you take an item out and it's
just gone forever
um
stood up for a while there no i don't
think
i don't think he wants to move anymore
he's decided
he wants to stay at home so i guess
let's go find
a new dog or two and uh
yeah if i can i don't even know where
i've seen one
like where can i go find dogs they're
pretty pretty rare sight especially in
an old world like mine
i found one i've been running around for
over an hour not even exaggerating
over an hour trying to find a wolf
somewhere
finally found one like i went all over
my world here
uh hopefully he'll be my friend
he's gone no
no where'd you go guy come on don't run
away from me
i got i got some nice treats
look how he walks oh first try awesome
all right
there's you there's a few of them here
i'm gonna grab them
because otherwise they'll just disappear
wait no that's not a dog
that's a creeper um
i saw two more oh there's one
awesome it's two
three we're gonna have so many buddies
four that should be good i think
i hope hopefully at least one or two
survive
uh the journey back we where are we even
negative 300 negative 600 that's not too
far away from home actually
so i'm gonna head on back and we finally
have wolves and we can we can get baby
wolves
so i think my favorite thing about
wolves is how you can make them do this
it's the coolest thing
just by going from a treat to not a
treat
uh anyway so we made it back got all
four guys they all survived
we're gonna get some some baby wolves
going
just because i want to see do they have
to be standing up
there you go i'm worried something's
going to happen to my sheep
little guy be nice to the sheep
oh they're so cute all right yeah so you
probably saw you probably know
but uh wolves will now chase skeletons
and we're gonna go check that out let's
see we're just going to take
how many should we take i want the
little guy for sure and maybe two
two adults all right let's go outside
guys
i want to see what kind of damage a
little the little baby puppy will do the
skeletons
um yeah so that is pretty cool it makes
sense
because the wolves like bones and
skeletons are made of bones
oh here's our first victim there's a
bunch of guys
here
oh yeah they are doing work
so the the thing that really surprised
me about this
that that really makes it cool
oh he's going after him
i find if they get in the water
they have a hard time killing the
skeleton still oh man
guys help me
that was a little guy little guy who did
some work there
so yeah the cool thing about it is the
skeletons
will actually stop like they won't
attack you
oh that's a skeleton
oh oh oh that's not good
oh
um poor dog
this is why we didn't take all of them
guys
very important all right protect me wolf
protect me
the skeletons will not shoot at you when
they're being chased which is awesome
oh oh oh okay maybe we should go back
so there's some obvious uh uses for this
uh we're gonna today try incorporate
one of the wolves into the mob sorting
system
it was pretty bad out there guy let me
let me get you back up the health
but another cool thing you could do is
uh
use these guys in a mob system you just
need like
uh four of them in each corner then you
get four ocelots in each corner
well not four in each corner one in each
corner so four total
uh for for the square and then all the
mobs just like
run towards the middle you get a
villager in the middle for the zombies
and that covers creepers skeletons
and zombies in the mob system
and you don't really have to worry about
witches too much because they're rare
so yeah pretty cool
let's see how are we gonna get these
guys
see can we get another baby no not right
now
we're gonna try to get this guy through
my portal if we can this is gonna be a
challenge
um think about uhc too these guys
would have huge implications in that
because skeletons are the biggest
problem in uhc
i see you over there
and he's gone i
i should probably relog all right
i think i didn't get him in the portal
come on guy
i need him out of the ground
oh don't don't come here for a treat
stay away i can't get him to move any
closer
if i try bump him he'll get bumped into
the lava maybe
or he'll bump me into the lava all right
all right
am i gonna die i might die
i think i'm gonna die guys do i have a
water budget
no i'm fine ah
so challenging anyway i'll be back in a
bit once i
get this worked out
all right so this is our current mob
sorter the mobs they fall down right
right there in front of the piston
ocelot makes the creepers run that way
villager makes the zombies run this
way uh and the skeletons we had just
fallen down there
they were the troublemakers because we
couldn't really tell them what to do
until now we have the wolves
to to boss them around for us so
i think we're gonna make another tube
for them to fall down
like around here and
i guess the witches will fall down
that tube because before it was the
skeletons and the witches mixed together
um if it if it all works perfect that is
of course
uh so that means the wolf should
probably go
here like right on this piston
because they'll fall down and they
should run this way
is the hope we'll see though what
happens here
um i guess block
trap door block
trap door this will be the place they
fall down
so i'm going to make a glass tube here
and we will try it out
well check this out guys my dog is
taking me for a walk
it's amazing can we go to the park
please
uh the leads do work they do work on the
dogs uh
it's just that one dog is like weird and
defective or something i'm not sure
so i can move them around with these but
i got to get them up there
and that's going to be challenging i
can't really use the lead for that
so i think i'll just pillar up and
hopefully he'll teleport up there
all right you ready guy i want you right
here if possible i'm gonna make you a
platform
you can do your super dog fly up here
move please
you should tell ports there we go
perfect all right i want you right on
the piston please
seems like a good spot yep very good
let's make some glass around you
oh i can't click there that's not glass
all right do that
i can't see what am i clicking on
i think i yeah that works okay
um unfortunately there's some redstone
here
i guess we'll just do that all right i'm
going to turn the system on and we will
see what happens hopefully
this makes it work a lot better but we
will see
actually i had a change of mind here i
think he'll be better
up here
because he's got to see the skeletons at
their head level
ah that didn't work i'm gonna try to get
him on top of this block
all right here we go guys i just
switched it on
what is it doing
um what
oops oh i messed up big somewhere um
why are the mine cart guys down in there
what did i do
i think some important block is missing
i can't tell what though
huh it's not doing it for these other
ones though it's just these two creepers
all right that's weird it's stupid my
car creepers
wrecked the whole thing
um oh did you see that
creep around that way might be because
of the minecarts though it's hard to
tell
i'll try to get rid of them oh just
happened again
what on earth like mob behavior has
changed a bit
too and now it's out of minecarts
maybe this cactus thing isn't working
anymore
yeah so we had a few problems there
didn't we
we're in a creative world now just to
check something
the t intersection had me worried it
looked like
the guys didn't want to go the right way
so i want the creeper to go there right
but i think some of the times he's gonna
come
this way
he's pretty slow these creepers
they're not too scared
that cat is gonna eat your face
your derpy face ah that made him run
the skeletons let's see where'd my
skeletons go
[Music]
skeletons are supposed to run this way
away from the dog but i think they'll
either go to the right left
or down here i don't think they're too
concerned
which way they go they just want to get
away from the dog
man these guys are taking their time
yeah look at that so
yeah t intersection will not work
properly
i think what we'll do instead we'll just
keep it aligned like it was
have the skeletons and the creepers go
to this one
so we'll put the dog with the cat over
there
and then we'll separate them again
at the bottom there i think there's a
way to do it so have another wolf
down there to split the creepers and the
skeletons up
if we do this it might not even be worth
it to be honest
because it was working okay before
uh this seems like it's just adding a
lot of extra to it i'm not sure if it'll
do much
okay i had another idea this might work
i'm gonna try move the cat
from there to let's see we want the
creepers there
right so we're going to move the cat to
here
hopefully the creepers won't run that
way they don't really have anywhere to
run
to so i think they might not
but i'm not sure we'll see zombies will
go that way
because they go after villagers like
with with the fierce vengeance
so they don't really care if there's no
land to walk to
uh and then what we'll do is we'll put
the wolf over
there and that will make the skeletons
go
this way i'm pretty sure and not go that
way because that would be
the direction of the wolf i think that's
way to handle that
and the reason i was having the minecart
problem there has been a change i had no
idea about
or when it happened but you can push
minecarts off of tracks now
it failed oh you're a quick guy
there we go yeah you just push it right
off the track
who knew i didn't know um
so that messed up my tactics thing i
tore it out
might try to use an activator rail
that's a new feature where you can
eject mobs from minecarts and yourself
if you have a powered activator rail
which is what this is
so it drops them off tends to drop the
guy off on the tracks though like the
mobs
so like not off to the side
so that might be a bit tricky still to
deal with
but it's something
you know sometimes when i'm playing
minecraft i just get that feeling like i
can't catch a break
and this is one of those moments another
new change
minecarts can activate a tripwire one
block above them now
if it's on the track it can activate the
tripwire
one block up who knew
i think we're done here for today i i
can't handle any more of this
i got another one for the list uh
activator rails
they can eject mobs like we saw
but they're also a little finicky they
don't always eject mobs
they're i don't know exactly why
but you can see he's on it for a good
second there and he's not getting
knocked out of the mine cart
uh you i need the slope as well so that
the minecart doesn't stop moving
and yeah so we got problems i should
really just work this out
another day um maybe we can go try to do
something else so
today before we end the episode i feel
like i wasted a ton of time here though
learnt new things i guess that's a plus
and we got some
some wolves again at least out of all
this
but uh yeah a little annoying
that there's so many problems now i just
wanted to test this out and uh
doesn't look like we're able to today
until i get a new
ejection system setup
yeah i think i should stop i can't get
anything to work
eject
come on so tempting
you could eject and blow up everything
and yet you still are stubborn
um yeah i don't get it
so i have officially moved on here guys
i could
i could derp around with that mob sorter
thing all day
i think um derping around is fun and all
don't get me wrong and even even the
frustrating stuff can be funny
but i do feel bad when i release an
episode and i don't get anything
productive done which is where i think
that was heading today
i think i have to just build it in
creative
and figure out how it works exactly
to get anywhere with it so we're going
to start something new
and try do it quick i saw this so this
really surprised me look at this we got
zombies and mobs every single possible
place they can spawn here
in the walls pretty much oh i should
have went down
oh he had a bad day
yeah like every dark spot in the wall
has mobs this is
this is where i got to build a mob
system uh eventually
like this is in the man cave by the tree
farm
this is such a good spawning area
it's crazy anyway so we are in
swamp land as well i'm gonna i want to
build a flower farm it's a very nice
simple project we can probably get done
uh at least the technical part of it
today might decorate it later
um
let's see i'm gonna head up to the grass
actually one sec
and look at this this is above that at
the surface just tons of mobs always
under the
the snowflake here so when i build the
mob system
uh by the man tave this is where it's
going his head's on backwards
or something so flower farm flower farm
uh swampland is the only place you can
get these blue flowers
and then we'll probably need to build
another flower farm in a flower forest
and i think that will get me
all the different types
the grass is a different color here
i just noticed that swampland it gets
greener here
and what okay this is river
huh that's kind of strange this i think
this is the old swamp grass
color i'm just fascinated by the
simplest things
this is like a new color isn't it
why is it so green here i love this
color this is a good color
for swamp much better than the brownish
color anyway hey guy
uh-huh that was weird so
there's been some changes with how
flowers work those a long time ago you
used to be able to just build a dark
room
here let's let's build a dark room real
quick just a very very tiny one
at two by two
you used to be able to build a dark room
and spam bone meal on grass
and as soon as a flower or grass would
grow on it it would get uprooted
instantly
that doesn't happen anymore
then it changed where you could update
it like if i broke this grass block next
to the flower
the flower used to pop up
and that doesn't happen anymore either
so now to actually harvest the flowers
you either gotta like
get a water stream to uproot them or
pistons to break them off or or
something like that you have to
physically remove the flower you can't
use light levels anymore i don't
think could be wrong but from what i can
tell
it seems that way so we're gonna use a
piston
design that i came up with today
um that you've probably seen before
it's not a new design or anything um i
haven't seen it used for a flower farm
yet though
awesome so i have found a location for
our flower farm we're gonna put it right
here
in the tree farm because this is the
only part of my cave that has swamp land
is in this tree farm area and we haven't
built anything here so
i think it's about time we start
expanding out this way
i feel bad like we have all these trees
and i never see them because i never
like i have nothing to walk to over here
so now i'll have something to walk to
um a flower farm and hopefully we'll add
more stuff
in this area eventually so
this is how it's going to go we're going
to lay down a bunch of rails here
and there's going to be a hopper
minecart that goes around picking up
um what you might call it
what am i thinking of picking up the
flowers and seeds and stuff
uh so basically have to do this
is it gonna connect yeah it does
see you dude like this really
yeah i tell you guys nothing nothing is
working for me today i
sort of regret upgrading to the snapshot
it seems kind of buggy
yeah that's a problem
really oh is there a
i think it was there still
and just invisible maybe
yes we did it we did it guys and
yeah oops all right that one was my
fault i admit that
okay anyway so i got some something
to tell you guys too uh oops
so difficult uh
so a long time ago i mentioned that my d
key stopped working on my keyboard like
that was a couple months ago
some of you might remember that it
didn't stop working it would
the spring in the d key broke
and so it was ultra sensitive uh i was
really thinking about getting a new
keyboard at that time i really like my
keyboard though
i've been using it for over 10 years and
it's just an awesome cheap little 30
dollar keyboard but i love it so much
i didn't want to change so i decided i'd
try to live with the broken
dt for a while and i actually got used
to it i
adjusted and didn't have too much
trouble using it
i need redstone blocks
hmm should i go run get him
nah you know what i'll do it later uh
yeah so
got used to the broken d key but then
the other day i noticed my w
key it was also on the verge of breaking
the spring broken it so it was like
pressed down
but it still worked totally normally
didn't notice any problems
uh it wasn't even sensitive like the d
key was
there's that sound um
so the other day i was recording with
pause and beef
we were doing simulation protocol and i
kept like getting stuck
and i couldn't tell on what like i would
i would be walking and then i would just
stop
and eventually i clued in that uh
my w key was broken like it wasn't
working at all like it would just
like i'd be walking forward stop walk
forward stop box
forward stop while holding it down like
it was wasn't registering
w um what it comes down to is i've
played minecraft so long now i've have
so many
hours logged in this game that my wasd
keys totally wore out on my keyboard
i think is basically what happened
we're using pistons like this by the way
and we'll push it over to
here let's see
how should we do this i almost think i
should put this in
further so you can't see it
so very sadly i decided i have to get a
new keyboard because it just kept
in getting worse and worse once i
noticed it like
within a couple hours my keyboard was
just shot
i just got worse and worse
so i got a new keyboard today new
keyboard new mouse because my mouse is
also acting up
um and just
it was like a 70 package with a wireless
keyboard
and a wireless mouse i vowed never to
get a wireless keyboard ever again
because i i got one when they first like
first
originally came out and it was new
technology and i was really excited and
it was terrible
and very unresponsive but this new one
it's actually pretty good
but it's taking me a while to get used
to the new like key layout
it's not exactly like my old keyboard
you know
which i've been using for years and
years
um that keyboard though
i spilled like five at least five drinks
in it and it never broke from that it
was such a good keyboard
i spilled two sprites in its uh like two
cups of water at least
and and some other stuff and it just
drained it out and it kept on working
and
i'll miss it but this new one seems fine
too
um anyway let me wire this up
basically i got to run a wire from all
along the pistons
and it's going to shift the grass left
and right and that will uproot all the
flowers and then the hopper minecart
below is going to pick them up
and take them to a chest to store them
and that's that's all you really need
pretty simple
oh yeah and you know one of my favorite
things about the new mouse and keyboard
they are very quiet oh yeah
so uh this is what the left and right
click sounds like
on the mouse you hear that
not too bad not too bad this is the old
mouse
really sharp clicking sound
and it really picked up in my videos too
i'm surprised nobody complained about it
at least what i saw in the comments
nobody complained about the clicking
sound
uh i do like you guys knowing when i'm
clicking
like my mouse buttons just so you know
an action is happening
uh even if if you don't see anything on
the screen you know i'm trying to click
it
but it doesn't need to be super loud and
old
keyboard spacebar
still connected by the way and the new
one
so much quieter the new the new ones
closer to the mic
too so it should be louder um
anyway so here we go this is our farm
it's not fully set up yet but it's
pretty
close we have the track over here
i set up a clock down here this only
activates when the pressure plate is
pressed up above
go back up so when this is stepped on it
uh unpowers the torch which allows the
clock to run
back and forth pretty simple
uh i did not set up the minecart to be
automatic yet
and this is not a hopper minecart oh
wait a minute
um but i'll get to that later another
day
i ran out of time for today
too much shot shopping for keyboards and
mice
all right there we go
so for now that'll just be manual anyway
so
let us give it a try bone meal
take that we'll cover this up and don't
i'll try to make this look nice later
too it's just stone right now
um and probably want the sound down for
this whenever i'm using it because it's
pretty loud
that's better all right here we go
so you just spam it in the middle that's
the middle
this right here
oh yeah pretty simple
i'm noticing the grass is growing
sometimes i'm wasting bone meal
so maybe i should speed it up
now that i see that actually not a bad
idea this clock has a limit of that
speed
so i'll have to create a new clock or a
different clock
uh if this isn't quick enough
it might not work now
yeah that's the problem with
playing with timings on camera it's not
going to work then
um see do i have a piston anywhere
i do it's up there though take this out
all right we're going to make a
monostable circuit over here as well
put it over here i guess
all right that should do it
um i might need to change the timing on
that repeater to two
it's not very uh it's not very friendly
working down here there's no
i don't have my ladders on me either i
can't get out of here easy
are they in there there they are let's
get these going man
so much better still not
don't know if i'm going to get it right
here
[Music]
hmm
oh oh we got it we got it look at that
amazing it might not be able to get much
quicker actually
okay let's try it out now let's see if
we accidentally make tall grass
again yeah i'm still doing it
i think
i think it was i'm i'm not going to hold
right click right now to see
yeah i'm still making tall grass if i
hold right click so that is a bit of a
flaw
but whatever i got tons of bone meal
all right let's try out our hopper mine
cart you're going to pick this stuff up
there it goes very cool
it missed the spot there though
oh got some more on the return trip
cool cool so i'll automate that later
i guess not bad though so i really need
one of these at a flower forest
though because i'm only getting the blue
ones the blue flowers here
flower forests have like all the flowers
uh which is what i really need
all right guys so i think that's going
to be about it for today though
i tried to make this episode a bit
longer to make up for the lack of
progress earlier
the derpiness of things not going my way
um that mob disorders just gives me so
much trouble always
it's not because i like i had it working
and now the updates seem to
have wrecked it so i have to redo it and
oh er
another day another day hey whoa
hey guy where did you come from
wow so here's a comment for today
there's that sound hey etho this is kind
of a random question but i was just
wondering
why don't you use thumbnails on your
videos
is it because you don't like them or is
it that you have difficulty with them
anyway i love your videos and thanks for
your awesome dedication
oh that was weird it like replayed the
sound
when i unpaused the the game there huh
so thumbnails guys this is
i've been meaning to bring this up again
just to see what you guys say again
because last time i asked if i should
use thumbnails like
there was a youtube uh
someone from youtube was contact me
contacted me to try to get me to do
thumbnails and
and like annotations at the end of my
videos and a few other things and i
i talked to you guys about that to see
what you thought and you said no
you don't think i need them which kind
of shocked me because i thought i did
need them
so i'm bringing it up again do you still
think i don't need thumbnails
yeah so let me know what you guys think
i i don't know what to do
because last time i asked you said no
not really necessary the majority said
no i should say
and then later the the person from
youtube called me back and
uh the thumbnail thing came up again she
said statistically
for video game youtube videos
uh they don't really make much
difference towards attracting
new people to your videos so i thought
well
if you guys don't seem to care and
it doesn't really affect my youtube
numbers why should i
care so that is why i haven't done
thumbnails up to this point but i'm
checking again
i'm checking again what you guys think
let me know anyway that is gonna be all
for today
what is going on out there
i'm gonna check for a charge creeper
real quick
i still want to charge creeper
[Music]
see any creepers around
anyway i should probably end the episode
so thank you for watching it guys
have yourselves a great day and i will
see you again in the next one
bye bye
[Music]