Hey how's it going everybody this is
Ethel welcome back guys
now don't worry about me I'm fine I'm
feeling great
very refreshed just took a little nap
little dirt nap it's all good
uh-huh so guys let's let's start out
with today talking about last episode
shall we I want to clarify a few things
because I know there was a lot of
confusion with that episode so first off
that was a backup obviously so I copied
our vanilla world here and I just used
my mod pack on it and created that whole
set up in my modded world on a backup so
nothing that we did last episode has
actually affected our world here we're
starting outs as things usually are here
if you're wondering why I made such a
weird episode last time it's because for
weeks now you guys have been asking me
in the comments to do something weird or
crazy for episode 404 because of the air
code 404 like the page not found air
code you sometimes get when you request
a webpage so I've been thinking of ideas
for it for a while and I decided I
wanted to try to surprise you guys and
confuse you and mission successful I
would say yeah but yeah I had a lot of
fun making that it was actually one of
my best received videos too had a lot of
likes a lot of dislikes it wasn't for
everybody but those of you that did
enjoy it a lot of you said it was your
favorite episode which makes me very
happy very happy indeed
I should not have gone through this
portal oh man all right okay
there we go and we are in the nether I
just wanted to show you guys where we're
at with that nether tunnel I've been
working on it here just kind of working
on it step-by-step and it's actually
just about done you can see we almost
got these arches all the way down and
got the mycelium in starting to put in
the nether brick and it's slowly coming
together it's a huge project working on
this but for today guys I had a lot of
fun with last episode this episode I'm
also very excited for because we're
going to be doing something pretty cool
here so let's head over to the man cave
area we'll just go in our our little
teleporter here shall we look at this
and three two one there we go
you like my little teleporter that that
transition probably wasn't very good
actually it's hard to match the lighting
in the nether to the overworld here but
anyway today guys the idea we're going
to be playing around with is actually a
teleporter we're going to be making an
ender Porter as I'm going to refer to it
anyway this idea I saw it on the reddit
the other day by it was posted by pi he
made a video on a rotating piston
contraption and he was able to suspend
and their pearls on it so they would
constantly bounce on the moving slime
blocks and the ender pearl would never
hit the ground um
and I'm going to link his video in the
description by the way if you want to
check it out for yourself so I've been
trying to make an ender pearl teleporter
for so long in the steam I know a lot of
other people have been too so that video
is huge
I played around with it a little bit
today the idea again and it turns out
you don't need a really huge crazy
contraption to do it either you can
actually do it really simply and I just
want to today's going to be a research
episode okay we're going to play around
with the idea and I want to show kind of
explain to you how it works and also
show you how to build it and we will
play play around with ways that we can
actually refine it and use it as a
teleporter like an actual teleporter in
our world so the idea is you need a a
piston that moves up and down and it
bounces the enderpearl on top here like
when you throw it this piston needs to
move up and and bounce it back up before
it hits the ground if it hits the slime
block it does actually absorb it so it
has to be moving when it hits it all
right guys so we're going to be doing
some experiments together here some
research I did not spend a lot of time
on this yet I did figure out a method
that works oh this isn't it I just want
to see if this works or not if it does
it's going to be a little bit more
compact than what I did before so it's
just a sticky piston with a slime block
and I got a comparator clock I'm going
to move it up and down really quickly
like that and then what we're going to
want to do put a water source here the
water slows down the enderpearls they
have higher friction in water than in
air and we want them moving as slow as
possible so it's more likely to bounce
off the sticky piston or the slime block
there then what we're going to do is
just to make a column with water up here
when I did this before like I tried this
one slime blocks first came out and I
was only able to make it bounce twice in
a row I think I might have got it
bounced three times in a row a couple
times I just never could get it
consistently working because I was
trying to precisely time everything and
it turns out if you just spam the piston
like this it actually works
very simple all right so if we throw
this up there's a chance I think it
might work okay that didn't work let's
do a couple times here
I don't know how consistent this is nope
whoa that's cool we can actually bounce
in the water up off the slime block yeah
it's not looking very good for this
let's try a couple more times just in
case we're getting unlucky or something
oh that one seems to take longer before
it stops now okay this isn't very good
this method my other one I try to
earlier work better than this so I'm
going to redo this okay so this is the
method that I got working earlier today
in a creative world it's pretty much the
same thing except I'm using regular
Pistons one's going up one's going down
here and we have two slime blocks this
is the one we're going to bounce it off
of this one over here in the middle
hopefully again I haven't played around
with this much so hopefully it actually
works okay we get it going like that and
same thing as before we're just going to
try throw an ender pearl up here and
look at that look how easy that is
unbelievable so cool so it's going to
keep bouncing on that slime block as far
as I could tell indefinitely like it's
always pushing at the same amount and
activating at the exact same time it's
kind of caught in a loop there so it's
going to keep going until you actually
shut off the machine and then it can hit
the ground and then you will teleport
that was weird as far as I could tell
earlier though oh we're fine we're good
earlier it didn't seem like I could get
it working 100% though so we might try
to refine this a bit more today
but it's pretty good like oh shut it off
again like it seemed to work at least
50% of the times I throw an ender pearl
let's try it again
so you're wondering probably well how am
I going to use this is a teleporter I'll
show you that in just a second here
actually it's pretty consistent isn't it
that's three in a row it works so it's
not bad not bad at all
so we can leave the chunk and come back
in it or leave like the load of chunks
in combat and it's still fine as far as
I could tell so we got to look into ways
of remotely flipping the switch
basically activating it if you're
playing on a server you could have your
ender pearl bouncing up and down and
then if a player wanted to like call you
their base for example if you have your
ender pearl at their base bouncing up
and down they could just push a button
and you'd be there instantly they could
instantly teleport you to their base
whenever they want to do for example it
is pretty cool
but in single-player it's a little bit
more tricky because you don't have that
other player loading the chunks and and
activating it for you you got to come up
with your own methods the first one I
want to try is just a hopper clock and
I'm going to build it between chunk
boundaries so hopefully it keeps the
chunk loaded so it says chunk 15 chunk 0
I think this is a chunk boundary between
this and this that's where I'm going to
put the hoppers the items will flow
through and hopefully keep the chunks
loaded and let me set this up alright
guys so here is our experiment this is
what we're going to try to do we have
two stacks of items in here so that will
give us a little bit of time we have the
hoppers between chunk boundaries so
hopefully this chunk over here stays
loaded and this machine keeps working
and after a certain amount of time we
should be able to teleport
although the as I'm thinking about this
I almost doubting it now but we're going
to run far away from here so that
hopefully we're far enough away the
chunks unload and we'll just see if we
randomly teleport back there after a
certain amount of time the reason I
think it might not work is because when
you load chunks in this way with with
redstone and stuff it doesn't actually
load entities so I don't think that
enderpearl will be moving when the chunk
is being loaded with the hoppers there
maybe if we push the Pistons into the
ender pearl it'll activate it but on its
own I kind of doubt it but we'll see
I'll give it a little bit of time here
ah
yes yay that is so cool so the idea is
like I could be at my amplified base for
example that's thousands of blocks away
I might need to run an errand to my
mancave here to pick something up and
then I want to go back what I could do
is just activate a machine like this on
a timer and run over to the man cave and
then after a certain amount of time I
would just get teleported back I want to
have to walk back so that would be
pretty cool this is like a simple way of
doing it but it's not very controllable
so we're going to look into one other
method here oh I might have got excited
a little too soon didn't work this time
I I'm all the way over at the stronghold
base I'm going to make my way back and
just see if we teleport eventually here
okay so check this out we're at Zed 650
we can probably go even a little bit
further here probably up to 700 it's
been doing a little bit more
experimenting should teleport any second
I believe maybe not maybe I got too far
away there we go and now we're at 206 on
the Zed so we teleported like five
hundred blocks there the reason we were
able to do that is because I turned my
chunks render distance up to 32
and 32 times 16 is 512 at 16 chunks
render we can only teleport 256 blocks
from the teleporter here so it turns out
there might be some limitations to this
when it doesn't work when I go far away
outside of the render distance and it
doesn't teleport me and I come back the
ender pearl isn't there anymore like
it's not bouncing around in here still
it's not doesn't teleport me to the spot
once the chunks load again it's just
gone so it's like it's getting destroyed
or hitting something but it's not
actually teleporting me when that
happens
all right everybody so this is now quite
a bit later here I've been playing
around with this idea kind of figure out
the mechanics what's going on and I got
a good grasp of it now so the big issue
was because I was playing on the 1.8
free one release of the game I've now
updated to one point eight point four I
might and I might teleport here I'm not
sure maybe maybe not no oh there we go I
had an ender pearl left in midair there
as one reef is going to take me back yes
I was in the one point eight four or at
one point eight pre-release and in that
version the reason the ender pearls were
just disappearing on me is because like
if you throw an ender pearl leave the
game and come back it doesn't actually
save the the pearl it's it's just gone
when you come back in the 1.8 for
release though it does save it properly
and because of that the end reporter is
going to happen guys it actually works
in 1.84 which I'm pretty happy about
still the same thing though as before
those chunks over there they're not
going to load the entities even though
the redstone is probably still running
right now so it's not until I get back
within render range which is about 500
or somewhere around the jungle tree
leave is when we get within 256 blocks
of the timer thing all right let's just
ender pearl there yes should be time up
by now I would think so we should just
randomly teleport as soon as those
chunks load within my render range I
think there we go and now we're back
yours so by now I'm guessing some of you
your eyes are glazing over and you're
like etho get to the point man why
should I care about this how can I use
it well I'm going to show you something
I've set up here I've been working on
this for a little while and I got three
ender borders set up in my world right
now we can add more but I got one in the
man cave over here so I've just got
suspended ender pearls at all three of
them and they're hooked together with
redstone this is the other way we can
control it instead of using a timer tap
a button and this is probably the best
way of doing it honestly so when I hit
this button it's going to activate the
other end reporter that I have by the
lake here all right this is the Midway
one over here so I also have another one
over the Nexus this button takes me to
the man cave this one takes me to the
Nexus before I do before i teleport
again I would want to reset the ender
pearl here and like if this is my
destination fine I can go do stuff but
if I want to do the Nexus now hit that
one
and bam we're at the Nexus which is
pretty cool isn't it like we've
transported hundreds and hundreds of
blocks in seconds doing this and we can
set up a network of these all over the
place they're really easy to set up
they're pretty easy to wire the only
real pain of this is we've got to run a
redstone wire or two of them actually
between all the end reporters and these
stretch like hundreds of blocks yeah so
basically the way this works let's say
this is the end reporter by the lake
this is the one at the man cave that
button over
they're from the man cave has to connect
to the clock at the lake and then the
lake one has a button that connects to
the clock at the man cave here so we
have two wires running between them and
basically from the lake Oh
it activates this wire down here and
once once it triggers this clock once it
shuts it off for a split second that
allows the ender pearl to land and we
get teleported because it's within
render range it's only about 200 blocks
away from here so yeah let's just go
over really quickly I tried to simplify
this the best that I could because it's
kind of complicated right these are the
conditions you need if you want to do
this you should be using Minecraft 1.8
for or later the ender Porter needs a
trigger device so either a button like
that or it needs a clock like we played
around with before it actually activate
it to disable it so the ender protein
land and the ender pearl must be in a
loaded chunk and there's three ways I
know of doing that you can either load
the chunk by yourself which is limited
by the render distance you have so
however many chunks times 16 where is it
where is it video settings there we go
so that's your render distance it could
either be activated by another player
and that's limited by whatever the
render distance of the server is and a
third way the only other way to load a
chunk that will process entities is the
spawn chunks there's a nine by nine area
at spawn that always loads entities like
the ender pearls will always be moving
there you can find that with a compass
let's see if we got one over here
actually we could probably just make one
do do to do to do simply Sark has some
pretty good tutorials on chunk loading
if you want to check that out see
compass and how to find your spawn
chunks and all that stuff but basically
the compass will take you directly to
your spawn points
oh no it's nighttime darn it and I found
mine like quite a while ago we've been
using it for that ender paroled
transport thing is asleep so we don't
get mobbed I've updated to 1.84 and I
went through the nether and I just got
wrecked by zombie pigman like didn't
even have a chance to react as soon as I
went through the portal I just got
mobbed
it was insane I died like four times
today um so yeah you see other compass
is focusing on this point here so from
this point a nine by nine area of chunks
with this as the center if we look at
our chunk numbers here if we go this way
that's zero now it jumps up to fifteen
so we just crossed into a new chunk so
we go one one chunk two chunks three
chunks up to four chunks well from from
our spawn there so up to where I got
this log here is as far as entities will
be loaded so if we set up one here it
would always be running and we could
activate it from anywhere in our world
using redstone there's just a few more
things I want to tell you guys about
this as well right now you can see my
frame rates pretty smooth but once I get
within 16 blocks of this for whatever
reason minecraft right my frame rate
does drops it's terrible it's pretty
choppy when I was on the 1.8 Prix one
release it was perfectly fine but on
1.84 it sucks so keep that in mind you
don't want to put it somewhere you're
going to be a lot because it'll probably
drive you crazy also the sound is really
annoying um in 1.84 they changed it so
ender pearls don't collide with players
so I believe you can actually set up
several of these if you want to have a
reserve if they're spaced apart rather
than activating this for like a full
second and a half you might just send it
a quick quick little pulse and maybe
only one enderpearl will hit the slime
block and then you'll still have a few
bouncing around if you want to keep like
several of them going I don't know if
I'd really recommend that though and the
other thing it turns out this backing
over here that I got is actually pretty
important to stabilizing them somehow
it's affecting their their thing or at
least on the setup yeah you see now
they're they're actually not staying
suspended yeah
so you need to have that backing
otherwise it's not going to work
Oh or it might bounce three times at the
start here and then it will eventually
just mess up I'm not doing very good
here a 10 bounce a few times before it
messes up one yeah so to put that
backing on if you do this well anyways
guys I think we'll probably wrap up our
episode here for today I hope you enjoy
this crazy crazy new contraption as much
as I do I think this thing is awesome
I'm going to be using it a lot in the
future playing around with it I'm going
to try refine it a bit better too if I
can but it works pretty good as it is
this is the kind of stuff I just love in
Minecraft when you can create new
devices like that like this that add new
features to the game even though all the
pieces have been there in the game all
along pretty much although this doesn't
work in older versions as I pointed out
it has to be one point eight point four
for the ender pearls to save properly
anyways let's get to it the comment of
the day it says did you just use your
mod pack with your survival world etho
how did you do it I don't think
1.8 versions of the mods you used in the
video even exist please make a making a
video for this it would be great
um yeah it's not that complicated really
so I just copied my vanilla world's then
I applied my mod pack to it that I use
in my modded series and that is a 1.7
but the reason I had prismarine blocks
and that kind of stuff is because I
added boat Aniyah to it as well
and boat Anya has prismarine blocks as
part of the mod and they look exactly
the same as as in vanilla minecraft
that's where those came from
other than that is pretty
straightforward really
whoop just the crazy episode to try
surprise you guys and make you not know
what would what was coming next in it
yeah I think that's going to be it for
today guys though if you have any more
questions about this that you want
answered I'll try answer them in the
future I might make a tutorial on this
but I think I've pretty much covered
everything today so unless I make some
major refinement to it we'll probably
leave it there
but anyways hope you guys have a great
day thank you for watching and I will
see you in the next episode today care
and bye bye
you