[Music]
hello
guys this is etho and welcome back to
another episode
i have been working on the villager
purifier some more
it's getting close to done i got it
wired
lights come on this thing extends
on all of them it's good uh
this is just a fun little side project i
don't know how much i'm actually going
to use it
who knows because we'll find out in time
but yeah it's getting close to done
we're not going to work on this so today
we've spent the last two episodes on it
i think
and i know you guys get tired i've seen
the same thing over and over
uh that's kind of the challenge of doing
this youtube stuff it's like
each of these projects i do i could like
if i if i just recorded in real time it
would probably fill
at least 10 episodes like this thing
alone even though this is a
relatively small project
it takes time so one of the benefits of
having lots of different projects going
on at the same time is i can
return to them weeks later and they
almost seem like new projects to you
guys
even though they're not
it's a sneaky little trick downside is i
have all these
half-finished projects that don't work
yeah oh you know what i thought that
slime
this happens every time i get tons of
spiders when i'm working on this thing
yeah there's a slime
tons of spiders because i'm in this hole
and they track me and they don't burn up
during the
day so they just keep accumulating every
night
oh oh hey so yeah we
are where i've updated to the
40a pay attention 48 snapshot and we got
some changes with slimes for one thing
uh they spawn in swamps now above ground
which is
pretty cool in low light according to
the thing
um so this is my first time going
outside since i've been working on it oh
man
there's quite a few around
someone over there
there's one in the back there drowning i
think
or or no he's stuck he can't jump that's
right
oh man so they've probably been
accumulating too
oh that actually really sucks with my
mob thing
ah dang
oh no i didn't even think of that
they're going to be taking up spots in
the mob count
huh i'm wondering if they still spawn
underground
i guess i'll find out as i go working
there a bit
there's quite a few of these these
buggers around
i don't know uh i don't know how quick
they spawn
i'm guessing they're fairly rare but
with my mob system they
they spawn more frequently for sure
oh where did he come from
don't do it don't do it
i don't think i have any dark spots in
here that's a little
a little scary i have seen slimes
let's see if there's any around yeah
there's some slime so they still spawn
underground
um yeah it's gonna affect my rates a
little bit
i think and i've gotten slimes in my
drops here so they're spawning in my
system too
um i don't think any of the big ones
will i think only the tiny ones so
that's okay
won't jam anything
let's see
i had a plan i can't remember what i was
going to do now
um well i've been underground for a
while maybe let's go look up
at the top again
and see just how many slimes are around
let's see so in this
snapshot there's a little bit of a bug
with
with breaking blocks but that's going to
get fixed i think tomorrow from what
i've heard
i think i hear him in there
the sun going down or up
it's going down
oh there he's
i guess one way i can control it is just
have pools of water around every
every so often or is this the same guy
from before and he hasn't drowned for
some reason
it doesn't seem to be taking damage
is it not deep enough
are they waterproof now
i'm a little scared man what if what if
they don't drown anymore
there he goes finally okay we're all
good
all right so this is the main thing the
big
change of the patch the reason i updated
the main reason
uh dinner bone has fixed the pillaring
which is awesome the invisible blocks
let's let's check it out
we'll go all the way up to here
oh so much better so much better thank
you
we can play the game again okay anyway
what i want to maybe do first here
uh maybe plan some stuff out so
i did not get as much heat about the
wood look of this place as i thought i
would
it does look strange to me though having
the snow i gotta admit
i think we need to do something about
that um
i asked what i should do about it and
one guy said well it's hard to know
unless you show us the walls and i don't
know what i'm doing with the walls so
let's play around with that i do know
with these arches i want them to stick
out so i want the wall
at this level okay so that gives us
one block here on the ground
um maybe okay
so i got i got snow how's it look if we
put snow on the walls
probably not too good but
oh those bats aren't that smart
they do that all the time
can i do this yeah
just we'll just set this up and see
that's what it would look like as snow
not as bad as i thought it would be um
anyway snow
oopsies
uh maybe let's try ice too
uh that's would be a lot more
challenging because again you got to
worry about it melting always
but just for the sake of this video
maybe that's all we'll do just get an
idea it's got a nice blue tinge to it
that would be cool but man the melting
issue
hmm
yeah i know i think it's gonna be a pain
to clean up
one second
here's what it would look like with
sandstone and i replaced the snow
like i would replace the snow rings with
sans sandstone as well
it it does blend well with the wood i do
not like the grass so i definitely don't
want to put grass there
it's way way too dark unfortunately
i have to use something else if we if we
go this way
uh anyway another thing i want to check
out is just what it would look like
if we were to put a little stair design
here
see we could go
go in or no that would be out
go out like this
nope i want to try the other way too
see so this way
[Music]
hmm crafting table
maybe
maybe maybe
do one there maybe one here
and one here
hmm does look a little strange though
this works pretty good for the crafting
tables too just to have have them
every so often and i added a dark stripe
around again
that's pretty good i like having
crafting tables all over the place it's
just so handy
otherwise you got to walk
did it again they're blind those bats
they don't
they can't fly straight uh
i also put in these glowstone lights
because there was a dark spot i think
that's where creepers spawned before
and now it seems to be okay
so yeah still gotta still gotta finish
organizing this stuff
and get our labels on but maybe
let's build for a little bit i i want to
make another one of these things
so let's let's build one over there
what are we yet
one two three four five that's where the
beam's at
one two three four five
right there okay
one two three four five six i think
that's what we want
all right so let's talk what should we
talk about
how school oh i feel so
sorry for the kids that have to go to
school
oh it's bad for me too actually i get
less views on my videos which means i
make less money now
i love i love holiday months
uh but yeah you guys have it worse than
me
you actually have to go to school but
hopefully you're learning stuff
one two three four one
two three four uh we played our race for
wall game the other
the other day our first one against
glacier pvp
uh spoilers cover your ears if you
haven't seen it
uh we won thankfully so we moved on to
round two
uh there's four rounds total in the
tournament
16 teams if you lose your outs
he got hurt again um a lot of people are
confused about the last
map but don't worry each map
or each each round is going to be on a
different map so the next one we're
playing is on mountain mayhem
which is a very classic race for wool
style
uh it should not be as confusing for you
guys
uh the other one it like intertwined and
it was actually a cool mechanic to it
uh if you understood the map but yeah if
it's your first time seeing it it's a
bit confusing
we could start our next one here
mountain mayhem is next and we're
playing
from what i hear some guys that are
pretty darn good at pvp like
at beau fighting and that so uh we have
to try extra hard i think this
time last time
i don't think many of us likes i think
uh i didn't think we had much time to
practice so we were a little bit
out of it and actually i messed up
really bad apparently
people said i almost costed us the game
because i put the tnt in the wrong place
when i was doing the exploits
look we just saw him fly into the block
but thankfully it didn't do that
uh actually during testing we found it
didn't work
nearly as well in multiplayer you guys
probably have no idea what i'm talking
about
a lot of i had to do like the tnt thing
like 10 times sometimes to get it to
work so it's not quite like on single
player
um anyway
mountain mayhem is next i hope it goes
well
i think we're doing that on wednesday
let's see
and there
such a slow builder i'm sorry
uh let's go up here actually no i need
slabs
that's not many slabs i know where
there's some crafting benches
oh yeah
um man i i have such an urge to get into
map making it's crazy i
keep saying i'm going to do it and then
i don't know i just don't
i like do it for a day or two i'll get i
have so many
ideas for maps but i just don't have
time to do them
and i can't justify the time because i
don't
i don't get paid for it
but i still really want to do it
i think what like i've tried i've tried
like
just to find the time by recording me
making the map
as i'm doing it and then plan to release
it later
so i don't spoil the map for anybody but
that's that's not working for me either
i still
still just let it hang
so i don't know maybe it's just a dream
i will never get to do but i do have
this big idea for a map i want to do
but i just spend spend all my day
recording
but maybe my dream will come true one
day and i'll actually make a map
that people will enjoy and that i'm
proud of
uh but yeah i i finished
amlap's uncharted territories today
that's a cool map i like that one
um thinking about playing a second
second uncharted territories
i think it was just released in beta
right now
um i saw a few screenshots it looks good
good reaction from people so far so it
looks like
that might be do that might be what i'm
doing next
all right so change that up
um i think i gotta stop building with
stairs and stuff so much i need to
try new stuff again i really like it
though
oh i know what i'm gonna do
like i like building with stairs and
half slabs but that limits me to what i
can actually use for blocks and
everything ends up looking the same so
in the future i might try different
stuff i'm really liking using
those stone slabs again they've been in
the game forever but i
just really started to appreciate them
but anyway you're probably getting bored
of me bored of watching me do this so
let's
let's go do something else
i want to see how close i can get to
this bat before he takes off
it's okay not gonna hurt you
pretty close oh there it is
what is that that's like one two three
that's only like three or four blocks
i'd say
you can get pretty close to those guys
haha they get in the way
okay i like them though they just
sometimes get my face when i'm down here
anyway i i finished
i didn't finish but i did the other two
you do the corners got to do these coves
lots and lots of wood required uh let me
know what you thought about the walls
and any other suggestions i am welcome
to
uh but yeah let's go do let's go do
something else i think uh
maybe we'll play around with the beacon
so once again in this new snapshot
the beacon has gotten another makeover i
think this is it's
it's at least a second i think it might
be the third time i know this is the
third time for the beam
so this is what it looks like now
pretty cool i like it oh oops
um i've actually like pretty much liked
them all so far i don't know why they
keep changing them
um so i think i'm gonna put it over here
actually i'm gonna have like a beacon
room
uh it works out pretty perfect
we're gonna do the full scale one so
we'll have 40 blocks all around it
in a square cube i should say
uh 40 block radius so at 320
160 that should cover just about
everything in my base all the way up to
here i think
what did i say 160
oh where are we oh there we are
um yeah so up to about here
going this way and then it should go i
think all the way up to my tree farm i
measured
wait is this covered i really want this
part to be covered 340. we can always
move it if it doesn't work out
storage room is it covered yeah so 320 3
360 up to about here is it cut off so
that works out pretty good
pretty much in the middle of everything
i've built here
um i don't know what the beam looks like
i'm curious i would have like
so far the beams have all been white i
kind of think it'd be cool if they did a
purple beam
because you know like ender chests and
that they have the purple particle
effect
it's kind of like what they're using to
to represent energy in this game
and purple looks cooler than white white
is plain purple is
purple's got color
okay well i'm gonna start digging a hole
um i want to hmm how should i do the
room
kind of want to do like a almost like a
reactor room
like with iron bars and precaution maybe
some lava i don't know
we'll see but i'm i think i want
the base of the beacon here so i'm going
to dig down and put the pyramid
like five blocks lower than this
and this is actually not the first time
i've done this today i've i set up a
beacon earlier on minecraft
but you'll probably see that tomorrow
let's see okay anyway hopefully there's
nothing of
importance underneath here
i've done some digging and we have
many many many problems it seems
we have the mushroom farm over here we
have the greenhouse
below here one of the walls is here
you can see through the cave so we got a
wall
basically we can't go any
left of this line here
um
the base of the pyramid for what i have
planned is supposed to be 11 by 11
and that is not going to fit down there
and i wanted
it to be like five blocks underground
this is only
one two three four
so and we have the potion room here
so i'm not quite sure what to do i think
we might have to put it above ground
actually
let's just let's check above here
this is the ideal position is the thing
i would like to have it here
just wish that worked out a little
better
i just want to see where it takes us
outside sounds like it's nighttime
oh no spiders have just been
tracking us this whole time and the
creepers
where are we
hmm this isn't a bad spot i got nothing
built here
so yeah maybe we'll put the beacon above
ground
instead of underground don't really know
how else i could do it
i want to get the most out of it too
because they're they're kind of tough to
get
looks like somebody had a bad day over
here
ouch they broke my boots
uh yeah i got got it ready
four and a half stacks iron i don't
think any quite all of it
and actually you know since it doesn't
matter if it's symmetrical or anything
uh since we've changed positions i'm
only gonna have
four beacons one of them will be for
speed
one for haste one for jumping and
maybe regen i'm not sure what i'm gonna
do for the fourth one
so i only need a 10 by 10 base and i've
got it
all already here
you can see the room down below it's
like five blocks below so
whatever i do put down there i want to
make sure i have room for a ceiling
a little bit of a buffer so yeah just
fill it in
i'm going to put obsidian over this as
well probably so if a creeper does blow
up
on the ground above i think
the iron will be okay and i'll probably
put iron bars around
the bottom of the beam too so the
beacons won't blow up
wow that was a whole stack already oh my
goodness
that's all right i got yeah i have like
at least 10 10 stacks of iron blocks
in my let's play here so i do not mind
spending a little bit
all right well i'll finish this up and
i'll get back to you
whoo that is pretty snazzy man look at
all that
iron so we're going to put the beacon on
still get some daylight i'm i'm being
very careful that i don't let it turn
night because i don't want
any surprises while working on this
so let's check out the new beam
that is cool i really do like that
okay that's an improvement if it was
purple that would be
the ultimate but yeah i think that is
definitely better than what they had i
wish it would turn a little
quicker though
wonder if that would cause problems
all right and the first one
did i say this is how much iron i have
left from what we had
um i think the first one i'm going to go
for
so i want i want jump haste speed
and i guess regen is what we'll go for
first one i'm doing
is the speed
okay and
oh it's kicked in speed two
that is gonna that's gonna be amazing
man
being able to run all the time super
fast
oh that's so cool
and i'm talking to people still and
nobody's as excited about beacons as me
for some reason
that i've talked to it's like why
why not it's so cool you can
uh i don't know like i'm around my man
cave all the time
and if if i can get around a lot quicker
ah this is such a great thing
but i don't know that's me like when
potions first came out
my plan was to just chug them constantly
all the time but what i found
is the time it takes to make them
constantly almost negates the time you
save
from moving around faster so i sort of
stopped that but if
if it's always active like that is just
that's what i've always wanted
and when i get jump boost i'm gonna be
all ninja like
jumping all over the place it's gonna be
sweet
okay so i'm gonna protect that
that's kind of a new glitch i've noticed
today as well stuff
some blocks are doing that a little
strange
or is that the same oh that's the same
old glitch i think that block is missing
for some reason it's not supposed to be
uh but yeah i'm going to obsidianize
that iron bar it
and just protect it as best as i can
from creepers
i've got like this problem when my
feather falling boots break
i so used to always having them on
i forget that fall damage hurts when you
don't have them on
oh well yeah i'm just loving the speed
man
i'll show you what i've done i've got
where is it guess what i can find it
easy to my home
because i got a beacon it has another
purpose
it shows you where it is yeah so i just
made an obsidian plate it's
it's um just
over here and here it's protected
diagonally too from explosions
and then i'm gonna have iron bars around
here
maybe three to five high and then
obsidian around the top of that just for
looks
and maybe try connect it to the ground
somehow i don't know
should be pretty safe though
oh it's getting night again
should be safe now though
all right how's that look i gotta be
careful with this block glitch because i
can just
instantly break obsidian i'm not careful
that's cool so yeah i might try to
connect it to the ground the top part
somehow
but i'm pretty much out of the obsidian
at the moment
so we'll leave it at that
very cool so i'm gonna read some
comments and we'll call it an episode
this is the comment i picked out for
today
dear etho lately i've noticed that you
clip away
very much of the things you upload i
would like you to not clip away as much
as you do
some things does not hurt to watch like
when you farm in uncharted territory
that's the map i'm playing but when you
dug as much as you did in the minecraft
episodes it
got boring i really like your videos
keep up the good work thank you
uh yes so the whole clipping
thing is one of the ways
my help or one of the ways i tried to
make my lp
unique from other lps at least at the
time
now you might see it more often but when
i first started
people pretty much uploaded a straight
15 to 20 minutes
period of them playing and i i was doing
clipping and stuff
uh it's a really hard bounce to find i
fi
i find um and some of it like i know
sometimes
there's stuff i should include but i
just totally skipped because i don't
feel like
putting on my headphones making sure
everything is
like around me is sound proof so it
won't interfere with my recording and
yeah so there's some laziness involved
with that
um specifically with uncharted
territories of farming in it
i've been doing montages of that
but i do watch a lot of other people
play ctm maps and
the thing i notice is they either
include
all of the farming or they
or usually people just cut it out
completely
and just get past it so i i sort of
think i have a good balance with that
with the minecraft episodes of me
digging i've actually only shown
like one or two percent of me digging
that hole
of the actual time involved so
that's all i'm doing lately on the
minecraft servers digging that hole
i could either try to make an episode
out of it
or just skip it completely i've been
trying to like do fun stuff on the
server as i do that and it's
i think it's been working out okay to
sort of buy me some time um
it is about done but yeah i think my
minecraft episode coming out after this
for
for the day after whatever um but
yeah i'm still working on getting the
right bounce with the clip being in it's
probably something i'll never
totally master but anyway
tata thank you for watching have a good
one
you