[Music]
hello everybody
welcome back get your snacks because
this is a special episode
today episode 150 we're gonna kill the
dragon
once and for all finally get that over
with
so that we can have a portal to
transport the pearls
and everything back to here so it'll
open up big opportunities big doors
moving up in the world and
i am going to get my stuff together here
we're going to make a lot of potions
i'm thinking uh weakness potions poison
i don't know what all works on the
dragon and what doesn't um
i'm gonna get uh strength potions for me
and
yeah you know basically all the potions
and then maybe if we have time we'll try
to do some enchantments
specifically for the fight i do have a
power 5 bow
but i would like to get a power 5 with
infinity on it
i don't think the flaming arrows
actually affect the dragon but i
and i'm not sure about punch
i'm not sure oh yeah by the way
apparently i gotta add some lighting
down there because it's a perfect
spawning space for spiders
did not think of that
and i did have that running with the
slimes it looks so funny
i love it hopefully we'll get a large
slime and i can show you it
they stopped when i logged out
and then he despawned when i walked away
yeah there's no big ones if we get a big
one i'll show it to you it's
very cool but anyway i'm gonna get my
stuff together
and then we might head off
okay i'm getting ready to do an
enchantment here
trying to be very careful not to go over
level 41 though
so i shook up i shook off all the xp i
didn't want
apparently my teeth spider farm oh stop
stop
get off of me oh
apparently the cave spider tubing had a
blockage in it
which i have fixed so it's working a lot
better now
there was a stair missing i don't know
when that happened but
uh i'm guessing it was affecting it for
a long time
so we're gonna do a bow enchantment and
i was looking at the numbers for
like the probability and all that for
the different levels for bow
enchantments
and apparently you don't want to go over
level 41 otherwise
you're going to get something worse so
is the number to go for maximum
and i will skip ahead here
alrighty we got it that was pretty quick
i need
i want power five and i want infinity
mostly
if i could get them together on the bow
awesome
punch two power five okay that's not bad
that's still better than
any bow i had before so that's probably
the one we'll use for the dragon
and i'm going to let the rest of that xp
that's laying on the ground
oh my games really lady from it
oh yeah now let's harvest this too
okay and i did do a bunch of brewing
already i think i got all the potions
set that we're gonna take to the end
um been waiting for a big slime to come
by so i could show you
that minecraft thing but none have
and what else i'll show you the potions
we're bringing
or at least i'll probably bring all
these
stay stay good boy
so i'm gonna bring i made some regen
potions
six of them they're extended
those are incredibly powerful if you've
ever played a spellbound caves
they are the winner um
instant health 2 splash
2 made some poisoned ones i did
i did check the wiki and apparently
there was a little bit of a quote where
it said
negative potions don't affect the dragon
but the way it was worded it's like they
weren't entirely sure about it like
they threw they threw a few at the
dragon they didn't notice any effect
the guy that wrote it so it's worth
trying
we got slowness but i'm not gonna make a
whole bunch of negative ones because
they probably won't
work so strength and i guess strength
only
works with melee attacks so i don't
think it'll add
power to the bow unfortunately
all right so another thing we're going
to be doing is uh bringing some snow
blocks with us to the end
for snowballs because people have been
telling me
they hurt the dragon apparently and also
i want to try
uh let a bunch of these guys run around
and see what happens
so i made a quick harvester here snow
harvester
and i got a bunch a bunch already and i
just want to try this shovel
efficiency 4. i know it's a waste of a
shovel but i just want to see how quick
it is
it's the same speed
no okay
i bet you there's fast well what
if i click on it i get two snowballs
what happens if i spam click
oh yeah it's much faster that is so much
faster
now i wish i had like an auto auto
clicking
mouse or something
okay we got like five or six stacks of
snow now that's more than we need
for sure i've been enchanting some
diamond armor that we'll probably use
i just put level one into the stuff uh i
got blast protection on the helmet
fire protection on the legs leggings
and i even got projectile protection 2
on the chest plate with a level 1 so
that's that's not bad
and i got 11 levels left so i'm gonna
put it into
the boots hopefully get some feather
falling or something
blast protection too okay so that's our
suit
i'm gonna suit up here and then i'm
gonna hunt some
creepers for gunpowder to make some tnt
and then i think we will be ready to go
that's the last thing on my list
creeper
hmm
oh
more creepers yes
get out of here
this sword is awesome
ouch
what
stupid grass
alright we finally got one i've been
waiting for
this now i can show you so i have a
little
temporary minecart track here which
hooks up to the loop
i've just been using it to manually try
this out
so should hopefully dock him
yep
all right let's go over here so i just
put the ground here to
oh oh dang we have spiders they're gonna
get in the way
spiders trying to wreck my day
here he comes
oh i love it so awesome
so now imagine like five or six of those
guys
well probably not that many but they'll
probably be at least two or three going
around
i think it'll look pretty funny and so i
have to set up
set that up to work automatically and i
need to
add like regulators and stuff so that
they're not
bumping into each other or if a cart
becomes empty i need some way to
make it go back into storage
that type of thing and i also will
probably need to
make a way to clear the carts in case
they get stuck
because i think if i log out that guy's
gonna get stuck
on the track and i will actually try
that
now so if i have a furnace my cart it'll
be able to collect them all and get them
moving again
all right here we go i'm gonna log out
log in oh he is moving
well for some reason he stopped one time
when i logged out
the first time maybe he ran into a
spider or something
well that's cool if he's if he's still
going this might not be as difficult as
i thought
anyway on with the show let's go get
that dragon
i made some tnt i was going to make some
bookshelves so we could enchant there
but i don't think i have enough reads
to to get 30 bookshelves so we might
have to skip that
so i am going to start carding stuff
over
and setting up storage minecarts there
and stuff
and then we will have our fight
all right everybody this is it this is
the big fight
all the preparations have been made i
have uh
i have about four stored well not about
i have exactly
exactly for storage minecarts in the end
uh they're full of potions and snow and
tnt and everything you could possibly
want for this fight
i have also made a backup
backup of my world why did he disappear
oh he must have hidden the block see i
was wondering if they did that i asked
somebody about that before and they said
they didn't i guess they do
just to try it i think he went into this
one
no no okay maybe they don't i don't know
you just disappeared though
sorry um yeah preparations are made
backup is made i just finished uploading
my world as well to mediafire so check
the video description for a link i'll
hopefully remember to include it if you
want to download my world and
check out all the new stuff uh this is
where i'm
gonna be though in the download and the
spawn is
at this bed too so if you have trouble
finding the cave
going by memory i think it is roughly at
x negative 300 z 200
so go around that area and look around
it you'll probably find it
look for the big group of reeds near the
entrance
that's how i usually find it because i i
often have trouble too
and by biomes maybe this will help you
too
imagine this is a swamp here mountains
here
desert here and then forest the cave is
in the forest
so don't go to the swamp mountain or
deserts
you're not going to find it there
anyway i think we're ready i'm going to
take diamond armor
i'm going to take my tools we won't lose
them because
we'll have the portal after we kill the
dragon
we'll have sharpness 4 which
should be pretty good um
one thing i did forget to grab those
diamonds to do the enchanting there i
brought bookshelves and everything
but i forgot the diamonds so
doesn't really matter we'll have to do
we'll just have to grab all the xp
here we go
final fight
and there is a good chance i will start
to sound bored after a while of doing
this
because it's not very exciting but
hopefully
hopefully we can make it fun
that's the goal here so first thing
we'll have to do is take out all
these uh healing orb things
which will take a long time i'm sure
um
let's see and i think i'm gonna use well
let's go through the stuff this is the
potions
i think i'm gonna use the infinity bow
to take out those towers because it
doesn't do
much damage um stop pushing me
infinity bow and i'm going to try some
snowballs too
somebody some people are telling me you
can
break those things with
uh with snowballs
that's right that's why i have the
shovel here too
sweet okay and we'll grab
some potions we'll use a long one to
start off with
and i think i have a long strength one
two
in case we have enderman getting mad at
us
grab some instant health and maybe a
regen
all right here we go power up
oh you know what else i want to do
this is for b double o thinking of you
man
hopefully the dragon doesn't wreck it
because i spent the diamond on this
thing
oh it looked like he uh he ran into the
healing orb and it kind of exploded but
didn't pretty sure that's what just
happened
okay let's get away from it don't wreck
it
are you mad at me why are you mad at me
drop you like a sack of potatoes
our chickens are still here awesome
i did not grab any mirrors dang it
oh i looked at another one
i'm not gonna put a pumpkin on my head
this fight's as lame as it is without
making it easy
where are the arrows there we go
trying to avoid the jukebox
okay so for the higher ones i'll
probably have to use arrows snowballs
aren't going to reach
pretty sure
on the record stopped no
yes just barely in range of it
this is one of the best songs
um yeah we'll save that one for later
get a little closer that one was really
far away
it's going to be hard to hit
so basically we just have to go all the
way around and shoot
all these things it's very challenging
very challenging to stay awake
oh come on this is actually pretty
challenging i'm not doing too well here
i need to get higher can't get the right
angle on it
might be able to hit from here
so this is actually going to be my
second time killing the dragon
not my first there we go finally
i did a collab thing with fvdisco
seth bling and co-star a few weeks ago
basically in one day we played for six
hours we started
in a fresh world
worked together to kill the dragon from
the start it was pretty
fun uh we were gonna release video of it
but
everybody's kind of gotten distracted
with other things i think
and it's just been sitting so i don't
know if we will end up releasing video
of it or not
but it was going to be about five
episodes or so
a real real lp ish type thing
but there were a few pretty funny
moments in it
so hopefully we'll get at least some
video out of it
and they work they do work awesome i
think that i think they damaged the
dragon too
i don't know how much probably not a
whole lot
got it
we should go revamp the jukebox
so for the fight i'm going to switch to
my powerboat
swoop down any moment
missed yeah i think we just about got
all these
i think this would be about 100 times
more entertaining if the dragon actually
shot something at you or blew fire or
did something
though and there's code in the game to
make mobs do that kind of stuff
but whatever
because he actually has range on you so
he should be arranged
fighter along with
stay away from the jukebox man or i will
kill you
and your mother
just kidding
don't do it
no i just looked at about 100 in there
okay let's switch out
uh we'll grab some more potions we'll
try the snowman out
tnt
i still have a regen i do okay
let's grab strength 2 and try slowness
poison
more poison at speed we have tried a lot
of things on the ender
dragon already like fishing rods and
that
so we know how that works guess we need
more arrows
so we won't mess around with that kind
of stuff today because we've done it
before
a lot of people keep saying to try catch
the dragon in the cage
you can't actually do that wow that did
a lot of damage
oh we missed one
we missed one guys yeah you can't
capture the dragon at all he can pass
through blocks
every type of block so
snowmen time
i should have brought some more records
did i drink my uh i did drink my stuff
all right one thing i'm thinking with
these snow golems
i've never tried them before but i think
it's possible they
might uh start attacking the enderman
and then all the endermen might go after
me instead of them i'm not sure
if that's the case i will
be in a lot of trouble here because i'll
have
every enderman in the world after me
but they might target the snow golems i
don't know
what are they doing
hang around here they aren't targeting
anybody at the moment
so they might target the dragon when it
swoops by
and i want to try slowness poison
slowness are you slow
i don't think he's slow that was a
direct hit too
got me we'll try poison right in the
face
his health is not going down i'm pretty
sure i hit him
[Music]
come on let's try it again
oh we need to refresh the jukebox again
i didn't grab a boat did i
oh yeah it was definitely a direct hit
and again oh that's gonna last a
minute man we gotta drink a regen
we're gonna die for sure
keep that instant health ready
okay snowballs are next up
[Music]
oh what's going on
it's so hard to concentrate when you're
getting poisoned
every second
okay we're gonna do it we're gonna do it
no no you won't stop me no
yes in your face
that's a lot of snow golems
poison stopped yes all right you're
gonna die
come on
that's right where's it where's the
dragon get
let's get this going here
ah come on
right over here buddy i'll he's swooping
he's swooping
oh that did not do much damage even
though we only got one off
i don't think snowballs are the way to
go
[Music]
i'll try them again
they're quick that's nice
oh yeah you kind of that's what i read
the wiki and it said you can kind of
stun them with him
he keeps switching direction when you
hit him it looks like
we'll try to get him close see if we can
stun them
oh boy nope burping up a storm here
[Music]
where is he where is he he
or she who knows
[Music]
eggs would suggest she though
stunned stun that ain't stunning
okay i'm gonna grab my bow oh people are
getting mad
what you got
i should focus here
and these guys are getting on my nerves
[Music]
what oh that dragon killed it
dang it
oh this fight's gonna feel 20 times
longer now you
bugger
oh
and i was really enjoying that
i made this so much more fun
now the record survived at least
okay what uh what should we do here
that's the infinity bow
i want the power bow
i want
some more potions grab a regen
or two
all right
oh yeah tnt we didn't do tnt i don't
know if i'm going to be able to get them
with this
oh actually we can use foot and steel
um the ender dragon definitely
is not a mob you can burn so i'm not
going to try flint and steel
lava doesn't work either i guess we'll
do this
we'll save the strength for when we're
actually attacking
get this ready okay so we'll have to try
time this i don't know if we can
have to try to
get him on a swoop
yeah that's gonna be tough
because he kind of hovers above the
ground too
hovers above the ground
so he's most of the time going to be out
of range
you can increase your chances by laying
down more
but gives us less tries to
come this way come this way oh
that was a hit but only one
and it didn't do a lot of damage
um i timed that pretty perfect though if
i do say so
myself
oh looking at enderman
try again
i time that really bad you mad at me
yeah all right strength time
we'll try our sword on the dragon
i think if you hit the head you do more
damage than the bottom
let's try to do a critical attack on the
face
and now we wait oh it's coming for
another
does a bit of damage i bet you the bow
does more though
but i don't think the strength potion
actually affects the
i bow my jukebox jukebox
jukebox back that's what i said
yeah it did a lot of damage
right between eyes
oh he's oh he's dead he's dead look at
that
it's like six in a row
yeah i did that on purpose
hmm so we don't actually want to kill
him here we wanna
try to kill him a little closer to the
enderman farm
oh didn't even see him her
him her whatever really hurt
hard to hit when he's not swooping
just about done
oh wow yeah aim for the face
okay one more hit we'll do it let's try
to kill it
a little closer to the enderman farm
if we can find it
chill it with an egg wouldn't that be
cool i don't know if you can
oh there's another one
do not want to get close to that edge
okay where is it um
we should be able to spot
the long pathway we have going to it
from a distance
still don't see it maybe it's this side
yeah we're not we're not going to kill
it right next to the enderman farm
though
but just on
the side of the island it's at at least
we can make a railroad track or
eats road or something to get from the
island to the enderman farm there it is
okay so maybe around here would be good
yeah we'll kill the dragon here
where'd he go
i don't know if it would follow you even
though i'm tempted to find out but
i don't really want to risk going on
that one wide path
and get pushed off oh we're so close
come a little
do your turn yeah i don't think that
damaged it
too bad we got a chicken though
oh okay i'm gonna do my taxes while we
wait here
carry the one
huzzah
perfect time for that to play to that
music or sound effect
that's the portal that'll let us go from
here to
the regular world or whatever back and
forth
and yeah i forgot my diamonds and
otherwise it would did the enchanting
here
because otherwise you waste quite a bit
of xp
doing it two big enchantments at once
instead of doing getting like 50 xp
then collecting more
cool and there's the egg
so hmm
i don't know how to collect these really
i'm gonna try make a platform for it
down here
cover up the portal don't want it to
fall into the portal
or maybe you can't collect these anymore
i don't know
hopefully i do it right not that it
matters much it's just
an ornamental thing
okay put snow there we will put our
piston next to it up here
okay and i guess pressure plates all i
can make
and torch is already below so i think
that'll work i hope it does
let's give it a try
there it is sweet dragon egg
spoils of war
okay let's get out of here mission
accomplished
uh we'll celebrate the proper way
gonna do some enchanting and we'll do
our victory dance
who end credits
never watch these not going to either
apparently it's like one of the craziest
things ever written by man
okay so we should spawn by our bed yep
hey
yeah that went pretty good
uh i don't we didn't get knocked off or
anything like that
um let's go through the portal one more
time just to make sure it works
let's send back here path
is still here yep and there's no dragon
anymore
and there's the portal suite so
so yeah we'll just build like a rail
line or eats road or something from
this island to there
should be fine there we go
sweet so now we can get all the ender
pearls we want
we have a good xp farm too
gonna be awesome we can get around so
much quicker now with these i bet
it's almost like we gained the ability
the ability to fly
the ability of flights with with this
fight
much faster than real travel or anything
else
except for the 40 blocks per second
trick thing
but anyway uh let's go back and do some
enchanting
i will try actually let's i want you
here when i try this i'm gonna
see how i can get around with these if i
can remember how to get out of here
anything i need to leave
now i'll take all this with me
sounds like it's raining
cool
i thought it stopped for a second
oh yeah and then you guys can see how to
get back did i bring more
i did awesome we might run a part of the
way too
so we head this way
ideally throw it at a 45 degree angle i
would assume
does two and a half hearts damage every
time so
okay we are at uh 7.75
let's see how far this takes us with one
pearl
at roughly a 45.
775 726 so roughly 50 blocks every
every throw that's pretty good
it does take a little bit of time to
land
uh speed two potions are probably still
faster
yeah actually i think running is quicker
too bad
speed two is definitely quicker
just because it takes so long for the
pearls to land
hmm actually we can test this let's
throw
let's see who gets there first
i think it is quicker actually yeah
of course oh my goodness
105 levels down the drain i
can't believe it oh
man we gotta get that stuff back
oh i can't believe that just happened
that was so sad
so sad oh
damn man
ah
what a waste oh well
it's not hard for me to get xp i just
better find that stuff i don't want to
lose that egg
actually i'm going to make a backup
right now just in case
okay i made a backup just in case this
stuff despawns before we get there
but i think we can find it
uh that's one of the awesome benefits of
uh recording while you're playing you
can go back and look at the video
so we were right past the village at
roughly
x negative 333 or so
and the pearl landed right next to red
rose
that's where the hole is so i think we
i think we'll have no trouble
oh man
just had to happen goofing around
should have just went straight back
oh well
just it's just eating at me though
that's one of the fun things about
minecraft though good good deaths like
that
just amazing coincidences
well maybe it works
oh i'm i'm way off here
should be coming up pretty quick
yeah we went past that spire there too
it's just after that
uh there's actually a lot of roses here
maybe
this might be it the place i've been
yeah how many levels are we gonna get
back
six that sounds fair
hmm this is where i was going to start
up my storage room wasn't it
i think this is a spot
and the mob system
yeah we got everything back i'm pretty
sure
okay um
we'll still do our victory dance even
though we had
quite a blow there
we're still gonna do our victory dance
we got the egg that's what counts
victory dance okay here we go uh
i wanna try out this other record i got
one
one night when i was hunting creepers
got blocks
a little bit sinister oh there we go
[Music]
not bad not bad
a little slow yeah we're going back to
cat
yeah well i can't think of any better
time to ride a pig
than after killing the dragon so here we
go
ready
oh yeah
[Music]
feels good
having time in my life here
but it's a little slow so let's
let's up up things a little bit here
all right super speed
let's go pig show the world what you're
made of
[Music]
oh yeah so much faster
i don't think he got any faster did he
[Music]
go big
yeah he's not moving at all oh well
anyway guys i'm going to end that
episode here i hope you enjoyed it
even though it's a boring fight i tried
my best to make it fun
and i did kind of have fun that was that
was cool i was a little sad when the
jukebox
was broke though but other than that
oh yeah and the death really sucked too
but
then things happen
all right i'll see you guys again next
time thanks for watching
[Music]
[Laughter]
you