hey everybody how's it going and just by
the cave spiders right now thinking
about ideas what I can do with them how
I want to set it up there's been a few
other designs people have shown which
are really good some of you have
probably seen jams crasher set up for
killing them that works really well it's
very accurate I still want to play
around with gravity here and maybe I'll
point something else out here too some
people said they had trouble setting up
a cave spider trap and you got to keep
something in mind this is really
important these little buggers they're
just so difficult to deal with they you
have to be within 16 blocks to the
spawners for them to be active and if
you're within 16 blocks of them you'll
be within range of the spiders and they
will track you so if I'm standing over
here they kind of go towards the hole
over there but if I move over here they
can fight the current and they'll follow
me you can see they're over here now so
they're not falling down the hole
anymore so you got to set up your water
streams so they go in the direction that
you are kind of thing and it's there
just a real pain that's what they are a
real pain
yeah so I'm thinking what I want to try
do today just playing around with an
idea I want to maybe it's going to take
a while but I want to dig all the area
below the spawners here about 15 blocks
down and just have them fall as soon as
they spawn instead of them being pushed
to a central point and then falling just
want them to fall right off the bat and
see how that works out these things are
a lot simpler to set up if you just have
one spawner if you have to it gets a lot
more complicated because like I said
they're tracking you so if I'm over I'm
over here the spiders from that spawner
will probably go towards the hole but
the ones from this spawner here are
probably going to go and get stuck
following me over here so it's just yeah
okay well anyway I'll play around with
it see what happens all right just to
build down all the way it's taking a
while but almost there not sure how this
will work out we won't be able to
accurately damage the spiders like this
because some will fall from greater
heights than others but yeah we'll see
we'll see what happens I just want to
try it and then I'll probably put fence
posts with water above they'll instantly
spawn they won't be able to climb
anything as they're falling the land on
the fence posts and then they'll get
collected somewhere is the plant
he stole a mushroom new this guy
how did you even get down here that's
what I want to know it's like he's above
me it's like I don't know it's so bright
down here they must step in water and
teleport and then I get down my table
the time because they're always in areas
that are too bright for them to spawn
and then I hit them they teleport out
and I never see them again
yeah this is pretty good it's really
scary being down here but I will have to
put a block above the spawner so I lose
one space doing that because otherwise
they'll spawn up there and they won't
fall down as you can see when they spawn
either one two four will spawn by the
looks of it and this is 16 blocks high
this this room here so 14 blocks below
the spawner
and a lot of them are dying when they
hit the ground so I think if I put fence
posts at this level here it'll work
that's the right height I'm going to try
it now and we'll see what happens if
they if they stay alive that's what I
want yeah so this is a good height this
is a they're not dying when they land on
the fences so that's there was 14 air
spaces below the spawner and then I put
fences there and they're all a one-hit
kill with a stone sword like I wanted
you could set it up so that so one hit
kill with your fist if if you made sure
you drop them from the exact same height
every time but I I'm fine with just
using a stone sword here I've also
noticed since I put fences there there
have
trouble climbing their behavior has
changed before they were climbing up
these walls to get me and now it's like
they don't know how so that's kind of
interesting as well so I'll probably put
water on top or yeah yeah I'll use water
probably I don't really need to because
it'll just follow me if I'm down there
but I might make them come back up here
yet just so I don't have to go down
lower and see if we need that working
and the nice thing is since they drop
down there like instantly out of the way
so that we don't have to worry about the
six spider limit next to the spawner
because before the two spawners were
kind of interfering with each other and
now there's no problems okay so I'll
keep working at it and I'll see you
again soon I came back to get some new
pics got a efficiency to one which is
nice you shouldn't see ones and my
melons and pumpkins are all grown here
so I thought I'd show you guys how it
looks I like it very happy with this
farm lost one again right there
it's not bad though put it back leave
and it's ready to go again
very nice
all right back to the spidered stuff
yeah so I'm just digging out this area
below the second spawner here almost at
the bottom
I got an efficiency to pick I think I
said that already
let's check it out it's pretty nice
quick it's not really worth putting your
levels into iron tools though I find
they just wear out too quickly normally
I just do a level one enchantment on
them but I used 15 levels to get the
proficiency to pick but the thing is the
better the quality of the tool to begin
with them better the skills we'll get on
it from my understanding so if you put
ten levels into a diamond pick you're
more likely to get better skills than if
you put ten levels into an iron pick
because it's a higher quality pick and I
think make the gold ones are the best
from what I've read so yeah usually I
just put one level into my iron iron
stuff so I'll have to put fences below
this one and water stream they'll
connect finding a strange thing with
these spiders the way I have it set up
right now they can't get out they can't
climb up to me unless like once they
fall down there they can't get to me and
even if they try one spider will shoot
out and then they fall back down kind of
kind of interesting a little weird
eventually that one spider will find a
position where they won't climb so he'll
just stay down with him but until then
he just gets rejected he's not part of
the not part of the pack they kick him
out every time that looks like we have
to rejects now
oh well poor spiders okay we're making a
good progress here coming along nicely
got lots done I've finished digging out
the second one you got the fences down
the water streams are set up there's
another stream that brings them towards
this center area for both of them
there's not really any way for me to
avoid them trapping me so I'm just gonna
have to try to deal with it so I have
like a lip here so they can't climb up
higher than the point that will kill
them you know like it's fine if they're
climbing like this as long as they want
to kill themselves from fall damage
that's what I need to avoid and then
when if I'm standing ooh oh that was
dangerous I'm sending around here
they'll they'll make it into the pack
here so that's okay they're all one hit
with a stone sword that's real nice and
they try to set something up so I can
get their items easily don't know what
I'll do about that yet for right now I
just have a ladder to go down is not
very good we got the nice glass lookout
which is cool I'll probably make it five
blocks high so I can see the spawner I
can just barely see it right now it's
over there and then I'll probably have a
lookout up top here too something over
here so that we can see both spawners
from above here and I did notice I had
my feelings about this before but I had
some torches around the spawner here the
lighting level was below seven but it
was close to seven in areas or below
eight I mean and lighting does seem to
affect the rate of spawning from what I
saw I'm 90% sure at least even though
the lighting was below 8 it was kind of
slow and then when I removed some of the
distant torches lighting went way down
and spawn rates went way up so maybe
sure lighting effects spawners now or
not now but now I'm now I'm pretty sure
that is my opinion
as of now that's how I'll word it yeah
ok um you know I have like the shortest
attention span of anybody I'm I feel
like starting a new project right now
and it's just I gotta keep working on
this it's not done not done it's going
well but it's not done and when we get
this done we'll be able to make some
kick butt diamond enchanted super duper
power tools
I want badges spoon everybody's talking
about badges spoon where he gets like 5
stacks of dirt in 20 seconds I saw it
it's amazing I want all my tools like
that all of them can be super powerful
ok and I did the iron bar thing again it
works good works well sorry
grammar nazis I'm sorry I'm not perfect
what else what else
forgetting something these guys give 5xb
apparently I thought it was more but I
looked at a chart and they give five the
only ones that give more than five are I
believe blaze and I'll probably make a
spotter for them too sometime that's the
most difficult one to deal with anyway
I'll see you again after a little bit
here and this is what it looks like
inside the spawning area I'm still
adjusting it a little bit I found I need
a two-block high clearance here because
when I had only one block the spiders
most the time would climb up the glass
and then they would fall down and die so
I got two blocks now I also raised our
iron bar thing up one so that means yeah
so this is up higher that's a four-block
drop I might have to put a half slab
below because if they fall down I think
they'll take damage now going up one
block though brings me closer to the
spawner x' as well so that'll be
beneficial I thought a really strange
glitch that I didn't know about while
building this and it's really really
annoying me actually if you have a fence
or a water stream pushing you on top of
a fence and you get pushed into a wall
this happens you automatically jump I'm
not I'm not pressing the jump button
right now it's just making me jump
constantly
it's really strange anyway um yes so
still tweaking it
lots of work involved I think I'm going
to start putting our stone bricks around
it to make it look nicer polish it up
because I'm guessing this is going to be
the final design for this one the one
closer to our base I may set up dot
games pressure style thing just for a
variety if I I probably won't do that in
a long time though since we've done this
since we've done it over here I don't
need to really but just some time I
might do it okay
oh don't you just hate that noise ah
only there was something we could do
that ended that's a lot of spiders 1:38
crazy so lights are off it's working at
about 100 percent now there's only like
one block for each spawner that I have
obstructed so it's just about as fast as
possibly you can make spider spawn here
and I got a yard of these guys my game
is down to 26 frames per second it's
unacceptable I love this part this is
the best part
watch my you use a lot of food fighting
and watch my hunger bar just going down
down down down down but my XP bar is
going up up up up my smile is getting
bigger and bigger and bigger as I do
this and it's just wonderful I love it
so I'm not done messing around with this
yet
I got a few changes I got to make yet
still someone corrected me in the
comments that I don't use yet correctly
actually be saying still whatever I'll
try I'll try to change that if I can ah
what was I talking about yeah I gotta do
something with the item collection I'll
probably put iron bars for the item
collection the items will fit through
what the spiders won't down below there
I gotta get rid of these guys first
though before I open this up otherwise
I'm going to
heat myself later would like to do more
polishing we'd like to set up a light
system and I want to set up an
enchantment room maybe a potion room
stuff like that down here in this area
this is a nice area so this takes a long
time I love it there's another sword
oh we've reached the end so right now I
just have to like I'm just doing this
one more down yet there we go okay but
yeah that's it I think I'm going to be
done working on this today well let's
try to the iron bar thing see how this
goes you light down here so the water
stream should be over here yeah Galit I
should show you the rate set they're
spawning to put iron an iron bar there
and one here
Oh like oh they can fit through that
still unless I put one hand but then
they won't climb hmm
didn't think this through how whatever
I'll figure out some other time but yeah
about 1 2 4 will spawn each time the
spawner goes so I think spawners average
spawning mom's every 21 seconds or so a
lot time they'll climb around if I'm not
in a good position down here but
and if they're backed up sometimes
they'll get on the glass and start
climbing not a big deal yeah so one two
four so we got two spawners so probably
four moms every 20 seconds or so 20 XP
yeah like one XP every second is the
rate I would say if I was to guesstimate
very roughly I'd say one XP per second
with my setup here nice all right and I
don't have to be the reparation have to
be directly over here I could probably
be moving around doing stuff in the area
as long as I'm 16 blocks within both
spawners it'll keep going yeah okay so
this was fun for today I'm going to
check the time maybe we'll do something
else all right so I did get the item
collection working here I used an iron
bar it worked I just had to put in a
different position so what's happening
now iron bars here the water stream is
directly above and there's enough of a
gap here for the items to fall down but
the spiders aren't able to come down
here and they're not able to hurt me
down here which is nice what I would
like to do is set up a piston pushing an
item pushing system to get the items up
here so I'll need one two three four
five at least five Pistons to do that ah
it won't be automatic or anything like
it won't be on a clock I mean I'll
probably have a button or a pressure
plate when I step on it the item so you
moved up here and towards me instead of
me having to go down there to pick them
up hopefully but I think we're out of
time for today it's getting late here so
I want to get editing this and then go
to bed
so this was fun for today though I hope
you enjoyed it
next time we'll probably do something
else and hopefully sometime I'll finish
this up get it looking nice set up some
more rooms that kind of thing around
here but yeah I'll see you guys again
next time take care