[Music]
hey how's it going everyone
this is etho and welcome back once again
[Music]
that thing always interrupts me
welcome back to another minecraft
episode uh
today i'm not sure but i have this
feeling it's going to be a longer
episode so you
you might want to go get a snack but i
don't know
i haven't i haven't recorded it yet so
you would know better in fact you can
just look at the time of the video and
and you'll be able to tell me if you
should get a snack or not
i'm really in no position honestly
because i don't even know if you have
snack food in your house to be honest
or maybe you're not even hungry i don't
know
if you do get a snack like what are you
gonna get are you gonna get you can get
some cookies there's some chocolate
some chips maybe maybe you should try
something healthy today
uh like get some fruits i i like
strawberries
myself but you might not like
strawberries and
hmm are you gonna get a drink you might
want to get a drink
you can't have a snack without a drink
honestly
in fact uh popcorn
you might want some popcorn popcorn's
kind of like the classic snack you can't
go with
wrong with popcorn but then you gotta
you get the popcorn popper and
you gotta put the butter on how much
butter is too much butter is a question
gotta have salt salt is a given but
don't don't put too much salt on if you
put too much on you can't undo it you
gotta start over so
so be careful but uh
anyway get a snack if you want i'm not
gonna coach you i'm i really don't know
what i should
should tell you honestly i i i shouldn't
be talking anymore
yep so today is kind of a special
episode everyone
uh because i have reached another one of
them youtube milestones
uh thanks thanks largely of course to
you guys
to you sitting there right now in your
chair i'm talking to you
where are you standing you better not be
standing this is weird um
but thanks to you guys being so awesome
and wonderful supporting my videos and
and watching them and commenting and
liking the videos and
of course a big part of it as well
subscribing because today is the 1.5
million
subscriber special woohoo
wait i got i got a couple more
so it's awesome thank you so much
everyone honestly
i really appreciate all you've done for
me this started out as like just a
little
silly hobby and uh here we are today
uh it's it's been a life-changing
experience for me personally
and i i owe it all thanks to you guys
right
i said that really badly i owe it to you
guys
thank you so much um
yep so today for this episode i thought
we would take this opportunity to uh
do a world tour of my let's play world
here because this is a pretty big part
of my channel
that helped us to get where we are today
and uh
it's actually been 11 months since the
last world tour so we're overdue for one
so i thought this would be a good time
to do it and uh
if you're new to my channel if you if
you're just getting into it
and and you're wondering what's going on
here and what's
what what i've all done this is a
perfect episode for you because we're
going to be
looking at all the different stuff and
i'll try to show you how it works and
and talk about it and yeah
and if you've seen it before if you
watch my episodes this might be a good
chance to reminisce
and i'm sure there's a few things you've
missed as well
okay so to start the tour i'm just going
to give a quick introduction to the
series
now we started in this world back in
episode 105
uh we had a world before this but
unfortunately
the adventure update broke most of the
things in it so i decided to start a new
one
and we've been here ever since and
it kind of went from this empty boring
place
little by little we kept adding more and
more builds and now there's actually
quite a bit to see there's lots
lots of cool little gadgets and gizmos
throughout the world which we're going
to check out today
when i started the world i had this idea
i was going to settle down in a cave
and try to do like a 404 challenge type
of thing
that idea has kind of changed since then
but
the 404 challenge you would like light
up a cave using lava buckets you didn't
have torches and that kind of thing
um i think this is where i teamed down
originally too right
in this area here um one of the first
things we built in the world
was actually it was the first thing
is this creeper face to mark the
territory
that this is our base um
and the goal has kind of been the same
throughout the the man cave here
uh try not to adjust adjust the shape of
it too much of course i make exceptions
but uh
try to finish it make it look nice
without using torches
there's still a few poking around here
but uh i guess we'll start
let's go up here to begin with this room
this is just like an
intersection room what is that oh it's a
slime
um got a tree in here i call these
glowing trees because they have glow
stone in
this thing is amazing this you can take
water from here and it will creates
an infinite amount it's like
yeah i don't even know how it works but
it's awesome
um this this room's mostly for looks and
to serve as an intersection we got a
bridge here a nice little waterfall
again for looks and then we come to this
area
this is my main storage room in the
world i plan on making a new one in the
future though
like a big one but uh
in the world before this
we had a giant storage room and i was
like running around that thing all the
time
i decided we need something a little
smaller uh in this one
just something very concise but still
have
like one of everything in it so i came
up with this plan we got 18 double
chests in this room
um i was able to organize just about
everything in here
to fit in these but some new items have
come out in the game
since then and it's gotten a little more
challenging
but uh all in all this storage room has
worked out pretty good for us
um i wanted to do this shutter
style thing i thought it would look cool
so
when you walk in it opens up like that
and then there's lighting behind the
chests which light up the room and
has a nice uh entrance feel to it when
you walk in
which is pretty uh this is another
important room over here we got the
furnace room
um this is for storing blaze rods but as
you can see it's not too
organized i mostly have just been
dropping off
junk that's that's a big portion of my
coal supply
uh this is set up so that um
when you put something in it triggers a
bud switch
and it plays a tune and each of these
has a different tune
and that plays so that when stuff
finishes smelting you can
you can hear it from a distance usually
which is pretty cool also this light
turns on
these two lights when you cook something
and with a lot of my builds if there's
redstone
behind the scenes i like to try to
include a door to get back there so
that's what this is for
check it out and work on it if you need
to
got the noteblocks there
uh-huh i think this area is not safe
from mobs actually
i remember like creepers would always
come come in this area and
blow me up this is behind the storage
room
all right anyway so we got that
probably the two most important rooms in
this whole cave like that i spend the
most time in
um up over here we got more waterfall
things
i got a anvils hidden over there
ender chest under this one and we have a
crafting table that comes out of the
ground here
it's pretty cool
a lot of people asked to see this thing
i made a backup before we started here
because i'll probably
load it once we're finished so i don't
mind destroying a few things
uh but it's basically just a a switch
or wait what do you call these again
i forget the name of these toggle no
they have a special name i totally
forgot
what do you call these things
oh man that's going to bug me now i'm
going to remember as soon as i stop
recording too
as usual
it's a block swapper i remember i just i
move on with my life now i feel better
about myself
yeah so it just switches out the grass
block with the crafting table and vice
versa
pretty cool uh oh yeah by the way
this these lights up here turn on when
it's daytime and they turn off when it's
nighttime
uh so right now it's daytime because
they're on that's pretty cool and we got
those
morning and nighttime tunes at play that
also indicate that we got clocks around
the place
so even though i'm underground here i
usually have a pretty good idea what
time it is in the world outside there
which is important because otherwise
i go outside and oh i don't want it to
be nighttime
and i have to go back in the cave and
sleep away the day
although i don't have a bedroom i still
need a bedroom in this place
anyway up these stairs we have this wall
room
um this is where i store my wool
obviously
but i i built this so because uh the
hardened clay blocks came out and i no
longer had a
i didn't really have a place to put them
in the storage room so i had to get rid
of the wall blocks
and i put them here and then the hard
clay took their spot down there
um and this kind of goes along with this
sheep farm i built as well this is
actually
one of my favorite things i've ever
built i really like how it looks like
the rainbow
effect it's got going on it's kind of
cool um
and there's lots of intricate details to
making it work here
so what you do you just run along it's
not very efficient though
i will say that this is not designed to
be efficient
uh i call it my pop-up sheep farm by the
way
so so uh oh you just saw it there
actually
uh when the sheep regrow their wool they
pop up and then the light turns on and
you know they're ready to go
when you harvest or harvest
that sounds so wrong when you when you
clip them
you don't harvest the sheep you can push
that to manually drop them down if you
want
or there's like a master control switch
at the start of the farm which i usually
use
this at the end here this is in case
i've never used this before actually
i kind of doubt it works still even
this is in case one of the sheep dies i
have backup sheep here that i can
i can breed a new one and then have them
take their place
this minecart is to get them out of
there i think but i don't think it works
anymore um anyway so you go along
you clip their wool
hey how's it going
he wants to be in the spotlight and then
water comes down out of the ceiling here
and it washes the wool
down these sewer grates and you see
there's some pressure plates
uh when they those get triggered it does
the same as pressing this button here
it drops them down so that is pretty
cool
but some things have changed in the game
the wool like explodes out further than
it used to so it doesn't work
quite right anymore
but i'll show you how how it works
anyway so this is the master control for
the water
makes this come up so the water doesn't
flow in here
and then you see though the wool blocks
go down the
the grates there
wait why didn't this one drop down ah
anyway it's kind of broken there's a
also a manual just drop them all down
switch here
which is usually what i use uh this
works off of a
double bud switch actually or
used to it would detect when
the grass would gloat the grass would
grow to this block here
and then it would detect again when the
sheep would eat it so it would
check it twice oh make time song
see did we miss it oops
[Music]
i think we missed it darn it
uh but all the wool
from the sheep automatically goes into
this chest
and then when this fills up i'll like
pick it up and
drop it off in the right place
all right cool cool
um what else what else we got an ender
pearl dispensing station here
i go through ender pearls really quickly
like i'm always using them
oh i have some blocks missing
oops there's some storage up there for
them
they're supposed to be more blocks some
were getting stuck back there
like that okay um
this here is for my potion room my
original one
i started this world before enchanting
and uh
potions and that were a thing uh let's
let's
head on over here this is my
three by three spiral door
it's pretty cool it's on a timer it'll
automatically close on its own
um yeah in here
we got some a potion pixel art thing
which is cool we got
are these all empty now they probably
are
oh we got some here this is a storage
room for the potions though
and behind each of these chests it's
color coded you see we've got
purple there for regen orange for
fire resistance blue for speed potions
and they're split up too like that's the
positive ones
these are the negative ones over here
weakness slowness
etc etc um back in the day of course we
didn't have hoppers and
and all that stuff so i designed this in
such a way that
i would try to make it as easy as
possible to to brew the potions but it
wasn't fully automatic
and behind that gold door is a bunch of
dispensers
so i would stand here and from those
dispensers like if i need glass bottles
that's what the top button does
i haven't used this in so long
drop down 10 glass bottles or is it not
oh it's 30 right because we have 10
brewing stands
what's in these by the way and basically
i would fill them all up then we have
nether warts get 10 of those
and then whatever other ingredients i
need i just hit the button and you would
get 10
10 of them see
i think those are actually all full too
the dispensers up there almost
because uh that little storage room
isn't big enough to store all my stuff
oh maybe not oh yeah here it comes we
got 10 of those cool cool
um yep and this is also where
my little lab assistants helped me out
we used to have jeff in here now it says
tom
i don't really know what happened to
jeff i tried to kill him before but he
uh
disappeared and we haven't seen him
since
uh this is potion dispensing systems
which uh i haven't used in a long time
they're empty
oh there is still this here uh there's a
hidden
chest behind this lava and also a
crafting table
which i almost never use if we head back
up here though we can check out the
dispenser area
i got this rigged now on
to open the door you have to throw an
item on the ground
[Music]
and then the closet there's pressure
plates on this side these are all the
dispensers though
they're all labeled gas tears
glycerin melons obviously this is not
full of gasters i'm not that rich
i've never yet this is actually one of
my goals
is to get a stack of gas tears i've
never done that before in survival
minecraft
i've come close but i always
like i always am brewing regen potions
too so i
i don't know just hasn't happened now or
it hasn't happened yet
uh the wiring for all this is pretty
messy
as well there's another layer up here
too
can we not oh yeah i guess we get get to
it over here
this is for the bottles and i think
gunpowder
yeah uh-huh
anyway we gotta keep moving because this
is gonna be a long tour
if i uh waste too much time i'll show
you what's under here though
there's a minecart hopper minecart
that's what picks up the item through
the ground
and somehow it detects when there's an
item here and it's supposed to spit it
out but for some reason there's one in
there
huh wait a minute
anyway i'm sure it works properly
okay let's head on down over here uh
this is a mini
mushroom farm thing i i made when they
made the change where mushrooms wouldn't
spread infinitely anymore
this is just like a stupid little farm i
never even
really planned on using to get mushrooms
i just did it to do it
and uh we actually got over a stack from
it so woohoo
a stack of mushrooms in like two years
or whatever it's been
not too shabby i get a lot of people
asking me
why i don't mind the diamonds in my
walls
and i have no idea what you're talking
about so
please explain it in more detail or or
stop suggesting it i don't know
make more sense please i don't know what
you mean
uh this is my auto jukebox area
i used to have a bud switch that would
turn these lights on and off but
uh now it's a comparator thing instead
alright that's my favorite song too by
the way
in the game ward awesome song highly
recommend it
out over here is the enchanting room i
set up a long time ago this is back when
enchanting came out
i had an idea of making it a variable
enchanting station
this is like back when it took 50 levels
to
to do a max enchantment
that was a pain i like the 30 level
thing
now it just seems a little too easy to
me
since they made the the recent change
with the lapis i also added in
these droppers up here with tools
and yeah we got a path that goes over to
a loot room
which is a work in progress still i
haven't done much there actually
so work in progress but without much
progress being made
but i do plan on finishing it this is
for
future expansion out this way i have a
chicken farm
slash chicken game idea which i'm
hopefully gonna do sometime soon over
here
uh we have a vine wall
over here i did this so that we could
get or so that i could make
uh the mossy cobblestone
and the mossy brick yeah
when that change came out got some
hoppers down below it's very low tech
actually
nothing too fancy oh what did i just do
did i not put them away or did i have
two on me
all right so this river is just for
looks
this is melted ice blocks that's how it
it keeps the shape
so if this updates the whole river gets
messed up
um and since we're on a backup i might
just do it just to see it
i've never done that before oh man
oh what a mess i had to be really
careful when i made this like that the
grass
was all grown before i melted the ice
blocks otherwise
the grass drawing would cause it to
update and yeah
this is my watermelon and pumpkin farm
i made this back when you had to hoe
or you had to till the soil for it to
grow on it
which you don't have to do anymore and i
had a dispenser back here with a
with a hole in it that would shoot out
when you'd walk in
i've used this farm a lot
oh and it's full this is my spider farm
again i made this one enchanting came
out and it's like how do you get 50
levels
i don't know and i had the idea of using
cave spider spawners
there's one below here and there's
another one over there
um and that was a lot of fun
because i they would kill me a lot and
they would run around my cave and
torture me and uh eventually though i
came up with a way
of moving them upwards this is a as an
elevator for cave spiders which probably
doesn't work anymore
it like goes up this way
and then up to here and then they would
drop down and take
just enough damage to get them down to a
one-hit kill
these were timers i don't think they
work anymore
probably not um
all right what else what else this is
for the slime farm
slimes get separated by their sizes we
got the slime
slime evader over here to bring them up
um and then
i had a thing before which doesn't work
anymore whoa
you see the mine carts there though they
would pick up the big slimes
automatically and then it would uh
bring them to this tree farm area and
they would go around and around
the tree farm just for the fun of it
which i need to fix eventually
okay let's keep going here uh this
this is probably the most out of place
thing i've ever built in my world
it's made out of brick the only thing
made out of brick here
uh it's super ugly it's got
it's like the purpose of it is this
infinite water source and the crafting
table but like i'll just
if i need to craft something i'll just
walk right by this thing
totally oblivious that it even exists
so i guess that's kind of good even
though it's ugly i don't notice it
anymore
and i don't think about it until today
now i want to rip it out
uh cows fall down here from this
ufo thing this is the cow ufo
if we go up there's a bunch of fishing
rods up here
and the idea is you stand in the middle
oh there's a lot of cows down there all
the water is being held up by these
fence gates which was really tough to
get there because you can't
you have to place them on a block you
can't play some
free floating like that so yeah
and the idea is you fish them and they
fly up into the water stream and
it all end up in a one by one thing but
it needs some work it's not really
working at the moment
um project pokemon is over here the goal
was to get
one of each type of villager when i made
this i had no idea you couldn't get the
green ones
so that's what this spot's for um
and i can't use villagers i've bred so i
have to get original villagers that
spawned
at a villager to finish this off so we
still need the priest and the blacksmith
and we got some hidden storage
and then hidden drafting table there
this is emerald city which
never really became a thing
despite many people wanting me to to
work on it
but these are villager houses we got
four of them
identical i thought these were the
coolest looking thing
when i built them and so many people
so many people told me how wrong i was
especially the original design that had
sandstone in it
um but yeah we kind of have a
replacement for this village now
thankfully which i like a lot more
but i still keep it here as a as like a
reminder
oh yeah this is a villager holding room
for it
i could push them down from the surface
and they would fall in here
and then i could deal with them later
all right let's keep going got lots lots
to do lots to see
this is the cow slash wheat farm uh we
got a map of the world of the area
over there with a pretty high zoom rates
we've got some towel pixel arts
this is storage for the tree farm
looks like i've been using it for random
junk though oh there we go
there's some tree stuff here um
these trees are like uh
a way of thanking people that donated to
me in the past i don't accept
donations anymore but uh i wanted to
include it in my world anyway
uh we got like a fancy roof in here that
i was
i still need to finish up oh i've
i even forgot about this thing this is a
flower farm
yeah i totally forgot we did this oh man
i gotta finish this
whoa
okay that might be a little glitchy in
the snapshot
that looks so weird
and there's a hopper minecart that can
run around
below it and pick them all up
pretty cool um let's keep going let's
keep going
i have a dual cave spider spawner thing
out this way i guess we'll check it out
i don't use it anymore i never go over
here anymore
in fact i'm just gonna i'm just gonna
cut my way in since this is a backup
because i don't even remember how to get
down oh here we go
still works i i actually did try this
out the other day it still works they
still
bunch up in this area
oh what's this oh yeah i have to go
underneath to kill them
they take no damage beforehand so you
have to like fully kill them there
a little enchanting area
this is like old school like before i
was using diamond tools i made a bunch
of iron picks
got some wool here still pretty cool
okay i'll show you guys this too i don't
know if you've seen this before but
i don't throw anything away i have tons
of stuff
throughout my world this is one of my
stashes of like
blocks i have millions of um
that's what we need the big storage room
for in the future
um but why throw them away i might need
them in the future you never know
okay out over here this is just like
this is where jeff used to be i don't
know what happened to him though
we have a window to look into one of the
cave spider spawners here
kind of like a kind of a nice viewing
area
to the farm there's a way down
dispensers to hold like wheat and seeds
and different things there another layer
here
all the the wheat and the cow meat and
leather
uh can flow to this middle we have like
a water stream thing to harvest the
crops
i don't have any crops growing there
right now though
oh man that caused lag so many cows
all right let's get back up
the slime farm is right here it's just a
single
pad the slimes will jump off the sides
and then they get stuck in this
uh slime evader thing
okay now we're kind of back at the new
stuff here
um this guy will also shoot arrows out
of his eyes
every so often it's random we have a a
room back here it's probably empty
though because i haven't seen it happen
yeah in a long time
but randomly he'll shoot fire arrows out
of his eyes we also have a snowball
fountain thing here
which will randomly shoot snowballs up
in the air every so often
this is also one of my favorite projects
i've ever done this is wilson
he's like our tamagotchi guy in
minecraft this is a
this was a really fun redstone project
which is still not complete it is
working
but it needs some some changes to it
a lot of changes let's see let's
bring him back to life for a second
there's a lot of redstone back here
some pretty cool devices i came up with
too like there's a random
or there's a variable randomizer that
determines if the guy gets sick
and some other pretty cool analog stuff
his face like displays five or six
different emotions too is he dead
oh no he's sick so
let's see do we have any golden apples
here we got one
okay yeah so he can get sick
and that's his health over there his
weight
his happiness level his hunger level
when he's sick he his condition worsens
very quickly
but you can cure him with a golden apple
now he's happy again and
his age is at the top there it's a fun
little redstone
computer thing
which needs a lot of work this
is my what i call this
mini farm i think i have a tutorial on
this actually you can do
wheat seeds carrot seeds potato seeds
and cocoa beans here
here let's grab some seeds and basically
you stand here
you could probably make this a lot
better nowadays but
stand here and crop on automatically
grows and harvests
got dispensers with bone meal in pretty
cool i actually use that quite a bit
this is for a snow farm which i think is
broken currently
um that also connects to the snowball
fountain
let's see up here is a way to get past
the river as well
and to the loot room
and let's head back
um yeah new area here
well kind of this is my fishing shack
this is where
i when i want to relax and kick back
i come here and do a little bit of
fishing um
then i got some cave spider spawners
here and an auto pickup thing down there
to pick up the string which is pretty
cool
this is a new area this is or this is
going to lead to a new area i haven't
built this stuff yet
i got a redstone access room to the
snowball fountain
over here yeah so in the future i'll be
building more down here
but there's not much right now got a
waterfall
ender chest crafting table some slime
blocks
i've been talking a long time here this
is where i keep my horses
or one of the places pretty cool
and when i'm i'm done writing them just
bring them back automatically closes
um this is like another intersection
room there's an elevator here
that works with horses with the slime
block update though this doesn't work
anymore
these slime blocks will not move up uh
they're stuck to something so i'll have
to fix that
this is my musical mushroom farm
not much going on there i still need to
finish this
uh let's see did we miss anything
i think we're good still still okay
all right then this leads to ethos lab
this is one of my favorite
builds i've ever done this is a fully
automatic
potion room well you got to supply it
with water bottles but it's like as
automatic as it can get
pretty much got netherwart farm
over here is where you create awkward
potions
you basically have to flip the switch
and it does it
totally on its own you have to fill it
with water bottles though which you do
up here you grab
empty bottles from the chest and you you
feel it in the water
here and then there's storage for like
for days
we got like four four double chests plus
all these hoppers
oh and now we're stuck in the system
yep so this is one of my favorite builds
i've done because
for one thing it's incredibly useful we
have like
infinite potions thanks to this build
we just have to keep it stocked with
supplies and there's plenty of storage
to do that uh there's an insane amount
of redstone stuff going on
behind the scenes and you know what i
think it looks pretty
good too which is a nice bonus to it
up above there is also an automatic
uh rail line system to to move the
potions around
yeah down here um
oh yeah this actually what it does it
takes the awkward potions we brew
oh it is running and then it keeps
everything supplied with them
so you don't have to manually move them
around which is nice
that's the quick way down uh but yeah
bruise all the different types of
potions except i'd never put in
for water breathing but there's also
some
some manual brewing stands at the back
here which is cool
i just put this in actually finally
finished this door
so this is my classic
three by three with the hole in the
middle design that i do
this is an intersection uh one way here
goes to the mob system we're in the
middle of building currently
whoa
okay then that's working pretty good
i haven't checked that in a little while
and there's a lot of stuff there
uh this is to a skeleton spawner which
we need to finish
and i really liked how this room looks
too i think it turned out pretty good
uh then down the stairs at the end of
the hall here is our underground village
which sort of replaces that emerald city
and we got all these cool little houses
nice and bright and colorful
we got the villager chief at the very
end here which i need to finish as well
i think i did fix his eyes though
although he doesn't cry anymore
anyway up here is
let's see where do we gotta go there's a
zombie spawner up here which i sometimes
use to bring
villagers to the village if it ever gets
wiped out it's
kind of like an emergency villager
supply area and they spawn in these dark
rooms
or dark areas and if there's ever a
zombie villager i can i can fix them up
and then
move them out
okay just keep breathing just keep
breathing i'm almost done
it's like running a triple marathon man
i am i'm tired of talking already
uh i think we've pretty much covered the
man cave so let's head on out
i missed this the spiral elevator
takes you to the surface
oh it still works too good got like a
little bridge across the river in case
uh
oh or to make it easier to cross got the
snowflake up there i
have no plan for it uh i use that mostly
as like
uh what you call it but kind of like a
beacon to see
like if i ever get lost in my world that
helps me find my way back
a lot of the times because even if i go
to zero zero in my world i often
have no clue where i am um
this is our oh what am i doing that's
not how you get down
i still did it what the heck i hit both
lily pads
this is to our what did we call this
place
abandoned mine shaft or something yeah
ender pearl dispensers here uh again
tons of
storage this is another one of my places
um don't usually come down here anymore
used to be some speed potions in that
one
um minecart system this is
this is like a fancy strip mine
basically
uh for a time in the game
oops when they introduced the color wood
the different colors of wood you could
uh oops
well that doesn't work anymore i i use
this area
you would place a boat in this thing and
it would automatically get destroyed by
lava
and drop the sticks and the planks and
then i would store them here
this was to convert like colored wood
into regular oak
oak planks um
and then again all all the people that
donated to me in the past
did i just hear a piston what was that
anyway it's like tons and tons of mine
shafts down here
with a sign for everybody that donated
so that's pretty cool
um you may have saw i had some something
dug out at the start here
yeah over here you see how this is dug
out i'm planning on putting an eats road
from the the cave the man cave to go to
here
as like a second way in and out oh yeah
there's snowmen walking around up here
and they will randomly step on these
lights
and turn them on and off to mimic a
flickering light effect
like in a spooky poorly maintained
mine shaft sort of thing it was the idea
i probably can't get out of here oh i
did it
i think oh no
anyway i'm gonna cut here
okay so we're back just above the man
cave here
something i built recently was this
cactus farm this is to
mimic a cactus farm i built back a long
time ago in one of my alpha worlds
you saw those lights just turned off all
those lights on this path are automatic
they turn on and off they turn on at
night and off during the day
this is a path i made for horses to get
to
the library which i do use every now and
then actually
it doesn't go all the way there though
it's the problem
it ends right here but the top of this
mountain is the library
which started as an idea of like at the
end of
all my episodes i i do this thing where
i read comments people leave me
in the video um and then i answer them
in the next episode
and this library was made as a place to
store them but
i have made i've i've made little
progress on this place
since i started it um
but i come here every now and then when
i feel like doing some building because
that's
pretty much all it is nothing too fancy
redstone wise
but now i'm going to be using this also
to store enchanted books
there was a little game thing i was
working on down here that didn't really
work out
um more recently i started working on
this bridge
oh it's gonna hurt oh oh
oh we got a mule up here
i want no comments on the shape of the
gold farm right now i'm gonna
fix it don't think i don't notice it
i really regret adding this extra
tunnel area but i definitely need to fix
that
okay so up here is the gold farm
um this connects to the nether and like
a bunch of zombie pigmen
get teleported through into this portal
and they fall down here and then there's
like a crushing system
uh to kill them all their drops get
picked up by these hoppers
and then they come down here and they
get sorted automatically into
their different types zombie flash gold
nuggets
and gold ingots uh this is
very much a project that needs to be
finished
uh we're still working on it
you can barely see it but up there is a
spawning platform if i ever die in my
worlds
um i i'm supposed to spawn up there and
there's boats that you can ride down
like a parachute
which is pretty fun and
let's see what else what else
let's go towards the desert i suppose
trying to think if i built anything past
those mountains i don't think i have
these are for project pokemon this is
where the villagers get pushed down
i have some people ask me about that
every so often because they're pretty
random
and i never use them that's like one of
the first things i built in the world
and we got my ugly beacon set up there
which i need to either tear down or
change as well
um all right we got the desert over here
recently we started building this mob
system that needs to
be finished up and made look
made to look nicer on the outside got my
giant sugar chain farm here this was for
when villager trading just came out i
was pretty quick to
exploit it and trade tons of paper with
the villagers
but i never ended up using those uh
emeralds
for uh like buying diamond stuff or
anything i use them for building
this is a well with a button on
surprisingly not too many people have
ever commented about this
even though uh that when i uh
when i made this world these wells
weren't auto generating
like this is before these wells even
existed so
i'm a little surprised not too many
people ask about that to be honest
and how many wells do you know have live
in that's that's just crazy
um this is a river i kind of custom made
it's actually a pretty nice boat ride
which we probably don't have time to
check out
but uh yeah
got trees all along the coast oh man i'm
going to crash it
this also just runs right outside the
man cave
got a nice cool waterfall there that i
made
every now and then i like to just do
terraforming outside
as a nice change of pace
pretty cool and then it goes
this is a custom-made overhang i did
oops
man that chicken was he put up a fight
there he
totally knocked me out uh yeah that's
totally like there was no overhang there
before i built that
um let's see
i guess we'll head out this way i got a
few things built here nothing too fancy
hmm yeah there's not a lot to see out
here but uh
just for a frame of reference the
library is up on that mountain
over there then in this desert we have
my obsidian farm
with this self closing portal you go in
it and it closes behind you
and then when you come back through here
it'll create a new portal every time and
you can
mine it out for the obsidian which is
cool this is also where i showed that
speed mining technique
originally down there is my mine shaft
where i got a lot of my redstone
and then over here a lot of people told
me
they really liked this episode that i
did this and then a lot of people told
me they really hated that episode so
it's like
this was an idea some people really
liked and some didn't
but this was a project where i
think i started with like a stack of
tracks or something
and this was my attempt at realistic
mining like
i pretended like places that looked like
they could cave in i would put up a
support beam and
i tried to make it look really organic
like a like a mine shaft
and i put up like fenced areas if mobs
hostile mobs could spawn behind there as
a safety and
yeah lots of silly things and the goal
was kind of to see how far i could get
mining like this
by converting all the iron i find into
tracks and see how far they'll take me
and then basically if i ran out of iron
that would end my journey
because the mine shaft wasn't very
profitable
it goes outside this ravine though i
actually ended up getting pretty far
i came back here too after the episode
and ended a little more
do not enter got a big wall here too
to prevent you from falling down the
ravine there
but i think that was about it i don't
think there's anything up here
i think i ran out of iron
hey guy oh there's a
i didn't know this was here there's a
way across
aha anyway let's go check out something
else
oh yeah and by the way i'm sorry if it
seems like i'm rushing through this
i am kind of i was hoping to keep it
under an hour but it's not looking
too good uh so far but anyway let's keep
going we're back at the man cave
through the creeper face oh that
clicking is a snowball fountain
through the creeper face is a portal
let's go on
in this takes us to the nether hub
and just today actually i set this up
this is part of the portal network which
i might
i might explain in just a little bit
um yeah it seems to work okay though
down this way goes to a mesa biome and
and some other stuff mostly i use this
for resources nothing too fancy
uh we have
a couple portals that way i think again
for resources
and same with that way nothing really
built
up here this this is an elevator oops
at this level we reached the gold farm
this thing was i spent a lot of time on
this thing it
is pretty cool but i i spent a lot of
time on it
uh we got a giant cage to protect the
whole thing from gas
and i tried to add a like some
somewhat of a design to it so it wasn't
just solid iron bars or something
it took a ton of iron too but
got that done and then each of these
things
is like a spawning pad for the zombie
pigmen they fall down
or they get pushed down by pistons they
go into the portal and they end up at
the gold farm on the other side
causes a tremendous amount of lag you
should not build anything like this
in multiplayer servers but if we go up
further
see what's here is there anything here
no
just the portal to get down
uh this goes all the way up to the top
of the nether though
i hear a guest
i can feel the leg you get out here and
then this is a timer thing that lets you
uh you put you push this button here and
then you stand here and it will push you
down after a certain amount of time
that a good amount of zombie pigmen have
spawned and then you go
down and you go kill them
okay so we're back to the nether hub
here usually if i come to the nether
it's to go down this tunnel
this takes us to our stronghold base and
a few other things
by the way this was a minecarts
selector system destination selector
which i never really hooked up and
probably never will
and there's a there's an access room
back there for the wiring this tunnel
goes to the stronghold though let's go
check it out
um it's not too far usually i just run
it in fact
oh yeah right over here
and we got a few other things here too
so the portal network maybe i'll explain
that quickly
it's like a selector thing it disables
all the nether portals
i have except for one
um and uh
it's it's a complicated thing but
there's basically
wires running throughout my nether that
connect all the portals together
and like if i want to go to my zombie
purifier i need to select 11 delay on
this
so 10 11 hit the button
turns on that portal turns off all the
other ones
so that when i go
um like if i go into this one
hit this when i come out i'm gonna end
up at that one over there
because this one closes behind me and
it's like a way of getting around the
nether a little easier especially if i'm
moving mobs around
but uh this is my stronghold base
um this was supposed to be
like my main base but it never ended up
turning into that i
i treated this area more as like a
workshop almost
like i i would build things here and
then i would tear them down and i'd
build them and tear them down and
nothing was really too permanent
the only thing that really has survived
is
my silverfish farm idea
which probably doesn't work quite right
anymore
i have a silverfish spawner there you
can see the end portals
is kind of uh all around it too by the
way
here let's let's turn it on
so that makes it dark in there silver
fish spawn they end up in this water
stream
they get pushed towards a stone block
here and i had this idea
of making like a stone generator
and it will automatically push
a new stone block to that area then when
the silverfish enters it
a bud switch detects that and causes
the chain to push forward and a new
stone block gets created and then
this stuff gets piled into a giant
cube of silverfish blocks
and yeah it was a
it was more for the fun of it i was
going to try to take these guys and use
them for mining
that didn't really turn out too well
although i i still need more of them
but the silver fish i create will
does this work
oh yeah that drops them down the
silverfish will go into this portal and
get transported somewhere using the
portal network
um
yeah kind of a strange strange idea
honestly
oh we gotta go to the end yet too oh my
goodness
it's never gonna end this is another
giant
warehouse of blocks we got stored here
let's go on up snow farm thing
let's see let's see i guess let's go up
here
yeah this place is pretty messy still i
should really try to finish it
i think if i i was a better builder back
in the day i would have done something
amazing with this but i
i just struggled so much trying to come
up with a design
i never did come up with one
but yeah we got a hostile mob system
here
there's a sorting system up there the
idea was to make a bomb factory with
this thing
and a lot of that doesn't work currently
but
maybe in the future this is going to be
a storage room
but i most likely will tear this down in
the future and
come up with something better if we go
up out of here we can check out the mob
system
[Music]
really quickly
not my best throw don't judge me on that
one
man yeah we got a lot to check out
this is the giant mob system not very
efficient
but back in the day it was pretty good
easy to set up there's a light switch to
turn it on and off here
oh um
that's where the majority of my
gunpowders come from actually in the
world
let's see i guess we'll go this way
out over here is my ice tray let me just
skip this
yeah i almost have this in the middle of
nowhere but this is my ice tray
i had this idea to make an ice firm a
little while ago which is a
pretty well known concept nowadays
and in fact there's some pretty cool
designs out there nowadays but
this one it works pretty good too uh
basically you pull this lever
all the snow blocks fall down those are
just there to make the water freeze
quicker because
it freezes quicker if there's an
adjacent block next to the water
compared to this being all solid water
um
then it freezes you harvest it
you hit this button it spits out the
water and then pulls it back and it
creates like a giant pool and then it
freezes
and you've seen it before
it's it's not anything new nowadays
all right so at the mom system here
there is also a
building up there which i don't really
know where it came from
every time i go there nobody's home so i
don't know
i don't know what the story is there's
lots of weird noises in that house
though
um out this way is the zombie
purifier let's head on down
this is done except for the entrance it
still needs a proper entrance like right
outside here
but other than that this is all done
kind of cool little place this is all
just for a zombie spawner
in there and then you
let them run down you can in sort
between the villager zombies and the
regular ones
the regular ones go into a killings area
over there
the villager ones they end up in this uh
oh we got we got a guy here even awesome
um they'll wander around up there and
then they'll fall down
then you hit a button
villager medicine you hit that one uh
give them a golden apple and they get
cured and then you hit the transports
oh it works this thing actually has some
pretty fancy redstone it'll detect if
there's a villager
or a zombie villager waiting there and
if they're not it doesn't shoot the
weakness potion and
or the minecarts it's pretty fancy
i don't use it very often though
all right where are we
yeah so you see it took us to this
portal instead of this one
obviously on a short distance that
doesn't really mean much but
as the portals get a little further
apart uh it kind of
becomes a cool concept to have the
portal network
we'll go back into here though
we'll head on over to the end we got a
few things built there
i'm losing my voice i
seriously i'm so tired of talking
all right this is my end area
and pretty much the only thing i got
here is
two ender enderman farms
and this eats road
let's see dare i try ride it
i have the steve skin too by the way i
think the servers are down
i can't get my normal skin back
all right so let's try ride it i'm
scared
did i not place it there i don't know if
it'll let me place it there
this might need some work oops
i'm scared to ride this thing because
i've fallen through the ground before
but this is a backup so i don't really
care what happens
uh but yeah this takes us to the
original enderman farm the ender ender
which a lot of enderman farms were based
off of
um looks like a crazy
i tried to make it look like crazy
ufo-ish so we got
what is that yellow wool and orange wool
and tons of redstone torches up there
okay we survived good uh if we head on
down
oh my horse is here still too we've got
a little enchanting area
endermen fall down from the spawning
pads up there and then you look at them
and then you kill them over here and
then there's also an ender pearl
transport thing here that
takes them back to the main island
okay and the other thing i have at the
end is the ender ender 2.0
i think i made this during one of my
last specials actually
i don't remember which special it was
i remember frantically trying to finish
this thing and it was such a huge
project
and oh my goodness they are loud
uh but yeah this this is a much improved
version of the
enderman farm uh has better spawn rates
a lot more spawning spaces uh they are
grouped up
thanks to the vertical uh trick
that the zip crowd guys came up with and
uh this design is also where i
showed off the idea of using tnt
to kill them for for xp let's see
yeah is it loaded i never even checked
yeah i think it is stand there shoot a
flaming
arrow tnt falls down
kills all the endermen in one shot and
then all the xp flows to the middle
pretty cool unfortunately xp has become
almost pointless in the game so i don't
come here too often anymore except when
i need ender pearls
um but it's a pretty cool build i like
this thing a lot
so we've made our way back to the nether
now we're getting very close to
finishing up our tour i just have a
couple things left to show you uh
definitely
gotta show you the blaze farm the dual
blaze farm here
uh we also have a single blaze farm at
another fortress but
it's basically the same thing except
half as cool
but definitely got to show you this
build because for a long time this was
my favorite build in my world
i still really like it too of course but
i don't use it too much anymore
back when it took 50 levels to enchant
something this place
oh man this place was amazing
um does this work
oh it does work awesome on off switch
forwards
uh yeah but blaze they give you double
xp compared to most
mobs and then having a double spawner
side by side like this
uh it was pretty good just afk here and
tons of blades would
collect at the center point here came up
with this idea for a conveyor belt
thing at least i think i did
i'm not sure if this was my idea or if i
saw a video on it honestly
i know i saw a video someone was using a
fence gate thing to do a conveyor belt
but i don't know if i saw this diagonal
thing
um anyway
then i send all the mobs to this crusher
thing
open the gates oh yeah lava flows down
they swim
up and then it's set up so that when you
hit the crusher it cuts off the lava
in just the right way and it
where are they does this not work
anymore
oh i think they're getting stuck now oh
no
yeah i don't think they like swimming up
lava anymore
huh that must be new i'll have to look
into that later i guess
um this is also one of the first times i
used this
timing system this is like an extended
delay system
but it's uh it's double effective
i don't know how to explain it like uh
it makes a repeater last twice as long
like eight ticks instead of four
um the way it's set up so that was
pretty cool
of course now we have like hopper timers
and other timer things that are better
but yeah that kind of stinks they don't
swim up that anymore i'll have to fix
this
uh in the nether here there's a few
other things i have a
castle crashers tribute the frog thing
and also there's a wither skeleton farm
which is pretty cool too but there's not
really much to see there so it's not
really worth
going out that way uh we do have this
village to check out yet
this is a pretty cool little place
this is where all my original villagers
are stashed like before the
the recent villager change so they have
the old trades
whoa that guy's blind
yeah old school old school villagers
here
this is also the village i got the
villagers for project pokemon from the
three we have
back before villagers did anything like
before they you could trade with them or
anything that this is where they came
from
um all these farms are also set up to
work
this is a village i killed and then i
brought back to life basically
um and tried to restore it added all
these lamps in it
um but it's basically just
just a village like most villages
awesome so we made it to the end of the
tour everyone this is pretty much the
last thing to show you
the you've been ethod 3d pixel art thing
this is based off of a really sassy
animated gif somebody made me
i tried to convert it from a 2d image to
a 3d
thing and it's pretty cool i like this
thing
also over here is fireworks lake
which is something i like to do at the
end of my specials
so let's go over to the shore
um sorry if i
i glanced over things today a little bit
i was trying to hurry as quickly as i
could
may have missed covering a few things
like
jungle trees over there for example now
that i see them
but uh all in all i think we did pretty
good
and if you want to see things in more
detail you're free to go check out some
of my older episodes
um lately i've been trying to get a
little bit more professional with my
videos and my channel and all that um
so one thing i've done believe it or not
i have created playlists
one of the most requested features on my
channel
i finally created playlists for you guys
so if you want to check out some of my
older videos
should be a lot easier now just go under
under my channel click the playlist tab
and there's there's a bunch there
i still have a few more to add mostly
the ctm map stuff
but the majority of my series are there
so you can check them out
if you wish get get the inside details
of how things seem to be what they are
here
let's start up the fireworks i love the
fireworks i added a bunch more today too
so it should be a different show
although i don't really like the star
ones i gotta say
other than that they're pretty awesome
[Music]
woohoo yep so thank you again everyone
really appreciate it um
whoa oh this is such a dangerous spot
they want to see the fireworks too
though i can't blame them
maybe we'll turn it down a little bit so
i can still talk
um yeah so maybe just quickly before we
end it
i thought it might be a good idea to
talk about
how my channel is doing and uh
and that kind of stuff i usually don't
talk about that too much
um but this is probably the best
opportunity
to do that overall things are going
pretty good the views on the channel
on the videos is still excellent so
thank you for
for all the support on that the one big
problem
it oh we're out here
no
that wasn't the big problem by the way
that was just a minor convenience
inconvenience oh please tell me i can
get my stuff back
dang creeper i turned it down then i
couldn't hear him
sneaky guy oh no no no no i'm not ready
for you
or for you why does it have to be an
armored guy
i can actually hit these guys in single
player though
which is nice multiplayer not a chance
two in a row he's got my button
um yeah so one problem
we okay we're safe
uh i don't know what it is but for some
reason i get the impression
youtube isn't really promoting my videos
like they used to
um and because of that for about a year
now
the rate that i'm gaining subscribers
has been
falling pretty drastically
like a year ago i was gaining about 2
new subscribers per day and now it's
gotten to the point where it's like 800
per day so like a quarter of what it
used to be
um the strange thing about that though
is like the views and
that on the the channel are still pretty
good
and i think a lot of that is because
because of you guys being so awesome and
being loyal and
and regularly checking out my videos
because as a
as the subscriber growth decreases my
view should also decrease but that
hasn't happened
they've remained about the same likes
and comments and all that are about the
same
everything is the same except for the
subscriber girls so hopefully
in the future i'll find a way to deal
with that i'm
i've been trying things but nothing has
worked so far
um but it's really up to youtube i think
uh other than that though yeah things
are going good on the channel
i hopefully will continue to
provide you with contents that you enjoy
um i may start getting into more
video editing in the future too that's
kind of one of my future goals
but i do want to be careful i don't
overdo it
people have told me that they like the
cuts and the transitions and stuff i do
and i i feel like i might be able to do
a lot more with my videos if i
just get into a little bit of editing
like it
make things just a little bit fancier
could go a long ways
um but yeah we will see how things turn
out in the future
but for now thank you everyone hope you
enjoyed this episode
i'm very tired of talking i
i'm going to enjoy relaxing my voice um
and until the next episode thanks for
watching have yourselves a great day
oops i almost made a mistake
almost broke tradition i forgot about
the comment
uh i had it on me and then the creeper
blew me up and that was like the one
thing that didn't survive and i didn't
notice
and all right so here we go this is the
backup
i made before we started the episode
because i was planning on messing things
up in the world
says hey etho you were talking about
blood
sugar and i was curious do you have any
allergies
or disorders such as asthma spelt wrong
or are you diabetic
just curious so i
i feel i'm pretty lucky in this regard
as far as i know
i don't have any allergies or physical
disorders or anything like that
as far as mental disorders go
no i think i'm okay but i'm not going to
be the judge on that um
the one thing i do have that's a little
weird i
may be allergic to like soda
and i i mean pop of course
you say pop in canada i said soda
because most viewers are
american by the way um
not all pop mostly dark pop like
coke pepsi root beer there's
something in there that might cause no
that might cause me nosebleeds i'm not
sure
hasn't been as big of a problem as i've
gotten older though
but uh it seems to happen if i if i have
pop and i'm tired and i did a lot of
physical activity
the day before and it's hot outside
those are like the perfect storm for me
getting a nosebleed
and when i say nosebleed i don't mean
like
you know put a kleenex over your nose i
mean like faucet dripping
almost run out of blood nosebleed i
almost had to go to the hospital a few
times i've had such bad nose bleeds
because i was running low on blood
um but yeah it hasn't been a problem
in quite a few years now honestly uh
there was also concern i might be
allergic to like
bees uh in fact i even had an epipen
is that what they're called for a little
while because one time when i got stung
in the forehead i got stung like three
or four times by a wasp
and uh my face just
swelled up entirely to the point that my
eyes
like closed in on themselves and i
couldn't see
and i got this epipen but then the next
time i got stung
my parents weren't around so
i wasn't able to to inject myself with
it and then
the sting did like nothing it was like a
mosquito bite so i didn't have a
reaction
and i haven't worried about it since uh
but i did rub
aspirin on the stings the time it
swelled up so
maybe that's what did it i might be able
to aspirin
i don't know anyway
that is it for today guys for sure now
thank you for watching have yourselves a
great day
bye bye
you