hello everybody this is etho and we're
going to be playing some more minecraft
today I was trying to think of things we
could do for this episode and I came up
with like 20 different things so we
won't be able to do all of them but
we'll probably be doing a bunch of
random stuff first step I'll show you
the purifier I got more done on it it's
very very close to done this is it I got
this like walkway going over top lots of
stone bricks and stuff in here I liked
how it looks I've actually really
enjoyed working on this project just a
little fun fun side project and controls
up here this is where the zombies are
ending up at the moment I got a got to
change that around though maybe we'll
get it going yeah we got our Junction
these zombies will fall down this hole
and then they'll come up over here and
then we got a step a killing machine to
get their XP in their drops and stuff
which I haven't done yet but yeah that's
where we're at with this right now
there he is oh you actually did get me
you know when I tried it before they
weren't able to touch me when I want to
live that that's weird oh maybe alright
but you know it is I bet when there's
more in there somehow prevents them so
now I can go right up yeah I'll be
changing that around okay oh yeah and
this this is going to be for furnace
minecarts so when we get our converted
villagers onto the track we'll just pop
out a furnace minecarts and it will take
them to wherever we have our track setup
to go and that's about it for now
okay today we are going to visit the
place we haven't been to in a very very
long time but first you know what I
don't know if ever said this but I did
fix the read farm to the new pattern you
can kind of see it probably look at all
the mobs out here it's this insane I
just killed a ton of them too so yeah
look at the lily pads that's the pattern
I've got going on for now and I would
like to expand it some more even though
I don't really use it anymore because
the trading exploits was fixed I do like
the look of it though
anyway a lot of people have been
wondering why hat why I haven't been
working on the village that the Emerald
City village it's because just been
doing other stuff really
and also I only have like 32 emerald
blocks and it's called Emerald City
that's another reason and we kind of
we're stuck last time so I haven't been
too inspired to go back but we will get
back to it eventually don't worry but
yeah we're going to take a visit to the
mines today it's been a long long time
since I've been down here and those are
still going thick green lights totally
forgot about that those are empty nope
actually not I brought a minecart uh
yeah you know what we're going to do I'm
going to set up that whole donator thing
like we talked about and and dedicate
each one of these mine shafts to
somebody that has donated in the past
and I might keep track of how much
resources we get from them I'm not sure
but yeah I'm going to set that up and
also I want to put like doors in front
of each of these
so I brought a whole ton of wood with me
so we'll do something like this did a
few doors go in here you can see I
haven't finished over there but yeah
what I want to do is put a door on each
of these like this just for looks you
know we've gone we've gone this far with
this mineshaft we may as well add extra
decoration to it so yeah you me it'll
probably take me a long time to set this
up but I'm going to try to get
everybody's name on and we'll check it
out after that whoo and it did take a
long time but I got it done got 50 names
down I still have 104 I need to add
later but 50 will do for today so let's
go through these and yes a big THANK YOU
to everybody that's donated in past I I
do really appreciate it and it's it's
been very encouraging I'm sorry it took
me so long to get around to this project
I had I've had it planned for months and
I just never never got around to it
because it takes a long time to organize
all the info but I made a point of it
today so yeah you course when I started
my youtube channel I did it as a hobby
and unexpectedly people watch me and
kept getting more and more subs so I in
turn I started putting more and more
hours into it to try to make what I was
showing better for everybody but it got
to the point where I could no longer
justify the amount of time I was putting
into it and that's when I started up the
donation thing just to make me you know
feel better about the time I was putting
in that I was actually getting some sort
of financial reward out of it and it was
extremely encouraging it in fact I don't
think my channel would be where it was
today if it wasn't for for the donations
i've gotten so thank you everybody
it kept me going and kept me producing
episodes I do still view this as a hobby
though of course I enjoy it yeah but I
do I am a YouTube partner now so I get
money other ways back then I wasn't when
I first started so now it's at the point
I have a lot of viewers and I I do make
enough money I don't need donations
anymore and I I've totally removed all
the links I'm pretty sure from my videos
so no need to donate anymore just watch
episodes I hope you enjoy them of course
I really appreciate supportive feedback
and all that and again you can help me
out by telling your friends and whatnot
I try to get more attention to my
channels appreciated it don't do it in
spammy ways though of course okay that's
the 50 so got to add 100 for more
there's 50 more shafts back that way
which we might do next episode but yeah
thank you everybody
like I said I'm not accepting donations
anymore I would recommend like if you
want to donate to somebody in the
Minecraft community if you want to
support someone financially I strongly
recommend you supports mapmakers and
people programming like making mods and
that I feel really bad like you know the
guy that made mcedit and all that he
could no longer justify the time he was
spending on it and he he turned it over
to someone else which was kind of sad if
he like if I'm just using him as an
example if he he received more donations
I'm sure he would have continued it so
just keep stuff like that in mind it
takes a lot of time to program like more
than I think people realize and also I
do have a little experience with
programming just I'm just pointing that
out I know what I'm talking about
and also like map makers spend a ton of
time on making maps that also takes a
lot of time so incur
to encourage the people that you like
and and if you really insist on helping
me I guess you could donate to the
minecraft server but I think I think
dudes getting enough support with that
as it is but I don't know it's your
money do what you want with it
but thank you everybody that's that's
done this and we'll continue this I
think next episode I'm not going to keep
track of the the resources I've decide
it would be very tedious I think and not
really that much fun for me and also
some of these have liked Eve's right
outside the door which kind of messes
things up but anyway let's go do
something oh man I can't get out of here
I've died three times trying now it
doesn't work like it used to I don't
think or else I've gotten really bad at
the trick dang it and I have to walk all
the way every time
oh and I forgot my enderpearl what if I
get to jump through this thing I don't
think I Chen
speed boost oh haha
I've got to go and chance some feather
following boots this is just getting
ridiculous
I keep dying I'm so used to them okay
one more see it does that it's like I
instantly fall like did you see how fast
that was ah I'm gonna get out this time
oh that didn't work
ah okay I have to I have to the lily
pads yes freedom so one of the
fundamental differences with my inter
farm and some of the newer ones you see
these days group them together in mind
you actually have to look at them so
it's it's kind of scary now with the new
sounds
yeah definitely gonna be turning my
sound down here
that's creepy
give me the feather fallin that is not
the feather fallen let's go again that's
how you do it
perfect alrighty guys we have moved on
to the nether the nether fortress and
our next project is going to be to
remove some of this lands that we don't
want our zombie pigman spawning on
change directions like the wind so yeah
we're going to be doing some TNT
blasting around here
which is always fun of course the goal
is to get as much done as quickly as
possible
netherrack explodes very nicely I always
like to keep a fire resist on my bar in
case it runs out when I'm swimming in
lab or something get it drink it real
quick you know so yeah I guess let's
just go down here this is the first
section I want to take out how thick is
it it's not very thick hey we might not
have to even bury the TNT we just might
be able to get away with spreading it
well there was my framerate come on
there we go pull through he wants to set
it up for us
whoa this is a good bow by the way hey
ok so yeah i'm going to play some tnt
around here kind of randomly and then
we'll go through and just take out
anything that we missed
Boop
this might go off on its own I'm not
sure yet there it goes cool so oh is it
gonna get them ha ha ha
it's a pretty good chain chittering how
randomly I placed it that was a pretty
effective and I might go down deeper
I think the pillar and glitch is still
in the game actually oh yeah here's
something I found out playing nail case
you guys didn't know
does this double check this don't think
you can you jump in front don't think
you can set off TNT from the top with a
fire bo has to be mean side yeah that's
what it is all right we're gonna step
some more teen teen will make it go off
actually you know what to be thorough
let's see if it works from the bottom
okay it looks hey it looks like it does
Wow and that's a good signal that my
fire is history on out
I gave this more thought though I
shouldn't really be blasting this maybe
not this part anyway I should be putting
down half slabs because it'll probably
be quicker than dumping lava all over
here I think so I'm just gonna try level
it out yeah my main focus with blasting
is going to be the overhangs I guess
like stuff like this just one second
there's some Withers over there there's
a lot of them and that's it oh no no
there was one more uh yeah let's see
what's this look like almost got me this
yes is kind of like a overhang too so
I'm going to blast this out as well see
I'm going to try do the star method with
the TNT
see how effective it is don't hit me
that did I good I did bring this I just
want to see how big of a hole that'll
make woohoo
very nice so if I do a few of those
around here I will get it done in no
time hmm whoa leave me alone and try out
one of these nice 3x3 that's a lot of
deity um it's kind of like in the middle
of a nice Cove here alright let's see
what happens oh um a little bit wasteful
I think not too bad
whoa whoa watch your step man
all right here we go and don't know what
the fastest way of doing this is almost
anyone a half slab mole is a bit ouch
yeahit's is so thick like I have to do
so many layers to get to the very bottom
of the overhangs so I got a bit done
there today which is good I think next
time I head out to that fortress I'm
going to bring it like a tonic ah below
and just half slab up the place extend
the fortress more I want to put that
back and stuff like that
it's gonna take a long time to get that
how I want it um you know what I want to
do now as you guys know I've been
playing a lot of PvP games I did finally
get a carrot and a lot of times I play
with uh nose and in pretty much all PvP
games there's a little spawning area
where people derp around a lot and one
of the things I'm most likes to do is
bring out the pigs with the saddles and
the the carrot sticks and have everybody
ride around with speed potions and stuff
it's you get going really fast the thing
is we spawn areas the spawn areas are
always enclosed and I want to see what
it's like in an open world so I'm going
to make some carrots on a stick here I
got to farm some carrots first and then
we will go right a pig I'm kind of
curious about something with the carrots
like when you grow them it takes one
carrot as the seed and when you harvest
it you either get one let's see what you
get
that was too
- right I was at three it's so hard to
tell because stuff stack snap she look
at my bar better okay I'm at four eight
not eight four we got four that time
that's quite a bit reaiiy think yep
three again I'm just wondering how it
compares with wheat mostly okay so
here's another interest interesting
thing like when you use fortune on wheat
when you're harvesting wheat it does
work it gives you more seed so it
doesn't give you more wheat I'm
wondering if there that's different with
carrots it looks like it is okay we got
for that time which it is an axe I think
it could have been a coincidence 16 to
24 again
that was five so yeah if you're using
fortune on this stuff it definitely gets
you better results and then using it on
wheat and interesting so I compared to
wheats I looked on the wiki the total
food value for wheat is 11 points and
the total food value for carrots is 8
point 8 and it takes 3 wheat to make it
wait what'd I say total food value for
bread is 11 points I think I said wheat
total food value for carrots is 8 point
8 so it takes 3 weeks to make bread so
you got to factor that in that's really
interesting but I think baked potatoes
are really good because they div I think
I can't remember what it was but they
give more food than wheat then bread
they did more food value than bread and
I'm sure you could use fortune on them
as well anyway well I finally found a
piggy I don't have that many animals in
my world really like the grassland is
just barren they've all wandered off for
died no new ones are spawning because we
got sheep there
you guys follow get a default carrots oh
there's another one
just this is what you used to bring them
yeah it is ok oh don't don't step there
piggy alright so to make one of these
things you just do it carrots on a
fishing rod do they follow this - yep ok
get a saddle just going to try to try
ride them first just the normal way so
you can direct which way they're going
with the
so see how how long is Excel time is
you're not really moving that quick wait
wait I think he's picking up speed
maybe maybe not
okay so I'm going to try right-click get
a speed boost oh yeah you see how much
durability that used up go piggy yeah
he's moving quicker definitely moving
quicker wonder how long he runs for
after you do that what happens if we do
it again oh we can
I won't let us actually you know what
we're going to do we're going to make
him go towards our beacon I think you
slowed down again there we go
they can go towards our beacon you did
it you did get going pretty good one if
you do a speed boost
oh how thanks let me use it oh okay
Oh make a new one it's too broken to use
it again I guess there we go yeah you
can only do one speed boost at a time it
seems to last for like fifteen seconds
or so alright I think we're in are we in
the speed boost area I wonder if he'll
be affected by the beach and even
actually might only be me should be
speed boost area yeah I'm speed boosted
the terrain is so rough though it's hard
to tell oh they fall in the water you
lose all control I think
ya know particle effects over the PE a
lot today we're going to give him a
speed one he's got the particle effects
now we're going to see if they stack
together the carrot on the stick boosts
plus is speed boost should get moving
pretty quick if it does yeah we're going
pretty good here holy I think it does
stack really hard to control though like
if you got any obstacles in your way
especially water all right here he goes
here he goes ah oh he doesn't like the
lily pads that's for sure 19 you fix
these by oh good he can't otherwise
you're gonna have all these broken ones
left over that you can't speed boost
with
but anyway this has been fun let's do
the comment reading thing and we'll call
it an episode hey guys this is a comment
I picked out for today
hey etho I was wondering if you could
show us your other worlds on your
minecraft accounts they must be pretty
interesting considering you probably
went by your own judgement rather than
ours because you don't do LPS on those
worlds alright well I hope you see this
and have a great day thank you very much
there aren't really any worlds I pretty
much only play on my let's play world
here I play on minecraft and i play CTM
maps and that like right now I'm doing
uncharted territories - I just started
that and then I have some creative
worlds which are really disorganized and
messy oh yeah and also I have three
older let's play worlds like three major
ones before this one two of those I did
before I start doing episodes back in
alpha days I've been tempted to look at
those again since it's been so long oh
man a leg oh it's bad it's like I'm
ripping through time as I run but yeah
maybe I'll comment on the J probably
went by your own judgement rather than
ours thing I pretty much do go by my own
my own judgment sometimes I asked for
what let other people's views on what
I'm building but I do always make the
final decision I make sure I'm happy
with it
I don't do something just because people
tell me that's what I should do and also
like what projects I choose to do and
and like sort of design I do that 100%
my own so I do feel like this is my
world I'm doing it the way I want it and
I'm happy with it
alright guys have a good day
you