hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
to another episode tell you what I get
10 cool points if I can walk through
this deal alright we got a deal
come on I didn't do it it's good time
just right and okay next time this cart
goes oh I made it
this is not to be trifled with this is a
very delicate operation don't you just
love that pattern that's amazing I think
it'll blow up if I change just one of
these fences think let's change let's
change this one
maybe not give it time give it time
let's try change this one nope
oh oh and it's got whoo
alright so a new snapshot has come out
I'm rockin the oh nine a snapshot now
it's mostly a bug fix one but there was
some improved support for entities
working together like if you're on a
minecart and you leave the game and come
back you're still in the minecart
instead of out of it now that kind of
thing and one of the bug fixes that has
a big effect on me is they fixed it so
that hopper is always update comparators
now it I believe when an item passes
through so that was the problem we were
having last episode and we can try this
out before it was like kind of hit and
miss where it would detect the item here
now it seems to work every single time
which is awesome you see the junction
switching haven't had a fail once yet I
did have a little bit of trouble though
I don't know if it was due to the
snapshots or if I just didn't notice it
before but this cart was picking up more
than one item sometime and I fixed that
by just adding an extra delay on this
repeater before I had it one if I switch
it to if I have it at two it doesn't
seem to have that problem but if we have
it at one like is now if we do this
enough times I'm sure we'll see it fail
or not come on
fail there we go yeah so the time before
I picked up two items so this was at 17
and when we threw one in now it brought
it back up to 18 this first number
alright but as it is now we're still
having one problem with it that I
haven't quite figured out a solution to
when the hopper minecart passes by it
sometimes
doesn't drop off the item still even
I've even slowed it down quite a bit
here more than I would like and it still
has issues like the junction didn't
switch that time because the item didn't
go to the hopper down here most of the
time though like it's much better than
it was last episode most the time it
does work try it one more time have face
that it will work this time Ariel yeah
I'm finding most of time orcs now I'll
probably just have to slow it down a
little bit more and all should be good
uh-huh
but other than that new in the snapshot
they also added one more option with
smooth lighting when you have the choice
of off minimum and maximum before it was
this on and off now I don't really know
what the difference is between minimum
and maximum though it looks pretty much
the same to me maybe if I go in a cave
we'll see it better
okay next mom I can't tell the
difference minimum they probably just
smooths it out a little bit more yeah
a lot of mobs here let's just check this
out okay yeah there's a lot oh man
that's how you enter a cave oh man
skeleton skeleton must not be able to
get here sounds like oh there's a room
there too I see I would love to find
like some more spawners around this area
because this is near my my man cave and
there's there's a few kids I haven't
explored here it seems that team dead
ended pretty quick I'm afraid I only
used like 15 torches to light it all up
so not much there but I got this thing
here to show you guys I thought this was
pretty cool and I'm gonna give you like
a water challenge or a water puzzle here
can you figure out how I did this I'm
not gonna give you the answer try it out
your cells and see if you can replicate
it because this is this is pretty cool
alright have fun with that okay
everybody I got another thing I want to
show you here this is just a really
simple redstone trick you might find
useful
with these new comparators there's a
common problem I see people trying to
work out and like we have these
different length redstone signals now
that come up often and you might want
something to happen if the signal gets
let's say three blocks down down the
line here but if it goes beyond that
you don't want that thing to happen
right so if you just use a repeater or
or branch the signal off from there
you can see it's four blocks down it's
past where we want to do the check and
this is still powered so we don't want
that we want that to be off so I've seen
people use like locking repeaters in and
things like that to to do it but a
really simple thing I found is you get a
redstone torch first then the repeater
and another torch they're connected the
wire together and that's it so let's
just put out an old block here so we can
get a better idea what's going on so now
that went down it goes two blocks three
blocks and that's when we want it to
activate right but then we don't want to
activate at four blocks so let's we're
down to two let's go to four and that
will happen when we flip this up that's
three before all right so it's it's gone
beyond there and this repeater just
basically cancels the signal out because
they have the same tick and it keeps
this powered so we can do a range check
basically with this like even if like if
we want something happen from 3 2 3 4 5
6 we can do it this way to you and yeah
just just a simple thing so if you want
to stuff to happen in a certain range
that's how you can do it and here's just
an example of when that might come up
like jukeboxes you put a comparator next
to them different records will send out
different lengths of a signal now so the
gold record for example
it only goes one block while what's this
one
mellow hi we'll go all the way up to
here and I got these checkers set up
watch what happens when you put
different records in this so you can use
these records as a key system basically
gold record only this one came on that
torch is still off put another one only
that torch team on this one never
flickered or anything okay maybe let's
work on Wilson for a few minutes this
episode too because poor guy he's so sad
look at that
he's been neglected lately I hate to say
it's one one big problem I'm having now
is my redstone supply it has run dry
once again very very close to being all
outs I'll have to go taming some more I
was looking at the pet project plan and
I think we'll focus on hunger right now
pet needs to be fed frequently hunger
dreams at a constant rate hunger can be
replenished with various meals and
snacks so it's thinking about it this is
actually gonna be pretty complicated so
we're going to simplify it as much as we
can we're only gonna have one type of
meal and one type of snack and also when
we feed them we can give a medicine if
you get sick so that's a third item I
will I think the best thing to use for
that is gonna be golden apples I would
like to give them potions to make them
better but there's no real way of
detecting them there is but it's it's
kind of complicated and then finally a
fourth effect is if we give him
something he can't digest like if we
give him a piece of cobble it's gonna go
into a storage chest at the very end of
a line and have some minor negative
effect on him
this is
let's dig this out a little bit how
close are we to the southern wiring and
space is gonna be an issue okay now I
think the easiest way to do it would be
just to have a water stream here we
throw stuff instead of throwing it into
a hopper so we might do that water
stream and then it's gonna run over top
of hoppers
so there'll probably be one here the
issue is we have to detect when an item
enters into it and that's that's a
little tough we got to basically do what
we did at that minecart Junction we're
working at where we set up a storage
minecart underneath each of these
hoppers that we set up let's make it go
this way we'll have a power rail and a
storage minecarts okay and it's just
going to bounce back and forth so we'll
have that there out there we'll need a
solid block here okay this will be
powered this rail just put that there so
when something enters into this we
needed to make this cart move and then I
guess this carts gonna have to well no
it doesn't have to drop stuff off does
it no just needs to hold it but then we
got to set up like four of these hoppers
I'll just I'll just try wrap my head
around this for a second this is gonna
be tough and I tell you one thing about
like all these new redstone gadgets we
have it's
it's so much tougher to manage your
inventory because there's there's this
so many new items like you got
comparators you got there's a new type
of rail there's these hoppers there's
droppers there's like now if you do
redstone stuff a lot of times you need
minecart stuff you need to bring with
you so you better have a storage room
nearby otherwise it's going to be a pain
to get anything done you'll have to go
back and forth so many times this might
actually not be too bad to do one thing
I forgot about those will be doing stuff
with these ports as well so we want to
try build away from these as much as we
can so we're gonna go this way towards
Wilson's face here and hopefully not run
into anything and as far as how to wire
this we will it won't be super
complicated I think we just need like a
comparator on this side it infringes on
this one a little bit I hope like I
don't know what I'm putting here yet is
the problem okay we will just get rid of
this for now we're gonna do it so if the
signal goes to blocks then oops then
it's gonna tell this minecart to come
pick up whatever is in the hopper and
it's gonna pick up one item so run this
down like this and a repeater carry the
signal further and that is going to
power this track which will make the
minecart move do this and that I think
that'll work
and then we just need to power this okay
that's everything right let's try it out
a little put cobblestone in here so it
should be fine up to 22 items signal
only goes one block and then if we put
one more in excellent but it picked up
two items that's the problem
now we'll have to we'll have to change
this just a little bit so it doesn't do
that oops although this looks like the
same setup I had before I guess maybe
just I did raise the track on the other
one like I made it come up like that
maybe that's that's the difference and I
kind of need this to be just two blocks
wide so we can tile four of these
together I saw we got a big slime coming
here I'm just curious like this is still
working he comes and be a sucker
hahaha as a lot of well what's making
all the particle effects I was weird I
think I'm gonna have to downgrade my
snapshot this one's not running so good
only getting 24 frames at the moment and
I did switch to minimal or minimum
smooth lighting some people are telling
me it's the same as like what was it the
o4a works good for me but like beyond
that the frame rates pretty crummy and I
I heard that minimum is the same as the
404 a but I don't think it is
I don't think it runs as well but yeah
this is it we got it this is all of this
here is just to detect what food we'd
give Wilson it doesn't actually do
anything yet we have to connect wires
from each of these now
and connect them to the different
variables to cause whatever we want to
happen and that's where things get more
tricky so this I'm scared to make it any
more complicated than this because this
is just gonna be a huge amount wiring
from this from these like three or four
different options alone but what we're
gonna do I think is is a main meal or
food of choice is gonna be steak so we
can get that ready for steak okay so if
we throw in one more if we feed them
there we go
so should always just pick up one pretty
sure yeah well I just even if it does
pick up two it doesn't matter
oh no yeah it doesn't matter nevermind
damn it
I had to like alternate these a little
bit they're not exact copies of each
other just because the way the wiring
worked out but you can see the wire
travels two blocks then it gets to a
repeater set at two and then it goes to
the power rail if I if I did that in
between two of these power rails one one
wire would activate both of them so I
kind of had to separate them so like
this wire for example it doesn't power
this one at all it goes up here and then
powers it that way this one powers its
to the right here from that block and so
on and so forth so what we're gonna do
cookies
I'm gonna make this snack of choice
could you seem like a good snack for
Wilson so how do you do it yeah oh and
they're cheap look at that
so these will recover is how here are
little bits they'll add quite a bit to
weights and then also add to happiness a
bit as well
okay so we'll give them cookies verses
second one here and again if this gets
beyond 22 my hair will come and pick it
up and then like all the stuff I feed
them will get stored in these chests and
it'll be cool like if he dies if our pet
dies we can come here afterwards and
just see how much we fed him over time
and kind of be like a stat report
afterwards said this one oh yeah this
one's for medicine if you get sick we
got to give them medicine and golden
apples are what I chose for that and I
made a bunch of them here medicine there
you go and finally this is like our junk
one like if we feed him anything that he
can't process oh why did it do that it
went on just one item
that was weird
did I put the full stack in maybe I did
that now I did yeah we'll just put a
stack of stuff there so if a junk item
goes into this one
like for example rotten flesh that
should always get pulled out of the
first slot these ones will never get
picked up and then there's there's
plenty of space in there for different
unique items so that'll be fine and then
what we're gonna do is we'll just run a
water stream above each of these hoppers
like so and be very careful not to let
the water pour into this wiring because
there's a lot here all right and that's
about it for the the food detection
system it's quite a bit to it actually
this is uh this is very simple part of
all this and it's it's pretty intricate
I'm a little worried doing the stuff
like before the redstone update finishes
because if just one one little thing
changes I might have to redo all this so
hopefully things are stable now okay and
that's about it
let's put water in a hopper might be
nicer but it does make it more
complicated area and I would like no box
to play like for each like a different
tune for each different food we give
them it's actually a good thing I didn't
put the hopper right there at this first
block because maybe I would be able to
throw it past it I don't think I can
with it at the second block which is
good and maybe we'll still be able to
use a slot somehow the wiring is like
right there though hopefully it's not a
problem
well I think that's about gonna do it
for today guys I hope you enjoyed
today's episode as always before we go
though there is two comments to read and
also I want to show you this location
this is where I've been thinking of
putting the library this area here it's
close to the man cave that's the beacon
for the man cave right there so it's
it's really not that far away and we got
this awesome mountain area here and
actually this spawner this one here this
is the one we found in the very first
episode in this world it took me a long
time to find this again but it's it's
like right here but you got kind of what
is this have I I was this one these
water pools but yeah we got like a nice
overhang there we could maybe build on
or let's just go up here we don't need
anything huge for the library although
there's no reason we can't build
anything huge either like this is a nice
flat spot if we want to build something
pretty big good view of the area up here
more arches there I got to say like my
world here I think the generation turned
out really nice like that was one thing
I was really worried about when I first
generated this world that'd be all
flattened plane but I got some really
cool mountains this is actually really
close to cloud level 2 that's it's not
something you get to up oh actually
library on that floating thing I think I
might have pointed this out before but I
love this floating island come on yeah
this could be a cool spot fairly big
fairly spacious again a good view it's
not that far away let's go down see what
it looks like from below that is pretty
cool
all right anyway here are the comments
for today east though the leg from your
HD high-definition videos is making the
videos buffer like crazy I love your
videos but I can't stand buffering can
you stop doing HD ah you know what guys
I'll be honest with you one of the big
reasons I wanted to do two HD just
because I thought it's gonna put it into
the wino HD comments you know because I
was getting tons of those and they're
really annoying to see all the time
because I've explained many times why I
didn't do HD now I'm doing HD and
everyone's like oh my god it's an HD you
know or I I can't stand the buffering
you know I get these new annoying
comments not that not that yeah it's
only this guy a lot of people are doing
it and I guess I'll just have to live
live with it but seriously guys I can't
be the only guy that's ever done HD on
youtube like to stop buffering you just
lower the quality it's not complicated
to come on give me a break
alright sorry for ripping into that so
bad anyway next comment a eso if you
want a hopper to collect items but also
hold its inventory if supplied with a
redstone signal place the hopper so
that's out put faces sideways and then
place a hopper underneath the first if
you apply redstone signal to the
underneath hopper the above hopper will
collect items but hold its inventory if
if it's if it there is no power if there
is no power the above hopper will output
items to the underneath hopper that's
actually a really good suggestion so
like today with those mine carts that's
basically what I was doing or trying to
do but you can also do that with hoppers
alone without eating a minecart and
that's what he's telling me here you do
it like like this have it sideways so
it's not pointing into the hopper and
then if you power this bottom one like
so and then you put an item on top
it can still go into that hopper but it
won't go it won't pass through the
system this one holds it until you let
it through so that's that's definitely
another good way of doing it and it's a
good thing to keep in mind if if you
need that need to figure out that
situation that the minecarts do work for
good for what I'm doing because I need
the inventory space but for other things
the hopper method might be better but
yeah that's all for today guys have a
good day