[Music]
hello
everybody how's it going uh we are
just over here i wanted to show you
something before i covered it up
i've been tearing out the floor and
what i'm doing i'm basically making a
lining for this ice
in case it ever melts or i'm digging
underneath which i
probably will be because there's kind of
a basement below here
if if i'm doing that i don't want to
accidentally hit an ice block and
have water spill everywhere so i'm just
putting the stone brick lining
all around everywhere i'm putting ice
above
as a protection then above the ice i'm
going to do the half slab
thing and yeah
just want to show you before i cover it
up in case you ever wonder in the future
what's
underneath the ground
check it out man i got myself an indoor
skating rink now it's great
this stuff is the best i play hockey on
it
and especially like check this out this
is normal sprint jumping
notice how much this helps like you move
quick you get around real fast with this
stuff
so that's that's going to be real handy
because i
i'll probably be around this area a lot
once this is all built
and all getting around quick is always
helpful
um now you might have saw
i'm thinking of instead of using this
light
birchwood plank stuff i'm going to use
just the regular
oak this stuff here i
it's still like it's still noticeable
it's it's lighter than this so
it stands out but it's not quite so
shocking as this stuff so
i think it's a better choice so i'll
replace that i'm gonna put down oak
slabs all over this ice so i don't have
to
worry so much about it melting when i
place down torches
if it's covered up this looks really
weird you got like
lava dripping down on the ice
[Music]
and it doesn't melt
no nor does it make sense it should but
you know
just weird to see anyway
i'm gonna do that and i'll get back to
you
okay i got that done and it's it's okay
it looks a little plain as it is right
now though so i'll have to add in some
patterns and
give it some more character in the
future but just for now
it'll do i got these switched it's also
pretty dark so i'm going to add more
lighting
over here and we might have to find ways
to add it into the walkway i still don't
know how wide this is going to be
before we get to our chests on the
outside so
i'm in the middle of organizing stuff
in a in a word document and once i get
that figured out
i can figure out how big of a room this
is actually going to be
and other dimensions i'm also
going to maybe put some lamps up here
too so we can get rid of these torches
and we'll see how that looks but i still
have this ice effect i still move quick
hopefully that doesn't get patched it's
a good feature to have in the game
for for several things not just
what i'm doing here so hopefully they
don't fix it
yeah i got those installed and they make
a big difference
extra lighting it's a lot brighter in
here now uh
so i put one there and i put one there
and i also realized uh one of these
circle things or quarter circles was not
right so i fixed it
somebody reminded me twice about that
they told me it's gonna change it then i
forgot then i
saw another comment from them i changed
it but i
guess there was another one that was
wrong or something i don't know
they're fixed now i think they're all
all right now
so up here i did the lamps like this
so i could put them here because this is
you can't see them through through the
logs
and they're hidden under the leaves so
they're not
super noticeable makes it really bright
up here there's no
no torches now
i'm gonna have to wire these up someday
someday soon uh but
uh i had an idea today maybe
maybe we'll go talk about that for a bit
so we're gonna head over to
other base i'm gonna try make one of
those
book and quill things or whatever
they're called and test that out
and i have an idea i want to talk to you
about
oh man i had to like go on this big
journey just to get what i needed for
these things i had
no feathers i had one egg
didn't get a chicken from it and i have
two chickens
by the cow farm there which i didn't
want to kill
so i had to go hunt for chicken but of
course there's none in my area here
because i guess they just disappear a
few
are in an area for a long time i don't
know they they're probably down in a
hole somewhere i can't find them
so i went out with my looting sword way
out
and got 24 feathers
so and on the way i also was hunting
um squid got a bunch of those
okay so we got this uh do we
okay right click
aha hello
world
if you hit enter it goes to next line
i can't remember i think it's like 50
pages or something crazy
could be wrong oh i see there's a
that's cool these things are going to be
really useful i'm glad they added this
for maps and s p they
could be pretty handy too
did i say maps i meant custom maps just
to just to clarify
so i think when you're done you just hit
sign
and i think you can copy paste
i'm gonna i'm gonna do it i'm scared to
see what i last copied
oh okay
uh that has to do with my idea i'll talk
about that in just a second
okay so do we have special characters i
thought we did i was hoping there would
be like a menu
to select them but maybe
maybe you got to use the keyboard
enter book title oh cool
test by ethel has my name
sign and close cool now if i
i just say right click on it yep and now
you can't edit it
that is really cool um
yes so our the idea um
i'm gonna set that up and i'll i'll
talk to you about it okay i got it all
ready in this chest here
but before i show you it uh i just want
to talk about the idea for
a little bit here it's actually
something i've been wanting to do for a
long time
but i knew it wouldn't be possible with
just using signs it would have been too
big of a hassle
uh but now we have these books and
they're awesome you can put a lot of
text on them
it's easy you can even copy and paste
which
is perfect for what i want to do here um
right so this idea i'm not set on it yet
like it's something i would like to do
but
i'm depending on your feedback here if
you guys think it's a good idea we'll do
it if not
we'll scrap it type thing but the plan
is to
have a structured segment
in every episode i do starting today
uh probably gonna keep it around one
minute
i don't want it to drag on too long
where i address some comments i get in
the previous episode
so sometimes i get comments
like people asking questions or giving
me advice
or you know saying something that makes
me feel good like gives
encourages me or something that
has a has a positive effect on me or
you know even people telling jokes or
whatever in the comments
um sometimes i i want to address these
where other people can hear what i have
to say
and if i reply to them in the comments
they usually get
buried so nobody sees it
and also it's not really personal
because it's text
so the idea is to pick out
a few comments not too many i got five
ready in here
five comments one two three four five
from the previous episode
um basically i would read these and then
reply to them in the episode
but try to keep it under a minute and
some episodes i may have more comments
some i may have less i don't know
but roughly one minute um
so just go over we'll go
through this this is our our test
segment
tell me if you liked it or not if you
want me to do it we will if you don't
we won't okay so comment number one
etho i don't want to spoil the party but
i don't know what that means a f a i k i
know it's like one of those internet
where they jumble words into a couple
letters
i think it means like if i recall or
something
anyway but if i recall that's what i'm
going to assume it means
the doors in your village need to be
exposed to sunlight in order to count as
valid doors
for villager breeding which i assume you
want to do
to get the other types of villagers
please
just check the wiki before you continue
with the village i'd hate to see you
spend hours on making a village and then
have it not work
as you intended if you already knew this
then never mind
but i'm a bit worried there a bit
worried here
please thumbs up so ethel can see
cybernetic soldier
so cybernetic soldier posted that
comment last episode
um now to address it i
i do know this somebody posted on the
minecraft reddit
a few weeks ago how this all works about
needing sunlight and it checks five
blocks in front of the door and five
blocks behind
and determines if it's the house that
way so
when i do this project i will have
uh sunlight down in the cave
next one etho put snow blocks under the
ice tray
that way you won't break the floor when
you harvest the ice
robot kid thank you for the tip
um yeah when i built that i wasn't
really planning on using it much maybe
just like once in a while but it turns
out i'm using it a lot now so i probably
will do that
and snow has a nicer benefit where
like efficiency enchantments don't break
the snow quicker so
that is why you want to use snow so i'll
do that
hey etho new subscriber here don't you
upload
720p videos alex um
i do for tutorials pretty much always
but for everything else i don't i've
tried in the past i've had problems it
takes too long i only have 0.5
like upload speed which oh it's just
terrible
so no plans on that until i get faster
internet
except for tutorials or anything else
fancy
etho you should bring back the suicide
booth from the old lp world this is
actually taking a lot longer than a
minute i'll have to
either pick shorter shorter comments or
fewer of them uh bring back the suicide
booth from the old lp world because now
that we have entered chess
you can access your items from where you
spawn
and if you do it you could make it more
sophisticated
with the multiple choice type thing for
how you die
for example if you press one button and
walk into the suicide booth you get
crushed or if you press a different
button
you get killed by lava and that would
make the suicide booth more like
futurama which is what inspired you
the first time the only lone wolf 95.
i missed the suicide booth uh i would do
it here but
really the nether portals are quick they
takes me like a minute to go from base
to base now which is
nothing to complain about if i was to
ever build something far far away
then we might bring that back
hey etho i found out there is more
a more efficient way to place water for
your sugarcane
farm you have to place one one water
block then you go up two blocks and one
left
there you place the next block and
another block
you place up and two right from the
first one
fourth you place basically he's telling
me
um there's a better way of placing the
sugar cane in the water at first i
thought it was the same thing as i did
but
i plotted it down on paper and is better
so thank you for that suggestion and
i may try to modify what i got already
to be that pattern
or i'll
anything future i put in i'll
use use this pattern here so thank you
for that and thank you for your comments
everybody
so that's an idea of how it would work
although i
gotta shorten it that was too long and
then the idea is
after i read the comments i would put
them in a chest
i was planning to build like a library
or something to hold the chests
and each chest would have an episode
number for it
put them in and they would that would
serve like is the archive for the book
so i don't throw them away
keep them there and build like a library
or some kind of building to hold
the chest which could be a fun project
too so
let me know what you think of the idea
and uh
but it'll be about a minute i don't know
how i would do it either it would either
be randomly in the middle of an episode
or
at the very end of an episode which do
you think would be
better
all right moving on uh the other day i
went through the sheep farm and did some
more fine tuning i'll just show you that
real quick
before the walls were all flat now i
have these little indents
on both sides which are kind of cool it
gives it more character
and also the ceiling was completely flat
before
now we have these half slabs half slab
beams
every every so often to give it
more more shape i guess
uh there's also some dead sheep which
have been replaced and
also the sheep that was wandering around
has been put back
so all is good in the sheep farm
you know what i would like to try out is
this thing
i haven't used in a long time
don't know if it still works
i can't remember how long it takes even
still no spiders so there's two
cave spider spawners underground here
there's one like right below here
and another one
i think it's over here
somewhere can't remember
they should come up this spiral thing
but i don't think it's happening let's
take a peek
what are you guys doing down there
hmm they really can fight the water
current
if i force them this way will it work
i know when i used it before i would
have to stand like right here
to get both of them working
uh
no i don't think it's working anymore
well it sounds like hmm
i don't think it used to take this long
that's for sure
oh oh we got one maybe it did
yeah here they come okay
but the second one there doesn't seem
like it's working because i
wait did i just see one
i thought i just saw one
it's not working well let's leave it at
that
but oh well i still have lots of string
and spider eyes and
wool and everything
we got our 30 let's enchant us a pick
see what we get
wow oh man i love the new enchanting
system it's
it's wonderful
but anyways guys i'm gonna get going
here it's late again
as usual uh thank you for watching
and please do leave your feedback on
what we talked about today it's
important for deciding what we're gonna
do
anyway see you guys