[Music]
hey hey how's it going everyone
this is etho welcome back guys to
another episode here
uh i saw in my comments the other day
that some people were talking about this
ufo thing
uh the guy didn't know what it was and
what it did
and it's like man i hardly use that
thing we should do that today
just really quick here to start off with
practice my fishing
it's been it's been too long
all right hopefully i can still do it uh
let's go for that one right there that
look
that guy looks plump and juicy
ah too juicy couldn't get him up
i always say him when it's her they're
cows right
yeah i think i held it too long there
you gotta do it like
ah no just can't quite get the height
man
i did too soon there i think you gotta
like wait just a little bit longer and
then
oh oh i think that one had enough speed
but it
no didn't i find a different spot where
it did work though
like a lot easier i think it was like
man i can't even remember now it's like
over here or something
[Music]
yeah anyway so guys i have uh
i've spent like the last six seven hours
uh just building around my cave here
it's it's been
it's been a lot of fun actually i i
don't do a lot of like
i haven't been doing enough off-camera
work i feel and i just
got in this mood where it's like i want
i want to build i want to finish things
i want to fix
things and
speaking of fixing things we might have
a problem with this
i swear there was a spot where i stood
and it worked really well
where was it
was it over here i don't think i don't
think it was over here
[Music]
oh no all right you're dead uh i can't
do the fishing it seems
didn't get a single one what on earth
unless i changed it maybe if i changed
it so i uh sit in a higher spot maybe it
would work then
because it comes really close to getting
in the water it's just like
a block or two short maybe i will look
into fixing this it might be possible
uh but yeah i thought maybe let's go
take a look around the cave
and uh check out some of the changes
i've done
um like for example there's
there's little things all over the place
like for example this weed is missing
and it's just like little things like
that bug me uh so
i decided just you know it's time let's
let's do a major
overhaul and i did a lot of general
things around here
uh i'll see how many of them i can
remember like for example
i'm going to say example a lot today i
feel uh we used to have soul sand around
around this tree i changed that out with
bonzel thought i would give it a try
planted some lilac some some grass there
just a simple little change i think it
looks a little better though
especially like on this side have those
pink lilacs there it's really cool
i like it i figured out finally
like every so often i would come here
and there would be uh there would be a
mob
or a creeper a spider or something
skeleton zombies
and i could never figure out where they
were coming from because i checked the
light levels everything looked good
and then today i noticed on this bridge
like right in the middle
it was just barely dark enough where
they could spawn
so i went underneath i added a bunch of
glowstone um
which you'll never see but i think the
light levels are okay now
9 8 yeah but the light is coming from
below so i think that's still fine
all right um
[Music]
this glass i got rid of the glass here
and changed it with the gray glass
and i thought we that was a voice crack
that i went really high there i thought
we tried that before and i didn't like
it and then i switched it back to normal
glass but
you know it might have been when uh
stained glass just came out and it
looked
a little different because i think that
looks a lot better now actually
it's you don't see as much junk in the
way it actually looks clear
to an extent which is nice i finished
this
off over here there used to be a few
torches and there aren't any more
um i hid one light over here
and that's light gray carpet which is
probably the closest match
to stone so i got that there
and i hid some lights over here this
area i got finished up as well
let's go take a look at this this
chicken
chicken fell down here and he hasn't
moved
she hasn't moved i keep doing that um
plant some more lilacs i really like
these lilacs actually i used to
like the roses the two these these were
my favorite
i think the lilacs are actually they're
uh
they're a little more subtle than the
bright red i find
if you're trying to decorate something
so i got some hidden lights all around
here
i added a hidden light over there
and another one over here which you
don't really see there's a vine in front
of it
to help blend it in a bit more if you
guys are not aware
any new guys to my channel one of the
goals with this place
like that the goal of the cave here was
to
slowly but surely transform it from a
barren
dangerous cave to
a lush vegetated
nice and green
area but still follow like the cave
shape like
keep the tunnels as good as i can
obviously i've made
some changes to all that and another big
thing
though is to get make sure i don't use
any torches so all finished areas
must not have any torches in them
so i've been i've been trying to get
that done i added uh
some slabs here i thought that might
made it look a little nicer even though
they don't really make sense uh over
here
see what did i do here oh the elevator i
finished the elevator here
so before there was a whole bunch of
like stone and dirt and it wasn't really
polished up so i added in
these logs all the way up to the the top
there
used to have cyan clay cyan clay
between the pistons i've changed that
with spruce
and then i just decided to add some
slime blocks
and uh spruce stairs and stuff
for a backing here just to make it look
a little interesting
let's write up behind these slime blocks
is glowstone so it keeps the whole thing
lit up
it's pretty cool um
let's see what else what else oh yeah
let's go over here
so much to show you guys we haven't even
seen the main thing yet
um although i do have to say six hours
seven hours of building i did not get
done as much as i thought i could in
that time like
everything takes quite a bit of time to
really polish up
uh but i'm planning on maybe making
a path like from here to go out through
this
rock we'll polish it up of course
and then give me access to above my
potion room here
something i did as well is i added all
this white glass over top
the wiring here so you can actually walk
over top it and look
down and it looks kind of cool i like it
did that over here too
aha all right where else where should we
go next
so unfortunately i did not get enough
time to uh work on wilson today
he was he was on my list i really wanted
to
to make you better wilson i'm sorry i'm
sorry but you're a giant time sink
you know that you steal all my time and
then i got nothing to show for it
uh seriously this anything i do with
this guy just takes forever and it's all
redstone stuff so i can't really show it
too well but hopefully soon i'll be able
to uh
update them and we can we can check them
out again
um probably the biggest change the area
that changed the most is over here this
was my least favorite part of the cave
and lately it's it's starting to get
better especially this new section i
added
so this is the intersection area here
um added some hidden lights around you
got
leaves there planted some carrots in
in this corner and there's another
hidden light over there
i tried to stagger them so we got them
on like three levels and they're
sort of offset from each other it's like
you know and uh kind of fixed up the
ceiling here i had a bunch of i think
redstone wiring showing
that's all covered up still need to make
a few changes here but
overall it's it's pretty good we did
this waterfall
thing was that last episode i think it
was
and uh kind of wanted to continue with
it so
i've got a wheat there got this like
archway
these glowstone lights up here light up
the bulk of this intersection like
whatever these hidden lights don't get
and then if we go down here this is uh
this is the new thing i added
there was a tunnel running through here
a pretty small tunnel i didn't really
know what to do with it
i wasn't really expecting to to do much
because i didn't have a lot of room to
work with uh oh
that's not a good sign there might be
some dark spots here
uh but i'm actually really happy with
how this turned out i think this place
looks pretty cool for a tunnel
and it kind of ends right here and then
we got this nice open spot
i'm hoping to do something cool in um
some of you that have been watching for
a long time might recognize this area i
used to
come over here just about every episode
in fact
and like jump down in this water got the
old slime farm
over there and then my nether portal i
think was over like right here in fact
right right in this wall uh
but i'm i'm excited to start building
down here because i want to keep
i want to make like a giant lava pool
and have like trees around that
and try to make it dangerous like
like uh you see how i got a pathway here
instead of doing something like this i
would have like
a button i press and then pistons extend
and you can
walk up across the lava for
a split second but if you if you take
too long i'm going to fall down here
so i i want to make it dangerous down at
this bottom level
but still try to make it look cool too
and of course it's not all about looks i
want to like build stuff down here too
different projects uh let's head on back
up all right
i think this is yeah this is a hidden
light i think
there's some glowstone somewhere down
there uh i added a door here this is to
the snowball fountain
wiring i didn't really have a good way
of getting to this so that's kind of
nice to have
more lilacs i want to put something
in this corner
um so it's not quite done there i just
put down some logs and some bushes and
stuff here it doesn't
it doesn't make a lot of sense but i
think it makes it look a lot better
um same with like i got like a fake root
coming out of the ceiling here
the waterfall i decided to make split
which also doesn't make a lot of sense
but
uh this side looks a lot better than
this side here where did you come from
why are there chickens everywhere man uh
then i threw some stuff down here
oh he's dead that did not last long
oh he's not dead he just took a little
damage i
yeah this is important to a workstation
here i don't have enough of these around
and i like have to run
pretty far to a an ender chest or an
anvil or a crafting table
i find so it's always good to have
something like this
every so often in your world i wanted to
put white flowers down there but i don't
have any
and then i made a path go
this way which we can put a room here or
or something i tried digging down
and lava is right before below there so
maybe we will do something fun with that
have like a pit
pit of doom type of thing
uh but anyway that's the new area let's
this is taking a long time man uh we
gotta hurry here
okay so another important thing this
snowball
apparently machine broken i just found
out
actually let's check this i want to make
sure the snowman was gone too
i want to check if he's still here yeah
he's still there i don't know how he
died
uh but that trick where you
you use pistons to push them into a
corner doesn't seem to work anymore
uh like when i did the one on the
minecraft server i
found that out so this one i'll have to
update as well and push him into an iron
bar or something so he's partially on
this block here
um so that's another thing on my to-do
list
oops finish that added that
uh change the glass here with green
glass
thinks i think it looks a little better
it's a little more transparent
i want to get a fisherman villager into
this fishing shack to it i just thought
of that would be cool
lots of torches around here i have to do
a lot of work on that yet
this dead ends dead ends into ugliness
as does this
so this area is not done by any means
and i also want to do something better
with this wall
if we go up here i changed out the glass
i had at the slime farm with
gray glass so you can see through it and
see what else i think that's about it
actually i think we
covered most of it there's probably a
few things i missed but we've been
we've been touring here for quite a
while actually uh oh yeah yeah let's go
check this out
so a big thing we got a gold pile again
oh yeah look at all this um so i'm going
to uh
hopefully set up a beacon at my wither
skeleton farm
and we'll go do that do that together
and
and try it out
oh just another small thing here i added
some birch slabs under this bridge
to help give it a little more contrast
before we go to the wither skeleton farm
though
i wanted to check out the cactus farm we
built last episode
since i've been in the world here for a
few hours i'm curious to see if we even
got a stack i want to see
just how inefficient it actually is
oh oh yeah i changed a few things here
too i added
added these trees and i took out the
torches
because i didn't have torches in my
original one
and i had those trees in as well so
maybe we can uh sneak in here
oh i think the mob trap got most of them
although it probably won't kill them so
we'll have to watch out
creeper there there's witches down there
yeah they're there i have to be careful
uh so the pixel piracy stuff by the way
i did send out
the pms so hopefully you got them if you
won
i had a few people reply back already
saying thanks so
that's good oh we got one two three four
five six
just about six stacks that's pretty good
actually uh it's more than i'll ever use
so yeah i i don't think there was any
problems which is good
i did think of one thing i should have
said the last episode i will not be
asking
any personal information from you in my
pm so hopefully nobody
pretended to be me and like
did that yeah you gotta be really
careful online guys
just about there's almost no case ever
where someone
should need your personal information so
don't give it out
unless it's on a website that you know
is official
and has like signed
what you may call it it's encrypted
you know you know what i mean it's a
safe website so
just be careful don't fall for those
things i actually just about fell for a
scam
uh today when i was checking my email it
looked so legit
and i was thinking about like the the
password crisis
recently on the internet and i thought
you know oh it happened somebody got my
password and i just about clicked the
link and i was like wait a minute
let me check out this company i did a
search and sure enough it was some scam
somebody claiming uh they i paid for
something i didn't actually pay for
uh anyway with our skeleton farm let's
go
okay here we are in the nether at the
wither skeleton farm and i found
the center of the fortress more or less
i think this is about the
best spot for the beacon so we gotta
punch a hole through the ceiling
and i got to first get on the ceiling so
here we go
oh well that was pretty good mark the
spot
just to make it a little easier to find
all right 44667 so we go to the whole
uh breaking the bedrock thing which is
always fun
these dark oak saplings i i've shown
this quite a few times as have many
other people so you probably know about
it
but every now and then i still see the
comments how do you how do you punch the
hole through the bedrock so just show it
really quick here
um assuming i can remember i think it
was like this
yeah there we go so if you grow the tree
like that
it has a chance of the roots punching a
hole through the bedrock
and looks like we got a hole already
that's pretty good so
i'm gonna spend some time here try to
make a
decent size one at most i'm gonna have
four
beacons here so a two by two would be
ideal
but uh i'm not picky
we'll see what we can get
oh yeah we got our oh
knock it off guy we got a two by two
beacon uh
managed to get a two by two in the
bedrock actually didn't take too long
either that's pretty cool i had exactly
four beacons
although i can pretty easily get more
the the tough part is getting all the
iron or
gold blocks and i was a little
short on the gold so i had to dip into
our iron reserves but
we can reclaim it later uh so this is
cool we got
speed 2 resistance 2
strength 2 regen and
jump boost so let's go try it out for a
second shall we
um so with this sword
sharpness five it's got looting three
we can one hits anything
which is pretty crazy because because of
the strength too
um so this should make
oh i don't have a bow let's see if we
can get a bow off somebody
should make wither skeleton hunting
pretty easy
and a few updates ago actually they
changed it so looting swords
have a higher chance of of getting rare
drops too so it's even
easier to get with their skeleton heads
than it used to be
um plus this farm is like crazy fast
at spotting them so that's pretty cool
and the way it's laid out oh i never did
get it
should we try ricochet there's a weather
skeleton up there
let's go say hi
hey yeah the way i got this laid out
the the beacon seems to reach everywhere
pretty much
like all the way up here
oh there it is right there
[Music]
i guess we gotta kill these guys too
oh yeah this is pretty cool and like
the very edge of the beacon is up at
this path so i can
wait where are we i'm a little lost
is this the right path yeah this is it
so the beacon reaches all the way up to
here just oh hey guy
this guy teleported into the nether with
me and somehow made it all the way over
here
um out this far the beacon
effect wears off but on this path
it still takes ticked in so i can i can
run on this pretty quick too
which is nice so yeah
should be should be a good setup
hopefully i can
get some more blocks so we can set up
beacons in other places too
[Music]
and i think uh oops let's go check our
chest
yeah we got 12 right now so we can get
four more beacons easy
oh hey we got a zombie so if you kill
zombie pigmen sometimes they will spawn
if you have a high difficulty in your
world
oh did we get one no
whoa little guy
[Music]
anyway so i'm gonna head back here
actually just wait a second here
something
weird happened that maybe i didn't
notice before but i just killed the
zombie pigmen
and they did not get mad
that is pretty strange is it because i'm
one-shotting them
yeah that's what it is so because i'm
they're not getting aggressive or
alerting the pack that's kind of uh
kind of cool i didn't know that
i still don't understand sir how did you
get on the outside
of the building
it just doesn't make sense what were you
doing
don't worry i'm a trained professional i
will get you down
oh okay
i kind of thought he would chase me down
but he didn't
so i just killed oh no he still doesn't
want to budge
there we go we got him
[Music]
well that's going to be it guys i have a
comment picked out says etho
why don't you show us your old world
sometime do you even have it
you should go through all your worlds
because it seems like you have
a lot of them and it would be really
entertaining
yeah i've had about four main worlds i
think it's four yeah four
uh counting this one of course so
i still do have the worlds i've been
considering maybe
making an episode on that but i'm not
sure because i
i did that once before at least
so i don't know if it would be kind of
repetitive but it might be neat to check
them out again
it's been a while anyway
so that's that's it guys that's all
thanks for watching hope you have a
great day
as usual and i will see you in the next
one
bye bye