[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho welcome back guys
how's it going what's going on what's
new how's the family
it's a stupid intro i did a long time
ago and i still think of it whenever i
start my episodes
oh all right very good
so lately guys we've been very busy in
our world here i've been getting a lot
of stuff
done um we did some work at the amplify
terrain not long ago
last episode we we uh worked on the
library again and
started that fresh got a lot done there
and today
and yesterday actually today and
yesterday two days i've been working on
the the beast here i've been tackling
the beast
the monster that haunts me in my
nightmares
the project that has no end
that's right the nexus i've been working
a lot on this lately i've been trying to
get it done
let's go check it out got got a lot done
on it
very happy all right
so yeah probably looks a little
different than last time i showed you it
the redstone man the redstone man that's
me
no the redstone is
just about done
um i often get asked like what is the
biggest project you've ever done etho
what
what what has taken the most time this
is officially the biggest
biggest project i've done in minecraft
and
we are not close to done it yet there's
still a lot to do
so yeah this thing is insane well i
guess the man cave
technically took longer but that's like
a collective group of projects
not just a single one but uh things are
going good
the way i've been doing it like we built
this first
section here right and we got this all
working we tried it out we tested it now
what i'm doing is i'm
i built like all seven things and i'm
piecing it together step by step like
instead of trying to build each one
individually then
moving on to the next one i'm just doing
like one step
in all of them and then i move on to the
next step kind of like an
assembly line that way i'm less likely
to make mistakes it's easier to memorize
like the redstone
and how i need to build its let's see
where was i
i forgot where i left off at we're not
done it but it's very close to done
oh yeah i was doing this row here
so as far as materials go with this
project we're actually doing pretty good
like that was the main hold up
on the building and i think we have
enough redstone to finish this room i
think we may even have enough iron if we
dip into
my non-poppy farm supplies
um so the only thing we really need to
collect is maybe a bit of glass
and the big thing is the quartz
i have used up my supply of quartz so we
might look into getting some today
but i'm not entirely sure what we're
doing yet i'm just going to do a bit
more building
and then we will try to do something
else here
yes i decided to uh
we have a friend here oh he got free he
got free no
oh snap he was he was stuck in here he
must have got out
all right i decided to go for a quartz
run
after all so in single player
of course i never carry a bow oh i just
did that
that's not good that's not good
i will explain what i was going to say
in just a second
let me get some ender pearls
get to high ground
oops all right what i was going to say
for getting quartz in single player it's
probably quickest
to just like you know
get it from the surface here this is
gonna be impossible to do now on camera
because uh we're fighting fighting a war
here now
apparently but yeah like just grabbing
stuff like this wherever you can
the only problem is it is very dangerous
up on the surface so what i wanted to
try
and this is especially probably good on
servers where
all the quartz has been mined out all
the easy to grab stuff
i want to try go down i'm going to block
this off because they are chasing me
right now
okay should be fine so if you go to the
top of the nether or the bottom it is
solid netherrack pretty much with the
odd cave running through
let's see so let's go down to maybe why
here i'm going to fire fire potion i
also brought
night vision to try this i'm wondering
if speed mining is a good way of getting
quartz basically is what i'm getting at
here so that's what we're trying out
so the idea is you would probably get
like a speed potion
all right maybe night vision probably
fire resistance so that you don't run
into any of the lava pockets
and then you would get like a cheap
burner pick
probably efficiency two or three
unbreaking three then you get another
good pick
with silk touch on or fortune
for collecting the courts and let's just
see
if this is a viable way of collecting
quartz or not
because it would be totally safe right
and a lot easier to do than than going
hunting on the surface because i've died
many times on a quartz run and lost
everything
and that really stinks
it took us a little while to find this
first vein here that's not so good
oh by the way guys i forgot to tell you
to get your snacks today
i have oh man guys lately
i've been eating the mandarin oranges if
you don't know about mandarin oranges
they come out like
for a month every year in winter and
this is their season
or chinese oranges or japanese oranges
whatever you like the small
sweet delicious oranges that is my snack
of choice right now i've been eating
so many of them like five a day for the
last couple weeks
they're so good such a great snack food
i love them
um but my fingernails have like turned
yellow
from peeling so many of them
all right it does take a little while
to find a vein the good thing though is
these veins
should be their full size sometimes when
they spawn near
air air pockets uh
the ore vein gets cut off right
so you should always find a big chunk
when you do find it
like sometimes it'll only be like one or
two pieces of quartz in a vein on the
surface here they should always be
like 10 or so
but i don't know if i would really do it
this way
it's not nearly efficient in terms of
picked your ability that's for sure
i thought we found another one here it's
not too bad
ah yeah so i did it for a little bit
here
it was uh it was okay but
it was a lot slower than just going on
the surface so i wouldn't recommend it
unless you
if you just want to chill and take it
easy then it kind of is a good way of
getting quartz
oh that looked weird i just saw a crazy
texture on that block
when i broke it looked like a torch and
some other stuff
um if you're on a server yeah you might
need to do that but in my single player
i do have to go about 500 to a thousand
blocks
out to get quartz because i generated my
nether before
quartz was in the game so i have i have
none of it closed
but uh it's still easier just to go out
and find it
i think oh i'm so
sad right now all that quartz all that
quartz that hard-earned quartz
giant cube of it four and a half stacks
i did not get this from that that's it
that's all we got
this this little bit here it's gonna go
so quick
so i'll have to go for several runs it
looks like but
we're gonna try some building out here
let's see we want more stairs for sure
and that just eats it up so quick ah
why can't you buy it from villagers that
would be so awesome
so a little while ago gone 52 is his
username he
he suggested an idea of how i could do
the front plate on this and actually
looked really good so i'm going to try
copy it and we'll see if we like it
see what it looks like and if we want to
change anything with it
but it looked pretty good from the
screenshots
so basically he was putting
let's see did i not have half slabs i'm
sure i made half slabs
yeah so half slabs on top of these and
now we're trying to fill in this middle
section here
so this is what what he did what gone 52
did
you know i recognized his name too god
52 i
believe we either played against him or
or we practiced with them a long time
ago when i was back when i was doing
the race for the wool stuff with seth
seth bling and fvdisco and tree um
gone 52 was really good at the bow if i
remember right like
really good and uh
yeah we either practiced with them or or
played against their team in race for
well i can't quite remember it was so
long ago now
those are those are fun days though um
and now
i think in the middle we're gonna flip
to the next color and just copy the same
thing
so we need a second floor to this so
that we can reach the chest
oh this is a regular kind oops we need
polish
polished the diorite is the one thing
i'm not so
convinced about though to be honest i
don't like diorite very much
um only when it's with these aqua blocks
does it sometimes work in my opinion
because they're pretty rough looking too
and this is a rough texture so they kind
of go together
but we'll see
okay second floor starts here
and what's it looking like now
i'll probably just build a couple
sections off camera and we'll take a
look at it because this is going to take
a little while
all right guys so check it out this is
what it looks like
pretty much all finished there is no no
roof on it yet we still have to do that
but uh huh
uh-huh what do you think about it should
we change anything
is there anything that needs adjusting
do you like it
um i especially like the ring at the top
here personally
i think that looks really cool and i
like how it's it's not totally solid
like
that's the second floor so we can look
down from the second floor to the first
floor
where we are here so i think that's
pretty cool
got dye right here the unpolished stuff
lots of light like it's nighttime right
now
so when we do put the roof on the
building and it's totally dark
this is how bright it's actually going
to be
which i think is pretty good so let's go
up to the second floor and check that
out
don't get creepered don't get creepered
i am all out of courts i used it all on
this this
little section two and a half sections
basically
all gone so sad
um i'm still missing a bunch of stuff
behind here
right but this is generally the look of
it
overall look i may change out uh
these here with the diorites
just so we carry that theme to the
second floor as well
yeah i like that more actually uh i did
the floor down below a little different
too i made it totally
out of this stuff because i ran out of
quartz
so i couldn't do it the way he did it
but i think it should be flat regardless
um but i might change that up a bit more
yet
oh i broke something here this area
is actually doing okay like i've been
watching the frame rate as i've been
building this and it hasn't dropped too
too significantly i am starting to
notice
a bit of jitter but i still get well
over 120 frames per second when i'm here
and not recording so that's good um
and that's like with all the hoppers
down just about we're still missing
uh maybe not we well
i think we have three rows we need to do
with hoppers yet
but they're almost all down that's
pretty cool
but anyways that is the nexus for today
what should we do
next um
library yeah library so
the response is pretty good on
on the library here last episode uh you
guys seem to like it which is great
a lot of you said it was your favorite
thing i've ever built so
that makes me feel good um
the water was a mixed reaction though
some people really liked it some people
really hated it
uh i think i'm gonna leave it for now
though i do kind of like it i like how
it uh
makes this walkway feel special you know
because you can't get to the enchanting
table from like this way
because the water is in the way you just
have this three wide walkway to get to
it and it's like
oh i don't know how to explain it it
just like
highlights it i guess um and we we need
it it's a function thing it moisturizes
the book so you don't get paper cut so
even if we don't like it i think we
still have to keep it
so uh in terms of the library though i
was trying to think what to do next
and probably should figure out where
we're going to put the back wall
and what we're doing with it so
i was thinking we're standing here right
the
back wall is only going to be a few more
blocks further that way
and for the middle we could do it either
two ways
uh i was thinking either having a big
giant window in the middle
and then like two statues one on each
side of that window
two tall statues or two
two things of highlight i guess i should
call it
or the other option is to have one thing
of
of highlight in the very middle and then
two giant windows
on each side so uh
not sure i think i might go for the two
windows and one
one big highlights in the center of the
room
um and for that highlight i was
considering
having an elder guardian bouncing up and
down i think that would be cool
so we'll plan for that but let's try
work this out so this
is sort of the border here maybe we will
go like
five blocks past that
i usually work with odd numbers so one
two three four five
and then maybe we will have another
border over here
and then like the window or
yeah windows over here then like at this
block spot
let's let me fill this in let's see what
that would look like
wait is that the right height
no let me go up one more block here
all right so we're going to try this
layout for the back i kind of like it
this would be the window here and
there and this is like the center piece
this is where the elder guardian would
be bouncing up and down
so we probably want to locate
a three by three for that
he only needs a two by two but since
it's an odd number we need to go three
by three
to keep it centered properly uh there's
a lot of spruce up here too so i was
considering putting some more carpets
if not the carpet we got to change up
the wood colors a bit more
so it's not so overpowering it's all
spruce
uh yeah maybe
but uh this is what's giving me trouble
i don't know what to make the back wall
out of like
this is probably what we would have on
the outside of the building here
so i don't know if i should go stone or
if i should go wood
or or what maybe clay
we'll try stone first
and just kind of roughly guess what the
window would look like
probably probably around here
and that's going to do about that shape
all right so then we'll do another one
over here
and
we'll do colored glass again i don't
know what color to use until we figure
out what block we're using here
uh-huh okay bring this up
i'm not going to put the elder guardian
in until the very end though
i don't want to build with that guy
annoying me the whole time
if we do that of course i may i may
change my mind on it
okay this i was going to build up i
don't know if i want to build both them
up all the way either
but we'll go up to here
same with this
this is dark wood right yeah spruce wood
and this
actually look pretty similar
sometimes i mix them up
okay we're just going to finish up the
wood and then we'll take a look
so one more row and we'll decide if we
like it
or if we should try different colors oh
i think i went one too high there
okay so from a distance in the middle
that's pretty good right i don't know if
i like the stone
hmm let me fill in
the back here i'm gonna put wood
for this back just to try that
i can't decide guys i don't know if i
like that
um i can think of three other ways of
maybe trying the window frame so either
we go with the stone brick here we might
go for
oak wood like this stuff here the oak
wood planks
if we want to use wood or another option
well two options
is to go for red clay or green clay
i don't know what would be the best out
of out of these four
i was also considering putting oak wood
here just to kind of add some more
variation because it all solid like this
doesn't work
something has to be put in there to make
it more interesting
okay so this is oak wood in the middle
that is definitely better i like that
more
still needs some variation to it but
that's a good start
good base to it the red clay here i
decided to try it
against the blue sky it is no good so we
definitely
need some some window pane in there
that's gonna
blend that a little better uh if we go
with that
do i like it more than the stone
i think i do actually
uh-huh but now we must ask the important
question
the question that really matters do we
like the red more than the green clay
this is a tough one i almost don't like
either of them
uh building is a lot of trial and error
and i often
have trouble with this part deciding on
simple
simple things like this there i don't
like the clean look i don't think
we need a block that's got some texture
to it
or that's more neutral not so bright and
stands out so much
i'll have to think about it i never did
try the oak actually
that has texture and it's more neutral
but i'm worried that's not gonna work
either doesn't really suit a window
frame so well
all right well i'm having trouble
deciding what to do back here for today
so i'm just going to leave it
if you have an idea what block to use
let me know
i don't feel like we can use either of
these though they just don't seem quite
right
but yeah let me know um we're going to
try to do one more thing
at the library here the walls we have to
work out the walls
for up here i'm gonna have some some
book areas i think
um and i decided let's make this the
middle
and from the middle on the right and the
left i want it to curve
inward like this way just ever so
slightly so it's not completely flat
um so maybe we'll put a beam between
here and
here so let's find the middle one
two three four five six seven eight
nine ten oh no
did i count that right one two three
four five six seven
eight nine ten yeah why is it an even
number
this is odd this is odd here oh i got
i got two blocks here whoops
uh that's fine we'll make it work um
okay so one two three four
five here and here that's the center
between the two
so if we're going to curve it inward
let's bring this up keep it flat
and i guess we'll put one post here
and then the other one here is that
going to work is this too tight
on this corner here no that's fine
that works out yeah so then we'll have
it
up here and then i think that would be
pretty cool
you see what i'm doing i'm not really
explaining this too well let's let's
take this out
we'll replace this with the logs as well
all right and then i want these like
little compartments with bookshelves in
maybe now i don't want it totally flat
like i don't want to put them here
we want more 3d depth to them so i'm
going to put them one more block
back i think and we probably want it at
least three blocks tall
anything less than that it feels kind of
cramped
okay so we'll do that seems like we'll
have to hide some lighting under the
carpet here too
actually i can probably do that right
now
yeah i like that
and do that very good okay so let's take
these out
to highlight the area again we're going
to be using oak wood
so that's the highlight color that were
that we've chosen
how does that look
that's pretty cool maybe
how about for the upstairs
do we want an upstairs i think we want
an upstairs guys
we're going upstairs let's let's plan to
have a balcony i like my balconies
okay i gotta figure it out guys i know
what we're doing
are you ready for this check this out so
to finish these off
oak slabs at the top like that
huh i think that looks really cool
i think that finishes it off nicely all
right
then the balcony balcony second floor
there's gonna be a second floor
we're gonna bring these up and we're
gonna do similar to what we
did down there and put fences in
hey no no you stay there
stay fences in
and we'll be able to look down from up
here
and i figure all along this wall we're
either going to put the comment of the
day or this is where we're going to put
our librarian villagers because they're
going to need a lot of space
and there's going to be a lot of space
up here on both sides
these leaves by the way if you were
wondering about them i probably should
have said this sooner
but they're preventing the water from
freezing down there so it's just a
temporary thing
we saw him and everything and he still
got me
man so much damage
too took out the armor stand even
man not cool
not cool oh wow
what a mess
um this i'll put that there
wow okay
um but yeah i think we're good with this
right let's just take a look
i'll fix that off camera oh
and
i think that's pretty sweet you know
even
here's an idea to give it more character
more shape let's do this as well
we're going to curve it in
is this going to work yeah
yeah let's do it like this instead
put that there is the fence going gonna
connect though
or did i mess this up i think we'd have
to take
that out and maybe do this
i wonder if that'll be weird let's go
take a look at that again
uh yeah that's
definitely better right we could do it
here too
oh man the ideas just keep coming uh
but that's about it for here i think for
today
we got a lot done again um
do you guys like building episodes like
this or is this like
boring for you let me know um i feel
like we've been doing a lot of building
lately maybe i need
need to tone it down a bit but
getting lots of stuff done which is
great
all right there we go one last look
and then we will do the comment of the
day for today
i am trapped oh man
okay go up and through the window
yeah i think that's better all right
guys so here we go
the comment for today okay i underlined
it i for sure underlined it now it's
gone
after i signed it the underline
disappeared on the name
happened on the last episode too uh it
says
you should use your etho banner for
minecraft
you should also put your comic book
somewhere in the library maybe use
minecart bookshelves
okay so i want to ask you guys a
question based on on this
um so to make the etho banner for
minecraft i need a creeper
uh creeper head and to get that i need a
creeper to get hit by lightning and all
that stuff
my question is there was this period
where everybody was building creeper
farms
and i know on the minecraft server seth
and and bt seeing those guys they never
ever got a creeper from it get struck by
lightning
and i'm wondering all you guys that
built creeper farms do they actually
work or not
let me know if you ever got a creeper
from your creeper farm
because that's a project i've been
considering doing but i have not heard
of anybody
actually having success with it and i've
seen a few people do it
and it didn't seem like it was working
for them either
but i don't know let me know you should
als
oh put your comic book somewhere in the
library yep that's planned maybe up in
the balcony there like i said
maybe use minecart bookshelves i'm not
gonna do that this time i tried that
last time it was pretty annoying
setting that up and uh
yeah i think it'll glitch out so i i
don't really want to do that this time
but anyways guys that is it for today i
hope you enjoyed the episode hope you're
having a good day
and i will see you again in the next one
take care have a good day bye