[Music]
hello everybody
this is etho and we
are just watching this thing for right
now
i just got back from caving around this
area i'm trying to make it go quicker
get better rates
and had a good run got lots of stuff
but yeah it's still really
really slow so i gotta do a lot more
caving it seems
if we look up our entity it
like it's not even really going above 10
so
there's it's not like it's not like
they're stuck up there they're just not
spawning up there
and it's uh it's a bit frustrating
because i've
i've lit up so many caves around here
and it's still slow
um some of it might be because i have
slime spawning in this area but even
still it shouldn't make that big of a
difference
um yeah i got a lot of stuff around here
lots of stuff
um actually i'm just gonna unload real
quick
uh let's go
let's go check actually i might need
that
where'd it go over there let's go check
things out here
okay um
i haven't really worked in this area
much i am doing
something with the silverfish right now
which we might get to today
but that's it's work in progress
this is how i get out of here right now
it's not
it's not ideal it's the only way out
i need to move the slider or something
or i could go through the nether
but yeah let's go to an extreme machine
and just
have a look around i'm still getting
used to that
very strange to see the sideways logs
uh but yeah like i got a lot of caves
lit up a lot of caves
there we go
and yes i know you can use glowstone i
like using tnt
it's cooler um
there's one dark spot there
um there's a a pool of water there that
needs to be lit up
but for the most part it like oh i guess
that too it's kind of dark that ravine
and there looks like a tave over there
so
oh and that there it's kind of dark
some stuff there but i think that's out
of range already
but yeah i got a lot lit up
um maybe let's check the other one i'll
stop recording for a sec while i walk
there
okay here's the other one so these are
100 blocks
away from that thing uh like 100 blocks
on the x coordinates and 100 on the zed
so it's actually further than 100.
it's uh what do you times it by 1.4 or
something i can't remember
oh now i gotta figure it out square root
of two
is
got my calculator one point four one
point four so
times a hundred about 141
blocks away from the mob system so it's
this is like the border of where mobs
will spawn if i'm
at the mob system okay this one there's
a lot more darkness
look at all this but pretty sure that's
out of the range most of it but
this this over here is within range
i'm guessing this big pocket thing here
is blocking my view of a lot of it
okay i'm gonna set up two more of these
one over that way
and another one uh opposite of here
and just take a look around too
okay we're over here now you can just
see the top of the mob
system right there we are here
again 100 and 100 away
i wasn't expecting there to be any caves
in this quadrant but look at this
like like unexplored caves i mean
i never even thought about lighting up
the mountains there's caves in the
mountains i have to go through too
um see how did i do this before
leave her there look like that
the fun thing about tnt is there's
always a risk of blowing yourself up
that's excitement okay so yeah
like i know i went through that that
thing is so
extremely insane look at all
all the places i've been in there
but yeah i have missed some spots
there's a snake over there
a bit of stuff there i think that's out
of range
uh that down there though is definitely
within range
i have to get to that that's a big
section
right below us
there's something there oh some surface
stuff over there and i'm sure in these
mountains there's a lot of stuff too
uh-huh so we're just trying to get a
perspective of how many keys i have to
light up yet
something there too looks like oh
so yeah there's more here than i thought
there's going to be let's check out the
last quadrant
a hundred uh 200 blocks this way
okay this is the last quadrant i haven't
checked it yet i don't know
what to expect really i'm i'm guessing
it might be
pretty unlit underground uh for a
perspective of where we are
uh the village where we got the
villagers is over there
and our base the man cave is that way
the ice tray is over in there
and the sand pit is that way
just to help you guys get your bearings
of my world but let's check this out
what do we got
oh yes oh hello
you can see oh cool that looks neat
that's my storage room
um yeah look at all this this is the
main culprit right here
slowing down my rates
okay problem found
huh well we know what we gotta do so
i'm gonna go just do some taping um
but we'll try build something today so
i'll skip the caving
for you guys i'll see you in a few hours
from now probably
man i found a pretty crazy ravine here
it goes way down
i can see redstone right there we are at
51 it goes all the way down to redstone
level
um got mine shaft lava
mushrooms if we go across
i took a peek already got this nice open
area
it's pretty cool
um pretty cool pretty wild stuff
and lots of mobs mobs everywhere which
is a good sign that means
there's only a little bit of cave
that's unlit around here
look at them all they're just they're
just everywhere
oh man and i already got ambushed once
while i was here just about died i was
down to one heart
i'm glad i armed up this time
oh yeah this is i think this is where
they blew up before
cool stuff
yeah like wraps around to the left
i want to check that out i'm gonna ender
pearl over there
maybe just to see how big the ravine is
oh yeah
oh look at all the mobs they're
everywhere man this is swarming with
mobs
that's cool
and i have made it back with a lot of
stuff again
oh boy
that's the main thing i was looking for
though i'm almost out of redstone
so it's always nice to get a big batch
like that now this thing does not seem
to be working much quicker
even after i've did a whole ton of
caving
maybe a little bit better but not really
noticeable
and i died once yeah
i'm back up to 17.
as i was going through there i came in i
kind of wished i would have
made a montage of it like a five minute
montage or something because i saw a lot
of cool stuff
um but maybe like i got a lot left to go
so maybe next time i go down there
i'll record a little bit of it but yeah
we're gonna head on over
to i think the village is what we'll
spend some time on today
so i'll see you guys there
and welcome to emerald city we still
only have two villagers but they're
still alive
as long as they don't die i'm happy but
we want to get some more
villagers around here and
i think the general consent consensus
or agreement or whatever the word is uh
is that the houses are better now that i
got rid of the sandstone which
i'm glad people like that a lot of
people want me
to make the lava flow down so you don't
see that little
like ninth of a block or whatever it is
or one pixel
at the top there missing but i actually
like it more
like this so i'm gonna keep it like that
um
and uh people seem to be pretty okay
with this mossy stuff so i think that's
what we'll keep uh
the thing i want to try now is the
fountain idea
it's a small little fountain in the
center here
see how it looks i'm going to play with
the height
let's try like this first of all
oh that looks that looks really weird
hmm
you know i don't know how to make a
fountain i've never made a fountain
before
oh boy
all right
okay i thought that was gonna look
better it didn't though
i guess what i could try to do
align it
see how it looks if it's any better
to do yeah it's like
it's almost like it's too wide or oh
that's probably what i gotta do maybe
have to make it a block higher
okay let's see how this looks
again it's gonna be swamp watercolor
which doesn't look that bad it's not as
green as
it used to be i don't think
well anyway we'll keep at that for now
what do you guys think of that
what i'm going to do next is punch a
skylight right above the center
2x2 of this thing and then we're going
to try to put some doors underneath it
people don't like the fountain i think
i'll just do a pond like just
flat water
actually i just want to try it with
cobble here so we could do this
or we could also extend it
like that
and there's one more thing i want to try
to just see what it looks like
let's also try just have this idea let's
try and put some emeralds here
i know a lot of people don't like
emeralds i love them though love them
my favorite block believe it or not
okay we'll think about that it's uh it's
pretty intense
i also wanted to try
do this just let water flow down here
and see how that looks if it comes all
the way down from the ceiling
uh yeah just having some fun playing
with ideas
trying lots of different things
see what this looks like
doesn't necessarily have to be a
fountain it could just be some
random thing like this too
oh it's too bad the water doesn't go all
the way to the top
that is weird
i like weird i don't know if i like this
though
could also do it like this and have like
stairs here
i think i like i do kind of like this
very strange
a lot of people thought i was basing
this or got the emerald city idea off of
wizard of oz i've never actually seen
wizard of oz it's just
i just wanted to make a weird village
the emerald city was actually a sonic
reference sonic the hedgehog
in one of the gamecube
versions of the game there was a level
called emerald city
which is where i got the name from and
because we're using emeralds as our main
block type
but yeah you know what i would really
like to do is have lava coming down
and maybe some iron bars and hmm
but if we do that the idea of them
swimming up through here is
totally out the window
okay so this is another idea of how we
could do
a water feature in the center uh this is
probably
my favorite if you guys have a favorite
let me know in the comments maybe
include a time stamp
of when you when you saw it in the video
let's try this too uh that way i know
what you're talking about
if you didn't like any maybe let me know
too
but please be kind please be kind if you
if you don't like something
i'm sure a lot of you won't like what
i'm doing here i am doing something very
weird
and strange uh
which is it's it's how i have fun
playing this game doing
doing unusual things in the game
that i haven't seen before
uh is how i have fun
let's see
as far as the the ones i've shown this
one would be the easiest to do something
technical with
because the villagers they aren't able
to swim into these
sides if i have these stairs here and
it's just a two by two thing of water
even though it looks wider and i could
do solid
water source blocks all the way up so
they can swim up quicker
instead of getting sucked down
but yeah uh moving on
all right so this is the idea i had for
the village we're gonna go
build in this fountain now i already put
the sides here so we can work um
let's see
let's go down
we gotta make like a mob evader to get
these guys up so maybe let's go
here i'm going to connect
each direction we did here it's going to
connect to one of the houses
all four ways
um there's gonna be some redstone
involved with this
as well but what i plan on doing is
hiding eight doors down here i got them
ready
um
as long as we i think i'm rambling a bit
i think if if the sunlight passes
through the water it still counts as a
valid door
i think i think transparent blocks still
count if they don't this idea is not
going to work at all
but i'm going to hide some doors down
here and they have to be
within five blocks of the
sunlight above us there so we can go one
two
three four five up to here
with the doors i think um
so i'll just put these down for now to
give you an idea of what we're going to
do so we'll have the doors pretty far
back
there's going to be i think dispensers
here
both sides with water in and
like some trip wire here
that if they pass it's going to turn the
water on push them to the middle
to a mob evader and they'll swim up and
that will tell
the house go back up
whoa i really went up there it'll tell
the house that the villagers are out so
these lights will come
off and also we're gonna have to dig
like a hole down here with another set
of trip wire
uh they should fall down a three block
drop like that and if we have tripwire
at this level
it'll turn the lights on when they fall
down there but they won't be able to
come out through these doors they'll be
underground
and basically we're adding two
doors to this house that are underground
here still following me i hope you are
so when they go through here it's like
they're going outside
because the sunlight's over here as well
and it's the only way out
so that's that's what i'm planning here
i'm gonna work at cleaning this up a bit
and we'll
see how it goes
okay so this is what we got so far um
let's pretend we're a villager it turns
night i'm scared i'm scared
run inside close the door
safe after a little while of derping
around in here they should fall down
this hole
i might have to make ways of uh making
that happen
sooner but they'll land on these
pressure plates which will trigger an rs
nor latch and when that triggers
the lights turn on over there and also
it will retract the water that's out
here
okay but yeah they're derping around in
during the night they're safe from
zombies even if there's a zombie siege
they'll all be isolated in their own
chambers so they should be
okay i would think
all right then it turns day oh and they
can see its day from
here because it's within five blocks and
they decide to go outside
and got dispensers with water
and these um
tripwires tripwires they'll go wander
across there and since these are ahead
of the
the water they won't be able to go back
but yeah it'll push them to the center
then at the center we're going to have
water sources
there and there and there so when they
hit those
they will start swimming upward up
through
here and then out
and the cycle will reset also when they
go through this trip wire it'll turn the
lights
off right
i found out something new i didn't know
about tripwire as well you can't um
you can't have a block underneath the
hooks like if that's a solid block
it doesn't work has to be
empty underneath apparently
but yeah that's where we're at right now
i'm just doing a solid stone brick
while i put this together and later we
will try to make it cooler
so yeah do that for all four houses and
i hope it works
i these guys still haven't bred yet
which makes me worried that the
this doesn't count as valid doors
whoa glitches getting some glitches
oh cool you went down here oh dang he
went down here now he can't get him out
because this isn't set up
ah
hmm yeah we got a problem guys it
doesn't seem like if the sunlight passes
through the water it counts
which is really too bad
this worked though like he went through
the doors and
now he's stuck there so we can control
him with the water
um but yeah
it doesn't work through water uh we
could get it to work
like if we
put a transparent block here like a
piston or something
um like if we did this
not that if we did this
and had sunlight pass through here it
would still register
properly oh
the guy doesn't know what's going on but
yeah he came here
during the night he went through those
doors at night so he
he just sees them as any other door
they're not outside doors to him
with the way this water is
but if we did this
and had sunlight above this then it
would work
but then it looks like that and we'd
have to punch more holes
into the ceiling so i don't know what do
you guys think of everything we've done
here
uh let me know your ideas i think i'm
gonna
put this at rest and think about it for
a bit more
um i have to get him out of here
let's go let's go read the comments
there's one thing i want to do yet
we should try doing an enchantment and i
cooked up
a lot of that stuff i got taving today
so let's see if we can get to
30. gold gives a lot
i think more than iron
27 28
oh i think we might make it
awesome we did it
um what should we do what should we do
i'll just download
that there do we have any
blank tools
sharpness um
kind of wanted to do a sword
i will just do a pick we got one ready
oh yeah and i did mess around up here a
little bit
not much i was doing some more arches
uh i just tried this out and
did like a half arch to this door and
then i'm gonna do another half arch
on this side that'll go down which i
think will
will complete it pretty good but still
messing with that sweets
but yeah things are coming together
little by little
pretty good pretty good
here we go etho what do you think of the
new updates
1.3 and 1.4 snapshots do you think it is
too much
i would love to hear your opinion thanks
for the videos
you're welcome um
for the most part i really like the
snapshots and the 1.3 update i love the
new features
uh what i would like them to focus on
though now
is to work at fixing the bugs that were
introduced and also
at optimizing the game
although i am really excited about the
1.4 features too especially the
the item frames i'm going to use that in
the storage room
so that you can see what's in the chests
from a distance i think that's pretty
cool
and there's a lot of other cool stuff
but all in all i'm pretty happy with it
i just want them to focus on fixing bugs
and stuff now
and uh yeah we're just gonna do one
comment today
uh i will talk about one other thing
real quick
uh about comments edit etiquette
if you guys see something in the
comments that is extremely rude
or negative or you know someone just
being a jerk
instead of replying to them just down
vote their comment because if you reply
to them it
can it can cause these long comment
chains to occur
and it brings attention to it and
it's best just to hide it if it's a
really stupid comment so
just a reminder um but yeah i'm gonna
get going here
guys thank you for watching and
i will see you again next time
you