hello hello everybody welcome thank you
for joining me again I hope you can hear
me all right I got a new headset if you
saw my Twitter post my old headset is
broken my twitter is ito LP because you
someone you're probably wondering now
what it is yeah I broke my old headset I
had my arm on the desk and I act I went
to pull it back and I my elbow bumped my
headset and it fell to the floor which
is something I've done many times before
but I just just the way it fell it broke
the frame in half like the two thing
holding the speaker's apart broke in
half whoo oh so yeah it was kind of
beyond repair I I was thinking about me
maybe trying to fix it but in fact it's
still usable like the mic and the
speakers are fine they just aren't being
held together properly and I was gonna
try fix it whoa oh yeah but I put out my
head and when I took it off I saw it was
like leaking glue out of the seams do
for some reason and I was like I'm not
putting that on my head anymore so yeah
went got a new mic got the exact same
one the Logitech G 330 so we're back in
business here kind of sad that it broke
I had that since the beginning I haven't
switched mics once yet really like this
headset and hopefully it's okay now it
doesn't quite fit my head the same as
old one I think I had it bent a certain
way whoo oh where am I
then this no that's right I marked this
before I started
all right now you go back up yeah I had
that one since the beginning is kind of
sad that's gone I remember when I was
picking out is like I don't really want
to spend this much money on it because I
probably won't use it hardly I was only
planning to do maybe a few Epis like LP
episodes and then stop unless people
reacted well to it and the rest is
history I used my headset pretty much
every day for a year and a half or so so
I got quite a bit of use out of it and
very few people very few people
complained about the sound quality so
that's why I got the same one again I
know in the past I didn't really have it
positioned correctly so in my older
videos you can really hear like saliva
in my mouth and a lot of time there
would be sound pops and that but over
time I figured out how to position it
from my face properly but this new one
it tends to want to rub against my face
that the microphone parts so hopefully
that gets bent properly and it's not too
loud today I don't know how it's going
to sound I haven't tested it yet but the
new one is actually a lot more
comfortable and the sound quality's a
lot better so I'm pretty sure the old
one was getting worn out because I can
notice quite a bit big difference
between the two but anyway onto the
episode what am I doing here
well I was going through the comments of
last episode oh one second
going through the comments and had quite
a few good suggestions hello of things I
could do okay that's fine that's fine oh
this is a stronghold okay I've been here
not a big deal and for the light the
lighting here oh I really like the idea
of using glass here and having a
skylight like digging up to the surface
instead of having these lamps that way
it'll light up the void fog below so
that's what we're going to do I also had
suggestions to switch this glass out
with ice which I think would look really
cool we'll do that in the new patch when
we can pick it up with silk touch and
also dad a little bit more to it so it's
not solid solid glass or solid ice to
add a little bit of a grid to it what
okay so that's the plan with that but
we're not just going to do a glass son
lights here I kind of came up with
another idea that works with it and I
will get to that in a bit I'm going to
haul this one out yet and we'll get
started okay let's get started here so
the advantage of using sunlight is
sunlight is a light level of 15 and that
gets all the way to the glass here look
how bright this room is right now it's
really really bright but if you were to
have like a lamp or a piece of glowstone
there it's it's light level 15 as well
but only at that block and then the
light dwindles in a diamond shape from
that so you go down one block it's
fourteen thirteen twelve eleven ten
glass by the time it gets the glass its
light little light level nine but if
it's sunlight glass is light level 15
you know in a column all the way down
the disadvantage of having a glass
sunlight is at night the light level
drops down to level 4 so a lamp would
almost be better at night and Sun lights
during the day and I think the sunlight
also blocks out void fog or used to
anyway I don't know yeah yeah it's gone
I'm pretty sure it's gone so that's
another advantage of having a sunlight
so here's what we're going to do we're
going to try to get the best of both
worlds I have this idea to do a block
switcher right above one of these
so let's I'll hollow this out and then
we'll get started I know I said that
right but I mean like take out the roof
the ceiling whatever let's go okay so
this is what we're going to do we're
going to build the block switcher here
and I believe this is C and B minecraft
blocks which er if I remember right it
could be wrong but I believe that's
right um goes like that then you have
redstone there right stone there torch
and the torch there and a torch there
okay and then you get a sticky piston it
has to go the same levels that redstone
torch fireman writes see if we can get
this
mm that's not let me place it where did
that go
Oh total miss let's try one more time
there we go now I'm stuck in it good job
I tried to break something I will break
the piston and we don't want that okay
so we got a 1 going down like that then
we have one here and we got to place our
other block I think I have to use
glowstone for it but we'll use a lamp
for right now and then another piston
here like that we will put glass here
for the skylight I keep saying sunlight
when I should be saying skylight ok and
then that is all there is to it so we
will test this out an idea is Pistons
are a transparent block so the light
watch she passes through it and also
through the glass so that's going to
work out really well now what am i doing
I want a button so just to demonstrate
actually I don't know if we saw that so
it was glass now it's the lamp
let's make ladders up because I'm going
to have to keep going up and down over
and over again this piston is not
necessary yeah press it again it will
switch the glass again so that's that's
what we're going to do we're going to
have a sunlight I did it again skylights
we're out of a skylight during the day
and at night we will have it
automatically switch to a piece of
glowstone probably using a day-night
sensor but we'll do that later that's
just the plan so with this setup I think
I can't run wire on these
slabs or stairs so what I'll actually do
is change this a little bit get rid of
that and we don't really need the button
actually so we'll do it like this we'll
have the torch over on the side like
this yeah and then we can have wire
running to it like like that at that
level we can put down a block that way
so we'll probably have a central wire in
the middle here which will branch out to
this one the one over here and same with
over there and there so this is all
built and wired now this is the main
wire here in the middle it connects to
all four of the switchers and when we
build the day-night sensor that's will
hook up to this wire but in the meantime
we just have a button which we can
switch between the two with and for the
default tool just leave it on glass
until we get the day-night sensor hooked
up because I think fake press yeah and I
got a dirt block there until we get
glowstone over here to I switch I
switched out the lamps because I think
they were causing more lag so yeah that
is done for right now anyway and I don't
think that's going to interfere with the
ceiling I think I think that'll work out
okay beautiful world's just beautiful
I think this is a tallest mountain in my
world that I found so far were 117 at
the peak and it's time for some intense
fishing oh it's so intense so intense
there we go
got it
a are you looking for interesting and
entertaining minecraft videos well look
no further than ethos lab etho keeps his
channel chock-full of awesome Minecraft
Let's Plays as well as plenty of helpful
tutorials check it out today at
youtube-dot-com forward-slash ethos lab
yes so intense
I didn't know you'd do that with boots
that's awesome
whoa how come I've never seen this
before that that was awesome
okay okay enough goofing around it's
time to get serious let's get back into
building mode here
not building mode planning mode I got
blueprints figured out in my head
finally for the step the tada mob system
it's gonna happen believe it or not
finally so I asked what they should
build it out of a few episodes ago and
snow was suggested by many loved the
idea so it's going to be out of snow
I'll probably build the whole thing out
of snow just to begin with and if I want
to add more character to it later we can
go back and revise it but I got one of
these guys here give us snow and sorry
distract got lots of snow I'll tell you
what we're gonna do
this is where it's bowing right above
the silverfish farm because the
silverfish farm is going to be the
basement and the storage room slash mob
system ground level is going to be about
here maybe a little bit higher for the
mob system right at this block here that
is where the silverfish spawner is that
is the epicenter of everything I plan to
build here a lot of people are wondering
why I haven't built the mob system yet
and I don't really have a good answer
for you but one of the reasons was
because when I build it I want it to be
built right I want everything in the
right place I don't want to have any
design regrets after it's done like I've
had in the past so I just want to make
sure I get it right position
right built right all right and then it
will be cool and I'll be happy with it
so this is the center right here the
plan is to build for EMP units you guys
remember the EMP units from the ice base
round episode 7080 ish that project
never really got finished because of the
patch and the new world here but we're
going to do we're just going to have for
EMP units it's going to be pretty simple
those are five by four five wide by four
deep a lot of the deepness is from the
wiring but this is the center and we're
going to do four of them this is how I
plan on laying it out this is what I've
been trying to figure out we're going to
have a five by five empty area around
the center like that and then each of
the EMP units will go like one will go
here so but I need five by five wait
wait wait
I feel like I figured out something
wrong here goes yeah we'll have ah
you got something wrong how's this kind
of layouts one will go there and then
yeah it's got to be spaced further okay
so it has to go from from there you're
imagining it right I know it's it's
pretty tough from that so one will go
there so the front of the IMP unit will
be right here
and it's five wide that's the Front's
then one two three blocks for the wiring
we will reserve another one we'll go
here so I'm just laying out of five by
four area for it so and it's faceplate
will be here
and then again so all the way around
we're going to have for a lot of blocks
as one will go there and main one will
be over here I think the one on the side
it doesn't really matter much which side
I choose and its face will be here again
and these will be for the wiring this
area here so this middle part will
probably just be empty space or I might
keep it open in case I have to add
something behind the NP units I don't
know now this main one over here is
going to be for creepers zombies and
skeletons so all three of them and then
one of these will be just for creepers
one will be just for skeletons one will
be just for zombies okay now for the
main one we're going to build the mob
system directly above it okay because we
want to be able to kill them as quick as
possible it's probably the one I'll use
the most so I want as short as travel
time as possible for the mobs so that we
can spawn more and get more items
quicker all right so the mob system will
probably be right over here it doesn't
need to be centered around the
silverfish spawner we just want the room
centered around that so if we're walking
around like over here or whatever
silverfish will be spawning as we're
doing stuff and then the storage room
will probably be like all the chests
will probably be all around this main
centerpiece but we're going to elevate
this a little bit off the floor to make
it stand out and have the storage room
level a few blocks lower than the EMP
level probably is what I'm thinking okay
lots of talking today ah as far as where
the building starts
it's going to start at y61 is what I
figured out on paper here so that gives
wait let me get my calculator 61 - where
do we get 30 while our feet are at 34
okay that's 27 blocks so we need 24
blocks for them to fall and die so
that's why we're going to have that
buffer there and each layer of the mob
system is five blocks tall so you'll
start at 61 will be the floor of it
it'll go all the way up to 127 we don't
want to go above that because then the
game has to check more space to spawn
mobs so it'll lower rates which is the
reason why my Enderman farm still works
good even after the anvil format is
because they only check extra area if
you build in the extra area like above
the the olds nap height right because
when it I figured when the new format
came out my Enderman farm was going to
be twice as slow because it would have
to check twice a space but it only does
that if you build above that so we're
going to avoid doing that if possible at
least I'm pretty sure that's the way it
works or still works okay so up we go
again that lag I stocked in a doctor
other day he says that's cause from the
game having to play sound or or like the
silverfish jumping in the water that's
what's causing that leg and that I
believe that makes sense so because it I
get that whenever I go like 16 blocks
away from the silverfish doesn't matter
which direction it could be up or down
well not down but left right you know
okay so rates
here this level this is a start I gotta
clear out space forts and I'll probably
try build a few layers today but I'm
going to do that off camera and we'll
see how it looks made of snow so we've
broken the land here we're getting
started I got a clear about three blocks
down for the first layer and then beyond
that it should get a lot simpler because
we're we got the space all cleared up
above but this mountain is in the way so
I'll have to chisel a lot of it away
probably which will slow things down a
bit and my dad you decide to teleport
here and watch me for some unknown
reason but that's okay I've marked the
center with the snow block here so like
I gotta go I think what is it's probably
close to about ten blocks this way still
and all the way up to 128 so I'll have
to remove a fair bit of the mountain now
I was looking at my old EMP video
tutorial to see how I did the wiring and
it looks like I can actually move the
them in a little bit one more block in
so it's going to be not quite as big of
a circle around so this is a this is the
four points the five by five and instead
of having them all the way out here
they're going to be over here now I
think it'll work out
oh boy well started raining I ran out of
snow blocks so I guess this is probably
as far as we'll get with this today
because I did get some more
I had like over 10 stacks I'm sure when
I started by just that's just as far as
10 stacks gets you so about one layer is
worth and I have to make a lot of them
which is good I'm glad I pick a snow
blocks because they're really easy to
make and make them real quick and I like
the way it looks it's pretty cool they
all look good when it's all done and
it's really easy to mix colored wool
with snow blocks too so if I want to
decorate it afterwards I can as also
thinking maybe using ice to decorate it
afterwards when we can pick it up again
that might be cool but yeah a little
more info about the mob system it's
going to be 12 layers is what I figured
it will be each layers a hundred
spawning spaces I found out a way to add
four more so it's an even hundred so
twelve hundred total when it's all done
and it should work really really well
but I am going to go to bed now thanks
for watching everybody and until next
time
you