[Music]
best
invention ever am i right guys oh man
we're getting so much use out of this
thing
it's the greatest uh yeah welcome back
my friends to another episode of our
let's play series how you doing
i just updated to the 1.9.2
version of this game and they uh
they did some changes i'm wondering
first off oh it's not nighttime yet
i'm wondering what they ended up doing
with the pvp stuff if they reverted it
because they made it so you could spam
click again and now i'm wondering if
they if they kept it or not
sound like they were going to tweak it
we'll check it out here in a second at
night time
they also added a sound for the
latcher wings i read so maybe we'll go
try that out
see what it sounds like go way up to the
top here
and oh it's just turning knight to
perfect
here we go
oh man that's pretty cool
that adds a nice nice touch to it you
know really feels like you're flying now
it seems to be uh it gets louder the
faster you're going to
which is cool all right guys i made some
stone swords here we're going to do some
damage per second testing between uh
spam clicking and uh
fully charged attack so that guy took
five attacks
i think it took about
[Music]
four or five seconds if i was to guess
oh i got the hiccups
one second all right so for spam
clicking i'll try
try to get this guy out of the pack here
a lot more attacks
i'm spam clicking pretty quickly here
though that felt like maybe
12 attacks and about
seven or eight seconds
yeah fully charging still seems to be
the way to go that was much faster
uh but the penalty for spam clicking
might not be so severe if we don't do it
quite as quickly so maybe we'll try a
couple more times not as fast
uh okay here's a good guy
okay i'm waiting a little bit
oh that's gonna hurt yeah i got more
fully charged attacks on him than i
wanted there
uh let's try again
i'm just wondering which is better now
yeah this is the speed i want i think
oh it was creeper please don't interrupt
ah it's so hard to do testing and
survival it never works out
uh let's let's try this guy okay so this
is
this is the speed we want not quite
fully charged
it's really hard to say maybe i'll do it
a little quicker
yeah as long as you're not like super
speed spam clicking i think it's okay to
spam click still like you don't have to
get fully charged
and it still still seems to do decent
damage here
which is good oh skeletal horse
all right let's switch to a real weapon
because i do actually want these guys
oh i think i hit the horse maybe we
should use a bow
new horses oh i don't have a saddle
though okay i'm gonna have to
get a saddle
okay i got a saddle here we can try out
our new horses our new buddies here
10 hearts kind of so-so jumper
uh kind of so-so speed as well nothing
too crazy with this guy
we're looking for good horses good
horses um
yeah i think the combat's at a pretty
good place now i would say
in my opinion anyway like they seem to
have gotten rid of the spam clicking we
saw it took like 10 or 12 hits
on that one zombie if we were spam
clicking and a very long time to kill
him like a
very low dps um
but we also saw like even at a half
charged attack in like three quarters we
were
doing decent damage so it's not like you
have to wait for the
the swing to be fully charged before you
attack again you still do decent damage
the most important thing is that you
just make sure your attacks
that guy's pretty fast he's pretty good
oh 26
26 hearts on this guy please be good oh
you're slow
no this would have been an amazing horse
yeah so the big thing with the combat
now is to make sure you actually
make contact when you swing your sword
if you miss you got that
that penalty where you got to wait for
it to get to like at least half a charge
otherwise it does very little damage
this guy's giving me trouble guys he's
been here for so long
i'm trying to get him out of here i
don't want to kill him
but i can't get him in this boat i
thought it was going to be super simple
like just put the boat down and he would
go in it
but there seems to be a bit more to it
than that
oh you can still break the boat even
when you have the mining fatigue
kind of thought you wouldn't be able to
okay if i put you here
oh please go in the boat
we're over at the guardian farm by the
way in case it wasn't obvious
every other mob i've tried this in
creative you can pick these guys up
and when they're in the boat they don't
damage you or at least
a few versions ago you could i haven't
tried it recently
come on go in the boat buddy oh oh
nope ah
uh yeah i think they made it so you
can't pick them up in the boat anymore
unfortunately
it was kind of cool but you can still
grab them with a minecart so that's what
we're gonna do here i set up a minecart
track to move this guy out
okay i guess i gotta take another milk
thank you for that
all right yeah i set up i think we're
good to go here
and they are i believe two blocks wide
so
we have a three wide path here should be
good if the if the tracks in the middle
won't suffocate him how
actually i gotta let him out here don't
i
yeah okay and then
did i get you i think i got him yes
see it's really easy to get him with the
minecart uh
and it used to be like that with the
boat too
okay you can pick up uh shulkers with a
boat as well
but or not as well because you can't
pick this guy up but
yeah if they shoot the boat the boat
doesn't float unfortunately
oh no hey buddy
oh there he goes there he goes okay
let's go try catch up with them
the coal in this thing lasts for like
five seconds
it's pretty bad okay
here we go oh it went right through him
what
did you get out of your mine cart
what i don't see the mine cart guys
what
no oh no that's a that's a glitch isn't
it
oh i'm i'm stupid
i think he's invisible i think he's
actually in that minecart
up here
or wherever it went yeah there he is
there he is okay oh i was like man he
just vanished
are you kidding me after all that
setting up these tracks and
oh we're gonna put him in the top of the
the windmill for right now i thought
about maybe putting him in that lake
uh by the you've been ethel kind of like
as uh as a monster in the lake
oh last little bit come on you can do it
oh did uh did i forget a track maybe
and push
i'm telling you guys missing this one
track in the corner is the worst thing
i have ever done because i cannot get
him back on the track now
and he hurts really really bad
okay maybe maybe we do this
i think this is the way to go about it
get a piston over there instead
and ice
ice we don't want him to suffocate
that's why we're using ice
oh you gotta be kidding me no
it's ice ice doesn't make you
oh he's gonna kill me oh
okay let's not use ice if i put a track
there okay it doesn't connect good so if
we push him
if we push him
his mind card is just gone now
oh something bad might have happened
here
i'm guessing he died and it just didn't
show it maybe
oh come on guys
oh he's up there he's up there
oh that was a lot more difficult than i
expected
okay okay we got him up here
he's gonna hurt he's gonna hurt us a lot
let's set up a safe space
okay okay good
um we should be able to drop them
without killing him good
oh and he got us okay i used up my last
milk i think
yeah okay okay this has been like a
puzzle and i feel like i did it the
wrong way and now i'm paying for it
i put down an activator rail there which
made the mine cart
seem to uh fall through the
the wooden slab there i don't know if it
where it is
that's the thing you kind of gotta guess
where stuff is in this game sometimes
all right but i'm gonna power it
and we'll we'll just have to see what
happens trying very hard not to kill
this guy but he's not making it easy
oh yeah he's free he's free sweets so
there we go guys we got our elder
guardian on top of the windmill
i would not recommend you do this
yourself i don't think it was worth it
that was pretty brutal but hey it's an
elder guardian on top of a windmill
that's gotta be worth some cool points
at least right
i think it looks pretty cool so we found
a place for
for that dude finally i think that was
actually better than the lake because
since he's in the middle of the
the wheat field here oh he can reach me
from over here though he wasn't getting
me while i was on the path
it's like just the right distance where
he's not going to be a nuisance you know
but we can we can see him and he looks
cool and that kind of stuff
if we put him in the lake there's a
chance he might like swim up to there
and
you know a lot of times i walked down
this path so he would he would get me
with his debuff
which would get pretty annoying um and
now that he's moved over there we can
actually work on the guardian farm we
might make some improvements on that
today
because it it's been a long time and i
haven't done anything with that thing
because i put that guy there and it's
like okay
now i can't do anything he he makes it
so you can't break any blocks
um i did fix this course fruit farm
as well guys and i did something here i
haven't done in a long time and i highly
recommend this because it's it's kind of
cool
after you do your redstone just go
through it you know give it a nice floor
and polish up the area a little bit if
you ever want to check it out later
make some changes it just makes it all
that much better
you know but
yeah guys i think today i feel like
doing some work on our guardian farm
here so
it'll be a fun project i need to do a
lot of work on this thing
at the moment it is functional it does
work
it's just not the best like last time i
used it i was trying to get some sea
lanterns i left my game running
overnight
came back and check the chests i think i
only got like two double chests of stuff
like after six or eight hours whatever
it was that i left it running
so i don't think those are very good
rates i think we could do a lot better
than that
um this was designed to be a simple farm
like something you could build in the
ocean
without having to remove all the water
like people generally do
all you have to do is remove the
guardian temple and then
put up these reeds and then this little
collection chamber below
with all the fence gates and stuff and
it should work decently but not
not too great as i have seen
so also this area needs a lot of polish
it looks
really crummy doesn't it like even the
little killing chamber here is
very very rough so let's do some stuff
here
the very first uh flaw i want to
tackle it's very obvious
one of the the biggest problems is the
guardians are getting stuck on this
glass here
and they just kind of sit there
eventually they will swim across to the
other side
the reason for this little uh overhang
here this lip
is because they won't cross the reeds if
they don't have water on the other side
to swim to so if there's guys over here
um they won't swim
into the reeds unless there's water on
the opposite side or at least that's the
way it was before so that's why i did
that
but what we could probably do
actually i just realized i'm not going
to be able to work on this without
getting killed
i need invisibility potions i think
and i did not bring any i didn't think
of that i was just like okay i'm going
to go in there and
we're going to get some work done
yeah let me go get some potions hmm
yeah i don't know guys i don't think
invisibility potions are working
properly anymore i tried
putting putting one on took my armor off
got nothing in my hand we go down and
look what happens like
most of them seem to ignore me
but i yeah we're not totally safe like
look how far away that guy is and he
targeted us
so i'm better off going down with my
armor i think
i don't want to i don't want to die
okay with the armor is there any way we
can clear these fools out
actually now they're ignoring me aren't
they
for the most part
with the armor on there they're ignoring
me what is happening
oh no not not entirely either okay
yeah i'm just gonna have to clear out
the area
using the bow really doesn't work too
well underwater though
oh no nope nope but what we're gonna
have to do here
is kill these pools
and then remove the water
oh oh how did he get me still i guess he
must have been above
okay i gotta make sure i keep my food
topped off oh and i'm
i'm about to i should have brought some
aqua potions
so we can use the empty buckets as well
i'm going to put fence gates up at the
second layer here and then
underneath that we're going to have
flowing water pushing them into the
reeds
and that should work out just fine i
don't think this will break the reeds
i have to be very careful of that as
we're doing this
whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa
whoa whoa whoa no no no no no
jerk face
all right guys very cool so we got some
stuff done on our farm here let's go
check out
the changes now also i think i lost my
sword in that death i i just recently
realized it kind of sucks but oh well it
happens
i still got my axe with sharpness on so
it's not terrible
uh but yeah so we got these fence gates
now they can fall through and they land
in the flowing water so the water then
pushes them
to the reeds as long as they don't fight
it too much and then they fall down they
go into the collection area
in the middle there they fall down to
the killing chamber down below
seems to have made the farm quite a bit
better
uh like there's no more dead zones where
they kind of just sit around they're
always getting moved towards the killing
zone now
and that seems to have increased the
rates of the farm quite a bit
i definitely think there's a lot of
caves around here that need to be lit up
still because like the spawning rates
aren't the greatest around here it seems
for these guys so i'll have to try to
find those they're really tough to find
uh because there's like a giant mine
shaft below this area
but yeah anyways the way we have it
right now they fall through the lava and
then they fall down take some fall
damage they burn up and then there's
some hoppers down there that pick up the
drops
we also had a system for sending them
through a portal into the nether
and i just kind of went through that and
fixed it up here made it
uh quite a bit more awesome so here is
our new
redstone for it basically when we press
this button
that's over there for the moment that
makes it so those pistons extend
on both sides it closes it so they can't
fall down anymore
and it also ejects some water buckets
from those dispensers and it pushes them
towards the portal over there
and i did a a pretty cool thing here
i've never
quite done like this before but
basically
this portal is only active when
the water is out so if i press this
button again
like i got a a water bucket
thing for breaking the portal and a
flint and steel for lighting it
and it it switches every time we we push
a button here
so we press the button again
water goes back did i just hear a
potion no that's the the glass breaking
sound that's the
the sound the portal makes when it
breaks it's like oh
i don't i didn't know where that came
from for a second so yeah that makes the
the water budgets
go out breaks the portal i guess there's
a possibility that there's still a guy
stuck in here when that happens
but yeah the two different modes are for
like
total afk farming so
when they fall down here they just
automatically die if we want to send
them through the portal into the nether
we can collect like 500 of them or so
uh it's kind of like semi-afk farming
these guys
collect like 500 of them go to the
portal kill them all at once
we get xp that way and we also can use
our looting
effect from the sword we just lost
if we have looting we can get more drops
from them that way
uh so we got like two options with this
farm i think i want to make it so they
fall farther though because they're
they're taking quite a while to die here
yeah i think we should definitely lower
that also we should check
out uh the portal situation here
because i think that was a mess too so
if we go through
i'm just gonna temporarily light this
just to check it out there might be a
bunch of guardians here
we will see hopefully not too crazy
it's a little bit crazy oh man oh man
okay run away run away yeah so i keep
having this problem
like i got the glass broken there and
it's kind of been like that forever
because
like when i use the portals i often get
teleported to there inside the killing
chamber
which is no bueno we need to
oh they're gonna kill me we gotta set up
another portal
that is preferred so we don't keep going
to that killing chamber
so uh maybe we'll try to put a portal
over here it's probably where it will
look the best
hopefully we can get it to line up the
way we want it to
yeah the idea is we're gonna have uh two
portals at the guardian farm
two portals over here so we want to be
able to go
back and forth uh between the guardian
farm and here easily
without ending up in the killing chamber
with the guardians because if we
get teleported into the killing chamber
we're not going to be able to get out of
it
if it's full of guardians so
we need two sets of portals and we don't
want them to
like mix up with each other so hopefully
this will kill us this will take us to
the guardian
portal over here now hopefully when we
go through this again
it takes us into the healing chamber
still and not with the one we just made
good okay very good so we're where we
want to be
so now we just need one more portal over
at the guardian farm to link up with
this one that we use and the guardians
don't
all right everybody so this is uh quite
a bit later now i've been doing some
things and having some trouble and
you know how it goes so i had a really
really hard time getting the portals to
link up like i wanted like they kept
interfering with each other
no matter where i put them like i tried
putting the portal like down here
try putting it over here try it over
here try it over here
try it here i tried a lot of different
places i just
i had a lot of troubles and i ended up
just putting it over here i think this
is a good spot for it
it's pretty nice you can just walk up to
it and
they don't interfere with each other
anymore this is where i had to
to put it in the overworld here like
just that little distance between
like where the guardian portal is in the
nether there and that one we just built
that huge distance in the overworld so
like from the middle of the farm to here
is how far apart we got to keep them
um but i think this is going to work out
pretty good so
like if we want to go to the nether um
i mean just go through the portals here
they're at uh
ground level this way you know and then
if we want to go
to the guardian farm i'm i'm working on
a thing here
basically and hop down here or we're
going to be able to
then i did like a diagonal passage
to the drop zone here and what i want to
do oh yeah and i tried lowering this as
well i guess we're very close to bedrock
already like this is where it was before
and this is bedrock so we don't have a
lot of space to drop them any further
and i think i gotta raise this up at
least five blocks so it's going to be
pretty much where it was i think
uh getting lots of drops now though like
this has just been filling up quickly
so much quicker than before
which is pretty cool like look how fast
they're coming down
without all the caves lit up so that's
i'm really happy about that
what we're gonna be end up doing here is
we're gonna have a bunch of chests
for collecting the drops we're gonna set
up item filters to filter them
and maybe a few other things and then
when we're
we want to go back i installed a
player elevator here these are so simple
to make it's so cool
let me just show you
so from the pressure plate here just got
a four ticks
monostable circuit here so it goes to
the piston and then
one tick repeater here one tick repeater
here
and let's see actually we can see it a
little bit clearer the pattern from
above here so let's just go into our
our elevator nice and quick
takes us up right to the portals
and the pattern you can fit it into a
2x3 area and just
like keep staircasing your way up which
is pretty cool
so it goes um
dust one tick repeater then you go up
dust dust one tick repeater you go up
then you go up
and just keep repeating it over and over
every layer i tried to put some torches
in i think i might have missed this one
just so we don't get any mobs spawning
inside there
yeah a good idea to do that too
and uh yeah pretty cool things are going
well with this project
but i think we're gonna have to call it
here for today so let's do the comment
of the day
all right guys so maybe to finish up
this episode i just want to show you a
couple things here so i've
been installing a new ice road
in the works right now this is to
the tree farm that we we built also to
the wither
the wither farm that we have and the
broken gold farm is off this direction
a couple things um so i'm switching out
all the path to ice and i'm gonna add
borders right now it's very dangerous
especially right around here
oh i made it i made it and we are here
awesome
uh over here at oh
uh he shouldn't cause any trouble
actually over here at the wither farm i
i changed the portal i put in the right
place now there
used to be over here in this location
uh but i moved it now over to here and
this takes you directly to the tree farm
which is very nice and convenient of
course
oh and i messed it up let's go check it
out
so i uh left this running for like three
hours
right and i was like oh man there's
gonna be so much wood in this chest when
i check it
and there was like five stacks or
something it got stuck
stopped working uh because
for some reason i had a slab here
with redstone dust on it and that
vanished so i don't know what caused
that exactly i'm thinking maybe oak
trees can destroy
blocks still maybe a leaf block grew
right there somehow and
and destroyed the slab i'm not exactly
sure but it was just gone
this is gone when i checked it when i
was trying to figure out what went wrong
so might need to figure out
how to move the redstone so it's not so
close to the trees
but anyways let's do the comment of the
day for today it says hey etho
it's been about a year since your last
world tour you should do another one
yeah it's been a long time guys i think
we're gonna do a new world tour
on maybe episode 450 would be a good
number
um they usually take like an hour
or longer it's really hard to get
through the whole world
uh and we have built a lot of stuff like
since
since the last one for sure so it's it's
about that time to do another one
uh so episode 450 is what i plan
and uh as usual if you guys have any
things to say about uh the projects we
worked on today or
in the future please let me know leave a
comment and i
am going to say goodbye thank you for
watching
and i'll see you in the next one take
care
bye bye