[Music]
here we
go again welcome back everybody
thanks for joining me again i felt bad
last episode we didn't really get much
done
and today is probably going to be the
same it's probably going to be a short
episode i don't know
but i did continue working on that slime
farm
up the look of it and
this is what i came up with
so i'm i'm actually really happy with
how this looks i think it's pretty cool
we got the small slimes here medium ones
over here which don't drown
and the large ones fall into here
they also don't drown the water keeps
them from jumping
the little guys though they drown in
this or at least i'm pretty sure they do
and these are our stairs here
and upside down ones over here so it's
one wide here two wide three wide
and the bottom kind of matches the top
we got upside down stairs at the top
here
um this corner i don't know what to do i
got uh
i had a stair here before the problem is
i need the track to go behind there
i'm not sure which looks better i like
how it looks with the stair but then you
can see through the crack like
the quarter block there so i don't know
which way i should keep it
but uh that's the slime thing
so to start off with today
i kind of want to work on the track for
it
and it has to go over here
i think what i want to do is
put a window for a pez dispenser right
here
or else over here i'm not sure this wall
i'm going to change a bit i don't want
it all
all stone brick like that
this is the elevator for those of you
that aren't familiar
and it does give me trouble too i know
some people have complained about this i
don't think this
uh design works quite like it used to
you have to enter just right
which is pretty frustrating
nighttime i really like the glowing tree
forest
swamp area type thing there at night
looks cool and that looks really cool
the mine there i like how it's got the
opening
hey got the glowing tree on top
um enderman damage
everywhere i don't want to fix it i want
to see how bad it will get
after many months of playing
because it it's getting pretty bad
that ladder didn't work um
yeah so we'll put a display here let's
just see how this looks
um
you could either have it here i have
mine carts behind there
or that's not so touch
we can move it over one more block
we're here
if it's over there it's kind of
symmetrical with this because it's in
the middle
of these three blocks but it is also
harder to see
yeah i think i'll do it over here
maybe i don't know um
let's see what are we gonna do here so
i'm gonna put a pez dispenser right
over here if possible we do have all the
wiring for the
elevator over there that we can't
interfere with
so this may be a challenge i just
watched
uh one of pear squirrel's old videos on
how he set up his
old pez dispenser things i don't know if
it's still the
the best way of doing it but it looks
pretty good to me so that's probably
what all
i'll copy because i don't really mess
around with minecart stuff too much on
my own so i
pretty much just copy other people's
stuff when i have to do it
alright so i will get started here
okay i think i got everything we need to
build the pez dispenser here
so we're gonna get started and as i do
that i will do my best to
talk about something interesting uh
i just realized the other day that
people don't know what i do for a living
and nobody's ever asked
no i'm kidding yeah i've never i've
never said what i've done for a living
and i know a lot of people want to know
i almost said what i did last year
like i was making videos last year
at the same time and i was going to
spill the beans i can't remember why i
didn't i think
people were guessing what i did in the
comments or something and i found it
funny how
how off some of the guesses were so i
just decided to keep it a secret or
something
i don't know i've actually said it
before
uh in streams
uh a lot of people think i'm a teacher
and i am not a teacher not even close
you may notice i have trouble speaking
sometimes and that's kind of one of the
key
ingredients to becoming a teacher you
have to be very charismatic
so not the teacher a lot of people think
i'm some kind of i.t
professional or whatever and that's not
true
either although that would be a job i
would probably be good at
i've mentioned before i'm i do
hobby programming and that stuff kind of
stuff too so i'm
i'm very familiar with computers i know
a lot about computers
and everything pertaining to them
whether it be web development
or programming
using various software whatever i'm very
good with computers
but that is not what i do either that's
more of a hobby
for me uh
what else do people think some people
think i work for nasa
right on the money no all right i'll
tell you what it is
so i work in a greenhouse that is what i
do that's
for a living it's seasonal work uh it
starts in february
and runs until
the beginning of june usually for me
that's my season
of work which is pretty nice because
that gives you
or gives me i should say uh
seven months where i don't have a whole
lot to do
which is really good for this youtube
stuff because
it gives me a lot of time uh during the
off season but at the moment i'm working
10 to 12 hour days so
youtube has been suffering quite a bit
from that
and it's actually a family business
a lot of people have been wondering why
i haven't quit my quit my job and just
focused on youtube
it's because i'm kind of locked in for
the year i don't want to just
quit and abandon my family because
they're relying on me to work
for them by the way the technical term
is horticulturist i don't know if i said
that already
uh but yeah i don't
i don't want to abandon my family and
just quit working
for the year but it just the way it's
turning out
this is going to be my last year working
in the greenhouse because they want to
retire
my parents and i'm going to be doing
this youtube thing
full time coming june
so for right now though i gotta work
quite a bit
but i'm excited to do youtube full time
afterwards
and i'll do that for as long as i can
because
i've mentioned this before youtube is
sort of
my dream job you know i get paid to play
video games from the advertisements
uh that play for my videos so that's uh
that's pretty awesome and then plus
people are super nice in the comments
and it's it's just really fun doing
youtube and
not only do i get paid for playing video
games it's not like
competitive video games where
you're really stressed out about it and
everything i
i did play casually as much or as little
as i want
whatever games i want although i mostly
play minecraft
all right i gotta take a break i gotta
think of what i'm doing here i gotta
make a short pulse on this trap door so
the mine carts will fall down
and oh yeah i need a block here i know
okay i gotta reexamine pear squirrel's
video here
so i went ahead and did a few things
here uh
i put a lever here to power this upward
track for loading the minecarts into
place
i also hooked up the wiring for this
trapdoor so this is what it does
you press the button goes down and up
real quick
and that gives the minecarts just enough
time to fall down
one minecart onto the power track below
so let's let's load this
um i only got two carts on me
and you can see it can pass between
those two blocks
that are diagonal of each other and they
stack like that i actually want to go
outside here and just see how it looks
since we're going to have them
as a display
all right well not the most impressive
sight but it's better than just the flat
wall i guess
um okay let's try this
so when the cart goes down it'll go up
pick up a slime
oh it just barely made it up that slope
that scares me a little bit
let's try this again
good so that motion is really important
for picking up the slimes
we can't have the cart stop here
and wait we need it to be moving uh
then what we need to happen is it go off
another direction we don't want to go
back there we want it to go
like this way maybe
so how's this gonna work if we put a
lever here
unpowered goes that way and power goes
that way
okay so if we put a detector rail
here that might do the trick
i might yeah if it's going slow like
that that might actually work out better
let's see if it'll auto switch for us
oh beautiful just beautiful that's
exactly what we want
i'm pretty sure i should hop into the
cart just
to mimic what it would be like if a
slime
the slime entered it there though
because the cart will move a little bit
quicker
okay so it still went that direction
that's good
oh that is very nice very compact the
way this wiring is here
uh this repeater
beyond this repeater the wire splits two
directions so that
there's one wire oop there's a wire
there and a wire behind there
right this wire goes to this block
and there is a redstone torch there that
goes up to the trap door
and also behind the block is a wire
which goes
to that block and to the trapdoor as
well
and that makes its open close real quick
but what i want to try i gotta make sure
this works too because what's going to
happen is
slime's going to land over there and
he's going to hit pressure plates
so he might be on that pressure plate
for a while so we want to mimic
oh i said that quick mimic a long pulse
on this
okay so look we need an on off for it to
work
hmm
okay i'll have to think about that a bit
yeah so this monostable circuit here
activates on the off states
of the circuit so that's on
that's off so i went and built another
monostable circuit i know this one
activates
on the on on
off on off
on off
so it's it's the reverse and i think the
reason is because this one has two
redstone torches
and this one only has one so we can
probably fix it
just by putting another
redstone torch in the circuit is what
i'm
guessing so now
yeah that was on off on
off so that's what we want so we'll need
to put in another redstone torch
before the repeater or else
just get rid of that wiring and put in
one of these instead
maybe
aha look what we caught this is perfect
we'll be able to
try this out make sure it works because
i haven't really done that properly yet
okay do i have enough yeah i have the
other one on me
may as well put it in make sure
uh the slime doesn't bump the carts or
something crazy
and
awesome so he can take a little bit of
damage
uh if he passes through blocks but we
don't want
him to suffocate obviously before he
gets to his destination
the rise will split and make a mess and
so yeah i guess i should probably
explain what this is all for because i'm
sure there's some newer subscribers that
don't know what we're doing
uh there is a track i i have underneath
the tree farm here goes all the way
around
and loops it keeps looping around and
around and around
the goal is to get big slimes into carts
underneath here
and their heads poke out a little bit
through these half slabs
the half slabs don't suffocate them so
they just keep going around it looks
really cool
it's all for fun and giggles
no real purpose to it uh
except except for the fun of it
and let's see
so that worked out pretty good we need
to hook this
this is the empty cart collection track
here
and this is the one for sending off the
slimes
so we'll have to hook both of these up
to that loop
um i'm going to grab some stuff and
we'll
we'll get going here again
the next thing we're gonna do here is
hook up our slime detector so let's get
rid of this water
uh i think i'll put a pressure plate in
the middle of this
just for the symmetry of it
um i might get rid of that stone brick
later i don't know
what block to use doesn't really matter
because the pressure plate's gonna
block most of the block block most of
the block texture
that made sense uh
does that still work yet so it still
pushes them to
this corner all right so
if there is a slime in here they will
always be on this pressure plate
no matter where they are in this three
by three area
and i'm sorry grass
we'll have to go underneath here now
so it's right there we're gonna hook
that up to an rs nor latch
actually is this wire in the way here i
hope not
uh yeah rs nor latch we'll go right
let's see where is this right here
like that um
yeah and
i think we really need to use an rs nor
latch like we can't just hook that
pressure plate up to the cart system
the pez dispenser because what happens
if two slimes
are in that area or they come in close
uh
if they arrive at close times together
it's not gonna work
because if the cart picks up one slime
there'll still be another slime on the
pressure plate and it will never get
that off
state you know which we need to
trigger the trap door again so
we need to be able to control it and rs
latch allows us to do that
hopefully this is the rates
rate state here so it's off right now
sorry grass it's still gonna be off yeah
we'll just put this here for now
okay so this will go to
i'm gonna hook that up to
the redstone torch here
okay i i decided to block off this
elevator temporarily
uh with the new mob ai they're actually
able to find their way
all the way down it's and uh
i heard one walk on the pressure plate
and it freaked me out
hopefully he's not in the cave somewhere
might have been a creeper i didn't hear
any noise
besides the elevator getting triggered
i got a slime being held at the moment
so we could test this
uh i got the rsnor latch hooked up to
that torch so i got one two
three redstone torches here
and that goes up right to the torch
right there and that connects to the
trapdoor
i got this loaded i think we're all
ready to try it
so as soon as he hits that pressure
plate it should send off the cart
to pick them up
that's cool i like that
you know on second thoughts that our
snore latch is probably
unnecessary because this pez dispenser
and the pickup spot is so close together
it's
probably only like a five second delay
or so maximum
i don't think it's really required in
this case
because we would need a second slime to
come within that five seconds
to cause a problem and i really doubt
that would happen
however i'm gonna leave the rs door
latch just because it's a little bit
more professional
way of dealing with the situation
and now we need to hook up a reset for
it
so i'll probably use this detector here
and maybe put a little bit of a delay on
it
see wire will be here
the detectors right above
it sounds like we've got another one
this pez dispenser will hold uh
what is it i think six carts which is
probably
sufficient i don't think we'll get more
slimes than that
let's see how do i want to do this
i want a little bit of a delay but not
much
yeah that connects if i do that
i just will go over
a little bit more info about my job so
there's lots of different types of
greenhouses i guess
out of stone bricks
in my greenhouse we sell bedding plants
so
flowers mostly vegetable plants like
tomato
tomato plants and that we sell as well
february to april is our growing or our
planting and growing season
and then in may we open up to the public
and then people
come and buy plants for their homes
to make them more pretty
and whatnot so during may
is real really crazy
uh let's see
yeah because we have like actual hours
that were open
and
i think this is okay now we got our
reset and i guess i'll just make this
drop off and go
straight to
the loop slime will probably take fall
damage from that i'm not sure
come on i gotta hit there we go perfect
heights
almost uh yeah we open to the public
so most of my work involves restocking
and helping customers answering their
questions
requires a lot of knowledge about
different types of plants
and also work on the till
i'm a clerk as well and
but it's not like you know your
department store
clerk job there's no barcodes or
anything you gotta
know all the prices and be good at math
and whatnot
and be friendly with customers you gotta
be really patient mostly customers
are retired and elderly they don't know
how to use debits
and stuff like that so you gotta be
really patient with them
and yeah it's a decent job
then after after made there's
renovations and stuff that usually need
to be done
so i have a little bit of a construction
knowledge as well and
uh there's lots of odd jobs
related to it as well cleanup and
let's see you basically got to be a
master of all
all types of different skills for the
job i do
not a master but have basic knowledge of
quite a
bit of stuff
all right and it's a nice job but i do
prefer the youtube thing over
that type of work so i'm really looking
forward to being done
youtube's actually fun and that's more
of a
job job
um probably don't need
no we don't need that many
yeah we'll just uh do regular rail
now i'm pretty sure that drop will cause
fall damage
to the slimes i could be wrong
we'll see if they survive
and that will send it right down there
okay let's head up i think we got
another one in there
yep so we will switch this
manually
oh no we no
sent another one he's fine he's going
why did it send another cart
okay i'll have to watch that video back
i wasn't expecting that
uh but that's the effect in case you've
never seen it
of them going around the tree farm
it's got their head poking out like that
they can
push you around looks pretty cool
yeah so i got some tweaking to do with
this thing the last slime i sent
suffocated two carts got sent out again
it might be the delay i have on our
snore latch
or i may just need to rip it out totally
i don't know
and i also see that the
large slime stopped for some reason
so don't know what to do about that or
why it happened
it's close to the corner
as far as i know if the chunk unloads
the slime should keep going
although i'm sure he would have
despawned before that so it's like he
hit something
i don't know got some tweaking to do
i gotta go to bed though so
i'm gonna call this episode and end for
today we got a bit done on this
at least and i'm gonna go check out
minecraft on xbox 360. it came out today
uh i said i was going to get it and
curious to see how it is some of you
might remember i made
a auto hotkey script
for playing minecraft with your xbox
360 controller on the pc
a long long time ago i'm curious to see
how
they mapped out the buttons in
the 360 version compared to how i mapped
the mouse
in my script and just to see how the
game is
period although i don't really expect to
play it much on the xbox i'm just
supporting mojang and i'm curious to see
how the game is but i don't plan on
recording it or anything
anyway that's it for today thanks for
watching everybody
and i will see you again
whenever i see you again