[Music]
hello
hello testing123 can you hear me
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back guys
to our let's play series here uh yeah
we're in a little bit of an audio crisis
mode right now
some of you have noticed that uh
yeah these last couple episodes my voice
has sounded kind of crummy
it's it's been uh popping it's been
peaking
it's been percolating all doing all
kinds of nasty stuff i hope
uh i kind of got it straightened out
here though um
yeah i'm not exactly sure what caused it
like it's it's confusing me a bit
because i
i went into surgery mode a couple days
ago i tried to fix my
old broken headsets like i have two old
broken headsets i tried to fix one of
them
i took all the tape off of it got rid of
all the nasty glue that is liquefied and
is this like a sticky slimy coating on
my headset it doesn't actually hold
anything anymore
it just gets gets in my hair and this is
gross
and yeah padding's falling apart like
i've talked about
got rid of all that garbage i uh got
some good super glue
and i bonded it together seemed to hold
really well actually
and then i also re-taped it again
and it was supposed to be good i thought
it was going to be good
it was like a brand new headset i was
really excited about it but then when i
started using it
it sounded terrible and you guys picked
up on it as well
so yeah so now i've tried doing the same
to my other one
and it still sounded kind of crummy so i
almost think it's an issue with my
windows
changing my audio settings on me without
telling me
like it likes to do um but i've also
tried lowering the volume now so
hopefully it's not peaking and doing
some some nasty stuff anyways this will
be a trial
uh we are now in the
16w068 snapshot guys new snapshot came
out
uh today when i'm recording this what am
i doing here what do we want to do
sp speed potions let's grab some speed
potions
yeah one of the big changes they made
again they decided to redo
how they do the the tipped arrows the
new arrows in the game
so let's put these in here
i think this will work yeah there's
actually a crafting recipe for it
because you know how they made it so
you're supposed to shoot the arrows into
a lingering potion before they got rid
of that now you just need
uh the lingering potion of your choice
and eight arrows around it
i thought this would work
wait did i do this reverse hey you
get out of here
i might have done this reverse is this
the output
or the inputs maybe i got to put them on
this side
let's put them in here oh yeah this is
it
this is it this is what we want now
they're going in
uh these are not brewing though
do you have to do it on splash potions
i've done this like once
total i i can't even remember how to do
it now
yeah it is splash potions so i got uh
eight minute ones in here
hey why is the shooting bottles out
oh do the dragon breath
oh these must release the bottle after
it consumes it right
is that what's happening yeah because
there's a bottle there there's one up
there now
um in in the 1.9 snapshots
i think it's redstone that's killing the
the frame well it's not frames the the
tick rate of the
the server whatever let's shut this off
notice how long it takes to lever to
switch
and see if it improves now
that wasn't too bad
oh actually it takes the redstone quite
a while to shut off on this lab
but yeah it takes the eight minute
potion converts it to a two minute
lingering potion
they mean the chest there we go then we
can take these and we can make arrows
out of them
yeah it's still super laggy
um
oh man somebody said it was an nvidia
issue
all i'd all i hope is that they fix this
before they officially
release 1.9 because if uh if they don't
i probably
am going to be very sad but yeah this is
the new recipe so
eight arrows around whatever type you
want you can do it with any type of
lingering potion
which is pretty cool and since we got a
lab that auto brews stuff
uh these are actually pretty convenient
for us to make so yeah i've been trying
to figure out what practical use can we
get out of these tipped arrows guys
because honestly in like single-player
survival
they are not the most uh beneficial
thing to the game
they're more for servers like where you
have more than one person or for mini
games or for
custom maps could have a lot of
applications for him
but in single-player like
i don't know i don't know what we'd
really use them for
um speed the swiftness ones
are actually kind of cool though because
you'll notice we have 64 of them stacked
together here
which is a big big deal it is a really
big deal
i don't know like i've i've done some
stuff with the potions in the past right
like this horse thing for example
let's get this guy out of here horses
are messed up in the snapshot again
they like move really quickly
like they their head bounces up and down
quickly
they move kind of slow and they can't
jump
but yeah anyways so we set up this thing
in here
that automatically will shoot swiftness
potions
and we got a bunch of storage back there
to contain them all and when it runs out
i got to refill it which
involves like moving you know 20 of them
at a time usually and
it's it's a lot of hassle but with this
a single stack
is 64. that is actually pretty
cool should we
take all these out i wonder because i
think i'm gonna be using these from now
on
oh man this thing was full maybe i
shouldn't have done that
oh now we have no storage all right
let's drop them off here
and like to get a 72 arrows i think only
takes three dragons breath so it's
it's not bad oh man i'm gonna do it
again
i'm trying to clean up around here now
i'm putting down more chests
all right yeah i gotta get rid of all
these though because was that a fish on
the ground
how long has that been there for um
yeah we gotta get rid of all these so
it'll actually shoot the arrow though
there we go finally out
okay so now if this guy's here and we
trigger this
does it give him the speed boost
what's the button this one that's the
one and does it damage him it does
damage him he's a heart and a half down
but he does have the speed
boost all right uh next question i have
here is does it damage
us that's kind of important as well
let's take off our protection gear here
okay yeah we got arrows
it does so that was a heart and a half
as well right pretty sure
but it did give us the full min of a
speed boost which is cool
and i'm pretty sure let's try this as
well
pretty sure you can shoot yourself with
these
like you can with normal arrows right
let's put these on
oh and let's check the durability on our
armor too so right now
pants are 492.
all right that refreshed the speed
potion we're back up to a minute
491 so it does take durability off your
armor if you do that
kinda sucks did it damage us though i
didn't notice let's try that again
yes yes it did yeah we're half a heart
down
right wait let's try that again
maybe i was already half heart down i'm
very bad at paying attention to details
no it's it's hurting us this is a
powerful bow
and infinity doesn't work with these
anymore
right yeah so it consumes arrows but you
can pick them up again
okay i got a couple more things to try
here and some more arrows
uh today's a goof around episode by the
way i don't know if we're gonna build
anything
kind of want to go to the end and get
some more dragon's breath like a whole
ton of it
so might might fight the dragon and i
kind of want to go get a backup elytra
wing today too
if we can so we might go look look
around the fortresses
um yeah let's try out some things here
i'm curious like if you have instant
health
and you shoot a horse does that damage a
horse
this might kill him actually this is a
strong bow
yeah it damages the horse he's almost
dead
okay um
yeah interesting
what about us i should have took my deer
off
or should i this might kill us
so if you're full health probably don't
want to shoot yourself with one of these
interesting okay the other question i
have
uh how do we do this so like
zombie pigmen this is a bad idea by the
way don't try this
zombie pigmen and do not take damage
from instant damage
potions but i'm guessing they're going
to because they're getting shot by an
arrow here right
this is what makes me regret life
oh we one shot him it did kill him
it did kill him so it didn't heal them
do we have any more if you one shot them
they don't get mad at you either
so i got a couple more of these guys
let's try this again
i almost think the damage actually does
damage these guys
like the damage effect it ignores the
fact that they're zombies right
because we one shot that fool
yeah we're one-shotting these guys the
damage to i think does
six hearts which would make these
very good arrows oh okay it's not a
guaranteed
not guaranteed oh there's one by me
ah i do have my armor on
that was a manly stream very manly
uh i wanted to try this as well
in case this happened so invisibility
it does nothing i missed
i do not want to make them invisible
there we go
i'm not sure if that even works on
zombie pigments i kind of doubt it does
but it's supposed to make it so mobs
can't see you
and they definitely see me still
yeah i'm pretty sure that doesn't
there's a lot of things with potions
i've never tried before i
i i have realized today so i'm kind of
playing around with it a bit okay was
there anything else that's gonna try
poison
oh man this is getting scary okay
it's all good oh
poison potion did not work or did it
i don't think it did
let's try that again
poison potion did not work on these guys
yeah i'm not too sure guys i'm having a
hard time telling
like with normal arrows one-shotted
that's a two-shotter the power four bow
[Music]
can't quite keep up killing them
two shots i think we might have shot
that guy before oh
oh as a sneaky guy
all right and then let's switch the
instant damage once again
with my armor on
no damage really
one heart okay
they don't seem to really affect me
that's kind of odd
i thought that would have done a lot of
damage to us even with a weak shot
hey you as a two shot
the instant health ones here should be
wrecking them though
oh man annoying guests but these are
also taking more than one shot
that was one shot
again a manly stream
the potion effects aren't really doing
anything on these guys right
i can't really notice much of a
difference
okay now i'm really curious so i decided
let's hop into creative here let's just
do it right
it's a lot easier to test this way so
zombie regular arrows
one two three four
five six seven all right
zombie again we will give um damage
arrows damage to one
two three four five
six seven okay those are the ones that
should heal them
they they work just like regular arrows
as far as i can tell
okay instant health
one two three four
five six seven so they're all the same
that's the one that should do a lot of
damage to them
ah what else do we try regen
see if regen has any effect
that should be like poison
pretty sure it was the same as a normal
arrow okay let's do
let's do the poison
yeah or does poison work on zombies i
can't remember i don't i don't think
oh yeah maybe it does maybe it does
i'm confused now you know what we're in
creative we can test it
poison let's do a real potion
i think it it works right
oh no it doesn't okay damage
one two three four
five six seven ah it looks like the same
right
let's try instant health one
two three four five
six seven okay
so basically they don't they don't work
right am i missing something
maybe they're working progress still oh
poison does work on villagers
water breathing arrow oh
there we go water breathing works
slowness slowness works
swiftness
swiftness works it works jump boost 2.
this one's this one's hard to test
doesn't work on slimes
doesn't work on guardians
oh he's jumping pretty high
i think it works on rabbits
fire resistance
yep let's try regen 2 on ourselves
see if there's any practical value to it
we gained like half a heart maybe
it only lasts two seconds is the problem
i think it needs to be
like buffed up to at least five seconds
so we're back in the lp world now a
little bit of a crisis situation i went
through this portal
to see where it went because i wasn't
exactly sure it goes to the dark oak
forest this is where we got our
uh first dark oak sampling from
uh but here's the problem
i can't get back
like for for realsies it's not letting
me through the portal anymore
i guess we'll try the enderpearl trick
and hope it works
please 500.
oh we actually ended up in an
underground lake here
okay oh man look at my character
alright uh yes welcome to minecraft
we are 63
which means we're right at the surface
beautiful
do i recognize this spot
i have no clue where we are but it's a
lot closer to than walking back from
where we were
um yeah all right anyways i'm gonna
get ready for the dragon fight
uh that i want to do all right uh yeah
let's
summarize the potion thing too i guess
not that way
i should figure out which way i have to
go first
is it this way i think it's this way uh
so most the potions do
actually work uh it's just the
instant health and instant damage ones
are broken at the moment it seems i
don't think that's intended
and uh regen does not cause a poison
effect on undead monsters like it should
and uh the leaping or the jumping potion
does not work like you would expect
uh for most monsters like the slimes and
the guardians do not get a
buff from it but otherwise everything
seems to be pretty good with it
all right this all looks like it's in
order very good
and we're back home
all right here we go guys so yeah we're
going to do the dragon fight
the goal is to get like a lifetime
supply
of uh
what was that sound that was a new one
i think it was a witch right it kinda
sounded like water
yeah we're gonna try to get a life
lifetime supply of uh dragon's breath
and also
i wanna see the the whole sequence of
the the dragon fight again
ender crystals let's do this right
put them on the four corners of the
portal
all right let's let's grab a snack
before we do it uh
i hope nothing gets destroyed
[Music]
oh yeah and then it responds all the
crystals again
oh man this is crazy there's no escape
right does it kill the portal yeah it
does kill the portal
so i gotta actually beat the dragon if i
want to get out of here
all right or i could kill myself
either is fine we have like chests and
stuff in the end that we i could drop
off my items
all right here is the dragon
this is what we want this stuff here
okay let me select
number five you hear it
so we basically gotta firm the dragon
here for a little bit
how many did we get six oh my goodness
this might take a while
i guess while i wait i can i can take
out the crystals and stuff
it does spawn on snow but
we're gonna land nope
oh yeah this stuff does hurt you
seems to only get six every time
oh oh she's landing
she does land
can't grab that oh that hurt oh that
really hurt
okay wait maybe i don't want to do that
she's loud
all right let's grab what we can hear
this is where you really get a good
harvest
when she does this ouch
all right don't kill me i just want your
precious stinky breath here
can i grab this no she's not moving at
all
oh here she goes okay can't get grab any
of this what are we up to now 54.
always in the same spot that makes it
convenient
just gotta be careful you don't get too
close to her because then you will get
wrecked
all right that's another good batch
and maybe one more yeah
man i got a lot that time
you can get pretty much a stack like
every time she does this
thank you
oh yeah good harvest good harvest okay
taking damage
oh
i got sucker punched no
ah really
that sucks this is weird you can see
yourself when you sleep in the bed now
like your feet little difference
okay so she doesn't destroy items though
right just blocks
if i'm if i remember correctly so
hopefully i can get my stuff back here
and all the all the dragon's breath
i do not want to lose my elytra wings
above all else
um i think it was around the middle
right yeah we were right at the portal
when she killed us
don't don't hit me yeah there's there's
all this stuff
good good a pumpkin
is extremely helpful while doing this by
the way
like usually oh there they are good
usually i don't bother with
oh
maybe i should have paid attention to
her
but i didn't really think much of it
don't do it don't do it don't do it
this time let's put the armor on as soon
as we get it
wings excellent
she after me she never like uh swoops
down to get you
anymore like while she's in this phase
at least oh
except when i'm apparently trying to get
my stuff back that's
the only time she's ever done it
what gives man like she has never
swooped down i've been in here for
half an hour i lose all my stuff and now
she starts doing it
i don't know something fishy
all right did we get everything back i
think we may
oh i gotta put my helmet on oops
this is how you farm iron bars by the
way
oh actually if you don't fall down after
each of these crystals
you can just hop from one tower to the
next but i missed
darn it
iron bars
yeah this one's like right here
see is that all of them i think i might
have got them all
right right let's go fly and figure it
out
man i love having elijah wings for this
fight
i flew right into her yeah it looks like
we got them all
i'm just gonna finish getting uh
they didn't spawn on these further out
ones it's just uh the ring around the
middle there yeah i think we're ready to
go
i'm gonna get the rest of the dragon's
breath i want here and then i'm gonna
kill her
so we just about got these all filled up
yeah angry dragon
oh that's it we got it all filled up
okay
now we killed her i wanted to try
spectral arrows
just bounced off what
oh can you not attack her when she's
doing that that might be what it is
i forget you can uh you can hit
her with the sword but man did i take
damage
no i don't think you can hit the head
either man
like right right in her face oh hello
oh that was crazy i just got launched
right up in the air
i don't know what happened there
i'm just gonna kill her with the bow i i
know i'm gonna die if i i keep trying to
like get her
when she's on the the pit is still here
last time i did this fight you could
just walk up to her and melee her but it
doesn't seem to work anymore
so this is a oh man she keeps doing that
like i think she lands and then she
automatically takes off when i'm not
paying attention
that's what it is if you turn your back
on her when she's on the pedestal i
think she takes off automatically
[Music]
let's put the theory to test so we're
gonna turn around
yeah and she takes off
that is awesome because otherwise you
gotta wait for the whole thing
and that can take up to a minute
sometimes this has been a really long
fight so far
okay this might do it turn around and
oh come on one more hit
there we go oh oh no no no no
oh she almost got me i wasn't paying
attention my health
okay this is it this is finally gonna be
it
okay she landed killed anderman
oh that time she took off right away
while looking at her
but we got her
that took very very long guys
if you thought the dragon fight was long
before i think it's even longer now
oh my goodness yeah i've been in here
for
almost two hours i think mostly
collecting dragon's breath but
that fight took a while too and well
taking the crystals down is
is quite the thing but yeah anyways we
got her we got
we got our dragon's breath the portals
back let's see if it made
another one of those uh portals to the
outer islands so we got one
over there i think that's a new one up
over there
where's our other one i was hoping they
wouldn't
spawn side by side yeah the other one's
on the opposite end that's awesome
so now i can reach some more islands
nice and conveniently cool
uh we kind of are running along here
though so i don't think i'm gonna go
look for elytra wings today uh we'll
probably have to wrap it up now
so the comment of the day for today guys
is in regards to the horse breeding
project that we got going on here it
says etho the breeding of a better
jumper
is nearly impossible at this point on
our server we have amazing horses
this is not by breeding but by going out
into the wild and testing
every horse we see we have a 5.5 jumper
those can never be bred with anything
other than
5.5 jumpers 15 health max same thing and
possibly the fastest horse in the game
but that hard to really test yes
point is stop breeding for better stats
that only works if they suck to begin
with go
and find better horses
all right yes that that is generally
true in my case here though
the reason we're doing this whole thing
is because
my world is about 500 gigs right now
i do not want to go explore anymore
unless we're
really looking for new content in the
game that was released or something
but yeah at the moment it takes forever
to do a backup
it takes forever to restore backup takes
up a lot of space to
to keep them all i don't want a bigger
world so exploring for more horses
is not really what i want to do we have
tried to make a passive
mob farm but we failed to do it because
we would have to deface the whole area
here because we'd have to remove all the
grass which would take forever
and also we have so many entities in the
spawn chunks that have to destroy my cow
farm
rabbit farm pig farm all the farms
in order to get any new horses to spawn
so
this was our last choice and
it is possible to get up to at least a
5.4 jumper
i'm pretty sure because how it works is
it takes the stats of the parents so
let's say
mama over here is a a two block high
jumper and
papa is a two block jumper so it would
be two plus two
and then it randomizes the stats of the
baby so it's going to be i think between
1.5 and 5.5
so let's say it is what's an easy number
let's say the baby random stats is a
five
block jumper so that would equal nine
and then it takes the stats of those
three divides it by
three so it would be nine divided by
three and then the baby would be a three
block jumper so that's an improvement of
one block
um and you keep doing that eventually
you get to the point where it's going to
be like a 5.4
plus a 5.4 and let's say the baby is a
5.5
extremely unlikely it might equal
5.5 it might round up
uh but it might just be a 5.4 at the
most
i'm not sure but it is possible that's
what i'm getting at here and we're kind
of doing this
to see how difficult it was to do that i
can say
like above four blocks it is extremely
difficult to breed a higher jumper
you have to do it many times and also to
see if it's possible to
to reach 5.4 5.5 whatever the
max is actually and i'm going to keep
trying
anyways thank you guys for watching i
hope you enjoyed today's episode
and i will see you again in the next one
take care bye-bye can you drink these
you can't drink these