hello hello everybody how's it going
what's going on what's new how's the
family everything good I hope it's all
good uh branch buy and I'm sorry going
to the branch mine again just I built
something here I want to show you or I'm
building in the process of building
something not related to the branch why
I just built it down in the branch mines
so don't worry about that
so it goes off to the left here now this
is new and if you can figure out what
this is before I tell you I will be very
impressed I'll tell you that because
it's a very simple thing but I've made
it very complicated very needlessly and
it's not necessarily a practical thing
I'm building here it's more doing it for
the fun of it I don't know if I'll
actually end up using it very much it's
so weird that block is flickering the
redstone one or to me it is anyway yeah
okay so down here is what I'm doing um
yeah if you can figure this out I'll be
impressed but I just want to show you
the wiring before I seal it up here and
so the wiring comes down the staircase
from this thing up here this is a it's
called a tea bud so what people named it
the bud switch that's a T flip-flop
basically so it's connected or it's
right below of this redstone block so at
this moment let's go down one more time
see this repeaters on if we right-click
on this you heard that
this is now off and it's going to stay
off for a little while I'm around them
random is your mount of time and then
it's going to come back on and this will
retract okay probably don't want to wait
around to watch it but that's what's
going to happen and then what we're
going to do so we got all these pistons
here which are going to hold water back
I think we're going to give them a
special delay just for a little bit of a
cool factor so we'll keep this middle
one on one then we'll switch these two
too and then the very side ones we will
put two three should be good this is
still off shits which still glowing and
see it's a little bit lighter right now
and now we got to connect these together
pay attention to this to this will make
a little bit more sense in a little
while here okay
good I have some on me I'm going to
connect this all together there so now
the pistons should be hooked up to this
well that's that's taking a really long
time to switch I'm surprised I oh I
can't get out of here can i nuts
um mm-hmm I hate to just destroy stuff
randomly here yeah it's a good thing I
showed you this because we're probably
not going to be coming back down here
and still on this it's taking a while
okay so we're going to close this all up
and
put water in over here and one over
there one there and one over there grab
a little bit more and the water flows
all go to this very edge here I really
hope that switches soon that's a crazy
amount of time that's been on okay well
I'll be back once it switches alright it
finally switched here it happened about
fifteen or thirty seconds after I
stopped recording and now we're going to
fill this in and I was looking at this
and I think I should really put a piston
here - so mr. Peter will go to this
block this wire and then it'll also
control a sticky piston right in between
these pumpkins I think that I'll make it
cooler do that and we'll put another one
here right over here
yeah I don't know how effective this is
going to be but I'm having fun building
it at least okay so we got that and then
finally I'll show you this Oh nuts you
got to be kidding me
didn't work
ah I'll be right back what's wrong now
ah I'll be right back ok I've spied the
problem it's right over here this
repeater sends power to this block and
there's that piston above it but it's
also sending power back to that wire and
it's making a continuous loop so it
never shuts off so we just have to move
this I guess over here probably work
something like that and ooh get bad
burps that one was gross yeah that
should work all right cover this again
and now let me right click beautiful
okay next thing I guess we'll put chest
down here here here here here here there
whoop and there then in the middle I
don't know what to do about the middle
sure maybe put wood or something I don't
know almost need this one to come up to
this looks fairly cool I like it so
that's what we're trying to get for over
here now and I figured out what I can do
to make it work is just a real nightmare
working out the wiring so what I did
there used to be Pistons all across here
now I loved the middle one and replace
it with this sticky piston and that
should work and now I'm going to also
put a sticky piston right here
apparently I can't place it
there we go okay right below that torch
and now I can put a block here and it
will go down when the water comes out
water goes over there okay and we'll
have a block here probably just stone I
will wait to put it though so what I got
to do now is run a redstone torch off
that block and run it to this one so I
can't actually get over there now so
that's how we're going to do it and
we'll go underneath
I think that's right I think right over
here should do it like that I hope and
we'll go back ouch oh where am I now
oh I didn't make it darn there we go
okay so now we can hopefully yeah so
that went underneath that block to that
torch so we can put one here bridge the
gap and I think all should be fine now I
hope and this should at the same timing
because we have two torches and that's
the same as going through this to this
so now all three of these will be time
the same okay yes that was good um so
put that back put this back and that
will just do it without the water first
see what it looks like I'm going to use
half slabs like that and what should
happen is that that and that should all
go down
excellent okay and that one went down so
now instead of the piston being over
there it's below that block so perfect
so I'm going to put the water back in
and this should be done finally
and when you find out what this is for
you're going to be like did you
seriously waste all your time doing that
and I'm going to be like yeah it's going
to be great okay I changed a few things
down below here as well I realized I'm
going to need a bunch of chests down
here for sure so I switch that over I'm
going to put wood all around here and I
left this open just so you can see
what's behind this these wood slabs
and I'm finally gonna tell you what this
is for maybe you figure it out already
and I'm very impressed if you did I was
watching b2b double O's let's play today
and he gave me inspiration for this
project basically he said and this is
true if you make a boat out of this
redwood or any of the new planks and
then break it you get regular planks
that's what this is for
it's to converts the other type of
planks into regular planks but this
comes at a cost as well
you get three wooden planks and two
sticks instead of five of the exotic
other planks alright so there is some
loss involved but the thing is I can
harvest jungle trees very very quickly
because I do a two by two tree grow it
with bone meal ender pearl to the top of
it and then just use my amazing axe and
cut my way down and I can get about ten
stacks of the jungle wood in like 15
minutes or so I found and that's what I
was doing when I started building all
this and then they introduced these new
plank types and now I can only get the
red ones from that and I have to harvest
the regular oak trees to get the type of
planks I need which is taking me a lot
longer so I'm still harvesting the
jungle trees and I've been just stacking
and like that to mimic wood wood planks
right but I'm finding that takes a
little while to place them all
especially at the top here which is
probably where I want regular planks the
most this top grid
and I think I think I'm gonna call this
a sawmill by the way I that's probably a
fitting name I think I can still harvest
jungle trees convert them to regular
planks like this quicker than I can
harvest oak trees I'm not sure even if I
can't this is just for fun but that's
the idea behind it that we're going to
do a test here and just see how well
this works in just a second in order for
this to be quicker like the time we
invest in to convert into crafting boats
and breaking them and losing that little
bit of wood that has to be faster than
just spending extra time growing oak
trees and cutting them down and it might
be I'm not sure the whole point of this
is to make crafting boats as quick as
possible destroying them as quickly as
possible and then collecting all the
resources as quick as possible
that's the whole point behind this and
we have 18 chests here I'm going to
empty my inventory before we get started
okay I got my inventory empty pretty
much and we're going to go through some
of the numbers behind all this there is
18 chests here and there is nine and a
half stacks of the jungle wood here okay
eighteen chess holds 486 boats which is
about how many boats nine and a half
stacks of the jungle wood converts into
and that is two thousand four hundred
and thirty red planks and that gets
converted into 1458 regular planks when
you break the boat plus nine hundred and
seventy two sticks so that's what this
all works out too assuming we feel all
these chests up and the main issue with
all of this is inventory management so
that's what this is all about up here
down there is just for breaking them
major like so the quickest way to make
boats I think is to shift click on wood
range your boats but when you shift
click on the boat it only makes as many
as you have inventory space for right
now you could go down there and destroy
all those but that would involve
manually moving it to that spot then you
place it and then you'll have to move
another one down there and it will take
a long time to do right so ideally what
you want is to have a ton of outs on the
ground right at your feet and every time
you right-click a new boat that's at
your feet will go in the exact same spot
so you can just hold right click
hopefully but that's the thing we need a
whole bunch of boats on the ground bias
to keep that going so we got to fill up
all these chests and then when we're
ready we break them all and there'll be
hundreds of boats on the ground
hopefully the game will be able to
handle it and right-click that the water
will push all the boats down into one
spot nice a nice distance away from the
breaking area and I should be able to
just right click and get a bunch of
planks from it that's the idea behind
all this I don't know how well it all
work
just for fun anyway but yeah I think the
quickest way of making boats is to do
that really only need 32 or so at a time
and get rid of them out of your
inventory very quick this way just by
spamming like this so I'll fill these up
I'm going to make a backup of my world
just in case
I accidentally crash it or something and
we will see how this works out
okay here comes the fun part I got these
awful votes now and we're about to
harvest them all should be fun and that
took me about five minutes to craft them
all and put them in these chests so that
is a bit of time and you add that to the
15 minutes it took to get the wood the
jungle woods that is 20 minutes total so
far so the only thing left is the
destroying time and yeah here we go
umm might only be able to do half at a
time I'm not sure
backup is made casus it gets crazy still
30 frames per second
no it's dropping dropping 10 or 20
frames per second
oh yeah I felt that there's a lot of
boats Wow
okay here we go
well that retract it quick so that only
needs to do the water only needs to be
running long enough for all the boats to
fall down let's see how many are left up
there actually one two two got stuck in
the wall for some reason okay here we go
see if I can hold right click I can
awesome oh that's so cool
oh and the frame rate is dropping more
and more down to 12 11 10 8 7 6 5 okay
I'm gonna stop recording yes the
nightmare I think I figured out what I
need to do though to prevent that from
happening again I need to fill my
inventory slots with this
single thing of planks like this so I
can walk up collect it and then prevent
leg planks and sticks
I'm just trying oh I got it all good
almost lost a bunch of wood there from
that because it was lagging so bad I
couldn't really deal with it but I think
managed to save it so in the future
that's probably all I need to do yeah so
I like this this is pretty cool all
right I'll clean it up here this is what
we got that works out to 1161 planks and
774 sticks so we lost a few of them
somewhere I'm guessing what happened is
they fell into the piston arms when I
broke the chest and got stuck down down
there there there and there so might be
an issue
oh well so then we would replace all the
chests here I'll show you the water
streams though before I do so that's
what happens pretty cool but yeah it's
probably going to take me 20 to 25
minutes to do all that and that's about
equivalent harvesting five to six stacks
of oak wood so pretty sure I could do
that in 20 to 25 minutes we might try
that a little bit here see how how long
it takes so one of the rumors I've heard
with the recent patch is I don't know if
it's true or not we're going to check it
now is that it's a lot easier to grow
these oak trees if they're in a line
either by the Sun or using bonemeal so
we'll see what happens here hopefully we
don't get a big one oh it is I don't
believe it
so before if you did that you would use
usually between 10 and 30 bonemeal to
try to grow one tree
I guess it's yeah so everything I just
built pretty much very unpractical but
it was all for fun so I don't care so
yeah that's the way to do it then you
just go right down and I may actually
make an automated farm sometime soon to
do this a little quicker see because I
think maybe not the quick binding trick
I think it works on on wood - yeah yeah
it does definitely all right you do get
these branches on the side hmm anyway it
seems to work I wonder what happens if
you try to grow grow like a cube you
know what I mean so something like this
will go one row at a time
it's tough will they grow side by side
they do that is amazing and they make
this game so easy now unreal okay well I
guess jungle trees have competition
after all that is crazy
well the main issue is the leaves
getting in your face but that's not a
big problem huh it's a solid thing would
that's crazy
okay I'm going to show you one more
thing and then I'll probably in the
episode all right so that one project
gave me an idea for a pretty cool secret
door you could do and I know you guys
like secret doors and I think you'll
like this so here's our door piston door
is all put together very rough I just
want to help you visualize it a little
bit we got a wall here just ignore this
wiring should be underground and behind
the wall is this there's basically a
pressure plate
loop pressure plates and then on there's
a block in between and then over here is
a place for lab it'll fall down and
that's being held by this piston which
is also connected to the pressure plate
okay so what happens is you can use ah
am i doing oh yeah
you can use it boats as a key to your
door and basically you have a flat wall
no signs that it's a secret key key
holder or anything and you just place
your boat here
tada let's go around so one corner of
the boats on the pressure plates and the
other corner gets destroyed by the lava
coming down and this is really neat
because you can actually time how long
you want the door open very well with
this so if if you don't know lava
travels one block every 1.5 seconds
in this setup our boat is a hovering
here so the lab has to travel one two
blocks to get to it before it destroys
it that's three seconds and then you
also have the redstone torch delay so
that's 0.3 seconds there so 3.3 seconds
is how long this door stays open for so
you can very accurately control how long
you want your door open for by raising
or lowering the lava or you could just
tap it so you put the boat down and door
stays open until you destroy it
- there's lots of ways you could set it
up but I thought it was kind of cool so
I hope you enjoyed that and that is all
we're doing for today I hope you enjoyed
the episode and I want to say thank you
to everybody that left feedback - the
last episode it was very encouraging and
I have been looking at or I did a little
bit of research into whoa into video
editing different programs I could use
because I'm still using virtualdub and
I've gone about as far as I can with it
I think it would be very good for
everybody if I actually got a real
editing program I'm really good with
virtualdub now but it's just very basic
just a simple thing like a transition
like a fade in can be a nightmare with
it so it would be good if I got
something better and what I did or what
I found in my research is that CyberLink
PowerDirector is the top rated video
editing thing if that's true let me know
it could have just been a biased website
that I was looking at and it was only 50
bucks which surprised me so if that's
the best the best editor and it's only
50 bucks I got no problem dishing that
out for some reason I thought editing
programs would be to 300 bucks but I
guess they're all really cheap by the
looks of it someone has suggested I use
Adobe Premiere
and I know a lot of my buddies use Sony
Vegas so what do you think is the best
let me know because I should probably
get something better it's that time time
to improve things okay so bye bye thanks
for watching