hello how's it going everybody this is
etho just just been relaxing here
enjoying my time practicing my fishing
I'm getting better at it
apparently this still does work I just
was doing it wrong I think that the
trick is I got a pullback as soon as it
hits them like almost the same instant
like that yeah
hi I'm getting the hang of it oh no you
hit something oh well ah see if I wait
too long they do that that's no good ah
my my position here might not be the
best I think I have too because I keep
hitting that thing in the middle
it still works from up on the UFO - I
found out I just love that so much
that's awesome oh come on
so I'm so finicky about it now that you
pull him back before I should don't get
the baby cows you lose points if you get
the baby cows it's not their time yet
yeah this is this is pretty sweet up
lost the point Oh baby don't want the
babies there we go yeah pretty cool oh I
almost had a baby there that was close
accidentally got a guy up there don't
think he's ever gonna come down from
there so he's gonna guard the map from
now on um yeah it's pretty fun though 30
levels woohoo awesome we shouldn't chant
something let's go let's go and chant a
book start off with you also been
thinking about ideas for Wilson thank
you everyone that sent me feedback about
the holes him making like emotional
sounds and the music experts sort of
confirms my suspicions oh this I was
trying something here with
I was gonna name wait a sec let me let
me explain what this is about
there might be one that is named
actually let me maybe not I had a button
in these item frames and I had a button
like a real button over top that you
could press um like that um I thought
that was going to be cool like it like I
would name this button shovel put that
in it would get hidden behind the button
and then when I would hover my cursor
over top of it it would say shovel above
the button right I thought that was
going to work but it turns out when I go
to click it now it just rotates the the
button inside the item frame instead of
actually pushing the button down so that
does not work which one is booked I
think this one I named book yeah see I
name this book for some reason it also
doesn't display book all the time either
when I hover over it anyway it was a
failed idea it doesn't work so let's get
our book let's do 30 power 4 kind of
crummy not really what I wanted but that
happens um where to go I must have had I
got it here okay so UFO seems to be
working now that's great I have some fun
with that again I also took a look at my
old sheep farm over here I don't use it
very much because it's it broke sort of
right after I built it so yeah kind of
stinks I find that happens a lot
whenever I make something and put a lot
of thought into it it like will break
almost immediately afterwards it's not
super badly broken there's a few things
wrong with it now maybe I'll try to
demonstrate it so one of the things that
changed is you see how far that will hop
there before when I made this it would
only go within a 3x3 area around here
which was really important to the
design and now it just flies all over
the place and when I hit the item
collection water here let's see if it'll
happen water comes down just long enough
where it should wash all the wool down
the grates without drowning the sheep
which for the most part does happen
exactly except now I don't know why this
happens I guess it's because it's jumps
out of the 3x3 area it it goes down here
and and wool can end up in the middle
now which isn't good so I almost wonder
probably all I need to do is just have
like some slabs maybe not running down
now try to figure out how to fix it okay
the water comes down here let's just see
what happens don't kill the Sheep data
if I do that yeah you see that it's
pushing the wool then I think but oops I
bet if wool was here when it would still
get stuck
yeah just pushes it right against there
so hmm another thing I could do kind of
wreck the whole concept of the farm is
replace all these Pistons here with
hoppers and then when I shear the sheep
that would just instantly collect I
think there's another idea but then the
whole water water collection system down
there and all that's kind of pointless
if I do that whoo and also this is kind
of messy here too I might mess around
with this and see if I can come up with
a solution okay you know that might work
actually so I I did put the slabs I used
stone brick slabs to divide each of the
colors so I think like the water comes
down here so it should flow yeah it
should flow that way I think
I'm not sure I like the look of it as
much it's kind of cool like when you're
here and you're looking like this that
the dividers between the colors but when
you're off way at the end here which is
where I usually view it from it sort of
blocks the view of the Sheep
pop-up sheep farm woo especially the
ones in the back like you don't get that
nice rainbow look going down like we did
before but it might make it work so that
that will probably be what we have to do
if it does so let's try it out
it's better it's working then and like
ugly then then not working and looking
great I guess I think it's the lesser of
the two evils it's looking like yeah the
wool isn't hopping over this divider
which is good as worried about that some
of it might still land like in this path
which would be bad so let's try just
that half first and see what happens so
since they're all sheared all the peeps
go down
did I say people all the peeps go down
all the sheep should go down when I hit
the water button is the goal here we'll
go inside just to watch it so when the
wool falls down there it makes the Sheep
go down no I'm not getting them all oh
and some of its not going down that was
weird so there's two pressure plates
there's two wood pressure plates I think
like if the wool from this side jumps
over to this side it's only going to
land on that pressure plate which will
only make that sheep go down and not
just the other one I think that's what
happened there
huh interesting but it did collect it a
lot better which is what I also want and
there's I could just do a manual reset
if I want so yeah I think that'll be
okay what do you guys think of that is
it look okay or did you identify and
just not working which is the lesser of
the two evils I guess is the question
okay let's go again here you know what
guys since we got the collection system
for this working properly now for the
most part the main thing is that it
actually gets the wool I don't mind
doing this afterwards oh that guy just
came up and he's like nope going back
down rejected grow better wool next time
um like this does work I think all the
wool got collected I think yeah I don't
see any around on the ground so that's
good so I just have to run through shear
all the wool shear all the Sheep I mean
and hit the button for the water then
hit the button for the reset and I get
the wool and since we got that working
let's get this working because it
honestly if I don't fix this this room
the storage room for the wool in the
collection for the room for the wool
sorry I'm all I'm jibber jabbering I'm
still not going to use the farm because
right now the way this works that looks
cool yes I like that that's neat but
then honestly to to go through each of
these chests and put the proper type of
wool in each of the chests when you only
have like five or less of each of the
colors no I don't do that to be honest I
just I just drop and also plate wood I
just drop it off in one of the chests
usually and don't horse around with it
and it's a real pain because you can
only pick up a couple at a time usually
if your inventories full I was lucky
this time my inventory wasn't full so we
are going to put a hopper in down below
here and then do an auto collection
system and also like this was made
before
trapped chests and that so I had to vary
the chests on each of the different
heights can have them next to each other
so we should try and make it look better
too and I'll show you this in case
you're wondering since we're talking
about the sheep farm today this is this
is what we got underneath so it's a
two-stage bud system the way it worked
is when the grass would grow regrow on
the soil block it would activate one of
the buds and then when the sheep would
eat the grass it would activate the
second one and it would push a grass
block up high enough so that grass
couldn't spread to it anymore um now I'm
not exactly sure if it works the way it
used to because I think they adjusted it
where um bud switches don't detect sheep
eating grass or something they might
have might have reverted that though
because it does work somehow still so it
knows I'll I never really looked at it
though why it still works
um but yeah let's let's fix up this room
shall we um so maybe one option I like
the idea of labeling the colors for the
the Ches I don't really like the item
frames to be honest can we would it look
good if we did like all the colors below
there's one option although I do like
the stone below maybe if we put it
behind each of the chests their proper
color that would look better and we can
have trapped chests this I think it's
going to look a lot better when I want
to fix this all up like that
okay I guess the big question is what's
behind here if I break this can I put
wool back here I think I can I think
we're safe too so for example I'll mask
my inventory is such a mess so for
example we would maybe replace these two
blocks with white wool or the wool for
each of the chests
oh don't lose those hoppers so it looked
like that white wool in the background
and I'll do like right here I don't have
a wool chest in my storage room anymore
so this is where I keep it
that might be cool let me try that oh
wow
this game it's either really trolling me
or there's a reason for this or I don't
know this okay so I looked into the
sheep farm as I'm building this I'm like
I wonder how many sheep every grown
their wool by now I look every single
light every sheep on the on the that's a
right I meant left every single light on
the left and every sheep was was up was
popped up in every single one on the
right the light was off and there was no
sheep up so that's starting to change
now now there's some on the right
there's one two three at least so either
crazy chance that they all came up on
the left before the ones on the right or
there's a reason like a directional
reason that they're not popping up on
the right as quick I think the game's
just trolling me because I spent five to
ten minutes below there looking at the
wiring trying to figure out what I
wrecked while building this this room
like making the changes because we we
opened up into the wire room back there
when I was breaking this I thought I
reckon that was crazy anyway so here we
go this is I think this will do okay
yeah I think so
another option just thought of this wait
a minute can't decide how I wanted to do
this maybe let's just check this out I
couldn't decide if I wanted to put like
stone slabs the white ones here or
stairs or what to do with that because I
do like the look of the bottom being
equal to the top but I don't like the
look of the full wool blocks so another
option how this would look this is just
stupid mmm now I think I like it more
with this stone yeah anyway so this is
what we got going on now for the
collection system maybe let's cheer them
one more time or a few of them anyway so
you just run along click click click
there is a total of 32 sheep in here I
believe so that's quite a bit of wool
that's over a stackable every time I
share them if I share them all ok let's
do just that side since it seems to
regrow faster for some reason run back
and water system for the collection so
this chest I have a central collection
chest here which is empty right now and
I believe the wool should start popping
up in here
give it time let's get a long ways to
travel should show up any minute oh here
we go here we go that took a lot longer
than I was expecting
it's running on ice it should be quick
but yeah it'll fill up and it'll sort
itself and then when there's like sixty
four of a color I can easily just pick
it up out of there and put in the proper
chests so that should be cool
it seemed to be missing a fair bit of
the wool five colors only and we shoot
them all what's that about and we
dropped a little bit here and ah the
sheep farm it does not want to work so
that must mean the wool got lost
somewhere down here right one second
I'll see if I can find it I really don't
know I thought it would be on these
pressure plates but I'm not picking it
up white was definitely one of the
colors that didn't get picked up it's
nowhere up there
can't find it down here which means it
must have gotten stuck down there
somewhere ah I'm not looking forward to
breaking all this oh man
I don't have a clue it doesn't exist
anywhere it's gone ah some of the wall
did get stuck in these droppers the
black did so that's accounted for I
don't think this was all the light gray
that dropped anyway this is the way I
did the elevator the item elevator if
there is an item well from the hopper
here all the wool goes down the stream
lands onto this hopper right you throw
let's throw in all our planks here okay
that turns this comparator on as it
funnels in that activates this clock
thing and that points into all the
droppers so it's really simple actually
but it seems to work pretty good as
actually surprised some got stuck in the
droppers because in all my testing here
you can see they're all empty so it just
must it must be because there is a a
single piece that went in or something I
don't know but the white and the light
gray it is gone oops not a clue where it
went like gray there's and ray where was
it gray
we missed out on three colors in that
harvest that was I'll have to keep my
eye on that alright everybody so one
more thing before we end this maybe
let's just spend a little time with
Wilson talking about Wilson maybe do a
thing or two here too so I hooked up a
wire from the cow sensor the player
sensor so when we're in the area
this wire pulses sort of randomly if
we're over thirty two blocks away from
the tower down there this stays off all
the time but looking at this at the
speeded pulses I think I'm just going to
hook this up directly to his happiness
so
every time it pulses his happiness goes
up by one and he has a range of zero to
fifty happiness so it would take 50 of
these pulses to take them from zero all
the way up to full so when we're in the
area he'll slowly get a little bit
happier over time but you can see it's
not very frequent that it goes so I
think it's a good rate so that'll be one
more way to increases happiness ed yes
yeah it's pretty slow pretty slow going
here and also yeah I start talking about
the whole note block thing thank you
everyone that sent a response on that
the musical geniuses have informed me
why the idea it won't really work the
way I wanted it like I wanted to make
actual creature sounds by combining
Knobloch Knobloch sounds like if we
could activate maybe twenty four to
thirty no blocks all within half a
second maybe we could make it a tune
that sounds like a creature roaring or
something kind of like cow the Pokemon
sound on the old Gameboy but it turns
out okay speaking of no blocks
do-do-do-do-do thanks for interrupting
um what was I saying this stupid note
blocks man uh I actually really like
that thing still but the timing between
repeaters is just too long like it's a
tenth of a second apparently and you
couldn't really continue the tune
throughout because of that delay it's a
little too long and also the range of
pitch probably the most important thing
isn't very big in Minecraft so very
limited on what you can do with the note
blocks and you can't really stop a tune
like partway through or anything like
that so just a lot of limitations that
won't allow it to happen but it is
possible make tunes that sound or that
convey happiness and
this and that so that's probably what
we'll do even if it doesn't sound like a
creature making noise so we can still
convey emotion with the note blocks
which is good one thing maybe today this
sandstone was just a temporary thing
i I've grown very used to it you guys
probably have to should we keep it
sandstone or should we change it I
brought red clay just to try here um try
to give Wilson a facelift if we can make
him look better if possible I don't mind
the sandstone personally but this might
look just a little bit better so let's
try this out give me a second what do
you guys think I don't know I didn't
change your background it's still
sandstone but I would use I think a
lighter color for the backgrounds maybe
quartz but I don't know if I really want
to use core so because then it would
just detract from the face detract
distract both are good words
yeah so that's red the other thing is
like if I change those stairs up there
to a full red clay block it might be
hard to see that that aged timer up
there
I don't know let me know you think
anyway here is the comments for today
first one it says hey etho I was
wondering if you add if you would ever
consider playing xbox 360 minecraft or
xbox one when it comes out keep up the
great videos they put a smile on my face
every time I watch one thank you for the
nice comment so I got minecraft on Xbox
360 right when it came out in fact I
think pause even released a video of us
playing together on it like the day of
um a long long time ago it was okay um
when I played it it was behind on the
updates quite a bit and I did not like
the controls at all I think if you have
a PC and an Xbox
you should probably play it on the PC
personally I have no interest in playing
on the on a console really just because
of the controls but if that's all you
got a console or if you just want to say
on your comfy couch and you don't have
your computer hooked up to your TV then
consoles good to getting the Xbox one
when it comes out I have no plans on
that or the ps4 I've heard nothing but
bad things about the new consoles and so
I'm going to give them a little while
and I have not seen a game that really
appeals to me yet for them so not that
I've looked I haven't looked at all
actually there probably is some good
stuff out there but yeah I've been
really disappointed with consoles
honestly like love the n64 even
PlayStation was decent even though I
never really liked PlayStation to be
honest then we hit the next-generation
GameCube it was still okay
like GameCube it was starting to get a
little titty though like lots of really
like they kept changing Nintendo kept
changing their characters to more fluffy
colourful rounded things I don't know it
just got more cartoony PlayStation 2 was
pretty good I got few games for that and
I liked them wait GameCube PlayStation 2
again then came ps3 and the Wii and Xbox
the we only really like Super Smash
Brothers on it brawl and then I'm going
on real ramble here never got a ps3
because I've never been a big
PlayStation fan it looked like there was
some good stuff for it though to be
honest good graphics and that got an
Xbox later much later like a few years
after Xbox came out 360 and that is what
I played the most it was pretty good
actually
even though has a few problems like it
runs really hot and red ring da me and
that kind of stuff but the new stuff I
don't know nothing too interesting to me
I'm really a PC gamer now PC games are
just so much better in my opinion next
one hi etho I watch a lot of your
episodes and I realized that you never
make noise no cry nothing
only your hum when you're disappointed
is it because you try hard to stay calm
when you when you're recording or
naturally you just you calm I just had
to put this comment on comment in
because it made me laugh when I see a
creeper in that my natural reaction is
not to cry definitely not I am pretty
calm by nature you have to really really
get me worked up to to get anger out of
me or anything like that you pretty much
have to threaten me or something like
that
reach those kind of levels for me to get
angry um otherwise I just sound kind of
disappointed but yes that is all for
today everyone thanks for watching as
always there it goes again I really like
knobloch things we need more noteblock
things I wanted to get a bunch of Zelda
tunes in my world here and I haven't
gotten around to that like song of Sarah
I saw a really good version of that on
YouTube but they didn't say the notes in
the video like they didn't show the
notes so I was have no idea how to
replicate it um yeah anyway enough
rambling thanks for watching have a
great
bye-bye