hey hi hello I didn't work good readings
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys
I am very happy today I'm very excited I
have good news my internet is finally
back the way it was
I took them a week to fix it but it's
fixed plus it was down another week
before that so it's basically two weeks
it's been down and it's very very
frustrating not having internet and
trying to do this YouTube thing still a
lot of times when eyes up loading stuff
through the hotspots and that the upload
would fail and I got to redo it and and
it would take like 12 hours plus per
episodes just very very annoying not
having proper internet so I'm very happy
it's back hopefully we don't have more
problems it definitely could happen
again I think but let's let's just not
think about it it's back we're happy all
is good again so to celebrate I thought
let's have some fun with a cannon here
something else interesting happened what
while I was just playing my
single-player world here I went caving
one day I wish I recorded it but i
seriously found the most diamonds I've
ever ever found in a single caving run
like every corner I took more diamonds
and every like diamonds I found it was
like veins of a torso pretty much so
within an hour - I got like a stack of
diamond ore blocks so cannons plus
diamonds I figure we'll use cannons and
diamonds as a target so let's have some
fun here let's see if we make the show
but I'm just going to do it this way
manual manually light it will have to
time it just right
oops I doubled up open
it's got to be shorter try this again
oh wait I said shorter right that was
longer
no what thought is going to come back
down this time I think I know what to do
Ariel that's the time that's the time
into it oh but it was off looks like we
actually hit one block up there the
taping run wasn't a total loss so I
found like two or three stacks of
redstone kind of thought I would hit it
by now I think we might be running out
of TNT come on Dario yay woohoo Oh none
survived I thought some would survive
but anyway here we are in the man cave
everyone and I want to take you all on a
little tour to start off this episode I
spent about three hours just going
through here and making lots of little
changes trying to finish up areas try to
make it look nice I also started on a
new section which I'll take you to
nothing really fancy has been done just
lots of little stuff so try to remember
them all first thing you will probably
notice no more torches down here and I
think that makes it look a lot better so
so clean and nice so I did have a little
trouble getting rid of them them all
like like before it was kind of like
this let's look at the difference it
makes when you get rid of torches like
it was like this before
basically and when you look at that from
up here it's just like yeah
you know without torte oh I think it
looks bad with torches anyway that's
kind of my thing I like to build
everything without torches now which is
really tough to do I almost do it too
much I think in it in a lot of ways it
it makes building tough so I probably
shouldn't do it all the time but for the
mancave
we're definitely doing it that way so I
was able to get rid of them all there's
of course lighting under these Pistons
and we have those every so often I was
kind of wondering maybe I should just I
don't really like how it looks when you
have just a random piston every so often
either it blends in pretty good but
maybe I don't know I thinking maybe just
doing the whole thing with pistons but
then I don't know I don't really like
the white sticking out as much as it
does but anyway so we got rid of the
torches down here to accomplish that I
had to pretty much line in the water
whoa accidental x-ray machine oh my
goodness
let me out I'm stuck don't do that okay
I lined the whole bottom like underneath
all the logs with glowstone here and
it's just barely enough to keep it above
spawning levels if we look at it block
like the BL over here goes down to seven
and a lot of places which seven will
spawn mobs eight will not but it's 7m my
head so since the lighting is coming
from down low it's actually eight at the
ground here so it's okay that's good we
got wheat here again decided to put it
back and then if we go over here I
polish it up this section this now
connects to the river goes up to here we
got a lily pad across and then we'll
probably build something here eventually
but I just I tried my best to do
something it's really again tough to do
tough to make
nice here because if if we go right
through here there's not oops not a lot
of space to work and I don't want to get
rid of that stone so and right here this
is actually the stairs so I can't really
change that it's only one thick there
and we got wheat here some leaves and
just some stairs in a pattern there for
some decoration or for some detail I
should say I just for right now I got
wood it or planks at the back there and
now let's see another small change is
with the horse stalls here this entrance
wasn't finished like these two blocks
there was stone and gravel and that
showing it didn't look too good I just
added a little wood detail some leaves
and whatnot just to complete the
entrance here we still need to build the
elevator here to go up to the surface
with the horses
um and then that will be done another
thing I changed like I said lots of
small details in the comments a lot of
people suggested I put carpets over
these pumpkins green carpets because I
didn't liked how at certain angles you
could still actually see them like from
here and if it's orange your eyes focus
in on that point because it's a
different color but if it's green you
don't really notice it as much so it's a
good change and they still let the light
through not that you're likely to see
them anyway I think I've never actually
checked yeah so if you walk by this
you're not going to focus on that little
orange speck there I always wanted to
get rid of this egg station up here
because I don't know that it wasn't
really working the eggs were coming up
all over the floor and they still are
actually I haven't killed the chickens
yet but I wanted to put an ender pearl
station here and but uh finally I did I
did it I've been talking about that for
a long time so you step on the pressure
plate use the ender pearls let's just go
take a look at the wire and quickly
pretty simple
you got compared our next to the
pressure plates it's on subtraction and
it loops back around so it does the the
quick pulse sink and you're on the
pressure plate but it goes up to a
dispenser which shoots enter pearls
through the glowstone at you and there's
a hopper and a bunch of chests up here
to feed the ender pearls down ah did not
take long to do oh wait you got to make
sure though that you have blocks there
otherwise the ender pearls look for the
closest air and they'll go that way
instead of out that's right okay
don't waste okay yeah let's go look you
know what let's go kill those chickens
because I've been wanting here to them
for a long time and then we're gonna
grab a looting suit
hey you little monsters oh I've been
wanting to get rid of you for so long if
you didn't know this is the reason I got
eggs randomly appearing all over my base
because of these guys when they lay an
egg it like shoots out randomly and it
comes up through the ground the way I
had it set up when I stepped on the
pressure plate at that ender pearl
station would send a signal down this
wire to this piston would make a glass
box come up in the negs will go up to
the top but we're not going to use this
really because there's way better ways
to do in chicken farms now you can can
use hoppers and dispensers in lava and
get fully automated once these guys are
sword
woohoo I get it klodin learn the ground
oh don't you run around no no no no no
your time in that ends now you are not
getting away you go a lot of them still
sounds like there's more in the ground
somewhere oh you know I think they ran
up here didn't they don't sting quieter
they're in the ground what
Wow spare no one
what look at them all there so many okay
don't mind the mass-murdering it's all
part of the game um cool I'll reclaim
this redstone stuff later let's set up
at yen we can get up through here I
think this is Wilson if I remember right
yeah
Wilson's over here what what else did we
do
I added in this piece of redstone
redstone ore so when you walk on it or
clicked it tada
and now I have a maintenance access to
the arrow dispenser from the creeper
eyes and also I can get to the portal
here which I'll probably try to fix one
day I didn't do that yet
then after a random amount of time that
closes again it's just that let's try to
take a look at the wiring it's going to
be tough it said it's a tea bud there's
a piston below the redstone here can't
really see it I'm sorry it's there
though it's all it is a tea bud so when
the redstone or updates it changes the
pistons like so ok moving on moving on
it's taking too long so if we head here
this is the new area here we'll go to
that in just a second this guy's moving
this guy's has been acting weird he'll
like start moving and I can't make him
sit down for some reason drop that for
right now I'll pick it up yeah I can't
make him sit it's really weird if I get
far enough away I think he sits down but
he follows me until then let's trade it
away from yeah look he's sitting but if
we get close he'll he'll sit up so weird
this area here I got rid of all the
torches and I add start adding a trim on
the ceiling here because it looked
really bad and from a distance it looks
pretty good I mean I don't have a lot of
space to work with there either so I
think that's ok
oops well enjoy
you ate my meal and this wood running
across its kind of just to hide
glowstone like random glowstone that was
there lighting up
the land above and let's go take a look
at the new area so this is there's not a
lot here this goes by the chief spider
spawners though and we can watch them
spawn and fall and they fall down to the
hoppers and they die and then the
hoppers click their string nope missed
it
come on and I added a little bit detail
there there's leaves underneath
I made this blast go down two blocks so
you can pretty much see the bottom
doesn't obstruct your view too much
aerial that took a while and again we
have leaves in the ceiling there's
glowstone up there too for lighting
we'll have to get rid of these torches
too and then we have this whole wall
here that I would like to do something
else with so yeah I believe that's about
it for our little tour all the changes I
can remember anyway I know there's a few
more I've been I've really been trying
to finish like finish up loose ends and
and work on projects existing projects
lately as much as I love starting new
ones
I always feel guilty because we got so
many unfinished ones but I've been good
lately I at least I feel I have been um
I haven't started anything new in a
while or nothing big today I do want to
start something it's gonna be like a
medium sized project I would say but
with with 1.7 coming out or snapshots
coming out I believe actually the rumor
I heard is it's coming out tomorrow
which is today for you but there's been
a few updates to the game one of the big
ones I've heard is the fishing it sounds
like the fishing mechanics got a major
overhaul in the latest snapshot it's
about time
dinner bones been spending some time
working on that from what I hear there's
three types of fishing now or three
types of catches you can catch different
types of fish so it's not just the one
type anymore and you can also catch like
items and loot and then there's junk you
can get from it so those three different
types of things one type of fish I read
there's going to be as a pufferfish
which is pretty cool I'm guessing when
you eat it it's going to damage you or
something and I also read on dinner
bones Twitter that's it's going to be
used for potions possibly like
underwater breathing potions so we want
to get in on the fishing here have a
special fishing spot that's what we're
going to do here to the left because
this area is a little bit plain like it
doesn't look terrible but it's just
paths basically and then this for most
parts of the cave I tried to do
something a little special like here we
have the water or up here we have a few
ran a random tree here and there you
know does some sort of natural well not
natural but some some sort of like
landscaping is done and I want to try to
do that here let's just dig and see if
there's anything back here so I want to
set up some kind of like pond and maybe
waterfalls trees that you can look down
from the left of the path here and and
and see like a little lake and and
something that looks nice and then maybe
set up a fishing shack and I'll do my
fishing there may be an automatic
fishing thing if that still works but
we'll get to that one when it comes out
which like I said is probably today when
you're watching this is probably out
already there's also going to be I don't
know there's different types of fishing
rods but I think there is
different Chapman so you can get and
depending on what you put on the rod
you'll get different luck with catching
different things I think is the way it's
going to work so yeah there's a bit
involved with fishing so cool to have a
little spot for it actually with
waterfalls I'm wondering let's let's
check this out is there some way we can
make this River here go all the way to
there and turn into a waterfall or
something what level is this okay so
it's it's level with this block here mm
if it was one or two blocks higher I
think we could make it go over the path
here but hmm we could make a go under
the path like maybe maybe have some
water to the left here it may go under
and then go go all the way here it would
have to be a little lower than this path
so maybe we'll go down a few blocks and
this will be like an upper view like a a
nice downward view at at the lake in
that and then maybe have another proper
access path to it somewhere else but
yeah I want to build a fishing shack
here so today we'll try to do a little
terraforming with it I'm going to get
some TNT and we will begin choosing the
spot out so I'm feeling a little bit
lazy today I really shouldn't do this
but usually I'm pretty careful with TNT
let's just hope this doesn't wreck
anything I don't think there's anything
here I know the portals a little bit
further back okay yeah it was good
there's nothing here whoo this is about
it's kind of what I want yeah can we go
this way a bit back go on maybe go this
way a bit more
uh-huh and you're probably guess I'd
have to shoot that should probably go
back this way so you can you I know the
port the portal room is going to be this
way though pretty sure so I want to be
too reckless that's good oh we found
gold ok how's this looking let's get an
upward or downward I keep saying upward
downward view from here on the size and
the shape it is that's good the reason I
want to use TNT to is it makes it a
little more random if I was to chisel
this out myself then women look too good
I don't think that oh did that arrow hit
me what was that I kind of I was weird I
got knocked back this way towards the
explosion more this way and maybe shave
off a little bit here I'm being I'm
being delicate to some extent
okay take one more look I'm going to
work some off-camera here to see I got
to get rid of a bunch of land in the
front here it's blocking the view yeah
that's pretty good I like that so if we
get the river here we'll have some kind
of waterfall on this side to the left
and we'll have have that connect to some
kind of pond and then we might make
water like another river flow from the
pond downward somewhere is what I'm
thinking oh darn it did it again it
pulled me forward that is so weird
okay I don't like this on the left it's
coming too close build it up a bit okay
I like that that's a nice view of
whatever we build here nice and nice and
open feeling might want to get rid of
some of this too I'm liking this thing
up here too there's like another layer
from a old mine shaft or something let's
let's look at this for a sec we might
want to include this somehow oh look at
this oh this is it this is for the cow
farm for the wheat farm I'm going to
make this go back some more okay I'm
trying to think of how we should build
this like where should the fishing shack
be in that the waterfall is going to be
there I was thinking we could have a
path going down here and maybe we'll
make that go straight to the building
like have have the building partially
online and partially in water and give
it a dock or something that goes this
way a little bit yeah so this will be
water can we make this come further out
without hitting anything I'm so worried
I'm gonna wreck something oh this is a
bit crazy I should not do six pieces at
once
oh-oh-oh we hit what is this chicken
farm woohoo I wanted to tear that down
that's perfect it'll look a lot better
when we get water and and grass down
here and smooth out all the rough edges
but anyway that's going to be about it
for this episode I think we got a good
start on this and we will continue it
next time and try to get most of it done
if we can as well assuming the snapshot
comes out we will probably check out
some changes with that to explore it a
bit I'm pretty sure terrain update is
not coming with a snapshot so that'll
come later but from what I hear there
have been lots of changes without that
even so that brings us to our comments
for today let's check out the first one
here hey etho I was wondering do you
have any special talents other than
being a boss at Minecraft oh snap
so there are things I'm good at
I actually looked this up because I
wasn't sure what what qualifies or
classifies as a special talent and in my
search results it the thing that mostly
came up is like weird things people can
do with their body like maybe some
special type of singing they can do er
or weird weird things that you can do
with their body so um I'm kind of
double-jointed with my feet so I can umm
how can i how can I demonstrate this
most people when they stand they have
their feet kind of together like this
when I stand I tend to make my feet go
like this outward from each other maybe
not a 45 like that but yeah I'm kind of
double-jointed to my feet and I can
actually make my feet like go more than
one a
like this I can actually make them go
backwards quite a bit like what's like
3/4 of a full rotation I would say like
I can pretty much turn my feet backwards
that's I guess I would call out a
special talent what else what else I can
crack just about every single one of my
joints if I want to and I can I didn't
stick my pinky finger in my ear and when
I pull it out I can make a loud popping
sound by creating a vacuum I'll actually
try that out in this video here one
second let me adjust my headset I don't
know if you're going to be able to hear
it or how loud it's going to be but in
real life it's pretty loud okay here
goes three two one I don't you heard
that
um yeah special talents woohoo I so what
is your favorite block to build with
currently I would say the hardened clay
stuff is really cool
particularly the cyan because it's grey
and it goes with a lot of stuff but I
think all time favorite block is
probably going to be just plain old
wooden planks because you can do stairs
and do half slabs and I don't know if I
think out fences and stuff like that
with it because it's the same texture
basically but yeah I like the stuff here
so that's the end of this episode I hope
you guys enjoyed and I will see you
again next time
we could we should come up with a name
for this tattoo anyway
bye bye
you