hello everyone this is etho and we're
just at the blaze farm right now in the
nether I think today is going to be
another episode what I'd like to do is
set up another word farm somewhere
around here for my another base I kind
of want this blaze farm to be the
epicenter of it so not exactly sure
where I want to build the farm yet I
think what I'll do is I'll just clear
out an area around this farm the blaze
farm and we'll take it from there
so I'm going to clean out a bunch of
this another rack set up some stairs or
something to get out of here I'm
thinking I should make the main floor at
least one block above these repeaters so
that would be at at this block level
here needs to be at least that high it
will probably go up another one or two
or so and then to get to the blaze farm
you go down some stairs or something
something like that I don't know we'll
see jazz up if we're a little bit higher
we'll be closer to the blaze spawner and
that will make it so this thing's active
more often as well without having to be
quite as close to it horizontally okay
so I'm going to clean up around here and
figure out maybe a shape or a pattern or
something and then we will get to
testing and building and all that fun
stuff so I'll see you in a little while
alright everybody we are back again got
some space cleared out a little bit and
if you notice my levels jumping around
throughout this episode it's because
I'm kind of doing stuff in the
background between recordings and
getting food and all that stuff so when
I go afk I usually do annex to the blaze
farm so my levels might be all over the
place
this episode I just got us another silk
touch pick actually which is awesome
diamond one so what were you going to do
now I have set up four rooms here one
there one there and that one and that
one so we're going to do some nether
wart experimenting because apparently
there's a lot of rumors that fire and
lava influence the growth rate as far as
I know they don't but I'm just going to
check it to be sure what we'll do we'll
try fill these rooms yeah well in these
corners like in one room we'll have fire
in the corner in another room we'll have
lava in the corners and in the third
room we'll have torches in the corners
and we'll see how the growth rates
compare after a little bit of time see
if there's any distinct advantage and
for the fourth room I want to make it
completely not completely dark but dim
lighting that's what we should figure
out first actually what lighting dude
does the nether wart need to live we're
going to figure that out right now
okay we'll set up some soul sand here
like so so if the lighting is not enough
it'll just pop out of the ground seems
to be okay still maybe we should pick a
darker spot we will go I will just dig
further this way I guess I never use my
diamond picked in the nether because I
don't want it to get wasted mine another
rack since it breaks pretty quickly
anyway I usually will use either a
cobblestone or iron because I have lots
of iron okay we'll set it up here make
it a huge mess oh please don't we have
another good okay we'll take out the
floor and replace it with slow sand now
we'll get rid of this excuse me get rid
of that torch the lighting so this is
really dark in here and will actually
block off this end just to be sure you
guys still see I hope we'll plant nether
warts I didn't break off what am I doing
wrong
it should right
hmm I'm confused guys why isn't it
breaking I thought if I placed one here
they would all chain react and break hmm
okay I'm going to do some more research
I guess and try figure out what's wrong
yeah I'm really not understanding this
because I've seen it happen before if it
if it's a dark area the nether wart
should uproot if you if a block updates
next to it and it doesn't seem to matter
if the light changes or anything it's
just not doing it here for some reason
I've seen it happen before I've seen it
happen other people's videos like I I
know vex just made a video showing it I
saw it in one of food's videos for sure
why why in fact there's a specific spot
in this map we're going to go there
where I'm sure it happens
I tried encasing the room with other
blocks besides another act and it didn't
work either
so I'm thoroughly confused right now
they will go to the original nether wart
farm where I saw it happen this is where
I originally got the nether wart from
these two natural farms here and in this
one there's one spot where I can't
replant it right here because it always
up roots let's see what happens if we
place a torch nothing just that one spot
it won't it won't work
like you implant it but as soon as
something updates I think it'll uproot
if it's dark yeah there it goes
so why why here and only there like this
one doesn't uproot when you break this
one but this one does if you break this
one so I don't know it can't be a
lighting issue because there's no little
difference in light is there still doing
it just there
what is special about the spot I know
someone probably knows and it's just
killing them that I can't figure it out
J 1 negative 143 and 193 mmm when I
think about it for a bit there's got to
be a reason for this yeah this is really
really strange first thing I did is I
removed the stone brick stairs because I
thought maybe they were influencing it
somehow turns out they weren't then I
expanded this farm a little bit and we
can have nether warts all around this
one spot no problem doesn't break off in
low light it's just this one spot here
where it happens and so I'm just be
because this is a region corner or not a
region a chunk corner this spot right
here so I'm going to try something I'm
going to go 16 blocks over this is
negative 143 we should go 16 blocks this
way and try see if we can plant slow
sand in that spot so we need to go to
negative 159 right here oh yeah another
thing it doesn't matter what the height
is either by the what I can tell here if
you update next to it it still breaks
off even though it's higher or lower
that's interesting I'm very curious to
see if it's because of the chunk corner
maybe actually we knew this place block
okay so it didn't break
oh that just makes me more confused
we'll set up a little 3x3 here see if we
can cause one of them to break in this
area I don't know the reason I'm so
concerned about this is because I plan
to base my farm around that nether wart
breaking trick for auto harvesting
instead of using Pistons to auto harvest
I wanted to get rid of the lighting and
have them all break off in a chain
reaction type thing so I would like to
mimic it if I can but I don't know why
it works in places and like when vexing
goo did it it wasn't just one plant like
I have here that was doing it it was
whole fields of these things that we're
breaking at once hmm
so it's fine there one thing we can do
now since we know a specific spot where
it will break we can actually check the
lighting required to make it break I
think possibly I don't know that's the
other thing when they remove their
torches that's when it broke and when
I'm doing it it's not breaking for some
reason but if I do a block update it
does and that doesn't happen normally
like if we do one over I wish it was
brighter here pretty sure I met max yeah
if we do a block update over here
doesn't break them yeah so we're just
going to figure out the exact lighting
that's causing this there shouldn't be
any other lights in this area just this
one torch over here so we can keep
moving at one block closer to figure out
the exact distance where it breaks so
it's breaking at that distance let's
move it closer still breaking hmm has to
be closer than I thought there we go
that's the exact distance right there
so that is torches or a light level of
14 this would be 13 12 11 10 9 and 8 so
netherwart needs a light level of 8 to
prevent it from uprooting in that
condition whatever that condition is
that's making this one uproot that
doesn't affect all these other ones for
some strange unlogical reason I don't
I'm really curious about this if you
guys know tell me what's going on
because you have no idea how confused
this is making me it doesn't seem to
follow any logic ok so light level 8 14
13 12 11 10 9 8 for sure
that's not that would be light level
seven and it breaks okay well whatever
the deal is with that we're still going
to do our test here this is our lighting
test to see if different lighting types
or levels affect the growth rates so
we're going to test the fire rumor we're
going to test the lab a rumor and this
room here is torches we have them one
block higher than the latha in the fire
because they are one light level lower
so we want it even and this is going to
be our darkroom so let's fill these up
with nether wart will let them grow try
to find them as quickly as we can here
I'll let them grow I'll keep checking
them we'll seal off these rooms so the
outside light doesn't affect them and
see if there's any any noticeable
difference between the four rooms so
we're about five minutes in now let's
open up and see where they're at mark
the doors okay that's the fire room one
two three four five yeah I really should
have marked the doors and of course it's
random to an extent
that's the torch room I am noticing a
difference in the torch room compared to
the fire and lava could be a coincidence
fire seems to be the best so far and the
dark room much like the torch room very
interesting okay we'll keep them going a
little bit longer here and we'll compare
it in and if it does seem like there is
a difference we will do a much larger
scale test to be sure let's check them
again quickly here we're about 10
minutes in now fire room looking pretty
good
lava room torch room still pretty far
behind by the looks of it the fire room
is likely a good 30 seconds ahead of
these ones just because I had the plants
I planted it first so there it's a
little bit ahead because of that but I
can't imagine it would make that big of
a difference okay I'll see you at 15
yeah we're just over 15 now like between
15 and 20 minutes this is what we're at
fire room lava room torch room and dark
room
and now we're about 30 minutes in a
little past this will probably be our
final check this is the fire room this
is the labrum again torch room over here
looks like the torch room's losing at
the moment that little that's not it
does have some tall ones in it and
finally this is the dark room which is
doing pretty good yeah I don't know to
me it seems like they're all fairly even
obviously some are ahead but I think
that's just due to the randomness I
don't think yeah they have any advantage
over each other in my opinion you guys
can judge yourselves from this test well
it looks like we just found another
nether fortress as looking for some slow
sand like a big patch of it and stumbled
across this so that's awesome we'll have
to check it out sometime but not right
now as it's looking for another patch of
the slow sand to see if we can find
another one of those places that causes
it to pop off and if we do that we might
be able to figure out what's actually
causing it to happen but doesn't seem
like this patch does that anywhere so
I'm going to try find some more and see
if we can replicate it again we might be
able to draw a connection somewhere yeah
I found a huge huge chunk of slow sand
here it wraps all the way around and
trying to place it randomly in places to
figure out another spot where it will
pop off but it just it's not happening I
don't know it's probably conditions I
can't control I just don't know what
they are so if you guys know please
please tell me because I would like to
know
I would really like to use in another
word farm that trick word where they pop
off because you could have like for
example if if this popped off and all
these popped off from that trick I could
just hit this and they would all break
at once and that way you won't need like
six Pistons to do that or if you got
another word farm with say a hundred in
and you can cause a chain reaction you
just need to break one instead of like
needing a hundred Pistons to move up and
down to break them which would be pretty
cool so you just need to like block off
the light or remove the light to make it
happen or that's that's how I'd like it
to work
I don't know also I was going to say
this I don't think I mentioned it yet
but I'm on a oh dang it
Oh leave me alone I'm on a race for wool
tournament on reddit's so it's it's me
sethbling disco and tree we're all
together on a team Team Red stoners and
it's a 16-team tournament with the with
four players on each team so if you guys
want to check it out I might be posting
a race for wool video soon of the
footage we got over the game we played
already but instead of spreading it out
over two or three episodes I'll just put
it all into one as and just give you the
highlights of it so you can get a good
overview of the match how it happened if
you guys want I'm a little behind on my
videos right now which is unfortunate I
need to catch up so that would help me
catch up for sure and yeah it was a good
match some of my recording got messed up
that's that's another reason why I want
to just do highlights because I don't
have it all but
so let me know if you want to see it and
I will post it I got all the footage I
just need to edit it which doesn't take
that long hmmm I guess there's another
another fortress right over here right
by the slow sand and the one we normally
go to is right there so they're pretty
close
I wouldn't mind finding two blaze
spawners together that would be huge
I think then I would probably build my
base here instead so maybe it's worth
checking out cuz I'd hate to start
building stuff in the nether and then
find out that there's a better spot you
know ten minutes later or something so
I'm going to investigate this yeah yes
what I think you know it turns out there
is another one so that one's right there
and the other ones right here so doesn't
get a whole lot better I think they're
perfectly aligned even same height one
two three four five six seven eight nine
I can't really count but they're they're
about 16 blocks apart which is awesome
so this is where we're going to do it
that will my my armor is just about gone
yeah this is awesome so definitely we'll
have to set that up that will double our
XP rates which is huge because it's
already good with that one farm but if
we can get a double farm unbelievable
and I'm lost no this is it this is it
good okay
sweet okay if you have to do one thing
in this episode so we'll do it real
quick I didn't check if netherwart will
grow if a blocks above it so let's let's
figure that out too before we end this
also just in case you don't know this
already there are three stages of growth
so this is a small stage and if you
break them one there like that if you
only get one always which make sense
this is the second stage just sight here
I think you get two or one
I guess one seems to always be one and
then at the third stage you get it's
either two or three I think three three
set for three up to so I think it's two
to four we I bet you a fortune works on
this three four
hmmm I should probably check
I should probably test fortune two just
to make this a complete episode but what
we'll do before that we're going to set
up some fresh ones and then we're going
to cover them and see if that's if they
can still grow and I think we just got
our answer there but we'll we'll do it
anyway and the the word is you can't
grow this stuff in the real world maybe
I'll try that too real quick just to be
sure yeah I don't think they're going to
grow here been watching them for a while
nurse they're still small so in this
world they don't seem to grow you can
plant them for looks but that's about it
and you have to be in the nether for
them to grow like within viewing range I
think for them to grow so that if you
got a farm in the nether it won't be
growing while you're here you have to
actually be there and near it for it to
work and bonemeal we should try bonemeal
does not work or at least not here we'll
try it in another as well so they can
grow if they're covered with a solid
block that's the verdict on that
bonemeal does not work okay and I do
have a fortune pic now fortune 3-1 so
I'm expecting we should get like four or
more often see what we get we have fifty
two that is yet we got four that time
try it again
oh we went beyond I think yeah I think
that was five
61 that was five again oops
three five and I think that was five
right I don't I can't remember
so fortune pick does seem to work on
these that's awesome
not that you couldn't get millions if
you made a big farm but good to know
yeah I think we got six they're so big
in it does help quite a bit
awesome so I think that's everything I
thought I wanted to do yeah so I will
call that an end of an episode
thank you for watching sorry we didn't
build anything you know the answer to my
question let me know hopefully we can
get building stuff again next time but
like I said on low on time lately so
this was an easy episode to get out and
it's important to research things before
building so that's why we were doing
that today okay thanks for watching guys
I'll see you again next time
actually before we end this I'm going to
give you one tip to and taste this ever
happens do you like you just happen to
me if you get stuck in the nether like
if a gas shoots out your nether portal
and you don't have any flint and steel
can't make any there's another way out
without killing yourself just you can
actually make a wick on another rat if
you have a flammable block this fire
will spread to this block or to that one
and then just lead it on over to the
portal
so that should eventually cause the
portal light up so watch it it probably
take a little while that's for sure but
it will eventually light it actually
didn't take that long yeah it's lit so
if you ever get stuck in the nether like
that as long as you got flammable blocks
you can get out just use the fire on the
ground