all right
everybody on the roof house party
not you cat you get lost um
yes yes awesome and then i get off the
roof perfect
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back to
another episode of our let's play series
and check it out
i have made some new friends guys these
these guys are pretty cool i am of
course using the 1.10 snapshot i decided
to
try it out here seems to be running not
too bad actually
um whenever i try out a new snapshot i
always go right to the man cave and i
check my fps and so far
it's pretty comparable to 1.9 um
haven't really noticed any anything
taking longer or anything not working
yet so
might actually stick with this but yeah
there is new new mobs there's new blocks
there's all kinds of crazy new stuff
we're gonna check out today
uh starting with these guys so these are
a new variant of zombies i believe
they're called husks
husks four
s's in there yes um
they actually look very different from
zombies though just because of the
the the coloring on them but it's a
similar skin for sure
uh or similar texture they only spawn
in hot climates so i have confirmed they
do spawn in deserts
in sandy city here this is where they
all came from
um pretty much exactly like
zombies they don't burn in the day
though
so that's why they're kind of sticking
around here even even though it was
sunny
now it's turning night time so we're
going to get a bunch more of them
spawning
um like zombies they can spawn with
armor they pick up uh
drops i have seen them go after
villagers and
it's it's like a zombie pretty much
exactly like them
when they uh when you hit them and they
spawn new
zombies like the the reinforcements it
actually spawns these
types not just random green zombies
and when they hit you they cause a
hunger status effect so
i think they have to have an empty hand
though
yeah so he gave it to me it lasts for 20
seconds
let's get hit by one of the guys with
the items like a boner
yeah so it doesn't actually cause the
status effect because it's their hand
that causes it and if they have any item
it counts as a weapon i think
yes um in my defense i was trying to say
bone or
arrow but i didn't finish my thought so
yeah giggle all you want i know what i
said
uh okay so i went and enchanted some of
my gear everything was falling apart
like my boots and my pants and
everything so
we're all good again oh i'm so sorry
i was trying to fly there we go
the poor little kitty you see we got one
of the guys like up on the pyramid here
so they're definitely spawning
in uh in the desert here i'm trying to
see if i can show you them spawning
reinforcements
but we gotta find one that actually does
that
doesn't look like this guy's doing it
oh right there you see that from a
normal zombie we got a husk
so i think it's actually biome dependent
so wherever the reinforcement spawns
that is what determines what type of
zombie it is so a regular zombie
in a desert can make husks and i think a
husk in like a forest
can probably make regular zombies is my
theory
anyway oh look at this a little baby one
so it is possible you can get the baby
ones now i'm wondering if you can get a
chicken jackie
like this as well i probably can just
extremely rare
uh they don't drop anything special
though these guys same
drops as normal zombies as of right now
just zombie flesh
and i have gotten a carrot off of one of
them so i'm guessing you can get an iron
ingot as well
here's something weird though i wanted
to point out to you so we saw one spawn
on the pyramid right
that is actually where my uh mob system
is
underneath there that's all desert biome
we can go up there and
confirm that
yeah so right underneath here is the
mob system if we look at the
biome there it says desert all the way
through here
but yeah check this out down below where
we just were
underneath the pyramid underneath the
mob system where they fall
down and die all the zombies
are just regular zombies they're regular
zombies there's no husks spawning so i
believe
uh they require sunlight or something to
spawn
they can't spawn in a covered area if i
was to guess
either that or they require certain
block types to spawn on like sand
uh the mop system is made out of clay
but i'm guessing it has to do with
direct sunlight uh-huh so that's
interesting
anyways let's go and check out maybe the
the new blocks in this patch
there's i believe five or six
six right i'm gonna say six um
yeah most of them are easy to get uh
they require nether brick
and we're gonna need some nether warts
which we just pass at our netherwort
farm
might have some in the chest here
not that one thirteen
ah all right that's not very much
let's see so the recipes are for
the nether the red nether brick that's
what's called
is like that do netherwort two nether
bricks um
i believe that's not a recipe i knew
that
is it two by two three by three oh it's
three by three for the nether wart block
and then there's also
a magma block which looks kind of cool
that requires i believe
are they called magma cream yeah so
let's grab some blaze powder
you get magma cream from the magma
slimes but don't forget you can also get
it just from regular slimes and a blaze
farm
so you have to place powder slime ball
mix them together
so it's it's a pretty easy block to get
like so all right and then the other one
the one i'm most excited about
is the bone blocks oh and i got salami
actually
not like that it is bone meal you
actually convert it into bone meal
so it's three bones per block
and then in creative mode there's a
structure block in the void
block structure void so six total right
okay guys so i took a moment here to
make a bunch of them up and to
get a few other blocks together here so
we can try find some color combinations
and that kind of thing
we're going to indulge for a little bit
here we're going to bring out our
inner builder and see if we can find
some way of using these so i do
i let me know what you guys think of
these too like before i
bias your opinion here i will say i love
the bone block i think the bone block is
great
uh the other three not quite as excited
about
this one is probably my second favorite
the magma block
just because it's animated like look at
this
oh yeah it's animated and it has a
special function where if you
if you step on it or if a mob steps on
it they take damage and this is not
fire damage it is lowering the
durability on my armor here
not on the lyra wings though of course
um
it's not fire damage it's similar to the
damage you get from a cactus
but unlike a cactus i don't believe it
destroys items
let's try that out yeah so you can have
items on there
it's really good as like a mob grinder
though
all right let's try out the
the nether brick i do really like how
this looks just on its own but i
worry guys i'm very concerned we're not
going to be able to use it in the game
because it doesn't go with anything else
i don't think
and especially this one the netherward
block
um i will say i like the textures on all
of the blocks i'm just not so sure about
like the saturation level and
and the coloring in that might not be
the best
but we'll see we'll try some stuff out
here so
we got our blocks um what do we try
first
okay nether brick netherrack let's try
the nether stuff first
and just see how it goes with it was
there any other nether stuff
uh i guess soul sand but i didn't bring
that
okay so nether brick next to this stuff
it's not bad it's not bad right
um it does look like the same texture
actually just a different
color and this one you can tell it has
like blotches that are particularly
high saturation and i like how that
looks like this brick here for example
is really stands out in this little
little square over here
i think that looks okay though i don't
know i think if i was to use it i would
use it for the
floor and the nether brick for the wall
maybe
it's not too bad okay okay
i could see putting those two together
let's try
another rack next to it netherrack is
one of my least favorite blocks in this
game
but it's all over the nether so
yeah they work together too for sure
oh yeah check it out guys
you can see it i am the best builder
in this game now i i know this looks
pretty bad
uh i was just doing some experiments
here trying to learn
a few things about the blocks and uh
yeah i think i
i figured out a couple things here let's
start with the netherwort block
um i would say this this netherward
block is not really good for um
like the foreground it's more of a
background block a backdrop
because it has it doesn't have any
straight lines in the texture it's more
chaotic
kind of like netherrack um i find in
this game blocks that have
straight lines look like they give
structural supports
like bricks here so those those are
better suited for the foreground
um that being said though i usually like
my background blocks to be kind of dull
and i want the foreground blocks to
stand out
so it's almost a conflict of interest
having a bright background block
but hey in if you use it right it'll
probably look good
it is very similar to the red nether
brick
and i do like how it looks with the
regular nether brick too
in fact i would maybe even prefer to use
regular just so there's that that
more contrast between the two
if i was to choose between red and and
regular um
also goes well with netherrack i do feel
though this magma block
doesn't look the best with the red
nether brick or with the
the netherwort over here because this is
more red burgundy
and this is more orange with the
in between here being kind of a burgundy
brown
um yeah not the best together
i do really like regular nether brick
with this stuff though because this
color over here in the middle
very very close to this isn't it
i think so they complement each other
pretty nicely
um this magma stuff actually spawns
next to netherrack i'm pretty sure and
together i don't know
i i feel like they could blend a little
bit better
but it's not it's not terrible it's not
terrible i guess
uh the bone block though because it's a
white block it could pretty much
be used with anything i feel um
kind of like nether quartz nether quartz
could pretty much be used with
everything too
uh i wanted to actually compare the two
next to each other
wow you know they're they're really
close together you could probably
replace quartz with the bone block in a
lot of cases
and that's uh that is wonderful if you
didn't know
collecting quartz is one of my least
favorite things in this game i've always
wished that villagers would trade it
i think that would be amazing and i
actually try to avoid using it just
because it's such a pain to get
some people like collecting quartz but i
don't
so i'm very happy it looks like i'm
going to be able to replace it
which is great and honestly this might
be better in most cases than quartz
because it doesn't have the lines so if
you have a bunch of them together it
looks cleaner than the quartz block
it looks like one big piece uh i am
noticing something weird going on here
though like if you look from a distance
there's definitely a horizontal line
right there
and when i had the nether brick over top
wait a second yeah i'm just playing with
the lighting here when i had it over top
i noticed two lines
yeah there's definitely a line over
there now too
so what is causing that exactly
i'm not so sure is it the torch here
could that possibly affect it
i would think
it would be the same throughout because
i don't see a line right now at the top
there
just at the bottom okay i i think i know
what's happening now it's pretty clear
here
i put a bigger piece down and it only
happens at the very bottom and that is
because of the smooth lighting engine
if there's a block below then it
transitions to that so it darkens
these blocks here so if we were to
remove this grass
i think it disappeared well maybe not
wait a second
i'm telling you that's what it is right
yeah now it's gone
so it sort of uh darkens things oops
and we can probably see that actually if
we put uh quartz
right here yeah so now we have a line
there and one over there
aha so that's what's going on with that
from a distance you don't want a big
chunk of this bone block so i don't
think because then it makes these
vertical lines that are very
very clear and
yeah not the best um i tried prismarine
stuff here by the way
um i don't feel this or this works with
any of them
maybe the dark prismarine kind of works
with this
maybe you could combine it with this and
this
if you want like a really strong
contrast
um let's do some some testing here
though with the
quartz and the bone block i'll tell you
why i think the bone block is going to
be better in just about every case
besides the whole line issue
um i shouldn't have put the chest back
here because now i never
check back here i always go to the first
chest i see i don't think of what i'm
actually looking for
um yeah so if we put like dark oak next
to both of these i bet you the bone is
going to be better
yeah most definitely definitely like the
bone block better there
um it's going to be like that for pretty
much all the blocks in the game because
this is darker
a little bit darker and since this hat
this game generally has like doll dollar
blocks
um dollar d-u-l-l
er yeah again i would say
bone winds uh it's gonna blend better
with them
that's gonna complement them better than
the quartz the quartz might look better
with clay though
because clay is a very smooth
block again i did it here let's just try
let's try maybe blue i usually really
like
this blue clay with quartz
and now which would i prefer
yeah again i think the bone block wins
so let's talk about some block
combinations now guys uh we're gonna
assume just about everything works with
the bone
the bone block because it's white white
and black
kind of work with everything but when
you mix colors together then things get
crazy
especially very bright red and orange
colors things might not work the best
but uh yeah doing logs here i was
surprised the oak wood looks very good
with this
it does um also the dark oak is not bad
acacia meh don't like it
uh actually i don't like the chaser with
any of these uh don't like the oak with
the the red
here but the dark oak could work
i could see that being a good thing um
spruce wood
over here which do you guys like more
the dark oak or the spruce with these
hmm i have a hard time deciding i think
the dark oak is better it's closer to
black
than spruce wood so i think in general
it's better
with most blocks on the other side here
we have the uglier
logs jungle wood birch and spruce
so well no spruce is a good log but
usually i prefer dark
oak over it um
yeah none of these really work except
maybe spruce and maybe
jungle wood with this orange stuff here
but i would prefer oak over it for sure
and
next up guys we have the plank blocks so
what do you think about these
i would say no oak wood with the red
here
either of these it's bad but everything
else i think is decent like
the acacia is pretty good with all three
of these
um i could see dark oak working
maybe the oak wood with this one they're
a little bit
closer together in color i do like the
spruce with this one too
especially this is jungle wood
it's got a little bit of red to it so
that might be a pretty good one too
usually i really don't like jungle wood
but with this
might be not too bad oh hello
oh no it's three hits i forgot it's
three hits
um birchwood is bad with all three of
them
i would say um and then between dark oak
and spruce
wood it's kind of hard to say i like uh
i like the dark oak more with this one
but i think i like the spruce wood more
with
this one
and don't really like the jungle wood
with the the magma here
all right guys here we have the stone
blocks and i find they stand out quite a
bit don't they
yeah uh they're a bit on the light side
if they were a darker gray i think they
would work
clay blocks okay so i don't really like
the white clay blocks with any of these
but everything else here is pretty good
this is the light gray this is a gray
i think that works good with all three
on the other side here we have black
pretty good as well brown it's not bad
and then the hardened clay just the
regular stuff
i find it works the best with this one
then maybe this one then this one
now we get into the colors here so
yellow and orange
good with this not the red uh
not the yellow with this but maybe the
orange and red
and same with this one um on the back
side here i am not sure
uh none of these with this one i know
that
but if you want something crazy looking
you might be able to pull this off
this one is a little bit more tricky for
me to decide i don't mind the green
actually
i thought i i thought they would be bad
but i don't mind it especially with the
orange here uh the cyan is bad
it doesn't really go on the other side
here we have the blues
and the lighter blues definitely no
but maybe the the dark blue here could
be pretty good um
and yeah that's that's probably enough
uh checking there's more blocks in the
game but we could be here forever
i will say one thing though you might be
like wow there's so many blocks that
work with this
uh you might notice every time i've been
testing these i've had them either on
the ground or
one block in front like that
the main problem with these new blocks
is nothing really
works flush with them okay
let me explain so let's take prismarine
for example
we have the bricks yeah here's the
bricks
so these two blocks they're very similar
in color and they're also very similar
in texture like the
they're both kind of broken looking um
because of that you can put them side by
side and they look pretty good
but these nothing is very
nothing really matches the color and
there's very few that match the texture
there are bricks in the game but like
even if we put nether brick
next to this like flush with it and we
tried to mix them in here i don't know
if it would look good
this is like as close as you're gonna
get to this
now it just stands out way too much the
color is so different
i don't know uh what other bricks are
there
yeah there's a
oh i guess there's regular bricks but
those probably wouldn't be good
um oh red sandstone kind of a brick look
like nope that's not gonna work this
again that's probably gonna be one of
the closest you can get to it and it
stands out so much so anything flush
with it is gonna be tough to do but if
you go one block forward a lot of stuff
will work
and there's one more trick i want to
remind you guys about in this game
not just with these blocks but all the
blocks in the game
if you find you can't quite make
something blend well
you can always try stained glass so
it gives it a slightly different hue
so you can make something look maybe a
bit more green or a bit more whatever
color you want
you still got the cool animated texture
in the back here
but now it kind of suits this a bit
better
uh so now let's look at a couple more
details with these new blocks
the magma block for example actually
puts out light
you won't notice this in the nether
because the nether has a
permanent light of seven if i remember
right
and this only puts out a light level of
uh i think
three at our feet right now it says two
one if we're over here so yeah i think
it's three
something kind of weird with them which
might be a bug is they actually save
the the lighting so if i place a torch
and then break it
it keeps the lighting that the torch
provided it
crazy i know all right now if we look at
the bone blocks
this is really neat something you might
not expect
but they're actually transparent blocks
so that means if we have a torch
on that side and we go to this side if
we look at our lighting it says light
level 11
12 11. so the light passes through these
they're kind of like glass but you can't
see through them
all right another thing to look at is
the redstone
functionality of them nether brick is a
solid block
so the redstone passes through but
nether warts and the
bone block are not magma one is
and another cool trick you might not
know if you hold
shift and you walk on the magma block
you don't take damage
if you let go of shift you do
and i wanted to try out the uh
block resistance on these so i have some
tnt set up we're gonna have some fun
first off nether brick i'm expecting to
be pretty tough
let's go ahead and light that see how
many dirt blocks get blown up
oh wow okay so that is actually tougher
than stone because if that was stone all
the blocks would have disappeared
interesting um bone
might be strong oh i can't place oh i
forgot
oh this might be tough to set off
because i can't actually place any
levers or buttons on here
yeah not quite as resistant for sure
let's do the magma
uh i'm guessing this stuff's probably
like stone
oh actually very similar so two blocks
down and actually the ground
got damaged so it's not very resistant
at all
um now this stuff
is probably pretty weak if i was to
guess
it's kind of like mushroom blocks i
think
but let's just see you break it with
your axe all the other blocks you use
your pick on
oh it's not not as bad as i thought
actually
so the magma was the the lowest blast
resistance i believe
um yeah you mine these with your pick
even with the ace 2
and efficiency 5 pick here you cannot
instant mind the bone
you can however instant mind this magma
stuff even without haste 2
um can't insta mine this you can insta
mine
the netherwart blocks with your axe if
you have efficiency
oh it's only four on here i guess
all right i think we covered the blocks
finally
there's a lot to this update i might
have talked about them too long
but it's exciting getting new building
blocks
um something i wanted to try here is the
auto jump feature
which a lot of people were complaining
about to clarify i believe this is for
people with disabilities mainly
by default they decided to turn it on
though which i don't necessarily agree
with
but yeah when you try out 1.10 you're
going to have auto jump on that's how
you configure it there
so if you walk into for example the
leaves here
i didn't press spacebar it just
automatically hot me over them
can probably run up a hill oh no
oh that was weird okay so if you run too
fast you'll run into the side of the
block and then it doesn't try to jump
anymore it looks like
which makes me think this is not going
to work one thing i'm concerned about is
that people
might be able to do inhumane amazing
jumping like if you try to jump up a
side of a hill like this
manually it's very difficult you're
gonna get stuck a lot
so i'm wondering if you just like fly
over this with auto jumping
no you you get stopped every every jump
to
like you would normally so i don't think
it can be abused
that's good um yeah people with
disabilities
some some have trouble pressing the
spacebar repeatedly
so that's what it's intended for mainly
i believe
and if anybody finds a convenience they
can use it too
last thing we're going to do today guys
we're going to see if we can find a
polar bear
at our ice spike biome i suspect we need
to go to a new area though
but we'll just take a fly around here
and also we're going to look for
a stray that's the new skeleton variant
oh there we go there we go whoa
this is new terrain here and that is a
stray guys
oh now he's done it very very much like
a skeleton
different look though they look really
cool
and i believe if you kill them yeah you
can get a slowness arrow just one
and i don't know if it's every time
but that's kind of cool so that's a new
drop in the game
oh what is this oh that's one of the
arrows he shot
actually keeps the potion effect on it i
think yeah look at them
they sparkle after he shoots them oh
here's another one
with an enchanted bow when he shoots you
you also get slowness for 30 seconds oh
wow
that's pretty brutal ah
did we yeah we got another one that time
cool
all right i'm gonna go back to the ice
bite biome i think
this guy is blue what is this guy
he's got blue armor
wait a minute what that was different
get blue armor on that was cool
i don't know it wasn't hmm he didn't
drop it though that's
that's kind of odd
all right guys so i looked around for a
while got lost two for a while
but uh my wings were starting to wear
out pretty
pretty low here so i had to get back did
not find a polar bear
did not find a polar bear even in the
new terrain i was at
so they are not super common
i did find strays in both the ice spike
biome
and in the new planes biomes i generated
there
so two two confirmed biomes you can get
them in
and uh yeah they're they're pretty neat
i like them
um it's a good addition to the game here
is the comment i picked out for today it
says hey etho i have done the ocean
monument
as well and sometimes the sponge rooms
have no entrance and you must break your
way in
just letting you know yeah i got a lot
of comments about that
on the last video we raided like three
it was three guardian temples
and i can assure you guys off camera i
dug through that whole place
and just found one sponge room in the
three of them so
i i don't think i missed the sponge
rooms
because i broke all the walls pretty
much and didn't find any
so new update guys pretty exciting stuff
i look forward to
trying out some some block combinations
and all the other good stuff oh yeah f3
g brings up chuck chuck
chunk borders
that's a nice feature to have for sure
and lots of other stuff has been added
like there's new villages
that spawn not only in like the plains
in savannah like before you can get them
in swamps you can get them
um all over the place and
they have different block variations so
that's a neat addition
and lots of other stuff too
we'll get more into it later i'm sure
but i hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching
and i believe you can feed wheat to
polar bears at the moment if you want to
breed them
but i was wasn't able to find one so i
wasn't able to try it today
but yeah thanks for watching hope you
enjoyed it and i'll see you in the next
one
take care bye
you