[Music]
hello everybody
this is etho and we are once again in
the end here
uh we're going to be doing just a little
bit of repairing stuff
uh i was going through my stronghold
chests trying to organize
everything because they were getting
pretty messy and i got to the tool
chest i have like two double
chests full of enchanted tools in my
world
and they're full so
i have a lot of these unbreaking three
picks and a lot of
pics i've been saving that are just
about broken
so hey let's make some great picks here
now that we can so here we go first one
up
unbreaking 3 efficiency 4 silk touch 1
36 levels very nice
i have another one of these so let's uh
let's get another awesome pick
amazing
not too bad i guess you can't get these
the efficiency for
fortune three unbreaking three by doing
this it's too expensive
oh well and this is a steal of a deal i
gotta say
get unbreaking 3 efficiency 4 pick
for 17 levels nice
there's a guy up there isn't there
i need to clean that up uh but yeah
we're back here now again
i've been under a little bit of a
building frenzy
you know i got called out got called out
on it a little bit uh last episode
i was expecting that but how i never
finished my projects
um which is true
uh i don't mind though you know i i i
love it though i love having like 10 or
projects on the go because then
i have lots to choose from when i want
to work on something
and i actually get to work on what i
want to do for the day
like today i really feel like working on
this place
but if i had to work on this all the
time i would just hate it
but yeah anyway i'm working on the
storage clothes so i got
all three of them hollowed out now got
tons and tons of wood
um and i'm just gonna
get to work here i've actually been hey
i've been farming wood for a few weeks
now just
every now and then i'll cut down
you know four or five stacks of wood
so but this takes a very long time so
i guess i will montage this or speed it
up or skip it or
do something with it
oh very nice so i got a few of these
built now
they're going okay um i tried recording
a montage
and i just i had to scrap the footage it
was so bad i was
fumbling around like an idiot here
they're
uh they're really complicated actually
and i figure out how to build them
so i've made a few now though and i i'm
getting used to the pattern
so i'll just build one on camera so you
know
exactly the torture i'm going through
uh no it's not too bad
it's just gotta be really careful with
the stair placement and all that
so you use stairs so you can still open
the chest that's important
you gotta position them in a way though
that it looks like a solid block
uh from the outside there
and that is a challenge
that okay then we do another three
i do really like this uh
storage idea though um
it looks pretty good like i really like
how it looks actually
and it's also very efficient
actually no i can use solid blocks here
and then to finish it off
do that that
one over here
a few more chests and i'm gonna go ahead
i'm gonna have to cut down some more
trees because i am just blowing through
this wood
the chest you know two logs each
and i'm making so many
all right so that's the general gist of
it
clean up the scrap in front
then i got this border going around the
top so to place that i go like this
and then again this way
and that's about it the item frames go
here
you can still see the stone i'm going to
have to put wood
on the edges there so you can't see this
little bit
but other than that it's it's really
cool
try it out it's good
uh-huh kind of came to my attention just
now
you remember uh that tutorial i did on
the spider tracker
uh slimes make pretty good trackers too
i think they work from farther away
huh this guy
should not be up there
he won't let me up either
all right well i got the storage coves
all done here
is this the slime chunk oh yeah it is
um
i guess what i'll do so yeah i have
slapped the slime chunk here
part of the storage cove is in it now
though
so just one row of it
i'm just gonna put down half slabs for
now to stop them from spawning on top
here
good i think that's right
anyway yeah so the storage coves are
done there's 35
unique items per thing which is quite a
bit
uh each unique item gets a two double
chest so
in total see 35 times 3
is
and 105. times four 420
chests of storage that's a lot i hope i
did that right otherwise i
just embarrassed myself um
they look good though i like them
so now i've been working out out here a
little bit
on the stairs i think i got this
pretty much figured out this is how i
have the stairs laid out
at the moment and i might keep it like
that
and then i think it'd be cool to have
like a column up here
like a decorative column
and then on top i would like these
these uh the settings layer to connect
to each other somehow so
maybe i don't know one option i thought
is like doing a quarter circle from
from there that kind of comes around to
this
uh it might look a little weird from
below there though so
another idea is to make it go
this way and wrap around to that side
and make it like a three-quarter circle
that could be cool or maybe even have it
go up
to a third story in a three-quarter
circle away
and like have stairs right here that go
up
but yeah pretty good
pretty good so i thought about it
i talked about maybe using ice or snow
snow
or you know what
the bat squeaking very annoying i love
the sound they make when you kill them
though
come on come on i don't want to hit that
item frames
that almost makes it worth the new sound
for the squeaking
i love that
right so sorry i got distracted uh
ice sandstone or snow
i sort of talked about and i've decided
i'm going to get rid of the snow
uh it's a hard choice to make because a
lot of people did like it
i don't mind it too much but i don't
know it just seems out of place
especially since we got all this wood
now and i like the wood
so i want to keep the wood uh so i'm
gonna do sandstone instead of the snow
so this will be sandstone this
over here the walls are going to be
sandstone
these things in the middle will be
and all in all i think that will look
better
to be honest
yeah because it just it i don't know it
just doesn't seem to go with this
all that good it makes me think of hot
chocolate and marshmallows for some
reason
which yeah that's what i'm going to work
on now i'm going to replace this ring of
snow with sandstone
i'm going to try change the walls with
sandstone and just mess with that for a
little bit
oh there we go guys i have finished the
transition over to sandstone
and you know what i think it looks a
whole lot better
personally personally i think it looks a
lot better
because it still has that same contrast
that the snow had still still a lot
brighter than
the wood but it it's more of an
earth tone so it matches better
and it's not as bright like i did this
wall here
looks pretty good as is i still want to
add some more detail to it but could you
imagine if that was snow like it would
just be pure white
i don't think it would look very good
so yeah these though i think they need a
little more character to them
so i'll be changing them up a bit
they're they're too plain
in my opinion and
something else is messing with over here
before this was all this regular wood
i think what i want to do is put ender
chests here
let's see do you think do you think
we'll be able to see through here still
i you know what that'll work yeah i
think that'll work
oh but i can't can't open it
forgot about that i'll have to change
this with a stair
if i want to do this
see do i have any do it like
like that that'll work
very cool so yeah we'll have ender
chests
just twos to bounce out the look another
option maybe is to use an anvil
have an anvil on one side i don't know
so we'll do that
then one thought i had with this little
gap here is to have a
very narrow staircase that goes down to
another level below this one with more
storage
it's one idea another idea maybe
just have a row of
leaves like going oop going along here
that could be cool too because then
it'll look like this
over here
30 30 frames per second very good
i don't know what it is i'm getting so
much like processor lag today
with my computer i think it needs a
reboot it's been almost
i don't reboot my computer very often so
i think it's
probably been about six months or so not
that it
necessarily helps but maybe
um but yeah with these corners i think i
should try to
join these two together somehow like
make an arch
of sorts and also this line this really
sharp line here i don't want that
so i'll have to try to get rid of that
too
and yeah i was going to mess around with
railings up here
and because i'm not overly happy with
the stair thing where you can just walk
off
and it's all one color
but maybe another date for now let's
change this up a little bit
where we've done a lot of building today
i want to
i want to mess with this for a bit so
there's um
aft streams are really the big thing now
um where you
get mob drops to go either
you get mob drops to go to unloaded
chunks basically so either
make them go far away from you
like 144 plus blocks away from you
so that's the item entity still stays in
game but
it won't despawn because it's an
unloaded chunk
um another way of doing it now is to
make or
it's to send stuff to the nether through
portals
but i have this kind of unique situation
where i have an
end portal right here so i want to try
make use of that
and to do that
we're just going to set up a quick test
here
and if this works out well i'll do a
proper setup later
um see
yeah i'm just gonna make a tube goes
right to it
i think i counted and it's nine blocks
long
so i'll have to break it some somehow
and
yeah because if this works i'll be able
to just collect gunpowder all the time
um and i'm pretty sure you can get it to
stack
so i won't have like thousands of
entities in my end here which will just
crash my game when i go into it
i think but that's one thing we gotta
check out
with this that's no good if it crashes
the game okay that'll do
just for a quick test let me put that
there
and um
i'm really scared of doing this oh
boy breaking ice with all his wiring
oh and i missed oh
oh man that freaked me out
okay good it's just a bit short
um what's the quick way we can fix this
i guess there isn't
any is there
um i'm gonna make this look really ugly
just because i'm oh i almost did it it's
because i'm lazy to get blocks right now
and there and
okay so that'll work for for testing
anyway
and we'll take out this trap door
so we're going to go above break that
lights
and kind of curious
if they will die when they hit the water
because if if it's positioned right
the mobs will actually die even though
they landed
in water
and i think i need to sleep because
there's not really any mob spawning
very good so any moments now
the other option is to put a fence above
and water on top that
which is probably what we're going to
have to end up doing
but i kind of want to see one of these
guys fall down
any any moment now would be perfect
come on guys where are you
nope they're not cooperating so i'm
gonna cut it one sec
okay so i got a few of them coming down
now
and some of them are dying some of them
are not so
i can't remember if i had vines
resetting their drop
height i thought i did
i think i need two vines for that
um
oh no i never did put vines okay so that
would explain why they're
some of them are dying and some are not
so i'll have to add that
uh but anyway
let's get a few guys going through here
and see what happens
okay i didn't see him fall through um
i'll actually have to really watch out
for that because they could jam things
up i think
xp orbs don't fall through the fence
that's interesting
okay so next
uh we're gonna do this thing again where
i fill up my inventory and just see
what's going on on the other end here
so all mob drops i'll pick that up later
don't worry
i'm not gonna throw away tnt
oh throw that out
okay i think that's good let's go check
it out what's going on
see if it stacks
okay it's not stacking
wow the leg
yeah it's not stacking
so i wonder
what should i do about that i'm pretty
sure anything i build here is going to
get destroyed which is a tough part of
this
um maybe
um i have an idea
or at least something else i want to try
here
if we have water
i'm not too sure how this all works yet
um we're going to place a few blocks see
if they disappear we're going to try
uh have ice or no water we'll have water
see if that disappears and also
we'll have the source block away from
the obsidian
but we'll have it flowing to it and see
if
see what happens with that too
okay
all right we're gonna re-enter and just
see what all gets destroyed here
major lag again
okay so the water stream got destroyed
and it did not update
darn that would have been nice if it
updated
hmm
yeah i'm not sure if we can make them
stack anyway
unless we do it before they enter but
ideally you'd like it to do it in here
um
all right
so this isn't something i've tried
before but i i broke a block
in the platform and i replaced the
middle with a fence
and i'm going to go through and just see
what happens
hmm is the platform going to get moved
is the fence going to be destroyed
what's going to happen
it's going to get replaced okay
what if we place a boat on the platform
if we do that the boat will
stay
that is interesting okay
so the cool thing about a boat
is it will raise items up enough where
they should
stack possibly depends if they're
getting snap to position
um they probably won't stack but if
they're moving at all and it's
it's attempting to stack them they will
i'm pretty sure so and try this again
put the boat right in the middle
throw a bunch of items through the
portal and see if they will stack then
okay here it is i've thrown about 50
zombie flesh in
and i've also moved around my cursor as
i was doing it
make sure we can't pick them up we'll go
through and just see
they did not stack okay so it's not
it's not checking to see if they
need to
pretty sure pretty sure
not the best place to test that um
well it doesn't matter either way we
can't do it
hmm yeah so if i want to stack them i
gotta do it before they enter the portal
well i've thought about it and i'm going
to do this afk stream
anyway just because i don't think it'll
be a problem
i would need to have lots of and lots of
entities like thousands i think
to ever cause a serious problem where it
will
crash the game instantly because
as soon as i go through the end portal
i'm going to pick up whatever items will
fit in my inventory anyway which will
greatly
reduce the number of them right off the
bat
um
i think i gotta get rid of the water in
the silverfish farm
so yeah you you know that lag that just
happened
um that will happen every time we cross
that border
let's see well actually there's not even
that many silverfish maybe that was
something else
there we go
but it's being caused by the sound
engine if i turn the sound off
the game runs so much smoother like
there's some serious problems with it
oh isn't that much nicer you can run
around and
your game doesn't freak out like that oh
it would be so much better
so hopefully they re re write the sound
engine or something sometime
um oh yeah and the thing with the boats
the thing with the boats i was talking
about i'll just demonstrate it
a little bit better over here
because the range of the sound is 16
blocks so once i pass that it freaks out
uh with all the mobs clustered together
so yeah they pretty much always stack if
you have a boat there
i just put that there to demonstrate
anyway i think that's it for this
episode
let's go read the comments and i'll say
goodbye to you guys
also another little small addition i've
added as i start putting some of these
item frames around hello uh my place
here and i think they had a lot
of character to it they look good
especially like this one
i don't want to add too many though
it'll overdo the effect
but anyway here is the comment i picked
for today
dear etho will you be worried or scared
about the redstone changes slash bug
fixes in 1.5
just wondering very very gentle face
yes i am worried i am really worried
what they're gonna do
because i really like the redstone in
this game and i
i hate the fact they're tampering with
it kind of because i'm worried that
it's not gonna be as good afterward um
it's the fear of change basically that's
all i have who knows they might even
make it better if they tamper with it
but
the fear of change has me worried yes um
from i'm not really sure why they're
changing it exactly i
i think it's because they want to make
it more user friendly
which i don't know i'm not too happy
about that
because i think by doing that they're
gonna
have to get rid of some
functions of it make it simpler and you
won't be able to do as much
with it i'm pretty sure
and sure it would be good if it's more
user friendly but
honestly the way it is i don't think
it's not user friendly like
it's complicated it you want it to do
complicated things so you want it to be
complicated once you understand and have
a little experience with it it's not too
bad you
like i hear people always complaining
about how it does such unpredictable
things
it's not really unpredictable once you
have some experience with it
granted there are a few very rare and
strange things that can occur
those sometimes can even become
something cool
like the bud switch that was an
unexpected
condition of redstone that became
something great
as another reason i'm worried about the
change because i've heard rumors that
they're going to get rid of bud switches
which would really suck because they're
so awesome
and a big part of the game now although
i have also heard rumors that they
might introduce a block type to
carry out the same function as a butt
switch so who knows
who knows i will say though if they're
aiming to optimize redstone that is a
good thing any optimizations to this
game they can make
awesome in fact that's where i would
recommend the focus
because as it is right now at least for
me it runs kind of crummy
um and people have commented about this
like i constantly get these
leg issues when i'm recording now ever
since 1.3
the game has taken a big performance
hits
but i could probably tamper with my
system and get squeeze a few extra
frames per second out somehow
i just need to get at it one of these
days
um but yeah fear of change yes i am
worried
anyway i'm going to get going guys
thank you for watching and i will see
you next time