I found a skeleton dungeon these things
are crazy now I think this is the first
one I found since they buff skeletons
and I wasn't even able to get in it I
just got shot to death
all right let's disable it with a punch
bows and and armor and stuff these guys
get now it's actually really hard to
take these over and I have tons armor on
right now so a little bit of a story
what am I doing here I came to get the
horses they're up above there and I
forgot a saddle alright
so instead of going back I decided hey
let's go caving maybe I'll find a
dungeon and maybe I'll get some saddles
in the dungeon so we are about to find
out oh and we even got a name tag I
didn't think these would generate here
oh sweet nametag you got a saddle
efficiency one projectile protection
three very cool and by the way these are
the first emeralds I've ever gotten in
this world because we're in extreme
Hills right now and this is newly
generated terrain so finally have
emeralds in my world
still gave in here and I see one in the
distance let's go check it out looks
like a spider one no chest ah robbed
found another one
zombie dungeon two chests this is
promising to saddles awesome oh man
touch a book and nametag I can get silk
touch tears finally hey and I didn't
even have to enchant it myself that's
awesome those those are extremely hard
to get like 1% chance or something crazy
that is amazing here's another first
guys I was just coming out of here and
there is an iron zombie that must be new
I'd even know that was added because
before it was this chainmail leather and
gold
well that was a very successful TV
expectation expedition
look at all this stuff Wow when I see
coal now I feel the need to always get
it with fortune because he can store it
really easy and you know we might build
stuff out of it I don't know I don't
know I just can't leave it behind now
got three saddles two named eggs eight
emeralds my first emeralds checked out
protection silk touch book totally cool
30 redstone very nice and I was just
looking here I think we have a tough key
I had how did I miss this guy when we
came here before did he just take damage
wait are these new horses oh these are
new horses what the heck I'm lost
I thought are are they
tonight yeah he kicked me up this is not
the white horse I found the other day
there's another black one here so I must
have found through the new set of horses
and anarchy yes oh he likes us well man
like this the first time Wow okay well
we got to get a donkey for sure Oh what
was the donkey called in Shrek is it
just don t I think it was just don t
yeah that's not gonna work
Wow another black horse there okay well
well im gonna tame all these guys and
I'll probably ride that donkey home then
all right we're in the nether now I'm in
like super adventure mode lately this is
so much fun I wanted to get three wither
skulls today so we could maybe try fight
a wither on a horse today it could be
fun I got one already but the other
wither farm area that I was gonna set up
kinda stinks really so I'm kind of just
going around looking for new fortresses
hopefully finding one that will spawn
lots of wither skeletons and this one
actually looks pretty good like it's in
a lava lake tons of lands or responible
area for the withers even this room here
and this intersection that they're right
next to each other so that's a big chunk
of space where they could spawn and I
did find a chest here I'm about to look
in it for the first time these are new
and fortresses now Oh baby good stuff
good stuff I'm hoping to find oh there's
another one hoping to find some more
nametags and stuff
alright guys saddle actually let's just
take a quick look through here I'm
wondering how common these actually are
let's go yeah this looks like a pretty
good fortress for a farm I wonder if
there's lava on this side too
there's quite a bit yeah
a little bit of land here which I don't
like but very good fortress and we have
courts in this area looks like it has a
lot of vertical height to it got another
chest two more saddles these things are
all over the place and dead end here
oh yeah look right in the middle of lava
lake that's perfect
well guys that was definitely some
excellent caving and adventuring there
we are going to do something with that
fortress I'm pretty sure and we got lots
of good stuff today too even found I
think we we know where there's like 20
horses now it's which is like what do I
do with all those horses there's so many
but I think we'll build some kind of
stable in the cave here at some point
soon we did get our weather skeleton
sore and try to fight the wither at the
end of this episode but first I want to
do some building and also I do want to
try a few things here these name tags
I read you got to name them in the anvil
to use them so we're gonna name Zenith
for sure Zenith Oh make sure I spell it
right or I'll have to live with that
actually I think you can rename stuff
too I wanted to name Jeff the villager
but I read you can't actually name
villagers I just we could try it though
just to make sure that guy he's a sneaky
guide you definitely want to know where
he is zenith and Jeff I'm sure I'll get
plenty of nametags
I do caving quite a bit I really like
these they're a nice addition so you can
put them on hostile mobs and stuff and
they won't be spawn they're very cool
all right Zenith
oh yeah there we go
Zenith so now we can see his name when
we get close to him you have to be very
close it looks like and we'll go check
out sneaky old Jeff here it's really
hard to tell these two parts one of them
is Tom and the sneaky guy is Jeff
unlicensed guy and when you tell them
apart it's very tough
obviously the sneaky guy's not gonna
agree to us so it's this is Jeff but
yeah I don't think I can actually name
him darn I guess we'll never know we'll
always wonder maybe in time who knows so
yeah I want to do some building today
that I have to machine things I want to
build if possible one of them is that
mini farm which I made a tutorial for I
think about a month ago which I'll
probably just put that in on my own and
show you after it because I've shown how
to build it's question is where we gonna
put this stuff actually maybe over in
this area because this is new new area
and it's all barren like there's no
nothing on these walls or anything so we
could put some machines here I think
let's just test this out make sure we
have space to put stuff both the things
I want to build are pretty small so I'm
not too worried about space yeah we
could put stuff here let's looks like a
solid wall with nothing behind I'll
check up a little bit yeah that's good
oh got some cobble there I know the
spider farm is very close to this it's
just over I see this quite a ways away
one of them is over here so I'll go
ahead and start setting that up probably
put it's right here and then the other
thing we'll put beside it or something
awesome so we got our mini farm built
here this
is very very handy to have I've wanted
to make one in my world here for a while
I made it tutorial on this about a month
ago so I'm not going to go into super
detail on how it works both I let the
kind of open just so we could get an
overview basically this is for growing
carrots cocoa beans wheat and potatoes I
don't have any potato seeds though but
yeah these dispensers they have bone
meal in all three of them and when we
step on this pressure plate just runs a
clock that makes this go up and down
chests are just for extra bone meal
storage hold right click and should work
yet we're getting more carrots than you
start with really simple if we take a
look down here this is the clock which
only gets activated when that goes off
further down we have some wiring it's a
little blocked up but yeah like I said
there is a tutorial on this if you want
to know let's finish closing this off
and we'll move on to our next project
next thing I want to build is a snow
golem farm for getting snow this is
about done right I did bring some chests
we could either put two chests inside
here for storing stuff or maybe we want
to put them over here even see I'll
probably put lamps and then the chests
on top so we can hide some lighting that
way on the outside here but yeah we're
gonna start the snow snow farm here and
I'm gonna get my stuff together for that
and we will begin so I don't know
exactly how I want to build this thing
the thing about snow golems they can
only leave a snow trail in certain
biomes and in some biomes they actually
die like desert and in the nether
they'll just die in there we're not
gonna stuff there it is
this is forest biome though we're gonna
put it over here pretty sure they'll
leave us no trail
a forest biome and I think a mountain
one I know they don't in a plane so yeah
look at that that's good
sorry you did not live long poor guy
but it's for science yes we'll mind this
out actually let's mark that spot so I
don't forget it I try to make stuff
symmetrical when I can and not that it's
super important but it does help to make
things look better in the end of the in
the end of everything so when I made the
snow my giant snow mob firm at the other
base I I have to get a lot of snow
harvested from these guys and I learnt
the two most painful parts of that is
picking up the snow after you you
collect it and then crafting it into
snow blocks it's probably the worst part
of it there's no real way to get around
that but we can Otto collects know with
hoppers and stuff so what we're trying
to do here and regardless I need the
snow farm for whenever I do a snow
project so if we do this all right it'll
leave us no trail he won't make it
outside of the glass area though until
we power these let's go ahead and try
that there we go I pushes them to the
corner and then he does this and we can
harvest that get snowballs the question
can we make that snow trail on top of a
hopper because if we can that simplifies
things greatly and it doesn't look like
it
No okay so that's it that makes it a
little more complicated I've thought of
this so I think the what the way we're
gonna deal with that is we're going to
use a hopper minecart instead like so
then I would like get on a track - we
can't really put it on a track like if
we put the track there we won't get the
snow if we do it this way push it
towards them
why did that go up does this does it
have a collision box to it now yeah we
could do something like that and that
collects it then the only question is
what do we do with the snow I guess yeah
let's put a hopper here since we can and
we can put a track on that that'll drain
the snowballs out of there that actually
is pretty slow though isn't it so
another idea is we could have another
hopper minecart underneath that block -
and then we'll have its exporting in two
places
fireeyes yeah I like that idea all right
well I'll work on that a little bit here
and see how it goes
I'm just wondering now if we were to get
rid of this hopper and just have a chest
there would it be able to put stuff in a
chest like it filled up huh should we
try to do this look for it as well or
should we try to do a snow look I wonder
maybe we'll just give this one a shot
and see what it looks like let's just
test this hopper minecart underneath -
and make sure that works picking it up
doesn't look like it did get any is
there any in the hopper oh there is some
good so that I'll pick up a few
snowballs but this will be the main one
we do that and then have a double chest
below we need a big storage tank for the
snowballs you like double chests there
then we need hoppers again so Auto
hoppers I forget how to make hoppers
chess just like that okay all right if
we do it this way we'll need some way of
getting down here to access the chest -
or at least the very bottom one that's
two double chests I would like at least
three I think
has a long ways down
mmm that looks better actually we should
have done that with this one oh yeah
much better so if we want to keep the
would look we should also probably get
rid of the glass give it a wood
background wood sides ah yeah tell you
what let's put a crafting table over
here instead of a wood block because
we'll definitely need one of those
around here
Oh what do we have here this is
unexpected
I was looking for our old with her
fighting spot I'm about ready here and I
stumbled across the village this is one
we apparently found but just never saw
because it's like the old I should have
better to watch this guy he's gonna run
into cactus it's in a desert but it's
not a desert village so that was old old
generation and it's only two houses huh
I must have gone too far then alright I
think this is where we fought the
withers before so we'll do it again here
today and this should be pretty
interesting not only are we doing it
with Zenith today but I haven't fought
with her in a long time and I know the
nerf protection armor in that time
before all you really needed was maxed
out protection and a regen potion and
you would not die so now I'm not really
sure I think we're gonna take a lot more
damage and with Zenith the horse
I have no idea how horse health really
works or I is the wither gonna target me
or zenus I'm not sure is wither gonna
really nail this guy I don't know I was
hoping to get armor from that fortress
today but it just didn't happen
so what do you think Zenith you up for
the challenge
lift your head up if you are oh yeah oh
I think he's ready let's see that
ferocious smile of yours come on oh yeah
he knows he knows what he's up against
he can handle it he's got 14 hearts this
guy come on you'll be fine
so I got a pretty good Armour power five
bow sharpness four sword I was hoping I
had it smite five around but I didn't so
we will have to make do with that and
got quite a few potions maybe should
have grabbed some more I don't know
we'll see how it goes if it gets bad we
might just run I don't know but here we
go
regen speed to fire resist don't think
maybe need fire is this Steven my plan
is to just kind of like try backpedal
and use the speed of the horse to our
advantage here I hope that works
oh look at this oh yeah this Domenici on
keep going Xena you're doing great
haven't even got hit yet what is going
on oh oh oh no you got it Xena don't
give up you're amazing oh and this guy
is taking damage he'll we got him Yahoo
Wow okay let's not do that again that
was a close call
oh look at us we are amazing
oh I buried you back on make sure he
doesn't die you okay oh you're still
you're still hurting there you go
you'll be fine yeah he's taking wither
damaged he took a ton of damage that was
risky oh man he's still getting hurt
oh you know a Zenith died like I do have
20 other horses but I cannot replace it
ena he is special he's he's amazing I
would I don't know if I could have lived
with myself if something happened to him
that was that was a big risk actually
worse than I thought it was but we we
survived you survived that backpedalling
worked really good because normally the
withers rate in your face and on the
horse here it's like you can keep your
distance and he can't hit you and you
can still shoot like you when you pull
back on a bone normally you did a speed
reduction but I think on a horse you can
keep moving yeah look at this
that's pretty cool
that's a nice mechanic there
we got another nether star I can make
another beat into I've always wanted to
put one in the nether and see how that
works I've heard you can so we'll
probably do that soon but wow what a
victory yeah so I guess let's go read
the comments guys that was pretty cool I
don't think I'm gonna do that I didn't
know till we get armor for this day
because I I think that could have gone
either way to be honest all right guys
we got two comments picked out for today
and yeah this guy I didn't put any
chests on him because I don't think
that's been implemented yet I think
we're gonna wait to do that and I'm not
sure if I could breed them after I do
that it's a bit risky but you had two
comments for today number one
hey etho nicely done and good to see
that you put the horse to work right
away and treating it well oh yeah only
the best of care for Zenith anyways I
got a question I'd like to ask you that
is have you ever considered making an F
TV series let's feed the beast series
besides your mind track one hmm no
that's not gonna happen
when I make a new series I would like it
to be different something something that
needs a new series feed the beast
minecraft is very different from my
single-player let's play here because
not only is it modded minecraft play
it's a collection of mods but it is also
a multiplayer while this is
single-player so the two are very
different even though I I treat both
like a let's play style they are quite
different from each other if I was to do
a single-player feed the beast it would
be like the multiplayer one I'm pretty
sure so no real point to it unless the
multiplayer one goes away for some
reason which it
it doesn't seem like it's gonna do so no
not gonna happen
number two I did a typo by the way I put
81 oh well II thought I'd loved all the
pvp stuff from you and other mine
crackers
I think the calamity PvP videos were
some really good videos and I've
actually been hungry for more lol well
that's good to hear thank you I talked
about PvP in my last episode hell even
though it's something I really like and
lots of people like it's not quite as
popular as other things at the moment in
Minecraft that's good to see some people
like it and there will definitely be
more don't you worry
in fact we're doing UHC right now which
is a type of PvP and hype hype I know a
lot of people like you HD so check that
out if you're interested anyway I guess
that's it for I think you could name a
bat now with nametag oh no he's getting
away
oh man he was hard to get he's a fighter
but yeah that's all for today guys thank
you for watching and I will see you
again next time