[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and here we are
once again ready to do
something we're gonna do something i
don't know exactly what
but there's something i have planned
um just a fun project
remember i showed you the zombie spawner
here the other day
i kind of want to make like a villager
separator the zombie villager separator
thingy
majig because it a zombie spawner will
spawn both zombies
and the zombie villagers
which is pretty cool now there is a new
snapshot out
and the 39a i'm still using 38b though
they've done a lot of changes with the
lighting engine
and i thought it was just going to be
visual stuff but apparently they've
changed game mechanics like lighting
lighting mechanics in the game so i
think
hasslab stuff like this is not going to
work anymore
and i have a lot of stuff to fix so i
want to make sure they're
they're certain what they're doing
before i start switching things around
so
i'm going to wait a little while on that
maybe next snapshot i'll
switch over um
but yeah i'm going to make
kind of drew some rough plans on paper
here i'm going to
have like a a door junction probably
here
or a piston junction with water streams
one
one way or one
one path of the junction will go for
zombie villagers and one path will just
go for regular zombies so
we're gonna split them manually i don't
think there's any other way to do it
oh there's one right there
hey he stole my box that guy
um yeah i don't think there's any way to
automatically do it that i can think of
right now anyway so we'll have a manual
splitter and then i want to do some
fancy thing with carts just for the fun
of it so
gonna go get glass and all that fun
stuff and we'll get going here
actually you know what it occurred to me
i should
no
okay are you still in the minecart
dang that really messed up my test
i think he is i was trying to see what
happens
when he converts if he'll stay in the
mine cart or not
oh no he he is not in the mine cart so
when he converts he gets
put out of it so that might affect
my design choice here it's good to know
ah this thing's still spawning zombies
so i'm gonna move the lighting around
we have it in a square shape like that
if we do if we just move them a little
bit i think we can stop it completely
but yeah we figured out a few things in
creative mode there
um let's see
if we i think if we move the lamps to
there that should work
yeah they go out of the carts um
when they convert i also did a few other
tests like i wanted to see how long it
takes them to convert so i
i set up four guys and time them
all four of them and it seems like it's
a random amount of time like they didn't
all change at the same time
but it was about three to four minutes
is how long it takes them
um also if you
if they have if the zombie villagers
have armor on and they convert
they lose it when they switch to
villagers so it's another thing i
figured out that's too bad it would be
cool if you could have
villagers with like swords and and armor
and
like enchanted armor or something that
would be cool
i think that'll stop him
[Music]
whoa there's a lot of zombies down here
already
and what else what else
yeah i'm also i didn't try this but i'm
guessing like if you
if you heard a zombie villager and like
get them down to half heart and they
convert
when they convert the villagers will
have full life but i'm just
assuming that i haven't i didn't
actually try it
but anyway to get this thing going
we need to move the zombies at least
eight blocks away from the spawner
so let's see where we at
one two three
four five
six seven eight so we need them to come
to at least here so that they'll they'll
keep
spawning from that spawner there
something like this should work out
pretty good so we'll just put
signs to hold our water
water will go there and there
oh you know what i just realized
something um
i was going to put another ice block
right here but i'll make an infinite
spring
unless i put it back further
all right anyway uh we'll put our signs
down
there and one there
get some glass going we'll so we'll
we'll probably stand around here we have
to be close enough to the spawner
that it will keep going and
would kind of like to set up a control
panel somewhere for this but we'll we'll
get to that later
i have to adjust this a bit yet
break that wait
break this one uh let's see how's this
gonna go for the zombies
they'll come through here and they'll
have to go up so we'll put
one there one here
one above that
so i've been playing this game called uh
faster than light lately
oh man am i addicted to that
oh it's so much fun it's very simple
simple game it looks simple and very
very basic graphics on it but
the game design on that is very good
um the day i got it i think i played it
eight hours
just could not stop i finally
shook the addiction a little bit but i
still
still been playing it quite a bit
all right um
so yeah maybe what we'll do
just put another water or block
one more back here
we just want we want a diagonal water
stream going here so that we can set up
a junction
we're doing it we're doing it the old
school way here
all right i need that okay um
it's been a while since i've done this i
need to go back
one more
see let's put glass for now
and that's
that there
okay that should work now
so when they'll meet it'll make a
diagonal water
okay and now we need to set up our
switch
i had this big plan for what i want to
do with the mine carts but if they
if they go out of the mine carts when
they convert i might have to rethink
that all
or simplify it or do something else i
don't know
that's a great way of like detecting
when they change though because you can
like you can have a minecart on top of a
painting
with a hole below and when they convert
they'll fall through and land on a
pressure plate or
tripwire or something and you can know
when they
when they switch over
um okay so so one path will go this way
one path will go straight will make the
zombie villagers go straight
here
and the zombies the regular ones will go
over here we're going to use i think
trapdoors for our junction
so give me a second to set that up
because that will probably take me a
little bit
oh yeah we got some stuff done here now
so this is the junction
this is a hole this is the junction
just a trap door thing
so yeah if it's closed if they're both
closed uh
the mobs will get stuck here
it's important that it opens to the left
here so that i don't get
or the the mob stone gets stuck on this
little little piece of the trapdoor
they'll be on aligned to the right side
here and should go through
and same with this one it opens to the
right
so away from where the water is pushing
and they can go this way and i got that
neatly
wired up to over here
so one of them will always be open and
one will always be closed
to pick the path
and sort as they come through here i can
eyeball is it is it a zombie villager or
is it a zombie
and up for villager that will make them
go straight
into this this path here see the doors
open
or if it's down they will come through
this way
and still got to set up paths for them
though
all right um i guess i'll show you the
wiring real
quick
are people finding me
i did close it off okay good with the
new with the the mabe eye you
can't be too careful
but anyway i got uh there's redstone
torches that come up from below there
um yeah let's see
the lever's there redstone wire comes
all the way to
here then up to here redstone torches
then to the repeater to this this block
here
which will trigger the trap door
also has wire that goes to this
inverter and then to there which is
above the door
so that's how that gets switched
and i also set up another one for
controlling the
the lights up there
that's awesome instant for zombies
uh maybe we'll just try this out
that one was special he had a shovel
very simple he made him go there too
cool that's all there is to it
to this part of it anyway
let's see
make them be quiet so
i'll set up a killing system for these
guys
but the main the main focus of this is
going to be
setting up a holding area for the zombie
villagers i think i have to keep them
all separate from each other
otherwise they'll like start killing
each other as they change i think
possibly so i need to get them into
their own separate areas
where i can give them the apples and
have them convert and i would like to
have mine carts to send them off
somewhere
of my of my choosing location of choice
all right so sadly i don't have a whole
lot of time to record today it's
it's partially partially because i've
been
addicted to that new game but it's also
just busy with other stuff and
had a lot of multiplayer stuff come up
we have that race for the wool thing
our first match coming up on saturday
which i've had to practice for and
there's been some minecraft stuff we've
been doing so we're
i'm in that testing mood so one thing i
wanted to check out is beacons
um i heard a rumor
okay it does melt ice i heard a i think
it's light level 15.
but i heard a rumor that uh
after you play some you can't pick them
up which i want to
check out for myself because i would be
a little bit
upset if i put one down and i couldn't
move it not knowing that
all right so i'll try with the diamond
pick first
okay you can pick it up again cool what
about
with an iron takes a really long time to
okay and stone
oh cool okay any pick
take your pick any pick
all right another thing i want to check
is it's
is it going to be affected by a creeper
blast
although it might it might have to be
powered like working before you can't
pick it up we should check that out too
i was really excited about these beacons
and i've talked to a few people
and not as many people
i should say people don't seem to be as
excited as i was when i first heard
about them i don't
know why that is
destroyed it but it did drop it
okay
let's try this one more time last one
i want a real creeper
real creeper my bags my bags
there we go yeah game mode
i guess i could just punch him either
way
yeah creepers can definitely take it out
okay so we know that now i want to see
like the effects
the thing that i'm really excited about
with these is the speed
the speed boost you can get and also
the the haste because there's no other
way of doing haste in this game
where you mine quicker
so i think let's just do
a full-blown one i think five by five
five by five is right i think it needs
to be solid
oh wait no i think it can get bigger
yeah i think this is only a level two
all right so if we i think we have to
feed it
okay there's regeneration regeneration
is always on we don't have the choice
for strength
we yeah we only have this level
so if i go to survival
i am not being affected by it so i think
we have to
power it
as far as i know it doesn't matter what
you power it with so let's
oh yeah there's jump boost i forgot
about jump boost
oh this is like all stuff you can't get
resistance jump boost taste
very cool uh let's pick
let's pick the haste one out haste two
can we pick more than one no
that is awesome oh i gotta try this out
we're just gonna use a regular diamond
pick
so i guess
let me think how's that work
though the bigger you make it i know the
further the range is
on it i wonder if you get more choices
too because i see strengths
not an option i think you gotta go up
one higher for that
um all right game mode well what should
we break let's break
let's just break some stone
and then we'll try we'll try mine this
again afterward and see if we can pick
it
up and that's about all i wanted to
check out
oh yeah that's that's quite a bit
quicker
pretty cool let's see how far away it
works
at level two
where is it it's up there
i think that like the max level it works
it has like a diameter of 80 blocks
which is pretty
awesome
uh yeah we're pretty close to it now
it's still not giving it to us
there it is huh
so i would like to have these in my my
man cave for sure
i was i was wondering like on the
minecraft server i'm digging that hole
it might be cool to set one of these up
there to speed that up too
anyway back to the lp world that was
cool to check out
okay so i set up a full-blown pyramid
now i just wanted to see if it would
change
or what it would all change so i got all
five attributes i'm just
a tad too far away to get two of them
there we go all five
uh it is it's an 80 diameter
cube around with the the beacon at the
center
it seems so even diagonally 40 blocks
both directions it works it's not a
not circle shaped uh
it's pretty cool man
so if you wanted to keep it symmetrical
you would
do an odd odd number like this
they can share share blocks with each
other
obviously though the best way of doing
it is just to do
a two by two thing of beacons and just
forget one of the traits
probably strength you don't really need
strength
but like on on the minecraft server my
my room is 75
in diameter so this is perfect if i had
in the center
um i would probably do it like this
another option would be to hide it
hide them in the walls so you couldn't
even see them and that could be pretty
cool too
like behind walls
and i tried like getting a better pick
to see if it would still
get the effects of the haste
and and none of the attributes are
improved like they're all still level
one speed
level one haste even though it says
level two on the beacon
it seems to be level one where is it
there it says haste two but i think it's
really only haste one
strength jump boost jump boost only lets
you jump
uh an extra half block in height like
you can't even jump two blocks
it's kinda sad but you jump one and a
half at least
and what else yeah i'll show you this
that's the speed with the efficiency 4
and haste one
it is quicker than than without it
that is for sure let's let's go over
here i'll show you
should wear off around here it's pretty
good range
but it would take a lot of iron in that
oh i'm floating
wait a minute maybe it's not that much
faster that seems
pretty similar
it's hard to say it's not it's not as
noticeable as i would have liked
you notice it more with an unenchanted
pick i would say
okay let's try it again
yeah you know what i think that's the
same speed
um that's disappointing
oh well anyway uh the main the main
effect i like is the speed one
um it would have been cool if haste was
better but
it is what it is
uh huh all right we're back in lp world
this guy just splat right next to me
uh anyway it's common reading time what
do the people have to say today
we have a two-part comment dear etho
i don't think i'm the only one wondering
this
does your minecraft blaze farm work
better than your single player worlds
the one in my single player world it
does not it's
my single player one is at least twice
as quick
i would say just because a lot of them
on minecraft die in the water it's uh
i don't know it just comes part like
i wanted to use water for the fun of it
and it's
it had a negative effect too but
other options to set up a whole ton of
pistons which is extremely laggy and
yeah so there's problems with both
methods but my single player one is
quicker
also i think you should start giving a
download link to just your good
creations
by that i mean using mcedit to make a
schematic
so we can just import it into our worlds
i would love to have your mindtrack
blaze farm in my
world thanks
well you know you can copy stuff
and i think shri has provided the
download before
um but really to have fun in this game
even if you're taking like almost
copying someone's design if you just add
a little bit of your own touch you'll
have a lot more fun to it like don't do
don't do an exact copy try try make it
your own somehow
and you'll probably enjoy it a lot more
it's just my recommendation so i'm not
gonna be doing that
uh anyway i'm gonna get going and i'll
hopefully get another lp episode out
soon to make up for
the easy one i did today okay guys
have a good day
[Music]