[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho welcome
i just had a scare
that's one thing you don't want to ever
see in your wiring
so i started working on
the furnace room while i was watching a
video and i realized
like without even realizing it i was
working on it and i
sort of stopped myself because i was
supposed to do this
while recording but i was working on
this arch
just want to see what this looks like
and do the same over here
get rid of this i don't know if i want
to keep this room it was like this room
wasn't supposed to be square but it's
starting to turn very squarish or
rectanglish
not sure if that's good or bad
put that there
uh-huh that's a nice uh that's a nice
entrance to it
i like how it's open this room
is probably one of my favorites i've
ever made to be honest
the storage room
and this one is very similar to it so i
like it a lot
as well uh what did i want to do
i should have planned things a little
better before i started i guess
well i'll show these working um
had some feedback on them people said i
should try lava behind
the iron instead of the leaves
i'm happy with the leaves i'm going to
leave it as the leaves
and also people suggested i should
invert these so
they're on by default and off when
they're cutting but
i don't know it just seems seems wrong
to do it that way
so i'll keep it like that as well i
i'm gonna try to put a piston door here
wait i remember if i decide if i want to
keep it like that
yeah we probably can i'm gonna try to
put a piston door here
just a one a one wide by two high
type door
these will squish together and hopefully
i have enough room to do the wiring for
this
she i might not hmm
well that shouldn't power it
i don't i'll try and make it work give
me a minute
i don't know guys there's really not
much room back here
so we're just gonna do the iron door i
think because we can't put anything next
to this piston
and we can't we got the wire right above
there so
instead we are going to do an iron door
how does it look if we flip it
and that
and this
sure why not we will put
a button out here and one on the other
side i hate using buttons for doors but
and there
maybe
no why am i using a button i want to use
a pressure plate
or at least on one side we can we could
here if we
switched this
i don't know i i don't really plan on
coming back here ever
or often but i do want an access way to
get back
there somewhere okay
um
i i don't know which one i'm going to
use uh i'll think about it for a sec
this here should we
should we do stairs or should we do full
blocks
we'll try full blocks first
okay if we do stairs
we can see more of this archway
but it might be too much of a
ripple effect going on here
oh no that's not too bad
and this would continue
so i hope you guys are enjoying the huge
series
uh we're uploading those every second
day
and uh
it's a tough map man it was or it is
we're not done it
we're definitely not done it but yeah
it's tough
um mostly because he doesn't give you
stuff and we didn't take the time to
farm
anything really at the beginning
okay
all right now the window hmm
what should we do with the window
well let's try to figure out how we're
going to join this to this next wall
see the thing i'm concerned about is we
got the the nice stone look on this side
but we don't
like it's only one wide so if we make it
stone brick
it's gonna be stone brick on outside and
it'll look weird
if we make this thicker
it's one option
although and remember i'm just putting
the sh i'm figuring out the shape of
things first then we will come
through here and try use different
blocks to add texture
so we could do that uh it really makes
it stand out now
um and it does block the view a little
bit
that way we could have it two different
types of blocks
and then we could put a chest a thing of
chests here like a column of them
for the blaze rods
what to do what to do i don't know
this is another option it opens it up
some more
helps to highlight it
let's try this
no i liked it the other way more
or do i that doesn't look bad either
um one thing i don't like about this
though
because we normally have the furnace
flush with the wall
and on this side the wall would be right
here
it should be more like that
but then this side doesn't really work
unless we take this back further
and i tried adding something like this
but it's not going to work
we can't get rid of these blocks here
we need them
i tried this too not liking it either
i'm still having trouble with this i
think i know the reason
i need this to go back one more block
and then this would be really easy
but i'm not going to do that it's
already
pretty close to the bridge and i don't
want to bring it in a block
so we'll just we'll just make it or try
and make it work like this
i just want to see how to look if we put
chests here with lighting behind
man it's because it's not symmetrical i
should have just made it symmetrical
i wanted i wanted it to have some
character
silly me
that's the spot here it's that's bugging
me the most
ah whatever see another trick we could
do
is i'm sure we could
i just like that
would be weird um
like for example we could
[Music]
what's going on over here we could maybe
hide one
uh where was that there
[Music]
that see now we got to worry about
lighting too is the other thing
we could put a lamp here i'll just use
this for now
and we could or we would need to put one
here to bounce out that look
the window look they would be
symmetrical then
this would have to be one of these
hmm we could put one here
[Music]
and if we do that we'll we need one here
man what am i doing
what am i doing
maybe i'm gonna i'm gonna replace those
with laps see if it looks better
beautiful absolutely
perfect now we're going to take them out
um uh-huh
i think i'm worrying about this too much
to be honest
i've thought about it and really
lighting doesn't matter much in this
room
so we've got half slabs in the middle
mobs won't spawn on those
over here if we look at our block
lighting we're we're well up
in the double digits even we're 12
there this is a block they could
potentially spawn on but it's
we're at 9 or 10 whatever then
this corner again we're pretty light the
only real dark spot
is this corner
drops down to five that's pretty bad we
could hide some
dim lighting in this corner and it would
work out okay i think
uh this is probably eight i'm gonna go
down
check no it is seven
yeah if we hide dim lighting it'll be
okay and then
this i think i'm going to leave these
two in as my
visual indicator that all the furnaces
are done cooking
wait a minute if that shows me when the
furnaces are all done
cooking that means it'll be on most of
the time right
huh never thought of that
well okay
oh boy just started recording that
happened
i have a few dark spots around here
apparently
and actually as i've been recording
today i've been having mobs fall down
here because i've been in the area
uh-huh maybe that's where we came from
uh anyway i'm gonna invert
the master these two these two all
invert so they're off most the time and
if the furnaces are cooking anything
they'll be on yeah
and we'll try to keep this room looking
dark or dim
like it is right now we can hide some
more lighting in the ceiling
which will keep it fairly dim it won't
go
it'll give some lighting like this
middle looks almost too dark
but we could get it up to i'm sure
that's if that was 15 14 13 12 11
10 easily get up to like eight or nine
no problem
uh and then this corner i wanted to try
maybe do one of those over here
i need some iron bars
and then we could hide we could put
leaves and uh
pumpkins below i just want to see how
that would look
it's an idea a week we still need to
find a place for the chest so
i just want to see what this would look
like
that's kind of cool
what happens if we bring it in one more
block
just messing around until i i'm i'm
as happy as i can be with this
uh for the most part i i really like how
this is turning out
i especially like this this door this uh
arch
i don't know why it just looks amazing
to me for some reason
i could do that too
that's without the lighting and if we
have the lighting
we'll do this
and then the iron
i'm not sure which is better i am going
to put the chests here
it's pretty good doesn't look terrible
from the other side either
whoa stop lighting it's raining
still pretty good i think uh what i will
also
do there's a problem if we take these
torches out
well i should say first of all like this
even without the sliding
this room is mob proof because they
won't be able to spawn on this
or over here
or on any of this stuff so even without
this
it's good and we can also still put some
in the ceiling
um but over here without these torches
this this entrance is a little bit dark
goes down to six at my head
um so what i'm going to do is put in
some of those piston lights
right there if i have any
outer pistons
okay yeah we'll just put them
right here
there we'll put pumpkins below
and that'll take care of the walkway no
problem
so even if these are off it'll still be
bright enough here
so that mobs won't spawn
and it will look decent because it's got
the wood texture
oh so that helps us get rid of those
torches
planning right now also lights up this
room a little bit more
you can see we have like a a ring of
light going all the way around the walls
except for here it's it's kind of dark
um what else what else should we do
uh maybe let's mess around with the
noteblocks real quick here
we'll just set some up and see how it
sounds
oh whoa no no no no
that has me very nervous if they can get
in here
there's a spider too okay where are they
coming from
they yeah they're just falling down
it's gotta be it that's freaky
i'll put a i'll box this in once we're
all done
i guess uh but yeah the note blocks
uh we could i believe we can just put it
right above here
and in order for it to play a note we
cannot have a block over top of it
could also put one behind
or
the thing is coming up with a tune
uh a unique tune for each of these i'm
not going to be able to do that very
well
i am not good with note blocks if we put
one
here they'll have a one tick delay too
okay we probably want piano
i think that is soil if i remember right
okay we'll just i don't know we'll just
see how this sounds
two random notes
i'll play with these afterwards and see
if we can make something that sounds
good
uh what can we cook cook stone
yeah we need a delay a longer delay
between the two
all right well that's that's how i'm
going to set them up set them up i'll
have to
have at least a two tick delay though
that was way too quick
oh did it play when it finished here
you have these string no you can use
stairs
okay listen
listen okay so that was on
startup only
we want on finishing so we would need to
invert that
okay i'll play with that off camera i'm
i wouldn't get very far with that today
i also want to just try something with
the ceiling over here
i'm gonna have to end this soon i'm um
some of this i recorded earlier and uh
now this final clip it's the next day
and it's like 1am here so i need to
finish this episode up i'm trying to get
into
recording my episodes more frequently
and i've decided i'm just to make that
happen like it's
gotten to the point where it's every
three or four days
and this is my main series
i should try to increase that but it's
difficult
unless i do shorter
and shorter episodes and i'm trying to
cut
a little less if i can help it
and that will make getting episodes out
a lot easier
and more frequent
with this project it's perfect because
it's it's a small project
and there's lots of variation to it so
you know it doesn't get repetitive quick
there's once you do something it's
you know you start something else pretty
soon and i do have an idea for the
crafting tables uh
i was going to do that today but i don't
think we have time
um could put leaves and lights behind
just just trying things here this is not
definite
how's that if we do something like that
it will mimic the floor
it's too dark that we would need lights
and
needs more shape too i feel it's way too
flat
very rare would you look straight up
this is how this is how
it would look
all right guys excellent so we got a
fair bit done again today we're making
uh constant progress which is what i
like
i was looking at some of my older
episodes today and i talked a lot
when i first started this in fact it was
like episode 40 before i had
the ceiling on the storage room the
first one so
i was quite the talker back then
um that's another reason i wanna
cut a little bit less i don't i'm still
gonna be very careful not to make things
boring
this is my uh bulk storage by the way
where i've been keeping stuff that i
don't have space for in the
in the tiny storage room at the moment
but yeah we we just had the 250k
special-ish sort of um
although i'm still working on that other
project related to it
it as i can i'm not forcing it
as i can i work on it and uh
this episode i believe is 199 so we have
200 coming out
right after this another another big
landmark
200 episodes we've had quite the ride
haven't we
um had a lot having lots of fun doing
this
and i always love the feedback and
everything i've
i have from people i i recognize people
in the comments i see them
frequently same people
so it feels like i have a community
which is great
and uh yeah i don't know what to do for
the 200 though typically
for the that sounds so bad
typically for my uh
landmark episode specials i'll do a tour
so we'll probably do a tour of this
world for sure
and we might go to some of the older
worlds i haven't seen them in a while
and just to you know
show that the new people how this all
came about and also
the people have been watching for a
while give them a feeling of nostalgia
myself included
there's also another thing i might try
to do but it
whether or not it turns out it's going
to depend on
my editing abilities and how much time i
can put into it but hopefully
that works out if you guys have any
ideas which we should do for the 200
special
let me know
this is the let's play i like to include
you guys as much as i can
so feedback is always appreciated but
that is all for today
thank you for watching everyone i hope
you enjoyed it
and i will see you again for the 200
special specialist
thing i don't know how special it's
going to be we'll see when it comes
so thanks everybody