hello greetings welcome everybody this
is etho how are you guys doing today I
am you can probably tell chant you hear
to my voice my morning voice while you
should I'm recording this at 6 a.m.
which is morning but crazy time I
actually woke up at 1 a.m. today so I'm
still on my crazy sleeping schedule
still trying to correct it I talked
about that last episode if you didn't
see it got lots of entertaining comments
on the last episode lots of good
suggestions on what to do and and that
kind of thing too and basically I'm just
about at the point where I'm going to
bed at 10:00 p.m. again and this time
I'm gonna set my alarm I think that's
the big mistake I made and force myself
to wake up at a certain time and
hopefully get set on a morning wake-up
time if all goes well anyway I I've been
working on the Nexus here in my early
early hours of the day or night got a
lot built we just about have the whole
facade part done and then we just need
to put the chests in back here and the
water streams and then we're good to go
but probably next episode or the one
after that we will be able to to move on
with this so what should we do instead
let's go I probably should have planned
that you know I've had some requests
that we work on the village so maybe
we'll just take a look at that today
maybe do a bit there oh where are we yes
we're good yeah ok do the village what
happens if I hit an iron golem in a
village exactly
like I know he gets mad what do the
villagers do does he forget about me or
not oh no he doesn't
alright anyway we're in the village and
I've made my first enemy so slow
no wonder the zombies always kill them
whoa okay I take it back you're cool oh
alright you stay over there for a second
I'm going to put that there so I was
looking around here guys trying to
decide what we need to do I do like the
houses quite a bit slight I liked how uh
how they turned out for the most parts
but the in-between it it needs more
polish right it's pretty rough-looking
in here so first thing I'm just gonna
try put down some passing so definitely
want path like here just gonna do gravel
first and just see what it looks like
and then I might put in another type of
block I do like this ladder thing even
though it tends to kill the villagers
but it's a fun watching them go down the
ladder that it seems to work pretty good
so we'll make the pass come up by here
and also we got stairs here so the path
should go here I have to be careful with
any changes I make here if I take out
torches for example I gotta make sure I
replace those that we're going to have
some zombie issues alright look at them
dance so we will have path there should
we have a path running down to these
houses as well maybe we'll probably take
out this wall at some point and expand
the village some more because I kind of
wanted to make this bigger as well
alright okay so here's the path guys I
decided to try out course dirt and I
mixed in some spruce wood I think it
looks kind of cool now you you're
looking at it you probably don't like it
because as it is right now this village
there's a lot of like plain empty spots
that look pretty clean and the path
looks really rough right but as as I
polish this it's it seems weird saying
polish because I'm actually making it
look more messy but as I add more mess
to the village I think this path will
suit it better than it looks right now
but if not I'll change it okay so second
thing we're going to do we got all these
flower boxes by the houses like these
here I think it's time we update these
so we have coarse dirts nowadays we
don't have to use regular dirts because
it keeps getting grass grown on it so
we'll change that out I'm also not a
huge fan of the yellow and red flowers
anymore never really really like them
either like in the past but it's all we
had but now we have all these nice new
flowers and probably my favorite are the
pink and white tulips and the oxide
daisies in areas like this so where we
have the desert grass I find the orange
flowers look really good and maybe red
ones so we'll probably do that but then
these areas like over here I'm going to
put the pink in why
once I decided it probably makes more
sense to match the flowers to the
building so we kind of got reddish
flowers by the red building blue flowers
by the blue one and green stems by the
green building sure okay next thing
we're going to do they use the orange
building actually like they're able to
find their way up this tiny little
walkway look we're going to change the
layout a little bit here let's move this
back one block I think yeah let's have
like a two wide walkway here and then
we'll let's use dark oak dark oak over
here originally I had like carrots and
stuff growing here but they always
trampled those so no point really
keeping them there we should set up a
proper farm somewhere else oh oh okay I
hit some water apparently oh and there
goes all the torches I'll have to fix
that but here let's maybe position this
like that
cool so check this out guys we got a
much nicer way of getting to the orange
building now nice walkway here and if we
want to expand the village this is a
perfect spot I think we'll take out this
wall and there's even some cave back
here so we'll expand out that way so
that gives us over this way that that
wall there we could expand out and maybe
I think we'll move mr. villager chief
here we're not going to get rid of him
but we'll move him I want to put him in
the ceiling and he'll look down on the
village I think I think that's a better
spot because he's kind of in the way
here actually because we can't really go
out any further he takes up the whole
wall all right well this is what it
looks like now he's a little bit creepy
up there but I think it's pretty good
what I should probably do though is
maybe raise them up very creepy indeed
maybe raise them two or three more
blocks higher I don't like how you can
see his eyebrow his nose like from here
it's just kind of strange he'll raise
them a little bit higher and then I'll I
think it will make a dome ceiling and
really highlight them and make this a
pretty big intersection type of thing
would be cool but not today what we'll
do next we got all these baby villagers
running around what we did
I think they grew up oh there's one
I want to make like a school for them
basically a special house just for them
that only they can enter and I'm think I
want them to get trapped in it so I know
what the new villagers are when they
grow up because they mix up with the
other ones and then I have a hard time
finding the new guys so let's hop into
creative world and we'll just experiment
with that idea yeah okay so I just want
to try test something with their AI I'm
not sure if this will work or not we're
going to make a
fake villager house here then hopefully
they go into and I think that's probably
big enough right so let's try this out
first I'm going to set up a villager
Phil ledger and we'll make it nighttime
times set 15100 is you're going to go
inside yet you went inside good alright
and time now zero come on out I'm going
to make a couple baby villagers next
there we go and we'll block the front
with one block and I want to see if
they'll go through that door still
alright time to go inside oh come on
guys get inside the building it looks
like it's not going to work come on if I
remove the block or they all are going
to run in then where are they going
they're trying to go somewhere
oh they see the house I think but they
can't figure out how to get inside I
remove it nope I think maybe the
building is just too small because even
without the block there they're not
going inside they keep running to the
back ok I'll make it bigger
ok let's try it again times it's
nighttime everybody inside
ok the little guy got in yeah it does
work ok cool the big guy can't get in as
much as he tries well it's still a work
in progress guys but our village now has
a school somewhere for the little guys
to be bored during the day that's right
so this is the front of it not totally
happy with this front I'll probably
change it but I I do like the little
door currently there's only one way in
and out and I have to use enderpearls
but inside we have a classroom with the
blackboard or the or the green board or
whatever board the board that makes you
bored at school a couple bookshelves in
here and I think all along the top I'm
going to put wood okay so the plan with
the school here like the little guys
will run in here and then there's a
chance they're gonna grow up and then
they'll be stuck in here so we have to
think of something to do with them right
how do we get them out so we'll probably
have one water elevator if they did did
well in school and they learn how to do
good trades they'll probably go on to a
good life back in the village if they
were bad at school and they learnt bad
trades there'll be another water
elevator that'll probably take them up
to the surface and they'll have to fend
for themselves out in the hostile world
I think unfortunately there's no little
guys in the village for us to try this
and we are missing one other thing yet
we need to get some sunlight to in front
the door here so I think if I dig
straight up we should be fine
hopefully there's nothing up above here
and there we go that should do the trick
I'm pretty sure looks like it's midday
that that was the Sun just to make sure
though I'm going to remove the stopper
or the blocker
I'll just put there for now so these
guys can get in there if it's a valid
house um I just want to make sure all
right but I'll finish polishing this up
another day oh yeah he came in right
away
very good I'm running low on time
actually brought one of the problems
with being a morning person like
normally if I if I need more time I just
stay up later but I actually have to
upload this very soon
it's like 11:30 now a.m. at the latest I
have to upload this at 1:00 p.m. so
oh yeah and I got a render it oh man
okay
it might be a shorter episode I have not
figured out this new schedule too well
all right so let's move on to something
else and try get something else going
here I want to have a rail cart system
that hopefully these guys will use so
they'll hop in a minecart it'll take
them to like the other end of the
village and then they'll hop out
automatically would be ideal that way I
think they'll be more likely to use
other houses too you know this is like
the first time I've seen a villager in
this one oh oh please don't be in the
village he's behind the wall we're good
he's like back there somewhere the
village seems to have grown a lot like
they're using the yellow and pink house
normally they stay up at that into the
village all right so anyway I think
could either put a track spot here or
maybe on this side of the yellow house
and the other end let's put it maybe
over here this is mostly just for show
like something fun to to watch right to
see them go on a minecart and move
around okay so here is what I got done
so far with this track idea this is a
popular end of the village right so if
we're only doing a one-way thing we want
them to start here and end on that end
of the village and then return like an
empty carts but we might try set up so
it works both ways but anyway no
volunteers everybody went inside darn it
must be nighttime okay so basically I
guess I'll go on it this is the layouts
we go over top the red building then got
over top the orange one then the yellow
one and we end up here there's an
activator rail that makes us get off
automatically and then it bounces back
the empty carts and it should make it
all the way there right yeah and since
this is this is a stair it stops at it
right and I'm using slabs to prevent the
villagers from walking that way but they
won't suffocate them where I could use
glass or something like that now we need
to find a way to incentive incentivize
yeah that's a word get them to go into
the minecart so we may try to like make
a door here like a fake house don't know
if I left enough space to do that though
because the track is where's the track
track goes up over there can I do it
here track is there if we had a door
right here oh but you know what they
don't try to cross tracks oh I forgot
about that
yeah villagers are like zombies like
they won't cross tracks I don't think
hmm that could be a problem how do I get
them in the minecart if they won't hmm
unless I set up a piston thing to push
them I didn't think this through very
well did I
okay let's his experiment to make sure
but I kind of doubt they're gonna try
enter the house sometime set 1,500 rawr
I'm a zombie I'm gonna eat you
oh he's even oh well whoa kind of worked
that was weird
it's like they flew over the door yeah
look at that they're like flying up here
and then going down on it here let's
maybe block this totally alright let's
try that again that was a little strange
J test number two rawr I'm a zombie nope
so they see this as it an actual block
like they don't Oh hmm why did he go I
think it was this a coincidence I think
he was in this block here and he he
brushed against the minecart maybe I
don't think he actually tried to go
through the door though yeah they seemed
to hover around the door so if they
happen to end up by the minecart they'll
go in it so that might be a little bit
difficult to get set up today totally
I'll try finish some of that stuff off
camera and show you it next time Oh
zombie zombie there must be a dark spot
in here right light 9 that's fine over
here 9 9 everything is 9 808 that might
be it I always have mob spawning in here
for some reason usually zombies yeah
there's a few eight spots so they're
probably seven at the floor okay I'll
have to keep that in mind but yeah maybe
something we can do to end this episode
just really quickly here I would finish
that but if you want a video today not
gonna happen so maybe we will just go
check around the place we have these
farms running all the time right and
quite often I forget to empty them of
the resources so one of those is the
slime farm I haven't checked this for
months Oh
basically we got a three by three thing
of hoppers here I don't know which way
they're pointing actually mmm maybe
we'll take out this one it's been too
long oh that is that's where the test is
okay and there's still a little bit of
space but it's good we looked at it so
I'll have to empty that oh oh drowning
or drowning there's one more over here
to which which side was that was that
here yeah there is oh I'm very
comparable actually okay so we'll have
to empty those there's one other farm
oh yeah the spider farm maybe we'll go
check out the cactus farm too I'm
wondering if there's mobs stuck in there
because they'll pick up the cactus and
open traps to pick up the cactus and get
stuck in the water streams there I think
there we go finally got out but let me
just put that back I'll empty that's
off-camera spider farms yes let's go
take a look real quick now that's the
snow farm this is a spider farm here
make sure these are still running to the
carts in the right place that's a good
sign there's still lots of space there
okay and what about this one
I'm guessing this one gets activated
more often than this one over here
because it's a it's closer to where I
walk usually but we will just see yeah
this one has lessen quite a bit it's in
the right spot too so that's looking
good let's go take a look at the cactus
farm now alright on the way here I
prepared the government of the day this
guy asks important questions of life
etho I was wondering what your favorite
pastry is thanks for all your awesome
videos oh man I haven't tried a lot of
different types of pastry I'm not sure I
don't think Donuts counts
do they oh look at this this is what I
was worried about I just saw a skeleton
you hear all the zombies though oh man
he's right there yeah there's a few guys
trapped down here I'm the clean house
they're slowing down my mob farm is a
problem oh yeah look at them all
if doughnuts count I would probably pick
doughnuts if not I do like oh there's
that skeleton I really like Danish like
the with the fruit center and like icing
on pretty good I don't know if
croissants count but those are also very
good what is a pastry exactly
I don't think croissants count do they
know that's that's pastry bread right
yeah croissants are very good - I like
croissants heat them up in a microwave
er or something and oh they're so gooey
gooey delicious cheese flavored mmm
anyway that's gonna do it for today guys
I hope you enjoyed the episode sorry for
sort of rushing it a little bit but
still trying to work out my weird times
anyway hope you have a great day I'll
see you again in the next one
bye bye