Hey
how's it going still working on the
blaze farm here I'm going to have to
deactivate it again so I have to hop in
quickly place blocks as fast as possible
without dying and before they all spawn
and it's not letting me okay well I
didn't think that through
I left
Oh No
and that's that
okay gonna have to come up with a better
plan the new plan I dug out all around
the sides of it so I'm going to run in
there should be no no blaze there at the
moment
and I'm gonna have to try quickly place
it this way the best I can go all the
way around might take a little while
but yeah so I'm going to do and I'll see
you in a little bit I did manage to
deactivate it so that was fun I'm gonna
make a few changes in here I'm gonna rid
of these corner pistons and pressure
plates because occasionally at this one
will you will push the blaze and then
this one extends to sometimes when that
happens they take some suffocation
damage and we don't want that happening
so I'm just going to get rid of all the
corner ones and I'm also going to add a
deactivation thing for the spawner so
I'm going to pour lava down in here in
these corners and that will pretty much
get get rid of all the blaze spawning
cuz if you have lava pouring down here
that will be light level 15 this will be
14 this will be 13 blaze need light
level 12 or lower to spawn so pretty
much this whole place will be bright
enough that they won't if I if I drop
lava here here here here here here here
and here
then I'll need maybe some on the sides
the four sides here as well and the nice
thing is these pressure plates will keep
the lava from flowing down will hold it
in place so that's what I'm going to do
I'll be back in a little bit
well I got lots to show you now make
those changes our ice cream cone has a
drizzle of hot fudge in it now looks
pretty cool I'd say it seems to
deactivate the blaze spawning completely
which is really confusing me because as
far as I know there are
there should be 24 blocks in there at
light level 12 which I've tested this a
few patches ago and please we're only
able to spawn at light level 12 or lower
so they should be able to spawn in here
but they're not so maybe something
changed in the patches they don't seem
to be spawning at light level 12 like I
thought they would which is a good thing
for me that means I don't need to put
lava down the sides which is nice this
is a this is a switch thing here to turn
the lab on or off we've got two lava
underneath each of these and so a piston
sticky piston here will push a block to
block it off or if it's open like it is
right now there's two holes and it'll
pour down below let's let's check it out
where's that link right so lava
disappears pretty quick I tried really
hard to make sure that would happen now
yeah spawning no problem now
maybe I'll just turn this back on before
we have some problems that works really
well happy about that pretty sure lava
doesn't kill these guys but maybe it
will suffocate them I don't know
get rid of him yes so this is what it
looks like on the inside
so lava pours down there and it's held
in place by the pressure plates and same
with over here that's where the other
lava ends got one glass block above the
spawner there so that will spawn above
it so nice feature to have that the
deactivating thing both for building it
and when it's all done you know it'll be
handy to be able to shut it off and
chase you're annoying me or you know if
I don't want blaze spawning because they
do like the game considerably because of
all the particles and stuff I've noticed
so next up we got to work on the crusher
then when that's all said and done we
need to look make this look nicer but
it's going it's going pretty good
it's a big project what went smoother if
I did more in creative mode like the
practice building at first but you know
it's more fun if you don't know exactly
what you're doing it is also I should
mention that with with this lava here I
have solid blocks on all six sides of it
when it shut off so that lavas above
this block here so there's there's block
below there's a block above and on all
four sides
and that makes sure that no light leaks
down to the spawning area below which
would lower spawning rates that's really
important all right so the next problem
we have to deal with is the fact that
these pressure plates are activating our
holding system system below we don't
want that happening so I think the best
way of dealing with that is just to
lower everything one more block for the
crushing system so the holder will be
here then at this level that will give
the the blaze two blocks here to fall
into and now has an extra benefit of
them not being able to jump out and walk
around on these pressure plates when
they're being held which would get
annoying downside is we have to go down
one more block which will take make us a
little bit further away from the spawner
but we're still able to be within range
of it yeah so I lowered this one block I
also replaced these corners with glass
just that I thought it would look cooler
you can see the lava through it we're
going to position the pistons now so
this will go down one I might change
this though I don't know if I'm own if
I'm going to use glass or not in the end
hmm yeah some pistons will go not there
first for the holding system I wanted
them like this over there
so they'll be one here and one here then
on the they'll be two over on the side
like that so when they are all extended
the blaze won't be able to fall down
here okay so I'm going to look glass all
around I feel like I've been very
serious ever since I got to the nether
you know I don't know this is serious
business I guess dying all the time
put me in serious mood okay so next
we'll do crusher and I wanted for sure
two Pistons in the back there I think
that's the right position we have to use
solid blocks we can't use glass for that
because a glass won't suffocate them and
then the other Pistons will go here
remember I I offset them diagonally
because I was having that issue with the
bottom piston not being able to retract
so that's important another one when we
go over here like so
and so these two will get pushed forward
first which will bring the blaze to
these one either of these two blocks
here and then they'll get crushed by
these two and I'll be right over here
being able to hit their feet and collect
their drops is the plan okay now we just
got to do the wiring for all this
awesome got the wiring done finally took
me took me a good hour anyway
it's kind of complicated I'll run you
through it pretty soon first let's see
it in action here we got we got the two
buttons like I wanted and the lever this
turns the blade spawning on or off this
button activates the crusher and this
one opens the the gate or whatever once
we collect our blaze rods and stuff you
can see they fall down and while while
it's closed they're able to collect
above there and it's not perfect but
it's working pretty good some a few do
die not really sure how to correct that
you can walk up and click there drops
and see they're collecting above there
and yeah so I'm gonna shut this off so
that we can see it see the lava starting
to flow down
see it one more time
pretty awesome I like it
one hit kills get lots of XP from it
I've made tons of blaze rods more than
I'll ever need okay I'm going to get rid
of these last you guys and we'll run
through the wiring yeah so a lot of this
wiring and stuff I should be able to
hide pretty good once I publish this
area up and hide it all behind walls or
under floors
I actually made an effort to put all
this stuff down low so I could put a
floor up a floor over top of it easily
so that's not a problem let's look at
this lever here first I guess this turns
the lava on or off which turns the blaze
spawning on or off this just has wire
goes to this block there's a redstone
torch there which goes up and then this
it's a vertical column of torches all
the way up to the top there and that
goes up to the lab a thing we built
earlier that was this episode I don't
even know yeah so let's torches come all
the way up here up to here powers this
block this wire goes to repeater which
sends the power through this block and
then powers all four Pistons so that's
how the lava turns on and off and we've
we've looked in that at that already
before okay now the fun parts um-hmm
yeah I guess before you build a redstone
project like this that's fairly
complicated it's good to figure out
exactly what needs to happen in your
head first before you start laying down
wire so with this I knew I needed these
four last blocks to come together so
that it would hold the blaze above and
then I realized I need these four
Vox to come forward as well to push the
plays closer so that I'll be able to
pick up their rods because if the rod
lands back here I can't grab it from
here so that's why I need them to come
forward I could have just made them drop
down on one by one tube as well and then
I want to have that problem but I
thought it'd be cooler to have a 2x2
area to hold them and and it is haha
okay yeah so figure out exactly what you
need to happen yeah they come forward
and then the crushers here and here
squish them for a certain amount of time
and then they're released and he hit
them blaze rods drop you don't want this
to open up yet because you don't want to
full health blaze mixing in with the one
hit health blaze and also you don't want
them here when you're collecting the
rods because they can attack you so and
you hit that and it releases everything
back to normal so there's basically two
groups of Pistons on this thing there's
there's a four glass blocks and then the
back wall they're all eight of those
Pistons are connected together on the
same wire and then there's also the -
crusher Pistons is the second group and
they're being powered from below here
there's a redstone torch and they're
connected by this wire down here the
first group though the gate one with the
eight Pistons is being controlled by
this wire here so there's one of them
one of the Pistons is over here and then
one of the front ones is over here it's
going to be really hard to show you the
wiring but eventually I'll put my world
up for download and if you want you can
check it out yourself in more detail
or I may make a tutorial in this as well
but yeah one of the Pistons is here for
the glass blocks one of the front ones
is over there this goes around goes down
here this is for the for a back wall
Pistons they're on a delay as well
because I wanted I want the glass blocks
to come together first and then have a
short delay before the back wall pushes
them because blaze need time to settle
down because they jump around and stuff
in there
it's another one of the Pistons here and
then this one goes to a front one as
well these two also control the glass so
a couple things about this there are
pressure plates above here so I wasn't
able to have the wire one block higher
here because the blaze walking on the
pressure plates above were messing with
my pistons down here when I had it
higher so I lowered it all also I was
not able to run the wire straight across
here because of that piston glitch if
this if I had wire running above this
block here it would send power to this
crusher piston down here and I would not
be able to retract it like I need to
yeah so those are the two groups this
repeater here just makes it so I can
pull like the power is going this way so
it sends power to this block excuse me
to this block here and then the repeater
pulls the power from it just a little
little redstone trick okay oops
moving on okay so um I've tried
explaining this about three times now
this is my fourth fourth attempt
I just am having so much trouble
explaining this this is something you
kind of have to see on a graph or paper
you know it's pretty pretty complicated
to see how the wiring all works when you
press this button though I'm gonna try
my best again when you press this button
here it closes the gates first and then
shortly after that these two crusher
pistons come together gates closed
crushers come together and see the timer
going back there through long chain and
repeaters once it gets the end he's open
the gate stays closed until you shut it
off or open it pressing this button
alright so this button here first of all
goes to an RS nor latch here which will
keep the power state of either on or off
pressing this button turns it on and
that sends power to our our group of
eight Pistons here then when you turn it
when you press this button here it sets
to off okay so that's one RS nor latch
there's two in total used in this
circuit okay when you press this button
the power or the wire also goes what
the heck son of a gun I blew up all my
wiring at you yeah that bugger blew up a
bunch of stuff I think I got it fixed
now I hope you hear all those gasps in
the background that's how you know I've
been in that nether for a long time here
because little by little the zombie
pigmen despawn but the gas they don't
they they have different rules so they
just keep spawning eventually you stayed
in one spot long enough I think pretty
much all the mobs would be gasps like
all 79 or whatever it is it's still 79
anyway back on to the redstone wiring
that a lot of you probably don't care
about hit this button it branches off
four places basically this wire here
goes to this RS nor latch for the gate
which we already covered it also goes
down here gets inverted goes to four
repeaters here and they go into they
point into it's really hard to see they
point into this wire here which is for
the pressures okay and they're delayed
so much just to give time for that back
wall to extend before before they crush
the blaze because you want them all
settled before that happens otherwise
some
some blaze might take inconsistent
damage and I'm still having that problem
okay so that's the second place as
branches off to the third place it goes
down to this RS nor latch here which
again holds a power state right now you
can see it's off when I send power to
this bottom block here it switches this
to on so normally a button presses a
one-second pulse so when this this gets
switched on it stays on until it gets
shut off so the pulse is would be
infinite but it also branches off here
to this long chain of repeaters which is
our timer and when it sends power to
this block it turns RS nor latch off and
that's how you that's how we control the
length of our pulse make sense yes no I
don't care yeah I explained it I did my
job
let's hope let's hope it's good enough
so I'm going to try polish this place up
and then I'm going to get get the heck
out of here because I'm sick of the
nether for right now it looks a little
bit better now that I got it all covered
up I have to do more tweaking and
polishing next time we're in the nether
uh-huh next time we build something I
did collect a little bit of nether wart
while I was building this thing but I
would like to set up a farm in here
sometime in this area it would be cool
one more for the road
if they're burning like that it means
they saw you and they're tracking you
lost a few there but overall I'm pretty
happy with this project turned out nice
yep we're out of the nether and before
we end the episode for today I just
wanted to do enchantment on a diamond
pickaxe with you watching so here we go
level 48 some people have been telling
me you know there's no point doing past
level 30 because you can get the
efficiency 5 and all the skills at level
30 something that might be true but
going higher level like closer you are
250 the higher chance you'll get
multiple enchantments on your on your
tools so there is benefit to going above
that level as well so here we go
although I've been very unlucky lately
with enchanting we'll see ya could have
been better
but I'm not going to complain that was
easy XP just tipped adding up quicker
and quicker as I was building a blaze
farm so not going to complain alright
guys thanks for watching I'll see you
again next time