what you got huh what you got you got
nothing got nothing on me you can't get
by man you go to the left I go to left
or the right I go to the right your left
I'm there uh-huh
can't do it I'm all over you man
I'm running out of intros guys come on
I've done too many of these episodes
it's so hard to think of how to start
these we can still come up with stuff
even if it's a bit goofy so yes welcome
everyone this is etho we are we're doing
stuff so I made some hard and clay
blocks finally you put put clay blocks
in furnace you hardened clay that's been
out for a while but also I have upgraded
to 13 W 19 a snapshot and now you can
get painted or stained clay so you take
your clay this is really cool by the way
take your clay and let's say your
favorite colors is green this is the
recipe for I'm sure you've seen it
already but just in case you haven't you
do that with the hardened clay do that
and then you get stained clay and I've
made every color I have not tried
placing it yet we're going to go check
that out so I'm gonna grab all these it
is so cool man like everybody in
Minecraft gets so excited when they add
a new block in in Minecraft it's like
yes um and they added like sixteen new
blocks this time which is really really
cool colorful blocks like oh yeah we got
the new there's a new texture for the
coal too so we'll check that out this is
the the base color the hardened clay
this is like your starter and then you
add the colors to it and you get the
sixteen other ones here you Church do
tonight I unequipped my weapons he's not
gonna leave us alone is he
all right so I've seen pictures of this
but I just want to see what it looks
like in game because sometimes pictures
change your color little bits or things
that can looked in for an end game
compared to what you see although since
you're watching this on YouTube
I guess it doesn't really work for you
either does it well maybe it does who
knows I'm trying to do it according to
the spectrum here as best as I can so
let's see what do maybe cyan like blue
or blue purple magenta pink red orange
it let's do those next what they all
look like side by side here so they're
not as bright as colored wool which is a
good thing I would say it makes them
different they have a nice smooth look
to them and since they're a bit duller
they I think they work better for
building they look like stucco to me
which is a type of siding for houses um
yes stucco I think is it well it's
mostly sand but yeah I'm not going to
comment on it I'm no I'm no experts so
that's the color is it pretty good I
also want to just see what it looks like
with other blocks next to it so I'm
going to try like stone bricks and and
these let's just see what these look
like how well they go together because
on the on their own they're fine but you
got to find stuff that works with them
too and see the contrast is pretty sharp
between those two types of blocks so I
don't know if that would work and also
let's check out the coal yeah I like
that a lot more the other one was kind
of like a blob of color this is more
more texture to it I like it more
alright check it out so I'm just trying
to get an idea of what it looks like
with some of the other block types like
the ones that have stairs and half slabs
with them and for some of these colors
I'd say it works but
other ones not as well like I don't like
the yellow with that pretty much
everything up to maybe here doesn't work
and then I'd say that kind of looks good
together up to up to about here and then
these last three I don't really like
with it
and I just wanted to see what like what
a wall would look like this is a
building scheme I really liked if you
saw my UHC platform I did this a lot
where I had a dark color at the bottom
in the top but a half slab in front and
then a brighter similar color over there
and it looks really good and with these
block types you can do that a lot easier
and I think that would would make a
pretty good wall and since a lot of
these colors are so similar you can mix
and match them together pretty easily
but let's try try a few more things real
quick here
I got nether brick here I think it looks
really good with like everything left of
here and maybe some of these ones at the
very rights
alright this normal brick here I would
say it works best with the colors from
maybe for from the right especially
these last three and maybe that I could
see it working with all these actually
yeah a whole sandstone I definitely like
this the most with I think these five
colors here maybe even this one um yeah
not really so much with everything else
the cool thing about having all this
variety and block types like them
introducing all these colors and stuff
is not that that was pretty lame
people's builds they're gonna be a lot
more varied from each other you know
like if you have a lemon type limited
number of block types everything kind of
starts looking the same as each other
you know
but with this I think you know stuff
people build is going to look a lot more
personalized and not something you've
seen
quite so often before and regular wood I
don't know about this I'm not sure the
textures work together you might have to
have like some kind of buffer transition
between the two if you're going to try
to combine them and cobblestone here I
don't like it all that much to be honest
these three colors the blues and that go
together the best I would say and the
rest is kind of yeah it could work maybe
but not a big fan of course I haven't
really seen anyone use this stuff yet
I'm sure once I see people using it
it'll give me ideas of how to make it
work but yeah quartz I don't really make
quartz around I don't think but I'm sure
that would work with all these because
it's a clean clean white block in these
are like a clean colored box so I think
you combine them no problem and there's
other stuff we can test to but I want to
get the episode going here so that's
that's enough color scheming for today
alright guys so the thing I want to
focus on this episode is let's do some
like terraforming and some some outside
projects today because there's been a
lot of things I wanted to to do out here
this area looks pretty good already like
especially the swamp at night looks
really cool and I love that mountain the
water we did the river a little while
ago I kind of want to continue that here
this is the first thing I'm going to do
is I'm going to change out this this
Coast along the river all the sand with
grass I hope and maybe plant some trees
along that kind of want to build a river
not not build a river build a bridge
across this river to enough we'll do
that today
um and a few other things so that's what
we'll do and I'm going to go ahead and
just do this off camera I think because
it's going to be very slow going and I
will be right back
ah very nice that's been all changed
over to grass all the way down here
looks pretty good on next thing let's
plant some tall grass and some flowers
around here this is a desert biome here
so the grass is not the ideal color but
it does add variety to so yeah we'll go
through do this just to help help break
up the flat look and then try to get
some trees let's put one over here whoa
you'll put one here hopefully you get a
couple truck a couple tall ones ear too
would be cool hopefully that grows yep
oh um maybe you should go just let's
have a couple spots where we have like
two together to get one oh it doesn't
like that flower there we go
let's put down a little bit more
bonemeal - missed a few spots over here
all right
that's pretty nice I like that it's
better than sand I think so a long time
ago I built this thing like really
really early in the world and thing is I
built it right in the center of our
River and actually cut it off so what I
would like to do because I want I want
to be able to ride down this river with
a boat all the way through and this is a
cut-off point right here so let's I
don't really want to rip these out
either so I think we should just go
around it will will make the river go to
the left and to the right and then meet
up so we're going to tear this whole or
check the land out try make it meet back
up with the river here like it's
supposed to
try to angle this upwards here that that
being a short clip all right I think
that's wide enough to get through here
pretty easily on the boat is we have the
sharp cliff kind of so we're gonna just
do some sweeping motions here level it
level it out try to even out the terrain
height very nice grass will regrow it'll
look beautiful and I want the water bill
these two deep throughout this too so
get rid of all this okay well I turned
out pretty good I would say it looks
fairly natural nice curve to it um I
I'm going to lower it at least one more
block sometime and also get rid of this
tree probably that one too because
floating trees don't make much sense
do they even though they look nice cool
and yeah I was going to put another
River that wraps around that side I
might just skip that just leave it like
this because this looks ok maybe get rid
of some of the square shape I got going
on I think there is a pretty square
looking thing on this side too over here
might I might get rid of some of this
water too um okay well next next project
let's go for the bridge just will maybe
try lay it out real quick here so we
come up our stairs here where is that
over here these are this is the main
entrance to our man cave so when we come
up I think we should have like almost I
don't know if we should do a diagonal
bridge like
here too there or if we should make a
path that comes out like up to here and
then go straight
obviously straight baths are easier to
work out let's just I think we should
just take this up take it straight and
do you want to do let's do half slabs
well man on I didn't bring an axe with
me that was a mistake okay well if it's
if it's on the ground let's use a full
block like this it'll come up to here
now we should start using half slabs
maybe well what am i doing oh you know
what I want to do I want to use half
slabs but start it from here so take out
the stair make this a half slab instead
like that I'm gonna get an axe here's
the path I laid out for it so I wanted
to go straight then go take a left turn
go over the water and then have some
stairs that come down to the land here
the way this is set up it's two blocks
above the water so we could write a boat
under here without hitting our head on
anything I think which is always nice
and now our challenge is to make it look
decent and not like some floaty platform
that looks out of place so we we may
move these half slabs up to this level
I'm not sure I want to try run oakwood
along here all the way across and put
fences on top of this I'm not sure how
that will work here
might be a cool way of doing it bridge
fence is going across I should have been
doing on the other side because that's
when we're going to look at here okay
let's do that
and like the reason I'm I'm sort of
doing this stuff now is with the horses
and all that I want a way I want path
set up for them I always want to make
sure anything I build from now on that
it's accessible to horses and so getting
across water with them is always a
challenge if we have a path that goes
across like this it will be much easier
okay all right try this out fences see
it's going to be flat on the bottom I'm
not sure I'm going to like that let's
see what it looks like from here right
now mmm-hmm take this out run that all
the way down
oh no if I like this I might tinker with
it a bit until I find something I like
you know what it is I just don't like
logs when they're sideways like this I
think because this looks so much better
to me for some reason and not just
because you know it's got the light top
but the bark looks weird to me when it's
sideways like that looks so much better
vertical so we'll go with that I'm happy
with that and we're going to do the old
spruce wood trick in water where you
basically get rid of all the logs in the
water replace it with spruce wood makes
it look a little bit darker like it's
like it's like it's wet basically all
there is to it I am a little concerned
with the setup that it's going to be
tough to get the boat through here if I
have too many of these support things
going so try not to get carried away I
think we'll have two more at the other
end here maybe like around here would be
good let's put right there and on the
other side as well here that'd be nice
to have a bridge here okay and what I
want to do is try connect it up to this
to this is the elevator from my base
let's go use it just to show you that
they have used it on camera in a long
time um that is right there
Oh easy piston elevator spiral elevator
takes you to the top here and then you
come out so I would like to connect a
walkway from here down to our bridge as
well
let's do make it go out a little more
yeah it's probably good here so then
we'll start doing a staircase down see
how this connects a little further okay
I just were there already hmm should we
do half slab staircase I wonder eyes
will probably be fine oops go like that
and then half slabs at the bottom that
will connect through here
very nice so I tell you what I'm going
to work at finishing this up of bits and
I will be back here's what we got guys
it's all done pretty much and we have
lights now I just did glowstone
trapdoors and I tried to alternate them
I thought it would look better that way
instead of having like one here one here
one here one here you know yeah they
staircase from here the only thing I
should probably change about this is
like if I come up my my walkway here I
might want to go to the right and
there's no way no proper way of getting
off to the right except for doing
something like this so probably do a few
tweaks with it but it turned out pretty
good
all right well I think I should go in
here for today so I'm going to get some
comments ready and we will call it an
end I got two comments picked out for
today guys and there was a surprising
number of people asking about a
different series of mine so I thought
I'd pick two comments regarding that
number one etho do you think of doing a
map like unchartered territory again
just wondering I'm charted territories
number three is coming out pretty soon I
think and I might play that I have just
done a CTM map with paws and vintage
beef though ruins of the mine crackers
so that series just ended so if you want
to see the whole thing it's there and
yeah it's fun to do CTM maps every so
often number two I watched every episode
from your single-player world from 1 to
now it was amazing you really improved
noticeably your inventions are useful
and sometimes just for the fun but I got
one question for you here it is in one
of your episodes you were talking about
starting a new series with an old game
is it coming or were you talking about
sort of the stars the pit and does this
game have any future for your channel
alright so the old game I was talking
about was themed Hospital and I still
might do it I don't know I saw like a
big channel just did it recently so I
don't know if I should do it or not also
I was having recording issues with it
but anyway sort of the stars the pit I
probably won't play that again on my
channel at least for a while I might do
it in the future again who knows
yeah that answers that pretty good I
would say cool well what a hoot I hope
you guys enjoyed the episode I will see
you again next time
and we will get more done around here
I'm sure so thanks for watching bye bye