[Music]
hey what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back once again to another
episode of the let's play series so I
just stumbled across a little bit of a
trick here I thought I'd show you guys
as goofing around with our orange sand
making machine here if you don't know
there was I
I got a rumor that this doesn't work in
1.13 so I tried it out and sure enough
the trick to changing yellow scent to
orange sand no longer work so I got as
like stockpile as much as possible
before that happens
otherwise I'm not gonna have orange sand
anymore but I had the idea what happens
if you just feed it into it's like in a
giant column like this it works it
actually works and it looks really cool
so it's another way of automatically
converting yellow Santa more nice and
kind of cool kind of cool
yeah so because I've switched my world
to amplified in the mesas we don't get
much orange sand because it only
generates around Y 64 ish so anywhere
that there's a mountain you basically
get no orange sand so I'm gonna have
trouble finding it in the future here I
want to get several double chests full
of it if possible that's like one of my
my jobs to do here before we update
and of course all that orange sand has
to come from somewhere right so been
doing a lot of sand farming in the
desert here a lot of shovel repairs
happening on the way too I broke I broke
one of my shovels you know when it's
like near zero durability but you just
keep going it's like at 50 it's like I
got I got quite a few uses left and then
it slips your mind for just a moment and
then you hear that think when the shovel
breaks oh just makes me feel so sad
afterwards so I had to make a new one
here yeah not a super exciting process
or anything just collecting resources I
still really enjoy that part of the game
though just letting stuff it's relaxing
it's enjoyable as long as you don't do
it for too long all right I usually only
do for hour at the most collecting one
thing and then I'll change to something
else or start building I thought I'd
share it with you guys
just in case like in the future when I
look into my double chest and there's
like several several of them full of
orange sand I don't want you guys to be
like where did those come from those
don't just appear out of nowhere that's
a lot of work I'm putting in the work
here trust me my fault pretty much
closed ah
anyways let's maybe head over to slab
city or something we'll do some building
there
all right everybody so here we are once
again at this lab City and last time we
worked on this tree farm I just put in
some tree stoppers here to keep the
trees from getting too tall and one
trim' outs we also worked on our sapling
dispensers thing here so I drew some
jungle trees and they were like 14
blocks tall or something crazy that the
Pistons couldn't even push them alright
that's that one seems good so yeah this
is what we did last time Oh still kind
of testing it it failed usually when it
fails it should keep going though I
wonder I might need to make some
modifications that one did it too
there is a way to make this go a bit
longer if we just put a block here then
this delay signal is gonna last longer
and it'll shoot more bonemeal so
hopefully that little change will make a
fix make the fix here I don't know we'll
try that out I got the burps one second
okay let's try this again with the
changes I also moved those tree Stoppers
up two blocks because we got one jungle
tree that was only four blocks tall
there we kind of want them around the
seven or eight range and having them
lower makes it less likely the trees
gonna grow here with with the bonemeal
this is like the perfect height that's
what I want
let's try again it's not failing now
that's good last one all right those are
all pretty much the right height I think
right let's try top it down I can't
reach that one unless I hop up okay it's
one block too tall maybe we lowered
these by one block so there's gonna be
nine air spaces between the sapling down
there and then the tree stopper here I
think that'll be perfect for this tree
farm and I was just trying something
here I saw an interesting idea on the
Minecraft right I thought I'd share it
with you guys if you didn't see it
somebody had the idea of making a
sapling farm not a tree farm
specifically a farm for farming saplings
and the way that it works is you set up
a column of dirt like this basically
trees can grow they'll ignore like air
spaces they ignore dirt blocks and wood
blocks if for example there was a piece
of stone here this tree would not be
able to grow but since it ignores dirt
blocks it will naturally grow or with
bone meal here and none of the dirt
blocks get replaced with wood so these
leaves have nothing to attach to and
they'll just be spawn and then you catch
the saplings that fall so that's kind of
a cool idea you don't have to chop down
the tree that way
one thing I I've noticed here like that
is this testing it to see how it works
and the leaves don't seem to de-spawn
after it grows here even though they
should until they receive some sort of
updates so you see nothing is the
spawning and I think is the spawning if
we break the wood block down here it
seems to trigger them up here you see
now that now they're going that's
interesting so if we were to make a farm
like this I I think you would want some
way of removing this wood block here
either you burn it or push it away with
pistons and maybe some way of collecting
the saplings when they fall might be a
fun idea to try out in the future here
but I thought it was pretty interesting
anyways around the base here what else
did we do I tried putting some orange
clay down there just for some color I
like the color but I don't like how that
looks
need to change that figure out something
else and I added a couple new slabs over
there
we'll probably build a bridge between
here and there and the main thing is I
tried detailing this overhang area again
I'm not really sure how to do that I
don't know if this looks good I think
it's okay we made like some pipes there
that stick out and some planters on that
side from the top here though I like how
it looks from the top and we turned it
into like a pond or whatever Andy that's
cool I like that but the stuff on the
side I'm not really sure yet and well I
put some leaves over here I had the
leaves originally like hanging down from
the very top there all the way down it
looked really weird though so I tried to
it
make it look like they're growing into
the side of this piece of stone or
whatever I don't know whatever still I
don't know if I should focus so much on
detailing things or if we should just
focus on expanding the base first what I
would like to do to begin with here is
set up a beacon somewhere so I'm gonna
put it on top of a building over here
and I brought the stuff for the beacon I
think we'll make this pop out one slab
so five six seven I always got to figure
it out I think we need one more this is
where the border would be right so
that'll come out and then let's probably
go over two slabs this way and make like
a 2x2 area very good so we got ourselves
a bit of a structure here nothing too
fancy it's just like a shell of a
building right now put the beacon on the
top there with haste - so we can dig
fast now around around the area and as
you can see I tried to stagger the tiles
as much as possible not like everything
square and at the same level I think
it's going to look better in the end of
things if we do that so I lowered it
here
for example would have been easier just
to keep it at that level but I dropped
it down and raised it up here possibly
will move this beacon down below and do
something fun with color-changing to try
to give information of some sorts but I
don't know what's what yet like you can
use beacons to send information visually
right but what what would they signal I
don't know maybe in the future if I
figure it out we'll move it though
that's what I'm trying to say
if not we'll try to look or try to make
it look like it's being held in place
here I guess with stairs and stuff does
this look like kind of goofy needs lots
of detailing probably I don't know we
might be able to make it look cool if we
keep it there on top of here we'll
probably put some trees and some Park
Park dish area saying what's over here
try to make it feel like we're in a bit
of a forest area to not just open like
it is right now above there maybe a
skylight and this is what it looks like
on the inside here so I want to talk to
you guys about something with our build
with our city here I definitely want to
do a minecart track and probably like
boat stuff again I want to get back into
the boat both things cuz in 1.13 boat
elevators are gonna be back it seems and
also like water ladders and and that
sort of thing it's it's gonna be much
like it was in the past so I think we're
gonna have fun with that but if you're
doing like a minecart system and a boat
system you gotta do it early with your
base building you don't build your base
and add them later that usually doesn't
work out so good so the question is guys
what kind of minecart system should we
build at our new base here like a point
A to point B system or a selection panel
you remember a while ago we looked into
the idea of doing a ticketing system
like like you do in rail crafts and we
still haven't really put that to use
anywhere so I thought might might use it
at this base but I think it'll take up
too much space or
too complicated so I want something a
bit more simple and I had the idea like
can we design a minecart system that you
drive like if you hold forward and a
minecart you move now all right so is
there a way to do an intersection where
if you hold forward you go straight
through but if you don't hold forward
you take the turn is is basically all we
want need to figure out with this so I
just set up a little test here with the
detector rail hop in hold forward the
whole way through we go forward through
good and ideally if we don't hold
forward we take a turn here we still go
through so what we got to find is the
exact sweet spot where that'll happen
it's because it's such a subtle change
between holding forward and not I don't
know if we will be able to actually do
it
so if we move this back one we'll just
try a few things here and see if we can
figure it out move this back and now
let's try hold forward
we went through goods if we don't hold
forward hopefully we don't go through
wait
did it actually work Oh Kate a second do
we go through the first time I got to
watch a video back I thought we went
through the first time okay so I checked
and we definitely went through there the
first time holding forward and I've done
this test several times now and we have
discovered our first problem
unfortunately so it's inconsistent
inconsistency is always terrible so you
see we went through that time the first
time we didn't they're like why not as
six times or so we're going through here
and it can happen even if we're not
holding forward
so our current setup here is no good no
bueno by the way I figured out a new
trick here I guess you can do the light
rowing thing just like that you just sit
space bar before you enter the minecart
and it keeps you in crawling mode or
whatever kind of cool so what I think we
gotta do is get rid of some of these
power drills and make make our pushing
forward a bigger impact might even need
to have like a dead zone that we have to
hold forward through I'm not sure
and since we're just very rarely
actually getting through this definitely
needs to be forward one like we had
originally okay so this is a sweet spot
for the detector rail let's actually get
rid of all these because I'm guessing
it's probably not gonna work
so if we hold forward we got through
good let's try not hold forward and if
this doesn't work then we have to
introduce dead spots holding forward
okay we still went through okay so I got
one kind of solution here but man I tell
you this has been a lot more difficult
to do than I expected because the
holding forward is just so subtle
compared to not like the change and then
there's that inconsistency I think cuz
like the detector rail I don't know what
it is maybe like the redstone powers the
junction but it only flips at certain
ticks like there's 20 ticks in a second
maybe only triggers every two or every
four or something like that and the in
the code not like every game tick and
that's where our problem is so in order
to get this to work I've had to
introduce two dead spots I couldn't get
to go with just one so we have two
unpowered power rails let's really slow
you down and that's kind of a problem
like if we hold forward we go through
now
every time and it had to fail yet and if
we don't hold forward we don't go
through butts
because we have to use the two power
wheels we actually totally stop and then
you have to hit forward again to get
going but it works let's call this
potential solution number one I'm going
to try maybe find a better one even
though this does work it's not as fast
or as smooth as I would like hmm you
know what after thinking about it for a
bit here we need a new plan we need a
better idea
because we've only been trying to do it
make it work for go in one direction
here like going this way either straight
or rights if we're holding forward or
not but we also got to make it work
going this direction either left or
right if we're holding forward or not or
straight or left from this direction and
that makes it way more complicated
because we have to set it up for all
three directions and it's also gonna
slow it down way more because we'll have
to have a slowdown on this side over
here and over here as gonna make the
intersection a lot slower I think unless
we come up with some clever idea which
I'm not gonna do I'm gonna leave that up
to you guys maybe you want to tackle
this problem can you make a three-way
intersection that works by holding
forward or not
that's that's your challenge because I'm
not doing it instead I had another idea
here we are gonna make an intersection
that works by triggering a fence gate
this isn't a new idea this is something
people have been doing for a while but
now that we have observers I think we
can get it to work
very very easily and very quickly
because observers are fast while the old
bud switches are kind of slow like this
is a thing people have been doing for a
while where you go down the track and
you try to hit a button as you go by
before you get to the junction and it
switches it's a lot of times the buttons
too small you miss it so people start
using fence gates instead because it's
got a full block collision here it's
easy to trigger it but again you kind of
have to have like it way back here and
another one over here and another one
over here
and that makes it more complicated but
now that we have observers I think we
can just put it right above the junction
here it'll be easy to hit going in all
three directions all right and all we
got to do very simple actually is make a
t flip-flop here so just sticky piston
and redstone block and then just run
redstone to the junction that's it so
now when we've we flip it switches
pretty simple all right now I want to
expand on this a little bit cuz it well
I've actually let's test it out first
cuz I don't know it might be hard to hit
it so right now it's going to the left
and just barely see it is another
problem so we got to try to switch it to
go to the right here
yet it's doable that's quick enough
oh that's that my sister so she's gonna
left let's try again
oh that was weird okay so you still got
to be kind of quick with it left there
it's gonna take some practice maybe but
it's definitely doable I switched it
straight
against which to go straight so I think
it's it's good it's quick enough so
that's cool but what I want to do in
addition is add some lights to it so we
don't have to look at the Junction's
because it's barely barely visible from
a distance it's hard to see especially
on video I'm guessing so I want to add
an indicator system some lamps up here
and like if you're over here and it's to
the left like it is right now then I
want this lamp to be on if it's to the
right I want this one on instead I think
oh we got to do to do that is let's hook
up some redstone to the block here and
we got to run up to the lights we will
put a block here and then
oh yeah just two slabs right up here so
we do a little redstone staircase up to
the lamps same on this side
and on one of these we want redstone
torch so I guess it would be this one
right oh and a block above - okay so now
I can get you can go up there and if we
switch it
there we go that's pretty simple right
so if we're going straight through here
I guess the light would be off I would
prefer if it was on but I don't think we
can can help that all right and this
direction the same rule applies light
light is off that means we go straight
cool all right so I'm pretty happy with
this actually I've tried it out of the
bunch now it seems to work good it's
quick we don't have to slow down the
minecart at all it's fairly easy to set
up there's not much redstone to it and
I've tried like hiding the wiring to see
what kind of footprint it'll take up and
it's it's not bad because again we got
to try align it with our chunks and like
if this is the center of the chunk here
it goes one two three blocks over so
this would be the border and from this
way one two three border would be here
this way one two three border here so it
fits within and it's only four blocks
tall so this is like the the
top border of the chunk or the tile or
slab or whatever we're calling it so
yeah I think we're good all right it's
very good so I think we got that figured
out and we still got a couple minutes
left we might be able to do one or two
more things before we wrap up today and
I wanted to do a bridge across here so
let's let's experiment with that I think
we'll start it here and with a lot of
the stuff we build in the space like
staircases paths bridges I think four
wide is kind of gonna be the the ideal
size like if it's five wide I think it's
gonna feel too fat if it's three wide
it's gonna feel too narrow maybe so yeah
let's let's aim for four wide in general
then we can keep it more ace in it
symmetrical too so it's not in the
center of the tile it's kind of ops up
sided here I think that's fine I'm okay
with that
so let's just do it like this in order
to make it Bend the bits I don't know
when you when you work with the small
small detail like this you can't do too
much can't do anything too fancy so
we'll just do a simple bridge and maybe
let's actually get rid of the stone here
and up to here we'll put in some dark
oak and some slabs on top there so you
don't see that the Rings although I
guess in 1.13 we're gonna have the new
blocks where you have log the bark on
all all six sides that's gonna be nice
we got a lot of cool new blocks in the
new update here like the stripped bark
looks really good oh I gotta get used to
that hey speaking now I'm breaking
everything yeah let's do that
and some slabs on top very very nice
very simple all right and this will
probably be passed here too
how does that look how's that feel I
think I think I'm okay with that from a
distance
actually it's it needs more decoration
bottom not that you can really see it
but maybe let's make
come down one more to show I decided
instead of making the bridge go straight
across I add in a little bit of a curve
to it I think that looks better and I'm
pretty happy with that I think it's a
nice simple bridge now we might end up
getting rid of the slab there and and
lowering it one and then having a walk
through from the tree farm to some other
part of the base I was gonna put the
walkthrough over there because otherwise
this tree farms totally enclosed you
know and you can't get to it
except by falling down here but we might
change a walk through - over over here
instead and go under the bridge now I
tried something over here and it's one
of those one of those cases where it's
like well I want to see what it looks
like and then when it's done it's like
hmm I don't really like that so we'll
probably have to change it but I think
the the issue is is we have so much so
many of the tiles go straight across
here like we have one two three four and
there'll be another one over there five
in a straight line basically I don't
think that looks too good so I think
we'll take that slab in that slab and
push it that way with one block I do
like having an overhang here but yeah
and basically the plan is to have a boat
system or boats pass here it will go
through and connect into the building
we'll probably put a bridge from here
going across the water and then the
water is probably gonna fall and drop
down somewhere here with a boat elevator
to get up when that's when that's
possible and also I think we will then
make it go this way over around here and
connect somewhere else
it is my current plan none of this looks
very good right now though because we
need to decorate it just this doesn't
look good until you add some more
details to stuff but it's a start I
think the base is coming along here well
I think that's about all we have time
for today guys so we're gonna have to
wrap up with our comment of the day it
says etho I know this comment is a
little
it's okay but you forgot about your
to-do list it's in the man cave on the
walls of the furnace room you can check
out lots of things alright so it's been
a while since we looked at our to-do
list guys let's let's go through it and
we'll just check out where we're at I
think it's this one
yes okay ethos never-ending to do this
library let's say sixty percent done
Wilson finish but can be improved Santee
city walls are pretty much done
buildings not pyramids we tried to
finish it and you guys didn't like it so
it's not done my card storage system
nope my car cheap firm I think we axe
that one arena
oh yeah the arena nope that's nothing
ceiling pattern in tree farm is done
that's when I finished silverfish farm I
think is finished right we redid the
bomb factory could use some more stuff
that one's kind of done though firework
room is finished completely tunnel -
deserts I don't know what that means
oh that's - like where we were farming
sander there today yeah we got that done
portal network needs work I think
underground village I think that one's
kind of done Nexus kind of done project
Pokemon not done or storage room I don't
even know what that means
man it's been a long time since I looked
at this I don't even know what half this
stuff is I think that's a next one
though
cmon game not done skeleton spawner and
man cave oh you know I think where we
built the second Nexus it I think that's
where we were gonna put that maybe so I
guess that's kind of axed Gold firm
number one I owe ya that's totally done
we just finished that musical portal
this finish dual blades firmware you
redid recently so that's pretty much all
done that could use some more decorating
around there nether hub design finished
horse jump project
it's not Finnish Guardian firm we redid
some of it but not the big area select
that's kind of a 50/50 uh-huh
all right that's that's the update what
is this oh this is our Nexus list aha
all right guys hopefully you enjoyed the
episode today I think we're gonna call
it here though so until next time thanks
for watching and I'll see you again in
the next one take care bye bye
[Music]