[Music]
now that
is one trippy looking mushroom
it's alive it's moving it's pulsating
it's flashing it's crazy
oh you know what guys our skin
this pink stuff for brown stuff for
whatever kind of stuff you got
not only does it make us look good it is
really amazing it keeps our guts inside
it
it does all kinds of stuff it regulates
our body temperature it protects us
from pathogens and infections
and stuff that would kill us and one of
the things it also does that we probably
take for granted
is it protects us from the deadly rays
of the sun
which is something skeletons
i'm sure wish they had the luxury of
because
i mean these guys can't go to beaches
they pretty much have to stay indoors
all times
uh this is not what i meant to be doing
but
once i started placing a few i couldn't
stop
there goes there goes
okay the thing i actually wanted to
check out was
just a quick experiment here how does
thorn's armor work when mobs kill you
and they're at low health
and they die do they give you experience
points
or or not i wasn't too sure
oh come on let me do it i what am i
17. whoa
whoa oh i'm not in
wait what how did i get into
why are they doing so little damage
oh it's because it's because i'm so
close and it's 152 they do so little
damage it's like nothing
i thought it was still in creative mode
there
okay let's just reset this
so i think uh i think they're gonna drop
experience points
when they die here we'll find out
yeah look okay so they do drop
experience points and probably like if
they have
uh armor or any anything else they have
a chance of dropping that too
come on that'd be amazing if we could
see this guy drop his armor or that bow
but they're spawning too quick
come on oh did he drop it
i'm pretty sure they do but it's a
chance thing
anyway let's go on to our lp
so i have pretty much finished the
you've been ethod guy
i think it turned out pretty good here i
went back to
the nether and i harvested another five
or six stacks of glowstone to
do the internal ring going all around
and that makes it look a lot better i
would say because it used to have like
gray going around and it broke up the
image kind of
now it's a constant background and in
total that background
of glowstone is like 15 stacks or so
which is
by far the most glowstone i've ever used
on a project that's insane
but i'm worth it i'm not gonna cheap out
on myself
that that would be wrong that that's
actually kind of a nice thing about
playing single player like you don't
have to worry about
somebody going through the nether and
taking all the glowstone
avarice or the quartz or whatever
there's plenty plenty in supply
um so i've also
if there's one thing i've learned from b
double o planting grass and
and trees and stuff makes it makes any
project look better pretty much
and it's really easy to do so i got a
couple trees around here now
um i've evened out the sides remember
there was the sharp cut off before now
it's kind of leveled
off and it i think blends in pretty well
same with this side
i think this side turned out a little
bit better than this one but
i think it's good let's head on up
whoa punch myself
um i still might add some waterfalls
around here yet though
so this is what i added all around this
this five block wide
ring on the inside
pretty cool but anyways today guys i
think we're gonna go work on that zombie
pigmen farm some more for a little bit
anyway
so let's head on over to the nether
this is where we are building our zombie
pigmen farm
our gold farm uh we cleared this out i
think two or three episodes ago with the
tnt and i've gone through and cleared
even more with the pick
and i still have a bunch to go though
especially down below here because we
need
the zombie pigmen to fall quite a ways
too
but let's head on up
this is i think the center right here
and we need to oh
ah smooth smooth we need to sort of
build our spawning pads in the shape of
a
semi sphere like with that as the flat
part
the ceiling here as the flat part and it
kind of doming outward
um sort of try to imagine that
uh so the spawning pads how far is this
let's
check this out i don't know how to how
big whoa
i think i just walked across that that
was pretty cool
i don't know how big we should make them
2 4 6 8
10 12. huh
i think what i want to do is make a
three wide space in the center
and then make it go out
let's go out 16 blocks make the spawning
pad 16 blocks long
and if we want to expand it in the
future we can and go out i think we can
do up to 30 blocks
long for each pad so
let's what's our height here
need three blocks height for each one
i think this is where we're at yeah i'm
going to build it
out of
the stone slabs i think the main thing
i'm worried about while building this
actually is the gas we're going to have
to put a cage around this thing
and i'll probably have to do that pretty
quick but
for now i'm going to try build it uh
with the gas around and i'll just have
to shoot
any that appear because they're going to
blow up my pistons and
string i got to use tripwires redstone
all that stuff can get blown up by gas
very easily
so let's just kind of get started here
i'm going to be using
jl's high efficiency spawning pads for
this
because they have lots of air spaces and
that makes
increases the chances of mobs spawning
on a small area
3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11
12 13
14 15
16. right
that's what we want okay and then it
goes
let's see if i can remember this i think
it goes pistons
here i
i'm gonna really run out of redstone on
this build i don't have much at the
moment
and every one of these pistons takes one
and then we need
a redstone on top of each piston so i'm
gonna
run out very quickly here i got lots of
iron so that's not a problem and i got
lots of
i don't know if i have much string
around i'll have to check that out too
but
for the most part we got what we need
for this
and then we put redstone on top of this
the problem with these slabs is you
gotta place two blocks for every one
but i do really like using these in the
nether because they're
nice and bright
okay and do i have any more i do
so then this will come out
um it's got to come out two blocks
then up and actually
i think the way i i did it on the
minecraft servers i had a half slab
underneath too
like that and then you put your trip
wire
over here and then that runs all the way
across
so when a mob spawns on this area here
they're going to spawn inside the
tripwire and that's going to tell all
these pistons to
extend and push whatever is on this pad
off
and
go out here
okay connected
good so let's run some redstone along
here and i'm not gonna do all this on
camera don't worry
i just wanted to do a half here and then
i'll do a bunch off camera
uh this is this is a very large build
oh uh but it's a very repetitive build
so i don't think it's gonna take
too long like it's fairly easy to do it
[Music]
but i'm not guaranteeing we're gonna get
it all done today that's for sure
especially the cage i don't know how to
do the cage uh i'll probably use iron
bars for that
and try mix a pattern in
so then i think we got to connect
over here that'll go to the tripwire
no
that's good i don't want to be up there
when he shoots again
all right so that's the general idea
behind it and then we uh
we'll put several several more pads
below that
and we'll probably space them out a
little bit too like
we gotta do that sphere like i said so
i'm gonna work on this for a bit
and i will be back oh no
oh no ah
really
ah
well that wasn't very nice
still mad don't be mad don't be bad
don't be mad oh dang it
and i didn't get my sword
[Music]
or pick that was a mistake too
dang it
[Music]
so i was up on the spawning pad gas shot
at me
shot the jazz and i don't know if the
gas ball
made them ah
made them mad at me or what
but um
yeah i tried to jump down to get away
from him and they land
they like jumped off the pads and got me
anyway
they like kamikaze to kill me
oh and i have no ender pearls
this is a nightmare
yeah so the problem get out of here
problem with this creeper face
is that uh i have to
ender pearl through it right which is
fine
but i have been neglecting getting more
ender pearls
and i was carrying the last of them so
didn't make it through did it
i don't see it oh it is there
come on let me get the boat
placed it too far i think
oh come on live
am i going to live there's no point
going through if i'm not going to live
two one and a half one
half ah
well i feel a little silly now
because that's what i had a bunch of
just laying around
okay i've heard
that if you just wait 40 seconds
the zombie pigmen will forget about you
or another option in fact as i could
let's maybe run far away and they'll
despawn
and then run back
[Music]
that should work too
yeah we'll do the time thing uh just in
case they have my sword and stuff i'm
not sure if they'll despawn with that
[Music]
so i would say that's pretty close to 40
seconds
can't wait too long or it's gonna all my
stuff's gonna despawn
anyway so let's go up and just see
what's how they're feeling let's let's
test their emotions
i think they would have followed me
yeah they forgot they love me
okay good so
oh look at this yeah i was fighting the
gas
hey no no no no no you don't you jerk
what did i do to that one why that one
i'm not going to hit him
i just want to get the rest of my stuff
up we go okay i was in the middle of
testing something actually
oh there's lots of them mad at me
i bet you there's some up here too mad
still too
stinking gasps man um
i just want to see something
no big mistake big mistake
i'll be right back
i don't deserve this kind of treatment
you guys won't leave me alone
oh i'm in so much trouble now i just
wanted to get the rest of this stuff
too oh look at that okay i can't find my
sword
my sword burnt up
for glory
yeah they're angry are they all angry is
this guy angry
yep oh yeah
yeah i'm definitely going to leave the
area and come back because this is bad
i feel much much safer now let's go take
a look at this thing real quick here
see what i got done so i've decided
i'm gonna do it like this i have a total
of
well each of these strips is 16 spawning
spaces
there's two percent so that's 32
and there's four sets per side so that's
and oops don't do that
there's two sides so in total i have 256
spawning spaces per layer and i'm doing
i think four layers with this thing so
one here
here and then here
that'll make it just over a thousand i
think 1024
spawning spaces which isn't going to be
enough to
like cap out the the mob spawning
but i really don't think i'm gonna need
that much gold so i'm not gonna
i'm not gonna get too crazy with this
thing uh if i really want in the future
i can
i can make it bigger but this should do
and i'm just laying out the
the blocks first and then i'll go
through and do the pistons and stuff
but it's going pretty good um
anyway let's go do something else for
today
real quick
so i do have some pretty disturbing news
oh man that's not good
why is it so dark there
oh i'm glad i got my bow
um it seems
jeff is gone uh
that has me very worried i don't know if
he's
to kill me to get revenge or if he
somehow died in the lava i have no idea
it's a sealed cage and he's gone
so your guess is is as good as mine i
don't know
gives me chills though just thinking
about it uh
what i want to try to do now
let's actually let's go i want to show
you guys the new
villager sounds just in case you haven't
heard them
they are hilarious
i wonder i bet i can do a trade with
them
i haven't heard the trade sound yet
that's out
written book or
books
hmm well i'll tell you what i'll
i'll give the emeralds up just to hear
the sound such a waste
did he do it i didn't hear anything
different
um my particles are on
is it only when i trade like on the last
trade because i didn't
i don't really notice anything there
15 can't do that
nope that's definitely not happening all
right
anyway actually there's a i bet you tom
has a trade we could do
let's go check out tom
hey do you oh it's
huh we could do this
awesome particles what new one did you
get
oh you can get enchanted books i didn't
know that
huh
i had no idea that's cool
i want to try breed
zenith oop and donkey here you get a
mule too
um is this gonna work with them on leads
and do you always get a mule from it oh
yeah
that's awesome
that little guy he looks so bony doesn't
he's like
stick legs cool
so we got a mule it's pretty small i
don't know if i have
i'm sure i got more weed around let's go
check
i don't know i'm guessing mules are
quicker than donkeys
i'm hoping actually let's go let's go up
here because i'm gonna need a saddle to
form
i'm sure i got saddles yep
and sugar
give him sugar does he
can't remember if the bread i know the
hay
try that out
do i really really like the horses in
this game
um i need to
build some bridges and stuff so i can
get around easier
it's growing very slow with that you
like spider eyes
whoa
oh he does that with anything i thought
maybe he really hated spider eyes
bread oh yeah that's making him grow
and i think he's done
all right i think i gotta tame him now
he's got 12 hearts i wonder how quick he
is
nope there
oh yeah cool
can we
okay you can saddle him
ah it's still pretty slow still pretty
slow
i i think you can give them my chest
though can't you
yeah there we go that's what i wanted
and if you yeah
you have to shift right click to open it
and you can put stuff inside that is so
cool
uh i might like the mules more than
the horses i'm not sure just because of
that fact
that is so handy to have 15
slots too
so i think the donkey is actually
quicker than the mule
just by a little bit he has less health
though
so i think that that might have been the
trade-off
and they seem to jump about the same
height as each other too
you can tell it's a little bit slower
but anyway we are going to name him uh
because of his performance and his ears
i dub the dumbo
oh man
maybe one last thing we'll do this
episode before we end it
uh wilson i haven't forgotten about
wilson
um i'm going to take you guys to a
creative world
where i was working on some of his
components and we can check those out
real quick
too
yeah i've been messing with a few
redstone ideas for wilson here and i'll
take you guys through them
give you an idea of how they're going to
work so first up this is pretty simple
you guys know these comparator clocks
where
signal goes back to the comparator and
it makes it pulse really really quick
as fast as possible i was trying to
think of a way i could regulate it
like choose to slow it down or remove
pulses
from from that and i figured this would
be a pretty easy way of doing it just
send it to
block controlled by a piston
and you could have different delay
settings for the other side so if it's
at two ticks
um well if it's at one tick maybe i'll
just show you first
it basically goes at the same speed
you can see they're about the same oh
break that if you slow it down
you can see you can reduce the number of
pulses you get out of that
reduced even more and even more
so you could sometimes it does that
i think that's a kind of a glitch
i'm not sure uh but yeah you can
regulate between
two different settings really easy just
by doing this
and what does that have to do with
wilson well i was thinking of using this
sort of for his stomach
the idea i had if wilson can only eat so
much food
in so much time basically
if you feed him too much at once then he
gets
a penalty like he he gains weight really
quickly is what i wanted it to do
so uh this is what's controlling that
he has uh
wait is that what i want i can't
remember how this works i think
i think we want that in there actually
uh the idea is
he can take up to 52 food points
uh like this is a buffer and
each pulse represents a food point he
got from eating something
and then when his his buffer runs out
like where
he's eaten too much and he's full
that'll switch
and then each of these pulses would add
one to his weight so when it switches
he receives double double the weight
from the food he eats so
kind of a little penalty for that um
over here this is for his bladder
i was messing around with this um
quite a bit going on basically
every update is represented by this
button
oh yeah and and with this every update
um he'll be able to re eat one more food
point like
over time he's going to get pulses from
this
and eventually this is going to return
back it's going to go up and he'll be
able to eat again
without any penalty
so with wilson's bladder system um
every time updates this is going to
pulse
this here and you can see as is right
now
it's not connected to anything right so
every update that would do nothing but
as wilson receives food so
as this pulses this line here it's going
to go to his bladder
um bladder input is over here
and that's represented by what's in this
dropper here so he has
64 plus 16 things in his bladder right
now
what does that equal 80. he has 80 80
bladder garbage at the moment and as he
receives food
this is going to pulse and he's going to
gain one every time
and at one point here once he has enough
stuff in his bladder
that triggers and then this pulse can
get through
that goes to a randomizer there's a one
in nine chance that the sword is going
to get chosen
to go into the hopper and that will send
out the signal to
the end here that then goes to
um this this is his bladder size like
the size of
um of relief
that he releases so at the moment i have
a 15 just for testing
um it's it's a hopper clock um
and that will trigger a pulser that then
goes
to send his bladder buffer back to
normal
and it then sends out
a pulse to this line as well which will
reduce his weight because when you go to
the bathroom
you get lighter so wilson does too
um anyway let's try it out
nothing nothing
so there's a chance wilson get can get
constipated from this too
like if if he's not lucky here he's
going to keep filling up more and more
till finally
go on poor wilson
he's not going to be feeling well at
this point
wow it's one to nine come on
trigger you stupid thing that's good i
actually want this behavior but
there we go finally so you can see it's
sending up pulse notes
do this thing and then after a certain
amount of time this goes back to normal
and you can see it's back to the state
where
pulse can't get through until he eats
more and his bladder fills up
oh wilson's gonna be so crazy when he's
done
i've been trying to decide like when he
goes to the bathroom
what comes out do i make it like
brown clay or do i make it some
redstone ore i don't know what he would
go
uh or how to do it or how i'm supposed
to clean it up afterwards but
yeah that's gonna be another part of
this that i haven't figured out yet
uh one last thing here to show you
ignore this in the back that was my
first
go at it this is supposed to be wilson's
immune system so
we wanted to make it where he can get
sick and we can give him medicine to
to make him recover from that the way
this
is going to work this represents his
health level here so it goes from one
two three
four five uh as he's healthier
he is less i wanted to make it so he's
less likely to get
sick and as he gets unhealthy he's more
and more likely so it's a very i have to
do like a variable
randomizer here so we have a bunch of
these
these randomizers i've been using five
of them
and per updates
i can send a signal to this wire
oh well if i do it like that it's
impossible for him to get sick if he's
at five
five health so let's take this out
uh so when i take that out this piston
is able to
retract it's no longer being powered and
then when you it receives a pulse
it can move forward every time and it
goes
over top of a redstone torch which goes
to the randomizer
and if the sword is selected
it will send a signal three blocks
um at this wire and it'll reach this
line here
and if if this receives a pulse it means
he gets sick
so as it is right now it's pretty
pretty low chance of him actually
getting sick if he's at four
oh there we go this won't trigger every
update either i'll probably add one more
randomizer before this
to decrease it
but as it gets more and more unhealthy
more and more of these things trigger
per update
that times two so it's twice as likely
to get sick at that point
uh unless i adjust the number of stuff
in these droppers i can
control it a little bit with that too
two let's take up more three
so at this point pretty reasonable
chance
it's like every one and three probably
i don't know what the actual odds are
but you can see it'll increase
even more if i do this
it's like every one and two now
uh-huh so that's how that works i think
it's pretty cool
anyway that's enough with wilson let's
go read the comments
so i'm not too sure what happened here
but when i logged back on
dumbo was right here i was beside him uh
when i logged back on
dumbo was gone he's just gone no idea
why he disappeared i'm guessing jeff
must have taken him
i don't know ah very strange
i dismounted before i logged off too
because i think there's a glitch with
that
if you're on a horse when you log off so
i made sure to get off
but yeah gone
this is gone donkey i don't know it's
all right you were faster anyway
um yeah so
the comment i picked out for today guys
is this one
etho do does anyone in real life
know you make videos how do they feel
uh after about a year of me doing this i
started telling people
um and at this point a lot of people
know
i've told a lot of people probably
probably at least 40 or 50 by now um
in general people are pretty supportive
and and like uh
when i first peop when i first tell
people usually the reaction is like
really like they they kind of laugh and
say really
uh together um and are usually pretty
interested in it too
uh in general people have been very
supportive though
and yeah
can't ask for anything better really a
couple of my friends are jealous
because i get to play video games for a
living
who wouldn't be um the most awkward
people i told i told two of my teachers
like i ran into two of my teachers and
they were like so what are you doing now
it's like i play video games for a
living
oh really
okay no it wasn't that awkward but
i think that was uh i think they might
have expected more they didn't really
understand
that it's actually a good job it is a
really good job
um so but yeah in general people are
supportive
and it's pretty cool i still like what
i'm doing that's what counts
uh anyway that's all guys thanks for
watching
have a good day
you