[Music]
yeah you know it's one of those things
guys if you asked me I wouldn't be able
to tell you I couldn't explain it but
there was just something special about
today this tree canopy is right by the
man cave right I see it constantly like
over and over every time I leave my base
every time I come back I see this thing
and I think to myself oh yeah I gotta
finish that oh yeah I gotta finish it
oh yeah you got to finish that over and
over it runs through my mind every time
I see it oh yeah but something about
today today was different guys it was
special I saw this and is like I'm gonna
finish that it's happening today's the
day so for whatever reason here we go it
is finally done just have to put a layer
leaves over this to finish it up so that
it has a bit of a bit more texture to it
than just having the clay here and I've
taken some some pauses in between
looking at it and I think it does look a
lot better with the leaves on actually
compared to the clay I don't have a
before-and-after for you but here's the
after now that it's all done look at
that oh snap finally got it done it was
actually a ridiculous amount of leaves
on this thing how how how big is this
area so we're at about a hundred and
fifteen here if we run all the way to
the other side cuz I felt like I just
dumped inventory after inventory on this
thing and it still wasn't done it still
wasn't done
115 all the way to about one about forty
here okay and then this way we're about
minus 280 I'm gonna do some quick math
to figure out how many stacks of leaves
I actually dropped on this minus 280 all
the way to
you 2:05 okay so that's about 75 bucks
aha so it's 75 by 75 roughly switch is
5625 leaves that had to be placed plus I
did that with the clay as well so it's
like double that and then there's a
section that kind of pops out a little
bit over there so all in all it was
probably actually about six thousand or
so blocks so somewhere between 90 and
100 stacks of leaves went into this
uh-huh but it's not done unfortunately
we still got it we got to add the the
trees that connect up to the canopy
right now it's just floating still but
we will save that for another day uh-huh
all right so well anyways let's move on
here you guys are probably like but Ito
you said it's a special day why don't
you just finish the whole thing today
no no no no it's a special day it's not
like I net there freezes over sort of
digging though guys we can't just go
around finishing whole projects in this
series that would just be crazy we
that's not what we do here I wanted to
head over here today to actually with
the next update I think they're gonna be
redoing all the villager trades so we're
running out of time where we can cash in
our pumpkins and I saw this thing is
just about totally filled up oh so these
are the new pumpkins these are the old
pumpkins with the faces these don't have
faces okay I don't know if we can trade
the the new ones oh wait maybe we can
only trade the new ones ah I got ripped
off already I thought I had to a little
next update no all the five kids I chat
trade them oh man I've been saving these
for four months guys months and it was
one of the other recent updates that
changed pumpkins so now the villager
tree got changed - oh my goodness okay
never mind we're doing something else
all right everyone so I decided let's
pop
into the amplified bass today and we
haven't been here in a very long time
and actually I don't know if I've shown
this yet but we had a bunch of floating
water up there and it's all updated now
so we have this this huge wall of water
here which is kind of cool we'll
probably have to clean it up
the reason we're over here though I saw
comment talking about that moveable
storage room thing we made and I can't
remember if we finished this I'm curious
so if not we're gonna try finish it
because I know we were very close and I
kind of want to see it in action because
I don't think we did much with it so
this is the buttons that started I'm
pretty sure let's just see if it works
at all so the way this works is it's
supposed to send off the storage
minecarts to one of the three stations
we have set up around here oh did they
stop on the track oh okay well that's
not good
yeah okay so track is kinda messed up I
guess the water washed it away okay so
the track is fixed let's do take two
here I put torches in all these
minecarts
so that we know where we want them to
end up at the next station so goes from
left to right top to bottom sort of
thing so now let's press this again whoo
so they should end up here I think oh I
hear them I think they're on their way
oh that's a good sign next row yeah okay
cool cool now let's check the torches so
again left to right left oh man I think
it actually works what what I thought we
had a lot left to do on this well not a
lot a lot left but I thought there was
like one big problem
okay let's try send it to the next
station then maybe I just finished one
of the station's and I was supposed to
do the other ones and I never did
because this station is definitely
working
ooh okay there's a problem looks like
they can't fit through there why is this
here okay so that's part of a build I
meant to do that oh dear
okay could have been worse
so it's looking like the main thing we
need to do with this is just like get it
polished up I did it looking the way we
want make sure all the tracks are
working properly and there's a lot of
areas I've found where mobs will be able
to spawn or walk on the tracks and we
got to make sure that doesn't happen too
and if because if the minecarts run into
a mob or something that's gonna mess
everything up and the storage room is
basically useless if they go out of
order or anything like that they get
stuck on the track somewhere so we got a
we got to make sure that never happens
so I'm gonna replace the stone here with
brick and I think we'll put some
spotlights in the bottom so that uh can
we change that actually I think we can
so that my carts look nice and bright
when they're here uh-huh
so we have a lot of areas like this
where it's opened up and we gotta we
gotta seal it off make sure no mobs can
get in there land on the track get in
the way you know so we gotta try make
that look natural blend it into the
terrain and then we also have areas like
that over there where the tractors
passes out into the open which doesn't
look like a big deal but like a mop
could be up here and then just get
knocked down by another mob or something
land on the track and then a minecart
will run into it and mess everything up
so anything like that we have to deal
with so I'm going to build like a tunnel
here probably that will hopefully still
look decent but we'll be safe from from
mobs landing on it so I think we'll do
like some fences and then put a a top on
that and I also found some parts of the
track here that have these really long
stretches with no power rails for some
reason I must have been low when I
built these so I'm gonna make sure
they're they're solid filled we're gonna
need a whole bunch of glass for one part
of the tunnel there so I decided to hop
over to the super smelter and finally
clean it out so all the furnaces had a
bunch of drown mushroom blocks in
because that's what we were using as
fuel before this update now they don't
burn though so they were clogging up the
furnaces we had to take them out and get
a new fuel source and I decided let's go
for spruce planks is what we're gonna be
using for fuel I know a lot of you told
me to use kelp but we don't really want
like a long burning fuel cuz if there's
only one item in the furnaces it's
pretty wasteful unless it's really easy
to farm I haven't actually looked into
it too much to be honest and just so I
know this is the fuel spot I'm gonna put
that there cuz I just put some sand in
here thinking this is where I smelt it
that's where we got a fuel it's okay
this is where we smell things over here
so let's let's get our sand we'll throw
that in here and make sure this still
works I think it should be fine though
it's been a while since I last used it
actually it's like when once you do like
a big load of glass or whatever it lasts
for a long time okay elevator stork's oh
yeah whole bunch of leg oh there was
some in here already oh I don't remember
it being this laggy we got one and a
half stack so we put four stacks in
something doesn't add up there huh oh is
it still good it's still running I see
okay never mind like wait a minute we
got a problem here four stacks came out
yes okay it's fine
back to the nether
oh no no ah you gotta be kidding me I
hit him twice he still wasn't dead this
is where we hope the ender pearl doesn't
hit the wall okay we made to the bottom
excellent
get out of here cool so I think the
whole minecart track is enclosed now
there's like a vertical drop there we
had to seal off we got our tunnels
there's one over there and we got one
over there and there's one more over
there too
okay wait a minute here it looks like
there is actually a problem that needs
to be solved when we use this just
listen to the minecarts
two of them go away to the next station
but for some reason a lot of them gets
stuck here like eight of them will get
stuck out of the den so I've got to
figure out why that's happening and fix
it we have one station that does work
and the other two don't but the one that
does work this is set to four here so
maybe that was a small little oversight
and maybe it'll work now we'll hope
without having to get really complicated
here let's try it again
oh I think they went way
no they didn't they're there jamm still
ok so that wasn't it it's something else
I guess there's no redstone controlling
these junctions like there's no I
thought there was like redstone torches
underneath or something no so they're
all they're all facing the wrong way
that's all it is so we gotta we gotta
flip them around so instead of
connecting to that rail it needs to
connect to that one might be a little
hard to do though cuz yeah the north's
or the default is to go into this one
right would you make it go that way if
we do that but then if we put this one
back it's facing the wrong way if we put
that there doesn't connect so this needs
then connect like this yes yes very good
and if this goes down then it's correct
and I want to check something out here
let's grab a track can we name a storage
minecart and have it keep the name so
let's let's say for example one of these
is gonna be our play chest let's call it
clay then after we place it does it keep
that name oh it does look at that yeah
that's probably what we would want to do
for the the storage system we're making
then to make it really fancy let's just
do a couple trial runs here before we
get that crazy because I think after we
break them it resets the name so you
just got to fill up this last little
column here we're gonna do five columns
of six I think is the plan so one two
three four five six okay so they're all
fully loaded and we're trapped up here
now get out here there's like no there's
no way for the mobs to get in but
there's no way for us to get out now
either okay so that's good we'll
probably have signs on the on the brick
here or something to see what's in the
chest as well
but let's give this a go so for the top
left I'm gonna put a torch here bottom
left we'll put on there just so we kind
of know that they keep the order after
we send them here you know because
that's pretty important
and top right so after they arrive at
their next destination that should all
be the same is the fan
I guess those junctions there we're
getting updated by some redstone and
resetting constantly so I have to power
them with levers by the way but yeah
basically they make their way down the
hill they drop down that that glass
column thing we did and the first stop
is over here takes them a little bit of
time to get here cuz it's quite a long
track actually that should be bottom
right yeah bottom left yep oh just
graphical glitches is nothing wrong
nothing wrong they're all perfectly in
order that is super cool though hey I
like that be so much easier to do
something like this with a chakra boxes
now though okay let's double check
they're all in the right order top
rights and top flaps so I think they
maintained order let's go to the next
station and you can have as many
stations as you want what's design with
this idea so that's pretty cool Ian and
stack is amazing one on top of each
other as well the only real catch with
this is we can't we can't unload the
chunks while they're being transferred
if we do they'll get all messed up so we
got to make sure we don't close the game
or or move away too far after we hit the
button we got to wait for them to arrive
at the next station
it'll again let's double check bottom
left yep
bottom right yeah I think it's good to
go guys I think we actually got it done
finally well it's official guys we threw
up some signs here so we have an actual
functioning storage system at the
amplified base now a little bit crazy
but it's a system I'm used to quite a
bit from the man cave so we're gonna
have to take all the all the junk we got
laying around here and throw it into
here there's like chests scattered
everywhere yeah we're gonna have to
clean up and throw in these mine carts
now
but the way I'm doing this is basically
by categories kind of like we do at the
man cave we can only put three signs per
column is the issue and they don't quite
line up perfectly with the minecarts so
the way it is is myst refers to that
minecart their tools that one potions
this one pearls that one seed links
that's like pumpkin seeds wheat seeds
saplings they go in their plants like
cactus and things yeah they go in their
leaves and stuff we got stone cobble
ugly blocks is like granite diorite and
andesite all andesite it's pretty nice
actually
concrete's soil that's like dirt course
dirts mycelium all that stuff grass
woods all the various types mod blocks
one and two is kind of like stuff that
doesn't fit in other categories like
prison rain for example is what I
consider an odd block glass all the
different colors sand and gravel
including sandstone and stuff goes in
there food
fences I decide to give it a chest not
really sure that's necessary but we'll
do it
clay terracotta wool function blocks
like fence dates and stuff would go in
there slabs and stairs minecarts rails
minecarts detective rails all that stuff
and finally ores and redstone and then
we got a few extra here in case we want
to add some more a little bit of
available storage but these are the main
catagories I think so let's try it out
terracotta or clay I still call it clay
even though it is named terracotta now
terracotta is the glaze kind no that's
what that refers to
soil goes in here so that would be grass
dirts yep stairs and slabs there's some
stairs there's some slabs we got more
dirt I didn't put in uh-huh so is it
gonna take a long time to
actually get organized here but we have
a system we're sticking to it mine carts
be that and that stuff huh
and yeah anyways I wanted to show you
guys this again as well this is a trick
that I think is super cool I've shown it
before a few times but it's one of those
things I don't think a lot of people
know about or they don't use so I'm just
gonna show it one more time today but
where it's like five thousand blocks out
here - five thousand there we do one of
these we throw the ender pearl in the
portal it takes us to - six hundred so
we're not quite home takes us to some
jungle kind of round our chunk airs do
it one more time no do it one more time
it's a little bit glitchy sometimes you
might need to read log I bet you yeah
it's kind of glitched out my my Elijah
wings not working now sometimes the
glitch is up sometimes it doesn't
yeah I can't fly so I got a real ugh no
it's got its ups and downs okay I reload
do it one more time and now it pretty
much takes us back home so every time we
do it it divides by eight on our
coordinates so we're at minus 100 or at
least I think it divides by eight
roughly and yeah this is our swamp
there's a canopy that we just finished
today and we are back home well we got a
few minutes left to this episode where
we can goof around so maybe we'll check
out some smaller projects now I can't
remember if I've shown this in a video
but I know during the world tour this
was broken when we tried it out but our
blue flower farm is back up working
again which is pretty cool
yeah because you kind of need to flower
farms in your world if you just have one
at a flower force you can't get the blue
flowers so you need that one at a swamp
as well so we got that set up at our man
cave here I think I wanted to finish
this room now it's I put like some blue
walls here I think I was gonna do green
glass but we got a bunch of that Brown
glass left right oh no I left at the
base which color or we could go for
whites or something I think I like I
think I like that one or that one it's
wonderful so I actually used some glazed
terracotta for once in my life and then
we we got the blue walls you might be
thinking Etha why blue walls it's
because it's a blue flower farm we have
to also write outside here we have blue
walls so it makes sense and that's why
we're doing it what about over here
let's do something over here get rid of
the stone stone is so last 10 years
we're moving on sunflowers and I mean
I'm not even gonna bother trying to
arrange him because that's crazy
takes too much effort so we're gonna do
that instead and then let's go for let's
actually wrap these down cuz why not
we have enough blocks to do it but now
we ran out so now we got to do something
else let's get get that up like this
actually you know what I'm gonna do I'm
gonna do like a half arch something like
that and then we'll put a stair here so
we got like a snow thing going on out
here it's unpleasant it's cold you know
but when we go inside BAM Hawaiian
shirts vacation you know you feel good
it's bright it's it's wonderful in here
feels nice yeah kind of like we're in a
sunroom right now let's do a lighting
check we got to get rid of this torch so
light level six here that's no-go let's
hide some lighting
under the chest then do we still have
some yeah we got a few more here okay so
that should definitely be bright enough
what about in the middle here looks like
we only go down to light level eats at
the lowest which is perfectly acceptable
at seven I think mobs can spawn though
so we gonna be careful I just noticed
the spot in our man cave here that
violates one of the rules of Minecraft
you can't have a four by four area or
bigger totally flat all the same block
type just not allowed guys not allowed
this is actually a three and a half by
like five but but it kind of falls in
the same realm so we got to put a
picture here or something not that one
not that one not that one okay let's do
one of these deals in if it's gonna be
like that
I want a three by two tall that's a too
tall
two by two we could probably get away
with a two by two actually are there any
that are three wide I think the wither
one right oh no that's that's a good
picture though we'll keep that and maybe
I'll try to do one more thing here we
might not be able to finish the whole
project but well we'll get started on it
but if we go over here for example we
have a nice little room right I like
this little room it's doesn't have a lot
of detail but it feels nice it's warm
cozy serves its purpose but then if we
go over here oh it's like a bomb went
off right so I kind of want to clean
this up a little bit today if we can
this is our pixel storage system where
we can search shelter boxes for a
specific item using a menu system so
like if we what do we have in here right
now we've got some stone we've got some
arrows so let's try search some arrows I
guess throw it in there
does it still work let's see if any
shelter boxes shoot out like they're not
supposed to do
ah see the shocker box is going up I
don't think anything landed on the
ground out here all right oh no
nevermind it's broken I think it would
work if we fix the elevator oh man this
is actually kind of eating me up here I
want to try fix it but I don't know if I
should there's four broken elevators in
this thing I believe unless I missed one
but yeah like what we would have to do
this like the way this is working is the
dropper shoots an item into solid blocks
and then in the past they want an escape
from here but for some reason it's like
shooting out the corners now so what we
probably have to do is replace all these
elevators with like bubble streams and
then that should work so we we want like
soul sand here and water above to bring
it up here and then we'll just break out
all the glass in the middle but the
problem is then we got to redo some
redstone and just the way we got this
laid out we kind of built it pretty
compact it might be hard to make work
with all these elevators this is like
the easiest one but I'll mess around
with it we'll see what we can do well we
got one elevator working here and it's
the biggest one but it's kind of on its
own and then we got lots of space so it
was easy to do the other ones they're a
little bit more complicated but check it
out we put that in and it's way faster
than the old one too with the bubble
streams like it gets the top almost
instantly which would mean the search
engine would be faster if we use this
one
ah let's go where are we let's go back
to the top here I think those are going
into here yeah okay so there's three
other elevators though it's a problem
and one of them I did like super compact
where I combine two elevators together
which is gonna make this ultra difficult
engine to change so there's one elevator
and it goes up to another elevator here
then which then it goes to the top I
think mixed in with a bunch of redstone
here too that's gonna be a little hard
to fix and then there's one here which
might be a little bit easier so this is
where we hope we don't spill water all
over a redstone you have this goes I
have a fortune pic I do let's use that
instead all right that should be good I
think we do this just to get it to go
over top the hoppers alright and then we
do that so it can't escape and I think
we got another elevator done maybe maybe
I really don't like putting water in
your your redstone it just freaks me out
guys you have no idea so I managed to
combine those two elevators together
again I did it with the hoppers though
so they only go into one dropper instead
of two different droppers like we had
before so one branch comes down or it
goes across here and down into here the
other one just goes across here into
that dropper so doesn't run at full
speed though hey wait wool ok but
nothing's flying out so that's kind of
the big thing right mm-hmm
and I just let's see if we can figure
out where that ended up
so the white wool and what do we use
stone brick should be together in here
yeah okay good I think that's where we
want it cool so maybe let's try this out
again I think it should be working now
so we have sand in here right
yes there's sand so let's search for
sand yeah now we find out we broke
everything
maybe well I think it ended up over here
actually yep okay I think it might
actually work again
uh oh okay we got some new leakage over
here now why did they why did that
happen oh man this thing is just just a
mess oh I wonder if I broke that over
there or did I just do that I kind of
messed around with the glass around this
area so maybe I opened it up so we can
escape now cuz I don't think that
happened the first time we used it
one more Oh bad jump we got it okay okay
so what are we gonna do to fix that I
think maybe if we just spam glass around
it a little bit more it'll be fine
so close so close to fixing it ah but I
don't think this is something we can get
around so the issue is this unit here is
the actual search engine there's two of
them in this thing and the one up there
is fine cuz there's glass above it but
this one we have a hopper above and they
changed hoppers so that they don't
occupy a full block anymore so you can
for example throw a block there when you
break this it stays on this ledge
because there's a bit of space there and
that's where the shocker boxes are
squeezing through now and that's causing
a lot of trouble so we need we need to
redesign this with the glass or
something solid above this area instead
of the hopper here and we can't just
move this hopper out of the way or to
take a different path because there's no
wiggle room like if we run it underneath
these hoppers it's gonna mess everything
up there's no space on
that side there's no space over here
there's no space over here so it's like
right in the heart of the machine so it
needs a total redesign to change the
layout pretty much well anyways guys we
gave it a good effort there at least we
know what's wrong
I'm a redesign it I'm not sure but we're
gonna end the episode for today we're
running a bit long so let's get to the
comments of the day like we always do
first one says hey etho I wanted to say
that I really did enjoy this world
improvement video I don't know how to
say it but it feels like a lot of
Minecraft videos have become too grand
and no longer feel like actual minecraft
so having a world series with simple
progression would be quite enjoyable for
me please make more episodes like this
one much love Amanda oh so nice right
so nice if you guys ever wonder why I
don't do exactly what you say in the
comments like what this was the top
comment why didn't you throw do what I
what I wanted him to do because then I
get other comments like what exactly
have you done in this episode you could
have employed the time better I expect
from you to see greater things
jack on the same video and thus eternal
conflict was born so if I do exactly
what you guys say always it's like
there's always a there's always
conflicting opinions then it would drive
me crazy so I kind of have to take what
you say with a grain of salt sometimes
anyways that's gonna be it for today
hope you enjoyed it until next time take
care have a wonderful day bye bye
you
[Music]