hey everybody this is etho welcome back
to my LP it's been a while again sorry
about that you know how I have been
having trouble finding animals well I
was I came to the desert here to harvest
some sand for glass and I found them I
know where they are they're in a hole
altogether just hanging out and I'm
noticing something watching these guys
that they don't seem to want to enter
the dark cave they're hanging out mostly
in this area here so I'm thinking that
might be new mob behavior that I didn't
know about yeah
something I really I'm gonna get some
wheat and we'll try bring them back to
my base it's not far from here but I'm
gonna watch these guys for a little
while I want to see if they go into the
chain or not because they should
actually I should block this off so they
can't get up yeah I just want to watch
him for a bit okay as harvesting some
sand here and I had a little surprise
lava and the weird thing is it's covered
up so I want to see if I can make the
sand fall down hmm maybe it's deeper
Ariel that could have been dangerous you
know if you're if you harvest some sand
and there's a lava pool below
all the sand would fall down and you
would fall in the lava the greatest
natural trap ever
that looks like that's the other stone
above it mostly weird and these animals
do not seem to be moving they seem to
prefer the light the daylight's like the
sunlight or moonlight so I'm going to
try see if I am I can push them if I
push them here if they're gonna like
always try to walk back come on buddy
move it actually I might hit a fishing
rod that's a good idea
I'll be right back okay I got a little
bit distracted here I want to show you
guys my favorite thing to do with a
fishing rod so I got my little buddy
here to help me out let's see if we can
hook um I love doing that oh good times
good times
alright so the plan here is to hook
these guys over here and see if they
automatically always try to run back to
the light
this guy's starting to come over here
like I went back that guy went back it's
not animal abuse that's what I keep
telling myself god I don't want to come
this way although if someone was trying
to hook me and my behind I wouldn't want
to go to him either okay so now let's
try with a torch let's see if they'll
stay here when I hook them why actually
hurt that guy still ran away your piggy
piggy
sorry jail not my fault it's for science
hey they're avoiding me still let's try
punch a hole in the ceiling to let in
natural light and see how that affects
them
I don't know if this is common knowledge
or not but this is news to me that light
affects these guys where's that a-hole
oh I didn't put in a very good place
yeah Mon there you now we have natural
light over here let's see if they'll run
back now that they have a closer a
source of it now it doesn't mind being
over here so in a way you can kind of
make changes for them using light and
only light so actually in my cave
instead of like making fences for them
all I need really is a Sun roof or
whatever come on
it seemed fine once they did with in
this area do not cooperate with me you
want to go back don't you know nothing
allow it not gonna allow it
okay well you like being here so I think
it's true
okay well that was my last fishing rod
so I will get some sand and we will go
back to the base and get some wheat I
got the strata again down to half a
heart here no food on me out at night
that will have to do I need to work on
my food situation because I keep eating
a zombie meat and it doesn't last very
long but I should be fine now okay we
made it back in one piece we're slowly
getting more and more resources here
we're actually doing pretty good I've
been doing some tunneling off-camera
just because I don't want to draw it out
too much in the lp I just want just want
to do it every so often a little bit
today I would like to take on that
abandoned mine shaft in the LP but
general tunneling isn't overly exciting
so I did some of it off camera basically
over here is the ravine just over here
yeah we're here so we got a nice open
space here I'm thinking I might build my
mob system in the ravine here I'll like
hollow out a big area near the bottom
and then I'll just hollow out like I got
a nice flat wall here I could just build
the hostile mob system in that no
problem and I'll get resources doing it
it's kind of like building my
underground style with the mob evader
except since I'm underground living
underground I can do a sky trap
underground and I won't have a big ugly
tower in the sky so that'll work out
good got the ravine here this goes down
to lava level this tunnel here oh hey
buddy it's not really lit up the
greatest
yeah that goes up to the surface there
we also have another path to the surface
um forget where grass is spreading
pretty good I've been slowly expanding
it trying to get all these different
tunnels but it takes its sweet time
that's for sure yeah the band and
mineshaft is just over here and I know
the spider spawner is closed because I
had one of the chief spiders chasing me
the other day when I got near it so it's
really close
oh yeah up there there's a path here
that goes around just kind of nice goes
around and slightly slopes up to this
area here and this goes to the surface
and it's raining apparently
so one plan I've had I'm having with
this new base is I kinda decided I
wanted all the areas to be accessible by
boat if that makes sense I did that in
my original starter world kind of in my
house I had like all these water roads
and it was pretty cool so I want to do
that it'll be like a mix of still water
areas and eats roads and elevators and
stuff so I'm thinking up now I'm hungry
again aren't I
I do have wheat some wheat not a lot but
I have a lot of bones yeah so I'm
thinking I'll try have a water thing
going around here nice water path it'll
go out over to here and then a water
elevator to the surface here and I'll be
able to come down to my base from with a
boat from there as well that's my plan
and I might have the water run down here
the pool over here and from there I
haven't figured it out but I'm not sure
how it's going to look either and
something else I want to play around
with was the iron bars you guys suggest
that I should use it for lighting the
lab a lighting thing I just want to see
how it looks
we'll put some on our creeper face here
see how it turns out because apparently
the wooden fences do burn now the nether
ones don't
oops achtung I'm never going to get that
back in my
I have no idea what the best tool is for
these either pick I'm guessing oh boy
okay well I'll do this and then we'll
see what it looks like
hmm well I don't think I like it for the
creeper face but for general lab
lighting it looks pretty good like to
have stuff like that around the place
seems like a good idea
better than fences anyway yeah so I'm
gonna actually I am ready let's go check
out the banded mineshaft here see what
we got so I think it was up here that
the spiders were harassing me when I got
close over here oh right right over
there it's right over there I can't
believe it out and open I hear a spider
but I don't see it I'm hoping to find
some watermelon seeds this abandoned
mineshaft is whoa where'd you come from
where are you there's more down there oh
dang oh he's after me Hank
oh don't come hear me oh there's two
no no no no no no no no no aah
hey and so there must be two spawners
hmm give me five minutes while my health
regenerates here okay as being sarcastic
about the five minute thing but it
literally did take like two minutes to
regenerate it's terrible so let's try
find this other one a how can I kill you
you see it I don't see it there's a
whole lot of webs down there though
where are you at
I say you come down here this mine shaft
is a mess down me oh dang oh okay wanna
go this way oh whoa man look at this
giant open weird I sound very closed
still this is weird soil and like a
square what is up with this
huh strange creeper some mushrooms a oh
that was that that was that ah
pay attention I was is memorized that he
didn't explode and I walked my own fire
why didn't he explode I don't think I
was hiding behind the fences - well oh
boy good stuff haven't found HS yet this
is actually my first band in my chaffed
I've taken on legitimately like in
survival mode
I've only seen them in creative mode so
far I'm out of the torches already
what's going on oh man is there another
one there is another one don't go back
me into a corner Wow if there's another
one here that's like three then this
very close area together yeah so here oh
darn Oh Oh spider web hmm hey I got ya
here oh I didn't bring armor with me cuz
I thought I could get away with it
I just regenerate so slowly why so slow
I gotta get some more torches there is
yes I've been playing legendary and ever
since then I've had like no fear of
going around cave systems anymore cuz
they are nothing in comparison and I'll
probably start posting videos of that
soon maybe tomorrow even we'll see I did
the race for the role that was a lot of
fun we got our butts kicked though
unfortunately but we might be like doing
a leak type thing as the plan so we'll
we'll have another chance of redeeming
ourselves and we have a I talked to the
guys and we have a good plan highly
detailed plan for
next time I don't know if you could tell
but we did that last one blind so we had
no idea what the map was like and we
never did a race together either but we
had a lot of fun that was an important
thing okay health is regenerated let's
go one more time
I lost where we were not over there it
was
looks like there's light up there or was
it not there must have been over here
yeah yeah down here okay here we go yeah
I see the spawner stops breaking my
whole torches darn it
ah I see hey I'm yeah I'm playing the
pre-release number three now if I
believe you can neutralize effects like
poison if you drink milk although I
might be wrong about that I should check
that out would be good to bring some
milk with me for this okay dead end is
there kind of no I'm not I'm not
recovered darn I could be fancy just
tunnel but yeah I'm in as well get a
little closer okay there's another path
here and I'm out of torches
all right here we go again
see if we can shut it down
well I think it me very close should get
her there he's stuck on the fence ha ha
I said on fire will Cobb let's burn
doesn't look like it no no no no don't
you touch me ah I thought the fire would
prevent them from spawning but it's not
working to him and that was a dumb idea
because now I'm stuck in a corner keep
my lunchbox line
and I killed on my torches oh but the
spiderwebs wash away did not know that a
lot worked out pretty good
he stopped spawning ah there we go I
think there's one up there still take
down the fence and get attacked yeah
there's a hot that's to spawn or so far
no chess this looks like a dead ends and
I want to see what's out here they're
very close must be above or not they're
driving me crazy
where was I found one oh that's you
again we found a zombie up here before
we should check it out
nothing
it's like they're so close but I can't
find them down below
they are cool oops oh we got some lab
over here check it out we found a chest
first chest what's inside
pretty good pretty good we go to
diamonds and I got a pick which is great
because mine was just running out and we
need an iron for a sort too so that
worked out pretty good I would have
liked some seeds but oh well
very nice take the chest with us cool so
oh another chest down there awesome
seed seed seeds I want some watermelon
ah
awesome we got them melon yeah that's
what we want
cool mission accomplished
so the only thing I want to do yet is
find that others bite your spawner
alright we're by that other spider
spawner let's see if we can take it down
quickly goes over here was it over here
down below there that right over there
there's another one unbelievable that's
like three in a really tiny area all
together
I probably don't want to fall down
they're actually not too difficult Oh
ninja almost got me there
hmm yeah I'm gonna do it nope bad idea
Oh bad idea
oh dang and I can't hit them that sucks
my life I'm alive so now I wish I had
more blocks okay well I'm gonna hang out
over here for a second
oh it's frayed out there there's one
over there too
how'd they get over there hey no well
that didn't go quite like I wanted oh
they can probably get up over to you
it'll be careful
cool uh I could shut down maybe not
there's a lot around here still one up
there riff there's more spawners
skeleton down there and a keeper oh whoa
no no why can't I hit him I'm stuck on
something here Oh
Oh for cryin out loud that was no fair
ah I couldn't hit him for some reason or
move
unbelievable I got to get back there
quick should I be around here I'm a
little bit lost there's a spawner up
there okay I remember this area a little
bit like bends around to the right and
then the big square room yet I should
have brought some weapons with me all
there's more creepers okay it goes up
and then down my sword I'm wondering if
there's another one up there let's get
my diamond make an opening this time
okay think I'm good now yeah I got
everything back I want you got up here
organized there's definitely something
up there I can't believe how many
spawners there're more evil eyes oh ah
you got me freaking fences man you can't
attack when you're here hey hey don't
chase me hey why is there spiders - like
disable them
found another chest here but there's a
spider as well a little worried about it
might be a spawner this spider is hide
really well the light just hover in the
ceiling yeah there he is oh oh you got
me oh man there it is hey and walk it
for now hey check the chest mmm not the
best take the gold I will leave what
will I leave arrows I guess we'll try
take this on quickly get my water oh
that won't work
darn this might have been one we've
gotten to already actually how they do
it I don't open though they're masters
there's a torch next to that spawner so
I've been here turns out that spawner is
right by our base here I had no idea
even so we had a good haul got some
melon seeds diamond bit of iron string
lots and lots of string some tracks I
picked up I'll have to go through there
again and clean up the area for iron and
coal and tracks and that stuff but that
is pretty good for today
oh I did have another show all that time
didn't even know it and check it out the
two spawners are like right next to each
other here less than 16 blocks apart and
there's another one about 40 blocks from
here so pretty close together I might
make a spider trap from this just for
the fun of it sensor since we got too
close together and we are right by our
base here it might be fun to do that but
not today
I'm going to call it an end for today
because it's again light here and I
thank you for watching as always