[Music]
greetings everybody
this is etho and i am back
back and ready to play again last
episode
i mentioned i would not be able to
record for four or five days i had
family visiting and i
wanted to spend as much time as possible
with them while they were here
now they are gone so it's back to
minecraft and
having fun playing with the new 1.3
stuff
uh i missed some of the 1.3 release hype
i wasn't able to get on minecraft server
and stuff but that's okay we can still
still have some fun here um over the
four
last four or five days i've had a few
minutes where i could
log in and do some stuff here so
i i messed with this area some more
so before we just had the arches now i
have this section here
i thought i would try it out i think it
looks pretty good i put a waterfall on
both sides
and might try to incorporate some more
water into here
in the future um
i think that's about it there's one
other big thing i've been working on
as i've had time and i'll go show it to
you
uh i wanted to do a big
paper trade with the villagers for this
episode so hopefully
we will have enough paper to get some
emeralds
but this is what i've been working on
over here this giant
reed farm just the simple
field of of uh reeds or sugar cane
and it's gotten pretty big
because i haven't really had a like
large sections of time where i could
really record anything
so i just would come on here for a few
minutes
work on this and then do that a little
bit every day
um and this tip growing and growing
and there's quite a bit of sugarcane
here
so it's just a simple farm there's no
automatic harvesting or anything like
that but
it's very very dense so we can just
do this and it should be
really effective i would think just
because of the sheer
number
of sugar cane here i think this will
fill up our inventory pretty quick
and all it is is water with lily pads
above so we can run through here without
falling in every
every couple steps we take into the
water and below the water is a glowing
pumpkin so even at night
don't have to worry about mobs spawning
in here
and messing up my patterns and reeds and
all that
so that's pretty cool
oh yeah go over top
give a nice overview and i may continue
to expand it some more i'm not sure at
this point it's
uh it's pretty quick like
i don't know i'm in the area so it just
grows and grows and grows
and don't need don't need to overdo it
but i might expand it some more
that way or something we'll see
so you can see it's getting dark and
it's still light all around
the sugar cane here i'm going to get a
bunch of them together and we'll try to
do a big trade with one of the villagers
oh and also um
i've done a few other loose loose end
things i've wanted to do
which i can't quite remember but
something else i want to do is i want to
put the ice between the snowflake
like we talked about and i don't know if
i'll
bother shaping it this episode might do
that in the future
but i'm going to film those spaces right
now
man look at that i thought this the
field was going to look huge from up
here but it's this
tiny little thing
it looks so big from down low though
oh well um yeah it's going to give us a
lot
of sugar cane i didn't even finish
harvesting it yet
and it wasn't even fully grown when i
did start
um looks like i'm gonna run out ice
though and i have to go harvest some
more
i use up four stacks pretty quickly yeah
it turns out
like every every water spot there was an
ice block that i just
that i let melt or i broke it myself so
the nice thing about ice is it's like
water that stacks you can you can bring
it with you
places really easy instead of using
water buckets so that's kind of
what i've gotten into doing now
uh well let's see how this looks anyway
go get some more ice
decide if we like it oh yeah that's
that's pretty cool
yeah i like that cool
here's a night shot of the thing very
bright
oh yeah
excellent so we got enough ice to finish
the snowflake finally
it looks pretty cool no pun intended
and we can see through we won't fall
through
let's go check it out from below um
gotta be real careful with the lighting
up here haven't figured it out yet
otherwise this ice will start melting
and water will flow down if we update it
i'm glad that like when ice melts it
still
and it creates water the water doesn't
start flowing
automatically on its own you still have
to update it which is
always a good thing otherwise you can
easily make a mess
of things oh yeah that looks pretty good
cool so that's just the 2d version of it
i still plan on
shaping it like i said i wanted to
start out thin at the edges and kind of
get
slowly get thicker and thicker and then
quickly get fatter and fatter
and make it sort of cone-shaped
have an ice elevator all the way up
actually that's something we'll do in
another day or
or something um
oh do that accidentally hit right click
um yeah
we're going to shape it later and give
it a little more character we're going
to put a boat elevator and some other
stuff on it
in the future cool so i'm going to get
some more paper together and we're going
to do a huge
villager trade
um we seem to have some 1.3 trouble here
the world is not loading
at all it just ends
end of the world here we're getting shot
at by something
huh yeah 1.3 is still pretty buggy man
they gotta they gotta improve the stuff
quick
man we are going to be so rich
so wealthy gonna have to find a bank
open up a bank account
store all our emeralds or else we could
just blow them all and
and buy anything we want oh it's going
to be great
so yeah we got about
um double chest just over a double chest
full of paper
that we're going to sell to our friend
here
19 per emerald i just built this around
so this paper doesn't spill out
all over the place it's a bit of a crude
way of doing it but this is our first
attempt
we want to make sure it's we're able to
pick it up where we're standing
should be about good here
can't wait too long it'll despawn and
now he doesn't want to trade what's
going on
am i too far away
hmm well hopefully we're close enough
all right
let the insanity begin
oh we can trade all we want as long as
we don't
leave this screen
there we go now i got my flow figured
out
that's a lot of emeralds man by a lot of
things
and it was so easy to get this paper
this is to take a while man
my goodness oh first stack
um toss that keep going
gotta hurry here lots of paper to go
through
another option is i could start up a
paper company
thunder mifflin and
support myself that way
over two stacks now
doesn't look like we're going to break
three stacks it was close
very close that's it that's all we got
now when we leave this screen this trade
is going to disappear for sure
and i missed i had like four six more
stacks
that i wasn't able to get through some
back there
yeah trade's gone if we just trade a few
more times i'm sure the paper
option will reappear and we can trade
some more
that was cool
all right terrific that turned out very
well
so we have over three stacks of emeralds
in our world
now uh thanks to our dunder mifflin
business
we've moved up to upper class citizens i
think i think we're gonna finally get
some respect
from these guys due to our recent
financial success
speaking of respect we have some on us
which we're going to use for our next
project so today
i want to begin the village project this
is something
this village has been on the to-do list
for a long time
there's supposed to be a village behind
this door
i haven't started it yet
so let's start it today it's going to be
a fairly large project
uh but one we can work on little bits
here and there we don't have to do it
all today
nor can we and we can keep expanding it
as much as we want or
if we're tired of it we can say it's
done type thing
but yeah we got to clear out a whole
bunch of space and we finally got enough
tnt
to really do that to make a big hole in
the world
for our friends here so
outside these doors i think what i'm
going to do is i'm going to make it go
downward try and make the blast go down
open up wide and high so it'll feel very
expansive when we look down from up here
just imagine a village right in front of
us a huge awesome village
that's kind of what i want to do and
today probably all we're going to do is
just clear out a bunch of space
and later we'll start placing blocks and
decorating and all that fun stuff
building houses
the theme i'm thinking of doing is sort
of an industrial theme
with a bit of a twist so i want to use
stone bricks
i want to use iron bars i
don't think i'm going to use nether
brick but i'm not sure yet
um stone brick iron bars
any other stone color too like that
maybe cobblestone
there's also going to be grass mixed in
nice green grass like this
there's going to be lots of lava lots of
water
some trees and stuff i think it'll look
good
if it turns out like i'm envisioning so
we've got our villagers here they're
still okay
we need a priest that's what we need so
we can do some actual trading
actually i don't want to trade with
these guys but yeah i'm going to start
laying some charges
and i hope i hope it turns out i make
i'm going to make a backup too before i
begin
you know what guys we're going to do
this the fun way
i was going to do my method where i blow
exactly
the number of blocks i want up and space
out the tnt all nice and that
but
i think the better way of doing this is
actually just to do a big
glob of tnt all together
and that will make
the cave we form a lot more random which
is what i want i don't want
a perfect square type thing i want it to
be pretty random
as far as i've tested before
this should blow up about a 20 by 20
by 15 tall
area or so into the world but we got all
this open space here so i'm not sure
exactly when i tried it
before it was solid underground
uh so i'm kind of excited to see what
this will do i think it'll be fairly
random
and i don't have as much tnt as i would
like
that's okay we will do this
and this is all my tnt
i hate to use it all on this but
we can get more in the future
um there okay so i've
drilled a hole up above there
we're gonna drop one tnt down
yeah like this is fairly open it's all
abandoned mine shaft around here lots of
empty space
i don't i think it'll blow a pretty big
opening
and it should be far enough away from
our other stuff
i did put up i'm gonna put up like a
wall here
i did put this up too just in case i
don't want it to
pull up any wiring or anything
uh but yeah this should be pretty fun
and this will be like the main
entrance to the village what we're gonna
blow up here
and then we can expand it further later
okay here we go that's not gonna do
anything
is it it did oh hello
oops
lots of mobs yeah right above the
village is going to be
the glowing trees which is cool um
okay have fun everybody
let's hope this doesn't kill me
excellent not much leg from that i'm
surprised let's
go see the damage
cool that's awesome
sweet okay how does that look from
our entrance how much stuff did we
destroy doing that
entrance is here
yeah that's pretty good that's like
exactly what i wanted it to do
cool have a nice look down area
up here and then we will continue to
expand it though as we get more into
tnt this was all i had
okay this thing get blown up
very good
um you know what on second thought this
isn't quite what i want
uh what i'm would prefer is if the
ground was
about five blocks higher and the ceiling
went up five blocks more too
so we should have put that blast a
little bit higher
this is i think this is too much of a
drop and that ceiling isn't as high as i
would have liked
so i'm gonna reload the back up we'll
try it again
except a little bit higher
all right so i repositioned it it's
about five blocks higher now
um being pretty picky about this i know
i know but it'll save me a lot of work
if i get this
first blast right i think
has a big effect on the project so i
want to make sure it's right
or the way i want it
which may not be right um
okay so we're gonna go back up here that
was a fail
awesome here we go take two
this is a good excuse to do it again too
that's much closer
sweet let's check it out
hey no actually i don't want you to blow
up
nope nope
i do but he'll probably kill me
cool man
nice try oh you know what i never did i
never put the wall
down here this time it looks okay i
don't think it blew anything up
um okay let's go up check it
check the feel
that's okay check for damages this is
still walled in that's good
they're holding on to each other they're
scared
ah yeah that's that's more like what i
want see it's a bit higher now
and this doesn't go as deep
but we can still have a nice cliff after
some terraforming it'll look
pretty good i think some more
terraforming some more personal
terraforming yeah
cool i went through here and i lit it up
clean up some of the jagged edges uh
thought about it some more and this
looks good this is what i want
but i would like it to go maybe
like 10 blocks further that way so i
want this whole wall
to get pushed back some more probably up
to
like the edge of this thing almost like
up to here
is where i would like it to end and
what we'll do is make let's go back up
here
i'm going to make the center of the
village at about
here type thing we'll put houses all
around that
and then it will expand from that point
that's what i want to do but we're out
of tnt
no so we got to get some more
before we can continue let's head over
to
the mob system the
oh thank you mob system and maybe we'll
play around with some ice there and
uh some stuff over there
[Music]
oh that was quick we are here um
yeah we just got a few minutes left in
this episode probably i'll just mess
around
here for a little while um the winner
out of these four themes if you guys
remember
we got this one
we got the nether brick fence one
uh the iron bars and
the regular fence out of those four the
winner was
this one i would say by quite a bit
um however
we did talk about putting ice here so
that might change people's opinions as
well
but i just want to mess with something
uh trying to figure out what i'm going
to do about the borders because i wanted
a
like a one wide border over here and we
also have sort of a border here with the
logs
but now we can place logs sideways or
something apparently
so i was thinking it might look good if
we had these sideways so it would be
dark
instead of light like that and also put
them sideways
here to get the wood look
um i had let's see if i can figure out
how to put them sideways
apparently it's really easy oh cool
that was easier than i thought um how do
you put them
i guess it's like placing a piston type
thing
oh i bet you can do a lot of cool stuff
with that
okay so yeah we can probably put this
stuff sideways
um
not sure how that would oh wait wait a
minute the grain
is like that then
hmm i wonder if that's better
that looks so weird why does that look
so weird
is it different by the direction like if
i place one like this and then i place
one like this
it's gonna be the same yeah it's the
same
pretty sure
well yeah it is it's the same
okay
hmm trying to decide if i like it or not
maybe i'll put a few of those down
anyway another thing i want to check
out i'll put a few of those down and
we'll check that in just a bit
but uh i know in the past if you had ice
and half slabs above you would still get
the
would still be like you're on ice
walking on the half slab so we're going
to try that out
see if it still works i'm a little
scared of using it because it might get
patched
everything seems to get patched if i use
it in my world
get out of here torches
um
if we use ice with this project we can
only use a certain amount
because i'm worried it's going to start
melting
okay so when you jump on ice you kind of
take off
you get a speed boost let's see if we
get the same thing with this
also you can slide items on ice
oh it still does work on half slabs it's
cool
very cool so let's just make sure it
works with us
yeah i think it did there yeah
so we can hide the ice underground and
then we can have half slabs two like we
wanted because i didn't want it to be
two blocks down i only wanted it one and
a half down
so that works out perfect
also it probably won't melt if it's
covered like that right
which is another benefit don't have to
worry about that
um
what else should we do with these stairs
i'll probably keep the light wood
and then have dark wood it highlights
the stairs if it's light here and dark
here
instead of having this the dark the dark
planks as well
do this just see how this looks
[Music]
we're not going to do it all one color
like this i just wanna
see the shape see if it's something we'd
like
yeah it's pretty good okay
uh to figure out the actual size of this
room i need to take inventory of every
single item
in the game organize it into groups
and figure out how many chests i need
and once i got that all figured out i'll
figure out i'll be able to figure out
how far apart
i want this from the wall
type thing so that's something i do
off-camera sometime
uh probably take me a couple hours to
organize it all
it's the same thing i did with the old
storage room just
a lot more items now than back then
so it'll take even longer
but yeah this is cool
no that doesn't look good not doing that
and you know what i don't like the
sideways logs for these either
so we're not doing them there
i want to get those back
yeah i just realized we got to
incorporate snow somehow too
we can't just have snow in the middle we
need it
on the outside as well to carry out the
feel
um so i got some snow with us we're
going to try to play with this some more
and again this doesn't need to be grass
it probably won't be when we're done
i was wondering how it would look if we
did
an outline here
so the half slabs would come up to the
snow
and it would go all the way around this
type thing now let's go get some more of
these
underneath the half slabs will be ice so
we can jump around quickly and
and why not oh ooh
did not know i had that there i have a
lot of iron now
lots of lots of materials
of all types
yeah let's see how this goes
and we could we could change this too
like we could have the dark plank
half slabs here and then with the border
and then
have the light ones on the inside type
thing or something like that
[Music]
it's not too bad because we could have
have snow here and then on this side we
could also have
a line of snow then it would carry out
the look pretty good
maybe because we don't have enough snow
snow themed stuff and if we cover up the
ice it's going to be even less
okay
yeah this is kind of what i was thinking
with the dark planks have them go around
the snow like this
as well then we have the light planks
here and depending on how wide these
become we
will try to mix some
dark plant texture in with them as well
just so it's not plain anywhere
what do you guys think do you like that
yes no
i think it could be pretty cool i'm
still deciding if i want to keep the
grass or not it really does look good
but i don't want to copy the old
design either not that we really are
this is already quite different than
what i'm used to
but yeah i'm gonna get going here thank
you for watching everybody
have a good day i will see you again
next time
[Music]
you