hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of this
game we love ever so much called
minecraft it's a long intro I know I'm
sorry we are over here at the library
guys this is episode 449 next episodes
450 we're going to do the world tour and
there's a very good chance I'll be
releasing a world download on episode
450 so today if I can get it hosted
somewhere today though let's sleep I
might make it our goal or our theme for
this episode to fix up some some stuff
that seems to be broken or incomplete
because when you get a hold of the world
I want you to be able to check out as
much stuff as possible without it being
broken so yeah we're going to try to fix
up some stuff I started off with our
book matrix thing here the item elevator
was broken I just added in a new one so
now if I want like a knock-back book for
example just press the button got like
all our enchanted books choosable here
they always pop up in the same spot here
and it knock back to so that's pretty
cool I do not have spots for frost
Walker or mending and we're not adding
them those came out after after we built
this I did leave like one free spot
available in case they introduced a new
enchantment to the game I did not think
they would but yeah def strider got that
spot already so they've added two three
since I built this thing that I was not
expecting anyways it's just a dropper
elevator thing I'm using those whenever
I have to go a short distance upward so
it's just like six droppers here facing
up and that's all there is to it pretty
much compared to the text if there's an
item in here if there is comparator
turns on repeater turns on this is like
a
delay makes a long pulse extension and
then repeater here grabs that goes to a
comparator clock so just signal wraps
back around and then there's an elevator
or out redstone wire staircase thing on
the other side here that goes to each of
the droppers just goes up here and yeah
that's kind of my go-to design I think
for any short distance item elevator I
need right now
um let's see actually let's go down
maybe we will fix up that conveyor thing
in that tunnel here I think we can get
to it down here if I don't die
ouch ouch ouch smack my face into that
wall a couple times yeah I remember this
thing here still haven't fixed it we
have one repeater between each of these
Pistons we need to add two otherwise
it's very iffy if it's going to work or
not yeah we got stuck there so I'm going
to try change this out to have two all
right guys I think I got it working now
let's go check it out to get to that
conveyor belt is through the waterfall
here our little secret waterfall I got
to go and chant something I just hop in
through there fly through our cool
tunnel here it still needs to be
decorate oh voice crack decorated hmm
yes I'm very manly
um and that takes us to the conveyor
belt here so to get the rest of the way
to the library since we can't quite make
it with the wings itself we're down to
bedrock now this pulls us the rest away
as long as it doesn't mess up on us I
haven't had to fail yet since the added
in expert Peters so I think we're good
fix this up an elevator and then BAM
library so that is pretty cool
should work out all right now let's head
back down very carefully here I've
almost died Oh what was that that's like
my fourth time now it always takes me
down to one heart so I just barely
survived every time all right yeah let's
check out the Redstone in case you want
to copy it fill up first so from this
pressure plate here all I did is pretty
simple all right there's a redstone dust
right below that that pressure plate
then a repeater here this is just to
give us a bit of delay so we have time
to fall into position there there's a
block goes to another repeater then this
is a sticky piston with a block above
that's our monolith stable circuits one
tick repeater there that repeater goes
to this piston first off and then it
does the zigzag thing this is the the
repeating pattern basically two
repeaters each piston and then I just
zig zag zig zag all the way down that's
all there is to it and it seems to work
now so that's good we're going to go
with that now to finish this up for the
the piston tract here I'll try to do
something simple just a poopy Brown that
we love ever so much probably will do it
nice and simple might need to add some
lighting in there though because
otherwise it will probably spawn mobs
and stuff so maybe above at the top
you'll add some lighting there's
something simple DOS I don't have to
spend a lot of time on this and then I
want it to put in a wall like maybe
right here so to cut off the rest this
tunnel so we don't have to decorate it
in the future um so I brought over some
fill that in brought over a bunch of
stuff here we'll try building a
cool-looking Waller a simple wall anyway
maybe starting here oops let's do a
little entrance thing see if we can come
up with something that looks half decent
here yeah we'll do that to start off
with and maybe let's just do like
columns all the way down then that's a
simple thing that might look decent
we'll see I'll put fences between them -
all right let's just check that out
right now yeah I kind of like that
that's simple let's do fences ah let's
go for spruce sir oak spruce or oak
let's do oak wood for contrast maybe and
behind that let's put oh well we need
contrast let's go for maybe spruce wood
see what that looks like
alright something pretty simple here
yeah that might be ok um let's let's put
a little border on the bottom maybe
would be better and then spruce wood and
then the fences oh and we're trapped
alright I just want to close off this
area because I don't want to decorate
back here that's that's a lot of extra
work when we get around to it and more
fences yeah it's not great but that's
it'll be ok like this we could even try
to add more detail to it like we could
put we don't want just like grass here
we'll let's put some oak wood for
example ooh do a little bit of wood down
there yeah that already makes a look a
better huh huh ah so check it out guys I
got I pretty much got this done now add
some more details to it I put like a
trim on the top here we got our entrance
highlighted so we know where to go it's
pretty pretty clear to see that and did
the trim on the ground here then
is really important like I was saying if
you want to make a transition from a
wall to the ground it's good to put like
just some kind of separation block
between them and got some skylights we
got some supports we got some leaves all
that good stuff and I think that's going
to do it also I never realized this
before but while while doing this I
connect the path block to this oak trim
the path block and oak are actually very
similar in color they go pretty good
together I'm going to keep that in mind
in the future yeah for future builds and
yeah while building this as trying to
think of what to do next
honestly I don't there's really that
much stuff broken in our world I'm
having trouble coming up with the next
idea I've been going through like all
the projects in our world I think we
pretty much got everything fixed right
now this is no wall machine nothing's
really standing out that needs to be
worked on there are a few projects I
would classify as broken still there is
the second gold farm the one that used
iron golems but we can't really fix that
because iron golems is died too easy now
before they dig no damage and we have to
eat roads in the world there's the one
in the end that goes to the ender ender
and there's this one over here that goes
to the abandoned mineshaft and I hate to
say it guys but eats Road is pretty much
done for these days it had a good run
light at the beginning it was it was
pretty viable good alternate to
minecarts but as patches got released
you know they never they did never did
make it so eats road would work on a
server too well and then they made it so
the boat elevators got nerfed and yeah
over time things just got worse and
worse for the etes road nowadays this is
what happens with the latest boat
changes I'm not going down there he
wants me to go down there I'm not going
down there that's right
uh because of the whole boat submerging
issue like you can't even hop in the
boat it's it's under water so you can't
go in it
oh I stuck in there help as soon as I
hit the water block there it ejected me
so yeah not really a thing anymore but
we got the ice rooms now so it's got a
good trade-off yeah so we don't have a
lot of like broken projects like
projects that we have finished that no
longer work because of some updates but
we do have a ton an absolute ton of
unfinished projects I decide to look at
our list here some of these are done now
I just can't cross them off I decided to
pick number 19 though gold farm at
number 1 this baby over here since other
gold farm doesn't work and we can't fix
it we should try to make this one a
little bit nicer because I am low on
gold and I need like power rails I need
gold and carrots that kind of stuff and
I just can't get them until well this
works I just don't really want to use it
or I have no desire to use it because
it's not done so yeah let's let's work
on this I'll try to tell you guys a
story as we do one of the comments I see
quite often is people want me to do a
follow up on my sleeping schedule
because I told you guys about this a
while ago basically I was a nighttime
person and it's trying to I wanted to
convert to becoming a morning person at
that time I think I was going to bed at
like 4:00 a.m. every night and that
sucks because you know other people
don't go to bed at 4 a.m. so if
sometimes you got to get up early and
it's yeah not not the best feeling when
you have to wake up early when you're a
nighttime person anyways so carry on the
story it got worse guys it got a lot
worse I got to the point where I was
going to bed at 5:00 a.m. every nights
then 6:00 a.m. every night and then 7:00
a.m. and this was in the winter time I
believe so at 7:00 a.m. that's when the
Sun would rise in the winter
and I would go to bed right when the Sun
was rising and then I wake up and the
Sun would go down in a like an hour
that's pretty much living in an eternal
nighttime which wasn't the best kind of
gets what do they call that winter
sickness or whatever winter depression
when you don't see the Sun enough it
gets to you you know it sucks I just
made a little correction here because I
didn't like how this was lining up so I
think it's good now let's carry on so
yeah one day I had this great idea guys
great idea it's 7:00 a.m. came around I
wasn't really tired my problem is the
day's sort of need to be twenty five
hours you know and just sleep an extra
10 minutes or something you know that
would be perfect for me
but the days are 24 hours every every
day I kind of want to stay up an hour
later because I'm not really tired and I
have trouble sleeping when I'm not tired
so 7 a.m. comes around one day it's like
okay I don't I don't really want to go
to bed the Sun just came up I'm feeling
pretty good I decide to pull an
all-nighter and this is where my life
turned into a living nightmare
like almost literally like oh my
goodness so I pull an all-nighter I
thought you know it it's gonna come
around 9 p.m. or something I'm gonna be
super tired and I'll just go to bed
early and it will all work out I'll
sleep like 12 hours and should work out
that I wake up at 8 a.m. or something
you know it'll be perfect so I'm tired
all day
and then uh soon as like evening hits
like 7:00 p.m. I turn wide awake I was
is a wreck all day 7 p.m. it's I'm wide
awake I don't want to go to bed I don't
know what changes or why I'm like that
but yeah soon as evening hits I don't
want to
I'm not tired anymore I could stay up
forever pretty much is it directive 6
here 1 2 3 oh I did I got it go down 1
whoops so yeah I ended up staying up to
like 12 a.m. or 1 a.m. or something and
then I slept 12 hours or whatever next
day comes around I decide I'm gonna try
this again maybe I just didn't do it
quite right maybe because I felt more
tired the second time trying it so I
thought you know maybe I'll be tired in
the evening this time so I do it again I
stay up to out two days in a row I'm a
wreck on the second day like I barely
think I just want to sleep um but I try
to hold out till evening because I want
to fall asleep at like 7 p.m. so it
works out I wake up at 8 a.m. the next
day
alright try to get my cycle aligned to
that 8 8 a.m. time slot but no as soon
as evening hits again I'm wide awake and
this goes on for about 2 weeks where I'm
staying up 2 days in a row and then
sleeping 1216 hours a couple of these
times I did actually go to bed at like 7
or 8 I forced myself to but you know
what would happen I would wake up at 3
a.m. or something I would only sleep 8
hours instead of this the full 12 or 16
I was expecting because I was so tired
um so it wasn't really aligning my sleep
schedule like I wanted um so I get this
new idea I'm going to kind of have a
normal day except I would try to be
awake for an extra 2 or 3 hours everyday
you know get rid of this staying up two
days in row thing just stay up an extra
2 3 hours and wake up at weird times if
I did that eventually it would get to
the point where I should change my sleep
schedules gradually that was a nightmare
that was that was even worse in staying
up two days in a row
uh you really need a routine guys with
your sleep if you don't have a routine I
tell you you almost you almost get kind
of crazy like you lose touch with
reality you lose all your ambitions you
lose all your focus um
you're kind of like a zombie is the best
way to put it but yeah I did that for
about a week guys where I was trying to
stay up an extra you know two hours
everyday and then waiting up three hours
later because you need to get extra
sleep for that extra time you're staying
up so I do them I'd wake up like 2 p.m.
one day then 4 p.m. the next day then 6
p.m. and 8 p.m. 10 p.m.
slowly slowly making my way over to that
8 a.m. wake-up time that gradual change
did the trick though believe it or not
somewhere along the line my body
switched and one day is like 11 p.m. and
guess what I'm yawning my eyes are
feeling heavy I'm I'm feeling tired
these are things that don't normally
happen to me at night like I don't get
that tired feeling I just go to bed
because I know I didn't wake for a long
time I need sleep I actually felt tired
at nighttime and then I went to bed I
woke up early and I I forced myself to
stick to this routine because I knew by
if I stayed up late I would wreck it so
for about a month I was a morning person
I had to go through quite the the nasty
experience you really need a routine
with your sleep schedule otherwise it's
the worst thing out ever it's worse in
staying up late two days in a row you
really need to wake up at the same time
every day or it's really really hard on
you but after about a month I think one
day I had to work late I lost track of
time doing some YouTube stuff and it
just wrecked everything I switched from
being a morning person back to a night
person and since then I haven't made any
effort to switch again I've just been
trying to not get too bad like I want to
stick it about the to 3:00 a.m. bedtime
earlier if I didn't do it but I don't
want to get any look later than that the
thing is I was a morning person for
about a month I didn't feel that great
like something was wrong with my stomach
that it was like always queasy feeling
and
I don't know just I've accepted now I'm
a nighttime person I don't really want
to change it I just have to try not to
get too bad with it and I'm happy with
that I'm feeling a lot better now that
I'm out of that crazy sleeping schedule
experiments and I do not recommend it
unless you guys have ever tried
something like that you probably can't
quite comprehend just how important
sleep is and how out of whack it you
make you feel if you don't get enough of
it or at the right times yeah it's not
not not a good experience stick to a
healthy routine I recommend it even if
your night person and you don't like it
aha all right everybody so it's been
about five or six hours of non-stop
building here I was on a roll and I'm
very proud to say that the gold firm is
still incomplete but it is basically
done now I just did not do the bottom
part of it I would like to clean that up
a bit more and we we need like an
elevator to get up to it or something
well we don't need to I have learned how
to fly with the lighter wings which I'll
be doing more of as soon as I get a
mending book but yeah anyways let's go
check it out it does have that one
problem it has that shape that we were
trying to avoid but there's really no
way around it but thankfully it's only
really apparent from this angle so yeah
let's just pretend it's not an issue and
go inside okay so you go you walk inside
here we've got some nice windows you get
a good view of the surrounding area and
check out the sandy city over there
looks pretty cool most of the stuff I've
built in this world or is underground
though I gotta admit got our elevator
here I guess we should try it out and
make sure it still works
all right good all right pushes up us up
here there's another portal this is
supposed to take us to the top of the
nether and we might want to try that out
actually what do these buttons do oh I
bet you I totally forgot like you can
control the portal from down below I
guess you can do it from above to maybe
not that button no I don't think you
can't actually I don't remember making
any way making the wire go down does
this take us to the top of the nether it
does not that is terrible oh oh oh I bet
you the portals broken I'm gonna have to
investigate that
hmm anyways let's ignore that fat for
right now this might have been all for
nothing
inside here this is the main room now
tada
so the zombie pigmen come through the
portal here there is a there it is so
when I press that button it lights that
portal it also lights the one at the top
there if I press this one
it breaks it and the one at the top
that's what the slime block stuff is all
about on the sides there it's like
vertical redstone and anyways so we got
a bedroom very small bedroom I guess an
enchanting room on the other side with
stuff we need this chest has to be moved
yet this is where I've been holding the
building materials for now and we got
our cleric villager I think it's safe to
order this now pretty sure everything is
lit up so nothing will spawn this guy's
really good though he's got 36 that's
the best trade you can get he's got 4
redstone that's the best trade you can
get for that I think 2 or 3 lapis is the
best oh but 3 glowstone is the best it
only has two unfortunately and all the
item filter stuff we have in this firm
used to be down below now I've moved it
up here which is kind of cool nice and
convenient so it's like gold bars gold
nuggets zombie flesh and then any other
random junk gets put in this chest we
got our crusher for killing the zombie
Pigman over here this is just like open
right now let's see I really want to
show you guys like the outside that's
that's kind of the cool part of it but
it's kind of tricky to fly around at the
moment
alright well I guess we'll hop up here
yeah that's like our Tower the elevator
over there and just kind of like some
random very very abstract build
that's the way I started it so I decided
just to carry on with that kind of theme
let's let's see where can we get some
altitude maybe if we go to the top here
fly around a little bit and get a view
of it from some angles that's a bad
angle whoa I'm falling down I tell you
what I'm going to go to the top of that
that elevator there and then we can get
a good view of it all right so we're
going to try fly down here and get a
view from a few different angles and
hopefully we don't sink too quickly it's
kind of hard to really look at this
thing for a long time I guess I can
swoop up here and it'll buy us a bit
more time I think this is what I would
call the front this angle here and we're
pretty much yeah we got to land okay
let's go inside I think I'm going to
keep that open so I can fly into here
once I get my bunch bow and let me show
you I don't think I did show you behind
the chest so I'm the item filter was
down below now it's back here and I
think this is gonna work out pretty good
I tried to cram it in here and as little
space as possible we even got a window
back here haha all right
yeah there's item filter stuff and
actually wait a second I was supposed to
this last one isn't actually supposed to
be an item filter so I should probably
break this down I think of it alright
everybody well it's that time again to
wrap up the episode for today let me
know what you guys think about this
build also I tried out the portals they
do work they do line up properly except
the zombie pigmen going through the
portals seems to cause a lot of lag in
1.9 I'm not sure I'd have to test it a
bit more but it might be an issue but
yeah anyways also I got one more problem
let's hop down here and I'll just show
you so what you know and I said the
zombie pigmen farms not quite completes
its because
very slowly very dramatically we're
gonna look up and the trees in the way
so we're going to move forward a little
bit more and then with the right amount
of delay we're going to look up and see
the bottom yeah so I do want to add some
more details to the bottom I just kind
of ran out of time for today maybe an
elevator to get up there and let me let
me know what you guys think should I
keep it floating or should we have like
a pillar support system going to the
ground to make it look like it's
actually being held up that floating
bridge doesn't look the best I got to
say doesn't match the style and it's
also not supported so I'm not sure what
to do about that but yeah anyways I do
like how the how the new gold firms
looking happy with the build so far and
let's do the comment of the day it says
ESO what do you think people should
prior prioritize in a new world such as
XP farms block firms etc and in what
order alright I would say make a very
simple potato farm to begin with then
look for like a skeleton spawner and
make a farm out of that seat get some
bones and that kind of stuff some basic
XP then make a cow farm then make a
villager breeder I would say and then an
iron farm which farm maybe interment
farm and zombie pigman farm in that
order I don't know do whatever
whatever's convenient to you but I kind
of recommend that order if you're going
for efficiency ah but yeah anyways hope
you enjoyed today's episode leave me
your feedback and next episode is going
to be the world tour so should be able
to get that one out pretty soon those
are usually a lot easier to do than
having to build things so until next
time take care thanks for watching bye
bye
you