[Music]
hey hey
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back to another episode of
our let's play
series so guys to get us going here
today
we are gonna be working on this mushroom
farm some more we're gonna try to get it
done today
uh to start off with hopefully doesn't
take too long
we did work out most of the design
before like we got the the double
extender thing
figured out here that's to push the
mushroom stock out of the hole so we can
harvest it easy
and also uh got tipped off on a cool
trick that apparently azuma did recently
in one of his mushroom farms so we're
going to grow the mushrooms on
podzol here so the special thing about
podzol
is like if you try to grow a mushroom on
grass
out in the open broad daylights does not
work
because there's too much sunlight so you
got to build like a sun shield which is
what we were doing over here
to block out some of the lighting so you
can actually plant down
the mushroom if you do it on mycelium
though it does allow you to grow it
in broad daylight or in the open sun
so you can actually plant it there and
then grow it
if you have enough space you need a 7x7
area to grow a big mushroom
uh-huh and try again
there we go that time it works so you
can do that the problem is
after a while that mycelium is going to
die because there's a block over top of
it the mushroom stem
so this is going to turn back to regular
dirt after a little bit of time here
uh cool thing about bodzill is it works
just like mycelium except it doesn't die
so you can plant the mushroom on it and
grow it
this is gonna stay as possible though
this you can see it just turned back to
dirt
it died uh-huh so we're gonna
we're gonna use podzol in our farm why
can't i sprint
oh i am sprinting i just feel slow
because i don't have the speed beacon
get so used to it and then when it's
gone it's it's weird
uh-huh okay so what we're gonna do is
put
four mushrooms diagonal of the middle
one here the one we're actually
to turn into the big mushroom hopefully
it'll be able to spread to this block
the bodzill block fairly quickly that
way we might not even need to replant
the mushrooms there's a spread and
then we just grow it with the bone meal
in the dispenser here
that's another thing we got to work out
is how we're going to get bone meal into
these dispensers
i figure probably the easiest
way of doing this is to set up three
hoppers on each of these farms
because there's going to be more than
just one one mushroom there's gonna be
like 30 or 40
in the whole farm uh but yeah set up
three of these
put down some packed ice for a water
stream
uh make sure this is blocked off get
down some water
and then just like with a dropper or
something shoot bone meal
into the water stream if there's space
for it to go in here it'll refill the
dispenser
uh otherwise if it's full it'll make its
way down to the next mushroom
if that's full goes the next one next
one all the way down the line until
they're all refilled and this is this
works out good too because this is the
level we need to stand
to chop down the mushrooms like right
over here so it'll be a block above the
water stream
like so and then we run across with our
axe
and chop down all the mushrooms
but uh anyways i'm gonna do most of this
off camera guys because we gotta copy
this design like 30 or 40 times
it's going to take a bit of time to do
that
i am going to maybe run a test before we
get started
um can can mushrooms actually spread on
podzol
i almost think we will need that sun
shield still
we're gonna we're gonna run a little
test here so i'm gonna put down maybe
brown mushroom here brown mushroom here
we'll see if it spreads at all
or if it needs darkness to spread
yeah we'll come back to that later but
i'm gonna get to building
oh okay guys so it's been a couple hours
here i've been building away like a
madman and it's it's going
pretty good just about got it all done
but i thought i'd give you an update
before we totally finish it up
so in total there are 29
mushrooms that we're making here
so it goes around place it starts over
there goes all the way around this
this pumpkin farm we built all the way
over to this side
and got most of the systems all
built in place there's actually quite a
bit to this i've
i've been discovering like each each
little function adds a lot to it
um oh yeah and by the way this did
spread so after
two three hours or so it only spread
once
this mushroom grew to over here which
surprised me i didn't it was gonna do
that but
man that is not very fast at all i think
i'm thinking if i was to guess the
darkness actually does affect the spread
rate
um because this one over here i've also
been testing it it seems to spread every
maybe 20 minutes or so it's not great
either but it does happen
a lot faster than that's been working
anyways
so let's take a look at what we got here
um
got our controls for the two pistons up
there let's hit some repeaters over here
this is our main wire
for controlling uh pushing the
the mushroom stocks out of the hole and
on the other side there's another wire
as well for controlling the the bone
meal and this
the dispenser that just runs underneath
the ice
path here all the way down and right now
i'm working on a way of picking up the
mushroom drops after we chop down the
mushrooms we want to
we want to collect them all together
automatically right so
i'm thinking we'll do something like
this
have the minecart bounce from one to the
next to the next
uh this will be a hopper minecart and
that will run
underneath this podzole block here so if
any mushroom blocks are on top of this
this puzzle block it'll pick it up
through the the block
as it passes underneath here is my plan
um so should be fairly simple to do just
gotta run
a rail line over to here at the junction
we need a
detector rail and as long as the
minecart's not moving
super fast this should work it might
need a little bit of tweaking
but yeah this as it passes over this
it'll flip this junction to go this way
and then when it comes back it'll be
going that way
all right guys cool so we're just
testing out the rail line here seems
like it's going to make it all the way
uh so we got everything done down below
here all the redstone all the
rail line stuff should be good passes
underneath the bottle block for
for each of the mushrooms so when we
wash it drops
uh towards that puzzle block it's gonna
it's gonna pick them up
and every mushroom we chop down is going
to give us about a stack of mushroom
blocks
a hopper minecart can only hold five
stacks though so that means we probably
need to send
like six hopper minecarts to pick up the
drops from the whole farm
um is the plan but yeah we're gonna
start sealing this up and then we gotta
work on the water stream and then we're
we're like done with this
and some of the control things too and
and this and that and a whole bunch of
other things this is taking quite a bit
of time there's a lot to this actually
so this is what it's going to look like
when it's all sealed up there'll be
mushroom stock right here and here so
it's just going to be a one by one hole
and all these uh spreading mushrooms
will be protected
they're not going to get washed away or
anything uh so yeah basically
just gotta start filling this back in
all around here because we only want
these mushrooms to be able to spread to
this middle block we don't want them
spreading anywhere else we gotta be
careful
like if we left this this spot open here
they would spread to that we got to make
sure that's all sealed up
okay although
no ev they won't spread to the piston
here because the mushroom stock will be
here
yeah cause they can spread to things
besides dirt i think they can spread the
stone in all kinds of blocks so
definitely got to make sure this is
sealed up well
hey there little guy uh i thought slimes
couldn't swim in water anymore i thought
they sink when they go in the water
no or is it just the big guys
oh man now i need to investigate
i'm not crazy right like they weren't
able to swim for a long time
and now they can again i don't know if
it's this snapshot that changed it
or if it happened a while ago but yeah
they can swim again look at that
anyways got a little sidetracked this
game is weird like that though like
you'll see something and it's like
did i did i get the facts wrong on that
has it changed when did it change
because like they could swim and then
they couldn't swim and now they can swim
again
and now i'm wondering like was there
ever a point where they actually
couldn't swim
or am i making that up uh
okay so it looks like we've converted
most of our bones here
don't you just love looking through
chests what we got to do now is fill up
those dispensers with bone meal
and then we should hopefully be able to
try out that mushroom farm it's just
about done
is a huge project though let's see
what we really need to do sometime is
build an elevator
like in this village because there's no
there's no good way of getting up to the
surface from here
so usually what i do now is like i just
do this
now that we can fly it's the best way of
getting out
okay cool so we got the ground refilled
in
at the mushroom farm here so basically i
chopped out all the dirt then i built
the redstone components
and then i refilled in the dirts maybe
not the best way of doing it but it sure
made the redstone part of this a lot
easier
um decide to use coarse dirt for the
ground here because it's
it's probably going to look better than
this green grass right
hopefully could probably make this look
a lot better if i tried
it's just one type of block i could mix
mix other things in with it
but honestly at this point i just kind
of wanted to get this done
because i've been working on it for so
long um
tried orange clay decided orange
sandstone looks better because it has
more texture
and maybe not the best block choice
either but we will roll with it
left a little bit of a crawl space down
here too so we can actually
check out the redstone and the rail line
stuff if we need to
down the road and now i've got the water
streams in
so i'm going to start filling up the
dispensers with bone meal
the easiest way to do that initially
here is just to throw in stacks and
stacks
of bone meal they'll go where they need
to go
aha this might bring back memories to
some of you some of you maybe not
i thought we would check out the
stronghold base for any bones though
because we're
we're using a lot of them up mr snowman
got free
he's just cruising around owning the
place
uh yeah let's check down below here go
through our storage because we used to
keep a lot of stuff around
here and i haven't really looked at it
in a long time
some of these i think i did empty though
oh no the saddles are still here
sandstone okay
uh some zombie flash
everybody always wonders what this
purple and black block is
i'm not gonna show you no i will it's uh
wooden slabs
the ones that don't burn uh oh we still
got some
tools quite a few tools around here
cool uh yeah some oh
i might want to bring that with me
actually
okay i do come here every time i go to
the end but i don't go through the
chests
uh usually let's see oh look there we go
that's what i was hoping for
cool we'll nab those and uh start
throwing them in our dispensers
what else do we have here though end
stone
just gonna point it out i did see the
bones in this chest by the way
i didn't say anything but if i don't say
something now if someone's gonna be like
ethos blind he looked right at the bones
and didn't notice them
what's wrong with etho
so this over here i think this was our
old bulk storage
so much cobblestone never throw
anything away i wonder if we kept any
bones in here
not looking like it's nope nope that's
it
okay
oh
whoa
okay this elevator is not working so
good anymore
i think pistons change every single
update right
like they said they they're not going to
change anymore
i think they still are though
oh well good thing we got fireworks
okay all right yeah that's that's not
bad right
that's kind of what i was hoping for the
orange sandstone gives the whole farm
area here
like a border it highlights it i think
that looks pretty good actually
maybe not from the ground level but from
a distance
it's it's pretty good actually ran out
of red sandstone though so that we're
like
less than a stack short of it probably
either gonna have to farm some more of
it or
set up a meta value changer to to create
it's from sand
um but yeah let's go ahead and get this
baby running so
it's filled up with bone meal now let's
grab some redstone
huh
oh wait a second no
i hate when you do that when you search
for a mob and then you just end up
making a big hole you can't find them
because i'm gonna have to fill this back
in now no i still can't find it
this way there you are
okay oh hey
is there a tape here oh
let's get let's let him blow up if we
can
just don't blow me up now okay
yeah there is there's a bit of a cave
here
oh wow okay
let's check this out real quick uh
yeah it keeps going here okay well we'll
just light up the top part here
and cover it up so for the redstone here
i think we've got to get this repeater
at four
and just set up a monostable circuit
here so basically if you
run a wire to that this should be good
that'll activate the
mushroom stock pusher mechanism and then
for the bone meal thing we want to run a
clock
uh while a lever is flipped probably so
this we will turn
or we will set up how let's put a
repeater here one two
three blocks from a comparator just do a
comparator clock
flip that and this has to run back
like i saw and that should be good and
then just put a repeater behind that's
good so if we run a signal to that then
it's going to grow the mushrooms
okay let's run this up here so we can
see it happening now some people
suggested like you can
you can set this up so the mushrooms
grow automatically
i think it's actually going to be pretty
cool here if we
control when it happens because we're
going to see them all grow at once
which is something i can't say i've ever
seen before in minecraft it's going to
be pretty cool i think
so let's let's try this out so we got
nothing right now and then there should
just be
a whole bunch of blocks all of a sudden
okay here we go
yep yep oh oh i didn't put the covering
over that
no i was supposed to put string above
the mushrooms so
they don't grow all the way
okay a little bit of a derp up there
uh but this is okay where we had the sun
shield
alright and then after we grow them we
want to trigger this
uh should just need a button push let's
see
stone i need stone oh we need
oh they're still finding their way up
here aren't they
um okay i might have to explore that off
camera
light it all up okay
yeah let's just put down a button over
here that'll push the mushroom
stocks out of the hole
all right or i guess the first time we
use it it's going to put them over there
so now we got this we all we got this
all done we just have to run down here
like so the only thing we're missing
right now
a couple things actually we're missing
the water stream stuff and we're missing
uh some of the minecart control stuff
like the minecart's not running
but yeah that's pretty good right then
on this side you do it as well
oh oh yes we ran out of sandstone there
okay so let's take a look at this how
did that do it looks like a couple
blocks did actually land on the
sandstone here and we didn't pick them
up as we
as we did this i was afraid of that i
was hoping that wouldn't happen
um maybe if we like instead of like
going straight across if we kind of
go at an angle like this as we go it
would be better
looks like we messed up the timing here
too there's there's still a mushroom
block here it should be underneath this
one
oh well uh what what did we do then i
thought i had this right
this is a five yet so it's supposed to
be
let's try change this to three
maybe i don't know
um i guess we're not gonna know until we
do another one
why is there a redstone torch here
that's really bad
why how
oh um
we might have disturbed up the whole
farm
yeah it broke the torch on every second
one here it looks like
oh that stinks okay uh gonna need to do
a little bit of maintenance and maybe a
little bit more testing
we did test this though i don't know
what i got wrong on it
like before we built the whole thing
here
okay guys well i tried really hard to
get this all done today
but there's still a little bit left to
do on it so i think
because i've been recording this over
several days by now
we should probably just split it into
another episode
uh it's close to done but there's
probably at least another two hours
left to work on it so i'll just show you
real quick here what i
intend to do to make the water streams
work so in the middle between two
mushrooms
uh let's see one two three four five six
blocks between them i'm hoping we can
just like put an ice block here ice
block here and then
let's see i got morning voice right now
too by the way
not depressed congested big difference
okay uh i think we would want it over
here yeah so hopefully with these four
water blocks
it'll be able to wash the mushroom
blocks into that hole
that gets left behind by the stem over
here
uh let's test out the water stream here
looks good
so hopefully anywhere the the mushroom
block lands it'll go there
and then that's where the hopper
minecart runs underneath it underneath
the puzzle block so it should be able to
pick up any drops
from there that is the plan i think
it'll work out pretty good but we got to
run some redstone to control the water
as well so there is a fair bit left to
do
there is one more thing we're going to
try out here together guys we're going
to make ourselves a
meta value changer which is a little bit
of a gray
area as far as cheating goes but i'm
okay with it personally i'm okay with uh
meta value changers
what i don't do in my world here is uh
block duplication
there's a lot of ways to like duplicate
rails or
or concrete there's a way of doing that
even i think sand and
some other stuff like that i've never
taken advantage of that
but this is just for like aesthetics
right
doesn't bother me and because
i have changed my world to amplified
there's actually
very little almost no red sand in my
world because it only generates in flat
areas
and because the terrain's amplified
there is almost no flat areas
so i have to really destroy the look of
the mesa to get it
that's my justification let's see if
this still works i'm just copying the
one that doc showed me
when we made that connect4 game uh let's
see i think
i think this is about right
sort of going off of memory here uh i
think i think he had redstone here
and then he made it come up to here to
the
monostable circuit i think so this has
to
come up somehow uh let's do it over
here yeah right here
sure okay that should work out so we run
the redstone up to the
the piston and hopefully i got this
right i'm not sure if i did
we'll test it out so how does it work
again i think
i might have got the sides wrong here
too oops put that there so if we
press the button works perfect
uh what did i do wrong here okay simple
thing easy thing
these repeaters were just facing the
wrong way i put them down reversed
whoops that's how you don't do redstone
in videos guys
uh-huh okay so yeah on this side we put
the white
and the orange this side the orange and
the whites
alright so this is not actually creating
blocks it is changing blocks
so white sand becomes orange sand
like so then when it hits this button
here it breaks it
so i might set up a big machine to do
this for us
that way we can actually build with
orange sand and orange sandstone and not
feel bad about it
anyways i think we're gonna wrap up here
for today guys so here is the comment i
picked out it's a
it's a pretty interesting one actually
it says etho
would you ever consider remaking the
base from your old world
in your new world new and improved
i've been thinking about maybe starting
a new base for the last few months here
okay um like what we have in the man
cave here is really cool
it's uh it's more of a sprawling
aesthetically
pleasing sort of base right or at least
i hope it is
but it's more for the organic look of
things
i've been thinking about making an
ultimate base sort of
same concept of chocolate island back in
the day
where you have a central mob system
central storage room
and a whole bunch of high-tech functions
uh built into the base
that's possibly what we're gonna do in
the future here i've been planning
things out
uh if we do it i want the pixel here to
be the center
of our storage room still working on
this concept a little bit though
like every good base needs a good mob
system and a good storage room
this is like going to be the ultimate
storage room if i can figure it out
and just been figuring out a few other
high-tech things that we could do
i'll show you one of them next episode
um didn't have time to get into it today
but if uh if we do build an ultimate
base it's one of the things we're going
to include into it
alright so a little teaser for next time
hopefully you guys enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching
and until next time take care bye
you