[Music]
hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and we are back again guys today
with another episode of the let's play
series I know you guys are like wowie so
really another let's play episode
already like stop spamming my
subscription feed there's so many listed
there it's too much take a break but you
know I can't I have to post another one
if only right if only now I kind of went
through a little bit of burnout I'm not
gonna lie one of the problems is like if
I go through burnouts I didn't have
enough projects going on guys not enough
new projects believe it or not yeah if I
go through a little bit of burnout in
the let's play here there's nothing to
pull me back really like if I ask myself
the question what's something I haven't
done in vanilla minecraft before there's
no answer really
I've done it all I've explored the
content many times over so in order to
like entertain myself in this series and
to entertain you guys I really have to
be creative and think of think of fun
things to do and sometimes that
creativity just isn't there I use it all
up and I gotta take a break and then
hopefully get some new ideas I'm not
gonna lie I don't have a lot of ideas
for this episode in fact I'm pretty much
on empty still but you know what if I
don't spend any time in this world I'm
not gonna think of anything so my plan
for today is I'm gonna keep it simple
now we're just gonna it's gonna go
around the world here a little bit and
look for anything interesting that we
might be able to do smaller projects
today I think that's gonna be the goal
but I think another big problem with
this series here is I don't do enough of
like the the Minecraft stuff anymore
like when was the last time you saw me
chop down a tree or collect resources
and stuff I don't do a lot of that on
camera and that makes
filler might might not be the most
entertaining of Schiller but you know
just a little bit in the episode I think
makes it feel more like a Minecraft
video instead of look at what I'm trying
to show you you know so I guess maybe to
begin with here I had somebody requests
that I do a really smooth transition in
the next episode next episode really
smooth transition in the next episode
next episode really smooth transition in
this episode which episode next episode
this episode and next episode
Oh last episode which episode next
episode yeah I think they meant this
episode but it doesn't matter guys we
don't have time for that foolishness
today because we're gonna get right into
the projects here that's right
transitions come on who's got time for
that really we're gonna what do we do
guys only don't know what we're doing
how do you figure out what to do in
Minecraft that's that's the key I think
a lot of people struggle with this when
they play the game for a long time
especially if you're lacking creativity
usually usually you identify something
you need or want in the game like maybe
resources or maybe you want something to
look nicer and then you work at making
that happen or you see something and you
ask you ask questions like what's the
best way of doing that right so that's
kind of my plan right now we got this
big lake and there's a bunch of rivers
and stuff that runs through our world
here and we never use the water here to
get around the world why is it guys is
it because we have Elijah wings because
we got mine carts and horses and so many
other better forms of transportation no
guys it's because we don't have any
boats where are the boats how are we
gonna get into this water hmm
yeah it's a good question isn't it
meanwhile while you guys are over there
rubbing your your beards or your smooth
faces and you're scratching your heads I
think I've come up with
the answer to our question how are we
gonna get boats into the water it's a
revolutionary idea are you ready for
this boat dispenser that's right so I
have realized there are boats in the
game there are dispensers in the game
what if we combine the two together oh
man I can't believe I was the first one
to think of this I'm leaving leaning a
little bit heavy on the crazy side today
guys
hopefully for entertainment or else
you're just cringing right now if you if
you know the old videos though there's
actually a very deep joke in all of this
trust me but yeah I think that's
actually an interesting question like if
we were to build a boat dispenser
nowadays how would we do it I don't know
exactly so we're gonna try figure it out
here
and then we'll build a few around our
worlds so that we can never use them now
we might we might you never know never
know we definitely won't if we don't
have them right okay part part of
Minecraft though is just making projects
when you don't need to that's that's a
big part of the game too it's more about
the journey and the result than an
actual purpose I find okay one question
I have I think I think I recall you
might not be able to grab moving boats
so we should test that get a couple
boats here for testing okay so if that's
on top there oh I missed it I wanna see
if I can grab it while it's in midair do
we yeah we kind of just sunk right away
where else is really glitchy or
something I don't know what happens Oh
try again
you see that like we kind of we kind of
just stopped me there and when we get
out it like tries to fly still okay so
in our design it can't be moving when we
hop in I think that's the key there were
and we're in for a world of hurt okay
second thing we got to consider here is
how are we gonna actually dispense the
boats there was a time in Minecraft
where if you shot a boat of a dispenser
it would place it's like always always
always now there's a rule you have to
have some water for it to go in I'm
pretty sure I don't there's any way
around that or at least I've never found
a way around it and I think the rule is
has to either be like right in front of
the dispenser
then it'll place it I think it can be
one block below then it places it yep
I don't think it can be blue blocks
below but let's just double check oh I
went down a little too far there uh-huh
this is how you design stuff first you
figure out the mechanics and it's empty
okay oh yeah
so that's too low what about if it's one
above I've ever tried that before
umm okay so it looks like it doesn't
really matter I thought we might end up
doing something like this but remember
in our previous test where we just had
the water below here it looks like it
needs an air block like right here where
the sign is because now it doesn't it
doesn't dispense it it just shoots item
out if that sign is gone though then it
can place it so if we need an air block
and water and I think it'll work with
flowing water too so yeah now it'll
place it's let's do one more test here
just so we know the full range of things
what if the water is only a water stream
yeah okay so water streams work too
what about water log blocks okay so that
that's water logged right now what if
the slab is on the top part
oh we tricked it
okay that's kind of cool so you can even
hide the water yeah so this is gonna be
very simple I think there's not gonna be
a lot to this I think the idea we're
gonna go with is have the dispenser
facing up have our water and then we'll
hide the water with a slab like that I
think that's gonna be like the the
smoothest way of doing it the boat will
be here and then to like get launched I
want to have some launching mechanic
like you there's slime launchers or the
water columns I want it to trigger right
when we hop in the boat so I think the
way to do that let's we'll probably just
have like a slime block launcher here
maybe like right in the corner and when
we hop in we have to trigger a pressure
plate or something like that I think is
probably the easiest way of doing this
do you think this is gonna work so I put
the pressure plate above the dispenser
with the boats in the idea is we'll have
a boat here all the times and when we
hop in we want to get launched by the
slime block launcher here so the
observer detects when this dispenser
gets activated and and launches us what
do you think you think it's gonna work
oh it actually did wait a second now
I've tried a few times because I don't
think it did the first time and the idea
is we want another boat to be placed
behind us too like all in one thing so
we want to get launched and we want a
new boat to be there so this time I'm
gonna actually hold forward because I
didn't there oh yeah kind of glitchy so
we got a new boat there though yeah
using slime block launchers probably
isn't the best of ideas I think it's the
client-server desync issue where the
game doesn't know what it's doing even
though it should I did get it to launch
a few times but it's very unreliable
otherwise it would be a pretty nice
dispenser I think they didn't gather to
launch once yet
come on there we go just have to
complain about it that's the trick
mm-hmm
so I kind of realized that we're not
gonna be able to get this to work
there's a long-standing issue with the
slime blocks like when you use them with
boats most of the time they just push
you one block both vertically and
sideways they're kind of glitched out
the odd time you will get launched the
bounce effect actually works from the
slime blocks but it's very inconsistent
and I don't think there's any way to
make it consistent so rather than
launching the boat like I wanted to
we're just gonna launch ourselves like
so that's the best that's the best
compromise I could come up with that's
the closest thing I could get to like
what I wanted aha so I think that I'll
have to do but look at this we can ride
ride the water now that's awesome so
while working on that I got to thinking
hey maybe let's add some trees along the
water here so let's do that I'm gonna go
for a t-shirt I normally I like to use
oak trees but let's change it up a bit
but I want to add can we change the bark
though cuz I don't like that Bart yeah
maybe let's just leave those two logs
there so the leaves don't be spawn and
then we'll try growing another one a
little bit different maybe raise it up
so we get some more layers is that gonna
work oh it does work look at that oh now
we got a super acacia tree uh-huh is
that a good idea is that gonna make it
look funny I kind of like it I I wish it
was like leaves on that layer than one
one block higher that layer then one
block higher you know it's like totally
flat right now you know what I think we
might actually have something here call
me crazy or don't please don't but I
don't think they look that bad actually
so these are like quick easy custom
trees basically each one is two acacia
trees merged together and then I
replaced the
bark and then bulk up the bottom and
that's about it
so I like this one the most look at this
this one turned out very good or I think
at least that's pretty cool it's a
little bit of a light game though like
trying to get trying to get to get it to
shape the way you want so usually the
first one I grow a little bit off the
ground like that and let's go for some
bone meal BAM ok so it's not a not a
great start I like it when it splits
into two at the at the very start but we
didn't mean try make this work so this
is a pretty straight up if it's lopsided
then you usually want to go on the
opposite sides it's kind of Leaning a
little bit that way so I'm gonna go just
a couple blocks over here not quite as
high this time actually let's go let's
go about it like here ideally we don't
want the leaves to merge we want the
layers the layers are what makes it look
good so hopefully they don't merge
together here okay so you merge at the
top darn I saw this it's like okay we
got something No so I would chop this
down to try again
round two so ideally we're trying to get
like three layers of leaves and then
that looks pretty good if you can make
that happen so again we're gonna go
three blocks off the ground to start
with seems to be a good height although
a little bit of a short tree we got two
layers though that's something if we get
another dual this might be a four layer
tree though
but it's probably gonna merge somewhere
so it's I feel like we want it like over
here I'm gonna go two blocks up again
it's all random the how tall the tree is
gonna be I have no idea
Oh even corrupted our other tree there
uh see I wanted that like a little bit
lower and it would have been great okay
that's a very boring starts let's go for
over here oh I think we got layers we
got layers guys look at that okay so we
got two big ones let's try a small one
over here that's not a tree
that's the grass okay let's try again oh
okay we can work with this maybe I kind
of wish this wasn't so big over here
maybe we do some trimming it's like
bringing it in one you know like we're
allowed to customise it a little bit
right uh-huh
shave it in a bit so it's not quite as
big okay yeah I think I think we can
make this into a tree this is good so
then what I would do you chop down all
these Keysha blocks and then you just
sort of draw branches towards like
imaginary thing in the middle so pretty
much when you get three leaf piles that
look pretty good together then you just
play connect the dots chop down the
acacia logs and then try connect the
wood together in like a central place
maybe we'll do something like this so
you kind of have to build the custom
treats widths or extent but placing the
leaves is like the part that takes the
longest normally when you're making
trees get rid of that yeah okay put this
there you gotta be careful old leaves
don't despawn on you though try to be
really careful here okay do something
like that that can come back then let's
bring this over towards the central
stock and everything should look pretty
good right let's chop down the rest of
this and I think we got a tree here not
too bad right I think that turned out
pretty well actually looks good from
other angles so the final thing I would
do is try to bulk up the bottom if he
can this one's a little hard cuz the
branches are so little whatever you can
do will make it look better yeah yeah my
big enough no no
sure let's actually bring this over oh
yeah you got to be a little bit finicky
with it basically it's that too far out
baby huh it'll work okay
I'm happy with that let's move on oh
wait a minute wait a minute I just
remembered something you guys are you
guys are probably freaking out right now
uh yeah we can't we can do this now
can't we a little bit late a little bit
late but let's do the lower stuff at
least the stuff we didn't see like down
to the ground it'll make a big
difference yeah so basically now you can
make trees where you don't see the
exposed sides which is pretty nice I
like that a lot all right so I just did
some bone meal around here as well I
think that makes it look a little bit
better Park Bench guys we can go for the
thick chunky one here it's one option
uh-huh we're getting an advance now are
you ready for this go for the wide bench
not like that like that
okay wide bench is better definitely
better or another option is go for the
skinny bench that doesn't look too bad
either actually we're gonna go with the
skinny bench all right so I just next up
here we're gonna do some passing mostly
off camera but I do like the view from
up here like this is not a place I
usually go it's kind of cool like we've
got a good view of the buildings
windmill River
trees and lake and me and all that kind
of stuff so I think I'll just show you
the path plan so we're gonna go like up
the hill here we'll wind around go
straight through here and then I think
I'm gonna dig a hole through the hill
and it's gonna come out somewhere around
here probably around here somewhere and
then the path is gonna wind around to
the door here and you know what today is
a simple episode maybe while I do this
we'll do a storytime with a though I
noticed a lot of you have asked in the
comments what my sleep schedule has been
like cuz I did mention this a while ago
I had some trouble regulating my sleep
going to bed on time and it was bad it
was bad to the point where I like was
really struggling to function in society
like waking up in the middle of the day
you know and people want to do things
and I'm tired stores are closing it when
I'm waking up and you know it's it's not
a good routine to have right basically
the way this all started I've always had
I've always been a bit of a night owl
but especially as a few years ago I had
to take someone to the airports at like
4:00 a.m. and by the time I got home
from that it was like 7:00 a.m. or
something so I I had this bright idea
why don't I stay up all night it's it's
like morning already you know I thought
it would be a fun idea you know I didn't
I hadn't done that in a long time I used
to love doing that when I was a kid
staying up all night cramming to get my
homework done you know so okay I did it
and then I got in says bad routine for a
while of like not waking up at a good
time but you know I I didn't think much
of it but then after a while I realized
that I got a bit of a problem I can't
actually I don't actually get tired
properly anymore like I my issue is I
feel like I don't get tired until like
twenty five hours have gone by instead
of like a day of 24 hours so every day I
want to stay up like an hour later but
after that event I
had another problem where I don't
actually feel tired I get the symptoms
of being tired like my eyes get dry I
get headaches and I'm up really long
then like my stomach starts shutting
down and I get cold and you know that
kind of stuff I think maybe the best way
of explaining it is like you know how
some people will fall asleep on the
couch when they're watching TV or
whatever that'll never happen to me like
I'll never doze off from staying up late
unless I'm up for about 18 hours or so
then in the morning usually is when I'll
start feeling tired and then I didn't go
to sleep very easily that'll last for
about four hours and then I'll be wide
awake again if I don't go to bed it's
kind of weird so I was on a bad routine
for a while last year I had something
else happened that was kind of weird I
suffered from insomnia for the first
time in my life which is where no matter
how hard you try to go to sleep when you
need to like you can be up for days and
be so tired like your body will be
shutting down and you still can't fall
asleep I experienced that last year for
about a week and that was pretty crummy
during the summer a bad combination of
my sleeping routine and it being
extremely hot out I just couldn't sleep
for about a week it was too hot and my
routine sucked so I would like go to bed
and lay there for hours and not be able
to fall asleep and I just got feeling so
crummy but eventually it cooled down and
I was able to sleep again
and then after that I made a real effort
to like fix my schedule because that was
torture and I've been good ever since
then actually I I finally fixed my
schedule still don't get tired I have to
really watch a clock and make sure I go
to bed at a good time but for like the
last four months or so I've been getting
up it
a normal time like 9 a.m. going to bed
at about 1:00 a.m. and it's been good so
that's that's kind of where I'm at right
now hopefully I can stick to it but
anyways we got the pass done here guys
and it is amazing I could probably use
some more decorating but overall pretty
happy with it so I went for the
cobblestone gravel and andesite mix like
we've we've done over there and keep in
mind we're missing like probably future
developments we'll probably add more
buildings do more decorating in this
area it's still kind of on the the plain
side so there's not a lot to look at
right now but it's only gonna get better
right so we go down a mineshaft sort of
thing here it's bit steep a bit rocky
and it goes through the door but yeah I
like doing paths just because like
they're not really a big thing but they
make a big difference when you view the
world so like look at this now with the
trees and stuff you got a little bit
extra colour over there now a little bit
more to draw draw our eyes same width
over here this looks pretty nice I think
and you can spot that like opening from
a distance pretty easily that little
it's like oh what's over there you know
uh-huh
anyways just a little project I thought
it would be nice to do nice to do but
anyways guys I think we're gonna keep it
kind of short and sweet and simple today
hopefully hopefully get into a more
regular routine with this with the
series and with that in mind I thought
this would be a comet to mention it's
kind of a general general question I
think he means I haven't watched a video
in over a year
now and been watching since around
episode 100 and I miss a lot of the
older things he used to do and what
happened with the S&P servers so first
part of the first part of this thing
miss a lot of the older things we used
to do if there's anything you guys miss
about what I used to do in the older
videos let me know maybe maybe we can
bring them back I don't know exactly
what he's
furring - but yeah if there's if there's
something you want to see in the
episodes here let me know or if there's
a specific project you want me to work
on or some idea you have for me to work
on let me know as far as SMP servers go
there's a general rule that they will
peter out after like three to six months
I like I don't expect them to last
longer than that ever it's a little bit
different with like vanilla minecraft
servers like mine crack and hermit craft
but eventually those tend to peter out -
they just have a little bit of a longer
time span uh-huh and then usually people
need a break and then they they're ready
to go in a few more months after their
break when they get inspired again
modded and SMP servers though those
usually only last three to six months
and I bring this question up because a
lot of people who have wondered what
happened to full crafts that series has
ended I'll say it officially again it
kind of petered out
I had a later start on that than most
people and the slower release schedule
than most people and like I was just
like starting to get into it and then
everybody was done the the Minecraft
patch came out the new hermit craft
started up and people moved on to that
and I don't blame him for it it worked
out well for them and we kind of knew
that was gonna happen before we started
the server but we didn't know when the
patch was actually gonna come out
because Mojang don't officially announce
though that like Munson it advanced or
anything so yeah it just kind of petered
out and it doesn't make sense for me to
play on the server alone because it's
not my server and like the government
would have to continuously like take
care of things on the server and keep it
updated and all for me you know
meanwhile someone else is paying for the
server and it just wouldn't be a good
situation so I felt like I shouldn't
continue it anyways that's kind of
the deal with that hopefully you guys
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching as always have yourselves a
wonderful day take care bye bye
[Music]