[Music]
well hello everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys once again to another
let's play episode how're you doing
things are good here yes yes very good
still live it under the sea
remember last episode we built this mob
system right so the problem was we were
getting attacked
non-stop by the drown mobs and this has
worked out great you can actually do
some building and stuff now under the
water without having to stop every every
second to kill something so that's what
I've been doing I was just trying to do
some more building here not really
planning things out or anything just
just building kind of the von sway way
rights and we built like a window last
time and it's like okay let's put
another window on the other side maybe
something in the middle I was like what
could we put in the middle and I had the
idea of let's go not a cola right let's
build an anchor so this is my attempt at
an anchor hung on the wall very accurate
rights to scale no not really
okay I don't know then I experimented
with some different columns here yeah
all right so to get us started here I
had an idea for a challenge alright I
think this is gonna be pretty fun
because we're building underwater right
so we're gonna have all these fun
underwater challenges with designing the
base and stuff what I want to do of
course every base should have a tree
farm right you always need more wood and
stuff it's really annoying to go go get
it's how we're gonna build a tree firm
that works underwater that's the
challenge I noticed something I think we
can use here yes pistons okay so when
you use a piston underwater check this
out when it retract
for a moment there just a very brief
moment you get like an air pockets right
and I think we can use that watch a
piston head just a brief moment I think
there's an air pockets it takes a moment
for the water to refill it alright we're
gonna try to use that to make a tree
farm work underwater and that's the plan
so what I think we'll do or do I know
what I'm doing
I think we got to set up like a column
of Pistons rights kind of like this
let's not worry about positioning and
all that stuff just yet I'll probably
fix it alpha camera I think we'll have
like a row of Pistons like that and
we'll try to grow the tree like over
here right now in order to grow a tree
you don't actually need a place for the
leaves to go you just need a place for
the the trunk right yeah okay I have to
go get some stuff and I have to think
how we're actually gonna do this cuz
it's a bit tricky right we got to run
some redstone to all these pistons how
do we do that underwater that's that's
gonna be fun so I guess we're gonna put
the sapling here we'll have a dispenser
with bonemeal in right to grow it and
then we're gonna need like something to
keep the water back so I think these
can't be waterlogged right now the
pressure plates right then that'll go
there as long as there's a like a log
airspace dirt or leaf block above it
it'll be able to grow if has enough
space so I think if we go like this tall
should be fine we'll always leave a wood
block over here so that the water
doesn't pour down on the sapling and
destroy its right and then my plan here
I think we're gonna use redstone blocks
we run redstone blocks onto this with
slime blocks hopefully running over
there
and then probably like a sticky piston
up over here that we got to control oh
right over there right yeah so then we
can control the whole column if if this
retracts really hard to do want redstone
under water yeah these are tracks it'll
pull the slime blocks back and then
those all retract to right it'll create
a little bit of airspace and in that
moment we need to activate the dispenser
to grow the tree yeah okay so I think
all we really need to do now is just add
a clock on to this and we're we're gonna
be able to try it out I know how to do
the redstone I just don't know how to
place the redstone without it washing
away so that's let's try that so we
gotta get like a redstone torch here to
slow okay I got a hold shift while I do
this - nope nope got it right I think I
was quick enough it's extended yeah okay
so that's in there good I'm gonna go
ahead and just cover this up maybe let's
try this put that there put that there
I'm hoping if we get rid of what I guess
we got to swim into here actually okay
so what I want this is now gonna work is
it we got to put some repeaters here
this one's got to be set to at least - I
know redstone there hey the waters not
washing it away actually this is gonna
work
comparator here Oh actually wait a
second I'm not gonna be able to place
the hoppers so we need a hopper facing
well let's put this here you know hopper
facing that way and one where that sand
is facing the other way if I'm quick
enough I can do this without it wrecking
everything
all right let's let's break that and
then I don't think the water will flow
in
right yeah okay that's the trick let's
put this over here facing another hopper
and just put one item in it'll bounce
back and forth that activates the
comparator and we'll want to switch for
this so it doesn't run all the time
right
probably another important thing we'll
figure out how to do that later
oh I washed it away no and that is or
did I Oh two items got in oh okay it's
fine okay so is this gonna work I guess
we got that there so we got to get the
timing right okay so we got a little
problem here it doesn't seem to be
working I tried all the possible timing
combinations on the repeaters and the
tree just wouldn't grow I can't get
anything so I have a one last possible
idea here I think there's not actually
an air pockets like when the Pistons are
trapped it seems to create an air pocket
if just one or Trek's but when you have
a whole group of them doing it I don't
know it's like it doesn't it doesn't do
it anymore
I look at this like you see an air
pocket there air pocket there but not
like the whole column right I think that
might be the problem
so here's my plan a little bit of a
tricky thing we're gonna get rid of all
these regular Pistons and replace them
with sticky pistons and you might be
like Oh eat all that what's the what's
the difference that's not gonna do
anything right I think it's gonna trick
it because what we're gonna do these are
gonna be sticky pistons will move the
tree over one block and like Pistons
pretty much retract instantly right so
it's gonna retract and I'm hoping it's
gonna like try to grow the tree it's
gonna see the wood above here as gonna
be like oh I can grow through that no
problem so it's gonna say yes I can grow
and then in that moment hopefully
afterwards these will retract and then
the tree will grow I don't know if it's
gonna work I don't know how it goes down
in the game code right so I guess we'll
just have to try it and see so I'm gonna
move this over
hmm Oh a groove Hey it grew when the
logs were there's no that's special but
if we just got to be a little bit longer
than probably at least two ticks stead
of oatmeal oh man oh it works oh my
goodness it works it works oh snap
finally got it we're gonna run out of
oatmeal but we're gonna try to get one
more gross there we go look at that
oh-ho okay so the final settings let's
shut this thing off
final settings I had to play with the
timing a bunch here so I guess this is
at 4:00 from the comparator to there and
on this side I doubled up the redstone
torches so there was one here on this
log like this right and then there's
another one over here right there uh-huh
so it's not it's not a good tree farm
it's snow it's doesn't create any leaves
so you don't get any drops or anything
but it works underwater and that was the
challenge so there we go guys we got it
I was actually pretty worried there for
a moment I wasn't gonna get it get it
working but okay now so we want to add
some extra features to our little tree
from here now so gotten a chest here for
extra bone meal feed into the dispenser
there right
also we want to add an on/off switch to
it so I was thinking probably the way to
do that is to get like a sticky piston
here
with a redstone block if the redstone
block is under the hopper here it'll
lock it so that this will stop bouncing
back and forth and shuts off the clock
right and then we'll just add like maybe
a trapdoor here with a observer
underneath all right and then redstone
dust so when we flip it flips the piston
right flip it down shuts off on off very
good that's what we want let's go ahead
and fill this in without destroying the
redstone hopefully got to leave a space
there for that so maybe let's just let's
toss that will put sandstone there
sandstone is the trick here okay and
then that there good
should be good okay so that then over
here I added a piston to push the log
sideways so we don't have to break it
every time I grow a tree and we will
probably we got any more sand actually
well we got a full chest a bit actually
look at that okay let's put a piece of
sandstone here with the pressure plates
like we had before what I want to do you
saw we had a piece of redstone next to
this so that's gonna activate the piston
if we step on this but then we'll also
[Music]
hopefully have how do we do this I'm
mumbling a little bit it's fine it's all
good let's hold shift got to be quick I
don't know if I was quick enough well
that we can have a reserve it's extra
saplings in there too and then maybe a
trapdoor II so after we grow a tree we
step on that and we get a sapling every
time oh snap oh snap
okay we're gonna take a little break
from the underwater stuff for a second
here are you a new one no I've met you
before I think this is a thunderstorm
I've been waiting for a thunderstorm so
that we can whoa uh not do that no no no
I should maybe fight these guys she's
really fast for some reason get away
from the witches oh we got phantoms
let's get both of these okay out of the
way oh I got him I got him
yes okay I've been wanting to get oh
I've been wanting to get a creeper head
for so long you have no idea do I
that might have might have burnt it
actually I might have messed that up
whoa okay I killed that one and get a
creeper head okay I don't know how to
get a creeper heads I gotta go look at
this up real quick
okay it's been so long I completely
forgot how it works so we got a we got
to get a charge creeper and then have
them blow up next to a regular creeper
and then we'll get the creeper head I
think that's the plan here okay so he
converted if he pops one sec I don't
want to die either you know it's kind of
important to be all over the place here
can we do like a circle around and get
like all of these mobs at once that
would be pretty crazy but I'm gonna die
my health is way too low right now get
away get away leave me alone I want to
do a circle around if I'm at full health
I'll take the chance and just blow up
next to the creeper okay we're gonna go
for it we're gonna go for it it's
probably good it's gonna get
so let's get them all over here say
hello to you okay
respond quickly so none of my stuff gets
blown up hopefully uh we're gonna have
to go check that out
I'm gonna maybe sleep no I'll run over
I'll run over bad idea though oh it's
over there okay okay I can't remember
where I died for some reason oh snap
oh that's bad timing good let's get her
stuff I don't think I'm gonna be able
get my stuff thank you there's a bad
idea I should just read your door slept
or something did I get food can't check
I got food guys good pants on okay we
are somehow still alive okay let's go
back I'm worried it's gonna be spawn
quickly here let's get as much as we can
so I only found I got a zombie head in
my inventory but that's it I was kind of
hoping we'd get a whole bunch at once
there with the big explosion but I think
it only gives you one at a time I guess
good there's my bed I was looking for
that cute a couple new horses so I'm
gonna do a couple things here I want to
repair some of our old broken stuff here
this is the entrance to our Guardian
front go down there and before I had a
piston translocation elevator to get
back up but that's been removed from the
game for a couple updates now I haven't
fixed it yet I think in our world
there's two of those I haven't fixed
as waiting for a good compact easy
elevator and now that we got the bubble
streams probably just rip this out and
fill it up with water and and bubbles
right yeah there we go we got our way
back up nice and quick very simple so
I'm probably gonna put some doors to
keep the water in place here I guess I
should have done this first right I
think I'm gonna take that water out
there put a block here so I can stand
here I think we gotta be facing this way
to place the doors yeah there we go
so that'll hold all the water in place
let's break this put the water back
there we go very simple elevator okay
and the second elevator I wanted to fix
here is the one hidden behind the
waterfall you guys remember we started
building this when the lighter wings
first came out before you could launch
yourself with the firework fireworks to
get a speed burst right so this is as
far as it could make it before then we
had the wall here and then we had a
bunch of piston trans locators pushing a
sideways through the tunnel here I just
ripped those all out all the Redstone
with them because it doesn't work
anymore that would take you around the
bend here and then we had piston
translocator elevator to bring us up
here and I refilled this with water so I
just gotta gotta get something in this
area to replace the tunnel horizontal
tunnel but we have a way up now might
just flood that area with water and
maybe put a dolphin down there and we
just swim through that whole section
yeah we have a way back up here now into
the library so that's cool that's all
fixed mm-hmm okay guys so we're back at
the base here I got this thing refilled
with bonemeal kind of I've used a bunch
up already
so I've been testing it out with other
types of trees I thought it would work
with everything except the dark oak and
acacia but it seems like it's only
working with oak we have tried to grow
spruce I've tried to jungle I've tried
birch none of them seem to be growing
and I'm wondering maybe I misunderstand
something about how trees work so I set
up a test here how did it grow already
no it didn't okay I was looking at this
tree yeah does it have to be a birch log
above this to grow or can it be any type
of log any type of log okay yeah so I
guess just oak trees work underwater
with our current setup I'm not exactly
sure what's the other trees check that
would prevent them from growing
but yeah I've left this run for so I'm
lost
well here we are okay yeah I let it run
for the jungle birch spruce acacia none
of them group so it's just gonna work
with oak only huh yeah there we go
really so yeah anyways after a tree
grows so you step here the piston pushes
it sideways activates the dispenser so
we did an extra sapling and we plants
sometimes it takes a while to throw
usually it's not too bad
oh yeah this is the idea of how the farm
works and then once you get like 12
grown you go and you get mine this so
you mine this out actually you know what
I did my challenge for today I got the
underwater tree farm working right
that's what I wanted to do I'll leave
this as a challenge for you guys can you
get it to work with other types of trees
like birch spruce jungle I'd be
surprised if you got it to work with
acacia but you could probably get it to
work with dark oak even uh-huh
can you figure it out so that's that's
my challenge to you alright
for the rest this episode we might try
make like a sea pickle farm - its kind
of curious how how that would work so I
think you got to grow them on corals
right is that the idea I keep saying
right today I don't know why you get
into that mood though are you just say a
word over and over I don't know why or I
do what I'm making my episodes and it
changes like between episodes you
remember a long time ago I used to say
rats like all the time like instead of
saying darn or oops er or whatever I
would say rats and I had that bad habit
for a long time and I keep beating these
habits but then I pick up a new word
that I say constantly I can't get I
can't get it's perfect ever uh-huh
where's my bow meal guys I'll just I'll
just steal it out of here I had some
more somewhere else so okay so can you
grow them outside of the coral reef so
plant them down here yes you can okay so
you just got a bow meal at once
is that the idea yeah got four again got
four again okay so you just got a bow
meal at once I thought it would would be
one for each each pickle all right can't
plant these sideways no if it's on sand
it doesn't work okay right yeah okay
so let's see if we can figure something
out here okay can auto plant them wasn't
expecting to but it's always worth
trying
ah so fill this up with bone meal see if
we can get an auto grow them with
dispensers that you probably can right
yeah look at that
okay that's good that's really good so
can we let's get an observer maybe see
if we can detect the growth snake it
over this way this way that'll make it a
constant loop though oh well we'll try
it here so I think we gotta replace two
of those blocks with trap doors right
there put that there
oh oh
J can we stop the jump from going okay
interesting
I don't want the kelp to grow though
that's it's wasting bone meal let's add
another trap door here and observer here
okay
I'm wondering if we can pick up the
water after grows oh it shot out the
budget too okay let's try plant this
okay it's picking up the water but it's
not it's not dealing the sea pickle huh
so they don't need water interesting I
just make light they do though alright
take that away yeah okay they need water
for light okay and they need water to
multiply - uh-huh
okay I don't have it yet here but I feel
like we might be getting close so I got
two coral blocks this is a regular
piston this is a sticky piston got two
observers this one activates this piston
this one
it's this piston alright dispenser in
the middle here and then trapdoors
attached to these blocks to activate the
bonemeal basically if we spam
right-click right now this is what
happens which feels like or maybe it is
growing I saw it grow a couple times
there at least I don't know if it's
growing every time I think it might be
growing one of the times and the other
time it doesn't it's really hard to tell
because it's so fast I do have more than
I started with it's okay so it's doing
something I don't know if it's perfect
though wait a minute wait a minutes this
is not kelp this is sea grass and seeing
it wrong the whole episode this is kelp
over here aha okay let's see if any of
the seed grass grows when we do this
because if it does that means it's
missing some of the times yeah okay so
[Music]
yeah it's it's alternating between
working and not working right now so
which which ones working which ones not
let's try get rid of this side so the
bone meal won't activate when this one
activates see if we only get seagrass or
if we only get growth
it's really hard to tell okay let's put
this one back let's get rid of this one
see if cuz we're getting seagrass still
we don't want to get seagrass because
that's wasting bone meal we're still
getting cigarettes okay I'm not really
sure maybe timing is definitely not
right though mm-hmm
okay so if it's working perfectly we
should get three stacks of sea pickles
per stack a bone meal which did not get
it working perfectly this is probably my
best best version over here right now
though still fairly compact and
basically I got two dispensers with this
version so I'm gonna split it half in
there half in there works pretty quickly
but it is not perfect here we go all
right hold right click
and it varies between these two on
finding the grout okay so we got a stack
in seven that we started with eight so
it's about one-third the efficiency all
right let's do another run just to see
how it varies at its best I've gotten
like two stacks at its worst like one
sack okay let's go again all depends on
like when you when you hold right click
probably depends on how frequently your
must updates and stuff to do I don't
know that time we got a stacked in 25 so
yeah all right
the other version I made here we can
just put in one dispenser as well I
should say and then I think it's more
efficient but it takes a little bit
longer right
3240 yeah I think it's about the same
action how's it out already okay yeah a
little go stacking for there so maybe
it's not better actually uh-huh anyways
the other version I came up with over
here is a little bit difference so I got
slime blocks underneath the coral and
basically you place the CD pickle here
updates this observer goes around here
activates a trapdoor sends power to a
dispenser just one dispenser on this one
then power passes through the dispenser
to a trapdoor down to the sticky piston
over here only one piston with this
design instead of two um so you load it
up here well if you don't have bone meal
in it basically does that once you add
the bone meal though
not working super great problem is if
you hold right click you place more than
one sometimes that lowers your
efficiency I don't even think we're
gonna break a stack here yeah so if you
watch it so sometimes when you place it
you see we just place down three before
it updated yeah so that's kind of the
problem with this design over here like
it takes so long from the time you place
this before the piston finally moves it
that you usually place down three and
then the bonemeal only will grow one
instead of like one turning into four
right it's three into four this design
works a lot better though if you don't
hold right click if you just like tap it
like two times the second so let's try
that instead I'm gonna ice the kind of
place to do that it's right clicking
like once a second maybe twice a second
you should get a lot more this way
NetWare over a stack almost two stacks
yeah so we almost got like 60 probably
about 60% efficiency 50 to 60 so yeah I
like I like this design over here though
because I don't have to think when I'm
doing it and just accept that you're
only getting about 33% efficiency but
it's pretty quick and bonemeal is
basically free so I don't care right
uh-huh can be improved a lot though oh
there we go there we go I'm gonna get
rid of that skeleton if we blow up a
charged creeper with a charged creeper
we should still get the creeper head
right I would think so oh man okay here
we go guys oh okay okay
did that work yes we got that creeper
head awesome okay that's how to do it
get them in the water and it's a lot
safer I kind of wish they kept it like
there was in the past like all mob heads
used to be a lot smaller and my headband
would go over the creeper face and it
looked really cool the mast and the
headband like covered over the mob head
but now it's just that's all you can see
now oh well I want to use this creeper
head for a banner though make thick my
etho banner finally but we're gonna wrap
up here for today guys I think so let's
check out the comment of the day it says
it's a good question how so you even
light em caves how do you find all the
caves very good question very good
question so I said recently that I lit
up all the caves or a lot of the caves
in the area here and the question is
like how did I go about doing that
actually what I like to do is crank up
your sound
crank up the hostiles maybe maybe
the friendlies and if you swim near the
bottom of the water here
be really quiet you hear that would
stores aam be so you'll either hear like
zombies skeletons you know bats are
pretty easy to listen to and you just
skim over the surface of the the ground
here and you'll find cheese all the time
there's also like lots of ravine
openings like this and antis caves in
the ground too so it's not too hard to
find the caves and a lot of the caves
are all connected to each other now the
way they generates so that's kind of the
trick I used to find most the caves in
there you know and thank you for the
question - alright guys so hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching and until next time take care
have a good day bye bye
[Music]