[Music]
hey how's it going everybody this is
etho morning Boise so actually not to be
confused with depressed ease oh ouch you
know that feeling like when you get
water up your nose and it sometimes
hurts you get that sharp pain kind of
feeling I don't know if maybe I'm the
only one that gets that but that's what
I was greeted with this morning I'm so
congested have so much liquid snot in my
nose that it like gave me that sharp
pain feeling right when I woke up wasn't
very pleasant so I'm pretty congested
hopefully it'll clear up as we go
through the episode though so to begin
with we're gonna have some fun here not
just one or two stacks of TNT this time
I got down a full chest of TNT one third
of my stash on the island here again
we're trying to clear this land for the
witch farm the rest of this I'll
probably have to clear with a pic though
yeah and where's gonna be a good place
to view it maybe I don't know probably
from the air actually I'll just have to
try it
not move not move very much I guess okay
here we go
get away
okay get some distance yeah you know
what I need is the one second once there
we go that was pretty cool how did we do
yeah we cleared a law to land here yeah
so this was like a solid mountain before
now we just have a thin wafer at the top
there that's pretty good ITT's not
really useful for clearing like stone if
you just like put it on a flat surface
like this you kind of want it by either
you dig a hole in the ground and then
place a bunch of tnt for it to really be
effective or it's really good for
clearing dirt like we just did here too
otherwise the Pickers usually faster I
find I had no idea they added this to
the game this is awesome I was writing
to the bed here and it's like wait a
minute wait a minutes
the beds are actually bouncy now you can
bounce on the bed you see that little
hop every every time that it's so cool
all right this is a long shot whoa don't
blow up my bed don't blow up my bed you
fool we're trying to test things here
okay this is this one's bouncy yeah one
second okay so now if you drop an anvil
on it I doubt it'll bounce
yeah just breaks okay we're probably
high enough right yeah the bed just
disappears okay so let's let's jump
let's see what happens now woo hoo Oh
interesting okay so we took we took fall
damage two hearts with our feather
falling on but we did bounce pretty good
too 17 18 19 20 21 22 we should probably
stop there so we lose half a heart for
every block we drop with no armor on
but it takes three bucks for us to
initial yet going so we should have like
half a heart left right I'm wondering if
the damage dampens our fall kind of like
the hay bales do but it's been a while
since I've done like falling tests so I
just might not know what's wet anymore
yeah let's try it without the bed now do
some proper science here you know with
and without okay now if we fall again so
we got down to four four Hertz down and
half heart okay so it does dampen the
fall kind of like hay bales okay so I
did a little bit of mining here you see
we got some flat spots now set up a
beacon with speed mining all that kind
of stuff went and got some hay bales and
now let's try these out no armor on it
goes down to hearts so that was four
hearts down this is two hearts down so
check it out everybody we're about to
pack up and go do some other stuff here
but that's not which farm and I just
want to show you what we've mined and
what we got left to mine here it's
actually pretty easy to see it now that
I've cut out this section so this is one
of our corners and there's a dividing
line somewhere here oh I think we didn't
see it over here yeah so this is our
dividing line so everything this way I
want to flood eventually that means we
got to get rid of all that up there all
that there and then we're like maybe
about just shy of 10 blocks probably
above the water so I want to dig down
still as well flood this all and then we
got light up the caves in this area and
then we should probably be able to get
some redstone off of our witch farm
hopefully but
let's let's take a run down here get an
idea of the size it is like 200 bucks
from one side to other right it's quite
a bit goes all the way up to here
aha so got some some work to do over
here ladies and gentlemen I present to
you the world's greatest sniper ever
known to mankind slushee the Snowman
he'll get it one day probably not though
alright everybody so I don't know if you
guys are gonna be able to handle this
but I have learnt a new trick check this
out
if you run and jump off these stairs oh
I can fly look at this yeah guys we are
in a copy of our LP world right now I
thought I'd include you on some design
stuff right now I don't know this is a
good idea or not but I decided maybe
let's try to get the bomb factory
working again the last like two or three
attempts of doing that have failed so
that's why I'm a little hesitant to try
again but the game has changed a bit
since last time so the big problem
before we got the bomb factory part
working like this complicated parts but
I was never able to reliably separate
the creepers from other mobs in our mob
separator part there that's really easy
to do now cuz creepers are shorter than
other mobs they made a change with that
but this bomb factory part doesn't work
anymore because they also have changed
skeletons since I originally made this
now skeletons you know they pull back on
the bow and they have a little bit
different
AI now so we got a redesign it a little
bit so when working with mobs I like to
go into creative because it just
simplifies things a lot which is why
we're here and I got a try a little
sequence here this is what I got to
figure out so we're gonna have a snow
golem
over here right so we want the snow
golem to shoot the skeleton once and we
also have to detect when that happens we
need to prevent the skeleton from
shooting the snow golem afterwards so
that's our first challenge then after
that so we we let the snow glow masseuse
the skeleton once we detect when that
happens using a tripwire above here if
we have a tripwire right above he'll hit
his head in that and we can use redstone
so then open up a thing here which will
let a creeper down and then the skeleton
will shoot the creeper and then the
creeper will blow up when he's near the
skeleton but but when we do that we got
to make sure the snow boom also doesn't
shoot the creeper let's focus on that
first here so how do we make the snow
golem shoot the skeleton but not the
creeper the way I was doing it before
was with a slab but I'm finding that's
changed sometimes the snow golem will
actually hit the creeper like the slab
used to always block the snow balls but
every once in a while he's actually
gonna hit the creeper here I've I've
noticed so this doesn't work anymore it
actually does nothing I think yeah it's
pretty rare but it does happen so what I
was experimenting with here is using
snow slabs snow slabs I think if we get
just the right height it might work
let's try it that height there we want
the snow golem to be able to still shoot
and we can go f3b to see line-of-sight -
that might help us out so yeah I don't
know kind of got to watch it for a bit
but I don't think you'll hit him because
of the obsidian here gets in the way Oh
No aha this is why we test because if
this happens when it's fully built
goodbye hours and hours of work we don't
want it to ever blow up let's go down
one lower hopefully we can find the
magic spot here
okay you can still see them it looks
like he's shooting upwards though so
that might be a problem okay okay you
hit a pretty sweet spot here it looks
like it's not quite perfect but it's
it's probably the best we're gonna get I
think the red line on the snow golem has
to be above the blocks here for this to
work oh did you get shot buddy or did
you shoot yourself I missed that
I think the skeleton can shoot him if
he's up in the air when he shoots so we
might even want to add like a trapdoor
here just so that's less likely but the
snow going to hit the skeleton very
important skeleton that seems to not be
able to shoot the snow golem which is
awesome and the big challenge here as
well those we don't want the snow gonna
shoot the creeper and he tries I did
have him hit him once but I think if
that happens it's just gonna be a dud
explosion I think we'll be will prevent
it from blowing up in in the chamber
here anyways like a dud when he
recombines with the skeleton I mean
uh-huh uh-huh yeah it looks pretty good
though now it would be really cool if we
could find out when the skeleton shoots
the creeper actually so I'm gonna try
put a tripwire above him that creeper is
shorter than skeletons so he might not
fly up high enough to trigger that let's
put a lamp on so we can see it easy if
it happens and we're gonna put the
skeleton in here so keep an eye up here
see if it flashes when we do this and
I'm gonna oh wait actually we got to get
this Nolan to shoot him first wait a
second sword get rid of this dude okay
block that we're gonna let creeper in
okay so now the skeleton should shoot
the creeper as it tries to shoot the
snow golem
and that did light up okay that's very
good and then once we recombine the
skeleton with the creeper not in the
chamber here but somewhere else I get a
cobblestone generator or a tree farm or
something then we can trigger an
explosion whenever we want wait a
minutes one moment here I made a mistake
with this I assumed like once we
introduce a creeper into this that the
snow golem was gonna shoot at the
creeper but no because they shoot each
other I don't know what I was thinking
they become each other's enemies right
so if we put a creeper in the middle
Skelton's gonna still try shoot the snow
golem snow golems gonna still try shoot
the skelton not the creeper right and
with that line of sight he will hit the
creeper the snow golem here which is no
good no bueno we don't want the snow
golem to hit the creeper before the
skeleton it's not actually a big deal if
he hits a creeper he just can't hit it
first cuz whoever hits a mob first
becomes that mobs enemy and we want this
the creeper mad at the skeleton so I was
experimenting here if we time this
trapdoor just right we can make sure the
skeleton always shoots before the snow
golem it seems are you there the snow
golem won the fight right here's the
trick watch the draw on the bow if he
finishes drawing like that then the snow
LuAnn will win try it one more time just
no golem wins again but if he's in the
middle of the draw like that and it just
finishes drawing I can make sure the
skelton always shoots first draw finish
draw finish draw finish but the draws
and over draws then the snow golem wins
so that's what I gotta do I just gotta
control the timing on this trap door and
we should be able to do it just right
alright everybody so check it out so
this is the new bomb factory 2.0 or 3.0
whatever we're on I don't know I've just
been testing it with zombies so far
we're about to move on to the real
creeper and skeleton tests I saved it as
a structure block
in case it does blow up we can reload it
pretty easily and before I explain how
it works lets us try it to make sure it
does work otherwise I'm wasting my
breath right so let's go for skeletons
and creepers the real deal here and load
in our snow golem the 100 divided
instruct the slabs I did all man should
have used Ethos slabs they could have
survived that okay bad joke move on
Ariel so he's in there and now let's do
it so first thing is we put the creeper
in here and skeleton goes here Skelton
falls down it's shots yeah all right
that's what I wanted to see let's try it
again it doesn't matter which what order
they go in here actually so the
important thing is skeleton has to go in
this one creeper has to go on this one
Skelton falls down nice so the the
creeper is aggro at the skeleton that's
why he blows up Oh oops
well what happens oh I should I know
what happens
undo oh but the creeper is too far away
so he can't detonate on the snow golem
oh okay so that's actually not a problem
if it happens
AHA not that it should ever happen all
right I think we're good I think we are
good here so notice the trap door closes
there for a brief moment I guess let's
actually try it without the trap door
maybe I added that in and it's not even
necessary cuz I didn't do any tests
without it not sure if it'll matter Oh
so it almost looked like the snow golem
shot him first there right Jen it might
actually matter come on there you go
yeah that is why we need the trapdoor
okay so we got the new one loaded in
here guys and I've added a chamber at
the bottom here I want to test something
I want to see how long that creeper
stays mad at the skeleton for last time
I tested this the creeper stayed mad
forever but that might have changed
because it was a long time ago I tried
that okay so you can see the skeletons
still mad at the snow golem there let's
give it a little bit of time here uh-huh
creepers looking at us that's fine but
now I think once he gets line of sight
to the skeleton he should oh oh no they
look like best friends Oh No
okay that could be a issue what happened
there what happened guys I don't know
let's try it again because I'm sure I've
had some that have been that longer than
that just be my set up here yeah you
still mad okay I tested it a little bit
more here guys and it seems like maybe
around 10 seconds roughly that they
forgive each other but here's the key I
found out if we renew their line of
sites every so often then he'll stay
angry it seems to reset the counter
he'll stay angry forever
I noticed the skeleton once he stops up
in there that's that's when he forgives
us no goal about that amount of time
yeah this week as long as we let them
see each other every now and then
without the creeper exploding we can
transport them as far as we want if they
don't despawn is the other condition
okay so now I'll try to show you the
Redstone and explain how it works for
quickly here if possible this is much
smaller than our old design and it seems
to work a lot better more reliable I
haven't had it fail yet which is good so
to begin with let's look over here you
see we have two sets of trip wires the
upper trip wires here one for both the
creeper and the skeleton and then
another pair down here so this first
pair at the top here just makes sure
that there is both a creeper and
skeleton ready in position so look at
this indeed over here the creeper is
there that torch goes off if a skeletons
here and that torch goes off which makes
this torture turn on all right and when
this torch turns on it activates the
redstone it down here goes to here to
the trapdoor which drops the skeleton at
the beginning so that's the first thing
that happens here only the skeleton
falls down not the creeper skeleton
waits to get shots and then he activates
the wire up there you see that so that
power is this line down here you follow
it around it goes to this trapdoor to
the creeper one drops down the creeper
and then when the creeper gets shots
then it activates this tripwire redstone
runs here got a sticky piston there down
to the redstone and pulls back the
piston so that they fall down if they
stayed in there the whole chamber would
explode but we use gravity to get them
out of there as quick as possible so
that we break the line of sight if we
used water streams or something there's
a chance they might fight the water
currents so that's why I decided to go
for a vertical design this time our old
one was using water streams which I
don't think was as good and we also got
to control that trapdoor right so we use
this wire here to do that connects to
the tripwire the skeleton activates if
we follow it along here
goes to an inverted trapdoor over here
so it's open most the time just when the
skeleton gets shot and he wants to shoot
the snow golem we close it so it breaks
the line of sight and it also sets up
the timing perfectly for when the the
creeper enters the chamber AHA and then
we got to do what we got to do one other
thing here you'll notice when the
skeleton Falls and when the creeper
falls they activate this tripwire here
on the way down and also when they get
shot so we have to add some redstone to
ignore when they initially fall down
which is what this stuff here is about
so if this isn't here it like makes this
block go up so that this wire can't
connect to here basically so if that's
not activated and we try to run this
watch the difference I think that one we
removed us for the creeper okay it works
kind of that time but basically it
doesn't wait for the creeper to get shot
other it's like as soon as the creeper
falls down then he then these pistons
retract whether or not he gets shot
unless this is here and then we also
have a thing here for the skeleton which
activates this piston and makes it
ignore letting the creeper and otherwise
as soon as the skeleton would fall down
and activate this tripwire he would let
the creeper fall down as well because it
connects right to the creeper one so we
got to ignore that the first time well I
think we got it figured out guys so we
are back in the LP world here just found
a dungeon wanted to check it out
I think this has been here a long time
though so there's probably nothing super
special but yeah I gotta get some
redstone still need redstone huh yes aha
okay not much there so this is where we
do the speed mining right at corrupted
border got our beacon here
[Music]
redstone it kills me some people
actually throw this stuff away like what
is wrong with you people that's been so
much time trying to collect it oh I'm at
the range of the beach in - okay cool so
we've got some redstone again guys got a
stack of blocks in here - uh-huh
very good we got our plan figured outs
but one thing we don't have is time
getting a little bit long in the episode
I think we'll try build the creeper
separator and then we'll do the rest
next time so we got to replace this old
system we have here that's the old bomb
factory there that we just read designs
so we're gonna be tearing most this outs
I think we had a switch at this no it's
this over here okay okay and then they
drop down here okay that is where we're
gonna start with the whole thing I guess
okay last time we did this I was trying
to do it with the minecarts and then I
discovered oh mobs can actually control
mine carts now and that did not work
like they didn't overpower power rails
even if you tell them to go down the
track and they won't listen to you so
that was kind of the big downfall last
time I just broke a bunch of stuff here
so we'd have some building space and I
think I got a plan for what we're gonna
try here so there's not gonna be any men
in the mob stream here so we only need
two blocks heights one two I think and
this is where we're gonna separate the
creepers out oh yeah this is a mess okay
umm it's really hard to do anything okay
so I think we're gonna want a piston
here
and then we're gonna try to get two more
Oh what just happened
big leg spike we're fine I think we'll
have a glass here two pistons here and
let's put a trapdoor here so this is the
thing like a skeleton and a zombie they
can't walk through here we can and
creepers can as well so there's no
chance of a zombie or Skelton going here
this is where the creepers will fall
down and then the skeletons and zombies
let's make them fall down here make a
little holding chamber for them just for
now while we test this oh that was our
floor uh-huh put that back you try to
make it nice and neat and now we're
stuck okay and then to activate these
pistons what do we do I think we want
this one extended maybe do it like this
do we have space here oh yeah there's a
little gap here okay I'm gonna put a
repeater here to activate that piston
and this will be the block we power and
then that will activate this piston and
then we need to invert this one so let's
do it like this let's put a repeater
here and redstone torch on the back and
redstone here okay
well want a little bit of delay on this
one probably and do we have stuff to
make a button I think we do okay
just to try it out here let's see if we
need take a step back to okay so I think
when we press this
kind of hard to see okay so this I think
pushed them that way first then when
that retracted this one pushed them and
then this one which went back into place
so I think that should work just
finished up the holding chambers here
got it all sealed up and now we're gonna
flip the switch we won't be able to get
them out of there just by leaving the
area only but this will be a good test
to see if the thing works so I think the
creepers might go there on their own
that's fine if they do yeah so it'll
fall down but the skeletons and zombies
will never fall down there and we want
to make sure no creepers go down here
because they can fit over here which is
why we got the arm holding them and now
let's see oh darn it
why did that happen hmm hmm maybe
because there was so many in there
already and got pushed that way we might
need to activate this pretty frequently
anyways we'll play with it more next
episode so I think we're gonna wrap up
here guys and here is the comment I
picked out this is something a lot of
you guys brought up actually we were
working on the witch farm last time it
says wouldn't it be better for the witch
farm if the time when there's no water
dispensed would be longer I get that you
need a certain time to flush out the
witches once they spawned but once
they're gone
shouldn't there be more time for them to
respond or in other words keep it dry so
that the in spawn yeah probably
we'll have to play with the timings more
once we actually light up the caves and
get maximum spawn rates at the at the
moment it's kind of whatever
yeah we'll refine it again later anyways
guys hopefully you enjoyed today's
so thank you for watching as always
until next time take care bye bye
[Music]