[Music]
hey what's up everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
oh it's not raining here another let's
play episode
guys there's a thunderstorm there are
skeletal horses that spawn in this game
and i have yet to find one
probably because i always sleep away
than the the rain
because i find it annoying but uh maybe
we'll go look around here see if we can
get lucky
we also uh wouldn't mind finding a
charged creeper if that would ever
happen again
let's see i think they're extremely rare
though
both both of those things
but i need to start looking for him
because i would love to get a skeletal
horse
i believe he can ride them and
everything
which is pretty cool
i'm not seeing anything though
yeah i think the highest chance of mobs
spawning is probably over
in this field here a couple creepers
here
oh man i'm not i'm not even looking at
my health i'm almost dead
oh snap there's that pig in a mine cart
oh okay let's uh let's run away for a
second
okay heal up heal up boy
oh baby guys
we got him
yes i got no way
i don't know what to do to tame them
though and they're probably gonna kill
me
oh man that's so cool they're not quite
as difficult to find as i thought i
thought there'd be like no chance of
finding him
oh man lightning strike right by us
you really want to check it out no no
charge creeper there
right okay yeah so it sounds like those
uh
skeletal horses are tamed as soon as the
trap triggers
i'm gonna go get some saddles and some
name tags so just in case
i want to make sure i name one of them
yep they are still here that is awesome
so i went and i got my stuff
i left this area they did not despawn on
me
um i don't think they will i think the
skeletons and the horse
are persistent from what i read i
checked out the wiki page on them
because i really don't know much about
these guys
um it says they spawn on the lightning
strikes
and on hard it's like 11 to 33
chance so they're actually pretty common
uh depends on your regional difficulty
your your
game mode difficulty so 33 at most
and i bet you i don't know for sure but
i bet if you push the creeper into
the horse before you triggered the trap
it would get you a charged reaper
i'm gonna try that next time we find one
of these guys if we can
uh might be a little bit tricky to get
the creeper to
to go where the horses but it didn't
look like the horse was moving before i
found it
all right so what do we do here let's
let's kill one skeleton for sure
we'll get an empty horse let's kill this
fool
all right man he just took it like a
boss didn't even flinch
okay so now is this horse gonna follow
me still or what's the deal with him
i think it's the skeleton that controls
them right
yeah the horse doesn't care about me now
okay
let's try to lure these other three
fools away
i went and got some better armor too my
helmet was like
one one shot away from breaking
what's the durability on it oh 11 11
durability okay not quite one shot
uh these two fools didn't follow me
hey you please don't kill me
oh no no no no don't shoot each other be
nice
we want you to live a long time okay
yeah just kind of get away
stay away from my village though i don't
want you to kill my villagers
all right now we'll circle around
what are they doing they're killing the
zombie okay
why did they do that where's the gold
one oh he's over there
hey oh man look at you
yeah you can hop on it 13 hearts
this is also a way of getting horses in
your world like if
if you're if you have my problem i don't
really want to explore
a lot because oh yeah you don't even
have to get
them to love you oh that's sweet
this is a very slow horse oh man this is
like the slowest horse i've ever had
but yeah i have a problem where i i
don't really want to explore to look for
horses
so i have no way of getting more but
this might be a good way of
getting a half decent one this is not
the one though let's
maybe we'll kill another skeleton we'll
try to get a better horse
honestly you know if they're not that
rare i don't mind
killing killing these guys even
all right okay that's one more down
we'll keep the gold guy alive
i just want to see if he despawns or not
over time
all right let's try this one out
and
look at how many hearts he has
is that for real i didn't know that
26 hearts all right
uh zenith might not be the biggest boss
of a horse anymore
compared to this guy oh man
is this one faster though he seems
really slow i wonder if they all have
like a preset speed
because that would kind of suck you know
like donkeys and mules they have a
preset speed you can't get any faster
uh okay we'll try one more guy out here
so you might be able to get up to like
30 hearts
this guy's down a heart uh he's a 10
harder he
seems maybe no he's slow too
yeah he's slow too let's check out their
jumping ability i wonder if it's all the
same
can you do three yeah i think that
counts as a full jump yeah that's that's
a full jump
you don't have to get all the way to the
very end one notch from it will work too
oh this guy can jump higher okay so
jumping height varies between them
hearts vary between them i just don't
know about speed because they were all
kind of slow
this guy can't jump either
i don't even know if he can jump too
like he is bad
can't even jump to oh my goodness
the boss all right i think i can name
him right
there we go cool it was between the boss
and hungary
uh or boney one of those i think the
boss works though
unfortunately in this version of
minecraft i can't really ride horses
because then the
the chunks don't load there are newer
versions out that fix that but i had
other issues with them so i'm kind of
waiting for
a stable version again oh yeah i forgot
my string all disappeared
ah so many issues with this game
and no no no you stay in there
you stay in there that's what this is
for okay
yeah one of the snapshots made all the
string in your world disappear all the
tripwires and stuff
so i'm still in the middle of fixing all
this
all right that should be good put that
there in case that ever happens again
uh so yeah let's move on to some other
stuff here today guys
uh i did work on the slime thing again i
think it's working
perfectly now i hope let's see can we
enter pearl through here like a boss
oh yeah how many times have i said the
boss
this episode i don't know all right
oh big slime
i hear a slime coming uh but yeah this
should all be fixed up now
so i i changed this around here it goes
up
empty minecart goes then a cactus breaks
it goes in those hoppers and back into
the dispenser over here
um so yeah the slimes go around
the tree farm here seems to happen
pretty consistently too like it's
it's been happening and i haven't seen
any carts get stuck
on the track down here yet which is
pretty good
let's double check it again
yeah no empty stray minecarts there
that's good
uh so today my big project in mind
we're gonna build a pumpkin farm guys
it's been a while since we really did
any
like automation farm building that kind
of stuff and i've been wanting to build
a pumpkin farm
so i have a pretty weird
oh man i want a stable version of
minecraft so badly
you have no idea everything just seems
to work bad right now
uh but yeah i have a pretty weird idea
in mind for a
pumpkin farm let's grab a couple here
okay so let's run through the design
here first off i'll show you guys uh
why mine's kind of weird so most pumpkin
farms we're doing like a fully automatic
where we
automatically harvest each individual
pumpkin as soon as it grows
is the hope kind of we're kind of doing
that it does have a flaw though
which we'll get to in a second uh no
usually the way these farms work you can
use redstone
as one method so like let's say
we have a piston uh
over here to harvest it or something
like that
and if a pumpkin's there
it sends a signal to the piston and then
automatically breaks it so if
ever a pumpkin grows here it'll
automatically harvest it
so that's one way you can use redstone
some of them they use bud switches
some of them they just run on a clock so
it constantly tries to harvest it
whether or not it's there uh the way
we're doing ours though
is a little bit strange basically
something like this uh we have the
piston
over here and
we're gonna have to go to the nether
though because i'm not another quartz
i just found out uh yeah we're using
daylight sensors i
thought this would be a fun way of doing
it so basically
sends a signal to that redstone down
there
then we'll go up redstone torch that's
all we have to do
then we just got to cover this up we can
like throw in a light here if we want
that to blink every time it harvests
and then like cover this up like so
so now if a pumpkin was to grow here
like if we had a plant here and a plant
here and a pumpkin grew here
then it will block off the light pistons
allow light to pass through
there we go that looked a little strange
for some reason but
uh this version of minecraft
redstone doesn't work the best i've been
finding
but yeah it's doing the trick
uh-huh so every time the light gets
blocked to that daylight sensor it
it breaks it the downside with this
method
is at night time this piston just
extends
and stays extended so no pumpkin can
grow
uh one way we might go around fixing
that
is to add a control underneath here to
override it
so that will make sure this is always
always locked even
like otherwise
like at nighttime this is how the piston
is going to be right but if we have a
torch under here we can control whether
it's extended or not
and then we could operate it on a clock
even if we wanted
but we're just doing this as like a fun
project too so i want to use the
daylight sensors
okay so i am nether quartz hunting now i
had to go out a little bit further in
the nether here
and i think this is a new fortress so
let's check out these chess
okay oh gold armor good
i'll take that that's a really good one
we'll give that to
the boss i'm sure he'll he'll like that
all right oh
so this is my first time like going
around in the nether since i got the
latcher wings too and it's actually
pretty nice
like when you're exploring these new
areas it's a lot easier to get around
and you don't use nearly as many ender
pearls usually when i go like nether
quartz hunting what i'll do i'll bring
uh
ender chest with me drops drop the
important stuff off in there
and i bring like a whole bunch of speed
potions just to get around quicker and
some fire resistant potions silk touch
and a fortune pick usually i use the the
silk touch on the nether quartz
um but if i know i'm going to make
like quartz blocks out of them it's
worth using a fortune pick because you
just
convert them as you go all right
there was one more branch off in this
nether maybe we'll go check that out
together quickly
i'll leave that torch there too so i
know i've been here now that i think of
it
a lot of times i'll go to these these
fortresses and i think they're a new one
and
nope i have looted it entirely
oh i think that's it yeah nothing here
i always think about that one guy in my
comments like whenever i
i'm exploring in the nether when i find
a new fortress i always look at that one
guy
who's like etho there's three blaze
spawners in your world at two thousand
two thousand
you should go check them out and i went
and they weren't there
and then i had to get back and i didn't
bring enough supplies with me and i got
like
stranded in the nether oh biggest
troll ever
that guy all right
okay let's try this out i'm ready to
head back here i think i know which
direction to go
all right gonna get to about zero zed
and yeah it should be around here
where's my path
oh man i don't see my path
wait i remember this fortress
whoa all right that didn't work out as
smoothly as i thought we're a little bit
lost right now
uh yeah i think our path is that why
64 is the problem we we went we went
down a little bit too low there
wait a minute wait a minute i guess one
big difference with these guys
is they don't have a spot for armor
because like if we look at this guy
armor goes right there
all right well hey you don't you run
away
okay there we go so we got back from the
nether
uh the whole point of that by the way
was to make the daylight sensors
because they they require quartz uh the
recipe
is what is the recipe we need
quartz glass and i think slabs right
i hardly ever make these things
yeah i think it's like this this
there we go that's it awesome so i think
we got all the stuff we need together
here guys we can start building our
giant pumpkin patch uh we're gonna do it
uh pretty close to the nexus actually
there's a a swamp area here
this is like on the back of the nexus
it's just right over there and on the
right side of it we got the swamp area
it's super flat
super big so we can go
as big as we want with this project and
let's see i'm going to build it on this
level
here so any dirt above this i'm just
going to level
level it out and like
so and this should be a fairly easy
thing to build
it's a simple pattern
let's see that maybe we'll start
around i don't know
we'll start over here so basically
pumpkins are going to grow on this dirt
right
you get two lines of it one on each side
the water stream is going to go in the
middle to carry the
the pumpkins to us uh to the hoppers or
whatever we set up
at the end of it all right
um the pistons they're gonna go
like over here here here
space them two apart from each other
all right all the way down uh
yeah so i think pumpkins are the way to
go
oh i have them on my hot bar it's like
man where'd they go
uh as far as villager trading goes uh
like if you trade something like paper
for example
it has that extra step to it where you
have to convert the sugarcane
to paper which you know might not sound
like a big deal but when you go on
large scale it gets really annoying
um something like zombie flash also not
the greatest thing
because you can only like trade
like every emerald you get from the
villager you have to
replace the stack of zombie flesh in the
trade window
um which takes a lot of time the big
thing
that takes time is like moving the items
around crafting them to whatever you
need
oops and then
waiting for the trade to refresh with
the villagers other big
time waster so pumpkins are nice
at the best trade it is eight pumpkins
for one emerald so you can do
uh a full stack of pumpkins we'll get
you eight emeralds
pretty good amount
um yeah anyways i'm gonna do a bunch of
building here
and then we will maybe check it out
okay well the redstone's all done
uh i think this is what i want to try
for the looks we'll do like uh
dark oak like so
pretty simple pattern uh i do want to do
the lamp i think it'll look cool
i might regret it later if it causes lag
but we'll try it out
and then we'll do oak slabs over top and
that's
pretty much all we got to do with this
this thing here oh yeah and we got to
plant the pumpkins yet
how's that look yeah i think that's good
i like the oak because it kind of
matches the piston head
well we are getting very close to uh
working farm here
i just did like 70 plants worth right
now we will
we will expand this though ah that's all
the materials i had
though need more redstone need more dark
oak
need more pretty much everything pistons
you name it
uh but yeah we'll try this out so
let's get our pumpkins planted
and yeah the water that moves the
pumpkins
like the ones we harvest is also what
hydrates the pumpkins here which is kind
of cool
uh this is not a perfect 100
lossless farm though i haven't even
bothered like there's a good chance
pumpkins will land in this dead space
here it's fine i'm not too worried about
it
um in my testing just about all of them
like always went into this middle stream
though
uh i had better success if i put like a
block
above where the piston pushes sometimes
the
the pumpkin will land on top of the
piston head
but if you if you have something here it
stops it but it doesn't look as good so
i don't know if we'll do it
all right run down here
and as soon as we grow these we are
going to start getting pumpkins maybe we
will do that already then
aha the farm is active
uh i hope i did not actually test them
growing
but i'm assuming it's gonna trigger the
daylight sensors right
there's no need for a block update or
anything i hope
well here we go everybody this is about
70 plants or so not exactly
there there was one pumpkin
it's pretty easy to spot them when they
grow actually
there's another one this will give us a
good idea of like habit
how big we want to make this farm too
like at the rate we're getting them here
seems to be about one every five to ten
seconds maybe
sometimes there's longer gaps though but
then sometimes you get two or three at
once
it's a really long gap
come on where are my pumpkins
uh wow okay
um any day now
why aren't they growing guys what
happened in minecraft
did time freeze
oh there we go finally that was a really
long
really long time
and again we're having a long gap here
okay
maybe not as fast as i thought oh there
goes one
but anyways uh because we have them
growing
on both sides here it's actually a
pretty efficient farm like
each plant can grow either to the left
or the right if you only have like one
spot it can grow to it's all
like half the speed right so this is
pretty cool
um yeah they're coming along it's good
it's fairly gone back too actually
there's another one cool but yeah
like i said it doesn't work at night
time so i would either have to
implement an override for it and then
control its
uh at one like with a central clock or
something
but we'll see i don't know
how necessary that will be since i built
it next to the nexus here i'll actually
be in the area that this will run
so i don't have to like afk edit for a
long period of time
but anyways guys it is that time again
to wrap up the episode here so
this is a comment i got picked out it
says hey etho
just caught up with this lp it was great
took me some months to watch them all
love to see you do some redstone
can't get enough of that but i wonder if
you already tried
throwing throwing an ender pearl into a
normal portal
it's an awesome it's a new and awesome
feature
oh really okay okay jelly
jelly we this is your chance jelly we
jelly y i guess it's jelly white kind of
like pie right
i have not tried that uh i have tried it
in the past
but not lately i know like in the past
even on multiplayer servers if you threw
an ender pearl i don't think it would
teleport you
but here we go try to impress me jelly
why
oh that scared me oh hey now
i do not like this what
it takes you to spawn
really
okay that's pretty cool i did not know
that that is really cool
is that a intended or is that a glitch
i recognize this spot by the way because
this happened to me when they messed up
the portals
a few patches ago it's like i dug up
uh i'm in the mountain right now
we should be only a few blocks away from
the top here
yep here we go and then i went to the
the end and i fell through the worlds
because
teleported me into the void but anyways
yeah exact same spot
as uh last time they messed up the
portals
that's very interesting i like that
thank you for sharing
um might be a cool way to get to
a certain spot in your world
i got nothing built over here though
everything's over that way
all right well anyways thanks for
watching guys i hope you enjoyed today's
episode
and if you have any comments or feedback
please let me know
gotta kill all these guys how do we do
it i don't know last time i tried they
took like a bajillion tnt so we need a
better method
i did fix this though finally
i got rid of the lava and now there's
like a pressure thing for him here
seems to work okay thanks for watching
guys
have a wonderful day bye bye
[Music]
you