[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode of the let's play
series
so lately we've been working really hard
on the world we've been tackling some
massive projects
and uh for today i thought we would slow
things down a bit
again i think we've got most of the
things i wanted to do off my list
actually except maybe the bee farm
would like to get that done before the
world tour but now i just want to get
uh oh we got two guys i didn't want two
guys
hey hey you over here you see me
yeah free free stuff here okay we got
him
hit the button and he goes down hit the
button they go down
but yeah i think our goal for today is
going to be to finish up some projects
instead of starting new ones
and one of those is the piglet bartering
we should at least get this functional
he goes down so yeah our plan here is to
have four piglet chambers
each one with three piglens inside for a
total of twelve
we got them named so they don't despawn
and after some testing today it seemed
about
it seemed like a hopper could handle the
items from about 2.8 or 2.9 piglens
but we can't divide a piglen into
decimals if we do they're
they're dead so we're gonna go up
round up to three and that way our
hopper is gonna be backed up with items
um and we can control how many items we
get by the rate we give these guys gold
i think it was about three episodes ago
i've been dragging my feet a little bit
with this project but we set up a dual
dropper chain to deliver the items to
the item filters below
for all the bartering items this
operates at four times hopper speed
which is why we're setting up four
different uh piglen chambers
each one with its own hopper then we
combine those together
so these two hoppers merge into a single
dropper which operates at two times
hopper speed
and then there's another dropper and the
other side merges into this one
and then at the end here we just have a
observer clock which will send items
down the chain here to the item filters
okay so now that we got them all loaded
in we're going to add some droppers
above them to shoot gold
ingots at them and good stuff so we got
four droppers to deliver them gold
now let's say we were to give these guys
16 gold we would want to split that
between the four droppers so
each one would get four we got to make
some kind of splitting system now
so easy way to do that is with a hopper
minecart
uh we're gonna merge our hoppers
together in the center
these two these four here and then try
set up a hopper minecart
somewhere in between the four so
usually the way i like to do this is to
use end rods to
center the minecart a little bit better
um
this can go here then we break the rail
and we kind of bump it to the middle and
we could leave it like that but we could
also try to like
lock it into place with some other
blocks um
one way of doing that is with the trap
door here maybe
can't place one here now uh-huh
uh i guess we'll just do like this you
might need to change that with something
else but yeah you got the idea
and then if we put a chest above this
the hopper will pull it out of the chest
and should split it evenly
four in each of these right yeah and it
does it pretty quickly as well
one that one and four on that one ah
that should be good that should be great
let's add a switch here to
the observer clocks maybe this will come
up like this and then if there's gold in
the droppers
we'll detect that with the comparator
and then cygnus
send the signal to the observer clock so
it'll start sending the items down
as long as the trading's happening then
when it's finished it'll stop
it's gonna need a bit of fine tuning i'm
sure but we gotta pretty close to done
actually
so if there's gold in this dropper we
added another branch off here
to activate a hopper clock this will run
right now i just have three items in it
and every time it triggers it's gonna
it's gonna trigger the four droppers
this redstone wraps around here
to all four of them and deliver gold so
as long as there's gold in the system
um gold gets delivered to the guys and
also the observer clock runs
so let's give this a try
they should be getting gold i don't know
if they're getting it too quickly if we
see gold at the end of the chain here
that means they're getting the gold too
quickly and we'll have to add more items
into the hopper clock
oh there is gold at the end okay so
we're giving it to them quick too
quickly then
i'm just going to add another item in
here and see if it happens again
something we should keep an eye on here
it's probably not a big deal but a few
items are getting left in the dropper
after it shuts down
because each of the guys will have a
piece of gold in their hand once this
runs out of gold in here
so it should get cleared once we start
it up again though
all right let's oh that's not what we
want to do
it goes in here you gotta split it
yeah so this stuff should get cleared
out and you see new stuff
is entering now i hate to say it but
we're actually low on gold at the moment
we used it all uh building the gold
beacon last episode
and we don't really have a high
efficiency gold farm
like the goon farm is mostly for iron
and the one
at our nether spawn is just like an xp
farm and we get a little bit of gold
from both of those but uh
yeah it's not quite enough okay it looks
like there's no gold at the end this
time so four items in the hopper is
probably good
awesome so we got our gold bartering
system set up now if we get any gold we
can trade it there
no problem uh and i'll work at polishing
that up later probably but it's
functional now so look at this this is
from i think 1.16.1 there is a glitch
where if an enderman picks up a snow
block and places it down it looks like
this it doesn't have the
snow layer on top like it usually gets
and when you break this it turns to
grass
this is uh patched in point two though
the next version
so i wanna see if we can collect it oh
it turns to grass
uh today's probably gonna be a bit of a
goof around episode i wanna see if we
can get these guys to
to pick up a snowblock and then if we
kill them we might get it
oh he got one okay now we try kill him
and it might drop as a snow block
no it's grass okay never mind our
mending villager he's god i think he
died
ah they made a change with beds i think
that's what did it
um you eject out of beds differently in
this update
and as a result villagers also eject out
of beds differently and i think you
might have ejected
out of his stall there somewhere as he
wasn't supposed to and uh
i think he's gone i don't see him around
anywhere
yeah oof that hurts a bit the llama
vader has been out of commission for
quite a while i think it was broken i
made some tweaks to it
and we gotta test it out now so get the
guy in here
uncle leo oh wait a second wait a second
put those back okay so let's try i guess
let's just hop on and see what happens
[Music]
uh what's going on with this thing oh
now it worked what
oh maybe i maybe it wasn't uh set right
is he gonna
plop when he goes down
oh he took damage and the boat broke
man this has been a bit of a tricky one
to fix actually i decided to get rid of
all the tripwires
they're gone we got a button there
instead now and redstone that runs up to
each of the pistons that goes up before
it was all like independently
controlled um so we just got this guy in
place we got a kitty in the boat so the
villagers don't go in with them
we hop on uh hit the button
and first test here
[Music]
oh i ejected poorly man i wish i could
tell you guys exactly what's wrong
all i know is it's the kitty's fault i
took the kitty out of the boat
and now it's working like no problem uh
somehow some reason if there's a a kitty
or probably another guy on the boat
it won't eject me out on the top here
uh but now that he's gone it's working
fine i just gotta make sure nobody goes
in the boat with him i guess
oh boy i need to learn how to fly around
my world with my eyes closed because
it's like everywhere i look
unfinished project over here unfinished
project over here
unfinished project everywhere we go
it's good though we've been getting lots
of them done so that's making me happy
uh last episode we worked on the
guardian farm i thought we'd stop by
here today and do a follow-up on it
so thank you very much for all the
feedback on that a lot of you guys
seemed to like it which made me happy
and also got some good suggestions if we
want to
add another mural or diorama whatever
they're called
i think i like the idea of doing a
chocolate island one
so we might put that again along this
wall eventually
uh but you can see i also did some more
work here we got a sandstone border
around all the sides now so they're
prepped they're ready to go if we
if we figure out what we're gonna put
here also we got a
line of glass along the top there with
water behind or like a blue
blue highlight which i thought was kind
of cool and then you guys gave some
feedback about the mural itself and i
think a lot of people
preferred the nether one the most
followed by the windmill and then
followed by the water temple i think the
thing a lot of people said about the
water temple was it looked a little bit
empty
so i've gone back to it and added a few
more details to it aha so we got a bit
of a land mass on the left side there
like we took our boat from there sailed
off uh
into the ocean and then got to the
guardian temple deployed our anvil
anchor and then went and conquered the
thing
and it just helps to fill up the scene
it was only like
half of the space was filled up before
now it's like much fuller looking
which i think is great we also replaced
all the stone and dirt in the background
there with water
you can see some kelp plants kind of
floating around even
and behind that is these warped work
blocks
and then you can see a bit of a
transition it's very subtle but
it's like there's the water a little bit
darker and then the sky there is the
again the packed ice and uh every now
and again we get some fish that spawn
back there too
so i wasn't sure if a charge creeper
blows up a husk if you get the zombie
head so i tried it out there and
i didn't get one and i died trying it
too
uh yeah anyways we are in the nether hub
now we're going to make
a couple improvements here as well
something that i should have done a long
time ago is add some kind of boat
dispensing thing here
because you know i take the boat down
one way and sometimes
it doesn't come back and then it's like
oh i need a boat i gotta craft a new one
and i gotta craft a new one i keep doing
that and it's kind of annoying
so let's get a couple extra here maybe
let's just do a dropper down here
with the boats in then we will have our
hopper
we'll do a barrel let's name these as
well i got my handle ready
so you can name barrels and any other
inventory in the game you want
to say what's what goes inside i like
doing that a lot now actually
so now it says boats up here and then
i guess we'll put the stone back here
let's put a piece of redstone here too
and sandstone we'll turn these into
buttons
like that and now when we click that it
should give us a boat
now there's no way of actually
dispensing the boat like in boat form
unfortunately you need water to do that
so we can't do that in the nether
one of our goals with our nether hub is
to try and make it easier to navigate
especially with the world tour coming up
i want you guys to be able to find stuff
so one thing we did was we set up the
lecterns now i'm wondering
we're gonna do a bit of experimenting
here we're gonna try out maps in the
nether
now i know you can't actually see
anything on another map
so let's just reconfirm that
if we make a map this is all we see even
though there's stuff built above us
right now it won't display it
all we can really see is our position on
the map
and as we move around we we do move
around on the map as well
but we won't be able to look at anything
but there is also the feature in the
game where you can make
markers and i'm wondering if that will
work on the nether map and if it could
be useful at all
so let's try nameless test one
i don't remember if the name shows up on
the map or if it's just the color
so then if we right click that oh it
does it does the
give the text actually okay that's great
so if we put a banner at each of our
nether portals
we can say what is there and then look
at it
from a map hopefully test two
and get that over here and then click
that and yeah we got test stone we got
test two so
i guess another question is how far
would we want to zoom out probably
all the way or maybe second from the
last one
so get our paper like that
well i guess let's look at it first so
at this distance oh it does reset all
the markers if we do that too
i think yeah they're gone
okay so before we go mark all our
portals with the banners we're also
going to farm up some netherrick because
i
think ooh that was a spooky sound i
think we're going to want to set up
loadstones for them as well
let's light this and then run as far as
we can away
i like to get close for the video you
know but it
usually kills me
[Music]
then we blast down the big uh tunnel
like that it seems to work pretty good
uh-huh so we got a bunch another right
just sitting here ancient debris we got
we got two there we got one over here
all right that was pretty good we got 14
from two stacks of tnt
here we go again
[Music]
there's a couple over there this time we
got eight
ancient debris with two stacks of tnt
woohoo all right so check it out we got
32 netherride in here and 40 in here 72
total
i'm hoping that's enough i'm not sure
how many portals we actually need to
mark
uh got a bit of gold here oh so that'll
give us
18 18. all right and then we take
chiseled stone bricks
combine them together with the nether
right it's one each loadstone it's
actually crazy expensive
that's our first lodestones in the world
look at these things so then you can
take compasses and
mark the location and then it points
towards that
lodestone okay so let's get to marking
things here so what i did is i went to
the four different quadrants of our
worlds
um and made four different nether maps
here all max zoomed out
uh each of these maps is i think about
2000 by 2000 area covers
so you can see us in the top left there
i named each one as well so this is
another plus plus this is
plus minus minus plus and then minus
minus so that's the coordinates
uh plus plus is positive x positive z
plus minus is positive x my negative z
and you kind of get the idea that way
so now we got a little kit put together
here
for each portal like our nether hub
portal here
we're going to mark it with a lodestone
gotta get a compass and we got to get a
banner
um when i think of our nether hub here i
think of purple so
we'll use a purple one for this we uh
have to name the banner
if we want the text to show up so this
is going to be netherhub
uh-huh all right another hub and then i
got a playset somewhere
i'm going to sneak it over here ah
no
my nether hub is such a disaster i'm
gonna just sneak it on the side here i
think
all right and then we gotta take the
proper map for
where we are we got to see our player
there uh where it has the triangle on
the player
then we right click that and we got it
marked at the top left there now
okay cool then we also gotta hide a
lodestone somewhere i guess we'll put
that
right at the banner too uh
right over here sure then we gotta mark
our compass
got it and then let's seal this back up
and i want to name this as well
netherhub
i did it again i'm not looking at my
keyboard
all right so we got our nether hub mark
so now the compass always points to that
cool so i'm going to go around marking
all our portals and then i'll show you
guys the final result when we're done
here and see what it looks like
awesome so we got it all marked out and
uh it took a fair bit of time probably
about an hour but we got i think most of
the key locations uh
marked on the map here and uh you know
the results are
kind of interesting i i do like it
though actually like it doesn't look
great
but it does a pretty good job at what
it's supposed to do like it gives us a
good idea of where stuff is
located and especially in relation to
each other so
another hub's right in the center here
one big problem i have though is my
nether hub is
odd based and the map is going to be
even based so
like this is our center and this is the
center of the nether hub so it doesn't
quite work out it might look better if i
add four more maps on this side
but i'm not really sure what to do about
it if you guys have an idea of where i
should put this let me know
um i was thinking maybe we put it at the
tunnels but
for now i got it right here but yeah
check it out so
like if we go straight down we go
forward
uh we will end up at the crimson keep if
we go down that tunnel and take a left
you can see it from the nether hub where
we are right now we go up
and to the left it's right over there
now
we also put the coordinates on the map
i'm glad i thought about this
uh it's probably hard to read on youtube
but they're there you can see it in game
pretty good they're kind of tiny though
and uh most of stuff is on these two
maps actually these two over here
so i think we can throw this in
and is it a map it wants okay it's a map
please don't mess up my uh original
i don't want to do it again okay that's
good
yeah it keeps the markers i was worried
i was gonna lose them very good very
good so we got a backup now of all five
maps just in case
something happens to them i hit it with
an end or pearl or piglen
shoots them you know they'll pop off and
we might lose them
and that but that would stink uh the
other thing we did though of course is
we did the lodestone so if you check out
the compasses here
we got the names of the things down the
tunnel and also
uh location we got the coordinates there
so
that's cool and the compass points at
them even while it's in the chest here
so the
juryville's a little bit off to the left
you see the pointers a bit to the left
there
while the ice forms a bit to the right
aha so another thing we should
definitely check out today i got so many
messages about this
is the changes with ender pearls and and
reporters or ender pearl status
chambers as they're sometimes called as
well
um i want to see like do they work now
actually or not
i have no idea um like obviously they
work
they have worked for a long time but the
big problem was with the chunk loading
and
unloading situation so like
this was always possible um
let's go make a new ender porter here
they're actually so simple to make too
all we gotta do is like dig a hole
oh we hit redstone so all we got to do
is like
get some soul sand and some water and
get the bubble columns going right and
that'll hold up an ender pearl now that
wasn't the case before so get our water
get our bubbles get our ender pearl
and now is this gonna float so it's
actually affected by bubble streams now
which is amazing
and i'm assuming it would work if we
leave the chunks right
let's go check that out because that was
the big problem you would teleport when
you didn't want to
but if we have total control over it now
that would be great
all right so we should be far enough
away where that hasn't loaded
and then when they would reload that's
when we would teleport
so let's head back
and i haven't teleported yet that's a
good sign
should still be there then
and it is okay cool so i'm gonna just
test it a bit more
off camera here make sure we didn't just
get lucky there
yes it actually works now everybody i'm
so excited about this
i've been wanting to make an ender pearl
transportation system forever
so i tried leaving the area a few times
and coming back having the chunks unload
and reload
i went to the nether and it still is
here and i also reloaded the game
both while within the chunks and while
outside of the chunks and
uh yeah every case it's fine this is
only one water source too so it's not
going to need
like a big big thing to do it so the
idea is we
oh i had the pistons already
the idea is we set up a piston here or
something maybe even a slime block
launcher
and uh then we trigger it and that
activates the ender pearl
and we can run redstone like hundreds of
blocks there's even ways of loading
chunks
uh we can go thousands of blocks and
trigger an ender pearl way
off somewhere else at a different base
or whatever
and and transport around our world that
way which is cool
so this is the new best way of uh
traveling in the game
like ice ice roads are cool
i like elijah wings but i don't like how
they don't require any setup which
yeah it's something that's always kind
of bothered me now we'll have a way of
getting around our world quickly and it
requires like
actual investment you got to set up
redstone systems and
like a panel of buttons here to choose
where you're going to teleport to
and stuff and it's going to be way more
satisfying
and uh and cool i think so i'm i'm
really happy about that
but we're kind of out of time for this
episode so that's going to have to
happen in a future one maybe
maybe next episode if we sacrifice the
bee farm
that's kind of what i want to do now
because it seems like it'd be a lot of
fun
uh but let's get to the comment of the
day and i i'm picking this one because
it's something that comes up
quite often and especially with the
world tour coming up it says
wild idea highly controversial
but how about episode 550 becomes season
finale and you start a new world i know
we all love this old lp world but i do
wonder if you're starting to become
bored of the world
there's only so many times you can
rebuild existing farms before it becomes
stale aha
yeah there's a lot to be said about this
comment um
so i've kind of flip-flopped with my
opinion on whether we should restart on
a new world or not
my current thinking at the moment is no
we're not restarting
i have uh lots of stuff i would like to
do in the world still
um i think this is true like even if i
do restart though like
building farms over and over becomes
stale even if we are in a new world
um what i try to do like if we are
building farms is i try to build
a different design every time not the
same ones over and over like even with
the gold farm here for example
this is a great great example i would
say because we have three different gold
farms in our world
each of them is different and
uh i hate to say it but we kind of need
a fourth one
we need a a high efficiency gold farm
still
so it's not like i'm loaded with gold at
the moment guys there's still purpose to
building farms
a lot of the resources actually i i
still need farms for
so there's plenty to do in that avenue i
don't feel like we've hit an end point
at all um but the other thing is with
the big project i have in mind
after the world tour um that's actually
a late game project
and having all this infrastructure in
our world is going to be great for that
you guys will know what i mean about
that pretty soon i think but uh
yeah i kind of feel like at this point
of time if we were to restart our world
it would just hold me back from doing
the projects i actually want to work on
at the moment
and i don't think that would be a good
thing uh but it's definitely uh
definitely something to think about and
consider and of course
i do appreciate you guys feedback about
that as well you play a big part in that
decision
what are they doing i think they can't
see the zombie pigmen sometimes
like if they get close like that might
need to make a couple tweaks there
uh but yeah i think i think we about
covered that
so hope you guys enjoyed today's episode
thank you for watching
and until the next one take care
have a good day bye