[Music]
I think I got this hold my coffee here I
go uh-huh
get all the teams all the team team
can't blow up simple games simple sport
far so good no you don't get me nope hey
I live the least Oh crash damn oops
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back to another episode of our let's
play series
the camera swirling things harder than
you might expect it takes a little bit
of skill I messed up there so today to
begin with here I'm gonna try to tell
you a story real quick ok kind of set
the set the stage for our episode here
you guys might not know this but before
I joined a mine crack before I even
started the the let's play series in the
YouTube channel and all that before all
that's like when you think of me now you
think of me as the redstone guy right or
a lot of you do anyways before that
though I was the TNT guy I was the
cannon guy I was on a server for like a
month or so before mine crack before my
let's play before the YouTube it was
these like 10 or 20 people this was back
before we had health in the game even
like it hadn't come out yet they were
they were preparing for it it was a pvp
server where they were like planning
strategies for like fighting and stuff
like they would they would run these
drills where they would try to build a
fortified fortress in 15 minutes
they would surround it with cactus and
lab emotes and and like set up these
storage areas with arrows and and stuff
like that and of course another big part
of the server was building cannons
playing around with TNT and that was
what I was really into on the server and
that was kind of how I got started with
redstone actually I
as making more and more complicated
cannons and to go along with that you
need more and more complicated redstone
right so eventually like the first
redstone thing I really built that was
complicated was a variable timer for the
TNT so you could choose if you wanted a
long shot or a short shot with the
cannon anyways I'm rambling my point is
I used to be really good with TNT
nowadays like they've changed it so many
times I have no idea how anything works
anymore I'm not no longer the cannon guy
right and I missed that so we're today
we're gonna be goofing around with TNT
we're gonna be experimenting with it
having some fun maybe building some
cannons and stuff where's my stash I
moved a little bit here uh-huh so to
begin with let's figure out some of the
mechanics with TNT okay let's go outside
somewhere we can blow stuff up
sweeping edge uh-huh
I I decided let's use up our 90 levels
here before I blow myself up repeatedly
to is probably a good idea depth Strider
last one oh I shouldn't have accepted
that one that was a waste okay this is
what we got in the end here dip Strider
three sweeping edge threes good looting
three protection fours are always nice
infinity uh-huh okay so I think we're
about ready to go here guys we got a
little test site set up here let me
sleep please thank you so we're gonna do
a simple test here to begin with I want
to see how close we can get to TNT
without it actually killing us and I'm
gonna be testing it with no armor with
iron armor diamond armor because these
are like two things you usually get on a
PvP server and then my standards like
what I generally wear over here and then
our blast protection full suit over here
see what kind of difference that makes -
so what I'm gonna do is set up the TNT
like this press the button oh I guess I
can't do it
down there I'm gonna guess we gotta
stand like here at least right okay so I
took off six hearts aha
so the TNT when we ignited it it hopped
up on the trapdoor here and blew
everything up so you wouldn't want to
use a trapdoor to hold TNT in place
right maybe let's try figure out what
the max height it will hop up on
something is so this is if we go here
you see the y-coordinate sixty three
point zero if we go up on the trapdoor
it's 0.1875 I got some snow slabs here
we'll go up one one above that so with
one earlier with two it's point one two
five with three it is 0.25 so that's
gonna mean the next stage up okay so
with no armor oh it looks like you
landed on the slab aha so you're gonna
got to go up higher even added one more
snow slab to this so we're at point
three seven five see if that's okay with
no armor it seems we can stand like
right here guys down to one hearts let's
one two three four five blocks away
basically let's go ahead and heal up
we'll try it with iron armor next here
so this is our no armor line over here I
thought with iron armor we would be able
to get like up to here that was my guess
but it really doesn't help very much
like only only like a quarter of a block
like I think this is about the closest
we can stand so this line here is about
how close we can get with no armor with
iron armor it's about over here not much
closer only about a quarter block but
with diamond armor we move quite a bit
closer I think up to to about here let's
try it out did one test and it seemed to
work fine yeah got down to two hearts or
so over here so that made a pretty big
difference between iron and diamonds so
what I'm wearing here is what I
basically consider the best possible
armor for general minecraft like this is
the dream here you cannot put protection
on Alijah wings if you're
not in creative so like this is as good
as it's gonna get if this was a diamond
chestplate we could survive a lot better
but we want to be able to fly right so I
think about three blocks yeah guys down
to one and a half so right over here
it's about half a block closer than just
diamond armor now I could be wrong maybe
we'll try figure this out - is this the
best possible blast protection armor you
can get with four four enchantments or
is it like three blasts and one
protection for I'm not exactly sure
about that
we'll try figure that out - let's see if
we can get right in with it here again
okay so I've got a stance about three
hearts or so we'll try to do the same
again except we'll change out one of the
pieces to something with protection for
on and just see what that does
okay so check this out this should get
us down to about three hearts three
hearts exactly that's with one piece of
blast protection and then three pieces
of protection okay with three pieces of
blast protection one of protection it
got us down to three hearts with two and
two three hearts with one in three three
hearts now if we go entirely protection
though four pieces of it then we start
having trouble so you kind of want three
three protection fours in one blast
protection for the ideal mix I think if
you're not using electro wings come on
you'll up saturation here we go
okay so we're fully healed this should
kill us yeah
all right so quite a bit already these
slabs seem to be working by the way at
0.375
anything lower than that I think is a
little bit dangerous I think it'll land
on it what we're gonna figure out next
is how vertical height affects us so
remember with no armor we could stand
about here five blocks away we're gonna
go up five blocks vertically and I'm
assuming we should take about the same
damage or less
is my assumption I can't reach it can I
whoops it's gonna be a little bit tough
to you gonna be fast like a ninja we
should live though yeah so we took a
little bit less damage I think the
reason we took less damage is because if
you look at our player model we're kind
of chunky right we stick out like if
we're standing right where we thought
we're right where we think it's safe
here right here we look at our player
model it goes over like four pixels on
that block right but at our feet were
flat with the block so we're like a
quarter block farther away vertically
right does that make sense I think so
okay that's good to know all right guys
so we're gonna start trying some weird
stuff out here so we got ourselves a
slime launcher here we're gonna stand on
and we have a 40 tick delay here I'm
pretty sure TNT still explodes in 40
ticks or four seconds like it always has
I don't think that changed basically we
stand here it launches it up through the
water here this is gonna be full of TNT
and I'm wondering if the motion we
gained from the slime launcher will will
launch us higher in the air when the TNT
explodes and what is the perfect timing
to it - I'm not sure
let's try remove three so we should be
in the air when the TNT explodes I think
that lands right above us in the water
oh yeah I get stuck on the ladder I
think I got stuck on the ladder guys try
that again
okay so we were waiting hi there hey
let's change the delay some more we
would want it to be longer then actually
let's go for what we originally had whoa
baby okay that was kind of cool the
water probably slows us down a bit too
though because it has friction
okay let's try change that again I don't
know if it's gonna get much better than
that here we go
that was pretty good hmm we didn't go as
high that time
mmm okay so that's that's the best
launch we could get with this design I
think I decided let's try a new design
to really get the most out of it though
so we don't want to pass through the
water because that'll slow us down and
we want the tea and just the right spot
when it explodes I don't know what that
right spot is so we want to be able to
adjust it which with this new design
we're going to be able to and we want to
be moving as fast as possible when the
tnt explodes I think so we want to get
launched right when the TNT explodes I
think so with this design basically
we've got a launcher for the TNT it's
gonna launch it up and at the top of the
TNT arc is then where we get launched
and the TNT should hopefully be
underneath us is the plan let's go up
there let's see if our one time version
here does anything it's got a pressure
plate and drop it on - if I can aim oh
come on really okay I'm supposed to
stand on the edge of the slime block
here yeah I don't think the slime block
launched us right so we got to shorten
the delay on this
okay there we go that was pretty good
okay guys so I tried a whole bunch of
different diamonds with this thing a few
different setups I even blew it up like
five times but I couldn't get it any
higher of a launch out of it so I think
it's not gonna be a super useful idea we
would need more TNT and we can just
barely survive one right we would need a
resistance to beacon and if you have to
there's always that chance you'll like
accidentally go into it not full health
and then you'll blow up and then the
second TNT is gonna blow up all your
gear which would be really bad but it
was cool to see like you can combine the
launch power of the slime block with the
TNT we went higher with the two combined
then you could go with either of them
separately so we kind of learned
something with it I guess
now I was thinking you know it would be
really fun I don't know how many of you
remember my old 360 cannon design is
like really really old I thought it'd be
cool if we could try to revise it with
the new stuff added into the game like
shooting TNT out of dispensers we'd be
able to compact it a lot with that and
we got comparators and stuff now I'm
sure we could do something really cool
so we're gonna try builds a new version
of it right in the middle here see the
problem with like most cannons it's like
you you see the guy he's at the cannon
oh he's trying to shoot me what do I do
what I do I'm gonna walk five steps to
the left and he'll never be able to hit
me because I can only shoot straight
right that's why I really like this old
360 cannon design you could actually aim
it and like to have different shot
towers and different timings to it you
could like actually hit moving targets
and stuff with it if you got really good
what I think we're gonna do trying to
think how to design this I think we'll
do a three by three to begin with here I
think I think we can get rid of or get
away with just like one water source in
the very middle the old design oh I
don't have any TNT with with me
pretend this is TNT the old design had
like 8p here these are the things that
launched the projectile and the
projectile TNT's were on the outside
like this we'll try to do something
similar like there was two rings the
launcher and the other ring was a
projectile tnt's so I think we will use
trapdoors just to hold the water in
place and they hopefully won't block up
the explosion power of the TNT and then
we'll have like a water source in the
middle here we'll drop the TNT
vertically down into and then we'll go
fences that just fall through I'm not
sure can I get back up oh I don't think
I shot further phone out we're getting
okay oh is it because I think I know
what happens yeah look at that okay so
you can place it but you place it while
you're in the collision box so you just
fall through then oh well that was a bad
thrill that was a bad throw alright so
this is what we're gonna do we're gonna
try have the projectile TNT the ones
we're launching on top of the fences
here and then actual launching TNT is
gonna go right in the middle here and
depending on how many we put in the
middle will affect how far the shot goes
and we have five plus five plus three
plus three 21 different angles we can
shoot the TNT from so hopefully that
gives us a nice range of shooting now we
got to figure out how we're gonna get
the the TNT on these fences like I think
let's just try a test here kind of like
what just happened to us I think if we
just ignite it on top of the fence it
might fall through let's see here okay
it does have to be ready to to break it
just okay so we can't we can't ignite it
on top of the fences fences are a bit of
a weird block because they're only they
only occupy one block space but they
have
collision box that's one and a half
blocks you see where it 81.5 on the
y-coordinate and the trap door is there
lower I think they're low enough they
won't block the TNT explosion so it'll
go to the fences and since these are
higher hopefully none of the explosion
from the TNT gets dampens that's what
we're trying to avoid with this so I
guess we got to go at least one block
higher for dropping the TNT like it's
got to be at least at this height mmm I
think we want to go one higher though
just so there's less chance of it
hitting our frame when it launches
yeah actually maybe we'll do this a
little bit different like the way I
originally did it is I had a ring of
redstone like this and then you put your
projectile TNT in for each launch and
then it it triggers right and then it
falls down on the fences but this time I
think we're gonna have a ring of
dispensers you see I got them over here
the problem with dispensers though is
they're hard to control like if you put
a ring a redstone around the dispensers
every single one's gonna shoot off TNT
every time you launch it right so you
got to tell it which ones you want to
actually drop the TNT and we can't
really do the switch trick with this
like here let me try demonstrate here
where's my repeaters you're there
hey we try to make a switch like this
where we have a block in front that we
can control and then if there's a sticky
piston here this isn't gonna work
because dispensers get bud powered right
that would be over there so like I was
thinking we could control the Pistons
with a lever and it'll either have the
block over here or down there but it
doesn't matter because if we send this a
pulse you hear that it still triggers a
dispenser wherever the block is so we'd
have to do it from a side angle if we
actually wanted to do that which would
not be very good
have to have it there and the piston
over here like that and then have the
repeater here Oh miss clicked like that
and then if that block is up but like
over here then it won't send a signal to
the dispenser problem is if we do that
this frame is gonna stick out super far
and we're likely going to hit it with
the trajectory of the TNT it's gonna fly
upwards a bit right and that's gonna hit
that and then fall straight down pretty
much so I think this is what we're going
to do instead we'll have hoppers above
each of the dispensers and then like the
guy operating the cannon is gonna be up
at the top here and he'll be able to see
oh there's a guy over there I think I
gotta throw in a a TNT over here it'll
go down to the dispenser but all the
other dispensers are gonna be empty all
right that way we don't have to load a
ton of TNT into this we don't have to
worry about the dispensers running out
of TNT oh that's not that's not the
right block and like it avoids the the
big problem cannons have cannons have a
habit of blowing up if you don't know
it's because because of user error so
you want to try avoid any possibility of
user error while using a cannon and to
do that you don't want the person having
to place the TNT in the cannon somewhere
because if they put it in the wrong spot
that's that's what's gonna destroy it
this way because we're not actually
placing TNT we're throwing it there's no
chance of us causing an explosion
somewhere hopefully all right and then
we'll run the ring of redstone around
this and we just got to send that a
pulse at the whatever timing we want so
I guess let's see if we can figure out
how we're gonna do the middle here we
still need our launching TNT the stuff
that drops into the water there and I
figured we'd do dispensers in the middle
we'll keep these full of TNT all the
time if we can and have them all face
each other let's go over here
should we do either should we do 12 I
think it's probably good right we'll try
8 first off and we want to be able to
adjust these so not all eight get
triggered every time we want to be able
to control the power of the cannon how
far it actually shoots cuz like if
somebody gets too close you still want
to be able to hit them right maybe I'll
do it like this actually let's go on top
here and have like another ring of
redstone up here and do it like this so
not a complete ring we will do it like
that and then either use buttons or
something else here so yeah redstone
only travels 15 blocks right so if we
have a bunch of buttons here like over
here and that triggers the redstone line
the closer one will go farther than the
farther one right so the closer one will
try set up so it's it triggers all the
dispensers all eight of them and then
the one one block farther away or two
blocks farther away it will only trigger
three sets and another lonely control
two sets and one will you control one
set maybe oh I say you know we could
maybe use a an item frame right I think
I got them on me because we got eight
dispensers and this has eight outputs
right or eight degrees of power how does
that work again I hardly use these if we
have a comparator here can you get it
from the side I don't know
now I decide doesn't work it's gonna be
actually on the block uh-huh so if we
cause it gonna be a behind the block
actually interesting like I never use
these hardly yeah that would work and I
think it's one to eight right or zero
two eight zero to seven maybe one
two three four five six hope too far too
far one two three four five six seven
eight
it does go to eights really and then
that's oh it it doesn't go to zero it
goes to one okay one two eight how do we
make that work because this travels two
blocks and that only travels one each
each flick mm so we could easily control
like four degrees of power I don't know
about all eight-year unless we do
something fancy what happens if we what
if we put a piston in the middle here
let's try something let's go down here
where we can blow stuff up if you have a
dispenser here and a piston here and the
arm blocks the dispenser I don't think
it'll launch the TNT right oh let's just
make sure um we don't have a lever okay
I guess I'll have to stand here so if
that's there and then we trigger the
dispenser is it gonna shoot the TNT oh
it does really what if it's a full block
let's try with a full block arm doesn't
work oh it still works okay all right
that idea is nothing I thought we could
like block four of them with the piston
and control that all right guys so this
episode is actually starting it a little
bit long I decided I'll just work out
the last couple pieces here off camera
and show them to you so this is our
device for triggering the the middle
dispensers here and depending on where
the item frame is controls two four six
or eight dispensers so this is our first
setting to actually launch a cannon I
decided to put the button right in the
middle of the cannon so no matter where
we are on the platform here we should be
able to reach this easily
you press it there's red
on top on top of that goes to the piston
that goes down and another comparator
and lets a signal through so let's just
check this out show it to you working so
at this setting here it's at the first
set of dispensers only travels to there
if we flip this two times it goes to up
to here two more times
it goes to six and you know what happens
on the last set goes all the way around
so triggers all eight so that's pretty
cool now the other thing we got to
figure out is how to add delay before
triggering our ring here because we want
to press a button and then have a little
bit of a delay and then trigger the
actual projectile TNT and we if possible
we'd like to be able to control that -
remember I said one of my first things I
designed was a variable timer and it was
like a 10 by 10 area so I worked out
something a little bit fancy here this
basically does the same thing as my old
timer except it all fits in neat little
package here you might recognize this
these six blocks here this is a pretty
popular timer to set up thing maybe I'll
show you show you that first because
that's the basis of this was it like
this turn these two subtracts and there
we go so now if you power that it takes
a long time for the signal to decay once
the button goes off you can see it
starts to fade out and then it finally
shuts off so I that's basically what we
do over here and then we control how
long it takes to fade off using our item
frame here that's also and subtracts oh
I should sleep here real quick one sec
okay so check this out this is like with
no delay on our variable timer here so
we press the button that turns on like
right away right flip it one more time
and it's a little bit longer a little
bit longer and I think every time we
flip it it adds two ticks of delay so at
16 range basically
all right
only problem is on the last one here
because these wooden wooden buttons only
last 15 ticks and this is 16 ticks it's
not quite long enough of a pulse like if
we use a lever it'll be fine
but or a pressure plate or something
like if we stand on here this will
eventually turn on you see that so we
got to add a little bit extra delay if
we want to use a wooden button which we
might end up doing with a cannon just so
we have the full range how do we do this
let's put a block here and something
like this should work great I think so
oh and we gonna maybe add to that yeah
it does turn on now though all right
cool so I'm going to try and stall that
on the cannon and it should be about
done then ah yeah yeah so there we go
guys that is our final cannon design the
bare-bones redstone to it and all that
not exactly a work of arts to behold but
hopefully it works that's all I care
about
I did notice that's sticking out a bit
far I'm hoping this shot doesn't fly up
and hit that might need to change that
to slabs or something if it's in the way
but yeah an important part of this as
you can see we got nothing really
blocking that the shooting area there's
no like columns that run up to the top
part there so everything all the
controls are self-contained at the top
which is really important and I made a
couple little tweaks to this so that it
looks balanced instead of having the
thing in the middle we now have it on
the left and the right here we got our
shot power on the left here that
controls this part over here and then we
got the delay which controls the ring
down here and basically like just like
we saw before let's see if we can get
over here with our our timer here the
redstone torch goes down and then it
goes to I think
five repeater set at four so it's 20
ticks a delay and then it finally goes
to the ring and ignites our projectile
TNT so bare minimum we're gonna have 20
ticks of delay here plus the 16 from our
shot delay maximum and I think I got
maybe a couple other ticks of delay
somewhere as well so it's gonna be
around 40 max without hopefully
exceeding that if it exceeds it the
cannons are gonna blow up is the problem
and I did put in our little extra delay
that we needed for the button so we got
the full range but anyways guys let's
give this a try this is the fun part now
I set up five targets we got a red one a
lime green green one up there orange and
a yellow one over there I doubt we're
gonna be able to hit them too well but
we'll see like if we can hit all five
that would be amazing but I don't think
we have that kind of control still even
with all our our stuff here but we'll
see let's aim for the green one first I
think that's gonna be the easiest to hit
so this is our center over here
I don't know I'm assuming hopefully if
we throw one in here it's gonna veer a
bit to the right and we'll change our
shot power to maybe four for tea and tea
okay and our delay let's just set that a
little bit higher I don't know what we
would need that's probably good and
hopefully it doesn't blow up this is
gonna be our first launch guys are you
ready here we go that's such a scary
sound oh okay that veered more right
than I expected
I just realized we're actually missing
something on here I think there's a
chance the TNT might fly up up up there
and explode but maybe not I'm not sure
exactly okay let's try oh ah really no
oh that sucks the TNT is exploding our
item
frames it was almost perfect guys almost
but we're back to the drawing board now
I think no matter how many blocks we
throw in front of it it's still gonna
kill the item frame right yeah
lame so we just have to have the proper
distance I guess let's try figure out
what that is let's go over here I think
it's eight blocks
if I remember right I think that's the
next range of TMT is that inside the
block what was that a visual glitch it
was visual okay let's go one closer and
yeah it's gotta be this far let's count
how many blocks that is so it's one two
three four five six seven eight
oh it's safe at eight so the easiest way
to fix this is just to lower the
launching platform so I dropped it down
three blocks hopefully that's far enough
away at the danger with that though is
like the TNT shoots out of those
dispensers at a random angle and if it
lands within those the inner ring of
trapdoors there when the TNT launches it
it might ram against the fence cuz the
fence is higher and then gets stuck up
there and blow up the launching platform
and probably a little bit of our cannon
but we'll see we'll see how it goes here
let's go back up hopefully it's far
enough away we might need to go one
lower but we will see put these back
okay so let's get this back to let's go
for six this time shot delay will put up
and let's aim I don't think we'll be
able to hit that that green targets so
it's kind of in-between these two angles
mm-hmm
we'll see here
and that's terrifying Oh wowthat's
its food kind of randomly there no no I
guess that's why all right we're done
with the cannon for today guys
what went wrong ah you know we should
have put a ring of slabs on the inside
and outside of the dispensers if we put
them one block lower I bet you that
would prevent the TNT from straying but
I'm not sure if that's what actually
blew it up because it like the amount of
damage it's like all six TNT exploded
right from the center like maybe it
didn't land in the water properly I'm
not sure I wish I could have saw what
happened there anyways let's go up there
and just make sure our item frames
arrived because that's what's most
important and then we'll wrap up with
the comment of the day here all they did
it's great a true success so he probably
got to go one block lower still uh-huh
hopefully next episode we'll check it
out again but let's finish up here it
comment says etho I cannot recommend you
play holo night enough it's an
exploration platformer and it is
brilliant in my opinion I don't even
mean it as a series but just in your
spare time please at least consider the
game I understand you're a very busy guy
but I've never played anything better
platformers may not be your forte but
the story should more than make it
worthwhile all the nights actually in my
list of Steam games I just hadn't played
it yet I got a bunch of James I want to
check out but haven't had time yet but
yeah I'm definitely gonna try that one
out it look cool from what I saw but I
gotta tell you I love platformer games
like I grew up on platformer games all
the good games were platformers
Commander Keen we got cosmos Jill of the
jungle Duke Nukem Sam secret agents
Crystal Caves you name it now I think
when people think of platformers oh
don't forget Cave Story guys that's a
newer one but I think when people think
of platformers now they think of
something like Super Meat Boy you know
those type of platformers where you die
repeat
they're good in their own way but I
think a lot of people don't like them so
they kind of associate platformers with
hatred and and you have platformers a
bad rap but there's lots of different
varieties to platformers and I think
they're really good games in general
even though they're not as common
anymore but yeah anyways guys I think
we're we definitely got to wrap up here
the episode is really long so hopefully
you enjoyed it thank you for watching as
always and I'll see you again in the
next one
take care bye bye
[Music]