hey
i love that thing but you would not
believe how many times it interrupts me
that's right i'm talking over you what
are you gonna do about it
all right it stopped welcome back guys
this is etho
get your snacks ah yeah uh
how are you doing today what's what's
new
what's going on how's the family uh
let's do a quick enchantment here to
start off with because that's always fun
let's try to get something better though
i don't want power
four here let's do a shovel
go on good enchantment to start off the
episode let's do it
that's a good sign yeah i like that
that's good
we we were successful there all right
so oh i got the book on me still
so i was looking at the comments on last
episode like i usually do
and this is like to introduce what we're
doing to start off with here we're
talking about the past
to go into the future but i was looking
at
the comments from last episode and of
course the library is
a project i've been supposed to be doing
for a long time and
i do a lot of projects in my world i
have like a lot of ongoing projects
because that's what i like to do
that's that's what keeps me from getting
bored i guess
it's just having lots of stuff so
there's always something i want to do
even if i'm not in the mood to work on
something else the library is one of
those projects i've ignored a lot
until recently and
of course with some projects people are
more of a fan of than others
and the library fans they were really
happy last episode i got lots of good
comments
thank you everybody lots of people were
very uh very happy and said it looked
good and
they enjoyed me working on it and all
that stuff
but then there's other fans out there
there's
primarily the wilson fans
they were like what's going on why are
you working on the library and you're
not working on wilson if you're going to
work on something you got to work on
wilson so
to show some love for wilson we're gonna
we're gonna get him going
um try start up our little buddy here
our friend our pets
uh so here's the plan here's what i'm
gonna do
you guys might not know this but he's
actually at the state where we can run
them
so i think that's what we will do this
is going to be like alpha testing wilson
we're going to we're going to set up a
test run he might not run
the greatest we might come across some
things we want to change as we go but
that's
that's what alpha testing is all about
right uh there is only
one one thing i got to do with them yet
this wire i never ran
this is from the center it's got to go
to his happiness meter
uh and then once i do that we're gonna
we're gonna boot him up for the first
time and do a
a test wilson run here and see how it
goes uh and i think that'll be good
because i'll be able to see
like what needs to be changed
uh like if i neglect him a lot and he
doesn't die
well then i gotta make him harder for
more difficult
ah he did i put a snowman down here i
can't remember now
cows cows don't work in sensors i've
learned that they escape
you know what we gotta get snowmen down
here in the sensor this is a player
sensor
when i stand near wilson he can
he can tell and it's supposed to make
him happier
uh so let's we gotta get a snowman
though
cows don't work they escape too too
often
snowballs um
i guess we could do it this way
kind of a waste of my shovel although i
got to get the pumped in anyway don't i
oops oh i didn't want to grab that
this is supposed to be easy i just
wanted some snowballs here
for snow golem
uh here let's take that uh let's head
over to the pumpkin farm
really quick and we will get that guy
going
then i'll attach a wire and then we'll
boot him up so
i think it'll be okay he might be a
little too easy i'm guessing
like i think i can neglect him for quite
a bit and he won't
die on us which isn't a good thing i
think
if i neglect him he should die pretty
quickly
but we'll see there's not really a lot
of ways for his happiness level to
change
and i think no i did get the pumpkin i
thought i forgot for a second
oh and i'm wearing mini etho on my on my
shirt here
skin checked it off there we go um
okay do that
so far i haven't seen a snow golem
escape from one of these things so i
think they're good
but cows definitely can get out
okay all right very good
hopefully we can escape ourselves
don't die don't die don't die getting
close there
three hearts cool
all right so we got that let's make sure
this is blinking yep
so every now and then he'll step on the
pressure plate down there and that makes
this blink
if i'm over 32 blocks away from him the
mob becomes inactive the snow golem and
he won't walk
anymore so this stops blinking so i'm
going to run this to his happiness meter
to increase it so i got to run a wire
all the way to
to here no i it's got to go
to this wire it's going to connect to
this dropper power that dropper puts an
ender pearl into there and then the
comparator reads it
um all my item frames have popped off
have popped off from me updating
to the snapshots more snowballs
so that's why they're all missing on him
i'll have to put those back on too
i think i saved them yeah they're there
all right so give me a moment
okay everyone so this is it that wire is
connected
that was the final thing i wanted to do
oh my goodness let's just pause for a
second
all right you done okay now we can talk
so
this is it this is wilson number one
guys the first official wilson
uh it's it is still a test of course
alpha alpha testing here
but i'm not like gonna interrupt it
halfway through or anything like that
i'm gonna actually try to keep them
alive
and get them to the full 15 light bars
of age
so wilson is coming alive today
i feel like i should say say a few words
for the
this momentous event but uh i don't know
what to say
welcome to the world hello world there
we go that's that's it
hello world yes
um okay so i reset his age
everything else is good i think i'm
gonna start him out with no hunger in
that just so we can
interact with them right away and i do
need to set his
timing i do not know what a good timing
is going to be for him
um since it's kind of still a test we'll
try to keep it going
pretty quick still maybe let's just add
in
let's try a stack and a half of items
this is his heart rates by the way this
is what controls how
how quickly he updates and all that
stuff it's all controlled here
in this hopper clock so that should be
pretty good
um all right let's get out of here
so there is no fancy like reset switch
to them yet
so that's one feature i can tell you
already just from doing this that we
need to add because
to start them i have to like empty all
this stuff manually in
and set it up manually which isn't the
best
um
is this his health i thought i had ender
pearls in this
i guess not okay
so here we go we're starting out at full
health
and it's begun
hey wilson he's got a
wait a minute he shouldn't be that happy
i guess it goes off of his happiness
meter
only and it's at full everything else is
not though
and he's already lost some health so
let's let's feed him
before he dies here
all right that'll add to his weight too
it'll get his weight going
because if he's underweight or
overweight he also
loses health quite a bit all right
and i'm over feeding him here so his
weight should go up pretty quickly
see the way it's set up i'm i'm not
supposed to be able to feed him
like five times in a row like that it's
supposed to increase his weight a lot
which it didn't
so that's another flaw i see it only
went up one bar
hmm okay
all right wilson welcome welcome to the
man cave
um i'm gonna have to redo his skin
of course we didn't do the note block
stuff yet either got a lot of
suggestions for that which i'm
hopefully gonna add soon
and he's at age number one all right
wilson i'm gonna leave you b
for right now i'll check in on you
pretty soon
um maybe let's while we're
wow stutter much
while we're around here let's let's
breed up a
a mule i've been trying to get like a
really fast mule
um a lot of people are wondering why i'm
not using golden carrots like i said i
would by the way
i didn't notice a huge difference with
them um
i might return to using them but for
right now i'm trying to save the gold
for beacons actually
um that i get from the gold farm it
takes a lot of gold
to make a beacon it's not like i have
unlimited gold now because of the gold
farm it still takes quite a bit of
of time to get the gold
all right zenith actually no let's not
do zenith let's do
this quick guy here
it doesn't have a name oh and i didn't
get
sugarcane all right you too
all right we got a baby mule um let's
let's grow them up really quick here
i should have actually you know what i
have wheat down here
got lots of wheat we can give them wheat
all right grow up big become strong
the chubby little guy i think after
after this we're gonna go
maybe try to make an obsidian farm today
okay i need uh
the saddle cause i'm all out of obsidian
it's kind of a pain to get it see
gotta ride them to tame them
horses is one of those things like you
do it and you really like it but then
you
kind of forget about it and you don't
use them too much i find
oops but they are really cool
okay that's not working can't control
them
okay this guy he's pretty quick he's got
13 hearts
not bad not bad
yeah he's actually really quick for a
mule
uh let's try out oops he's jumping
did this change by the way like i'm
noticing i take a lot of damage now from
leaves
i think you used to be able to ride
through the leaves
when you were on a horse
oh he's a pretty good jumper
not bad not bad that's three blocks
yeah i like that this this guy's a
keeper
my other horses they they couldn't jump
really high either so that's not bad
cool okay so
obsidian farm i'm gonna set up maybe a
timer on a portal
um in the overworld go through it
go back through the nether portal and
when it takes me back to the overworld
it should create a new portal which we
then break to get the obsidian that's
that's my plan with the farm so let me
maybe set up some of that and we'll test
it out
and try to find a spot for it and all
that stuff so i'll be right
back oh i almost forgot guys we should
check wilson before we leave too
just to see where he's at it's been
maybe
five minutes and he lost one hunger okay
other than that he looks decent his
weight is a little low and his health
is one bar down i'm gonna have to
if possible i want to link his facial
expressions to his health instead of his
happiness
that makes more sense to me problem is
there's a lot of wiring on the health as
well as the happiness so
it might not be possible but i'm going
to look into that too all right
yeah he's full very good
i think we can leave him for now
um he's still pretty happy
and his age is still at one okay
all right guys so i am out here
kind of in the middle of nowhere but
we've been here many times before this
is about two
300 blocks away from the man cave uh
this is where we did
the realistic caving adventure that one
time
in this cave let's go check that out
actually just really quick here
it's been a while that came to an end by
the way if people were wondering what
happened the goal with that was to see
how far i could get without
bringing any iron with me and
yeah i ran out of iron i couldn't make
any more tracks
so it hit a dead end eventually but we
made it pretty far with that actually
this is also where i did the speed
mining things so i have a haste 2 beacon
out here
which is perfect for our obsidian farm
because we want to mine it as quick as
possible
and i got one of these special portals
that closes on itself once you go
through
so the lower dispenser has a flint and
steel for lighting the portal
upper one has a water bucket this
dispenser
triggers twice so it it drops the budget
to break the portal and then it picks it
up right away before the water spills
everywhere
and the portal closes 41 ticks after
it opens so
if we go through
here the piston it just closed right
when we went through
so now when we go back since there's no
overworld portal there anymore
it has to create a new one
and let's see i'm trying to
it's definitely an obsidian farm already
but i'm trying to learn how this works
to be honest i'm not just
trying to get obsidian here i'm trying
to figure out how it decides where to
spawn the portal if you see these
cuts in the ground like there was a
portal here once
there was a portal here once i think a
portal formed here once
uh here here and now here
i'm wondering if there's a way where we
can
force it to spawn in a specific spot and
if there is
we might be able to take this to another
level
of like an afk obsidian farm
if we can control it so
of course by the time i figure that out
i'm going to have so much obsidian
uh i won't need it because i have to
break the portal every time
and i'm already up to let's see
over two stacks already oh man
so here's a test i want to try no sun is
setting
i'm going to lower this all one
right because every time it spawns in
the portal it
takes out four blocks below it so i'm
wondering if we
like gave it a thing to target
like that like if if it'll make the
portal right here because it's
it's higher higher ground which it seems
to
prefer maybe i don't know let's sleep
really quick here before we try this so
i don't want mobs around
there is a bed here
um don't know
like the rules to how it decides
where to put the portal um
sometimes i wish i had like access to
the game code
because that would make a lot of things
very simple
all right and i'm trying to make sure i
go through at the
exact same spot every time so 88 12
this spot not here if i went in this
block it would take us to a different
spot
alright
oh formed right by it that's interesting
okay let's break this
and also went lower too
okay if this doesn't work i have another
idea maybe we can
put pressure plates on the ground and
see what it does
if that doesn't work we can put
structures
and i don't know we gotta find some kind
of surface it won't
spawn on
let's see if it goes to the same spot
again i kind of doubt it will
all right it might kind of i wonder if
it depends where i'm standing
i should try to force myself to line
perfectly when i go through too so i'm
going to go right into the corner
like a fraction of my position might
affect it
all right so it went there let's break
it one more time
go through at the exact same spot and
see if that works
um and if not i'll experiment with a few
other things
i hate breaking it every time come on
this is efficiency five pick and haste
two so this is as quick as you can break
it
and it still seems so slow all right
so we're gonna go through again exactly
the same position when we go
go through the portal and see if that's
what determines it
so i want to line right in the corner
again
okay 88.3 12.3
and you know what i can't remember where
it spawned last time
i'm gonna check the the recording i i
know it spawned there once i don't know
if it was
their last time i think it spawned here
actually now that i think of it last
time
uh-huh chicken get out of here you're
gonna wreck science
the experiment we're doing here don't
contaminate our field
um so i checked the video and
even though i went through the exact
same spot in the nether every time it
shows a random spot
each time uh to put the
nether portal so we can't control it
that way we're gonna try control it by
obstructing where it can spawn hopefully
pressure plates will do that we'll see
if it breaks them
i'm trying to target this area here and
there might not be enough pressure
blades
we'll see
this is a learning experience hopefully
the chickens stay away
not that they would affect it but still
yeah we're gonna line into the corner
every time though
just for consistency
oh all right we might need more pressure
plates
okay i have another idea for a test
from what i've noticed the portal always
seems to
spawn at four blocks that are at the
same height level
like if they're all together
but it won't for example spawn like here
here here and here because two of these
are up two of them are down
um i'm guessing i'm guessing this is
just what i've noticed
while doing this so i kind of broke this
up in such a way that i think
no four blocks are together
could be wrong i kind of did it randomly
so i might have missed a few
but let's try this out these are the
only four together in the middle
pretty sure like it can't spawn here i
don't think because
that's down this is up these are down
these pressure plant
pressure plants pressure plates count
those full blocks too for example so
this one's down
this is up this is down this is up this
is up this is up this is down up
down up you know um
anyway let's just try it see what
happens i'm probably gonna have a hard
time to tell
for sure until i review the video though
all right here we go
it spawned outside of my uh range here
darn it
uh that's the other question is how far
can it spawn away from its target spot
hmm
man this is gonna be tough
um
all right i might try this one more time
uh-huh so i managed to replicate a
glitch i did once
a long time ago and i wasn't able to
reproduce it
but uh check this out
that portal's off that portal's off that
one's off we're going to go through this
one it's going to close behind itself
like it does every time
where do you think the new portal is
going to be this is a trick question now
going to be
we'll check it out
oh it didn't work darn it
oh man
i'm gonna try it one more time that
might have been a fluke
i think what happens or the way it works
by the way i think it tries to place the
portal several hundred times
and it keeps trying until it finds a
spot that's acceptable
and clearly the heights has to be the
same for all four blocks that's why it's
not
going anywhere here anymore it seems to
prefer
the center of where it's supposed to go
which seems to be about there and you'll
notice every time it's placing it just
outside of my perimeter here where i've
put torches in
and junk to block it it's not like
placing it way out here for example
so that's kind of interesting but let's
try to do this glitch
i wanted to show it
i did it twice in a row and now it's not
working
all right come on
and nope okay i'll tell you what the
glitch is i guess
basically i went through the portal and
it took me to
this one here except the portal was out
it teleported me here even though the
portal was broken
which is a very rare rare thing but it
can happen i'm not sure why
um i can't seem to do it again
okay it just happened three times in a
row i'm gonna try to show it one more
time
so all these portals are out it's
teleporting me to that one
let's see if we can do it again
three in a row it's better than the last
time
okay let's go back through
there we go check it out teleport me
here even though there's no portal and
it's broken
it's pretty weird
so that glitch is happening just about
every
time now actually um
i'm appearing there right now i think
what happens
it tries a certain number of times to
place a portal
if it doesn't find a proper spot in all
those tests
for all those tries i think it just
takes you to the last one you went
through
if it's in memory
oh it took us here
i can almost guarantee we will go
through or we'll end up here even though
i just broke it
it's pretty interesting
very oddly though it hasn't spawned once
in that target area
so i don't know why that is yeah there
we are
it hasn't spawned here once
so for some reason i don't think it's
seen as a proper spot either
all right here we go again
yeah same spot again so i guess i can
kind of control it
and predict it but it's not like uh i
was hoping
anyway i got enough obsidian for today
i'll think about this some more
uh let's head back to the man cave and
check on wilson
oh no
wilson got sick guys like he must have
got sick right when we left he's almost
he's almost dead man
um oh no
oh i got some medicine here good that's
weird have to go make some
feel better wilson
ah there we go we definitely gotta
change the face though to the
the health because he's almost dead and
he's happy so that
that's not quite right um
it's gonna be really tough to change
that over those problem
uh he's underweight his happiness is
down he's starving to death
oh man when he gets sick all three of
his uh stat points drain
quickly so
yeah he's not doing so well what's
he's he's at three right now on his age
i'm gonna give him some cookies that'll
be good for his weight and also
for his hunger and his happiness
all right because cookies
they make them a little fatter than
steak
um and he's got a long ways to go to
recover though
a little worried and this isn't uh
boosting his happiness as much as i
thought
come on wilson you can bounce back we
believe in you
all right at this point oh his weight
went up
good happiness hasn't gone up yet though
i've given them a lot of cookies
all right hunger is at
four
hmm
well if we stay here long enough his
happiness will go up
oh i think it i heard something
i don't know what that was let's give
him one more that's a lot of cookies
wilson
all right let's just stand here for a
while he might he might become happy
just
from us being around i guess so i have
picked out
two comments for today's episode uh the
first one says
hey etho i was just wondering have you
ever played pokemon and if so do you
still
play it keep up the good work
i played pokemon red that was the first
one i played right when it came out
on the original game boy uh
i think i got just about all the pokemon
in it
i really liked pokemon it was an awesome
game
uh then after that i think on the game
boy advance i got pokemon
emerald and some somewhere in between
that i also played
game boy emulators on my computer and i
think i played a few pokemon on that
i remember i got pokemon snap for the
n64
which isn't really a pokemon game um
yeah that was kind of a weird game i
think i got that though because it was
the first
like 3d pokemon game and i wanted to see
it
um yeah
played it quite a bit uh haven't played
all the versions though
and i don't really have a game boy
anymore like i don't have it i never got
a gameboy ds
never got uh the new 3d game boy
so i haven't played too many pokemon
games but i enjoyed the ones i did play
come on wilson cheer up
number two you should put in a secret
room inside your library
yes this is a great idea i think we're
gonna have
a few secret things in the library
libraries they need to have like secret
passages and that kind of stuff
otherwise it's not really it's not a
good library without some secrets
hidden around uh the question is should
i show you guys or should i leave it up
to you to find it later
if i ever release a world download i
wonder
hmm give him one more cookie
i thought his happiness would have went
to five
maybe we should check on the snowman
he's still there you see i can see his
head
looks like he's kind of stuck though
doesn't it
oh he is stuck okay
um i'll have to look into that later i
guess
that's why his happiness isn't going up
okay
well i think that's going to be it for
today guys
i hope you enjoyed today's episode and i
will try to keep
wilson alive between now and the next
one
now that his health is down low he's
more likely to get sick
and uh if he gets sick he's gonna die
very quickly especially with his health
so low so i have to really keep an eye
on him
until he bounces back is the way it
works
anyway all in good fun i hope you
enjoyed the episode and i will see you
in the next one
have a good day bye bye everyone
you