well hello everyone this is etho and not
that that's evil
this is etho and we are at the village
right now I came here I wanted to see
like if we could get some more villagers
but these guys are really antisocial or
do you go out of his house
they're like staying in their houses
it's daytime and they can go outside I
don't know
there you go that's how you do it
good job it's about time and it's almost
sunset by the time you finally left this
house anyway out while I'm here I
thought I'd do a little project you know
so I can keep the village loaded while
I'm here Oh seriously come on I was way
way way way way weight ways away from
there ah
sad thing is this is oh oh yeah they can
leave now they won't leave their houses
what am I worried about they're gonna
stay inside all day um yeah this is
actually where I wanted to build the
thing I wanted to build and now it's
blown up so one second while I fix this
I got this portal there I want to move
that and put in a proper place so figure
I'm going to build a portal room for it
over here kind of like a gate to the
village I want that gravel so that's the
plan we're going to put it two rates
were these three fences are I think well
that's where the entrance to the portal
room is going to be let's do that for
now I'm going to get some more fences
once set in while I finish repairing
that alrighty then let's make this a
take - so I wanted to make a portal room
for the
village move that out of there into it
and I figured I'd build a date for it as
well kind of get for the village and
we'll put that here I was going to do a
three by three piston door
I made one another day that I really
liked so I'll I'll try that out I when I
built it originally I used sandstone so
we'll see what that looks like first but
we might want to change that because
there's no sandstone in this village as
much as I love it
you can always use it even when you want
to so yeah I really like this design
basically what I did is I had stairs in
the corners I use these for the middles
and just the second
oops I'm not using the right blocks even
I use the creeperface ones there we go
and I'm just going to build off on the
side here get this flipped like so and
one more over there that's the basic
look of the door it you know I like the
ones I don't know why I actually prefer
the ones with the hole in the middle and
they're a lot easier to build so that's
what we're doing it kind of makes an X
shape just for now we'll put up our
beams on the sides this is what it looks
like when it's closed I should say so
just do this for now get a frame for it
hop over to the other side do the same
thing
this thing is actually fairly easy to
wire it's not much to it
oops
nope well we might change this up anyway
so that's our basic door that we want to
make the way I would did it before is I
put just rip up the whole door after we
laid it out here what I did is I put
pistons on the sides three of them no
let's go further right no that was right
three pistons on the sides do that for
both sides that takes care of those and
I had one on the top so gotta go higher
no that's right right there one there
and then also one down below here like
that so those are all the Pistons we
need to move the eight blocks and to
wire them it's fairly simple what I did
see should we use these galaxies those
for the wiring okay so I have it where's
my redstone and torches we need torches
okay
also yeah I brought these for just add
some more life to the let's see if we
get some chicken stock there we go
hopefully they stay inside so I think I
went down one torch there and then oops
redstone above so that takes care of the
three pistons do that for this one as
well
okay so that's six Pistons then
reconnects I ran the wiring up below
actually let's do it on this side this
will be our main side this is going to
be a one-way door I figure so we want
the villagers to go from the portal room
into the village but we don't want them
to go from the village into the portal
room
yeah then see what do we do
think mmm I'm very forgetful how did I
do that I think I had yeah as blocks
running here I remember them encircling
the piston and I had a redstone torch
below that the wire kind of wraps around
like that and somehow yeah I just need
to make it go directly to that block and
that's pretty much all there is to it I
got too much junk don't I think I do
that and one more over here
okay so that goes the torch and then up
there do the same for this side where's
my soil just I can't have empty spaces
underground it bugs me I really got to
throw waste on this junk though so I
gotta fill this in or drive me crazy
just like that's I think this is right
okay let's get up
oh you know what I'm doing I'm breaking
my gravel blocks and that's becoming
Flint's and that's where all the Flint's
going and to add to the troubles I'm
going to introduce a lever into my
inventory let's just try this out okay
so that retracts seven Pistons all in
the same same tick then we got to get
one to the top still and sadly I did not
come up with a super fancy way of doing
that what I did is right put a half slab
here half slabs are awesome for redstone
by the way if you if you're not used to
using them they are really cool what you
can do with okay go on a little redstone
dad tangent here something really cool
you can do with them is you can run a
staircase up kind of like you can with
glowstone so if we whoops if we do this
and put redstone dust on that it'll go
all the way up so just just a quick
tangent here there so if we power this
it can climb up the staircase like that
right it doesn't go down no which is
interesting
so we powered from above it won't go
down the staircase it only only goes up
so JC didn't know that that's a pretty
handy way of doing redstone and that's
what I did with this door although I
have to make it come out an extra block
which I don't really like with the way I
have it here there might be a better way
of doing it I didn't spend a whole lot
of time on it though that comes out over
to there actually we should be using
maybe sandstone kind of slabs that
doesn't matter too much
and basically I this runs up to the
piston on the top like so and there we
go so that's all eight Pistons I believe
they all go together so that's that's
pretty cool so I'm going to fill this in
a little bit and might continue it all
right it very good so this is the door
it's wired here's the demonstration of
it working pretty sleek I like it
we can even see the Sun when the door is
closed you know I liked it
okay I'll tell you why I like the ones
with the hole in the middle they keep
the mobs out still you can see what's on
the other side so it's kind of like
having a glass door hey guy but also
there's a way to go through without the
mobs being able to go through using
enderpearls OOP that was weird so yeah
that's why I like the ones with the hole
in the middle so I was thinking about
how I'm going to finalize this and I
decide I want to have pressure plates on
this side and I want buttons like this
on this side okay and I even have a wire
right now but you can see if I press a
button it opens and then it closes I got
to hook up a T flip-flop to this as well
so it it will stay open if I hit the
button and then it'll close if I hit it
again or if I walk over the pressure
plates it'll open and stay open and
close if I walk back over them so that's
the idea but I had I had a new idea of
how to wire it that's a little bit
bizarre but I think it'll work out
pretty good so since I don't want to
spend the whole episode on the door
alone I'm going to just go ahead and do
it and I'll show you afterwards when I
got it done
if it works well there we go guys it is
done and best of all it works
hahaha so I'll give you a quick
run-through of its there's actually a
few tricks I want to point out to you
that I used here first of all there's no
more redstone torches they're too slow I
don't like them we got rid of them
actually they wouldn't work for what I
have planned I don't think so
Oh actually maybe they would have well
either wait it's faster without them so
we got rid of them here's a quick
demonstration SuperDuper fast very cool
and I have it all open up still so you
can see the wiring and over here with
the buttons again very quick I'm going
to hold right click on it just so you
can see how quick it can all go that's
pretty cool
so first trick I kind of all kind of
trick first kind of cool thing I did
here I had to connect this wire and this
wire together right so what I did is I
went below the piston and since a piston
is a block that doesn't cut the power
it's able to connect down below here but
I also have to power the piston and
thankfully since this wire is still
pointing at it it does that as well so
it's like killing - killing three birds
really with one stone alright so wanted
to connect them wanted power well maybe
two words whatever so that's kind of
cool I also used two T flip-flops in
this believe it or not which allows me
to do something neat which I'll show you
in a second but I set this up just to
help you understand how it works
there's a really cool trick you can do
in Minecraft for making a monostable
circuit which is a circuit that allows
you to control the timing of a pulse so
normally with if you press a button it
lasts for a second but if I think it's a
second still maybe they changed it who
knows but with this little do
gee it's very simple just a sticky
piston and a block and a repeater or
yeah so if you press that it's this
repeater only goes on for one tick I'll
set up another piston so you can see it
and if we want we can extend that that
would make it two ticks the pulse this
would make it three ticks you can see
it's kind of slowing down for ticks
before this only used to be a
directional trick but with the recent
patches it now works pretty reliably
I've noticed so that's what I've been
using for my T flip-flops actually so
I'll show you how that works there's a
trick with pistons if you only power it
for one tick it will leave a block
behind so there so even though it's a
sticky piston it doesn't retract and it
does that so if we put a redstone torch
below this it's effectively a redstone
or a T flip-flop I don't have a light or
anything so we'll just use this to show
you when the repeaters on the circuit is
on what's off it's off so that's kind of
how I did the TTIP flops here this
pressure plate or these pressure plates
they go down here and this is my
monostable circuits and it goes to my
door wiring which connects to all the
Pistons and same with on the other side
here I'm going to spend the whole day on
this door I didn't want to but that's
how it's going so over here same thing I
got another one of those they're
independent of each other which is
important for what I what I've done here
and that goes to this bottom part below
the piston and connects to the main part
of the door so where is the D flip-flop
you may ask it's the whole door
kind of so when those Pistons extends
you'll notice that the pistons aren't
extended right now even though the
blocks are out so it leaves the whole
door behind all eight Pistons so I
thought that was kind of cool since
these are independent it also allows us
to do something kind of cool if it
allows us to make a locking mechanism
for the door so if I have I can have a
button on one side and a lever on the
other side
all right control it with the lever
oh yeah every up and down is only one
pulse I was like why is it going so slow
those fast doors fast but if this is
powered wait yeah we can we can lock it
so that this button won't open it
anymore we can also lock it the other
way I guess so if if we pulse it one
time now we can't close it so we can do
that the other thing is if we go to the
other side though even though it's
locked right now check this out right
through the donut hole
I like the donuts to have the hole in
the middle to just just putting that out
there I like the more than the the
cream-filled ones okay we can still open
it on this side even though it's locked
on this side and it's raining so anyway
that's my door enough about the door I
got I'm going to fill it in and and we
should try to design a little look for
it to hide all the pistons and stuff if
there's time we might just go do
something else I don't know you know
it's kind of kind of triangle-shaped
isn't it so there's there's something I
used on the blaze the dual blades firm
on the minecraft server that I really
like I think I'll try it out here
it's a checker checker ish pattern and
since it's for high that works out
really well and then over here okay just
connect these although I don't mmm don't
want that let's put a stair this way I
think I should change this with wood
though to be honest sandstone just
doesn't really do it justice
look another sand stone there just
actually kind of hard to see detail with
all the sandstone do something like that
that's not bad
I almost feel like I should do something
with this corner block like maybe maybe
maybe maybe a glowstone lamp or
something in the corners that I also got
to hide the pista on the top don't I
I could put hmmm I don't think I could
put glowstone lamps on the top here
without interfering with with this
piston so I might have to put glowstone
i'd i'd i brought some with me i think
let's just try this out see what this
looks like
whee whoa whoops i think if we did
something like this it might be kind of
cool and half slabs on the top too bulky
maybe but not too bad that would look a
lot better if it was lamp still one in
it hmm the hides a piston how could i
power that mm I don't think I could put
a lever here no I don't know I might
mess with around with it some other time
ah the important thing about the store
is you can run through it though without
getting stopped that's cool
all right well enough with the door
still got to build the portal room I
might do that on my own I did want to
show you guys one more thing the river
I've done some work on that so let's
head over there and just check see if
these guys did anything they're both
kind of avoiding each other aren't they
I haven't seen any little villagers so
I'm guessing looks like they're miles
apart
so lonely um yeah I'm guessing they
didn't do anything too bad I've been
here for Oh at least 30 minutes to an
hour and we are here welcome to the
river amazing scenic wonderful place
we've been trying to create so I planted
some more trees and I put vines on most
of them they still are in the middle of
growing I've also put sugarcane around
some and I've grown grass maybe got
carried away with the grass a little bit
but it's pretty sweet
you can see that the vines are still
working at growing oh yeah you know what
mmm maybe we'll do it next time I was
thinking putting a waterfall that kind
of came down here never did that I was
supposed to do that today I forgot uh
but yeah it's I think it's pretty sweet
oh did I hit anything even I don't think
I did don't think I did to be honest I
made a second one okay I did not place
that very well um I see a boat down
there drifting away okay I'm still in
the boat it seems I don't know what's
going on because I can't enter prom now
um so my ride is getting away from me
even though I'm in it what happens if I
click this I do not click it what if I
break it I cannot break it to either
hmmm okay this is not going how I
thought it would
I'm going to have to reload yes once I
can okay let's hope everything is okay
now hey there's the other boat so I I do
have both out now so yeah we'll take one
more ride down our little river here I
still need to add glowstone glowing
trees or some kind of lighting for
nights
what else was I going to do the
waterfall and there was one more thing I
can't remember now you got a replace I
still never put stone on over or in the
tunnel area I never put stone there is
that creeper going to get us you think
now it's got better things to do
and so yeah mobs constantly swim up here
his there's a ravine below that the
water goes to oh no no I like how the
the vines kind of go in your face now oh
I know what I was going to do it's going
to show you where else I wanted to make
the river connects so yeah I got to put
stone on the ceiling there still but it
comes out here so where is that do you
think I can find it over this way
there's some more mountains this way
let's see if we'll go on a little
adventure here I think it was pretty
close so I at the very edge of the
glowing trees where I stopped putting
them there's there's a place I want to
modify and I don't think I get through
there ooh I reckon a little billy pads
maybe we'll get out of the boat it'll
probably be faster
I think we're within range yeah there it
is just loading right now kind of slow
to go over this way there's another big
swamp area let's get up high so we can
see just saw this today so at glowing
trees glowing trees glowing trees then I
didn't do over there those aren't
glowing trees and also the river it kind
of comes out over here bends around
and then it dead-ends and then there's
dry dry land here and then there's a big
water area here that kind of comes out
and then dead ends so I want to connect
that with that and make it run through
there yep all right uh okay yeah that's
what that's the plan anyway so yeah I
know you guys are thinking I've been at
level 30 pretty much the whole episode
here so would be very cruel of me not to
enchant something before we end it so
we're going to read the comments so the
comment I picked up for today says yo do
you ever think you will finish all your
projects and run out of stuff to do in
this world um from history I can tell
you that's probably not going to happen
I tend to come up with ideas faster than
I get them finished in my world so I'm
more likely to have lots of unfinished
projects but lots of lots of ideas for
projects so I don't think I'm gonna get
bored if anything I'm just going to
become a tee otic mess which I'm trying
to avoid but you are you are what you
are I couldn't do that I'm not that mean
so here we go for real what are we gonna
get something bad because I was mean oh
yes very good see I'm a nice guy the
game thinks so but anyways that's it for
today guys I hope you enjoyed today's
episode and I will catch you again next
time thank you for watching
you