[Music]
hello hello
how's it going everyone this is etho and
welcome back to another episode of the
let's play series
i want to try something here i got my
fireworks i've got my chorus fruit
let's fly so i think
i think if we uh eat the chorus fruit up
in the air we'll get teleport to the
ground right
yeah but i did take damage
let's try that again but this time let's
fall a little bit
that was kind of weird i did like a jump
there almost
oh i'm using way too many fireworks too
okay let's fall for a little bit and
then
you know i i knew that was going to
happen kind of but it didn't really kick
in until it just happened
why did i do that okay let's uh let's do
a couple experiments here i want to see
if there's
different ways of taking off from the
water because that's a bit of an issue
if you're in the middle of the ocean
you might have trouble flying out of it
um so i know if you fly into the water
like if you activate your wings first
and you're in the water you do this sort
of swimming animation
and then yeah you can use the firework
anytime you want
but if you just like walk into the water
or you
touch the bottom of the the ocean then
you're in the standing position and when
you're in this
position i don't think you can activate
oh you can okay
if you're really lucky maybe
i've tried it before spamming space bar
and right click right now
is really how did i do that
oh man it is possible okay it's really
tough to do though
really tough to do you gotta get the
timing just perfect and then if you
spam spacebar right click you can
probably do it okay another thing i
wanted to try though is the boats
um if we get a boat we can probably
activate the wings before we hit the
water
yeah there we go so then we could fly
out
ouch can we uh just use a water budget i
wonder or
a bucket so if we spam space bar
oh
no i can't activate the wings that way
okay a lot of you guys also want me to
try out our little uh tunnel here
no no i don't think it's gonna work
because
we have to be in the air to use the
fireworks and this is just the right
amount of space where
well unless we fall between a flowerpot
oh nope
nope
that's pretty sweet
i'm a dolphin
[Applause]
yeah lego boss
okay i gotta jump activate the wings
firework fishing rod yeah
should be possible
the manly stream it's a manly stream i
tell you
i did it i did it
oh man that was awesome yeah so it is
possible that that's pretty crazy
you can move players now with a fishing
rod so that's like the ultimate way
of trolling your friends on a server if
for some reason they don't have wings
you can like fly by pick them up and
then drop them
that's pretty crazy you know actually
you can probably
if you got really good at it you could
probably juggle somebody even
like pick them up in midair again and
keep like
tossing them
i got him that's pretty easy to do
juggling them is a whole nother story
though
oh now we're using our noggins here
this might actually be a really good way
of moving animals if we use leads
the thing about the fishing rods is once
you get too far away
like it doesn't actually pull the animal
right or the the mob
and if you get too far away it just
breaks the connection
yeah it's broken so leads
let's see if we can use the firework
with the lead like with the fishing rod
you can't
even if you go into offhand
it activates the fishing rod first
unless what if you switch it
now even still why does it always
activate the fishing rod first
well anyways let's try with the lead so
we got the lead and then the
firework we got a lot of things active
right now wait a second
wait a second
okay here we go nope
oh but if you move too fast with the
lead it breaks doesn't it
that's right hmm
is there a way around that okay i
managed to get one flight here so
we'll try it again i think we got to
figure out what angle and when to
activate the firework
i think that's the key to this now this
is really uh
really useful let's say you got to move
mushrooms back to your home or something
this is a way to do it quickly not
necessarily safely
get back here so
let's go into this camera view this is
the way i did it before look straight up
if we fly straight up it seems to work
pretty good
oh oh
oh well that was short-lived why didn't
it activate again
i think i pressed i think i pressed it
again but i
couldn't fly anymore okay how about you
good sir come with me good sir
he's still with us and then we lost them
so i think i might have activated the
fireworks too
frequently there we'll try to slow it
down a bit more
okay come with me good sir
and oh i did
i did too so you still with me still
with me oh and then
and then no we're still good now if we
fly sideways oh we lost them darn it
hmm
i know there's a way to do it you just
got to figure out the timings
to the fireworks and the right angle to
the flight
i'm sure of it
once you level out stays with us but as
soon as i activated another firework i
think that's it
yeah we can't just activate another
firework we have to like
we have to like turn around and use one
and then quickly turn back
just so we don't accelerate super
quickly all at once
hey you can't pull a squid out of water
yeah why don't we just do this use one
firework to to make him fly
and as long as you're safe like this
he's not really is he gonna die as soon
as he hits the ground is that the
is that the idea he won't if we land in
water
but that might be hard to plan is he
gonna die
i think he died he died hmm
that works pretty good
whoa ouch
oh i don't belong here
oh boy
oh it's awesome
yes this is the big moment guys this is
what we trained for
i found a pack of llamas we're going to
start up
llama airlines um which way is it
this way not that way we gotta go 2 500
blocks to get home
so this is going to be a real test i
want to try to keep them alive if we can
yeah this is the way okay so
hopefully this goes okay
now i only can use one firework rocket i
was not able to find a way to
consistently use more than one
this seems pretty safe though
okay then we level out
why did my camera view change that's not
good for me
i can't see them i don't even know if i
have them
oh no what
what
did you see that they like oh you know
what i think i'm generating new terrain
that's what happened
ah that sucks
did they die what happened
hmm
[Music]
i don't know what happened to them let's
investigate
if we can what do they drop when they
die is it leather
or is it voice crack is it uh
or do they even drop anything i'm not
sure
what i was even going that fast
oh that's bogus where am i
yeah if you are using fireworks in brand
new terrain that has to generate and
it's amplified and laggy
you better watch yourself you better
watch it
because come on don't kill me don't do
it don't kill me
yeah it doesn't seem to work right
so i'm hunting for more llamas right now
but i got distracted by this
check this out this is really cool it
goes all the way up to the sky you got
walls all around you it's almost like
the inside of a volcano
or something without the lava inside the
lake down here
all kinds of cool caves and spiky
formations
i don't know i thought it was pretty
neat
okay watch this watch this look how long
this firework lasts for
this is what happens when you go to new
terrain and it's laggy
so the fireworks are client-side so if
the client can't keep up the firework
never stops
so if i run into any ground jeering
that's
lag it's gonna kill me that i think
that's what happened before
the firework got stuck on and then i hit
the ground or something
really quickly i found a polar bear
not quite what i was looking for but i
do need a polar bear
hi there let's go for a ride wait which
way are we going
this way and this way yes okay so it's
about
over 2500 blocks this time
see if we can do it oh no
what oh we might not be able to pull
polar bears
why can't you pull polar bears let's try
it again
and now he's
he's like a brick he doesn't want to
come with me
okay okay we got one more shot at this
i found another pack of llamas here
finally i have traveled so far they're
so
few and far apart in my world here i
don't know why
but uh let's see if we can get him back
i let that area generate for quite a
while so hopefully lag isn't a
big issue let's look at the sun sun
isn't really jumping is it
seems fine yeah okay
i'm gonna try it no no no no
i did a dud jump are you serious it
happens every now and then
and it kills the animals like every time
no they're still here they're still here
okay yeah they got a little bit more
health than like uh pigs and
and sheep and stuff don't they okay
let's try this again
oh man i just want to get these guys
home safely
which way are we going again i lost i
lost my bearings it's this way isn't it
yeah and that way okay seriously
please
okay no dead jump this time oh but they
broke off
they broke off on their own
maybe you can't move llamas
because like the sheep in that they they
would never break off let's just do one
at a time i'm
i'm being greedy here one at a time
yeah maybe because they're a heavier
animal i don't know
okay one at a time seems a lot safer
if you fly above 256 i think that's when
your camera view changes
oh i might be going too fast slow down
slow down
okay i still can't look back oh maybe i
can now
i can we lost them ah man
i might have been going too fast for a
moment there i'm not sure
this is not easy though it might just be
better to move on through a
through another portal unless it's
something easy like pigs and cows and
stuff
sure if they die it's no big deal but
llamas
i don't know
okay we got one we got one
i'm gonna go nice and slow
i broke off okay
so i have concluded probably not gonna
be able to get a llama back that way
because i i keep passing into new chunks
and then it lags
and then the llama detaches that's
that's just what happens
but are you ready for this i think we
should do a dragon fight
and see what it's like now that we can
fly very easily um
i'm gonna want some tnt ready and
should be everything this should be a
really easy fight cause
i'm i'm sure you're faster than the
dragon right
oh and can we do these already i think
we can right no
whoa i got night vision on
that might have been a mistake i never
know if i should use it
holy smoke could you be quieter thank
you
all right let's take care of the
crystals first
yeah i can't see anything with this
night vision this is terrible
what was i thinking
boom
yeah night vision not the best choice
got it okay for these gauged ones i want
to try to use tnt
let's put like a piece of tnt on it and
then shoot it
should work right
hopefully and
cabalzis
so i let the night vision run out here
because just couldn't see anything with
it
um i'm finding though
going melee on the dragon isn't as good
as you might think
because whenever you get near the dragon
you get like knocked back
and damaged and because i'm wearing
elijah wins my armor is not so great
oh run away run away
oh no no no fly you stupid jerk
really that sucked
okay i'm just gonna try like chase chase
them with a bow
it's probably a lot better than melee
[Music]
right seems better and then if he lands
then
did the sound go up again
and let's jump in
jump and chop that's probably the way to
go
okay took off and then whoa flew right
into him by a mistake
chase him with the bow this was really
good for getting rid of the crystals
like i got rid of the crystals in less
than two minutes i think
and normally you have to wait for them
to like land again before you attack
this way you can
keep the pressure on although you do got
to be careful
definitely gotta be careful still
and kapow
i feel like i die every single ender
dragon fight i do some in some stupid
way
all right and he killed my flower pots
really
they were so beautiful now they're gone
you know what it just occurred to me
like i always use instant health potions
when i do a dragon fight or a wither
fight
and golden apples are so much better
aren't they
so we're down to four and a half hearts
instant health two wow that's four
hearts isn't it
okay maybe it's not super bad i thought
it was only three hearts
four and a half yeah golden apple though
it gives you two hearts it gives you
regen
and it gives you the food saturation
and since we did the dragon fight we
should probably do the wither fight to
be complete i had some people
request i try out that don't touch the
ground challenge again
i want to see if i can place this as i
fly by
i did yes awesome all right so
can't touch the ground had trouble doing
this with the punch bow before because
uh actually we probably don't need that
just yet let's take one of these though
the issue with the punch bow was i
couldn't couldn't melee him
yeah come attack me
oh he's up there what oh i almost
touched the ground
you can see when your uh your hearts run
low
nice and easily hey you above you
it's uh yeah it's actually a little hard
to keep keep on
here hmm
like i'm too fast oh
what am i doing okay
but hmm
i just need this isn't working so good
like i gotta look up to shoot them and
then i fall
because he always he always goes right
above you it's so annoying
why did they design them like that i
don't know
oh it's fine we didn't touch the ground
uh
technicalities
boom two hits
he's being good though he's just like
kind of sitting there because i'm doing
this over water
like he waits for me to return every
time oh halfway point
okay okay strength potion up
and then yeah he's just like sitting
there for me
that's great and
nope firework ran out
ah so hard to land a hit
two hits okay heal up
and
got another hits good
okay what's the trick here what do we do
see like i really felt like i should
have hit him there it's really hard to
hit him for some reason
nope nope
okay there we go there we go two hits
two hits
probably best just to fight the wither
normally i gotta say
okay we got a hit that's kind of a spam
click
yeah you just gotta like sneak up to him
let the firework run out right when you
arrive
and then you can get him
oh i was actually moving pretty fast and
i got him that time
okay just about done at this point he
can't really hurt us it seems like i
haven't been hit in a very long time
here
oh you know what the star is going to
land at the bottom of the water
darn well
oh there goes there goes chase it down
chase it down and
where'd it go i didn't get it
the xp is right here there's a start
right over there
all right guys well we're gonna have to
wrap up the episode here for today i got
a comment picked out which says
eso in 1.11.1 you can now smelt down
gold and iron tools and armor into gold
nuggets
and the new iron nuggets you could try
making a smelting system for your gold
farm
that turns those old junk golden swords
into more nuggets
not chicken nuggets however every sword
only yields one nuggets
you know this was my first reaction to i
thought oh man this is great i'm gonna
get even more gold out of the gold farm
let's try it out here but in reality
this is a really bad thing to do i think
because the gold farm nets you infinite
gold at the expense of time right
um this will get you more gold
in less time it doesn't really cost time
though because it's totally afkable as
well
but this also has the additional expense
of consuming fuel
so you have to use coal or wood or
charcoal or
blaze rods or lava buckets would also
probably be a good one
um getting all those things though the
only one that's
like totally afk able is charcoal or
wood
and yeah my wood farm is totally afk
able
it's a little bit glitchy and it's a
little bit slow so i don't really want
to
waste fuel on something i can get easily
more gold uh-huh let's try out
what what else should we smell can we
smelt a water bucket i wonder
i haven't even tried this out yet oh and
actually as shears and flint and steel
weren't working for a while
i can't remember if it got fixed let's
try those out too
so this should give us an iron nugget i
think
nope can't put oh wait nope
that doesn't work shears shears are no
bueno still
let's try out uh iron budget should work
okay um something should work
i don't know if i have any iron tools i
want to smelt down here even
now we can we can ditch those let's try
out the iron boots i guess
just to try it get my first iron nugget
[Music]
yeah yeah i don't think that's really
worth it it's like a
a cool thing hey you can get iron or
gold if you're in a pinch
but really it's not something you'd want
to do i don't think
it's not worth it you need to smell so
many golden swords or so many
iron things yeah
anyways hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode i had a lot of fun with it
trying out different
tricks and stuff and until next time
thanks for watching
take care bye