hey everyone how's it going
this is etho your best buddy in the
whole wide world
unless you've crossed me in some way if
you crossed me this is Ethel you're your
mortal enemy the worst enemy you've ever
had oday it alright well that brings me
on to my next subject I okay I have
changed the stone down there remember it
was kind of dull I talked about putting
grass there with flowers and stuff
before I don't know why I never did that
so I switched it we have grass we have
flowers
apparently they catch fire so that's a
little scary from the from the lab a guy
down here mm-hmm
don't think flowers burn but I think the
grass does yeah so if we get rid of that
last piece of grass oh where am I going
that's a good sign if you get lost in
your own place right mmm
should I remove that grass darn I had a
whole bunch of grass here it's gone now
I think it's out of range yeah we'll
stick with that
okay next subject
or next topic or next plan or whatever I
brought with me some of these mossy
stone bricks and some of these crap ones
I thought it would be a nice touch to
maybe add a few in this furnace room
hopefully that I don't mess in it mess
up any redstone that's good yeah because
we got the leaves
I'm so worried I'm going to break some
redstone yeah I'm gonna go along and do
that with all these I think let's try
the cracked ones - maybe we'll mix and
match yeah we'll put a few crack ones in
maybe on the walls - I don't know yeah
we'll see what happens here mm-hmm yeah
just roughed it up a little bit I think
that's good
adds a little more character to it I
remember how I had the Pistons and all
that showing before I put up a wall
there so now it's hidden away I would
like to do something with this area
sometime soon but today what I really
want to work on is the sheep farm thing
because you know it's so sad it's it's
very sad I got this all done finally
it's all all working buts this been
sitting not fully functioning because I
don't have the item the item stream set
up now that it's easier to move items up
vertically we could actually do that
fairly easily I think so be a good day
to work on that where is he wants me on
the surface and I also labeled these
buttons finally because I always always
forgot which one is which so the water
reset has a water bucket on and the
manual reset is just empty water bucket
so yeah
i dint idea is if we shear them we can
automatically collect the wool and send
the sheep down the proper sheep down by
precipice it's not it's not perfect
though unfortunately but it's it's
pretty good so will gets washed down the
grates and oh um did this used to work
what happened there none of them went
down what is that wool doing ah man is
it broken that's not good
ah Oh Kate we're a step further away now
an item goes on these pressure plates it
should what that something really weird
is going on with this
like what is that doing you throw an
item down and it like goes like this
for some reason okay right that might be
a bug I don't know what to do now
ah I must have be problems I don't know
I don't think I have my way into that
room anymore either do I maybe this was
it yeah this is it whoa thought I had a
better way of getting in
so obviously the wall didn't fall down
otherwise it would have washed down
these streams so it's like it can't go
through the stairs anymore it's very
strange
I bet you it's because of that whole
items and blocks getting transported
it's considering the stairs as a full
block let's test that idea maybe okay so
this is a setup here we got an upside
down stair before an item used people
pass through that now it seems like
doesn't want to refuses if multiple
items go they get clumped together that
is very strange I pretty sure that's a
bug with the snapshots
well actually this isn't a snapshot is
it I don't know anymore what what the
deal is
let's try a half slab upside down a half
slab
throw an item and it will it's that goes
down this upside down stairs that don't
weird hopefully yeah well you know what
we're gonna work on this today anyway
even despite that because I'm guessing
it's about if it if it's a bug hopefully
it'll get fixed if it if it if it
doesn't get fixed we can always just
change these two half slabs I'm pretty
sure yeah so we will be able to make it
work we just might have to modify things
a little bit so the idea is I want a
room here for the wall like the wall we
get from the Sheep let's just get rid of
these guys because that's fun to do yeah
we're going to make a wool storage room
I've taken the liberty of emptying his
chest a head of time here got a simple
touch so we're gonna clean this out and
what I think we should do dude there was
an egg there and that egg farm is crazy
an egg an egg from below here somehow
made its all the way over to that water
there it's crazy
alright anyway I think we should make it
the walls of this thing from here to
here so it's going to be 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 wide we need storage for the 16 colors
of wool clean that up so and in the
middle I think we should have a
dispenser with shears and just so it's
easy to
you know come here [ __ ] cheers go sheer
drop-off cheers you know hit button get
wool so get rid of this water and I'm
going to start shaping this out what
should it be so we can fit possibly
eight going across here so we'll have to
put four per side if we can fit eight so
we need this to be nine nine wide by at
least four deep I guess that's pretty
much cleared out already isn't it okay
for the floor
we'll try connect that together
oh my inventory is full a hate when that
happens I'm going to drop off some stuff
otherwise it's so hard to build anything
connect that do we want it wood or do we
want it stone I don't know let's try
wood first I'm going to snip a little
bit of this actually so one second
alright check this out guys I was
clearing out the land for this and red
stone for the sheep farm is right here
like right right here and there's some
there so the wall was supposed to go
here so that works out just perfect
cutting it close
cutting it very close so I thought you
know what the sheep farm we got this
line of stone brick going around the
bottom and then wood maybe we should do
that here to see how that goes so one
two three four five might do it like
that I wanted to have a half slabs on
the ground
although I just you can see full blocks
yet there can't you might look a little
weird if we only have half a block
showing and we got to figure out the
layout for the chess and we're going to
tweak this don't worry this is just the
rough layout a rough plan so the thing
with the chess though it's really it's
really hard to have lots of unique items
going in chess because okay well first
of all we should have some kind of thing
there to hide the redstone so we should
actually make this come out at least one
more to count for that and then like to
do chess I think we'd have to stagger
them um just kind of crummy I guess I
don't know that I might use dispensers
because you can put them side by side
downside is you don't have as much
storage and they're they're not really
meant for storage
okay well let's let's trap some wool
varies colors of wool we're trying to
figure out the layouts which how should
we put this so I want to label them too
with the color let's pretend we have a
color wheel going around the top that's
one option
doing it like that let's see what it
looks like when we put the wood in yeah
that would be one possible method I
don't like that at all no let's try
something else
and new noop noop not gonna happen oh I
can tell I'm gonna have a hard time with
this already ah
hmm well I do like that a little bit
more but it's kind of cluttered I don't
know not sure if I'm going to be happy
with how this turns out
can't do that yeah I like it a little
more I think with the wood above -
although I you know what I'll probably
put a pattern in the floor like I have
in my storage room here with the
sandstone probably a sandstone border
outlining the edges and also I would
like to get some leaves maybe in all the
corners okay guys you're gonna have to
let me know what you think of this I
think it's I feel it feels a lot better
now that it's the full room um so we got
we got sixteen chests total five per
side no we don't yeah we do yeah we do
five plus five plus six sixteen and then
we have this year's in the middle the
dish with the dispenser behind the item
frame I put lighting in the corners
glowing pumpkins I got the sandstone
border feels like it's got to be changed
a bit yet though you know what I'm going
to do I'm going to put the proper wool
spectrum in that it'll look better if
it's not just random colors alright
we're getting there we're getting there
seems a little bit better now
I also changed it so that these wood
blocks are actually stairs you can see
just barely
it's stair from this angle so that means
we can open the chest same with the odd
it's trying to collect it I wasn't
trying to break it same with those
blocks I have to go back there and fix
it ah but yeah those are stairs I'd open
all the chests got that going I'm not
liking the leave so so we're going to
get rid of them my new plan is to use
lamps because it also feels a little bit
dark in here it's close to what I want
but not quite so if we get lamps we'll
get rid of the pumpkins just do that
this might be good
and instead you know what else I would
like maybe have out a ring or a kind of
like a half circle of leaves going
around the top here that could look cool
so we'll try that out too how's that you
know that lit up the room a little bit
more doesn't feel too out of place maybe
we want to lamp there too I like it's on
this side if we don't have one there
because then it looks like it connects
from here and goes down mm-hmm so I'm
going to fix that in which I put some
leaves
maybe another line of wood and then a
ceiling oh and also I wanted to try this
to kind of make an X here and who knows
that might look cool the idea of this is
we're going to have the items pop out of
the floor over here so we're going to
run I'm going to run a nice stream these
two sides are going to connect
you're going to go to just below that
and then they're going to pop up with a
little bit of wiring hopefully that's
the plan
where's my sandstone there we go let's
see if we like this
another possibility with the items
popping on the ground we might not be
will have a half slab there so we could
potentially have a lamp there if it
doesn't let us use a half slab and just
have a drop maybe I'm that might be what
we do also I was looking at this and
since we can connect stairs together
maybe we should do that so it looks a
little strange
my other beef is with this the fences
are not connecting to the stairs on both
sides so we should change that to a full
block I think yeah I think that's better
I'm not good with this kind of stuff
guys OOP no I don't want that that's not
going to connect I know there's a trick
to placing them I haven't figured out
how do that though but if you place it a
certain way oh there we go maybe I have
figured out the trick this one's
different to you hmm
nope nope
who anyway I'll fix it up is this good
but I like this
yeah I think that's okay alrighty then I
got that done and this is like the final
review for the episode this is what's
going to sit at unless you know I get
some suggestions on how to change it
that I like one of these look messed up
with the patch I never notice that till
just now I got to fix that okay
yeah final reveal and there we go
so you know I'm actually pretty happy
with that I especially like this the
leaves around the top I think that just
completes the look this middle little
part here I tried that let's try it
without the light I'll just put that
there for now I'll have to go down there
and fix it anyway without the light it
would be like that and without the
sandstone mmm not sure about that yeah I
think it turned out
oh I rotate it I don't want to rotate it
I think it turned out pretty good it
suits the other rooms too like it
matches a style so I'm happy about that
yeah projects sort of done so we just
got to do the the piping here although
yeah you can probably guess on then do
them just gonna run ice and then water
streams with signs to hold the water in
place and such and then we'll bring it
down to over here and I'm guessing I'll
make its hit a pressure plate which will
move a piston which will put the item in
a block and make it go up that's sort of
what I'm thinking of doing although I'm
running out of time today so we did not
get this done today unfortunately not
totally but we are very very very very
close and it's all stuff I think I could
do on my own so cool uh yeah that that
bug with this too is kind of holding me
back so I think I'll wait on that
hopefully it gets fixed and if not I'll
fix I'll I'll switch to half slabs now
we have these little areas here these
things that we need to finish there's
one there and there's one here I thought
you know might be cool if I plant wheat
here change that to dirt hide some water
somewhere plant wheats we'll see what
that looks like
although on this side I have a problem
with the repeaters I don't know what to
do about that these eggs man they're
everywhere
they just pop out of the floor of any
any place they want I gotta fix that
farm so crazy
who knew it would be so tough has me a
little worried about this too that the
wool is not going to fly straight up
it's going all over the place maybe
although it's only four or five blocks
that I got to move it up so it can't
scatter too far from that yeah I went
through here and I did some cleanup so I
got rid of the chests that were in the
way I changed this door I don't know if
you notice this but I used to have
through torches here well there and I
had some Pistons that were letting light
through down there now I got lamps and
they light up a lot better I don't know
they really fit but seems to be a better
better way of lighting place for sure
because without them it drops below a
light level eight here so mobs could
potentially spawn which is a bad thing
actually I noticed here too there's a
level level seven spot right there which
is a little bit of a problem but yeah I
got the wheats on this side I think it's
a pretty good addition and I want to do
it over here but we have the repeater
but I was looking at it and I might be
able to move that thankfully this door
design wasn't all that compact so I can
tweak it a little bit I think if I
remove this ah nuts it opens or goes to
there hmm because what I want to do is
put that over there and then move the
repeater in one more block
like that then we could seal that up but
now we have the problem that we
infiltrate the other side I know I know
use the hotties I use the hotkeys there
quicker there and I checked its it's
bright enough over there that moms won't
spawn that's good door still works move
it left a little bit there did it huh
now we got that showing always another
problem well simple fix would just be
put some stairs there instead that would
actually look better too I think because
it's it's like really wide and low
that's that's probably what I'll do you
cool so we got a bit done today I think
we're gonna go to read the go to reading
in the comments and we'll call it an
episode let's do it I picked out three
comments for today number one East Oh
what is your favorite Block in vanilla
minecraft PS look wise not redstone hmm
so I can't use TNT either huh
I would have to say it's a tie between
very green grass and sandstone next
question hey etho what's with the
delayed video uploads lately don't rush
perfection no um honestly I'm a little
bit addicted to feed the beast actually
pretty much all the mine trackers on our
I would say they're on it all the time
I'm on it all the time
the only things I've really been doing
lately is feed the beast and my let's
play I've kind of been neglecting
playing on the minecraft server and
doing the arena game normally I I work a
little bit on everything every
but I'm sure the diction will pass as do
most things usually and also like I had
it scheduled where if I upload two
videos a day everything work out fine
and so some some days I have two videos
but then there'll be a day where there's
nothing or there's only one and what
happened is I either I like was what
happened is I decided to take a day off
basically and my upload slowed down so
yeah I need a break every now and then
number three hey Eve so I was just
wondering what are your thoughts on
texter pet what your thoughts on texture
packs are in my opinion the default is
my favorites I'd like to hear your
opinion sincerely a fellow minecrafter
you know what I
I really like the normal texture pack I
have no problem with the other ones
though like I won that always caught my
eye was the faithful thirty to one
and also I've always been tempted to
modify it my grass file modify my grass
file to make the grass generally more
green not totally green but just a bit
more green but you know that one of the
challenges of Minecraft I feel is making
stuff look good with what you got
so for that reason I have no intention
of adjusting the texture pack at all the
other thing is since I'm doing YouTube I
want people to know what the blocks do
and the one texture patch everybody's
familiar with is the default one so
that's why I use that if I if I ever if
I didn't do the YouTube thing I'm sure I
would have tried out texture packs by
now but yeah that's basically the dealio
with that
okay guys well I hope you have a great
day I'm gonna get going here and I'll
see you again next time
oh man I forgot again I keep meaning to
mention this but people are asking about
the world download I I will release
another one soon I could do it today but
I don't know if you guys know this but I
like to hide Easter eggs in my world and
I haven't gotten around to adding a new
one so that's hold up but hopefully in
an episode or two I'll get a new
download ready for you guys okay bye