[Music]
don't let them pet them but hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode of my let's play
series today a little bit special this
is episode number 300 which is
absolutely positively incredible I can't
believe it I have been doing this for a
long time I think this is one of the
longest-running minecraft series
actually I thought about that today yeah
I've been doing this for quite a few
years and you guys have been great
throughout the time giving me lots of
supports and I really appreciate it
and of course even though we're 300
episodes in the format hasn't changed a
whole lot with my series and still
having a lot of a lot of fun with this
game so that's great
of course updates help too they can help
to keep things fresh
but yeah 300 episodes so for today I
wanted to do something a little special
and if you're looking at the episode
title it's a bit of a spoiler we are
going to be building the ender ender 2.0
so this is the original ender ender
right up here built this don't want to
look at you guy don't want to look at
you or any of your friends built this a
long time ago over over a year maybe
year and a half maybe even two years I
can't remember it seems like a long time
though it still works really good
actually but wouldn't hurt to have an
update on my Enderman firm design and I
was gonna actually build let's actually
start walking cuz it's a bit of a ways I
want sure you had to get to it
I actually was planning to build this
ender ender 2.0 on the minecraft server
it's an idea I've had for a while but
the day I was actually looking into it
and trying to figure out if it would
work or not was the day the Enderman
farm got built on there just by
coincidence
so Oh No
yeah well okay so I decided instead I'm
gonna build in my single-player world
for my 300th episode and I've designed
it already in creative this was actually
a big big very ambitious project I
wanted my 300th episode to to build
something and I wanted it to be sort of
memorable something I would use wanted
it to be ambitious and hopefully
something other people will find useful
as well
oops so I thought an Enderman farm would
be good for that too so we'll head on
over to the build site I haven't built
it yet or anything we're gonna do that
today and try to get it all done and
then we can play around with it test it
out that kind of thing and later I might
even make it to toriel on it if I don't
if people want something a little more
concise than this episode because it's
gonna be hard to Dokken and record this
all very very quickly but yeah this is
our road off from the island oh I forgot
to put water down that's fine sticking
it back
I built this stained glass road to get
to it
with this arrow pattern isn't chasing me
no sometimes they teleport on here I saw
an interesting statistic actually a few
months ago abouts
I was looking up what people's favorite
colors statistically you know turns out
the majority of people there was a site
that had information like people were
voting based on their age and gender for
males like 60% of people prefer blue and
like for females like 40 or so prefer
blue as their favorite color so the vast
majority of people like blue as their
favorite color so I thought for this
path let's make it blue and people will
like it statistically at least and so I
got that coming out here and actually
I've been using that rule for a lot of
things in Minecraft
well it's not a rule it's just
statistics that I thought were
interesting
so this this area here this is a bit
further away from the islands and I need
to make it but it lines up pretty nice
in this spot is 100 X and 300 Zed so a
nice bounce number that I'll be able to
work off of easily as we're building
this today and I have like I put I put
many hours into this is designing this
but also many hours into gathering the
materials need to build it today and I
think I got everything we need here good
to go so let's get to it enter the ender
ender 2.0 first thing we're gonna be
building is the room down below where we
have like our enchanting table and vil
chests that kind of stuff then above
that is where the Enderman are actually
gonna land and then above that way up in
the sky is gonna be all the spawning
pads that they fall down off we're gonna
do a piston pusher setup so a couple
things if you are trying to follow what
I'm doing here and you're building your
own Enderman farm keep in mind you want
to build your spawning pads and that at
least 128 blocks away from the main
island over there so you want your path
to come out that far
so that's Enderman won't be spawning on
the island and instead they all spawn
inside your trap that you build and also
you want to build it as low as possible
if you look at my y-coordinate here I
met my feet are at y1 because the lower
you build your farm the better the
spawning rates are gonna be minecraft
that checks a 17 by 17 chunk area
centered on your player and every 16
blocks you build up is another 16 blocks
vertically that gets checked every time
it tries to place an internment so I
think if I just build 16 blocks up here
my spawn rates get cut in half because
there's twice as much space vertically
it needs to check so try to keep it as
low as you can the way I got down here
is by propelling down water and then
placing
blocks on my way down and I got to do
that again here and I'm probably gonna
die so let's let's get our stuff in the
chest and I'll show you how this works
I'm gonna keep a few hundred pearls on
me just in case I can save myself
get this stuff off I have a bit of
trouble here who's trying to build the
foundation for our Enderman farm here
we're gonna build it out of quartz
because quartz is pretty nice I like it
stands out really really well in the end
as well I wanted to have these these
quartz pillars like down here though
turns out you can't really do that this
is just a regular piston I can't I can't
push the quartz block down anyway and if
I try to place it on the side of this
block here it's gonna be facing the
wrong way so this is an interesting
challenge here I'll just show you this -
like the piston is working it's just
won't push it down that last block there
for some reason that is in the game so
we got a water propelling on I guess
I'll get some quartz blocks this is my
first real challenge due to this grabs
free I'll try to do one and if I can do
it I'll do them all this way another
idea I have is maybe use this sticky
piston and send it a one tick false and
maybe a little little let me push that
and leave the block behind oh yeah yeah
you can see we're right at the the
bottom here this is very dangerous
well well that would have been okay
actually I can't jump in this I have to
walk off okay if I jumped I would have
fell through and then I gotta place it
like that okay and that is how you do it
I got to do that for each of these fun
stuff so I will be right back this is
really getting my adrenaline pumped up
doing this over and over constantly
facing near-death experiences okay come
on come on so far I've done them all
without dying no which is great and that
is the last one
so let's read gear up here my main
concern today is I'm gonna fall into the
void with all my courts or redstone or
Pistons or something and won't be able
to finish today or something like that
but I'm gonna be very careful even if I
fall off with nothing though it's a long
walk back here which is kind of painful
so the next thing we're gonna do is get
our style on let's get some more let's
get the court soda yes and we're gonna
have a blue seem for reasons I've
explained already let's do let's just do
a stack lovin any blue stained glass I'm
still in the older snapshot though so
the borders are more defined and the
glasses and s-trans parents hopefully
it'll look good in the nick snapshot too
I haven't updated yet cuz my track
hasn't updated and it's just a pain to
switch between the two what else do we
need I need trial court's where is it
there it is chiseled and we will do more
pillars all right
no we want stairs that's what we want
okay and as I do this maybe I will talk
about the history of Enderman farms a
little bit and what we plan to do
different today so back when I made my
original ender ender I remember looking
on YouTube for examples of how people
were building Edmond firms at that time
and the majority of people were like
flooding their entire in the island or
or lighting it all up with torches and
then building these funnel traps similar
to my blaze farm and that was that was
the norm at the time so I had the idea
back then to build far away from the
island - I got it yes to easily get
knacks bond rates and then also the
piston pusher method to get them down to
one house which turned out really well
and I wasn't even trying to make an XP
farm at that time it just so happened
that it
was one of the most amazing actually it
is the most amazing way of making an XP
farm is an Enderman farm which is what
people mainly make them for I just
wanted the ender pearls though and then
since then primarily the zip crowd true
I think panda mainly has come up with
some improvements most notable is the
vine trick which allows you to reset the
fall damage of the mobs and then they
then you can stack spawning pads on top
of each other vertically so that was a
huge improvement and then also tripwires
and that came out in the game and other
efficiencies were figured out and with
mine honestly there's not much left to
improve it's been pretty much perfected
at this point but there is one one trick
we're gonna be focusing on today with
this that you can do with TNT which is
gonna make it convenient like my blaze
farm like with my place for my pretty
much just have to push a button and I
tend get tons of XP just by sitting
there but it takes time the Enderman
farm you tons of XP quickly but you have
to constantly spam the click button
which is annoying but I think in 1.5
possibly I know for sure and once the
point 6 a change was made in the game
where when you ignite TNT with a flint
and steel or with a flame bow it now
keeps track of the player so that's this
is not very well known at this point I
don't think but when the TNT kills a mob
they drop experience points and intermn
do not teleport away from that so that
is the main trick we're using to make
this an amazing Enderman farm today and
hopefully all turns out well we're gonna
first make our little room down here
though so this is going to be enchanting
table right here so I just let's put a
piece of glowstone there
doo-doo-doo no stone all rights and this
is this is huge project late it's gonna
take I'm gonna do a lot off-camera here
I just want to do this is probably the
most varied thing I'm doing right now by
buried I mean on repetitive okay well do
that and I have my pillars still let's
do a simple little pattern like this but
you can make your your room down below
however you want it to look you don't
have to copy what I'm doing and then
okay we take this out I'm building this
from memory because I've already
designed it and creative like I said and
we will put chiseled I'm pretty sure
goes there like that and then we're
gonna have pillars that go up to the
next layer with ladders on over here
okay and see let's change this up put a
stair there and one over here like so
okay and then our books are gonna go
around here let's go get our books inner
enchanting table I tried to bring
everything I could so I'm gonna have to
keep running back and forth also our
anvil split that just thank you said I I
think I need 16 actually I've been
saying actually a lot today and it's has
me worried that I picked up a new filler
word which is something I I noticed when
I watch myself back i I have these bad
words I use as filler sometimes or that
I keep using repetitive repeatedly and
today seems to be actually and I hope it
doesn't catch on in my vocabulary okay
put another chiseled bear trying not to
lose my precious courts because the
stuff is a pain to get
I didn't lose too much Jaso chiselled
there and there I believe
and then pillars okay that's good and
let's fill it up with our bookshelves
and with my other design I actually did
it again darn it I put this here just
because it looked better
which means I probably don't have enough
bookshelves probably is another word I
use a ton I just can't help myself okay
let's go back get two more okay and this
is this is the main place we're gonna be
standing as we use this farme okay and
I'm gonna put ender chest here and anvil
on top and then ladders to go up here to
the next level and let's see here
this is stuff to remember I believe we
want to have quartz blocks around the
glowstone on the next level it's very
important with this design or this trick
we're going to be doing that it's only
two blocks high the ceiling here
it just works better and also the room
dimensions are really important so this
the actual building I'm doing here is a
13 by 13 square from here to here those
only 11 by 11 so that's important to
keep in mind because I'm going to be
putting TNT in the very center and when
it explodes the farthest they can reach
the Enderman is up to here if you go one
block further the TNT won't hit them so
that is very important and then maybe
I'll do a few more things off-camera
here just to speed this along
aha very good very good so I have the
bottom room just about all done here we
just need some finishing touches which
we can do on camera real quick here but
this is the grand reveal
so that is our like enchanting room and
storage for the Enderman farm at this
level here and then at the top level
there is where the Enderman actually
land and we have to build one other key
component up there well let's go take a
look inside there is some levers there
which I don't really care for but it's
the only way I could power the lamps
which are lighting pretty much the whole
place these things here in the corners
so finishing touches we have the lower
level here we are going to put cyan
carpets I love my cyan wool right there
to cover up the glowstone we are going
to get some chests down for storage
cannot use item frames down here if you
use item frames
unfortunately the TNT blows them up no
matter where you have them pretty much
because the blast reaches everywhere so
for labeling the chests you have to use
good old-fashioned signs or something
but put trap chest in the middle I don't
know what I'm putting in these yet but
we'll need most likely food and well
don't really need food if I'm not
hitting them okay and yes
the major advantage of this far and this
is a total etho thing here I like to put
stuff underneath chess usually I'm not a
big fan of how crafting tables look
generally especially when you have like
a pure white build a crafting table
looks really out of place so I like to
hide it underneath chests if I can
although putting the anvil on top
doesn't make sense either
I would like to have the anvil on the
bottom and the chest on top but I've had
it in quartz pillars here for the top
layer let's go take a look up there
so I wouldn't have been able to open the
chest so got the middle and I like how
the top layer looks especially
these areas here are where the Enderman
are gonna be falling so the spawning
pads go right above you'll notice it's a
split spawning system that was one of
the key features I thought would be
great for Minecraft entities more than
one person wanted to use the Enderman
farm you could have one person on this
side one person on this side and should
be able to keep up pretty well but in
single-player doesn't really matter too
much now let's see what else do we got
to do here let's take a lie guess we're
gonna be going up in a second anyway so
this middle part this is really
important is there anything else I
forgot to do we are going to put a
ladder right here this is gonna hold
water up and it also leaves an opening
for XP orbs to fall down on us you could
probably use a trap door too but iron
bars do not work I'm guessing glass
panes don't work and yeah so pretty much
limited to trap door or ladder here you
don't want to use a sign because we're
gonna have TNT above here and a TNT can
fall through if there's a sign there but
the ladder makes the space just a little
bit bigger than what TNT can fit through
and get this going
pressure plates to hold the water in
place did I bring the water I did that's
gonna go on top here we're building the
blast chamber right now I think let's do
it like this on the back side we will
have a ladder this is what we're gonna
use to refill the TNT as we use it not
exactly sure how how high up I want this
to go I'll probably figure that out
off-camera let's just go up aways though
whoa oh I missed darn it
so we'll have a wave getting up to the
top from the back here I should put a
torch on the top - just for now I'll put
glass at the very top when this is all
done and I figure out what height I want
but let's see let's go down here and
just look at this pattern I did it with
a glass I want to copy it so it goes
white blue light blue white blue light
blue okay so that's dude
downward facing arrows and we'll start
with whites I suppose and I guess blue
weight will go up like that that's and
then next will be cyan or light light
blue I guess I didn't you sign with this
oh this is gonna be tedious to build oh
my goodness
the main I got a really hustle today cuz
the main time-consuming part of all this
is going to be building the spawning
pads that is by far the biggest volume
of blocks I got a place okay so next to
be blue white and what we're doing is
we're making a tube that we're gonna
fill up with TNT all the way up to the
top there and this is gonna be like our
TNT reserve and I'm gonna stand down
below there and shoot up with a flame
bow and that will will mark the TNT as
mine so when it kills the Enderman oops
it's gonna register as my kill and I
will get XP orbs from it you could also
just have place for one TNT in a tube or
something if you just want to use a
flint and steel yeah you get the idea so
the other thing we got to do these are
11 blocks wide 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
and 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 so it is a
square but it's 11 living long and
there'll be Pistons like over here at
the spawning pads and also over here
that push them together in the middle
well I got the burps excuse me
so that's going
b22 spawning spaces for each of these so
44 total so each layer of Pistons I put
is going to be 44 spawning spaces and in
total I'm gonna make at least 16 layers
I think seems to give good rates but
maybe more maybe less
I might not be able to do it all today
oh yeah and we're gonna start on the
Rings here so from somewhere above here
like within two blocks we want so every
delayed I just makes me want to face bum
because this episode is gonna get really
long there's so much to do with this
build it's crazy and I forgot to bring
stone slabs with me so let's go back
quickly quickly just show you how to do
these rings real quick okay so two
blocks up is where I'm gonna start mine
and that's gonna follow the outline of
this I have speed potion know right and
you might have noticed my XP is down it
too I did die but it was on purpose I
just wanted a quick teleport back to my
base so I put all my stuff in the chest
and jumped off so I could get home
really quick okay so that is the pattern
we're gonna follow with this this is
gonna take a while I got to get some
speed potion so I can do this quicker
okay and then the next ring on the other
side is gonna be five blocks spacing
apart so three four five and then on the
sixth one is where the next one starts
although you can just look down below
and I'm gonna have these rings I'm using
this stone I would like to use the
quartz actually but I did it again darn
it
quartz is just way too expensive so I'm
just gonna use stone and I'm gonna go up
to about y49
so I will be back in a bit when I do
that and we will continue on on the
spawning pads or something man okay so
jump forward a few hours and I've gotten
a lot done here I decided to do one half
pretty much all off camera I'm just
gonna show you how I do the spawning
pads and that real quick it is 4 a.m.
right now for me and I want to go to bed
so we are not finishing this today but
we should be able to test it at least it
just won't be as quick as if I was to
get all the spawning pads done so if the
Enderman seem like they're spawning so
don't worry once I get it all finished
it will be just fantastic but yeah they
fall down and they all gather into these
side things when the other side's done
they will gather here and I can still
use it like a regular Enderman fern not
a problem and like I said you can get
two people going in here if we had them
fallen on the other side that's good
let's head on up to start on the other
side so those rings that we just
installed are to keep them from flying
out of where I want them to drop because
if they bump each other in midair they
they'll knock each other all over the
place so above the ring going all the
way down all right go back up okay so
above the Rings I have stopped these at
Y 44 43.5 this is the top one and of
course that all depends on how you do
the room below but you need the Enderman
to fall I believe 43 blocks get them
down to a one-hit kill so to reset the
fall damage we are setting up I'm using
this as my guide trying to anyway I
think I went up that much so Y 46 then
we do a ring out of just regular bricks
and this is
be our vines over here let's go quickly
quickly
ah man I am beat
this is a huge project oh I really wish
I had a helper that could do the other
side while I did this cuz wow this is so
many blocks that even go up quite as
high as I want it to be I think it only
goes about about up to why 100 I wanted
to go to think what why 120 is where
I'll stop and just see how that works
but we're gonna build why she oh I
didn't grab I was gonna use wood buttons
but it just doesn't really matter does
it so we will make a bunch of buttons
and we're gonna use these at the bottom
of here and this prevents your Pistons
going this prevents the vines from
drawing down lower than this points down
both sides and let's go back up higher
[Music]
this is gonna be really cool when it's
all done I tell you really really cool
have tools for days okay so I just
skipped ahead a little bit here oh
what's he doing I might need to adjust
the vines a little bit that they they
work but sometimes the inner men do
strange things I'm not sure if they
should really be doing some of the
strange things they're doing but anyway
this is our vine wall and of course all
places you see if I don't put the block
here this is gonna be three blocks tall
and they can spawn on that so we want to
make sure there's absolutely no place
outside of the trap where Enderman can
spawn or teleport to if possible okay so
don't think I have enough fines to
totally fill this all so we'll just put
the top and then go down to the buttons
like so do it on both sides yeah we want
them to go down to about that point
there you don't have enough vines I find
the Enderman will just fall right
through them and bypass the block and it
won't reset their fall damage all right
hopefully that all grows I think it will
now we are going to begin on the
spawning pads and this ladder here is
just temporary
just his way of getting up and down so
I've done quite a few of these already
and I have a pretty good pattern joy I
think let's see let's see if I can
remember it go up like so pistons are
here those are really loud and we'll do
a wall all along so this is 11 Pistons
per side and there's four sides per
layer all in all I think it's about 700
to 800 Pistons total if we do 16 layers
which is quite a bit actually okay and
next thing we will do we're gonna put
some blocks here some half slabs just
this filler so again Enderman can't go
where we don't want them to get four
blocks go in there do the same on this
side all right and let's go up ourselves
now what I've been doing is I've just
covered those up with blocks hop on I'll
place one out there and there break
those and this is just a thing for the
tripwire hooks put one over there one
over there and then usually I
I run across as I place the blocks over
the Pistons go over to the other side do
the same thing I haven't fallen yet I am
surprised I'm usually a lot more
careless and I have been that I have oh
hi I'm tired then I have been today
because I have not I I do not want to
lose my stuff while I'm building this
absolutely not alright and then we're
gonna go four blocks over top like so
this is the next spawning pad this ring
we're doing right now so there's quite a
bit to each of these layers this is a
big build all right but I think that's
about as simple loops I'm not even doing
this right oh man I'm gonna look at this
video tomorrow I'm gonna be like what am
I talking about what am I saying
delirious alright so then we gotta send
power that's normal by the way that
that's spamming thing that's just a
addition I added which we will look at
in just a second here oh yeah and of
course make make sure there's no
spawning spaces so we gotta cover
everything with half slabs if it's a
full block on pretty much it why on the
other side like so and so one of these
sides I've been making special not this
one the one away from our walkway yeah
you see this this extra gizmo stuff over
here insects or redstone what I've been
doing place on the half slabs there go
down this is optional you don't need to
do this if you don't want to but
basically I've been adding in one of
these to each of them
with the comparator turn to subtraction
and repeater set at 1 and what this does
is sometimes with pistons when they push
an enderman or any mob period the mob
will get the glitched inside the piston
head and it won't retract because the
piston is extended and Enderman will get
stuck in the string that we're gonna put
over there so what this does is it makes
a clock so that if they're in that
string it just keeps spamming the piston
until it actually pushes them out and
from my tests that does seem to work
pretty good occasionally it sometimes
takes two or three tries but otherwise
if they get stuck in the piston heads
the Enderman need to de-spawn on their
own and that can take 30 seconds or so
where that spawning pet is not being
used to its full potential so I think
this is a good addition if you're
willing to do that this extra little
step here otherwise again just connects
directly like that
alright and you only need to do this on
one of the sides not on both yeah okay
so that's the gist of the layers and I'm
doing 16 of those on each side so it
does take quite a while I'm just gonna
tap this one off right now with the
torch I'll come back to it later but we
are not gonna be getting that far today
of course also got to do the string
which I forgot to do so it's connected
now when I jump I see if I jump here
what kind of chances do I have a
surviving wishing me
that little extra dismal thing I did
also makes these retract wicker after
they push an Enderman instead of it
taking a full second or whatever is
normally it's a little bit quicker and
yeah so that's about it so we are gonna
head down there and actually testing
test this thing out with what we got set
up today which is a lot actually it
probably only need another two or three
hours to finish this up at most I would
think alright everyone so we are going
to try this thing out today after all
it's not finished it will be about twice
as quick when it's all finished the
spawning rates and all that but we can
we can see it in action not a problem
and also I'll have to do something about
the path I'll cover it with water
probably make it too high or something
and put water above 32 blocks away from
my main building there and might need to
also shield a few other places cuz he
and see Enderman are walking around
where I don't want them to be so the way
we are going to do the TNG thing I
brought a flame bow and some arrows and
hopefully I don't die with these I'm
gonna put them away actually so the way
to stock this thing up by the way and
I'm gonna use a trap door for it
place one one TNT there to begin with
it's very important do you build this
the way I told you to otherwise your
whole thing is gonna explode on you and
you're gonna be very sad from my testing
what am I supposed to do this isn't
supposed to be there how does that work
I think that's fine yeah I think that's
fine
this is how I plan on filling it it's
not a big deal gonna even enderpearl
down to it but in all my tests I think I
tried this about a hundred times I
didn't have the TNT blow up anything on
me so I hope hopefully got everything
set up right otherwise I'm gonna be very
sad oh and he took one see that's the
thing that's why you don't want them
outside of those barriers because they
steal your TNT if they can get to that
middle but this is the way it works you
take your flame bow which I put over
here and when you don't need the TNT
anymore
press f3 when it gets to about 80
entities and all the XP and ender pearls
are picked up that means you're ready
for another harvest so you take your
your flame bow you shoot up TNT falls
down get out of the way yeah everybody's
dead
and you stand in the middle here and
enjoy haha and while you're cutting your
XP changing on its own it's really weird
the XP orbs seem to update the trapdoor
might change that back to the ladder I
like the idea of being able to control
it but if it's doing its own thing and
that's an 8 year yeah sounds like
there's a few guys mad at me too because
there was probably some full health guys
around that weren't supposed to be this
guy here I don't know he was one hit
what is it's the it's XP orbs for sure
let's break this my carpet okay let's
let's go again here I think we're about
ready yeah
so you just keep doing it over and over
very little effort to team two
explosions I think we'll get you up to
level 30 and it's got the convenience of
my blaze farm with the speed of my old
ender ender all combined into one Autons
just a little bit short and if you need
to end up Rosie and still go up and
collect them if you want not a problem
and the size of this thing was important
because that's about the limit to how
far the XP orbs will track you if you're
standing in the middle not I love doing
that so that is the ender ender 2.0 I'm
gonna finish this up guys and then we
will see you in next episode probably
and it's full glory and when I'm well
rested and able to speak in a more
excited way because I'm really happy
this is done but yeah that is that is
the ender ender for today so let's go
read the comments and we will call this
an episode okay everybody so what do we
got here what do we got here
common number one for episode 300 says
on episode 300 put your world up for
download please so many people have been
requesting my world up for download it's
been a long time since I last updated
that I am going to finish the ender
ender 2.0 and then I am going to put the
download link up for my world so episode
301 is when I
most likely get my world up for download
again and you guys will be able to check
out all the new stuff I've done around
the world and I will try to remember you
try to remind you next episode too but
yeah check the video description next
episode for the download link 2nd
comments this is a question I get asked
pretty frequently actually so etho after
all the time I've been wondering all
this time how did you come up with the
name etho I must say it's one of the
most unique names and I love it
also I want to send congrats for making
an LP that is still interesting and
stays fun after 300 episodes I think
you're the only one who succeeded in
that Congrats man and also greets from a
Belgian fan thank you very much for your
comments it's very nice of you
the name etho mmm I've had four on lot
different online names I've had etho for
about 10 years
give or take maybe even longer actually
but my first online name was that that
didn't goober like hurts like you know
like Curt's goober that's what my
original online name was for about a
year then I switched over to master of
disguise that was because I was playing
this game called worms world party worms
Armageddon some of you most of you
probably know what that team is and I
was a little bit immature a little bit
troll ish in my younger days
definitely not today and I would do this
thing where I would copy somebody's name
and copy their their team and then play
against them with exact copy of their
team and they would always have like a
what how did you do this type of
reaction and I thought it was funny I
did that for about two weeks or so but I
dipped the name master of disguise for
quite a while
and then I decided to change it to
ersatz which is e
rs80 Zed which means copy so that was
kind of a play off of the old name
masters guys and then finally from Earth
SATs I moved on to ESO I liked I liked
having a name like ersatz
i like the unique e to it so i decide
for my next name i would use
e is the first letter and i just added a
th o at the end of that and that is how
i became etho it's nothing to do with
the Greek ethos thing and that's just a
coincidence yeah great story bro
the name ethos lab also came from my
days playing worms I made a bunch of
programs or utilities for people to use
for those games and I became known as
sort of a technical kind of guy and
somebody that I played with offered me a
sub domain where I could host up all the
programs and and little helper things
they made for people and when he asked
me what I wanted my sub domain name to
be I said I don't care and he gave me
the name ethos lab on his own so when I
made my youtube account I did it without
even thinking and just used the name
ethos lab cool story bro alright guys
that is the end of episode three hundred
I hope you enjoyed it we will finish up
that ender ender 2.0 and checked it out
next time and probably do a bunch of
enchanting and I will see you guys then
and I really appreciate I'm not just
saying I really appreciate all the
support you guys have given me since I
started this it's really really awesome
thanks again bye-bye
you
[Music]