hey everybody how you doing today I
believe last time we left off in the
nether as exploring this fortress thing
I've gone through it all now I'm pretty
sure and I found to blaze spawners in
total I was hoping to find two together
but then never happened
I don't know how rare that is but
probably probably fairly rare the other
one I found is over here and it's in a
pretty cool area surrounded by glowstone
so I think I'm just going to leave that
be for now and there's some more
glowstone here I'm surprised they never
put any chests or anything in these
fortress things to make them you know a
little bit more interesting basically
they all just dead end it's not really
overly exciting to explore once you've
seen a few of them but yeah the other
one we found was over here and this is
the one we're going to make a blaze
spawner with today I'm hoping right over
there it's still not disabled I cannot
disable it using torches alone because
there's still spotting in midair in the
area so the best way I can think of of
disabling this thing is just to put
blocks around its so that no more I will
be able to spawn in the area so that's
what I'm going to do now
boom no not a freaking gas so nice shot
hey Jess no no no runnin on the arrows
here dare butter so gonna run out arrows
not arrows please don't shoot me better
whoa whoa what the heck buddy Wow
pretty much invulnerable with us
but these guys are so annoying that I
can't do anything getting rid of oh I
get a fishing that's you
alright so I have no arrows left do it
the hard way absolutely no arrows
disable a spawning
what happens if you use a fishing rod on
a blaze
yeah I am I need arrows so bad
this is silly ah alright so I did get my
stuff back but dying there has made me
kind of accept them not really in any
position to deal with the nether like I
am here I can't I can't handle the gas
without any arrows this is too difficult
so like my original plan was to build a
base around this blaze spawner here I
think I'm going to have to do it around
the one back there because it's enclosed
it'll be a lot easier to set up I just I
just can't deal with the open area until
I build a real mob system so we will we
will set up a blaze farm at the other
one yeah so it's been a whole lot easier
working in this little room here because
there's no guests shooting me so much
more peaceful I mean take out the
glowstone now I got my fortune three pic
and apparently using fortune 3 on
glowstone makes it more likely that
you'll get for dust when you break it
normally it's two to four so let's check
it out got four four four yeah it seems
to seems to do it oh is it I think
that's three yep
you don't always get four but most the
time you will three and
yeah so I'm going to fish in casing this
area with cobblestone I'm making an 8 by
8 by 3 hi rectangle square 2 whatever
whatever it's called area where the
blades can spawn and once I fill that
all in they won't be able to spawn at
all and I'll be able to just build
around the big concrete slab or whatever
so I'll see you once I finish that okay
so I got it all filled in here they are
not able to spawn anymore regardless of
the lighting condition so lighting
condition does really slow down spawning
but the thing is it's very difficult to
work around if you're constantly
breaking torches or moving lava so I
would recommend you you do this encasing
thing if you're building a blaze farm
okay we probably won't get into building
it today just because it'll take a long
time to do probably or at least all all
I want to show probably 20 or 30 minutes
of LP time and I have something very
important I wanted to do today so we're
going to stop construction here today on
this but I will go over a few important
things so this is the area where the mob
spawning occurs from a spawner it's area
that's checked blaze though are 2 blocks
high so this isn't all necessary this
bottom bottom layer is not required ok
so so for example let's say the game
checks this spot here to see if a blaze
is to spawn that's where their feet
would be and then their head would be
one block up in in this cobblestone here
so they won't be able to spawn
with this one just one air block below
the blaze spawner but if I remove one of
these ha oops yeah so that's one deal
there and on top
much the same thing I fish to fill that
in so the blaze spawner is right below
here they're not able to spawn one block
up but if you go one block down they'll
be able to spawn in that area like you
just saw so to get the absolute highest
spawn rates possible from this one blaze
spawner here so absolute highest XP
output from it I'm going to have to make
sure all this cobble area is err blocks
when I'm done my farm so that's the 8x8
for this layer this layer this layer and
also one layer above because if a blaze
was to spawn at this block here that's
where his feet would be and his head
would be one block higher so he needs
one air space as well so in total I need
an 8 by 8 by 4 high area of airspace
also when my blaze farm is all done here
I'm going to have to make sure I have no
torches or lava glowstone or anything
lighting the 8 by 8 by 4 area I want
that space as dark as possible because
that will increase the rate that the
blaze will spawn ok and I'll tell you
how I figure out that how to position 8
by 8 I've covered this before when I was
doing the cave spiders but I'll go over
it again if you count this way from the
spawner it goes 1 2
three blocks but this way it goes one
two three four blocks so how do you know
which one to make four blocks and which
one to go three blocks well I use the
coordinates here if you look at X and
Zed
when I'm walking this way they both get
smaller so I know that's OOP that's the
one that I need to go four blocks on and
if I'm going this way they get larger so
that's that's the three blocks I'd and
if you count one two three four five six
seven eight one two three four five six
seven eight so it is eight by eight
it's just lopsided a little bit okay now
the other thing ah this probably won't
be quite as effective as my team spider
system just because I have to cave
spider spawners together these guys they
give 10 X B each and cave spiders give 5
X B each so 2 times 5 is 10 it's the
same but I believe cave spiders have a
higher chance of more spawning at a time
then these Blais do because the blaze
are occupied two blocks of space when
they spawn and cave spiders only occupy
one block of space so I'm pretty sure
it's more likely you'll get more cave
spiders
it's a little bit complicated the other
thing is these Blaise they have a lot of
particle effects and animations to them
so I'm pretty sure they're going to like
my game a lot more so I can't just let
300 collect like I can with cheap cave
spiders without experiencing technical
issues probably so another thing to keep
in mind yeah so the plan is to have this
thing the blaze farm as the center of my
nether base so I can have it running be
active when I'm when I'm doing stuff
around the nether here because I need to
be 16 blocks within the spawner 4 to be
working and I don't know how big the
nether base is going to be or everything
I'm going to do in it
but I know I need another work farm
because it only grows in the nether when
you're in the nether as far as I know so
that's one thing we also will probably
set up some transportation systems and
another some time just because it's a
lot faster traveling in the nether other
step to my plan is to make it nice to
set up like grass and trees and and
everything like that I want to I want to
kick butt nether here but anyway we will
move on oh yeah so since well this will
probably be very similar in
effectiveness to the spider XP farm I
have right now but the main reason I'm
doing this is so I'll have something the
nether to get XP and also so I can get
blaze rods I can use blaze powder for
potions for ender eyes also blaze rods
can be used in furnaces and stuff so
overall they're pretty effective are
pretty useful item to have so let's lie
on a farm here but yeah let's go with
don't do what we're gonna do in the main
world all right everybody we're back
home here and I am ready to show you the
the project it's a big project it took
me many many hours it's still not
finished I got to do the walls and
ceiling few other things to make it nice
but the most time-consuming part and the
most important part is done now so here
we go
the tree farm I've given everybody
that's donated to my channel a tree of
their own in my world this area of my
world is dedicated to the donors I hope
you guys liked it I had to haul out this
whole area it took so long
you have no idea I had to collect all
the sand glowstone every every tree has
a glow stone I want to get rid of these
pumpkins too and replace them with
glowstone so there's a bit to go yet but
I think it's pretty cool and it's very
useful I've been collecting a lot of
your wood please refrain from
inappropriate jokes yeah so I think
we'll just go through and look at all
the names for the rest of this episode
and maybe talk about a few things here
we go and I just want to say thank you
to everybody that's donated I really
appreciate it brings a big smile to my
face now that I have the tree farm down
here I can I got like a visual
representation of everybody that's
donated and it just it's amazing to see
it really I think in total 118 people
have donated some of these are
compounded like for example some people
have donated more than once so it just
gets added to their sign and these are
in canadian funds
after PayPal takes Orkut that's why it's
all weird numbers conversion rates and I
think there's a processing charge on
everyone so I think the processing
charge is at least 30 cents so some
people might have zero on their sign if
if there was nothing left after that but
yeah thank you everybody I am a YouTube
partner now so I make money through ads
on my videos but it's not so don't
really don't feel like you need to
donate but if you want to I really do
appreciate it
everybody that does of course but yeah I
do make money from my videos in other
ways now so everybody that watches my
videos is donating in a way that's the
first 40 I accidently miscounted and I
added an extra rule there but if more
people donate that's where your trees
are going to go and what else what else
is new well minecraft 1.0.0 is out and I
I'm using it this is this is the
official release a lot of people are
wondering if I went to my con I did not
it would have been fun to go yeah but I
don't know at the time when I had to get
a ticket in that I didn't realize how
big of a deal it was going to be and
also I didn't really I can't really
justify the expense of going usually if
I go traveling it's the visit family in
the States so going to Las Vegas isn't
really something I would do probably but
yeah 1.0 is out 1.0.0 sorry I haven't
noticed any changes with it really since
at least candidate 2 I've heard some
people say you can reach further
I don't know if that's true or not
hopefully some more bugs were fixed
that's always a nice thing and from what
I've heard it sounds like notch and jab
and that are going to continue releasing
patches for the game which is nice as
long as this game is profitable and that
it sounds like they're going to continue
even if they were to stop I think the
community would kind of take over the
game and they'd probably become a
central mod group that kind of finished
the game on their own which wouldn't be
a bad thing either so I think my
minecraft will continue to get patches
in that for for a long time still it's a
great game a lot of people play it I
notice recently though fewer people are
playing it creeper check since Skyrim
and that came outside I noticed views on
basically all YouTube channels that do
minecraft have dropped it's like 70
percent of what they normally get so I'm
hoping those people come back and that
they're not done with minecraft I'd hate
for the community to get smaller yeah
like all games you get bored of its and
eventually you might try it out again
so hopefully they'll be back I'm still
loving the game I hope you guys are too
looking forward to all the future
content and that I think we're just
about at the end here so many people and
it's day month years the way I've been
doing it and I think I got them all in
order which is good so yeah thank you
everybody that's that's a huge giant
tree farm that took many many hours to
make I got these space
these birch trees they need a a 5x5 area
to grow that can't be obstructed but
they can share leaves and that so
closest you can have them together is
with a two block space here so that's
why I have it this size and I wanted a
nice walking area here so yeah that's
the tree farm thanks everybody thanks
for watching my videos thanks for
donating and I think I'm going to end
that both sowed here today next time
little hopefully finish to the blaze
farm but until then take care thanks for
watching I almost forgot it's going to
put this world up for download now let
the tree farms done so if you want to
check out the world see what I've built
around here just to get a better idea of
everything check the video description
I'll hopefully have a download link in
it and you can play around in it
yourself