[Music]
they're so beautiful
hello everybody this is etho now
if you're watching this video in the
year 2013 i just want to take a moment
to say thank you
thank you for taking the time to watch
my older videos it's much appreciated
watch all my videos um if you're
watching this
in the year 2012
i just blew your mind and if you're
watching this in the year 2013
but you also watched it in the year 2012
you know what treat yourself to
something good because you're one of my
favorite
persons in the world to take the time to
re-watch a video you've seen already
that's
that's the real that's the real ticket
there
anyway uh new patch new blocks
you've seen them they're amazing
there's actually a creeper face on the
sandstone like
how much better could it be it
kind like a soul sand kind of had a
creeper face on already but it wasn't
overly defined that is definitely a
creeper face
and on the best block can't beat that
can't um i like the new look of the
sandstone
i couldn't figure out at first when i
saw it alone why it had this like lip at
the top and then
when i put it next to the regular
sandstone oh yeah
it has a lip too so it kind of goes with
it that way
it's one thing i i don't know
i guess it looks good yeah it does it's
just
for the flow vertically it's a little
that's pretty good uh has the same
top and i believe the same bottom as
regular sandstone so it goes
together that way and then we got the
new planks which are really cool because
they're
they're kind of colors that we don't
quite
have or they look
they flow very nicely together and
they're they're very unique colors which
is great
so obviously you know you get them
from their respect respective wood types
dark wood gives you the dark planks
birchwood gives you the light ones
and
regular wood gets the regular ones
jungle wood gets you the reddish kind i
like that
exotic wood type look
um yeah
and i think if you craft like the new
wood
the new planks you still get the regular
half slabs and probably the regular
stairs yeah
so maybe one day we'll get those too
that would be cool
this lighter wood actually is very close
to the same color
as sandstone
very interesting sad thing for me though
working on that mine shaft a lot to the
branch mind
branch mine and uh
the easiest trees to collect wood from
are obviously the jungle ones because i
just
plant one of the big ones throw an ender
pearl and
cut my way down get like two stacks of
wood that way
and i would just make planks out of them
because it takes a lot of planks to do
that
uh branch mine design
and now i have to get them from these
trees and that takes a little bit longer
you can see i've been cutting them down
and replanting them here
and cutting them down at the tree farm
and all that
too and yeah it's just a little bit work
for me now
one trick i could do i could
if i wanted i'm going to pick those
tracks up again
in just a second you could convert it to
the wooden slabs and then just do a
double
and it would look the same i think it
might
i don't know if it has a lighting issue
the stairs had a lighting issue for me
when i tried
yeah it looks it looks right
that's one way you could take advantage
of using the old or the jungle tree
still for
for collecting blanks
anyway let's head
down to the branch mine
all right we're here i don't know if i
showed this last time but i put lamps at
this entrance parts
that are always on there's a levers
above them
i've been working and expanding this
quite a bit since last episode
changed this drop here too so it's
it's one of the cubes too i haven't had
any mobs spawn in here yet from the
flickering lights which is good
and just been doing
getting more stuff as i've been mining
you can see i've almost used up the
awesome pick just
just on this alone uh lots and lots of
digging
and i guess we'll go for a little bit of
a run i almost forgot to
get that
and we got the full six minutes that's
awesome so i don't know if you guys know
this but with
splash potions uh you want them
to hit you in the face you don't want
them to hit your feet
ideally so it's the last longer if you
throw them at a at a wall like that
instead of
at your feet like that so just a little
trick
to keep in mind um
yeah i mostly expanded this way
so there's 25 of these branches now
haven't started mining at all just uh
just the main corridors
uh then it started starts going this way
so and as i've been going through here
i've been finding caves and everything
too every so often i've just
been blocking them off and lighting them
up and stuff
now having a little bit of a problem
over here
i think you might be able to guess what
it is
um yeah so i'm gonna be
using the the double half slabs
at any of these type sections where
there's lava
um look at all the redstone
beautiful so
the way the pattern the way this pattern
works is it's a five
wide by four high plus
this block down on the left and on the
right is cut out
and then i just run planks all the way
down there and there
and then the top left and right corners
as well
and then i do the cross sections that go
all the way around pretty simple
and then i put a pumpkin
at the top uh this one goes quite a ways
yet too
and then it stops i have hit uh
that will go down i have hit my other
mine
unfortunately over here
so one of the branches is pretty much
going to get nothing
because it's the same exact spot as that
one
so if i do the donor thing i'm sorry if
you get that one because you'll
probably get no resources to your name
uh if that if that matters to you
but we'll leave that up to the luck of
the draw i guess
um yeah
a lot of people seem to want me to do
the tracks and i think i might
that's why i brought these with me just
so you can see what it looks like
some people suggested i should change
the floor with soil
i tried it it looks pretty good it does
the problem is i kind of want to keep
the soil because i
only i don't even have like a chest full
of it
i'm pretty low on soil and i will
probably need it for future projects
so if i can keep it wrong tool
if i can keep it that would be good so
i'll probably keep the smooth stone
because it's a lot easier usually i
don't have to replace it because it's
a good chance it will be smooth stone as
i dig this out
uh this goes away these are the pumpkins
above the lighting looks really good
very even and i think i stopped here
i want to show you this cave it's
pretty crazy
before i start lighting it up and stuff
and going through it it's huge
like just it looks so cool too
i i was impressed anyway
so yeah
very cool so i'll have fun going through
that
and i think i found another one too
it's crazy i can be over here
and like creepers will just find me
constantly
i'm hungry
okay i'll run down to the other other
path and we can see the other cave there
too i think there was one
yeah this other main corridor comes down
to this cave but i guess i went through
it already i forgot i did
got a lot of stuff in here though uh
it's fairly
fairly big but anyway
today i want to do a little bit of uh
messing around with minecart stuff
i don't uh do a lot of minecart things
but i've had an
idea for a like a player sensor
to see if a player is a mine is in a
minecart or if it's a regular
empty one or a storage minecart type
thing
and uh the reason i want that
is so that if at any point in the system
i just bring a storage minecart with me
put it on the tracks fill it up with my
stuff and then push it
i want it to find its way back to the
main hub there and then also
go into a separate track specifically
for
the storage minecarts ideally that's
what i would like to happen
like once it gets here then it goes to a
storage minecart track that maybe goes
to
a storage room or something at my main
base that would be really cool
but i need to detect if it's a storage
minecart or if it's a regular minecarts
so that is what we're gonna do
here today right now at this moment
all right so i was just doing some stuff
around my place here some chores
cutting down trees and stuff and
i got a visitor unexpectedly
i tell ya the new mob ai
is crazy they are so smart now
apparently they've been programmed to
appreciate artwork
which is just mind-boggling
just can't stop staring at the
awesomeness
it's time for you to go home
you like it
i think he likes it um
so apparently i'm pretty safe here if i
ever have zombie visitors which is good
i have no idea where he came from though
which
terrifies me
okay so time for the minecart stuff um
i only know of two ways of detecting if
the there's a player in the cart or if
it's an empty cart
one of them is kind of like this uh you
have an iron
fence above the pressure plate though
and you ram the cart
into it falls down
and it will be half on the power rail
here
and half on the pressure plate type
thing
and if there's a player in it the stone
plate will go down
that's one way and there's different ra
different ways you can
use wooden and stone pressure plates
the other way i know of is like this
this is something i saw in
one of pear squirrel's videos uh
this is the best one i know of just a
little v
section here and if there's
if it's an empty cart it goes right over
if there's a player in it
then it gets active so that's actually a
really good way of doing it very compact
the one thing i don't like about it in
pretty much
all designs is you have to have
a v or you can't do it with a street
track
and that's what i want to try to do
today make it work with this
straight track so it's seamless um
and i think i know how to do it but
we're going to play with idea i haven't
tried it yet
and i'm sorry if this has been done
before i don't really keep up to date
with
minecart stuff
but the idea is we will have
two detector rails i don't know how far
to space them or anything we'll
i'll play around with it a bit here
maybe we'll try
we'll try four blocks apart
okay and we will put power rails right
next to them just to make sure
the carts go in max speed when we do
this
um
and we will put power rails here too i
guess this will be our
our take off
cart will go there and the idea is
we can measure the time it takes the
cart to go from
this one to this one empty carts travel
slower
than carts with players in and we could
potentially use this to detect furnace
mine carts too because they're even
slower than empty
carts generally well actually no
if they're boosted with a power rail i
think they might be the same speed but
on their own they're slow
i don't know anyway what we'll do
one of these will have a delay
and again i don't know what kind of
delay we might have to do a
monostable circuit here i'm not sure
they'll meet and into an and gate
actually the delay should be on this one
okay no delay there
and gates make some torches
and hopefully we'll figure this out
i like it because uh it's seamless
you just have two detector rails in your
track
and you don't have to make a mess of
things you can hide all this underground
probably
yeah we'll take this
okay
let's see what happens what happened to
the button
oh it's over here
we will see what happens
they put the keys so close together i
tell you
and we should probably power that
one more time here we go
okay so it didn't this didn't light up
music
the music box didn't play um
and we'll just see what happens if i
ride it now if it's any different
and if it's not i'll play around with
the timings until i find the sweet spot
i guess um
nope okay so i'll play around with the
timings a little bit off camera so i
don't waste a whole bunch of your time
here
all right i got it figured out is pretty
simple
i just uh made a little
test track over here this is it
it's an and gate uh
except it's only one wide underneath the
track
and it's pretty simple
so here we go empty cart
passes right over
and if there's a player in it
it it detects it so it's pretty cool um
and yeah it's the detector rails there
one
two three four five six seven eight
blocks apart
which is uh i think the closest you can
get this andy to fit
if it's one wide otherwise you gotta
build it either
a little bit to the left or right and
you get the outputs
uh from this middle block here either on
this side or the other one
or you could also
wait no no that won't work never mind uh
yeah
so that's all there is to it pretty
simple
i like it i might use it um
we should try it with a storage minecart
just to make sure
they're the same speed and wait
i knew i had one here make sure they're
the same speed
maybe we'll try furnace minecarts too
and yeah i really don't do much with
mine carts
i don't know i've always had trouble
doing anything cool with them for some
reason
yeah so they're just like empty ones
i'm i'm guessing the furnace minecarts
are just like empty ones
too unless they're being coal powered
on an unboosted track
there we go
that was weird i wonder why i lost its
power so quick
try it again
it just freezes man i didn't know it did
that
okay well i'll put some coal in it
um then we'll see what happens
that's not where the coal goes oh yeah
you got to put it in your hand
all right okay so you could potentially
detect
three different types of carts empty
carts furnace carts or
carts with players in and storage carts
are the same as empty carts
so that's all there is to that i guess
you could uh probably
arrange those detector things closer
together too and just build the andean
off to the side
with these two power rails here i think
it should work
all the time because i think these will
bring them up to max speed
and then it should be consistent
regardless of how many power power rails
and where you have them before that
if you got rid of these and had like a
power rail over here you could
probably build this closer together too
and
just the timing to to make it all work
out the same
but yeah that's all we're going to do
with that today and we'll probably end
the episode here
um it's getting late here so
tomorrow is the ultra hardcore series
i know you guys are loving that uh i'll
i've also
recorded me playing through spellbound
caves single-player
so i'll be uploading that soon once i
need filler episodes again
that was a lot of fun it's kind of like
a speed run but not
quite um you'll see
it's very action-packed i'm hoping you
enjoy it
when i release it but
uh yeah i think that's all i'm gonna do
today
so take care thanks for watching
stay cool