hello everybody this is Ito welcome back
guys to our let's play series and go get
your snacks
having said that a long time have I you
know what guys I have to tell you
something you know and you really like a
food like a certain type of food you
just love it you eat it a lot you kind
of get used to it after a while don't
it's not so special to you so maybe
you'll stop eating it for a while
I love bagels guys absolutely love
bagels I've gone over a year without
eating a bagel and then the other day is
like I like bagels I should eat a bagel
so I had a bagel today toasted
everything bagel with cream cheese or as
I like to call them the all inclusive
bagels and it was so good oh it was so
good mmm
best snack in a long time so go get your
snacks get something you really like
maybe you haven't had in a long time
guys to start off with today I had an
idea for something pretty random here we
are going to be building a sandworm or
attempting to anyway what is a sandworm
ah
the best the thing that's what am I
trying to say my inspiration for the
sandworm is you know when you go to
those fancy malls sometimes they have
the water jet fountains like the water
snakes that jump over the path so it'll
be like a burst of water that shoots
into the air and it'll hop from one
fountain to the next one and it kind of
looks like a snake hopping around but
it's just water timed at certain
intervals and it looks really cool it
bounces around it's very fun to watch
we're going to try build something like
that here in Sandy City okay so to make
this happen guys we got to build like an
array of sand block launchers so when
the sand falls down before it hits the
slime block down here we want it to get
shot up while it's still an entity form
if it lands on the slime block that's it
Gigi because you can't launch it
afterwards it sticks to it and it won't
fall ever again so we want it to launch
up and then this will shoot it sideways
and whoa I thought I fell down the hole
there it's going to shoot it up over
this way and like if we're standing here
it'll go over top our head type of thing
and hopefully just have like a two-block
hole somewhere around here where the
sand will get launched to fall down into
another one of these launchers and it'll
shoot it another direction or to another
area type of thing that's that's the
goal with this so I've set it up so it
should work with a OTO a smart piston
type of thing so if a block lands here
that will shoot that'll push it sideways
and then we just got to take this delay
and send a signal to this piston and it
should automatically launch a sand block
if it ever falls into here let's just do
it really rough to start off with I'll
polish up off-camera but what we got to
do is maybe just give it a short delay
see we have a two tick delay down there
so we should give this one a three tick
we want them one tick apart and that
will go to this piston like so and now I
think it will will do what we want let's
try this out woohoo oh we almost got the
creeper I was really close on the on the
guess there too
that's pretty cool so we want to set up
a bunch of these and it should like
chutes and blocks all over the village
kind of automatically on its own Kate
you are making me nervous
we're going to take them out aha so if
we were to put a block here I wonder
what happens is that gonna be in the way
oh no it still does it
sweet okay so we only need like a yeah
like a two-block 2x1 hole here for it to
work okay that's pretty good so I'm in
the middle of polishing this up now like
I redid the wiring I'll show you how we
how to do it when we build the second
one here from scratch and I'm also
trying to hide it the best weekend too
so I filled sand in wherever we can put
it as it is right now it still works we
have to keep these sides open though
unfortunately because otherwise it tries
to move this sand next to it and it
doesn't have a spot for it so it can't
extend let's see I guess what we could
do is like half slab over top of it
possibly let's not put it there maybe I
miss miss clicking like crazy here you
do something like that
or bring it out even further still work
still works very good if we have a block
here still works
what about slab let's try a slab oh it
still works okay full block if it does a
full block that would be amazing
no that's the limit okay so we might
want to lower this all by one because
all these labs can be sand pretty much
except for these two that they would
have to be sandstone yeah we could make
this look a lot better if it was one
lower so I think that's what we'll do I
wonder if we can get this to juggle like
three three at once
Oh messed up
Oh got to
awesome I thought my machine how to
jungle that's so cool we might even be
able to get four but I'm not I'm not
greedy this is the effect I want so
we're gonna have like a big reserve of
sand somewhere and it's gonna shoot like
10 20 blocks hopefully and they'll jump
from one to another one will set up
another one over here should look pretty
cool oh man this is pretty cool guys I
got four of them set up right now and
this is what they look like when they're
there all completes when they're flush
with the ground so I moved it down the
block and checked it out let's try to
keep up with it here so yeah just kind
of bounces around goes from one to
another all automatic it's not on timers
or anything and I think that looks
pretty cool we might even be able to
just hook it up in a loop and have it go
all the time I don't know if that would
be a good idea or not or if there'd be
any problems but that would be a really
simple way of doing it um so yeah I
managed I'm going to set up another one
here I'll kind of show you the process
so I want to see where this lands again
okay so actually goes pretty high in the
air doesn't it so it lands over here but
this is the middle of the road I don't
really want to put a hole in the middle
of the road there so maybe what we could
do is just build like a tree over here
and hopefully it'll hit the leaf blocks
and just fall down and then we're going
to send the next one going this way I
think all right so tell you what let's
just set up a wall of leaves here maybe
two blocks out from the wood there and
see what happens next so if we put it in
here oh okay I don't know if we can stop
it actually not sure if it landed on it
or if it just breaks whenever it hits
something let's try it again
is it gonna stop oh okay yeah that
worked ah let's try it one more time
make sure it like freezes that's so
strange
yeah so let's try set one of these up
together if we can just in case you want
to build it for yourselves I'll show you
how to do it here the very first thing
you got to do if you're chaining them
together is figure out where the sand
block is going to land and make sure it
actually lands and does it doesn't get
destroyed when it hits the ground it's
really important and then you got to dig
down I think three blocks or so and then
you place a furnace or some block that
doesn't move okay and we're going to go
that way so then what I like to do is
put the piston opposite of that no put
the piston on the side you want it want
to go that's the way you do it yes and
then put the sticky piston the sideways
pusher on the opposite side so I think
that would be over here
one block below the ground level and
then over here dig down this is a little
bit confusing make sure you get rid of
all the blocks beside the piston here
otherwise it won't be able to move and
you can put furnace blocks or whatever
you want instead oh it's going to be
nighttime okay so the slime block should
be one below this furnace and I'm gonna
sleep just so we can skip this night
time ok back at its here what I like to
do next is set up the smart pissed and
stuff so I'm not going to put stone
brick down just because we're doing this
on video otherwise I would trust me but
it's a little bit faster if we don't so
have it powered so that if a block lands
here it'll send power out to the other
side there and just loop it back to this
piston so just do this I got put stone
brick here
and that works pretty good so now if we
do this it automatically pushes it and
then what we want to do is take the
signal from this block here move it down
towards this lower piston you want a two
tick delay from from that okay so we can
run it down like this and what I like to
do is just put down block here next to
the piston put some redstone furnace or
some some block that transmits power and
doesn't move and then grab the signal
from this dust put it to the furnace and
down set this to - all right so that
should be the the bottom one hooked up
that launches it up very good then
just run the signal to this and this is
pretty easy to do all right put a stone
brick down there and just about done
okay we usually don't do redstone
together but you know we should we used
to do it all the time and it's been a
long time since we we did anything like
this so now it should all be good to go
right yes and launches it about twenty
eight blocks on level ground from what
I've seen let me just cover over the
dust and stuff with the with the sand
oops
next to this one I like to put double
furnace on both sides like that net so
that's it we're not too worried about
sticking to anything and you can't cover
over all this and we are basically done
with it so the thing is we got to keep
that 2x1 hole but we also need a half
slab the direction it's going here
otherwise it's going to run into the
block all right I think we're good to go
and drop it on top the furnace ooh and
that's all there is to it
all right everybody so I just added in a
few more of these things and we're gonna
have some fun with it now because it
does a full cycle a full loop around
this place so it doesn't ever stop when
we put one in here um I want to see what
it looks like when we get a ton of them
just flying around so I'm going to make
a big long chain and then we're gonna
watch and see what it looks like because
I think it's gonna be pretty cool and we
can have some fun doing some experiments
here I'm curious how much lag it's going
to cause alright it's probably gonna
come back around about me now oh yeah
pretty close pretty close to it oh man
look at this this is so cool
getting a little bit of lag yeah we're
down to 20 frames so this is not
something we probably want to keep
running all the time or at least not
this many at once it might just be the
sound from the Pistons so I'm not sure
because when we're far away like this
it's not lagging anymore
that's pretty cool though the sandworm
okay so the other thing I want to see is
if it gets messed up if we leave the
area and come back so I'm going to walk
far away so the chunks unload and go out
a render distance and then we'll come
back and see if it's still going or not
okay so we're on our way back now and
we're gonna see what happened to those
sand entities because if you take
minecarts for example if they go to
unloaded chunks sometimes they can bunch
up if there's lots of them and that
stuff can happen I'm wondering if that's
going to be the case with these because
they're flying into unloaded chunks as
well when you leave the area and that
might cause some trouble oh oh darn yeah
we're having some issues like we had
solid
sand blocks like a unbroken chain and
now there is only three jumping around
I'm wondering if they bunched up or
maybe they broke somehow I'm not seeing
them on the ground like the item entity
anywhere though hmm if there's only one
block it should never have trouble yeah
I don't see them on the ground anywhere
so there might be like just a whole
bunch of them bunched together there
tell you what let's let's break this
chain and see how many we get back is I
only see like three or four flying
around at the moment
how many sand blocks do we have on us
just just under two stacks okay
one each yeah there's only one there for
each of those so I don't know what
happened to them that's pretty weird
they wouldn't be on the ground and we
didn't get them back there huh so we
might need we have two options here we
either have to make some system that
will detect when we're in the area and
then release them or just have like one
flying around at a time which is
probably the best way of doing it right
that's the simplest just to have one
block jumping around we'll get the least
amount of leg that way too but let me
know if you guys have any ideas in the
comments I suppose and I think we're
going to go do something else here
there's something we really need to do
today guys like this is getting
ridiculous I have so many drops saved up
from this mob system I've just been
stashing them in this room here and it's
getting to the points where like we got
chests all over the place and these are
denoted with bones and arrows and
gunpowder for days so I'm going to try
convert this stuff into TNT the
Gunpowder at least and that will free up
a lot of space but we need a lot of sand
to do it so
head over to our our desert where we get
our sand sandy place you know what I'm
talking about yes this place over here
it's just so much easier to show you
than to try to tell you about it so I've
been getting sandstone from down below
and sand from up top here I'm shaving
away this whole cliff ideally and gonna
grab a bunch of it I wanted to follow up
on on the pillow-talk
remember I think it's last episode I
talked about how I wake up in the
morning feeling you know always stuffed
up with a raspy voice and you guys said
in the comments it's probably because
I'm allergic to dust mites so I tried
steam cleaning my pillow and it seems to
have helped actually like I'm still a
little bit stuffed up in the morning but
not quite as bad so I think that was
possibly it's oh look at this this might
be a pretty good sand fall let's let's
see what it does it was okay it wasn't
great oh oh that's a little bit better
all right so we are just about done with
the TNT crafting here you know I thought
it was going to be like Oh dicks and for
30 minutes or so no joke there was so
much gunpowder here I dug sand for three
hours there was there was just so much
TNT to make um and we're just about done
went through like ten shovel repairs and
oh my goodness it was crazy but are you
ready for this bump bump bump bump bump
bump bump bump bump up um but uh look at
all that to you into you guys we are
gonna have some fun with that not today
but we're gonna blow up something
sometime soon very soon oh yeah I should
probably comment on how I'm doing the
crafting here too because there's always
a lot of questions about like how do you
how do you put the items in the chests
so quick or take them out like that's
what you do is you hold shifts double
click to put it in double click to take
it out whatever item you click on is
what it does right and then for the
crafting if you want to craft things
quickly like TNT use your hotkeys like
the 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 wherever your
mouse cursor is hovering over in the
crafting window that's where it will go
so I just press 6 there 7 8 9 and
shift-click to get them down there so
you don't have to drag drop them and
then 5 6 7 8
shift left click crap the whole stack oh
no we got we got skeletons here let's
see I think we just about got all the
Gunpowder is there any way oh there was
a little bit left here okay
I'm gonna finish up looks like we got
well over a double chest worth though a
pap now alright everyone so I think
we're going to wrap things up here for
today I did want to mention though next
episode I think is going to be the big
nexus revealing or ribbon-cutting type
of
type of episode where we actually fire
this thing up for the first time I did
more wiring here like all this stuff up
here wasn't here before
the only thing is where this red clay is
and where these two repeaters are
there's like a line here got to add a
little bit more redstone for the memory
for the selection but this red clay and
this whole selection panel thing is in
the way and I got a tear it down and
rebuild it in place and I gotta like
figure out how to do that because I got
to build it in Reverse like from the
wiring the back of the wiring to the
front yeah it's gonna be tough to do but
I think we're going to get that done
next time and then we'll be able to
start programming things in and getting
stuff where it needs to go and I think
that should be pretty fun but anyways
let's get to the comment of the day for
today it says what has happened to
Flyboys are you still playing it also
what happened to mine crack otherwise
everything is great - keep up the good
work so I wanted to bring up this
comment because a lot of people been
asking about the - with Flyboys
unfortunately hasn't been going very
good for me like I would go on the
server I would try to build stuff and I
was never I was never really happy with
anything I made I've recorded so much
footage like I've really tried but I
just wasn't happy with anything I
recorded and I kept the leading stuff
and it was wasting time and I just
decided and something something about
that series or that mod pack or whatever
just wasn't really jiving too well with
me I don't think but we're not really
officially done with it if there's going
to be a battle and stuff if they want me
to get involved
I'll probably get involved with that so
there may be a few more episodes of that
but I'll probably bail out next season
if they do another season and with mine
crack for those of you that missed it I
know a lot of you didn't tear the news
or whatever but basically I'm not part
of mine crack anymore there was some
business remodeling within the group or
however you want to call it and I
decided to to not be a part of that
there was some trademark stuff I would
have to sign if if I wanted to be part
of it and I wasn't too comfortable with
it and a couple other things just didn't
really make this make sense to go along
with with that kind of stuff so I
decided to to leave yes so if you're
wondering what's up with that there
probably won't be any more minecraft
episode um and yeah just wanted to let
you guys know for all of you asking
don't want to leave you out of the loop
or anything but yeah hope you guys
enjoyed today's episode I'll see you
guys in the next one take care have a
good day bye