[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody here this
is etho and we are back at it here guys
with another episode of the let's play
series how you doing today hopefully
things are good things are going good
with me here if you guys it oh I broke
the boat darn it hate when that happens
am i right if you guys didn't see my
last tweet I actually tweeted oh yeah
you can't fix it anymore and I've had
family visiting here for like the last
two three weeks so I have fallen very
far behind on the videos I'm sorry about
that just had her like hermit quest
pre-recorded and that's like alders Ben
got a couple episodes of project ozone
uploaded while they were here but yeah
I've been I've been busy here and it was
decided like hey let's go to the
mountains all of a sudden and then like
six hours after deciding that we were
leaving to go to the mountains the Rocky
Mountains so I just got back from that
had a lot of fun and my family went back
today and now it is time to get back
into some sort of routine here hopefully
so let's let's get back to it here um so
I built this thing it's trying to make a
launcher to get up to our tunnel there
and I'm having quite a bit of trouble
with it because it's inconsistent right
let you go slow that goes up before you
go over top it so I wanted to see maybe
we can do it a little bit smarter like
try to make it so this pressure plate
and this pressure plate both have to be
down so that like the boat is centered
like in the middle there before it tries
to launch because right now it's like if
either of these get stepped on it gets
launched which is not good it doesn't
really land does it
it's gotta be a visual glitch I think if
I stand here yeah I land on my head then
okay so I tried something here I kind of
added in an and D so when both of these
are down see like if we just step on one
or the other doesn't work but they both
have to be down and then that goes up
right turns out though that doesn't
really work because the and E is just
too slow and I don't think there's any
way to speed it up so it's like if we're
going slow it works just great
look at that perfect but if we get any
speed go and then it's not going to work
so good see it went up but we were we
were long gone by then
lesson of the day here if you're playing
single-player pressure plates go on the
left and the right like this if you're
playing multiplayer if you want this to
activate you got to put the pressure
plate here because that one extra block
from the piston that one extra block of
boat travel time before it gets over
here helps to deal with the leg on the
server while in single-player that's not
really a problem and it's kind of hit
and miss on a server in single-player
this I think over just about every time
though but I'm having one more problem
let's get like some some real distance
here just to make sure we don't skim
over top it that's full speed no problem
which is pretty cool the problem we're
having now is a lot of the time let's go
a little bit slower here a lot of the
time we hit our head you see that like
we hit our head going over top this
thing and you see that like weird just
little movement of the boat there when
we hopped out there's nothing above us
nothing at all for quite a ways here and
we're still hitting our head okay okay
here we go this really clearly shows the
problem so sometimes we get launched
sometimes we don't and to be honest with
you I don't know exactly why
is because of the games not treating
that as a slime block sometimes like
it's pushing us up one block and then
looks like we're going higher because of
like client/server do you think I'm not
sure adding more slime blocks doesn't
seem to fix it now we got a double
extender a slime launcher guys super
high-tech it looks like it's working but
it's it's not it's stuck in the a good
loop here we go in it seems like it's
working ah-ha there you go there you go
so that's not the solution either double
extender
I thought mics might fix it but no now
when you think of itto you think of
Canada and when you think of Canada you
think of wax hockey no no there's one
more thing curling AHA we are also the
masters of curling so see if I can I can
do this right and they're wheel aha so I
made this weird device here where it
brings the boat to a dead stop it falls
down there and then shoots it up and
then shoots it sideways I figured out
this is max height you need for slime
blocks up like this this one at the very
top is what actually shoot sideways with
a one tick one pick pulse so it goes up
and then one tick later goes sideways
and you need four blocks with this if
the boat is unmanned anyways I think I
can't get it to work to find in it oh
man we we are not the Masters of flying
I never said that okay let's try this
I'm going to go in the boats go down
just like we curled it in a kind of
words not much not much sideways thrust
there is there I
wasn't holding any like forward keys
though let's try hold forward failed
first time whoa all right well I kind of
kind of realized this is going to be
hard to find a perfect solution to so
this is what I decided to do just keep
it simple I put it right at the end here
so if you fail the first time you'll
land back on it anyways and whoa
and you'll fisher get up no problem
might take one or two tries sometimes
it'll work the first time and then when
we go back because it's right at the end
there will just float over top of it aha
you guys remember the good old boats
elevators with the water streams those
are the good days and then notch is like
you know what those those are glitchy
those don't make sense
they disobeyed physics and this is what
we have now although it's the nether I
know I couldn't use water streams anyway
whatever
all right very cool guys very cool this
is like totally done now woohoo
so this is what it looks like it's just
like a random collection of purpur
sandstone glass and cyan clay or
terracotta as it's called now I'll
probably continue calling it hardened
clay though mm-hmm
this is what we we got on the outside
let's check out the outside first kind
of a kind of a big purple thing alright
let's go down into the inside of the
tunnel woohoo
so I did the the triple track thing if
you don't know why I do this is just to
prevent mobs from spawning on the ice
which is really really annoying if it
does happen there's a reason I don't use
normal ice isn't there maybe not maybe I
should switch over I kind of feel like I
had a reason for not using it before and
now I'm questioning it mm-hmm
anyways another big change over here is
I got rid of all the chests and storage
and garbage I just keep leaving laying
around it's gone finished up to our
little enchanting area here that's an
nothing too too fancy and you might be
like etho yeah dum dum you can't have an
enchanting station without a crafting
table or like where's your lapis in your
books and stuff look at it
uh-huh these are crafting tables and we
have a sneaky chests back here so all we
need in life can even access it from
here look at that
got our ender chest or anvil so that is
all good and I think we're going to get
out of the nether finally let's do one
one boat trip back up here and just see
there we get lucky and it goes if it
works the first time here ah yeah then
we go over here I still got a triple
track this stuff why don't I use regular
ice
and really thinking about I do like how
the pack dice looks more but when you
put the tracks on doesn't look as good
anymore because like over here I did the
triple track thing as well hmm yeah
because I'm pretty sure regular I still
doesn't spawn mobs right so we wouldn't
have to put the tracks on top which
would be nice it would probably look
better but I was thinking about it we
got to worry about the ice melting if we
use regular ice we also have to worry
about like what's underneath the ice I'd
have to place more blocks because you'd
be able to see through this and like if
there's netherrack on the other side of
the ice it's not going to look good so
it's more work to do that and also a
couple other things here I think like in
this case for example a zombie pigmen
could spawn here and he won't walk over
here because they don't walk on tracks
but if this was regular ice they would
watch here so yeah maybe Pat dice is
still better okay I tell you what guys
we're going to do some investigating
here there's actually something I've
been wondering about mm-hmm so I just
threw it ender pearl threw the creeper
face I landed around here and there was
a skeleton on the bridge here this spot
can actually spawn mobs it's pretty rare
yeah light level 7 no good very bad so I
was here a skeleton was their skills and
start chasing me shot me and then this
kitty cats teleported down into the cave
here from who knows where and I just sat
him down so today we're going to look
into one of the deep dark secrets of the
let's play here you might have noticed
like we have wolves and we got cats all
over the place kind of randomly and I've
never really explained why they're
coming from the mob system so our mob
system uses wolves to scare skeletons
uses cats to spear creepers and some our
villagers to trap
zombies right I think over here we got
got on the roof here I did try to
replace all the wolves in and cats once
let's look inside and to see how many
are left so if I take damage near this
thing like within 32 blocks of one of
the animals I think they'll teleport
outs looks like we've got some activity
in there and you notice those creepers
aren't running they should be running
but I bet you the cats gone that was
over there yeah okay okay so that's not
going to work get them around the corner
yeah I don't really want them to blow up
here okay there was three right maybe
you walked over so before we had both
these spots so there would be I think a
cat down here and a wolf up here on both
sides wolf a wolf bottom cap top okay on
all the layers here's another one I've
been waiting a long time here for them
all fall down sorry I think we're going
to go oh okay ain't quite get them all
so it looks like second layer missing
animals there and and here as well so
this layer is like totally messed up
it's gone this mob system used to be
very effective actually and now I've
noticed it's slowed down quite a bit
because all the animals are gone we got
a cat there Oh
Skelton he's gone okay and this side we
got nothing and woke alright another
layer looks like they're all gone
so yeah it's it's looking bad they need
to be replaced again in the patch notes
I saw they don't teleport if you put
them in mine cards now which is how I
originally did this but they did
teleport out of the mine carts and would
eventually kill themselves
see oh we still have a minecart they're
actually with tracks okay I did a bad
job of finishing this then I guess I
missed this all right guys so we got
three wolves here one in a minecart and
then these two I just have sitting down
there all tamed wolves in the past if I
would shoot myself near these guys they
would all teleport to me the only
difference is the one in the minecart
would then teleport back into the
minecart so we would quickly teleport to
me then and then back within like one
one frame problem is like if you're near
lava or blocks sometimes they would
suffocate or catch on fire and then they
would just die even though they they
were in a mine cards these guys they
would teleport or they they'd sit up if
you would get shot in here them let's
just see what happens now okay so like I
got it so even though they were sitting
down they sat up that's not good this
guy I didn't notice him dude he
teleports I don't think you did
which is what they supposed to be fixed
I think we're good like every one of
those shots you would teleport to me
before so I think if we put them in mine
carts in our mob system they'll be fine
now so I think for today we're just
going to try to get the population these
guys up we need like a dozen of each
kitty cats and puppy dogs and that's
going take a little bit of time in the
next episode we'll try to do it before
and after like before what kind of rates
we gain with the mob system and then
after we put the animals in how good it
becomes I think that'll be cool to see
but I'll put the men off camera cuz it's
gonna be pretty long and tedious I think
oh yeah you guys don't need fish okay I
thought I switched oh yeah why don't
they like each other there we go
and puppy dog okay good stuff sit down
don't run away
now a few episodes ago I mentioned that
something was wrong with the Guardian
farm here I checked it out today it
actually seems like it's fine like look
at that that's pretty good there's quite
a few in there
I did notice there's a lot of zombies
they pick up the the ink sacs doesn't
get stuck there forever so I got to go
in and kill them every so often is there
a way to prevent that I guess if we put
lighting down here they'll stop spawning
in the reeds right is that where they're
coming from yeah I think so okay that's
what we'll do with that but yeah this is
good this is all good still is it wool
or is it woo wool or wool I say wool but
now I'm questioning myself whoa aha well
that's what she said right whoa cool
cool cool wool
oh that's not good okay guys so I think
what we're going to do here I've been
talking about extending this path here
right now goes up to the windmill and
and that's it a dead ends but it
actually goes like from the windmill
follow it down goes through sandy City
connects right up to the man cave so
it's about two three hundred blocks long
right now we want to extend it we want
to go I think from there kind of in
between the two fences there go through
that area wrap it around up to the Nexus
and super smelter area there so we'll
see what we can do with it and the way I
do my path is pretty simple I just like
run with the shovel and see what happens
and I try not to make it straight
and then I just fill it in with gravel
and then I go again with like
cobblestone and andesite with this path
okay so I'm expecting we're going to
want to build this up maybe although
this is like down here right
maybe maybe we lower it and then build
like some kind of cool wall on this side
and a diagonally super-exciting stopped
am i right now we're going to need
thousands and thousands of gravel blocks
right so we're going to go to the secret
stash did you guys know this was here
it's from a long time ago and there's
not enough room for this stuff in the
the Nexus so it's kind of stayed here
but I'm trying to slowly use up the
supplies here we're going to try it old
elevator doesn't work kind of expected
that this is still here though I used to
use that all the time to get down into
the man caves before I built the
entrance to it okay let's take a look at
the aerial view right now it is looking
not super defined over there it's pretty
good though
so I think I'll start filling in here
okay so let's check out the first pass
here see what it's like and it's a good
angle that's okay I like how this curves
a little little curve around the hill
there it's good see how it goes like
that that's I think that's good that's
natural this part might be a bit too
straight here but I like this curve over
here I think that's good yeah it looks
kind of straight doesn't it maybe I
should end up add a bend in somewhere
there okay very good very good
so this is our alternate path I'm going
to change the side back to grass I think
and then we'll we'll use this one
instead let's look from a distance here
always good to get a distance viewpoints
so before I was going to stray
through now can I have a bend in it and
hopefully that would look better mm-hmm
I like it I like it a lot so we're going
to go with it so yeah this is kind of
strange while I was working on the pass
here this guy decided to teleport to me
while sitting down he didn't he wasn't
walking or anything he teleported here
and he was sitting down as soon as he
teleported he didn't move at all and
also I didn't take any damage when it
happened I was just like moving around
and then he was here all of a sudden so
I don't know maybe yeah chunka loaded or
unloaded and then he teleported for some
reason I'm hoping it doesn't happen when
we put them in the mine cards cuz I
really don't want to redo that thing for
like a third time all right guys well I
think that's going to have to do it for
today's episode so let's get to the
comment of the day and let's do it by
the river we never go to the river and I
really like this river it looks so nice
still have some torches here huh it's
not quite finished I'm actually
terrified to do anything here because if
I update this water there's no putting
it back you can't do that anymore
like I'd be really careful with any
changes but yeah here we go it says
anyone else
curious how Ethos sleep schedule is
doing or is is it or is his headphones
are still duct tapes yes not duct tapes
super glued superglue is amazing stuff
they've they actually are still holding
like the superglue hasn't broken I
thought I'd have to reapply it
eventually still good it's amazing it's
like good never broke still using
Kleenex for the padding though on the
headphones and that sucks and some of
you have been commenting like my my
voice is clipping or the pop filters not
working as well now I think that might
be an issue so I might have to do
something about that so I'm not sure
what exactly though sleep schedule sleep
schedule got back to the river got
pretty bad
for a while like at the beginning of
summer it was probably at its worst here
um so I decided you know I got to do it
I just got a stay up later everyday and
it got to the point where I was like
waking up at nighttime and going to bed
during the day and that sucks I don't
like doing that but if I keep doing that
eventually that my sleep schedule rolls
over and it's like hey I'm waking up
it's at 4 a.m. now I'm waking up 5 a.m.
6 a.m. and that's how I got back to
normal again and I was really good for a
few months but then this camping trip to
the mountains kind of frightening again
not too bad I'm like at a 3m for um
bedtime so I can live with that it's
when it gets like 5 6 a.m. 7 a.m. 8 a.m.
it's like man not good not good so I'm
going to have to be very disciplined
here areas guys hopefully you enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and I will see you again in the next one
take care bye bye
[Music]