so I got a question can you make an iron
golem kill a villager is that is that
possible let's find out I need to know
this that you you just stand there don't
move all right uh whoa no I don't think
he can Oh yep yeah that villager was
right between us and he took no damage
hold him back guys I will mess him up so
bad they're not gonna let him get get me
here this is awesome what are they doing
it's like they're all trying to go to
the same spot all right you probably
can't attack this guy but we'll try it
oh I didn't heal enough all right no
more foolishness we know now iron golems
don't cause collateral damage they just
started their targets whoa
so yeah welcome back guys how you doing
how's it going what's going on do you
think I didn't make it all the way down
oh why did I do my intro like this okay
he's on us no maybe he's not on a slab
he might not cause any damage it caused
a lot of damage you didn't blow up my
tree at least this is the very first
custom tree I made I would have been
very sad if he wrecked that oh but look
at look at this let's not do the intros
like that anymore I'll fix it later
okay let's keep going let's go down here
I had something to show you and I don't
want to get distracted all right so
we're gonna go over to the sheep farm
that we started last episode I take your
shortcuts whoa
boy ouch
yes little top on down here I I spent a
bit of time on this I went into a
creative world and like tried to work it
out in a very crazy way like where I'd
controlled each sheep individually and
did all his fancy stuff the thing was
starting he have very big though and it
was getting very complicated so I just
closed that world team back to my LP
world and just tried to figure it out to
your and very happy with what we got now
so I ended up just using a simple date
system over here this block this block
right here we're gonna need that to be
glass so it doesn't suffocate the sheep
and then I'm gonna put one more block
over here so that when a minecart goes
this way it'll crash into that and fall
down here nice and aligned and now what
happens if a sheep in a minecart goes
through here they do the whole thing
come back around oh yeah this is all
this is all not being used that let me
take that out so it doesn't distract you
all right that's all gone let's see it a
couple more times here so when this is
open they can fall down they hit this
detector real instantly this block goes
into place so no more she can can go
down after them it's not till they go
over this detector rail here that this
block gets pushed back over this way
from this piston all right and that
allows another sheep to go through so
only one can go through at a time which
is very important otherwise the whole
thing gets messed up so you see this
block is still here and now it's out of
the way once once they go through the
whole jump pad thing so if another sheep
was to come up it would just wait there
until it goes over this detector rail so
I think that's gonna work out pretty
good all we got to do is make sure we
don't let any sheep to flow back this
way as well so what we'll probably do is
drop them we're gonna run out of space
yep we're totally out of space darn it
let me see here
you know I'll finish this off-camera and
I'll just show you and aha yes so it's
kind of working
kinda we'll see if this goes full-scale
we have three minecarts in there right
now they're working flawlessly but I
think we might have some trouble once we
start adding more so this is kind of
what's going on down here this area over
here is where the sheep reservoir is
basically let's try out a couple more so
for now I think the minecarts are gonna
staff together oh that one snuck in how
to do that what resolved but that wasn't
very good
I think things will get stable though
when it's running but yeah they're
definitely bunching together that's not
good let's just add a whole bunch and
just see what happens when things get
crazy they're all stacking together it's
terrible uh-oh
no way I don't even think I've ever seen
that happen before this is a power rail
over here they have their interlocking
right now ones going this way ones going
to the left and they're like in perfect
strength where they can't defeat each
other or something I don't know
come on no there jamm man I'm pushing up
and stuff it's not moving at all that
that's insane
I'm very sad right now
very sad darn it's that kind of sucks
that means we're gonna have to do
something like this instead where we
control each sheep individually which is
what I was trying to avoid it's very
complicated and it takes a lot of space
so when this minecart would go there
then we would have to power this
junction which is glitched out for some
reason there we go and then the next one
would go to the next one type a thing
and then the next one I think I know why
this happens this is a glitch I think it
has to update no why does that happen
it's very strange actually yeah I'm not
sure what that's about this is gonna
take a lot of space though and it's
gonna be a little bit tricky to do and I
don't feel like doing it today so I'm
not going to oh yeah I took this one way
of course it's not going but it'll run
fine with three four right now alright
everybody so what is next on our agenda
what are we doing well come on guys look
where we are
we're in the nether hub we're gonna be
working on the nether hub today I'm to
try tackle it
so I've talked about it a lot lately how
I've wanted to redesign this and redo it
and make it all all nice and perfect and
wonderful but honestly I think that's a
terrible idea now as great as that
sounds there's some flaws with that idea
I think so
here's here's my thinking behind it
we've gotten used to this I'm stumbling
a lot I keep saying like we we I I why
am i doing that it's because I'm so
excited to talk to you guys I guess that
that has me worried now it's like a
speech problem do i I don't normally do
that do I
I hope not I think it's just in this
clip for some reason alright anyway
so we've gotten used to this I'm sort of
nostalgic with it I'm sure you guys are
as well even though I I could do it
better if I redid it today that is
basically time that we would take away
from doing other things in our world
because we would have to tear this all
down spend time redoing it and like even
this tunnel here for example this this
tunnel is pretty plain and boring I
don't totally liked it anymore but I
spent hours and hours building this
thing and that would be hours and hours
we would have to spend redoing it you
know so that doesn't sound too appealing
it is what it is I think we just have to
accept it and rather let's focus on
making other things that we build nice
instead of deconstructing and
reconstructing let's just focus on
constructing but that said look at this
like it's not done we never did actually
finish it so that's that's what we're
gonna try to do today I've gotten so
used to this netherrack ceiling though I
don't know if we could really change it
to any other colour the only thing I
could think of I want it to look
finished but at the same time I don't
think we can really change it because it
would throw me off so much but we might
be able to do another brick yeah I think
I think I could handle that originally I
was gonna make a dome dome ceiling which
is big basically the shape it is right
now this a little rough in in places I
also originally plan on having lights
all around it with like a minecart going
around and lighting those up I might try
to do that still ignore the voicecrack
there by the way I I tried not to bring
attention to it but I couldn't help
myself
so yeah that's that's what I'm gonna do
I'm gonna first do the ceiling with
nether brick also with the ground like
it's all one one type of block maybe we
could try mix in some stuff I have no
problem with refinement it's just the
whole total reconstructing I think I
would
regret later but maybe bring character
to it we could try mixing another type
of block I don't know if this is the
right type probably not
I don't like cow likes sandstone is very
clean-looking
this has like lines around each of the
blocks which is very distracting so that
might not be the right block to use but
maybe we'll find something all right I
think it's also a good idea to try get
rid of all this wood we placed earlier
oops
I tried redoing the nether hub before
and failed that's what all this wood is
about I never really got too far with it
but nether brick is probably better than
than the wood it actually goes with the
purple pretty good too because it's it's
burgundy right which is red and purple
um yeah I think that's okay I'd like
that
something it needs work yet okay so I
threw in a thing of lights here just to
see what it would be like and I've added
some stairs above those good work out I
think that's okay maybe one more row up
we would go with purple wool just to
finish up or to balance out the look
with the floor on the roof and then from
that we would probably start nether
brick so maybe let's take this out oh
man getting very high up let's go for
some slabs let's see just toss that for
right now Oh Drake drop No double fail
there we go all right so the way I did
it on the ground here I got a half slab
in front of the purple wool we're gonna
do the same thing on the roof except
we'll use a nether brick tap slab and
barely reach it oh no
the worst thing about having slabs on
your floor is it's so hard to do
anything like if you want to stack up
you can't you have to well I guess I
could do this yeah this works just fine
all right so it would go purple and then
this it might look terrible we will see
but I'm gonna do the whole roof and
we'll have a better idea
oh man I can't believe this in all my
time playing in this world I've never
seen a magma cube get into the nether
hub I don't know how he did it he must
have jumped all the way down that 3x3
tunnel like he could barely fit down
there so yeah that just happened I don't
know what I was thinking guys it just it
just kind of happened you know what it
was this this is how it happened okay I
was I was thinking what kind of style
should I build in and I was like oh you
know what sandstone in purple wool
that's that's kind of weird
it's a weird combination that should be
my style I'm gonna I'm gonna build weird
and here we are so yeah I don't know
what to say about it I'm a little
worried I'm going to lose my building
privileges after today you guys are
gonna be like I'm gonna be like you know
what I want to build this today and you
guys will be like no etho you remember
that time you went and worked on the
nether hub yeah just just do some
redstone today it's fine okay well let's
take a look here so I decided to add
these weird shapes to the ground because
couldn't really find anything that went
well with the sandstone and that kind of
blends it a bit or mixes it I guess what
else so we got the stairs and the dome
ceiling going on here
I think the dome shape is pretty good in
the middle I decided to try ice just
because I like
bring together all of this is very
subjective though guys depending on the
feedback and what I think after looking
at it for a while we might be changing
it there's actually a pretty good chance
we'll change some stuff at least now
decided to put ice in the middle this
thing here look very plain so I decided
to try to give it some character and
some shape and I just threw some stares
on it made it look like it was kind of
twisted I kind of liked that but yeah so
where do we go from here what should we
do again this is subject to change but
let's just continue with it let's roll
with it for today I was going to do one
thing here had a pretty good idea I
think yeah over here let's grab this the
carpets we didn't have carpet when I
built this originally and I never really
liked these lights here that's why I
have them in the corner so you can't
really see them unless you're up close
but if we have carpet we can just go
over top all of this and hide the
lighting that's other thing this room's
pretty dark right now we will be putting
or turning these lights on pretty soon
we might need to get some lighting in
the middle though because it is fairly
dark but yeah I'm gonna go all around
with this and then I think what we'll do
next is try to hook these up yeah you
know what the more I look at this the
more I feel like the ice just needs to
get out of here you know it doesn't
quite suit the building but I want to
see what you guys have to say about this
so make sure you leave your feedback
about the design and how how your eyes
hurts from looking at it and all that
kind of stuff we could change this out
with sandstone though would probably
look pretty good anyway we're gonna
focus on these lights next so
instead of doing the Micra thing I'm
going to try do the chicken power thing
I'm gonna have to oh whoops
yeah we're gonna have to remove a lot of
blocks actually so I'm gonna do it like
this let's go up here remove all these
and although trying to think here
because some of these lights are on a
diagnose this is gonna be a bit tricky
to do the way I want but we'll have
chickens running around up here and
probably want least one block up from
these lights oops
trapped so pressure plate on here if
they step on the pressure plates they'll
turn on the lights and it'll be kind of
random this here though for the
diagonals who might put a pressure plate
down here cuz otherwise they'll walk
here and then the lights will be on and
then they'll walk here and they'll turn
on might look a little weird or we could
just keep everything on the light level
put all the pressure plates down here
yeah I'm gonna try that first maybe
alright guys so this is an example of
the chicken power got three chickens up
in the pressure plates there and they're
free to walk around but I think it might
be a failure they don't really move
around a lot they also tend to group up
quite often like there's two over there
and one over there
not too sure the main thing I don't like
about those them noise you can hear them
I don't like that because if we have one
in each corner anywhere you are in the
nether hub you'll probably hear them
unless you're right in the center here
maybe
because you got to be 16 blocks away
from them for to not hear them so yeah
we probably will go for a minecart or a
red stone controlled system what else
what else this is another big thing we
got to work on with the nether hub I
took this thing out for for a ride today
all right Rick I was using this I use
this quite often for some reason a horse
died in it today I hit this buttons to
swap them and like the horse just went
underground through the slime blocks but
yeah this thing's really cool it's not
fully effective right now though because
like if we go out this way this is where
we go to get to the amplified base by
the way the tunnels aren't really done
like at all it's kind of dangerous to
walk here sometimes there's gas that
shoot at us so we got a lot of tunnels
we need to build and they take a lot of
time a lot of time over here is the Mesa
biome this is where I get hardened clay
from but then further on here's where we
especially have a problem no we got a
guest yeah this is like the end of the
line this is not the amplified base here
it's a little bit further down down here
and the thing is like we came and get a
horse down here right now so we got a
lot of work to do with our nether hub
for it to actually be effective this
portal I might just take down let's go
check this out I don't think there was
anything here this is if I remember
right a forest biome like a nice taiga
type of thing
oh all the snows gone
oh no it's up there okay yeah I think
when we first went to the amplified
terrain this is like where we first came
out and saw it for the first time how
many first can I squeeze into that
sentence
but there's not actually anything bill T
or nothing we need here so I think we'll
take this portal out for sure cuz it
just confuses me sometimes I forget what
it's for but anyways guys that's gonna
have to be a project for another day
we're gonna have to wrap this episode up
so got a comment there's a zombie nearby
I think he's outside though we're fine
and we got a new librarian here too
which is cool
um so comet says a etho for your 400th
episode I was asking suggestions for
that it says you should make another
Rube Goldberg machine like you tried to
do in your first world redstone has
advanced a lot since then and there are
all sorts of new new mechanics to
Minecraft I think you should do a
segment of the machine for every 10
episodes so 40 segments I would oh oh
that's a big project I was so excited
when I found out you were going to make
one but then you didn't I think you
should try again I actually really liked
the suggestion I think it would be fun
to try it again a lot of you probably
don't even remember that it was so long
ago but in my old world we spent a bit
of time trying to make one but the
problem I had when I tried it originally
is I did a lot of stuff that relied on
random chance those very unlikely the
machine would work and also I did a lot
of stuff that was kind of slow and would
take a long time to actually activate so
yeah kind of learnt a few things from
that first one but it was unfortunately
not that great but I would like to try
it again if you guys think that's a good
idea
alright mr. librarian I want the best
books in the world you greedy little guy
he wants
more emeralds okay go on
you got two books for sale all right he
unlocked one of them I don't know why
but I just I just love this part this is
my favorite thing about this village is
seeing what book trades we get from
librarians all right so the first one by
the way was fire ESPA to which who cares
next one is o infinity one four seven
pretty good oh and so touch four eight
also very good I think we had so touch
for a cheaper price somewhere though I'm
not sure that's not bad though I was
gonna point this out too by the way a
few episodes ago we built this villager
school it's not getting used at all I
have not seen a single baby villager get
in there I heard damage I have a
concerned parent so what we're gonna do
I think we'll just tear down the wall or
this thing problem is since only babies
can use it it's not getting used very
often and it's not really registered as
a house I think so I'm just gonna leave
it open so that actually it's used at
least but anyways that's it for today
guys
thank you for watching I hope you
enjoyed and we'll see you again in the
next one take care have a good day bye
bye
you