oh I'm gonna be in trouble I know it
welcome back to everybody to another
episode of our let's play series this is
etho I am back from the dead here sorry
sorry about the upload schedule lately
guys I have been sick if you didn't see
my post on Twitter do they call them
posts tweet my tweet on Twitter I've had
I've had the flu yeah the last few days
here still not over it but I thought I'd
try to get a video out for you guys
today because I know you've been waiting
so let's get to it here guys
last episode we looked into this whole
bunny hole concept and you guys seemed
to really really liked it so we might
try to build that base using this today
I'm not sure yet though but yeah we
looked into some of the ways this works
and some tricks with it got some good
feedback from you guys too apparently
there's more tricks to it than I even
realized like one of the big rules I
thought here was you had to have a
transparent block above you so if we
look into oh I don't know if we're gonna
be able to see actually like you got to
have like a slab or glass block or
something non solid above you I thought
was a rule but apparently there's a way
around that as I fall here I have to
press the spacebar so sometimes I
prematurely press it like that but if
you get really good at it looks really
cool you just like automatically going
to the hole here okay so let's try this
apparently you can just force your way
through the solid area so like because
there's a dirt block above there it's
not really letting me go into that space
but if I hold sprint yeah look at that
you can't actually force your way in and
then once you're in the solid blocks I
think it it allows you to keep going
here let's see what happens if we
transition because stone salt dirt
here's some stone yeah it's still going
even if you change block types so that's
kind of cool
that makes us way simpler like way
easier to get around because you only
got to mine one block then instead of to
every block you go forward and another
trick you guys showed me here is if you
have a non solid block so like a slab of
course you can then move into that slab
area but if you try to go forward you
get kind of get locked you got to force
your way through which is pretty slow
when you try to do that there's
apparently a cool way of getting by all
that issue though so I got it's a free
spot over there if we have a piston here
and then we go wrong way go right way
piston wrong way I wonder if we can not
place it the right way
oh no there we go okay so if we push
that dirt block above us while we're in
the the non solid block I think then
it's gonna automatically transition us
to the solid block and then you don't
have that really long wait time to get
through here like this you know so let's
go ahead and try that oh it actually
forced me out of that spot okay maybe I
didn't do that right okay I'm gonna hold
forward this time or left I'll hold left
yeah there you go you go right through
then there's no wait time so that's cool
okay a little bit of redstone here I
just wanted to see can you make this
transition a little bit easier so we're
going from the the slabs to the solid
clay block here if we do this it takes
like five seconds or so and you got to
hold control and you know there's a
little bit to it so I set this up so if
you put a pressure plate down it's going
to extend the sticky piston the slime
blocks will move this pink clay over top
where our head is so you'll notice this
is gonna switch to the pink clay block
when our heads there even still though
if I hold forward it's not letting me
through here so that's and it resets too
which is nice what you got to do is hold
sprint and then it lets you through and
you'll notice it's much faster than just
doing it the other way like just forcing
your way through it's like one second
instead of five but there's an even
better way it seems if you also move the
block
behind behind you get some more slime
down there then you don't even need to
press sprint you can just hold forward
super smooth that's cool that's the way
we're gonna do it and all I did here is
from that that's pressure plate got a
little repeater and then it goes up to
the piston here very simple oh man I'm
getting a little distracted here guys
but I just I just realized something we
can use this for transport which may or
may not be cool well it will be cool I
don't know how effective it would be
though so for example it tries to move
us towards an open air space like if
there's room for our whole body it's
gonna try to push us to that area
automatically so if I break this block
it's gonna move us there but if I
replace it before we get there we don't
leave the solid block mode here okay
well you could probably get it to work
is this not gonna be very good it's way
too slow let's try it it out a little
bit here I didn't fine-tune them the
timing or anything here but I don't
think it's gonna really be good anyways
let's get to the base building here guys
I have spent some time looking around
doing a little bit of planning I think I
got it figured out what I want to do now
for this mini base if we're gonna be
building a base we should actually have
it serve some function cuz if we just
build it like around the mancave area
never gonna use it it's gonna be for
show and I kind of want to build like an
outpost where a base that has a little
bit of everything in it so we're gonna
go a little ways off here and then if we
ever decide to build out this area
around this area then we will have like
a source of maybe some mini farms and
that sort of thing is the plan anyways
and it turns out if we go straight this
way I did a little bit of scouting where
we got here
well did I pass it already might have
passed it thought it was like straight
maybe it gotta go I don't know I think
it is a little bit this way this is an
area we've been to in the past yeah
right over here right over here so this
is actually one of our strongholds in
the world so this will give us a nice
quick way of getting to the end and back
to spawn like if we want to ever if we
ever want to do that where's the way
down guys
young etho wasn't good at marking things
Oh double torch there we go man that was
not - not an easy thing to see no
ladders no ladders what was wrong with
you Ethel I don't even know does this
actually go to the portal it does okay I
never even opened it though yeah I
brought a few ender eyes it looks like I
don't have enough though oh snap but
we're gonna try to build our base in
such a way that it'll also connect to
this end portal and we'll have a quick
way back if we want to oh me oh my this
is actually a really nice area is this
looking around a bit like especially
here we got this like pool down below
then we got nice flat spots up here kind
of an arch going around then there's
this big hill in front of us and on the
other side is where the end portal is
down down over there so I don't know how
it extensive of a base we're gonna make
your but there's definitely room for
potential it's a nice area lots of hills
lots of nice hills rolling hills here I
think where I'm gonna start it like if
we want to make something pretty big
will want to go off that way and we'll
want to go off this way so this is
probably around the middle ish area and
I think it'd be cool like we want to do
some tunnels maybe eventually though
we'll build outside here and try to make
the outside look nice too I think we're
gonna try start over over around here
we'll build like a little balcony thing
alright today is gonna be a bit of a
test too because I have
I have what rimma call it enderchest
explain explain what I mean
shocker boxes I have sort of a put one
of everything in the shocker boxes now
so hopefully I don't have to cut quite
as often when I'm building and stuff if
I ever need to get an item like right
now I need sluice wood sprue slabs so we
have a stairs and slab rocker box now
and look at that spruce labs right off
the bat so I'm gonna make me be a 5/5
for could be cool actually let's go into
the hill a little bit here 5x4 sort of
platform here alright and we're just bit
we're just making like a balcony that's
gonna start tunneling into the side of
the hill here and then we'll go from
there yes do something like this bring
it up and go around should we do another
pillar here aha so I have to cut the
video already but I think it's looking
okay so far I think that's a good spot
for that so let's continue here I
realized if if we're doing some building
here I should really think of something
to talk about so I just took a moment
here to think of something cuz otherwise
I'm just gonna be like okay place it
back here oh that looks nice doop boop
boop so let's let's I have to try to
have a bit of a conversation here today
boop boop
yes today we're gonna talk about
sickness okay getting sick and whose
whose fault is it
alright so in parts I'm gonna blame
myself you know it kind of sucks I just
got sick actually in the summertime
probably not even four months ago I got
a really bad flu in the summer that
knocked me out for weeks and I just got
sick again here this one's not so bad
though at least let's go for we're gonna
put a little bit of a roof over this I
think we'll go for or maybe Teesha or
I'm gonna try maybe sandstone red
sandstone here yeah let's give this a
try but you know I kind of blame myself
because I don't get the flu shots so
maybe that's something I should do I'm
not sure something I asked often
contemplates mm-hmm
okay I think we can do that that's fine
some of you might be like what are you
crazy why don't you just get the flu
shot isn't it free in Canada I think it
is actually it's covered by our health
care which is pretty cool some downsides
obviously if you get the flu shots you
got to get a shot you got to get a
needle that's not fun what's to do that
not me you have to go and actually get
it and take time out of your day that's
that's not fun one concern of mine knows
if I don't get it
I might actually like get other people
sick because if I get the flu then I
might start spreading it that's that's
not a good thing so yeah anyways I'm
kind of curious what do you guys think
about the flu shot do you get it do you
not get it why or why not if you do get
it here's a big thing if you get it you
still get the flu sometimes or if you
get it does it sometimes seemed like it
infects you like I great after you get
the flu shot you get the flu it does
that happen like I'm not sure I haven't
really looked into it too much because
because if the dosage is too high or if
your immune systems weak I could see
that happening right is that a thing I
think I've heard of people getting that
yeah curiously what you guys will see in
the comments about it I'll give you the
big reason though why I don't get the
flu shot personally a little bit of a
story time with etho here I'm looking
for glowstone I think these chakra boxes
they're great but they do kind of make a
mess here starting it quite a few of
them here also need Miska stuff alright
so yeah apparently my family did get the
flu shot quite regularly up until I was
two years old something happened they
gave me the flu shots and I had a very
bad reaction to it is what I've been
told that obviously I was 2 years old
I'm too young to remember it myself but
this is just what I've been told had a
bad reaction to it apparently it changed
my personality they my parents told me
like I used to be a really good
wonderful baby and then I got the flu
shots and I became very cranky like
immediately very cranky and very
stubborn and that didn't go away it it
lasted I remember when I was young I was
a stubborn kid like you could not make
me do anything I didn't want to do I
think up until I was four or five maybe
even longer I can't I don't remember
exactly yeah a little fun fact though a
little story time here I I was very
stubborn up until I think four or five
and my parents kind of got sick of it
they had enough of it that's like okay
we got to do something about this this
can't keep going on you know I should
maybe move this forward yeah so they
were like okay we got to break this kid
we got to stop this so what what ended
up happening
one day I dropped a box of crowns on on
the ground right and I refused to pick
it up like there was no way I was gonna
pick up these crowns so it's like okay
give him a spanking it's like okay
you're gonna pick up the crowns now no
give him another spanking
are you gonna pick up the crowns now no
and this went on and on for I was told
like three hours two or three hours I
believe ended up getting 37 spankings I
think it was in a row and finally
finally they broke me and it's like okay
I'll pick up the crowns and then after
that I was I was a good kid again I
wasn't stubborn anymore
all right well I think we
our balcony pretty much figured out here
I'd worked out some more details
off-camera so I tried to mix in acacia
wood in the in the sandstone there I
think that looks okay
then I added a like a brace at the
bottom there
triple brace kind of staggered them as
well I think that looks cool and some
flower pots and some carpet I think
we're gonna go for orange end and blue
colors for this baseless to go pretty
good together got some orange tulips
here uh-huh
I tried mixing in oak here I don't know
if that's a really good idea but we'll
try it for now let's actually get to the
crawling part of the base now that the
tunneling parts so this is gonna serve
as the entrance exits or one of them
there will probably be many of them and
it'll be something that hopefully looks
good in case we develop the outside of
this area too not just like tunneling
the whole time but let's let's get the
tunneling here all right so maybe we
would keep the carpet going and here's
the thing though I'm not quite decided
what I'm gonna do like oh we can do this
if we're if we're limited to a one high
area we're very uh we're not gonna be
able to do much detail right oh I got
pushed out darn it maybe we should try
to go for the too high I think it'll
look better in general and then some we
might have some tiger spots that are
only only one high let's maybe go for
four about this shape two by three two
tall three wide we'll do like a bit of a
tunnel to begin with here at the base
maybe maybe let's build out a stone
stone goes really good with the cyan
wool color you could do that along the
side and maybe just go like five blocks
and then we'll have another break here
so let's add some dark wood like that
ah my commentary is so good this is why
we don't do building guys I can't like
think and build at the same time I think
a lot of youtubers have this problem
it's very hard to be creative at and
like talking at the same time alright I
got an idea here for this little section
entrance to our base we're gonna
actually use fire I think with this base
that's gonna give us an orange color to
mix in with the blue when we're not
actually using orange I'm sure we'll use
a lot of orange tulips as well yeah
let's go to netherrack both sides here
we'll light this on fire like a so I
think that's outside of range yeah
that's outside of range of the carpets
and then brought some grills put those
in the front and then just probably
cobblestone kind of like that's sure
let's build this up and we'll slope the
ceiling maybe how should we do it well
we definitely need a slab here otherwise
we'll stand up I just I guess we got to
use stairs then so we'll do stairs over
here and over here and slab over here
kind of give it that shape see what
that's like let's go ahead and finish up
here okay flowerpots over there and over
there and over there
yeah okay maybe what would look nice
orange tulips is that gonna be too many
orange tulips I wonder it's quite a few
orange tulips alright so we got fire we
got weren't you two looks great so now
this next section here I think we're
gonna go for more of an intersection I
want to be able to turn left now and
start going that way let's see if we go
this way how far till we hit the surface
pretty soon here so we might need to
start going downhill as well so we kind
of want to go off off that way because
that's where the end portals gonna be
yeah I think I think what are the keys
to this building style when you're in
miniature mode here
is like this is one block tall this is
two blocks tall this is three blocks
tall so we're like in a three block tall
room even though it's a block and a half
everything gets shrunk down half the
size because of our lower in perspective
so to get more detailed like minecraft
is very limited I tried some something
here though you can see you can mix
stone brick and cobblestone very nicely
together I think this is cool so you can
get more detailed by texture mixing and
also they've they both have stairs and
slabs with the block type so that's good
so I have put some stairs here as well
and this room feels very detailed very
finished to me now let's go ahead and
move on here
so this next room the intersection I
think I want this to kind of go
something like that and then off this
way as well in the middle here we're
gonna have a drop maybe let's go for
some dark oak just for now probably it's
free by three hole here I would like it
if we could look down there without
actually falling down I don't know if
that's gonna be possible
but we'll try it out and do that's okay
maybe maybe it's some fences around this
- should we let's just do it like this
all right we might mix in some stairs
with this dark oak just for more detail
as well but let's go for this right now
and stairs around here and then every
corner we might go up like that yeah
anyways let's continue on with our
sickness stock the the main person I
blame for me getting sick is all of you
everybody but me because when you get
sick it's usually because you're around
somebody else that is sick right and
they pass it on to you that's the way it
goes that's the way it is
so my my thing that I want to say today
something we don't really do in society
is sickness shaming like we're yeah you
really rag on someone like oh why are
you out sick that's that's such a bad
thing to do you're gonna get everybody
else sick to a certain extent I think
that's a good thing
but you don't want to take it too far
obviously rather the better thing is we
should all be a little more careful when
we are sick I think it's something we
all do we go out when we're sick and we
get other people sick just because we we
can't stand to stay at home or we got
something important to do but a lot of
people you know it's like they they
really don't need to go out but they're
still going out when it they're sick and
to you I say stay at home if you don't
absolutely have to be out when you're
sick don't do it to stay at home get
better so you don't get everybody else
sick ah yes very ugly indeed so I've
been experimenting with this
intersection room now it's really liking
it too much I think we're gonna go for a
redesign oops so I've learned to maybe a
few things here though I think just like
avoid the window for right now the ugly
window and some of the other weird stuff
just the size of the room like the shape
of it might be a bit on the large scale
when you're at this perspective so 1 2 3
4 5 6 7 blocks from there to there think
we should maybe keep rooms at the most 5
blocks would feel a lot better a lot
more cozy this is this I wanted this to
feel like a fairly big room but wait up
we got to cram it down a bit more
alright guys well this episode is
getting a little bit long so I decided
to make some progress off camera here
went for a different take this time so
check it out got like a beautiful nature
room here oh look at this so nice nature
builds are my favorite team in this game
if you guys don't know like anytime I
can build out in nature I just love it
so easy or I find it so easy cuz there's
so many lock choices you can use so it
is actually pretty challenging building
small though I gotta say like every
single block really makes a huge
difference on the overall look so one
thing that I found really helped was
using trauma and dirt here so you have
these little little bump ups every so
often that adds a lot to the overall
kiosks or the overall things that break
up your eye here as you look compared to
when it was like all grass here
yeah I think it's quite nice turned out
okay doesn't really do much this is more
of an intersection room but I did put in
like a little fishing station we can get
our fishing right here let's see if this
actually works and we fish in small mode
looks like we can oh yeah fresh water
fresh fishies no fishies they fixed the
fishing in 1.11 by the way so the bobber
actually settles where it's supposed to
go instead of like up in the air a block
or two so it's pretty nice if we're
gonna get any fishies oh here we go yeah
except we can't actually get it started
so you had a secret sea lantern there if
I go down I tent you back up so not the
best place to do fishing actually what
else got a brewing station here I tried
putting a trapdoor up here I was hoping
you could still like stay underneath it
but you do go out of tunneling mode so
that's not that might not work there
actually well anyways guys I think we
should probably call the episode here
for today so let's get to the comments
it says etho hurry up and play Terraria
1.3 for new items and dungeons go wake
up zits News Channel yes I checked it
out right when I came out 1.3 for when
did we play immunes these two I think
- and I proper grammar come on I think
it was 1.3 - right so I missed the 1.33
patch totally honestly like I played it
I think 10 hours like right when it came
out the 134 and within those 10 hours
over a few days or whatever I didn't
find anything new I don't think except I
noticed the deserts had storms now but I
didn't really notice any changes so I
don't think it's really warranted to
start a brand new playthrough with just
the last two patches or so maybe it's
maybe you have to get the hard mode
first I'm not sure but I didn't find
anything new I don't know anyways I am
hoping that terraria overworld or
whatever's is eventually gonna come out
or overwatch or Tory or something with
an O but it got delayed
it sounds like they started working on
it or they they posted something on it
recently that they're still working on
it so hopefully eventually gets released
and who knows we might play that but
yeah do you guys have ideas for the new
base on how we can add some variety to
it and whatever please let me know in
the comments but anyways hopefully you
enjoyed the episode until next time take
care bye bye
[Music]