your readings everybody this is etho
although I'm wearing Steve skin once
again logged in must be broken
doing a whole bunch of enchanting to
start out the episode so here we go well
excellent give it give me all of the XPS
go perfect we are going to do a pic all
right here it is oh dang got lots of
those I don't need another one
okay let's head back and that was a Miss
somehow through to woo hoo now her all
that one that one was perfect
that's good
those you can never complain about
that's like one of the best enchantments
he can get whoo aah chanting stuff is so
much more fun now I would like to get a
whole bunch of looting swords if I could
there's the leg again I would like to
set up a more permanent and chanting
station here sometime Oh
looting - I was excited there for a
second still good it's just not perfect
she grabs a blazer on Stu alright now
I'm going to do at least another batch
yet though oops went uh went a little
bit too far there we're at 400 over 400
I was on the minecraft server while I
was doing this and I got distracted
should be okay yeah the game works a lot
better than 1.3 like when that happens
because I used to crash it 250 quite
consistently and if I didn't restart the
game I would actually corrupt my my save
file here so they've made some great
improvements in that way
oh I thought I didn't get it there vers
eggs like where's the XP what's going on
here locked in at 10 frames per second
and I made my tools already so this
should go quicker going to do a pic
first again Wow oh good
I'm actually really running out of soap
type stuff I've been harvesting so much
ice lately okay
back again we'll do the shovel this time
oh very good next up is the sword let's
try get looting three once again No dang
it okay we are going to do another sword
still trying that's actually a good sort
though happy about that alright so that
was round two pretty good we enchanted
for more things and we have bunch of
blaze ready to go again
awesome
daga Matt I accidentally made one two
three four five six seven eight nine 10
11 12 13 diamond swords i shift-click ah
dang mmm about another 400 hehe this is
going to be that's the right button
right I got ya it's gonna be our last
round I think should keep us going for a
while with all these tools whoo speed
yeah that's so weird having that delay
here it eat those that we only have the
highest frame rates for our videos we
are extremely professional
okay we'll do a pic again good good
stuff okay let's do the shovel excellent
and since we made all these swords we
may as well do a few enchantments on
them ah de looting three no no we might
get thirty make it thirty we did it
all right we can do another one I was
five and one go I thought there one of
those come on all right well we did a
bunch in chanting there that went pretty
good that get on to work
aha so today is the day we're going to
try work on the village get it going
let's go through here double check our
guys are still here there should be two
yep still still happy in together this
is where we left it last time we're
going to set off some more TNT around
there I think we just want to extend
this further so I think if we go we set
it off somewhere around here oh let's
just check this this might be my old
spiders on it if I remember right
although I think that's more this way
why it's even dark here and well okay I
think we're safe to blow this up then
we're going to blow another big crater
here we should do I did make a backup in
case this backfires let's go about here
yeah and I'm going to start laying down
some TNT yeah I think that's I think
this is a good spot
mmm-hmm excellent let's try this out
this is all the TNT I had I really need
more about it's just under a stack and
maybe let's go a little further away
just a little bit further
you never know that probably won't even
set it off will it still burning still
burning should come on you can do it
still burning Wow come on
should have poured some gasoline on it I
guess so how's everybody doing today I'm
doing well I could go for some more
coffee
feels like it's Coffee time okay come on
ah uh-huh let's have a staring contest
with this TNT ah I you know they nerf
fire a long time ago and I was never
really happy when they did that it used
to be used to be fun you know it was
guaranteed to him if you light something
on fire it's gonna go all go up pretty
much now it's like who knows what's
going to happen burn so slow it's random
what's the time it goes out unless you
have a lot of fuel this time it should
definitely go very anti-climatic though
ah well I just okay fine
not as big as the previous one
I don't think previous explosion that's
not bad though we cleared out a lot of
space with Daddy
even still let's just check it out
yeah look look how much space left
cleared out there as the most important
thing to me that it cleared out a fairly
high high amount of space not just yeah
this this is perfect so I'm going to
tear down this wall
tear down the wall I say and it should
feel pretty open up opened up in here
and then we'll put our village start
building it somewhere around here well
there we go guys this is what we are
working with now it's a lot of space
it's a big mess a really big mess
there's mobs around there's tunnels
everywhere I've been looking at it for a
while trying to decide how I want to do
it all and got roughly a plan first
thing just a I'm going to do I think
that this level here will be our ground
level so I'm going to shave this all off
and then with these millions of holes I
have around I'm going to start filling
them in just so you can get something
flat to work with wait yeah yeah that
should be about right and I talked about
what kind of blocks I plan on using for
this it's going to go with industrial
theme with lava and stone bricks and and
grass and all that slight change of
plans I think lately I've been building
a lot with snow and ice and I really
liked it it looks really good it's a
pain to collect it but yeah it's cool so
we're going to try to do an ice village
like pretty pure like mostly just snow
and ice might be one other type of block
like stone brick mixed in might still
put lava in that in if it'll look cool
it might not make sense
but yeah it's just what I'm thinking so
I'm going to have to put a layer of snow
all over what I'm putting down here and
I should probably go through these
tunnels a little bit more on this one
dead ends some of them have dark spots I
don't want to hear mobs once I fill them
all up like I'm going to cover them so
mobs can't get into here but I want to
make sure there's no dark spots when I
do that otherwise I will hear mobs
always when I'm in this area right so
snow ice filling up the holes what else
what else so we're just starting with
this make this area here we're going to
put a few houses around like a central
circle type thing that will all be
pretty close together and then we'll
expand from that and as we work on this
we'll add decorations and stuff like
that to it it's not going to be stone it
won't look like this when it's all done
all right so we flattened out a bunch of
land here and we also harvested a bunch
of snow so we should be ready to go here
I marked that as the center those four
torches there it's in line with this
door and I think that'll work out good
what I what I'm going to do first is
just mark out a 16 by 16 circle so 1 2 3
4 5 6 7 8 see how big that looks and go
from there and then put the houses kind
of around it 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 like 1 2 3
4 5 6 7 8
I hope I'm counting right 1 2 3 4 5 6
wait 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
alright so we got go a little more this
way for sure but yeah I've read up a
whole bunch about villages and villager
behavior and how a house gets considered
to be part of a village and and all that
stuff and there's a lot to it there
really is that's it's a pretty cool game
mechanic should feel listen and also I
read up about sieges I had no idea those
were even in the game I never knew that
and I just that's what happened look in
last episode when I had all those
zombies just going crazy lost our priest
and a whole bunch of villagers to them
just cuz yeah just spawn like crazy and
like like 3 would go after one villager
at times it's not so apparently there's
sieges that can occur in villages even
if even if the village is lit
they can still spawn like in the village
you benefits lit up so you really need
iron golems or something to help protect
against that that might have been will
happen to good actually with when Anders
L did the prank who knows but yeah
there's lots of cool little mechanics as
far as the breeding goes I'm not going
to build one of those
how is this looking how big is this I'm
not going to build one of those breeding
cell things I think that would take away
some of the fun from this because I
think it'll be exciting every time I get
a new villager yeah I'll have to mmm
feel like I need more TNT you go to blow
more space or something maybe I'll make
the circle smaller I'll try a smaller
circle or not you know it does look like
a good size I just need to clear out
more space really all there is to it
I tried ice instead of stone brick and I
think that'll work out better besides
having villagers that can get be cool to
have a whole bunch of snow golems
running around here too so if you if you
use stone brick though the snow golems
are going to leave a snow covering over
top so you won't see it if you use ice
though they won't do that so that's one
of the reasons I decided to change it
and I'm just playing around with designs
here I'm going to be pretty creative
with the lighting I'm sure with this too
as ice melts let's mark this with
something besides torches it's going to
be real dark until we start settling in
here just want to try three circles
that's the center let's try put one here
three tiny circles inside the circle
I probably should moved it over more and
just see how that looks
I really need light though I need to
figure out what the light level is for
melting ice actually like exactly what
it is so I'm having that trouble I
thought it was supposed to be 12 maybe
we'll just set up a test here and I do
see you there or not he's gone put a
torch here that's 14 13 12 put one there
and we will put one here and in a little
while we will check those up maybe we'll
do a fourth one so two blocks three
blocks one two three four and one more
there mmm yeah that doesn't look quite
right circles need to be up one maybe
the bottom ones oh my goodness I just
walked away for a second to get us so
touch unbelievable there are so many
mobs there now
what the heck
I think I had that many tubes lit up no
no no can't believe that I've never seen
anything like that over here you gotta
try this again I'm gonna walk away one
more time just just watch it okay
Moulson we're gone let's just walk away
see if they spawn I came in here I just
saw it like 100 spawning like they all
spawned yeah look at that that's unreal
huh all right anyway I'm going to fix
that pattern mmm I don't know guys this
is uh this isn't looking too good
I guess we'll break this into two two
things here first of all what do you
think of the pattern and second of all
what do you think of the block choice
personally I think this isn't going to
work I don't think we can do I think we
have to make it a rule where we can't
use ice on the ground is if we use ice
on the ground
we can't light up the snow and if you
don't light up the snow it looks
terrible absolutely terrible and I let's
just check what we got going on here so
it's been a while and only this one's
melted this is 14 13 12 11 so at light
level 11 is when ice melts
yeah it's going to be real tough to
light this up with that rule so maybe
maybe I'll play around with it a little
bit this is supposed to be again this is
supposed to be like a center and then
houses all around it and then also
branching off to maybe other areas
including up here yeah and this whole
area is supposed to be snow snow and ice
when this is done so I'm going to have
to imagine it a bit all right this is
with a different type of block we got
stone bricks now and I don't like it too
much so we're going to try something
else
here's another block type we got the
dark planks I like this a little bit
more than the stone stone brick but I'm
still not sold on it J new idea new idea
I think this one's going to be the
keeper what I'm going to do going to put
lava on the stone brick I put stone
brick around the circle and have lava
then glass and I think that will look
really cool you get rid of the torches
in and yeah I think that's I think
that's what we're going to try to do
here also I thought of another idea for
a pattern which might be better let's
try this out like fulfill this in first
I noticed something here over here it
kind of makes like it quarter circle so
I thought it might be cool to try do
this OOP this ready do something like
this and then shovels are too good way
too good sometimes like that
if we do that in all four corners let's
see how to look okay that gives us a
pattern like this and this is looking
cool let's let's continue we'll join
this these circles maybe here and then
see what that looks like
ooh awful ah once we once we figure out
what we're doing here it'll go quick
don't worry
sure bit the houses I kind of want to
build out of ice but I think I have to
put some kind of roof over that I don't
think they work if it's totally
transparent type of block all right
what's this look like that's pretty cool
um let's try one more thing here just
ten another idea let's do one of those
other circles inside it'll be kind of a
highlight that way and everywhere I'm
hollowing out here is going to be glass
with lava below that's the plan all
right let's check this out
yeah I think you'll be cool okay so
that's that's what we're going to try
out I'm going to line line it all with
stone bricks oh my OCD feels good and
then fill it with lava and put the glass
and we'll see what it looks like and
there it is
so I'm liking this a lot more than what
we had before makes more sense it's a
lot brighter and should work out good as
long as no creepers blow up on here that
would make a huge mess lava plus snow
and glass oh just everything would be
gone and leaking everywhere um yeah so I
started expanding this ooh this is going
to keep spending out quite a bit I'm
going to have to tear down a lot more of
the caves to like this has to go back
further every direction by a lot it's
going to be a big project hopefully I
think it's more T&T and will will expand
further but the very least this will do
for about four to eight houses I think
in our village and the main point of
this thing is just time a central
central point for the villagers to Kleck
together which i think they will pretty
sure they will with this maybe we have
it set up and once we get the houses
around of course but it's getting to
that time where I need to call it an end
to this episode I would like to get more
done but I did a lot of tearing down and
retrying other things if you have ideas
let me know as for the ice most of its
probably going to go on the walls and we
will probably try some icicles hanging
from the ceiling I think that'd be cool
and I do want to try building the houses
for the villagers out of ice not sure
how that's going to look or how it's
going to work out but that's something
I'm definitely going to try
and we will do that next time
so let's let's wrap this up we'll go
read through some comments real quick
and call it an end gather round boys and
girls it's comment reading time and we
do not have our library so we will we
will just read them over here for now
one day we'll have it so first comment
episode 151 is the ice biome portal
thank you for this this is a response to
last episode where I found a random
portal an ice biome and I was convinced
I did not make it but apparently I did I
went and watched one I watched episode
151 and at the end of it I built it so I
guess I just forgot so it was me all
along
I am the culprits second one eat though
could you do a tutorial on your man cave
or is there a video or something on it
there's a let's play on it watch from
episodes 104 to now but as far as the
tutorial go there's basically three
rules three main rules on going by here
using grass for the floor not using
torches for lighting that's the ultimate
goal there's still some around which I
have to deal with and thirdly try to
make everything I build go with the
natural terrain without having to adjust
it too much so that's that's the rules
to my man cape here or the tutorial to
it whatever if though whenever you go
into your inventory in the series for
some reason you never have armor AHA
this is true for the most part I got
this from the village last episode this
is what I usually wear in in the let's
play just diamond boots with feather
falling for that's that's good enough
for me I very rarely died two mobs or
anything in this game anymore in
single-player anyway so to make it more
challenging I just wear diamond boots
and I only wear diamond boots
so I can enter pearl around quickly
otherwise I would probably wear nothing
number four I think I enjoyed the
silverfish farm the most out of every
project you have done so far thank you
thank you very much what you would
really like to see you use them for
mining in the future maybe I'll try to
get that going for next episode haul a
bunch of them over like I said they are
ready for harvesting so could be cool I
would like to see that too give me
monies this is actually for him let's
make a trade excellent
new trade option what do you got ah we
got paper again 29 ah man it's brutal
brutal but yeah that's all we're doing
for today guys thank you for watching
and I will see you see you again next
time