hello how's it going everybody this is
etho welcome back to another episode
here in the bump bump bump bump bump
bump the chocolate dome look at this
place guys what do you think of it huh
it's pretty dark pretty brown I know
there's other things that are brown but
if you ever refer to this as some sort
of bowel movement I will I will kill you
no that's not empty threat maybe it is
okay so I i voice cracked that was
embarrassing
I really like this guy's I think it's
good it was a close battle between the
black clay and the cyan clay in the
comments I was trying to I asked you
guys what you preferred and I think the
black clay won by just a little bit it's
my it was my favorite too though so
that's why it gets special treatment the
red and hardened clay were probably next
in line but they were not recommended
nearly as much I just wanted to try
something here let's see this what
happens if we totally enclose the sides
in that glass uh-huh kind of has a weird
feel to it doesn't it it's almost like
sensory deprivation of some sorts like
your eyes you pretty much only focus on
the floor here and you just feel like
you're trapped in a small space it's
kind of interesting I want to try
something here if we get rid of all the
torches it's going to be really dark
right I'm assuming yeah obviously but we
should go get a night vision potion and
I just want to see what it's like if we
if we have that going because I got to
figure out how we're doing the lighting
and if we do lighting the issue is
creepers are going to blow it up all the
time right so maybe we should just plant
it so that we have to use a night vision
potion when we fight in the arena here
this one here yes but
okay let's grab a couple of these and
we'll go check it out
in today's episode guys I think what
we'll do is we're gonna start that Rube
Goldberg machine that we were hopefully
going to do for the 400th episode
because I kind of like to do something
specific or special oh dude there's so
many in there just a second let's live
knit like I've I have lost of words
right now the words have escaped me I
don't even know what to say about that
I've left this area dark many times I
don't think I've ever seen that many
mobs in it when I came back oh I should
have been in there when I did that
actually so we saw the difference holy
oh it's very interesting isn't it
there's no way I could kill all these
mobs you know what I want to get out of
here actually creeper king let me go by
oh and clothes yeah thank you for
helping me cat you can sit down now you
did your job
you did nothing they're still at it in
there uh-huh
Oh what do you guys think of that is
that too dark is it too weird let me
know we might go with this so I wanted
to shoot all the bats and now I can't
cuz these guys are in the way look look
how clearly you can see these bats oh we
can't get them he's too far in the
corner
got him yes what are they doing they're
like fighting each other anyway I'm
wasting time here yeah so we're going to
work on the Rube Goldberg machine today
guys I think what we'll do is a ghost
scout out of location I'm going to go
try find one maybe in the amplified
terrain would be cool okay so how about
over here this looks pretty good right I
looked around for a little while and
this looks like the best spot that I've
found so far anyway so we got lots of
elevation changes the terrain looks cool
we'll try to keep everything built
within sort of this enclosed loosely
enclosed area and we're going to start
it right here I think okay so I I'm
going to try go through this as quick as
I can with you guys and then I'll polish
it up off-camera but I put some thought
into it we're gonna give the Rube
Goldberg machine a seam and it's going
to be villagers bad day okay so we're
going to start out with a little
villager Shack or house up on top of the
hill here and when he goes outside we'll
have the door blocked off while we're
working on this but then when we're
ready to start the machine will just
remove like a block in front the door
and he'll be able to get out when he
goes outside though he's going to find
the land has washed away outside his
door here so we're gonna dig down I'll
build the house off-camera because if we
focus on that too much we're not getting
anything done right all right and we're
gonna set up some water streams down
here hopefully and it'll wash the
villager down this cliff I'm hoping we
want stuff with lots of motion and
that's fun to watch so I think watching
a villager go down a cliff would look
pretty funny let's just see what happens
if we put ice here in here we're going
to make a big mess getting it to flow
nicely down here it's going to be tough
and we got to make sure the villager can
escape the water too as he goes down I'm
kind of hoping you'll just like kind of
Bend
up and around yeah something like that's
good I would say we're going to stop the
water around here somewhere though oh if
we can alright so that's pretty cool
now to actually get the villager into
the water we're going to have to do
something though outside his door we're
gonna have to put some trap doors so
he'll walk off the ledge here oh this is
getting tricky already I don't have a
chess set up or anything so my
inventories a mess I want to build a
house I can actually store stuff there
and you can see I got TNT and TNT
minecarts that's right we're going to
have some fun with that I can't think of
anything more fun to watch then like TNT
minecarts moving around and blown up so
hopefully the second step of this is we
can get into that I'm trying to do
something here what was it trapdoors
let's get some trapdoors so we'll have
to make it so he paths finds his way off
a cliff and he'll walk into the water so
maybe if we just do something like this
and over here he'll try to walk over to
these trapdoors but he won't be able to
inhale just fall down although here he
could let's move this one like that and
we'll get the water down oops
we'll get the water - over here - okay I
need a tiny a moment here to polish it
up one second okay very cool so I got
this first part polished up a lot a lot
better now
we actually got a building here for our
villager and I'm just using this for
myself as well currently as like a
temporary work base so I got a bed in
here and my chess and stuff uh-huh so I
did ring over Golden Apple weakness
potion as soon as I see a zombie
villager at nights here I'm going to try
get them into here and we'll lock them
in
once we do that I guess I can still
access stuff from outside yeah because
once we get a villager in there he's not
getting out we're going to block the
door and you'll be trapped right and
then to actually activate the Rube
Goldberg machine here what we'll do at
night time we'll remove the block from
the door and then we'll head down to
over here where this bed is we got to
think about where we're going to be
watching this as it runs - so I thought
this would be a nice vantage point to
start it off that villager will come out
the door and he'll fall in the water and
we can watch them go all the way down
but start the machine all we got to do
is sleep in the bed and then in the
daytime the start of the day villager is
going to start his day out very badly
he's going to come up the door and it's
going to fall fall in the water and make
his way down to here alright so we
should test this out let's double check
I got the water streams all right try to
try to get it just right so I built up
the banks along this river - as you
might notice so hopefully there's no
place for the villager to get out as I
go down here I'm just going to hold
spacebar because that kind of mimics how
mobs behave in water they do move a
little bit too but not very much don't
think they'll be able to get out of the
water here though it's actually quite a
bit slower than I had hoped
darn it alright maybe it'll be like a
slow epic start to the whole thing I'll
just slowly watch them go down here and
then they'll get to this point and
they'll fall down alright
very cool so at this point that's kind
of like the first and second step I
guess first step is I'm falling into the
water second step is I'm going down the
water stream third step let's start that
and I did not bring what I needed
let's go back up what I want to do is
try to get the villager into a minecart
at this part so what I'm going to do is
grab a dispenser might need redstone
oonh yeah so as he falls down
OOP I guess we can take this down
ourselves as he falls down here I'm
going to make them hit some tripwire so
maybe we should raise this one block so
it doesn't take damage to I don't know
what we're going to build the track out
of I'll just put that there so it'll be
a rail here OOP goes that way we'll have
a dispenser to release a carts and I
think when this release is a minecart
it'll pick up the villager so we just
need to activate it so we'll have a
tripwire here and here okay and we'll
connect it to the dispenser and that
should be good I think we'll have to
make sure he can't actually get out of
here though so we'll need to build it up
- all right and up here - sure oops
not there if I do that he can't get down
we need one over here maybe like that
sure all right
and I had an idea let's go back up here
we might redo this first step like where
the part where he falls in the water
it's a little bit lame having him just
walk off the ledge I was sneaking let's
try one thing here and I might regret
this but we're gonna try activate it
with TNT
I have no clay how have I used all the
clay up you'll just grab a couple pieces
okay I'll fix that later I think what we
could do is just have like a three by
three by three thing of clay and we'll
put a piece of TNT in the middle and we
might even make it so the water gets
released then - instead of it always
flowing here like maybe part of the
cliff blows up and then he falls down I
really wish I had more clay we're right
by the clay mining outpost by the way
should be easy to get some but I didn't
plan ahead grab a little bit more okay
put the TNT in the middle here let's get
rid of these trapdoors so maybe instead
of them just like watching out the ledge
we'll make them step on a pressure plate
with a piece of TNT in the middle of
this I don't think it will hurt him and
it would have a much cooler effect that
way something like this we'll have to
make it so other mobs can't activate it
though we'll just try it for right now
I'm going to put some of my stuff away
here just in case I'm wrong about this
but I don't think it's gonna kill me you
can take off my boots and my armor so
we're the villager coming out in the
morning we step over here and yeah we're
fine
so if we could make it so the water
starts flowing then that would be really
cool oh man I think this might work guys
let's try it out I got water in the the
corners so one here one here and then
two in the middle there going to be
behind clay like this and oops not there
let's just build it up like it would be
I'm just using red clay because I got
lots of it around here we'll use it
something that actually matches in the
official version but this is just a test
alright and do that in that let's put a
tnt there there and there
oh that's not right how did I do that is
one of them
oh man that water's in the wrong spot
umm wonder if that'll be okay let's just
try it let's see what happens I thought
it was over one more cover this up and
we'll have the pressure plates over top
each of these there and there I guess
and we'll probably put a fence around
here just so no other mobs can get in
and activate these at nighttime or
something stupid alright so it'll be
like villager comes out in the morning
to get his newspaper
and uh I was worried about that no my
stuff no no no and I haven't made any
backups yet so it's gone it's gone the
water worked well though look at this
made it all the way down I got some
stuff I got my shovel oh that's sad
because uh the tnt blew it up doing a
little bit once so losing the tools
isn't so bad like I got books and stuff
I can replace him I had a I didn't have
my sword on me that was one of the
tougher things to make and I had a
backup pick I got my shovel back it's a
cheapo axe I had laying around so I'm
pretty much back in terms of tools oh no
I can't name its I'll name it next time
dip Strider on there the thing that
really hurts about that though is the
Redstone and I had like 20 dispensers on
me those are such a pain to make I had
rails ahead my repeaters and I'm low on
redstone this is it this is all I got
left
I've lost the stack of TNT would you
know all the stuff that actually takes
time to get I had on me tools you know I
got lots of that laying around it
doesn't hurt so bad
the redstone so sad okay guys we're
getting back on track here oh no no no
no no I want him to come in but I don't
want to be in here when he comes in
let's do this let's grab our stuff all
right and you come didn't work Hey
Oh okay I don't want it I don't want it
oh no I don't want to kill you I love
you so much oh I can't do it darn it
hey how's it going all right let's try
this again we'll do the old switcheroo
on him oh and there got him get kill his
friend and we should be good to go here
aha
now I can't reach him I hear another guy
coming too ah ah okay got him oh oh wow
they didn't get me there oh but he's got
my sword this is wonderful um darn it I
got to get this other guy back inside
before daytime too otherwise he's gonna
burn although he does have a helmet so
stupid all right go back I am just
having the best of luck here today
things were on the upswing - I thought
we were gonna get get back in a good
groove here get close that and close
that okay good good good
got all my stuff yep okay so I'm gonna
wait for that guy to convert I'm going
to work on this and hopefully we'll see
it when it's all done here okay guys
let's get serious now this is going to
be our first real test here it's just
turning night time which is perfect
got a fenced off area here so mobs
should not be able to get in here hello
we got a villager just realize something
this pressure plate here I put it right
in front the door now I should not make
a wood pressure plate though because
when I break that block above its going
to activate it that's better
okay so rather than having the three T's
separate I've linked them all together
to this pressure plates and we're
going to cover it over top they should
all activate at the exact same time
there should not be any of that crazy
chain one after another type of thing
going on here I should be safe to break
this block now the villager won't go
outside because it's nighttime right mr.
villager yes okay so when I sleep that's
when it should activate the whole thing
and I am I forgetting anything I think
we're good I think I got the water
streams rights that's that was a pretty
big challenge got our bed here I got it
set up so the villager should go in the
minecarts and I just made a little bit
of a track now not much right now that's
going to be the next part of this if
this works so let's try it out okay so
this is how we should start it up I
don't know how long it's going to take
the villager to go outside it's kind of
random maybe maybe we should start up
here actually it's pretty far away I'm
almost wondering if I should be like on
a minecart that sort of goes with it as
it moves because this would be a nice
place to start
villager please go outside it's
beautiful out today it's no rain there's
never any rain in the Mesa it's perfect
all the time you should never be inside
what's he doing did he die no you're
live oh it's gone outside he activated
the TNT oh what a fool and he gets
washed away always having a terrible day
what a bad day I still have some water
stream left down there just so that the
flow would work correctly I don't know
if I should do something about that you
get he gets through that pretty quick
oh now something activate the carts the
blocks oh I see okay
mmm I'm not sure what to do about that
I'll have to think about it
I just say beat him down he's still
would have a mic hurt that's awesome I
did make a backup this time guys so I'm
just going to reload that and we'll be
back to where it was okay let's not test
this right away again but I'm pretty
sure it's going to work let's put this
here for looks get some torches what I'm
going to do to prevent the items from
hitting the tripwire is just make a
little item catcher here like that's
good and it wash away the redstone the
villager should be able to swim over top
that let's just make sure I'm gonna hold
space on the villager okay what I can do
and yet still gets the spot that's great
okay so that should take care of that
problem I just went and did a supply run
I forgot to drop this stuff off oh man
that that's what takes the most time
with this is just running back and forth
getting stuff now we're going to start
the next section of this so we're going
to build it like in stages and then
hopefully for next episode we'll have
like a grand finale where we see the
whole thing run through and it works
flawlessly hopefully I have an idea for
this next part in it this might be a
pretty big part of the whole Rube
Goldberg machine like this mechanic
we're going to put a TNT minecarts in
here we're going to take advantage of
the fact that I believe TNT my cards
don't blow up the tractor on but I think
they'll blow up blocks like upwards and
like sort of sideways if I remember
correctly so what we'll do is have this
go maybe go over and activate a rail I
know like all the recipes in this game
by hearts like no question except for
activated rails I always forget the
recipe for them and I have to look it up
so annoying because how often do use
activator rails honestly okay so
villager is going to keep going along
this track I'm going to make it look
like he rat runs into some boulders here
so like with this clay
and he hits a dead end basically so yeah
but then underneath he's going to have
this TNT minecart go over an activator
track over here and then we got to make
it go to right underneath where he is
since we have a clay block between him
and the TNT I don't think it's going to
kill him oh this is going to be tough oh
that worked okay let's get rid of this
and this and we still have a downward
slope there that's good so he's going to
fall from up here down to this track
here I'm pretty sure that's what we're
testing anyway that TNT minecart should
end up over here somewhere and yeah
think so let's do it do a test I'm not
going to make a backup for this because
I don't think it's going to cause much
of an explosion but we'll put our
minecart in here should I ride it maybe
I should ride it just to try it oh whoa
because the TNT no I always make backups
need more power rails start it
ridiculous okay I give up you win you
win I'm out of here I made a backup this
time I'm not building a rebuilding any
more than I need to from this point on
okay so I made it look like I tried to
make it look like a pile of gravel fell
on the track and broke it so at this
point it breaks there's a big gravel
pile in the way of the villager and TT
minecart goes up to the pile blows it up
any gravel that lands on the track over
there should break automatically and I
don't think there'll be any trouble I
did change out this block here it used
to be clay I've changed it changed it to
gravel so it for sure will fall and last
time I tested it it did not blow up for
some reason so I'm not exactly sure how
t minecarts work compared to normal tnt
it's not quite the same though for sure
okay let's get our card in here we're
gonna have to actually ride this
otherwise the oh it's going pretty slow
to really enter that very well yeah I
didn't take any damage one piece of
gravel suffocated me for a bit there but
I didn't take any damage so I think our
villager is gonna be okay that was
actually really cool isn't it
all right I'm happy with that but
anyways guys I think we're gonna have to
call it here for today and wrap things
up we're gonna work on this again next
time though and hopefully get like at
least five more track pieces built on to
it because otherwise there's not going
to be much to it at the grand finale
next episode um kind of needed to start
this two episodes ago or three episodes
ago to be honest but don't think you
would want to watch me work on it five
episodes straight either right so the
plan we're gonna we're going to activate
this just to make sure it works - the
plan is did you go outside no after the
400th episode after next one will take a
break from this book from time to time
we're going to come back to it and just
keep adding more and more pieces to it
and will will activate the sequence
every now and then - and I think it'll
be a fun little side project to do and
hopefully it turns into something really
cool down the line villagers being shy
he's not coming outside doesn't want to
play so let's read the comment of the
day
it says hello etho I was wondering do
you have pets like cats or dogs
uh keep school in there I used to have
cats like but I haven't had any pets in
like ten years I used to always have a
cat around though oh there he goes and
paws never had a dog
here let's just watch this
no you stupid guy okay I might need to
move the fences in one block that's an
issue get in the water I can't even hit
the fool that's it I'm angry this was
supposed to be amazing and you wrecked
it yeah
small small little issue I can fix that
easy just because he went right next to
the fence he didn't fall down okay
he's making his way down he actually
gets through that pretty quickly
none of the blocks have hit the tripwire
it's good this is the moment of truth
big moment too right here aha good he
went in the minecart and please work
he's still alive awesome that's cool
that's like what is that like 20 seconds
30 seconds of this show right now um
might be able to get up to like two
minutes or something next time which
would be pretty cool anyway let's keep
on with this also do you like slash eat
fast food like McDonald's and Domino's
Pizza by the way you are awesome ah ha I
do like fast food especially like sub
places and pizza places are awesome
every now and then I like burgers - as
far as McDonald's goes I kinda really
hate McDonald's personally and whenever
I eat there I seem to like find blue
pellets in my my burgers and stuff but
hey maybe that's just me noticing what
they actually put in their food I know
some people love love McDonald's they're
loving it I also know there's many crazy
people in this world whether or not
those two are related it's not up to me
to judge but yeah that's just my opinion
Domino's Pizza not super popular here
there's not really any like one pizza
place here
think all right here's an idea for the
arena floor pattern each time a creeper
blows up the floor choose a random
colored clay to fill in it and see how
it turns out over time that's a
fantastic idea I love it I'm loving it a
lot of people thumbs up thumbs up that
that comment so I think we'll do it it's
going to turn into randomly like all
sorts of random colors like like a child
painted it like I painted the floor or
something I don't know we'll do it I
like that idea anyways guys I'll see you
again in the next episode hope you
enjoyed today and have a wonderful day
bye might