here we go again
this is episode 110 and one already and
so I wanted a win-win-win situation for
our brightness issue but obviously I'm
not going to please everybody so this is
what I decided to do brightness eighty
percent I went with a compromise I'm
hoping it works okay for everybody you
can adjust your monitor brightness if
you find it too dark still but and I do
recommend you do because it really
shouldn't be too dark at that level okay
so we are going to do a little bit work
on this again today our farm it's not
much left I'm going to run a tube up
here this is where I want the animals to
fall down right at this block here so
yeah put down some soil oops
just I don't know what I don't know what
I'm doing here
put soil there then glass I figure I
want two things two options to happen
here either animals fall down here and
they automatically die by falling
through lava so that their their meat
chop to get roasted or whatever
automatically or the other thing I would
want is the option to have them weakened
to the point where I can one-hit kill
them to get their XP those are the two
things I want the two options so
I figure if they fall from this height
they should be pretty close to 1 hit
kill so that'll take care of that nice
easy and for the lava we would just need
to set up a piston a lava blade
controlled by a piston shouldn't be too
difficult so that is a situation where
are my shears if I had cheers cool I was
thinking about using glass panes I tried
them they looked funny so I I just
canceled that all right yeah so this
shoot will be for the animals and then
I'll have a ladder going up for me
around around here somewhere and a water
break on the opposite side for coming
back down it's the plan right on so it's
working to some extent now we do have
more work to do on it but for today I
believe that's all we'll do they'll fall
down here I tried it already they fall
the odd time they will die from that
drop so I might need some sort of a
water break but if they don't it's a 1
hit kill always which is what I wanted I
will need to add a lava option yet
sometime I had a little trouble just a
little bit that the mobs did not want to
go the places I wanted them to this is
how I get down to the center by the way
just over here I do need to polish up
the area a lot yet a little glass look
out all around but yeah the mob path
pathfinding it's a little different than
I was expecting
I tried adding a skylight there it
seemed to draw them to the area but they
did not want to walk down this hole here
as I expected so I put a sign on to this
last block here to trick them into
thinking it's ground that's how you used
to be able to make mobs fall more than
three and a half blocks but when I did
it it did not work I don't know why I
don't know if that trick was patched or
what the deal is but it just did not
work and I'm having another problem when
they land on these half slabs they don't
seem to treat these leaves as normal
ground they don't seem to have an equal
chance of walking down here as they do
walk down the slabs they will eventually
wander off though but it takes half a
minute to minute usually not a big deal
really and I just add two water canals
to speed it up because as having
wandering issues so it at the back there
it splits it goes left and right and
then they meet back over here and the
mobs fall down so cool I'm going to try
do a little fishing I'll show you
working okay here we go so it does take
a bit of skill to do this the trick
seems to be for them not to be too close
to you and to be settled this that might
be a little too close nothing worked
oops actually I want to take out the
piece
close to close oops good so that's the
thing and that's why I couldn't use
fences over here that's why I have leaf
blocks because if you right-click your
fishing rod and it's highlighted then it
opens the fence instead of throwing your
rod casting instead of throwing the line
the hook whatever I don't go fishing I
don't know the terms my sound just
stopped what happened it did that's
weird
one sec that was strange very strange on
the air rid of all the pigs his cows are
much better
some people want me get the mushrooms
and if we ever find a mushroom biome or
whatever the biome is called mushroom
biome we definitely will I guess if the
animals don't cooperate like this guys
right in the center
you switch to a different tool go for
another one
yeah this is animals the don't cooperate
totally like he doesn't want to walk off
but he does eventually I kind of go on
the edge and then sometimes they fall
it's strange but it works let's head
down and yeah they're they're very happy
that one that cow that just fell died so
they're probably falling one block
further than they need to be you can get
some XP but mobs
the friendly mobs don't seem to give
much XP aha
thank you for your bacon something I
wanted is make today was a melon and a
pumpkin farm and yes I have an
enchanting table now haven't used it yet
we'll hopefully do that today too I just
made it actually but I did not have
enough books to yet enchanting it level
11 we'll talk about it later
anyway yeah I want to make a pumpkin and
melon farm but I need sticky pistons to
make sticky pistons you need slime balls
so I need to make a slime farm or
something before I can do that
so here we go I went on the slime finder
app and I found two chunks near here I
can make a slime farm at there's
actually not very many slime jumps
around here
and I'll link it in the description if I
remember let's see where do I want to go
here it's over here possibly yeah
over here so this is where I was first
getting my lava from then I found
there's a huge lab a pool down here huge
like it goes all the way back there it
goes to the left goes back there
somewhere wraps around here all the way
over here and not only that it goes like
and I think it goes to that pool over
there to some over there but yeah you
hear that sound that's the sound of
glory so right here is one slime chunk
actually right by this lava pool and
there's another one diagonally from it
over here I have three slime balls right
now so this guy's a huge score if he
doesn't kill me or himself
I found a few big slimes like this but
they keep jumping in the lava before I
did to him don't you dare kill me now
don't now now I sigh Bob most of them
died but I got a few so this is the
other slime chunk right right about here
so I believe what I'm going to do I'm
just going to hollow out the area for
now and then later eventually I'll work
on finishing up the slime farm I just
want them to be able to spawn safely
though for in it for now so I'll
probably hollow this part out first yes
I just basically hollowed out a chunk
for slimes to spawn in here
a three-high area so the big slimes
won't suffocate when they spawn and we
have a wall on the side so they don't
jump in the lab like they have been
doing so I'll be able to get all the
slime balls now and I recorded myself
hollowing this out and then my computer
locked up so we lost all that footage
but I'll just summarize quickly how this
works if you're new to the game that
trunk is a sixteen by sixteen area and
slimes only spawn in ten percent of
chunks so you can't just dig down to New
York and expect slimes will spawn
there's only 10 percent chance they'll
spawn in any given chunk which is
determined randomly basically with an
algorithm you can actually figure it out
on a calculator if you want but it would
take forever so I just use the slime
finder app and that tells me locations
of the chunks that spawn slimes and then
I use ft to find the coordinates in game
and that's how I figure out where to
hollow my room here and yeah an slimes
spawn at any light level below level 16
for the y-coordinate so that's the trick
but only in slime chunks it's also a lot
more rare for slimes to spawn than other
mobs so it'll probably take a while to
get a few so we're just trying to pass
the time I'm also waiting for some reeds
to grow so let me do some enchanting but
I think I think Reed growth has slowed
down or at least it seems to it seems to
have
let's see I have two pigs left in my
farm I think I'm going to get rid of 101
pig left and I just lost my fishing rod
so he is gonna have a lucky day actually
the wheat is grown so let's go harvest
it okay I don't know if I've done that
on camera before but it legs oh the joy
nothing looks cooler than that I love
that yes so try do some chanting um
maybe you'll be able to check the slime
front see if any spawns I'm a vet a
standstill right now as to what to do oh
yeah some reason I always take a jello
when I see these guys I always want
jello
not very exciting is it this is what
I've been doing like 20 minutes just
watching the reeds grow although they're
not growing while they are it's just so
slow why so slow we're going to skip and
chanting for just a little while we do
have enough sticky pistons or we can
make enough sticky pistons now for what
I wanted to do with the pumpkin farm but
I remembered now I wanted to mess around
with those cheap spider spawners so
let's do that yeah so we have two of
these spawners to keep spider spawners
one here and one down there close
together near our farm near our creeper
face up there so we should capitalize on
this yes I want to make it so I can get
their XP when they spawn I also would
like to make it so they don't stop
spawning if I'm near them monster
spawners will spawn mobs if you're
within 16 blocks of them so just imagine
a sphere all around this spawner with a
radius of 16 blocks and if you're within
that day we can spawn mobs and these are
cave spider spawners which are a huge
pain because cave spiders fit within one
block there less than one by one by one
in size they can climb they're poisonous
so huge pain to deal with and I believe
they spawn if it slipped below light
level 8 and I don't know if this is true
but I believe they spawn up to 4 blocks
away from the spawner so 1 2 3 4 so they
should be able to spawn here but no
further just I usually just imagine a 9
by 9 square
around the spotter yeah and I mmm
this this always confuses me I know they
can spawn at this level and I know they
can spawn if you go to one down now I
can't remember if you go one more down
if they'll spawn or if it's one more up
from here maybe we'll try it if I make
no light there we'll see if they spawn
in there well they are spawning but I
think I messed up this test a little bit
okay well let's go with this one first
that one spawned one block above the
spawner and I dug a hole too deep but I
realize now that they possibly are
spawning in midair and then falling down
because I dug a hole three deep here and
they also spawn so I didn't do it right
so I will adjust it give me a sec yeah
so this time I'll dig do down but I'll
cover it here and I know they can spawn
at this level so I will make a 1 by 1 by
1 dark area and see if they'll spawn
there so I'm not sure if you need a too
high clearance I've been watching this
while I've been doing lots of different
tests and I think I finally get it I
understand what's responders to an
extent anyway as always confused about
the spawning but with cave spiders they
can spawn
oops okay you know one by one by one
area like that they can spawn at this
level here if the spawner is there or
they can spawn at this level if the
spawner is there or one block up so
level with the top of the spawner they
can also spawn so those are the three
Heights and the only three Heights and
it's an 8 by 8 square it's not a 9 by 9
like I thought it's a little strange how
it works so it goes out diagonally
blocks this way so this is the furthest
they'll spawn this way but then it goes
4 blocks this way so it's not centered
so numbers get bigger this way and they
get smaller this way for the coordinates
so that's why you can figure it out and
the other thing I found is the mobs are
more likely to spawn closer to the
spawner than they are farther away from
it so even though I have had a spider
spawn in this space here 4 blocks
diagonally from the spawner even though
it's dark right now most of the time
they will spawn in this little
one-by-one area next to this water
because it's closer the only other thing
I'm wondering about is if hole lighting
affects it like a light level of zero
compared to a light level of 7 if
there's a difference in probability I
don't know yet but this should give me a
good good start for understanding how to
build this ok something else interesting
here I guess these cave spiders are less
than half a block in height because they
can fit
a half slab so in this case monster
spawner czar transparent they let light
through half slabs do not let light
through so I get the monster spawner
surrounded on all sides except this one
there's a block above and half slabs so
this spot right above the spawner will
become completely dark if I put a block
here and they'll be able to spawn any
moment that would result there yes so
yeah
deadly guys okay let's do it so I was
originally planning on building like a
huge room for these guys to spawn in but
now that we know what we know since
they're more likely to spawn closer to
this spawner there's not really much
point to it
so I'm thinking I'm just going to make a
really really small spawning you for
them okay and I'm just going to low out
of cobble start off with yeah that so
they can spawn that block below and at
this height and one more up yet they can
spawn
so I'll probably just have a water
stream here for them to fall in the
plenty of spawning space next is spawner
and then yeah and then what I'll do
we'll just put a block here up here
they'll flow through there I may be able
to put glass there for now okay and we
will close this up and see what happens
I'm worried they're going to get stuck
climbing like on this wall here that
didn't take long and he's in the right
position it's good yeah so then I just
need to hook some kind of kill anything
up for them
I'll watch this for a while see how it
turns out it's another one
yeah they don't seem to be any stuck
that's good well I believe I'm going to
wait till next episode to work on that
spider thing some more because our time
is almost up but I wanted to try out
enchanting before we end it today so
let's do that quickly I just stuck it
over here but I think I want to move it
use your pick to get it has to be your
pick as you lose it
and our reeds have finally grown a
little bit I got some paper on me I
believe on I made books already books so
we have enough for two whole bookcases
amazing it only took oh like an hour to
get that much that many books from that
mini sugar cane so it seems like I need
a sugar cane farm
okay let's another day another day
always lots of projects to do see where
am I going
I want to go up here and I wanted to put
it over here yeah so this this just dead
ends cells is a pretty good place to put
it for now anyway
so put our table over here
AHA and so with no bookshelves around
you only can enchant things up to level
five maximum one to five but with
bookshelves around you can get up to
level 50 so that's what they do and I
don't know stick don't know what the
best way of placing them is maybe try
here don't think that did anything it's
too far away
yep too far away that was a waste and
now I can't get it back we will try it
over here five and still not doing
anything hmm oh it is okay so it's
within range now out level six you saw
that cool I have no way of getting this
bookshelf back though oh it gives you
books cool so the enchanting system some
people want to know what I thought about
it overall I like it as I like yeah how
it makes it possible to speed up things
like mining is possible to do faster now
within chanting table because you have
like upgrades for your pick to mine
quicker and stuff like that which is
awesome some people think it's
overpowered really I think the amount of
sacrifice you do is makes it
justified like it takes forever to get
to level 50 so it's not like you're
going to be doing level 50 enchantments
all the time so I think it's fine the
only thing I thought was overpowered was
the silk touch thing I saw doc M using
it and he was just mining through stone
like nothing with it so I don't know
what the deal is with that you should
not be able to instant mine with one
punch that's that's my only concern
let's try it out
upgraded unbreaking lame-o well I think
that just makes it last longer some
other things I'm wondering about is
there's like a fortune one that makes
more more items drop when you break a
block so I'm wondering if you combine
like silk touch and fortune together if
you can mine and I Minh block and keep
like getting more and more diamonds from
it if that's possible I don't know could
be exploited though but yeah overall
pretty cool
or does unbreaking me and it doesn't oh
there it goes so just sometimes it won't
use up a tool you say yes that's cool
let's try one more time here I got
another bookshelf now and I'll do a pick
again
see guessing the max level is eight now
with three bookshelves hopefully Oh past
it there we go
I don't believe you can pick your steel
based on these words I think these are
just random words in that cryptic
language of course it's funny I actually
recognized what these were
right away because I'm a huge Commander
Keen fan it was one of my favorite games
for the longest time when I was a kid so
I I knew exactly what these were when I
saw them let's try this one out
efficiency cool so I think I can mine
faster with that yep
scary fast actually that's pretty quick
I'll take it yep
so within chanting table potions the
breeding system as long as like they
give you a benefit but as long as some
sacrifice is given to bounce out the
effect I think it's an okay addition to
the game enchanting it uses up the
levels you gain from killing mobs so
that's cool it gives you a reason to go
fight mobs so it's definitely an
improvement potions you got a sacrifice
glowstone redstone I wouldn't want to do
that to get the good stuff so I think
that bounces itself up to pretty well
breeding was imbalanced at first but now
that there's a delay and all that before
they can breed again I think it's
bounced out too so all these new changes
that are being added I think are okay
really with the few exceptions like I
said still touch that fortune thing I'm
a little concerned about and also moving
monsters spawners around to make big
farms and that I think that's not really
intended so I'm not going to do that
unless they leave it in for another
patch because I don't know just seems
like cheating and I got to remind myself
when I'm playing ISA pre-releases that
you know there's they're not going to
put as much attention into making sure
the game is bounced in them I feel so I
shouldn't exploit something if I feel it
is an exploit like moving monster
spawner
so yeah but anyway that's it for today
and thank you for watching I will see
you again next time and hopefully we'll
do some more building