[Music]
Wow I mean Wow
who knew guys who knew today was gonna
be the day I had no clue I was devoted
honestly her purr for life am i right
but I think purpur has served its
purpose today is the day we honor her
purr we give purr purr the respect it
deserves I know it's not the most loved
building block in the game not even by a
long shot
some people openly hate it but you know
what it's better than granite her purr
has been the backbone of our world here
guys it has allowed us to reach places I
never thought possible through the
nether and for that it will always hold
a special place in my hearts
well we're not gonna be building with it
anymore Nino times are changing and we
got to change with them
yeah so over the past few days here I've
been doing an incredible amount of
grindy work in our world here one of the
main things being building this nether
tunnel out to the new crimson keep area
we started which is about 4,500 blocks
away which is a very very long nether
tunnel but we had about a thousand of
that built already with the perper
tunnel and I'm currently working on the
final thousand block section of this
4500 block tunnel guys and I can hardly
wait till it's done because oh my
goodness it's taking a long time
I call it my tunnel to insanity I've
also had to take a few breaks while
building this because I was starting to
get that carpal tunnel feeling and my my
risk from placing so many blocks so I
had a bit of a tough time deciding near
what to do because I felt like there was
three main options to choose for what to
do with our nether tunnels number one
being just continue the original perper
design we had here I wanted to stop
using this because perper is actually a
real pain to collect like you gotta even
though we got a big firm for it you
still got a smelt it you're gonna craft
it you got to replant it all that kind
of stuff I think the easiest way of
collecting it is actually just to set up
a speed mining beacon at a and fortress
and just plow it down but even still
that's
a lot of work I also didn't like how I
use solid glass here that's a lot more
resources compared to like using glass
panes which is what we ended up
upgrading to here and also we're using
three wide packed ice and Pat dice is
only 40 bucks per second travel speed by
boat while blue ice what we upgraded to
here is 60 blocks per second so that's
the time and half quicker and that is a
big deal when you're going a long
distance like we are here so second
option was to upgrade our tunnel which
is what we chose but the third option is
we could have just flew around the
nether ceiling now like portals connects
from the nether ceiling you don't
actually need to make nether tunnels
anymore but I decided to still go with
the tunnels because I wanted the blue
ice it's a faster way of traveling
compared to Rockets I think in general
and also we have the option now to carry
mobs around through our nether by boat
which i think was better while if we
were flying around the roof and we want
to move a mob around we still have a big
problem so as you saw there we need a
lot of power rails that's one of our big
problems right now and then I this is
our final thousand block stretch that
I'm gonna work on here I gotta go click
more blue ice right now and you guys
will be happy to know I'm not doing this
in a crazy way anymore
I've actually looked for a frozen ocean
now that we can destroy and steal all
the packed ice and blue ice from it does
spawn naturally here in these glaciers
although you can't instant mine it but
like with the purple tunnels all that
ice I crafted
this is also a newly generated area for
me so I got pretty excited when I saw
this this is a bamboo jungle the very
first one I found and I was hoping we
would find pandas and I looked through
here and I can't find any though which
is a little bit disappointing I think
cuz we're unamplified
it messes up some of the passive mob
spawning like they only spawn at certain
levels I'm guessing and because most the
terrain is amplified up high there's
very little area where new mobs can
actually spawn oh well we only need two
we'll find them eventually I gotta say I
do really enjoy the amplifi terrain
still though like it's so much fun to
explore this stuff look at this this is
so cool and now I got a computer they
didn't actually handle it
well we only got one rocket left here we
got to make it count straight up and
over and we made it awesome okay 40
Rockets excellent so there's also a
giant desert by that frozen ocean so I'm
probably gonna make that my new sand
mining outpost because the other one we
were using is running out actually we're
gonna smelt that up into some glass for
the blue glass of the tunnels
oh man I'm actually pretty excited about
this it's been months I think since we
last had to fire up our lab here today's
the day we're running low on potions
finally I wish we could run this more
often but it just lasts for so long yeah
used up a bunch of speed potions let's
go through our stock here gonna get an
idea I don't think I've used any poison
ink we're running low on weakness no
maybe not maybe not
what are we low on we're low on
invisibility a little bit used a lot of
night vision and fire resistance yeah
there's none left I really like to use
speed potions when I'm building cuz the
rate of your right-click when you hold
it down is almost exactly the same as
your movement speed when you're using a
speed one potion one problem I've been
having while building this tunnel is I
keep running into basalt Delta's and get
a bunch of this basalt in your way and
you can't mine it very quickly and it's
really annoying
it's not really worth moving a speed
beacon over here because it's not as
super long stretch usually just a few
blocks I've actually been using the
golden picks to speed meinem funny
enough I didn't think that would
actually have any practical value but
yeah Here I am oh man oh snappers we got
it done here we actually got it done and
I am so happy this is gonna be huge for
our world having this road ah man so it
comes out at minus 1,000 minus 3,500 so
that is that our crimson key area here
you might be thinking II thought you
know that seems a bit crazy to build a
tunnel just to get to your trims and
keep that's not just what it's for this
gives us
a big range of area in our overworld
that we can cover now so like with all
our another tunnels we didn't cover over
like a 50,000 block area in the
overworld so when new content comes out
in the game there's a good chance it's
gonna be reachable now
oh yeah and I'll give you guys a view
from the outside as well because I think
it looks pretty cool on the outside too
I'm happy with that it's not like I'm
gonna build the support posts or
anything for it though that's getting
too crazy I wanted to try to keep the
tunnel as simple as I could while still
keeping it as detailed as I could so
it's just five blocks tall so that's ten
and then three connecting on the top and
bottom so that's sixteen blocks every
one block of space you want to move
forward more detailed tunnels obviously
will look better but that adds so much
more work every single block you add to
it yeah so I said it's done but it's not
actually done we're missing the power
rails for about two thousand blocks of
the tunnel right now so we got to get
those somehow and as you can see they
are super important because without them
you get mob spotting on the tunnel on
the ice here and that means we need gold
everybody lots and lots of gold for the
power rails oh he's getting out we could
just use gold farm number three we
recently fixed that up and it is working
again but I got to thinking what about
gold from number two guys this could be
one of the most perfect projects we
could ever do actually so let me try
explain this to you
gold farm number two here is actually
broken it broke a long time ago because
some game mechanics changed before we
had some iron golems in here we just
manually spun them in and they would
attack the zombie pigmen and the zombie
pigmen weren't able to hurt the iron
golem before so they would just kill all
the zombie pigmen now they're gonna turn
on me let's get out of here yeah now the
Pigman killed pretty quickly and then
there's no more iron golems right and
farms broken now the other side to all
this is we also desperately need an iron
farm in our world our snowflake one
broke a while ago and I've just been
cannibal
vegan bases lately to get our iron but
that's gonna run out pretty soon and so
we need something so how perfect is this
right we need iron we need gold why
don't we just set up some villagers here
they'll spawn an iron golems on the
platform they don't spawn on glass so
this is all fine well they should spot
on the platform I believe and iron
golems will fight the zombie pigmen the
zombie pigmen will fight the iron golems
and we'll get both and we'll be fixing
an old broken project in the process so
it's like three birds in one stone right
and the crazy thing is there was
actually two villagers here just sitting
here is like when you punch a zombie
pigman sometimes they would spawn
zombies and I think a couple of them
were zombie villagers I cured them just
because I was bored and yeah so we can
start up a village pretty easily here I
think and these villagers are from
before the villager changes and I
suspect this might be another cheat
though because just says cleric it
doesn't say rank or anything up here
well this case has leather worker
journeyman so I'm it I suspect we can
trade infinitely with this guy let's try
get these guys out of here he's got a
gold ring so I'm trying to get him up on
the roof here and he's going on his own
pretty well yeah we're gonna get him on
the roof we're gonna start up a village
up there
enjoy oh I stole it I missed it I left
for a moment to grab some stuff and when
I came back they had a villager already
amazing so all they need is a bed a
workstation and food we've been feeding
them bread so they can make babies oh we
got baby we got baby baby oh yeah we got
a little one noise
and I sleep here oh my goodness you can
sleep by it yes what that shouldn't be
I'll take it though
all right heading back I've been
skipping the night by going to the Oprah
world's physical obviously you can't
sleep in the nether right and they won't
breathe during the nighttime so to save
a bit of time while making this project
I run run to the overworld there sleep
and then when I come back they should
start making babies again very good very
good so it looks like we're up to seven
or eight villagers here already their
breeding pretty quickly actually kind of
in a race with them I wanted to set up
my part before they were finished so
what I've done is I found the center
point which is right here of this
platform
then I went out diagonally from there
until it looked like we had about twenty
something blocks space from one end to
the other and looks like we have space
to do eight villager cells pretty
comfortably here so we're gonna go
villager sell zombie villager sell
villager sell zombie villager sell you
get the idea right so in the village
ourselves we put three villagers each so
three times eight means we need 24
villagers for this farm and we need to
have at least a ten block space between
the villager cells otherwise like one of
them will spawn in an iron golem they'll
be like hey guys you're pretty close to
us you don't need to worry about
spawning it in one yourself right but if
there are at least ten blocks apart from
each other both spawn and iron golems
and we'll get eight at a time here in
the farm so if we count it one two three
four five six blocks to the zombie one
two three four five six blocks to the
next villager sell so that's at least a
ten block space between the villagers so
that should be good and then from here
from this villager sell to that one you
got one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve to this one
so again we have a 10 block space
alright well I think we're ready to get
started here and this is
be so easy for us to build because all
the hard work is done we got the
platform we got the collection system
underneath that we got this glass cover
all we got to do is build the villager
cells and get some zombies up here so
villager cells go in here and I should
warn you this is not pre-built and
creative so it might not work we will
find out I got to be very careful not to
right-click a bed as well as I'm doing
this or I'm gonna be very sad so I think
we need the pillow part facing the the
villagers and we want surround this now
with some glass this is the eco custom
cell let's see if it works or not
okay I'm gonna come over there and we
got to make sure when they wake up out
of the bed they don't spawn outside here
on the ground so I'm gonna build up here
I think I need to and possibly outside
here as well well no I think they
spawned from the pillow block not the
not the foot so that everything else
around that surrounded the glass overtop
of this as well and then we just got to
make sure the villagers can't get out so
we're gonna put some slabs in front
they'll bump their head on that and then
we need to make sure nothing spawns on
top of this so we're gonna put more
slabs over top here just cover the whole
thing although they don't spawn nothing
spawns on glass so we don't really need
to put it of that I'm gonna do it anyway
okay and I think that's pretty much all
there is to it although I realized stuff
might spawn on top of these workstations
so I'm gonna put some redstone on top of
them that stops mobs from spawning good
use power rails as well or something
like that but that should be good I
think I don't think that blocks the
villagers from using the work station it
could be wrong again I don't really know
a lot about the mechanics but just the
basics so the zombies gonna go into his
cage over he
you'll be able to see the villagers
villagers will be able to see him and
they're gonna freak out they're gonna
panic and then they're gonna spawn iron
golems up to six blocks but below them
and above them and six blocks below them
just happens to be a platform where we
want them time for school time the wake
up let's go let's go and actually I
don't even need to move them into the
cell if we just block them in there oh
my goodness that's gonna be so easy
well I learned something new while
building this I did not know four
villagers to breed they need not only a
bed a workstation and food they also
need two air spaces above the beds for
the baby villagers to jump on otherwise
they don't see it as a valid bed so we
covered over the beds here I could not
figure out for like an hour why the
villagers totally stopped reading it's
because we had glass above the beds here
so now that they're done breeding we got
enough villagers these are all full now
I'm gonna cover over them again okay
good stuff so the night past year and
all the villagers woke up inside their
cells not outside because when they get
out of bed they look all around the bed
for a free space and this is the only
free space available to them over here
so that's good I got rid of some of the
slabs over top here because I thought it
might look better actually being more
glass and I got like a platform up there
to view everything now and now it's time
for the tricky part
we got a zombie so I'm gonna leave the
area
I want those guests gone first off okay
let's try this again
alright I have a new plan now I realized
we gotta go in here we gotta cover up
all this clothes stone because we need
zombies to spawn and they don't spawn in
light areas so it needs to be dark in
here actually okay so I'm gonna keep
punching them here and I'm hoping yeah
there we go we got a zombie sweets so we
want to try to get a zombie that will
pick up items
dude we stole all the gold give it back
is that gonna be a problem with this
farm actually I wonder those guys might
steal all the gold that lands on the
ground before the minecart can grab it
oh he grabbed the sword okay that's a
zombie we can use so a zombie that picks
up an item won't be spawn so we if we
put them in a holding area here he'll
stay there forever
zombies also preferred to kill you over
the villagers you take priority so
they're gonna ignore the villagers as
long as I'm here and oh he was so close
come on you can do it oh he won't walk
over whoa your ninja how did you do that
yeah no don't don't come on you're
killing me here I put this year
oh we figured it out okay we got him in
there all right here we go the final
zombie then we got four block it and
then we slab it then we slab it there we
go then we're free to remove all this
stuff and he is stuck in there good okay
so we got everything built that I wanted
to do here but now comes the bug fixing
so I've been watching it is very strange
so we just got an iron golem spawn there
it's supposed to spawn eight at a time
my thoughts we got another one but it's
sort of sporadic like it'll spawn an
iron golem in like five seconds later
another one will spawn sometimes it'll
be three sometimes will be four I think
what we got to do is add some redstone
controls so that the villagers see the
zombie all at the same time all right
all the villagers just went to bed here
I'm gonna try flip the switch so that
the zombies scare them oh except for you
please go to bed it's bedtime go to bed
alright well let's let's see what
happened anyway here we go
Oh iron golems yeah 1 2 only 2 3
supposed to be 8 why is it not eat hmm
alright I guess let's try this again I
got a lot to learn about iron golem
farms apparently how many are we gonna
get here none why would we get none oh
man this is so confusing I don't know
what's going on here the mechanics are
so strange three four five six okay that
was a good one we got at least six iron
golems was it only six or was ready
we're trying to get eight four five six
I'm only seeing six hmm
alright well I think that's all we're
gonna do with this for today I know it's
not perfect but I know I can just read
the comments after this episode and
somebody's probably gonna give me the
answer to this so that's a lot easier
than trying to figure it out so thank
you in advance for that but I did see
eight spawn at once so there's
definitely potential here I think that
means the cells are spaced properly
there's this some other mechanic in play
that I don't understand I know you're
supposed to drop iron golems like
sixteen blocks away from villagers we
can't really do that with this project
cuz we're at the top of the roof here so
that might lower our iron rates a little
bit because we're not doing that but I
don't think it should be a big deal but
I could be wrong the way this works is
we put in some filters here for what
items we want to collect then when a
hopper minecart passes by those it grabs
one of each
and then it goes underneath the farm and
grabs all the stuff that way it doesn't
grab any of the swords or or poppies or
anything else that you might not want to
collect alright and I just checked in
what we got so far with the farm and
it's definitely producing a bit quite a
bit iron here already seven eight nine
kind of about nine stacks of iron so far
I think one or two of those are from the
filter that I supplied myself so
probably 7 or so stacks how many's out
of here it's not gonna happen smithing
so I have to manually put this stuff in
here with the way I got the firm set up
but it lasts for quite a few hours
before you have to refill yeah it's it's
gonna give us gas tears it's gonna give
us gold we got quite a bit of gold here
too we could get eight iron golem
spawning at once every single time
that's like eight every minute I think
then it's gonna really start producing
and I think once we get all the
mechanics working good on this farm I'm
also gonna turn it into a villager
Trading Post because we got 24 villagers
here they are on ground level so I can
interact with them and and trade with
them so I may as well that way it'll be
like three things in one iron farm gold
farm and Trading Post oh yeah before we
leave here I did want to check if this
guy's a cheap though which means
basically he doesn't have a limit to how
many times you can trade with them 67 oh
yeah he's cheap though normally I think
you're limited to 16 trades and we just
did 20 there and he didn't have to
restock I am kind of curious what
happens if you hear one of these guys if
the price is dropping you can still do
that then it becomes like super cheap
though he traded like one flesh for an
emerald with no restock time and
attempted to do that but that might be
too cheap though oh yeah and I thought
of a new name for the farm as well so
rather than just calling it gold farm
number two like we've been doing Oh even
though that's a lovely name I thought we
would call it the goon farm which is
gold and iron first two letters of gold
last two letters of iron
ah I like it I think that's good oh man
here we go guys this is the big moment
last episode you noticed that we were
about to hit day 10,000 in our world
here day 10,000 since the statistics
worked anyways it's actually a lot older
than that but yeah here we go
we have finally hit day 10,000 154 so
kind of went past it by quite a bit I
actually missed the when it rolled over
so I've actually played odd Suns since
last episode here a big chunk of that
was building the nether tunnel but I've
also been doing a lot of other stuff you
stole my door
oh my so some of you guys told me to
flip them yeah we trick them so this is
easy
you're the open sound that's an open
door that's a closed door so the open
door should get ignored by the zombies
apparently aha so you guys might be
wondering about those hundred and fifty
plus days since last episode I'm trying
to go through a major shift with our
let's play series here where we're doing
things here lots of up camera work is
being done essentially I'm trying to
update things for one thing trying to
get things running smoother like for
example one of the things I did here is
I got a villager in the stall like we
were supposed to I cured him so his
trades are only cost one emerald and he
has mending which is something I've
needed for a long time my other villager
that has this it cost like thirty
emeralds or something crazy and you know
just simple things like that around the
world makes it a lot easier for me to
get stuff done and another pretty big
thing I did is I went on an end rating
run recently I explored three more of
these map sections these 2000 block Maps
got a bunch more shocker boxes I was
lacking them it was kind of hard moving
stuff around because I didn't have
enough free ones available now we got
quite a few more I think I found like
over a stack of chakra shells although
I've kind of used them all up already I
also spent quite a bit of time reor
organizing my enderchest and the system
I use for it so for example look how
beautiful this is
fences every single fence in the game
right there available nether stuff look
how beautifully organized that is I love
it so that's gonna simplify things quite
a bit for me so I'm actually pretty
serious about there being a major shift
in the let's play series like usually
with these episodes I just hop on and I
do what I feel like doing for that
episode and it's pretty random and and
crazy right um I actually have a plan
guys I have a plan
I think for the next 50 episodes roughly
I have a pretty big chunk of them
figured out already which is gonna be
very different we're still gonna be
doing random stuff mixed in I'm sure but
for the next ten here I'm hoping for the
world tour and world download coming up
at episode 550 we're gonna be ready for
it we're gonna finish up some projects
here fix up some things and also I want
to organize the world a bit better so
like it would be nice to have signs that
tell you what's where how stuff works
that sort of thing
I noticed when people check out my world
they're actually really confused a lot
of the time which isn't really what I
want I would like them to be able to
find things and understand things right
so I'm gonna put an effort into that and
we're gonna be doing another stuff in
between as well I'm hoping then sometime
after episode 550 is when we're gonna
start the major special project I don't
want to over hype it I don't want to
give too much away right now but I got
something massive planned that's gonna
be like the main feature of our world I
think so pretty excited about that I
want to start it today but I'm holding
off I'll give myself more time to plan
it out and it'll hopefully be better
aha so in line with that goal this
episode we did do some other stuff we
built that another tunnel and we fixed
up a broken project the gold firm number
2 and made something new out of it so
that is pretty cool but probably the
second biggest thing I did besides the
nether tunnel is I worked on fixing up
the broken pumpkin and round mushroom
farm we had yeah so the pumpkin farmer
broken because before a pumpkin would
grow in front of the piston like that
and that would block out the light from
reaching the daylight sensor which would
cause us to trigger and activate the
piston breaking the pumpkin and letting
light through again that was when light
would pass through Pistons which isn't
the case anymore so this piston would
get stuck after that update and couldn't
grow any more pumpkins now the new
system that we upgraded to here is
pumpkin grows in front of the piston
under the note block that updates the
note block which observer detects ours
this block here which powers the piston
diagonally and we update the piston with
the power rail down below here now it's
important to keep in mind if you are
building a farm like this it does not
work with melons that is because melons
don't actually change the notes on the
note block still piano while pumpkins
uh-huh awesome so this is a new fully
upgraded pumpkin and brown mushroom farm
with the new mechanics ever pumpkin
grows it triggers uh-huh I put glass
over top here now as well as having some
issues where mobs respond here and they
would trample the the crops now they
can't do that and we also did a few
aesthetic things around here so we added
some lights some some lanterns here with
the chain block we added posts before
this is all floating and it didn't look
very good we got rid of the regular dark
oak and we stripped it all and added
some rings around each of the mushroom
plants here and the idea what the
trapdoors here I haven't tried them out
yet but we were having mushrooms that
were staggered in their Heights well
some were a block taller than others
that's because they don't require an air
block above them anymore that was a
change as well so now that that's fixed
up with the trapdoors let's try press to
grow
and they're all at the same height now
which is amazing it'll be a lot easier
to collect them this is what it looks
like at night time here oh yeah I think
that's supposed to happen it's like what
was that noise don't remember there be
more Pistons oh yeah we did the outside
here too with the lanterns so it's it's
pretty nice around here anyways let's
get to the comment of the day guys it's
time to wrap up for today it says why is
your twitch in your bio or description
if the last time you were live was over
four years ago I get asked this question
a lot and it's actually for a good
reason number one it's actually a few
reasons number one I would say it looks
pretty good like if you're trying to get
partnered on twitch and you have like a
hundred thousand followers because
people are still signing up and you've
never streamed before you can be like a
twitch alright you mind partnering me I
got a lot of followers and they'll be
like oh yeah for sure I am actually
partnered but I think I have to get
repart nerd that's if I ever want to
start screaming again so there's that
second reason it's to help protect
against imposters so people like to
start up channels or things similar a
name of to me and pretend to be me so
how do you know who is the official etho
who's the real guy while you're watching
this video what's linked with this video
my Twitter my twitch you know those are
the accurate ones and no others if you
see me on Instagram for example I don't
have that linked in my channel
description that's not me I don't have
an Instagram but anyways thank you for
the question thank you for the comments
everybody I appreciate it to finish off
today we are gonna head into the
statistics cuz I got a I got a firmly
plant myself as the leader of the most
Blackstone ever mind I think I'm in the
lead at the moment world record here
probably twenty eight thousand four
hundred and thirty six I could be wrong
somebody might have done more but I have
a hunch that's that's the world record
at the moment assault we're at twenty
thousand seven hundred and forty three
and yeah I thought this was kind of cool
too passed over a million on the diamond
pick
I think this got reset at some point as
well though because it seems kind of low
some of these stats like I it says I
never used quartz pillars I saw and I
know I've used them on the Nexus so I
don't know nether I pick is a 121,000
already but also redstone I think is in
the top ten blocks used which I thought
was kind of funny
uh-huh anyways I hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
until next time take care
have a good day
[Music]