[Music]
ah
man poor wilson
poor poor wilson it kills me crushes my
heart
every time i walk by here i see a sad
little face and i feel
so sorry for the guy still doesn't have
a brain
still waiting on me to finish him
and he's sad i want to turn his frown
upside down
so oh
i came back here today started working
on him a little bit
uh could not remember for the life of me
how it all works uh i came back here and
i just
stared at the redstone it's like oh man
i wonder if this is what the viewers
feel like when they see it just
a whole bunch of nothing uh but after a
little bit it started to come back to me
and i think i know what i need to do
um like i think the last thing we did is
we installed these things
and now i need to connect those to
his health variable over here
it's all very complicated it's not easy
to work on this i gotta say like it
takes a lot of planning
and i got this problem where i over
analyze stuff and i really plan
stuff out because i want to get it right
the first time i do it and that's
that's not a good way of going about
things because
it takes a lot of time to figure it out
perfect without making a few mistakes
this is a test i was doing
like i think i'm just going to start
running wires all over the place and if
something gets in the way of something
else i'll
i'll move it and figure it out later
but i just need to get it done uh i set
this little test up
because it looked like these comparator
clocks are running faster than the
repeater for some reason but
i think it was just a trick with my eyes
seems to work okay
oh man let me up
so we have 12 and 12 in those droppers
one of the droppers is before the
repeater one is after it
and if we give it a pulse
it turns out they shoot out the same
number of items so
it should work if i hook up repeaters
but anyway
i'm going to work on this a bit and if i
do anything interesting that i can
i feel i can explain pretty well i will
go over it
afterwards
oh man look where this guy spawned
he fits perfectly in there that's
awesome
all right congratulations wilson my
friend you have health now
his health has been programmed in uh
it's the first stat we got figured out
and the most complicated part of wilson
we actually had to invent the variable
pulse extender thing for him to make
that work
i'm not going to get into too much
detail check out episode 264
of my let's play if you want more
details how this is actually calculated
but essentially we figure out how much
is
his health should increase or decrease
per
update by the level of his happiness
his hunger and his weight those three
get put together and
it either increases or decreases based
on them
so if his weight is at zero like it is
now
or one or five there's no
increase to hunger or to health if it's
at one
or if it's at two or four it goes up by
one
and at level three it goes up by two
and then for happiness and hunger
this level here is zero this would be
one this
two three and 4 for both of them so
the increase we should get from this is
0 for that
plus 1 for happiness and then plus 4 for
hunger so 5 is our total number there
so now let's just check this out make
sure it works
this is the variable variable pulse
extender so
not going to get into too much detail
but basically we take all three of those
that we set up
merge them together all the pulses go
down this wire to
wilson's health variable here
every time this dropper gets a pulse it
sends one item into this one
and it increases his health by one
so since it's supposed to increase it by
five
uh there's there should be five less in
here
once we cause it to update which we can
do with this
one two three four five very good
very good let's just check it so this
was at
14 now it's down to nine so that is five
and if we fool around with some of these
other variables it should change the
number of pulses so let's
do that it's really only
there's not many of these in here um
this is his happiness
let's go see what that did i'm not sure
if i increased it or decreased it
it was at two before now it's at three
he's got a straight face
alright so that should be six pulses now
let's just check that out
and then i'll get back to work on it
here ah
oh i hate walking around this guy
there's so many places to fall
all right we want six pulses that was at
nine
one two three four five six i think you
did it
this was a nine it should be at three
very good so
i think it's working i'm going to try a
few other numbers here just to make sure
uh but then i'm going to try do some
other
his other stats here i'm going to try to
work those out too maybe today
and i'll be right back
yeah so i tried out a bunch of different
other combinations of these three stats
and they all seemed to work the way that
i intended them to uh
at the very least he gained zero health
points back
per updates at the max he gains 10
back but every update i'm supposed to
make it
subtract six from him as well so if he
gains zero and he subtracts six then
that goes down by six points
um if i subtract six and it goes up by
ten he gains
four so that's that's the way it's going
to be
and that'll determine if that goes up
and down now
i've also done one other thing for you
wilson um
i've given you a stomach and
you can digest food and tell your brain
that you're happy and
all kinds of crazy stuff so let's let's
give it a go here
um so
at the moment i have him where he can
eat two different things he can eat
steak and he can eat cookies
he has 50 hunger points
and 50 happiness points and at the
moment they're both at zero because none
of the lights are on
eating steak will recover 12 points so
12 out of 50.
so we feed them some steak and that goes
up to level one
uh basically every piece of steak is
going to be like a quarter of the bar
almost
now cookies they give him back six
hunger points
and six happiness so
uh if we feed him cookies begins
on both of these bars that went up to
level one
give him another cookie make him a
little happier
he likes his junk food oh yeah
way to go wilson give him another one
and you can see the hungers going up too
now the way i'm gonna make this game
though i could
i'm only gonna be able to feed them so
often if i feed him like two things
at one shot i think i'm going to make it
so he gains a lot of weight
because he over ate and also with
cookies
you know they give him happiness and
hunger but they're also going to make
his
weight go up a little extra compared to
the food value he gets from steak i
think
oh yeah uh pretty cool
look at that guy so happy so let's go up
here i'll just show it to you really
quick and then we'll go do something
else um
these are the the inner pearls are his
hunger and
happiness points basically so three
stacks plus two is fifty
and if we move them all over
his happiness goes all the way back down
to zero
at the moment i don't have it set up
where
anything is subtracting though so it's
not quite at that point yet but that
will be pretty easy to do
um what i was going to do
is show you the redstone real quick here
let's get this reset back to zero for
both of them
all right so zero zero if we go over
here
we had this set up before this part with
the hoppers this detects what
food we're feeding him so if we give
them steak it goes down to this one and
this torch flickers
if we give them cookies this torch
flickers and i now have this set up here
it goes to two different pulse extenders
the one on the right here is for the
steak it's a little bit longer
and this one is for the cookies so this
one
then you well they both go to one of
these comparator clocks this one will
pulse
12 times this one pulses six times
because it's all
a shorter duration
and then they go up here
the hunger value from the steak and from
the cookies joined together here
and they keep going up further but for
the cookies i have it split off before
that
and it goes up the staircase
here and that goes up to the happiness
variable
here so so it sends
six pulses to this dropper and those go
into here
basically oh now i've done it
and just a quick demonstration if we are
quick enough we can
go down and watch it move
so you see that that wire pulsing six
times
i just made it so the hunger and the
happiness he gets back from cookies
is done by the same pulse extender just
to simplify it
um steak should make it pulse 12 times
oh i can't see it it's behind there
anyway you get the idea
very cool so wilson we got a lot done on
youtube today guy
a little bit more work and i think he'll
be pretty close to
all done or at least working phase then
we'll probably do a bunch of tweaking
too
all right guys moving on here um
i'm gonna do a test right now got some
of this hardened clay
i want to see how it stands up to a
creeper blast
because when i was building the path the
other day
oh i'm not ready for you just yet
no when i was building that path the
other day
i had quite a few creepers blow up near
it and it didn't seem to take any damage
which i thought was kind of interesting
so i'm just going to set up like a wall
get a creeper over here
blow up and then depending on how this
goes
we might use this for a build idea
all right he's right by here
okay
all right so it's pretty good resistance
it's not
it's not uh creeper proof obviously
uh we're gonna go to the nether now and
see how it oh
or not i tried to jump in the water i
didn't do it quick enough
darn it um
we're gonna go to the nether and see how
it stands up against gas
okay there's a gas there uh what i want
to find out is if we can use this stuff
as a building material
here in the nether because
[Music]
this stuff is actually kind of colorful
oh yeah
i like the looks of that
come on one more just to confirm
a little too high gotta get them like
right here
there we go yeah so it's gas proof and
stuff
that's really cool because that means we
can use some pretty bright colors
in the nether here we got to get out of
here
go scuba gas
you know i can never seem to like knock
these back anymore
you used to be able to now it's like oh
there we go
like it looks like i'm hitting it but
it's really random now got him
oh
anyway oh oh oh
no really hard to do now it used to be
so easy
and i'm dying
that's really neat that uh those resist
gas explosions because
there's actually not a lot of different
types of blocks
you can use in the nether that don't
blow up like
um wool wood
sandstone all pretty much all bright or
warm colors
are not gas proof in this game
so if the hardened clay works that's
awesome because that's like 16
fairly like versatile colors you can use
in the nether
without having to worry and we're going
to use those
right away here for a little experiment
i want to do
i've been really interested in the
nether lately actually
after that beacon test last episode
i figure it's probably possible to
build a fully working or fully
functioning village
in the nether because uh the skylight
actually gets down like through the
bedrock through the netherrack um
this this isn't new information this is
like like even when i was
goofing around with netherwart a long
long time ago
i i experienced that but i thought it
would it was
fixed but i guess not
so i i i kind of think we can get a
village working and that's
our next goal here and we're going to
build the houses out of those clay
bricks
uh the tough part we'll be getting a
villager a villager down here of course
but
i'm sure we can pull it off
and i brought a bunch with me i have an
ender chest in the fortress there which
i'll have to
i like left the dies and stuff in there
so uh
i'm gonna finish extending this platform
and we'll start building something
okay this should do for now
i'm just gonna build one house today
because i don't have a lot of time
um let's head on over here the main
thing we gotta watch for is glowstone
above because
i'm pretty sure that blocks out any
skylight
falling magma cube
now how good can i end a pearl here
there's a zombie pigmen right where i
need to go
i don't want to hit him
oh come on
ah
i'll be right back
oh why did a blaze spa oh he's still mad
don't do it
i'll be back again
this is actually getting pretty annoying
i have to
say
there's a zombie pigman and i hit him
there
that would probably be the end of the
episode
but i'm a patient guy i can deal with
this we're fine
i do have armor i like the challenge
we'll see how it goes
[Music]
in fact i'm going to take this minecart
this time
this is how we're going to transport the
villagers uh out there most likely
through this track
it goes mostly already
oh but it's not powered so we are
getting off here
yeah always bring a bow with you if you
anger zombie pigmen because
they're jerks
it's like the only way to recover your
gear
unless you have unless you put on like
tons of armor and stuff
i brought food this time
should all be okay it's a long walk too
is the annoying part
and we died on the edge there so there's
a good chance a lot of our stuff fell
off into fire but we will see
all right these guys they should be fine
yeah he's our friend
we're gonna go up here there was a
wither skeleton chasing me
earlier let's hope he's gone
two of them now oh
jerk pigment caught in the way
oh this sucks
okay i got armor on this time
looks like most of mobs despawned which
is good
got our bow back got some food
gotta hurry though we gotta get uh that
other stuff
i think those skeletons are gone
i'm gonna run this time if i see him
all right sweet whoo
those pigmen though they're probably
still mad
we'll see what happens with that
uh most of this stuff was unloaded so i
don't think a whole lot of time is
passed on the items actually but we'll
see
recover no
no no
yeah yeah
this is really annoying it's
not not an easy place to get back to
even with armor like oh swerve
[Music]
forget about us good okay so that place
was over
here it's in that room
yeah look no oh i thought it just
despawned i saw blocks disappear
friends no
dude i saw i saw it disappear and i
thought that was it i thought we lost it
all
probably some stuff down here too
oh no no no
oh there's lots of stuff
no dang it
[Applause]
not in the mood for you
got him would he blow up i think he blew
up something there
okay but anyway we recovered more or
less
um i do still need to get back up there
we have armor this time though
gonna do it foolishly again
all right
[Music]
okay so i want to get to the ender chest
we have uh dies and stuff in that
oh man can't catch a break
good good sweet uh let's get some of
this stuff in there
i want to mostly build out out of orange
i think
there's something moving
orange maybe a bitty yellow
oh yeah that's not how you do it
i'm gonna prepare a little better here
one sec
i think the only thing we lost at all
this is our fire resist potion
and it was our only one too lazy to go
back
pushing our luck
i think we'll be okay okay
so let's build a house shall we i want
to build
think orange i'm gonna have to really
watch it i don't fall off the edge now
i think i want to do it like this make
it go orange on the bottom
five oh what's doing that
and maybe a little further
and have it wrap around let's make a
five
wide house
one two three four five not counting the
walls of course
have that go around i'm gonna put like
a bunch of a bunch of doors in this
probably close to 10 or so
just to see if it'll spawn villagers
once we get two down here
um let's make it go maybe
three blocks out actually
like that over here
and then wrap back
okay
that now i want to do yellow for the
walls
go up three blocks
all the way and then we'll put orange on
top of that
and then i think we'll have a brick roof
is what i was planning here i think
that'll go with these two colors okay
not that we're really trying to do
anything super fancy here
uh it's just a basic house
and actually i think i want a brick
floor too
no not that
so uh just give me a moment here
see what a brick floor looks like
i think i want this the front of the
house here too so
we'll expand uh our stone brick floor
a little further out
that's pretty cool
cool i brought iron bars for windows
i planned ahead almost lost it all but i
planned ahead
oh one here
anyway i will work on this a little bit
and i'll be
back uh once i get it done
okay guys we moved out of the nether for
a moment here uh we are at the
villager purifier we're using it again
i want to get two villagers all the way
over to that
nether area so
give them their medicine
oh and now i gotta wait like three to
five minutes
uh this guy switched already i think
this one's gonna change any second now
i know you want to come on do we have
minecarts in here still can
check yeah we do hey
both butchers wow
terrible trade and social trade
okay let's get them out of here build
your transports
and that doesn't work of course
there we go just give him rough him up a
little bit he'll go
this guy i never did fix this
it's not launching them properly
and they look weird in minecarts now
it's like they're standing in them
their head goes into that oh wow
okay don't hit the pigmen
there he goes where'd the other guy go
oh he's going back
come back
you're gonna love your new home guy
trust me it's one of a kind
blast resistant only state of the art
materials went into it
and you guys stop trying to run that way
get into the minecart it's too bad i
don't think you can use those new leads
on these guys
that would that would simplify things a
lot
and you can't really nudge them out of
corners anymore either
so it's like you're pretty much helpless
get into minecarts no
all right yeah oh you jerked you made it
go
now i'm sh i don't have enough
ah all right i'm gonna go through get
that mine cart
i have it running all the way now
oh we got a pigmen now
okay back we go
got it okay you
you could sir get in the mine carts
or i will force you to
forced let's get it
going here all right that should work
i'm going to lay down a furnace minecart
and push them the rest away
wherever they end up they should go
pretty far though
furnace minecarts best way of pushing
mobs around
doing some all right
i might try to snag that can we get
ahead of them yeah
furnace minecrafts are so slow
all right they should get pushed all the
way to the house we built
whoa none of that we don't want any of
that
guys oh skelton
good thing zombies don't spawn in the
nether here zombie pigmen
you know they've grown beyond these guys
they don't care for
the villagers i don't think
wait what
i guess they got way ahead of it almost
there guys don't you worry
up to you keep our distance in case
there's bad guys
okay and down the roller coaster that
should
oh oh he hit us
man all right that'll go down
do we get a weather head no never get
wither heads
don't hear any
oh there it goes
look at that house beautiful
uh i did this one this color i might try
other colors if
if this idea actually works if we can
build a village
this will be the test oh
no you gotta be kidding me
really
that's not happening
please tell me that's not happening
oh this is going so bad
i'm gonna re-log
okay
oh i can't believe i pushed that guy
into lava that sucks so bad
thing is there is no day night cycle so
maybe this won't work
we'll find out with this one guy if he
goes in the house
all is good if he doesn't well this will
be his own personal house
come on go to the door
i know you want to
of course i could have figured this all
out and created very quickly
oh man and is there anything above
no okay so that should be a clear shot
to the sky
here's our house
very nice he doesn't see it though he
doesn't
doesn't seem to want to go in
it's not looking good
hmm okay i'm gonna wait a bit and just
see what he does
oh oh look at that beautiful
so it does work he does view it as a
house
ah why did that guy die
oh i've had so many setbacks today it's
unreal
he'll be fine on his own you know he's
not going to walk into the lava
the way i have this set up zombie pigmen
are not going to
attack him did he just die
no he's worth her um
as long as i keep my distance he'll be
fine
actually i don't want i don't want this
he's gonna wreck the tracks
um okay i'm gonna try to get another one
here i
really don't have much time left for
today though we'll see how it goes
ah we got a tough guy this time guys
gold armor and
everything i like it
he's gonna lose it though unfortunately
man this guy he is giving me trouble
somehow he found his way uh
i had like a one place i didn't have
sealed up
that he found and he ran into it first
thing he does jumps in fire
so i think he's almost dead already but
we'll get him there
um our goal basically is just to get one
one baby villager out of this guy and
that's all we need
and if that works it's proof that you
can do a village
in the nether
but this time
let's be a little more careful
it's all right he's fine it's fine we've
done this before
there he is okay uh i want to get away
from that gas
okay we have to get a bunch of doors in
this village for it to work
uh each door counts as
every three doors basically counts as
one villager so i think we should get
nine in in this house just to see if
this works
and we'll take it from there
i don't know guys it's a really hard
call
there's been no hearts that i've seen so
far uh
this this house has 10 doors in which
should be enough for three villagers
if this is considered village should get
a baby out of these two
they are using the house like they're
going in and out
but yeah no hearts yet and i've been
sitting afk for a bit uh
so it's not looking too good
hearts they're looking at each other
yeah they'll look at each other too is
other weird thing
but nothing happens
anyway um i'm going to leave at that for
today
no conclusive proof that it works or
doesn't work
it's looking like it doesn't work though
from what i didn't tell
well i'll tell you what guys i'm gonna
afk at that house uh after this episode
i'll let you know
next episode whether or not it works for
sure
i i did afk there for about 20 minutes
and it wasn't looking too good like they
go in and out of the house but there was
no hearts
or any sign of it being an actual
village to them
so i don't know uh anyway
on to the comment for today i thought
this was a pretty good one
so how much wool do you plan to replace
with the new clay blocks
i was just thinking how much better the
hardened clay would go with all the
sandstone and stone brick blocks in your
world
probably not going to change anything in
the world this stuff
is pretty cool it's not exactly a
replacement for wool blocks which is
good they're they're
quite a bit different like even though
these are colorful and everything
they all have a reddish tinge to them
like cyan looks gray this yellow looks
kind of orange
so it's not a perfect match with
their respective wool colors
smooth texture is nice but um
they're different and i like the wool
the way i've used it like in the nether
hub for example we got purple wool it's
nice and bright
good contrast with the sandstone so
probably not going to be much change but
i will be using these a lot in the
future i think
yeah alright guys well i think that's
going to be the end for today
thanks for watching everyone hope you
enjoyed it i'll see you again next time