hello how's it going everybody this is
Ito welcome back did you guys see last
episode where we built the end reporter
teleporter crazy machine in Minecraft
that's what you see over here well today
I just finished building a hexadecimal
decoder in Minecraft yeah and I started
wondering it's like guys what happened
what happened you remember minecraft
when we just tried to survive our first
night tune and when we were building
dirt houses and all that stuff now look
at the things we do it's insane the
difference so so yeah I built this over
here pretty happy with how this turned
out you might remember we were going to
do an 8 lever code system for the items
in the Nexus but many of you in the
comments pressured me you were like yo
you got to use a hexadecimal system it's
gonna be better it's simpler
not not easier to set up but simpler in
the end of things and I resisted I was
like no I'm not gonna do that not gonna
do it my way is better and I was being a
little bit stubborn about it but I did
finally crack down and just decided to
do it here tried to figure it out so you
might not realize this guys but I
actually didn't know how to build a
hexadecimal decoder shocking right I
know I sometimes appeared to know what
I'm doing in this game all the time but
I got to figure this stuff out and I was
not too excited to try learn how to make
a hexadecimal decoder just saying that
saying those words it's like let's go do
something else but thanks thanks to you
guys as support and all your ideas and
all that and especially to Josh white he
made a video for me specifically showing
me how to set it up and how hexadecimal
decoders work and especially what was
helpful for me is he laid it out like
she showed me the pattern it creates
when when you do it so if you're not
familiar with a hexadecimal it's
basically a numbering system from what I
understand I'm a programmer I should
know exactly but I don't it so it goes
from zero one two three four five six
seven eight nine and then instead of ten
it goes a a is 10 B is 11 C is 12 D is
13 is 14 F is 15 so there's 16 different
numbers and each of these numbers
corresponds with the binary as you see
below so zero is zero zero zero zero if
we take seven it's zero one one one
and it basically translates one button
press can get converted into four four
of the levers we had before basically so
in other words instead of entering a
code like no threes something like this
to request an item from our Nexus here
now our codes are going to look like
something like this instead just two
digits and like if we say torches had
the code seven B to request that item
you got the signs up here seven is in
the bottom right on this one and then we
would press B which is over here so if
we press that it's going to select
torches and then we pull the lever we
get torches so quite a bit simpler
easier to remember it's just a little
bit tricky to set this all up but I'm
pretty happy with how it resulted and it
all works it's all good the only problem
we're getting really close to the other
wiring in the nexus and i think i have
to move all this all the logic and stuff
is figured out now in the nexus the only
problem is we got to connect all these
loose wires you see how they're not
connected to anything we're going to
hook them all together and there's no
bundled cable or anything like that in
Minecraft so it's going to be tricky
running all the wires and I don't know
exactly how to do it just yet and I'm
not doing it today but yes things are
looking up with this this idea so I've
also had quite a bit of feedback with
from you guys about how we should keep
track of the codes how we should
memorize them and we looked into the
book option before of storing all the
codes in a book then I talked about that
map idea not all of you were too happy
about that so I don't think we're going
to do it even though it's probably the
best method where we would set up some
Maps and have the codes visible just by
looking at them here instead what we're
probably going to end up doing we can
store all the codes in six double chests
like so we would have the chest maybe
over here and we would put each of the
items in these and then what we'll have
to do so again if torches add the code
seven B in order to memorize that what
I'll probably do is go to a handle name
a torch seven B oh there goes anvil darn
it and then all 256 unique items are
going to be in these chests down here
and if I need to look up a code what I
would do is just hover over it with the
mouse you'll say seven B and just seven
B uh-huh so that's kind of the method
we're going to go with with the Nexus
hopefully it all works out but I got to
figure out how to run all the wire now
and I'm not looking forward to it
once that's done though we are basically
done with all the crazy redstone part of
this alright guys so let's take a moment
here I want to talk to you about the end
reporter a little bit more today as well
you informed me in the comments
something I didn't realize there's
actually a way to make this work over a
long distance there's a trick to loading
chunks I didn't know about if you have
I don't know if we have enough space if
you send redstone to a 5x5 area of
chunks that torch is in the way look I'm
just going to lay it out a little bit
here we're going to be missing a corner
yeah if we for example sent a redstone
signal to the amplified base thousands
of blocks away and then we loaded a 5x5
area of chunks the one in the very
middle will process entities so if
that's where the end reporter is we can
actually teleport to it it is the theory
anyway I'm going to try set that up
sometime soon I don't have enough
redstone to do it today but hopefully we
can get that working and try it out so
that's pretty cool the other thing that
was suggested is let's change the way we
do this instead of disabling the clock
to activate this let's shut this off
right now - yeah we're going to put some
slime blocks behind here and they're
going to bump oops darn it
they're going to bump the enderpearl out
of the water stream and that way when we
teleport we're not going to be in the
water we're going to be on ground which
would be a little bit nicer I think so
we'll set it up like this basically the
ender pearl bounces three blocks up oops
so we'll have sticky pistons up to three
blocks actually we only need one of
these right yeah that's right we don't
need all one for each of these because
sticky pistons stick to themselves
all right so we'll go up like this and
then up here we're going to need a
furnace or something they don't stick to
and since the water gets blocked off we
want to try prevent it from flowing
everywhere so maybe we'll just put some
blocks around around here - like this oh
man
okay so instead of sending the signal to
the clock here we're going to leave the
clock running all the time and we'll
just send it to this piston and it
should push the ender pearl out of the
water kind of like this oops
oh wait a second Oh what's it sticking
to wait why doesn't that work okay
that's fine over there that's a furnace
up there why can't I move this guy's
that's a furnace oh it's sticking on the
carpet oh snap that's kind of bad I like
the way the carpet looked yeah it's
going to do that yeah so check this out
with the slime block pushers it's quite
a bit smoother let's go back to the man
cave so you end up on the ground like
this and if you put something in front
that the Ender Pro can run into you end
up right by the water so you can reset
it a little bit easier - oops I am
having a little bit of issues with this
thing still it's a little bit tricky to
set the enter Pro sometimes it sometimes
it hits the slime block still and also
when I go through another portal or a
bed it doesn't always happens but
sometimes I say go through a bed I'm in
slept in a bed sometimes when I do that
I'll just randomly teleport to one of
these and I don't know why exactly that
happens oh yeah see it's not perfect
every time oh you stupid little guy did
you mess that up for me but it's like
maybe 70% of the time when you throw the
ender pearl it works Oh
Oh sometimes Egan's get stuck at the
very bottom what's she doing over there
so I tell you what guys lately we've
been doing a lot of technical stuff in
our let's play here and I've already
built a hexadecimal decoder today so
maybe for the rest of the episode we'll
we'll do some building how's that sound
gotta get that variety hungry
there you go he loves me he doesn't love
me he loves my food all right
oh I don't have enough space bye bye
sticks I will miss you go fetch fetch
boy bring me my sticks they should bring
you sticks why don't they bring you
sticks that's what dogs do right in 1.9
new feature okay so we're going to do
some building around our man cave here
and I thought maybe we would hit up this
area over here ah we don't really go
over here too often but we sort of
expanded out this way just not very very
much so far first off there's like a
little bridge here I started building
but it doesn't really go anywhere
kinda we got the waterfall from the
mushroom area over there goes down under
the bridge and I would like to connect
up to here there's been a lot of people
asking about Wilson I know guys I will
get back to Wilson soon we will do more
Wilson the reason I haven't felt like
touching him lately
did I just say that the reason I haven't
felt like working on Wilson that sounded
better is because we've been doing a lot
of technical stuff lately so I want to
focus on the Nexus and the library and
all that stuff and then maybe we'll get
back to Wilson how
we do this kind of want a gradual slope
up wait wait wait let's do it like this
this and like this all right so this
connects through the Wilson room a lot
of you probably didn't know this was
here even all right and then it goes up
the stairs here to this area so we'll
have a way down through the bridge and
then it goes up these stairs here this
is all kind of rough still I feel like
we got to build this up maybe a bit more
should put one there thing is if you if
you do these angled staircases you can
easily run into a block and it's kind of
annoying okay we also have this firework
room I never did put a skin in here like
it's it functions but it's not really a
building right it doesn't feel like a
building it's just a cave so we got that
to work on but I've also been
considering maybe let's go I like how
this looks over here and maybe we should
expand our cave let's see where would we
put it maybe up through this way to make
sure I don't break anything here and
then have a viewing window down onto
this this is the potion lab by the way
can light look down at the Redstone I
got it all covered
spent allh spent a bit of time trying
to make this look decent even though
it's redstone wiring I tried to follow
up the best I could and I think I
want to keep it visible if we can so
we're going to build like a pathway
beside it here and maybe keep it open on
the left so that we can look down at
this okay so we got some land cleared
and we are going to start to building
our path I wanted to try to stab dark
oak running along the side here we're
going to change it up compared to some
of the other parts of the man cave
because for this area we used oak as a
border all along I'm going to switch it
over to dark oak just so there's some
variation and maybe we will connect it
to the ceiling in places like so now
we're going to do the grass still though
we could either make it go right next to
this or we might try to keep that border
I'm not sure which would look better so
let's let's try this all right mm-hmm do
we want to keep the oak here or not I'm
not sure we will probably have some sort
of fence maybe every five blocks between
like this trying to decide if I like it
or not I don't think it looks too bad I
just worry it's on the plain side isn't
it over here it looks pretty decent I
would say like it's not a super refined
area like with with all this stuff
showing I do want to keep this visible
as well though because we have this rail
cart system and when this is running you
can see the minecart running around
which looks pretty cool
and from up here we could watch it but
these long straights straightaways like
this aren't so good we almost need to
put like an obstacle here into the
middle and then have it have the walkway
go around it somehow let go this way
just to break it up a bit
okay we're going to do it like this we
got Oakwood running between the pillars
like so and then spruce wood beside that
and I think that looks pretty cool I put
jungle leaves in up here we can hide
lighting behind the jungle leaves us to
see if that works or not because without
these torches it's going to be pretty
dark in here
and we want to get rid of all the
torches that's our goal all right what
if we put one up here is that going to
light it up enough let's see let's check
our lighting I know it doesn't really
look like it does it gets up too we
would have to have them like all along I
think see skylights or block light is it
nine that's what we need it at ten nine
eight seven now we probably have to have
lighting down below can't just get away
with roof lighting all right um the
other thing though maybe at this one
over here to break it up I'm just going
to put a wall over here a stone wall
like so to make it look like the end and
then we will make a passageway going
this way and that's where we'll probably
change it up quite a bit they'll be a
big room here or something and then
somewhere in there it's going to go to
the left again and if we keep going this
way eventually we will hit the village
underground village further down in the
man cave so we'll connect to it there
yeah okay I think this is pretty good
for right now I got to refine it a bit
more but we'll have decorations on the
right some flowers and bushes whatever I
think of later and probably over here -
mm-hmm
we can we can see into here nicely when
we come this way all in all I'm pretty
happy with that and maybe you can clean
this up a bit
wondering why I sound so terrible now I
this is morning eat though I'm sorry for
that I can't help it I wasn't able to
finish her lust last bit of this episode
last night and my voice doesn't sound
very good in the morning I tried my best
not to record in the morning but can
always help it okay we do need to maybe
make a way to get into here this is a
wire room to that firework room usually
I like to leave an access to get to the
redstone wiring to all my builds maybe
mmm maybe we could put a door here even
to get into that room that would line up
pretty nicely alright and we will want
some kind of border here but maybe a
little move on to something else
uh I actually have a scouting mission to
do today I've been informed where I
might be able to find a witch spawner
not like a witch spawner but you know
witch hunt and I've never found one in
my world yet you guys are always telling
me eso make a witch farm it's like I've
never found one I don't know where where
I can make one so I'm gonna go check
these out I got two coordinates and
they're about a thousand blocks away
from here and we'll see if we can find a
witch hut or not so I got a little bit
of a problem here guys you know I got
this horse stable and whenever I want to
go somewhere I'm afraid to take these
horses because this is my fastest horse
over here Zenith Zenith is amazing and I
don't have any more donkeys so I can't
make mules so all these guys are like
super precious and I'm always worried
they're gonna die if I take them out I
can probably risk losing a mule because
I have to but still I don't know these
horse stables aren't really doing their
thing they're more for trying to figure
out which is which they're more for
animals storage not really for use
alright let's get out of here
go go exploring how quick are you he's
not too bad so we found some horses over
here I wonder if these guys are tamed
have I been out this way I'm not sure
he's got 15 hearts oh man oh yeah he
seems to be tamed wait a second we got
to try this guy out 15 heart horse
that's pretty cool
probably slow as molasses though yeah
can you jump at least no you can't
oh well today we've hit the amplified
border over here the coordinates I got
were 1100 and 500 just a little bit over
this way it is not a swap biome over
here so either I've been trolled or I
generated this world before the terrain
change which is probably what happened
so right in this spot
there's probably actually a witch
spawning area but there's no Hut because
my world was generated before witch hats
came out a lot of it hmm so this first
one doesn't look like we're gonna be
able to find the spot whoa oh man this
one might actually be here we gotta go
250 negative about 1,300 so we're pretty
close and there is a swamp here oh I did
the auto jump trick look at that day
6000 we made it
can't believe 6000 days in my world here
yeah we're generating your terrain here
it's legend like crazy uh 30 blocks this
way mmm I don't see which Hut's should
be right around here darn I don't think
there is one
again this was generated just before
they came out probably and it's on the
amplified border again so in order to
find
which hat we're gonna have to find it in
amplified terrain probably and I have
explored a lot of amplified terrain and
I have never well I found one swamp I
think one swamp in all the terrain I've
explored and it didn't have one yeah so
might not be able to make a witch farm
unless you guys give me coordinates
again let's see yeah it doesn't look
like it's nope it's a bus guys it's a
bust okay well it is possible guys I
might have found a witch hut in the past
and I just don't remember it or I never
noticed it so if you guys remember me
finding one or if you know where there
is one let me know in the comments and
I'll try find it in the future but here
is the comment for today's episode it
says hey etho there is a way to create
an instantaneous redstone but it
requires a lot of slime you can attach a
redstone block to the ends to the end of
a long chain of slime blocks attached to
a sticky piston the redstone block
powers the next piston without a
repeater delay effectively it all
happens within a couple game ticks dr.
m77 has a video on it you could use this
to make the button to the next end
reporter quicker yeah I thought about
using instant wire the problem is while
one it costs a little bit more to the
biggest time-consuming part of this is
digging these tunnels for the redstone
wire and if we have to put pistons in
here we can't walk through this anymore
so we have to either make the tunnel
wider or it'll just take a little bit
longer to set up as is my concern and
also I'm not sure I'm curious about this
if you do instant wire and you're
loading chunks does it actually make it
faster because it the game still has to
load those chunks which takes time and
the way I'm doing it with the redstone
it's loading a chunk every tenth of a
second which is pretty quick I don't
even know if the game could keep up with
that but yeah kind of interesting
anyway I did want to point something out
because I didn't really explain this too
well the whole reason we were building
this area over here by the way or why
we're working on it is because we've
we've run low on areas of expansion in
the man cave so if we want to add more
rooms we don't really have a spot to do
it anymore
until today anyway so I've added on here
we didn't build this way if we want
ideally I would have liked if there was
a cave here but there there doesn't seem
to be one maybe we'll run into one soon
because I tried to follow the shape of
the caves with this project anyways guys
I think that's going to do it for
today's episode I hope you enjoyed it
hope you have a wonderful day and I'll
see you in the next one take care night