well hello everyone this is etho and we
are playing some more minecraft today
and we were cutting down trees why are
we cutting down trees
do you guys know you know what we're
doing today umm washi I'm growing trees
I'm not actually cutting them down not
at the moment
today's going to be crazy today is going
to be wild today's exciting today we are
going to do something involving this
this this this this this and a whole lot
of this stuff yeah
now we're it's pretty crazy we're going
cheating there's been something I wanted
to try for a long time I don't know how
it's going to turn out it's we're going
caving but with a twist a very like I
don't know exactly what I want to do but
I do have a general idea basically we're
going caving with rules and the rules
are we we can only place torches on
something we've built well I'll explain
the concept first I'll help you
understand better where I'm coming from
with this usually when you go to aving
you go and you get all the iron and all
this resources and all the good stuff as
quickly as you can and you get out and
then you never want to go back to that
cave ever again because it's just the
plain old cave with nothing good in it
because you took it all out and there's
torches everywhere so what I want to do
is actually go caving and try to
decorate it's not really the word I want
to want to use but I want to make the
cave look good like I want it to be
something I might actually want to
explore some time down the line like
I'm feeling nostalgic something
something interesting to go back to not
just another generic cave all right and
to do that I'm going to like put up
wooden supports and and instead of just
running through and getting everything
as quick as I can I'm going to build a a
track all the way with a storage
minecart in it and I have to put all the
stuff I collect in that and then when
we're all done take it out using the
track that's the general idea behind it
so I got my kid picked out I'm just
trying to get wood for the support beams
we're going to build and we'll probably
figure out the style as we go in it we
might adjust it's kind of like I've
never why built the that mineshaft over
there but that's about my only
experience with trying to make a
realistic cave there's also some other
restrictions we're going to use I'm
going to take off my feather falling
boots and all my armor we're putting
that in chest also going to rid myself
of my ender pearls and no buckets if I
come across lava I can't just put water
over top of it I have to deal with it I
can't just pull her up I have to use
ladders or something to move vertically
and what else like if I come to a ravine
I can't just hop the other side I have
to build an actual proper bridge to get
across so stuff like that so I'm going
to finish getting what I need here and
we'll get going with the idea and just
see how it goes okay let's try this
again
so from our home here this is tape two
by the way I got lost trying to find the
cave we're going this way this way this
time over to the beautiful mountains
we're going to go on a little adventure
this is all the goodies I'm taken with
me aha these mountains are so nice I
shed my speak potion still
so yeah I think this is the mountain
where I started the world actually
around here this is a spawn spot
confused why it's down by the swamp now
if this was the original it must got
changed somehow we go further this way
we come to one of my favorites things
the floating island up there totally
floating Big Island amazing if we keep
going further actually where is it I
want to find I want to show you guys
something to if I can if I can find it
quick enough here I think it was up over
here no we must have passed it already
okay nevermind
yeah the cave is just on the edge of
this deserts and I think it was no not
there must be over here isn't that cool
I love that that Island up there where
it's the cave I thought I knew where it
was
oh I think it's this hill I don't come
out this area too often yeah this is it
so this is the cave we're going to start
and I marked it with the torches and
what we're going to do this is going to
be our starter trackage yes so all our
stuff we have to carry with us in
minecarts so that's going to be our best
buddy well not have to carry it or have
it in here at all times we can carry
like a status stack of it thing at a
time that's no problem you get an ender
chest as well I was going to set my
spawn but it's a little too early in the
day just in case and no armor get that
in there I might need to make another
chest
I took a quick peek in this cave and it
looks pretty decent
oh I I had a chest okay all right
put that in there can't take that or
this no ender pearls the idea so this is
another part of the idea all the torches
I get are going to come from the coal I
find I'm trying to see also all the iron
for the tracks we get has to come from
the cave to I'm going to start with just
a little bit just like a stack and see
how far we get with that I'm curious to
see if using mine cards the proper way
if you get enough iron to get a profit
out of the cave all right
can't leave everybody behind coming with
us so all right now another rule is I
kind of want to always have a torch on a
fence or something something I built J
and like stuff like this where I had to
go down a step I want to a nice half
slab thing to go up and we're just going
to take our time although I guess that's
going to cause trouble with the tracks
isn't it mm all right well we'll just do
that for the track one so far no
resources at all I don't have enough
space for all the stuff I want to use
okay how we do in structure wise is key
going to support itself I think it's
okay it's pretty good maybe we'll put a
beam in right here just to make sure
because we're going by realistic
standards here of course maybe shape
that out just put a beam across the top
this might look a little stupid
how's that ah I'll probably adjust my
style as we go here to get some more
torches alright I just want random stuff
like this everywhere okay let's move up
further next part of the cave gets a
little steep doesn't it have to really
watch ourselves here oh don't lose the
cart no no alright we're still good
oh it's really dark here though it's
more lights I just we could do and I
don't want to put there oh I heard
something and maybe as we go here I'll
talk about try to talk about stuff my
I'm kind of uh oh you know what I need
no team over nope our buddy
oh I was terrible no oh well we survived
let's get our buddy back together
ah poor guy get that back in yeah you
know what I need is stairs I never made
wooden stairs that would be really
helpful for these steep parts and a
crafting table so I want to talk about I
guess I'll try to talk about feed the
beast a little bit and just general
general youtube stuff and stuff
pertaining to my let's play ah I am
really enjoying feed the beast it's a
lot of fun it's kind of renewed my
creative spark I find as well like not
like sure on feed the beast there's all
this crazy new stuff to play around with
which I love but even
even in say like vanilla I'm trying to
get a little more creative with stuff
lately I find ok I really enjoyed the
response I got on the last mine crack
video where I was working on the rail
line well I guess we'll I don't have to
live with that I placed it nope can't
put that there I have ha man this the
only problem with what we're doing here
is I feel I need more hotbar space ok
pretty good
how's our structure here looking ok uh
first set up iron here I felt like I
might it might sound like I'm getting a
little negative here but this is a
positive thing I'm speaking about a
place that there can i all right we have
no armor we have to deal with them like
a month or two ago I felt like I was
kind of getting in a creative rut
playing Minecraft and everybody goes
through these in fact I think that's why
a lot of people quit playing Minecraft
when they do it's like they're in a rut
that they just don't get out of which I
don't really want to ever happen to me
but like a few months ago it's like
everything I tried to do didn't seem to
work anymore
and I'm going to view two examples of
that I like I would overlook some really
important thing like I tried to make for
example something that detected weather
and I built that in creative mode spent
good two three hours on it really happy
with how it turned out and then it's
like I was about to record a tutorial on
it's like oh yeah you know like I wanted
to use it to to detect whether so that
people could clear it instantly on on a
map that are making or something like
that so I thought I had something good
but then it's like oh yeah there's a
clear weather like 10,000 100,000
however long you want command
which pretty much made it pointless and
yeah I had that problem with a few other
things so it's like I was getting a
little discouraged about the things I
was making like nothing was working I
just would get the cold - right but I I
felt like I started to get out of that
creative rut when I started the
mapmaking series again or not again but
the originally kind of got me thinking
creatively again and that now feed the
beast has done the same it's not just on
feed the beast in vanilla I'm thinking
about things in a more creative way -
which is good that's how you have fun
playing Minecraft let's get a fence over
here and as we go what we should really
do there's so much stuff to manage as we
go though what we should do is try to
smelt the iron we find and use that time
to build stuff if I'm rambling a lot
this episode I apologize it's really
hard to to do what I'm doing here and
talk at the same time hard to speak
coherently let's see where do we want to
go now I think we should have junctions
- like if I come across stuff like this
we should make a junction of some sorts
so let's put in a detector rail and so I
brought these and these should always go
to a return to the surface there so see
Junction actually no we don't want that
switch OOP that'll just go on his own
woman yeah both ways it'll go there
that's good
alright this caves pretty pretty quiet
actually how are we doing on supports
over here should I put in a pillar you
think oh we got trouble
alright we're good
I guess there's a natural pillar here I
think it'll hold itself alright actually
you know what we don't get too far here
because we have our iron back there but
yeah with that being said I am really
really enjoying this game again not that
I wasn't before it sighs okay in a rut I
felt like like I couldn't do anything
right
I think that's around the same times
worked on Emerald City too and I was I
was never really happy with how that
turned out I kind of understand why I
don't like it now and what I need to do
to fix it but we'll get to that later
yeah I'm really enjoying the game if you
guys ever find here and I'm in a rut in
this game don't forget there's like I
find a lot of people don't really
explore all avenues of the game like
there's this what I want to do I don't
think I want to do this do I let's leave
this open like this like there's a
there's three main avenues I'd say to
this game there's the technical side to
it that's sort of how I became what I am
although now I tend to do everything I
find like I also lately I've been
focusing more on building stuff as well
trying to make stuff look good the
learning process I'm not saying I'm good
at it but I'm trying to get good at it
let's always store our stuff in here too
I'm going to make make use of our buddy
and I'm going to put a pillar why not
right
let's put it here now there's a
technical side of Minecraft there's the
building trying to make stuff look good
there's also the pb PvP side that a lot
of people don't really get into either
you might not like them at first but if
you if you do them if you try them out
you'll probably like them F like if you
get good at PvP you'll like PvP is what
I'm saying not saying I'm good at PvP
either but let's try different stuff if
you if you're looking for something
different I guess if you need need to
have fun in the game try something
different or or watch someone's video of
something amazing they made and maybe
it'll inspire you to do something
interesting as well
Ike you put me on the floor I don't know
how far we're going to get with this
today it's actually taking a lot of time
and I'm trying to move fairly quick here
even though it might not seem like it
all right what do we got here oh there's
water oh boy grounds little soft here
too maybe we should change this out just
to wood it's silly I know it's really
but it's that's kind of fun OOP if you
force yourself limitations you kind of
have to it makes you do interesting
things as well all right we'll do that
I hear mobs around I got these equipped
let's use those um and find a lot to
feed the beast starting to get into it I
was on there for probably four or five
hours today I haven't been working on my
map I really need to though I do plan on
finishing it don't worry
well it's not it's not a map it's a game
genre
sort of alright let's gooo oh we don't
want that okay this might be a cave-in
area so we're going to do a full full
beam over top
oops what I've been doing a lot lately
is a PvP actually like every second
night or so play game a nailer
revolution is another game we play and
having fun with that and I haven't
really been working on my map like I
would like I should be come on there we
go it's dark in here let's put our our
lights on the posts this time and over
there it's actually surprisingly few
mobs whoa no what is this it was
dangerous let's put a let's try beam
like this across this time change it up
there we go but we'll have to build a
bridge here or something to get our iron
alright there you go buddy this looks a
little weird let's change this up okay
what kind of bridge should we build I
guess we'll make it go should we just do
a cheesy bridge it's not really much of
a pool I'll just do a cheesy bridge a
little log going across or something
works for me
OOP
and we are out of rails so the question
is how much iron do we do we have from
doing this only got 12 it's not very
much I'll do this what 32 more yeah all
right we can go a little further with
that do you think we need railing guys
if this needs a rail to or can we walk
it safely maybe do this too whoops
oh there's coal here let's grab the coal
the pool water down there really mmm
another torch here mmm
might have to part this up oh you know
we'll use for boarding this up let's use
just regular fences I think something
like this danger all right
oh man
this is gonna be cool when it's all done
that's kind of neat if it nobody sees
this episode and they download my world
later and they walk through this will be
like what the heck all right should we
go this way really running low on rails
sweet okay you know what I should have
brought is some TNT so if I ever come to
grab a like this I just blow it up oh
because it's like our passage is blocked
now darn alright this is a dead end dead
end
alright let's go this way then we got
over here this will put a detector rail
here to switch it not going to work even
yeah that worked okay let's go over here
just about out hyoeun mmm yes cave I
don't trust this cave if we need to get
another beam going here oh yeah this is
looking sweet
all right oh I was really hard to get on
there there we go finally okay we need
some coal for more torches get that in
there
live his journey on further we're just
about out of rails I hate to say it I've
got to iron that's not enough for more
either OOP mmm and passport here just in
case at that roof you know the ceiling
it's made out of soil it's not very
stable
you never know not taking chances
another one over here
oh that was not my sword that's more
coal where's the iron ed guys we need
iron this is not going to go very well
if we don't get iron danger yeah we kind
of want this track to connect to don't
we
that's it man that's all the rails we
have well if we see some iron down here
we can grab it we're going a little yeah
I think that's as far as we can get with
what we had
we started with 64 tracks to is a sad
thing so we didn't get too far
all right guys I think it's time we pack
our bags and head on home and go to the
bank apply for a loan because we need
and we need a lot more iron to continue
this it looks like I cheated a little
bit I went back to the here I went down
there and found a bit of iron ten pieces
or so put it in a bowl and that was
about it just so we can make a minecart
to get out of here because I am trapped
I can't I can't walk out of here we need
the convenience of a minecart oh yeah
and I cheated over here - I saw can't
put torches on the wall I guess we'll
just block this off this is a dangerous
area it's dark get out of here man oh
there's another one guy you should be
behind the dangerous area
oh all right so let's get out of here
before we die get a minecart for
ourselves and put that there
I think this should take us out of here
pack our stuff up okay yeah give it some
coal get in mine Kurt
I think this is how my cards are
supposed to be used in the game like
minecart this is what you think the
intended purpose is I should say I know
it was never intended to be used like
this and you know for how old these
furnace mine carts are they really
should be improved like oh man it's so
sad you can't get up a hill with them
darn it
what do we do guys what do we do if we
make a second one do you think you'll
have enough power then let's try that
out all right and get just a little bit
more cool
there goes come on
oh my ride no no my ride there we go so
it doesn't work if you have to that's
interesting ah
oh I'm inside something oh oh all right
well we made it out safe and sound had
to use two furnace pine carts and a
creeper blew up but we got outs alive so
let's just read a quick comment here to
end the episode it says etho do you have
your old LP world because you said you
would keep this one forever I became
curious yeah I do have it I think I even
have a download available still in some
of my older videos although there's a
very good chance that got removed but
maybe like if you guys still want to get
it you might be able to I'm not sure but
I do have it on my harddrive here I have
a few different dates of it actually
like the most recent one and also some
threw outs when I was making backups and
I even have my original two worlds
before the LP world even so yeah I've I
haven't lost anything to crashes like
hard drive crashes or anything like that
I'm happy
and I've been tempted to look at them
again sometime sometime soon because
it's been a while since I last checked
them out get that nostalgic feeling
going again you know what I would like
to get some time as an old version of
Minecraft like an alpha version just to
I don't just feel how different the game
is now compared to them again but yeah
it's gonna do it for today guys the mind
turned out pretty good I'd say it's I
want to try something different I guess
it's very very strange way to go caving
and I think if I took my time on it I
could actually make it look pretty good
but as sort of rushing through it today
but yeah I think I'm going to go on here
take care guys and I'll see you again
next time