hey what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys we're here playing
some more minecraft again today and I
have updated guys we're on 16 wo for a
now latest snapshot I might just have a
bad memory but I think they added a few
new sounds in these latest snapshots in
particular the one I like is the fence
gates especially the opening that work
ah it kinda reminds me of the the
pac-man
Wacka Wacka you know wakka but if you
had two of them open at the same time
anyways the one sound though that's
really throwing me off here it's kind of
freaking me out a little bit is the
chest sound listen to this here let's
crank this up two blocks yes master
volume oh yeah and they they changed it
out they change the GUI here a little
bit they got realms notifications in the
list now is the one change I noticed
they moved it like the difficulty
settings down here I wish they kept to
like swap these two because this has
always been up over here and it's
throwing me off a little bit but yeah
check out the chest sounds that you hear
that close the squeaky hinge now that
might not sound scary but when I hear
that I think I'm playing Terra Firma
craft and that sounds like the bear
growl you know and it freaks me out
sometimes when I'm not thinking about it
because like if you hear the bear growl
you run you you run it's like the
creeper sizzle except even more deadly
so my initial reaction is to run away
flee um yeah anyways I set this up here
let's do this
I apologize in advance this might start
to get annoying all right Valis Duval
and there's one more thing about this
snapshot I really want to show you guys
just in case you didn't see it already
it's like a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity because they're gonna fix it
they made a mistake with the boats where
they have very little friction which
means you can drive them around like a
vehicle on the land like they just kind
of slip along which is really cool I
kind of wish they would leave this in
and you can like drift and is it's
really neat that I set up some chip jump
pads here woo let's go to this one let's
see how high we jump to you because it
seems like oh oh no that's the thing
though if you fall down you can't get
back up it seems like you jump really
high on the boats doesn't it okay you go
in smooth oh yeah that's that's like ten
blocks
that's incredible all right well let's
get things rolling here for today I got
a couple things to show you to begin
with I like I did a bunch of resource
gathering and some building off-camera
here this morning I woke up early like
6:00 a.m. as like I wanted to play
Minecraft but oh that was loud just an
iron golem fell down they felt very hurt
I just be I woke up at 6:00 a.m. as like
I want to play Minecraft but I got my
morning voice I sound groggy umm even
now later in the day when I'm Pepe I
still sound groggy it's just my voice
but I sound really groggy in the morning
and I don't like to record but I wanted
to play minecraft is like well I'm gonna
do some building some resource gathering
and stuff so I did that ice column there
um mainly I did a bunch of building in
this this rough part of the man cave
it's pretty much like where I would call
it finished now so I added in the the
leaf ceiling design thing that I like to
do like oak slabs on the side
it's kind of made some of these
entranceways a little fancier like we
got oak Oak pillars and that kind of
stuff at them same with over there uh
with a slime minecart thing here I put
some yellow clay in the back there it's
fences in front just to give it some
color sealed this all up oaks lab
ceiling there why is there a slime stuck
up there I'll have to check that out in
a sec and over here in particular I
don't know if you remember but like all
this area like over here was just a mess
like stone blocks all over the place
redstone levers and just a bunch of
garbage so it's all kind of finished up
here and finished off this this wacky
little ceiling we got I decided to like
build a wall over here and then I just
put some leaves against its wheat field
I really like this wheat field I don't
know what what it is about this one in
particular but I think it's just a nice
little decorative thing to this area put
in a window here to the Cape spider
spawner which is kind of neat because
you can see through the other window
over there from this lower part so if
for some reason you had more than one
player you could see like the guy going
across there or or if you're up there
you can see someone walking over here
but this is a single player so that's
never going to happen and I think out of
all this so I particularly like this
this area here something about like the
way these logs are positioned like they
go up and sideways and then over top and
it's kind of wacky like nonce a sim
symmetry you know going on there I think
it looks kind of cool happy with how
that turned out
so yeah that is basically all done over
there now which is cool
well it's kind of tough for me because
some of the stuff I built in the past
like this thing over here it's like I
would never build this today I think it
looks a little dumb but at the same time
I don't want to remove it so I have to
try to blend it in and make it work and
um it's not exactly my favorite part of
the man cave over there but it's decent
this is my favorite parts over here I
think this area looks really cool the
baby brown code villager here has grown
up have you become a man that I'm proud
of no pure Shepherd we want a farmer
your disappointment alright everybody so
I have a just a little quick project we
can do over at Sandy City here a lot of
the times when I pass through here I
want to use a nether portal and there's
not really a proper one here we do have
one up on top the building there it I
didn't place that it spawned up there
and I always forget to use it because
it's kind of out of sight out of mind
and also like if I want to use it I feel
like there climb up the building here or
ender pearl up there it's not in a
convenient location is what I'm getting
at so we're going to try build a proper
nether portal in this area and I thought
it would be cool if we put in the well
here like a little secret one so what
we're gonna do have will have like this
layer of water so it still looks like a
well and then we have to I want to make
it like automatic you know what I mean
what's the best way actually let's go
back up which way did we fall from oh I
happen to have an ender pearl there we
go alright so generally when we use this
we're probably going to enter from this
direction falling this way so we want
the the portal like over on this side I
guess just so it's a little less
disorienting disorientating when we use
it ah let's let's try to build that
actually let's mmm what's what's the
first thing to do here maybe we should
figure out where to put the
the first platform now we want to go
down at this level so what we're going
to do is have like Pistons and pressure
plates if we land on the pressure plates
let's see these pistons will push you oh
you know what's going to happen here I'm
going to break the signs I'm going to
break the gravel the signs are going to
break and then the water is going to
fall on us unless I can break it in
places very quickly now I failed oh wait
no the signs are on that side okay this
might be okay I placed it but it's
breaking what you guys see that the the
piston broke when I placed it that was
weird
did I actually lose it or what happened
I want to see man do that again 61 we
had 61 now we have 60 what happened the
piston
oh man that's weird
59 yeah we're losing kissed ins okay
kind of strange I'm pretty sure it never
used to do that
okay let's rebuild this all right so I
guess the ideas we'll put repeaters here
um
redstone on top of these blocks is what
we're gonna have to try dude this is
really annoying having all this gravel
and sand here I got to say maybe we
should just get rid of the water
temporarily because otherwise I'm going
to struggle with this the whole time
it's like a juggling act you know trying
to build well stopping the water yeah
well just get rid of that for now okay
so I just took a little moment here to
figure out a few things it occurred to
me we could probably do this a little
bit better than what I was trying to do
here also when we enter the well we're
probably actually going to enter either
from this side or the other side because
we have the post in the way so we'll
pick one or the other here oh I guess
we'll go
yeah let's put the nether portal on this
side new plan okay
alright this is what I was doing and I
just had like pressure plate repeater
sticky piston hit the pressure plate it
pushes you and I need to go down one
step in the middle we'd have another one
and then another one at the third layer
would have taken up a lot of space and
it occurred to me you know we have we
have slime blocks in the game I should
really take advantage of them here so
that's why I have a new plan now okay
let's let's see the nether portal goes
there what we're going to do then is
have a 3x3 thing of pressure plates that
will detect it when we land
so let's I'm getting really used to this
middle middle clicking to select the
block you want it's really really cool
alright so just put some redstone down
here oops
fill that in oh I keep bragging like the
one and only torch we have down here
alright this pressure plates and out if
we step on any of these it's going to
trigger that redstone down below let's
break this stuff since we're not using
it okay and then what we're going to do
is have like a arm that pushes us from
this side into the nether portal over
here let's go ahead and build the nether
portal just so we know where it's going
oh and that's okay good and also I'm
going to try set this up so that when we
go through the nether portal it
automatically closes behind us as well
so that we if like we're in the nether
we use another portal we never want to
end up down in the well here that would
not be this would not be a good place to
come out it's kind of inconvenient okay
there's our nether portal alright so now
we need our arm that pushes us so we're
going to do a little slime block thing
here basically goes the torch basically
it's going to go like this
clear garbage here and we will do oh we
got invisible blocks guys we're going to
do that that shape there I'm pretty sure
and then like sticky pistons on each of
these let me break these temporarily
okay I'm back and I can't remember where
where do we have to trigger this I think
at this line here right yeah okay we're
going to assume that so then we put that
down there
now we need to go up here I'm rambling
let's uh get some more land what we'll
do is put down a torch I don't do a lot
of redstone on camera I thought this
would be a simple enough thing to do but
as you can see even simple things like
this I struggle a little bit with um
which one do we have to activate first
let's figure out the sequence maybe a
good way of figuring out the sequence of
things is using levers and triggering it
one by one
so I'm guessing it's this one first
right oh wait a sec it's not going to
work as we got invisible block we've got
all this land on the side we need to get
rid of let's break this is a the slime
blocks are sticking to that that's not
good okay let's try it again okay so it
goes forward one oops oh and these are
gonna have to be obsidian yeah because
otherwise they move with it or some
block that doesn't get triggered right
that one then you trigger this one the
whole thing moves forward good and then
when we pull it back oops is it all
retract properly yeah okay good umm so
probably what we're going to do get rid
of these again
oh that's a skeleton horse I found a few
more of them but none of them were were
all that great so then I think we set
this the two this the four let's try it
out
this should be the the sequence yeah
then retract oh did not retract properly
uh-huh it was because I had the
repeaters reversed so I flipped them
here so now whole thing seems to work
okay nice and simple all we got to do
now is connect this to our three by
three thing of redstone down here and we
should be good to go
all right I guess we have to come up to
here don't want to attach here because
then the redstone is going to face the
wrong way and so are we out of we are
out of it let's make some more okay
sometimes I put redstone on sandstone I
don't know why I did that yeah so now
let's try it out as soon as we land on
any of these we get pushed into the
nether portal now that's what we want
it's not glitching out that's great
so what I'm going to do now is hook up
the timer on the portal so when we hit
the pressure plate portal turns on then
after I think it's 41 ticks 41 redstone
ticks we shut it off awesome so I think
it's just about done here let's just put
the finishing touches on it so we're
going to put down our water again this
will work right this is the part I'm
scared of I hate I hate how water rex
redstone you know if only they could get
along but they just don't alright so
basically from these pressure plates I
have a 5 tick delay here this is just to
give us enough time so that we're within
the portal area we don't want to turn it
turn it on before we are at the portal
otherwise this isn't going to work so
then goes up here this redstone
activates this dispenser first off we're
going to fill this up with flint and
steel so it lights the portal alright
and then we have ten repeaters that's 40
and then there's little mom stable
circuit here alright and then one more
ticks so 41 total then it goes to this
dispenser which we're going to put a
water bucket in so that ejects the water
breaks the portal and then it also sends
a signal down this line and with a 2
redstone delay after that it's going to
activate this again to pick up the water
and that's pretty much all we got to do
so let's try this out it almost seemed
to light that a little too soon doing it
maybe I'll add a little bit more delay
that was definitely fine we could
probably make it 6 okay I love that
water sound that's so cool
also I got some some Sealand lanterns
here we don't want mobs spawning down
here because this will activate the
thing and cause some trouble right so we
want to make sure it's bright enough and
a weekend
finish this off hopefully without
getting teleported this okay
everything's good here it's lit up yeah
once I close this off I probably never
enter back here again want to make sure
it's lit up well enough good okay very
quickly got it so it should be good to
go now where is it gonna put us in the
nether
I'll put us on the stupid potion track
oh that might be a problem this is not
actually connected with another hub not
directly
another hub is through here oh very very
hurry okay okay so we got it all set up
here it should be good to go let's try
it out for for real this time make sure
it does what we want it to do gives us
that good effect okay push this into the
portal portal turned on and I heard it
shut off aha awesome that is really cool
so I disabled that potion another portal
just for the time being
till I figure out what to do about it
takes us there and since the portal
automatically shut off we're back to the
man cave now very cool I like it I love
the horse sound that's so awesome okay
today we're gonna check out the horses
as well the jumping project we're trying
to breed a super high jumping horse and
we got a couple more candidate
candidates to try out here I know some
of you guys always ask about this
alright we're trying to jump on top of
the snow here doesn't look like this
guy's a winner so we're gonna get rid of
them alright let's try out the next one
yeah those skeleton horses they're
really cool but you can't actually breed
them if you guys didn't know that
otherwise I would I would like breed a a
nice black horse with 30 hearts that
would be pretty cool alright whoa okay
this guy's not bad I don't think you can
do it though yeah he's just a little bit
shy so if you didn't know we're like at
the point where we have to tame like 50
horses or so before we can break our old
record by just a little bit so chances
of us actually doing this is pretty low
Oh
okay you're all good okay how about you
you're a nice-looking one nope no good
nope no good all right the last horse
the brown one the special one doesn't do
it oh man
so that was six more horses that were
not able to beat the old record hmm do
you guys know any of you guys know what
is causing this exactly in the latest
snapshots
there's just crazy tick legs every so
often like look at this you see how long
it took me to pick up the villagers
you're walking slow I'm not sure what's
what's doing it it's not the iron golems
I have confirmed that there's no iron
golems wandering around well there's a
there's a couple here I'm not they're
not totally gone but there's not like a
hundred of them like there was before
but we're still lagging and I'm not sure
what is doing it or if there's any fix
to it mm-hmm anyways I think we're gonna
have to call episode here for today
because trying to get more regular with
the uploads and this is supposed to go
up in less than half an hour which is
not going to happen it's going to be
late already
so yeah let's let's get to it here oh
man look at this uh-huh yeah today might
feel like a shorter episode but we
actually did a lot of stuff like I did a
bunch off-camera and then we did a
project together on camera it's kind of
unusual because usually I do a mix of
like off camera on camera which i think
is better but today is going to be the
exception where we do like one extreme
and then the other extreme but yeah here
we go it says do you ever wonder if
you'd make more money on your channel if
you did all survival minecraft videos I
notice that they seem to get the most
views I'm all for you keeping it
interesting for yourself so don't get
bored so you don't get bored but vanilla
minecraft survival is the thing you do
that I enjoy the most I don't really
watch the other ones
mm-hmm so I know some people have done
polls on this in the past and for sure
the vanilla minecraft series this series
here is the one that people seem to like
the most um but I know like some people
like Terra Firma graph the most some
people like modded the most or whatever
else I got going on Ark survival a lot
of people like bats it's not the the top
one though for sure this is the top
series what I find though is if I do too
much vanilla minecraft like even back in
the day when we had the minecraft server
going on um a lot of times man I would
get so burnt out I would hide it as best
as I could but it's really hard to do
too many series of vanilla minecraft
even at hermit craft like that was good
for a while but eventually it got to the
point where it's like I don't want to
play minecraft anymore because I was
doing too much vanilla minecraft so I
think it's really important to have a
belts and I recommend this for you guys
too if all you do is survival minecraft
man give modded minecraft a try it
really grows on you it's fun for sure
might be confusing at first but you
really get into it after a while most
people do anyway maybe it's not for you
maybe you've tried it but I think the
variety is really important and even
like in my vanilla series here I try to
have a lot of variety I do building I do
redstone I do whatever I can think of
venturing what else is there just to
keep things interesting for myself and
for you guys hopefully anyways I'm
rambling let's end it here thank you
guys for watching I hope you have a
wonderful day and hopefully this doesn't
take too long to upload take care bye
bye
you