[Music]
hey hey what's up everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
our let's play world
how you doing hopefully you're having a
wonderful day um
we're here in sandy city right now i was
just
playing around with these chorus fruits
a little bit that's kind of what i want
to do today i want to make a course
fruit farm i've been wanting to do that
the last couple episodes
and we just haven't had time so today's
the day
let's talk about this uh what the plan
is
so okay i've been trying to figure out
the design for this um one of the big
problems with the chorus fruits
is you need these seeds and i just
planted some of them over here last time
this is how they grow they grow all
crazy and chaotically like that
in order to actually get these seeds you
have to break
the seed pod over here if you like break
the stem over here
you don't get any seeds and then you you
have nothing to replant it with
okay that's our first challenge
um so when they're way up in the air
like that there's not really any good
way of
of getting the seeds harvested even if
you built like a platform to
kind of stand on up there it's still
kind of crazy and chaotic
so something a lot of people are doing
i've seen i think azuma even had a
a tutorial on this is you just uh
you kind of block their their growth
by putting a ceiling over top them like
three blocks up here
and they'll still split into multiple
seeds so this one has three
three seed pods for example you easily
harvest them because there are
at eye level here which is kind of nice
i think that's
one thing we're going to do for sure
that way we don't have to worry about
getting more of these seeds
and trying to figure out a way of of
collecting them easily
uh the thing to note about these plants
though they're kind of
interesting if you want to get these
seed pods you can't just oh
yeah you can't just like push them with
a piston unfortunately
uh they don't like having any blocks
next to them
if uh if you do that it just it just
destroys the plant like you saw
here let's try this um
oh i do have levers excellent
okay so yeah as soon as a another
something like another block or piston
head or anything gets next to it it just
breaks and you don't get the seed out of
it
so that's kind of challenging there's no
way of automating it that means
so you got to manually break them the
other thing is if we want to
break the plant there's a couple ways we
can do it like if you break the stem
everything above that gets broken you
can put a block next to the stems
and then if you if you destroy that
the whole plant gets destroyed and drops
all the fruits that's one way you can do
it
another way you could do it is to
move the the end stone that it's planted
on
so for example if you do this the whole
plant gets destroyed
and finally another way well there might
be
even more ways i'm not sure if you
if you wash away with water
that also will break the plant so
there's a couple different ways of doing
it
okay well anyways that's the general
idea to how these plants work
what we're going to be doing today i
want to build both a seed farm
so something similar to this we're going
to try optimize it as best as we can
so we get seeds very quickly and then
we're going to have another
a second farm for growing the full-blown
plants like this
the the bigger the plant is the more
fruits
the more of this fruit you get and more
fruit you get the more
perper blocks you get so we want we want
to collect as much as we can as the idea
um when we build our farm we're going to
try to automatically
collect the fruit and we're going to try
to automatically smelt it in a furnace
is what i want to do
now i had one idea originally i was
gonna do something like
this um so we have these fence gates
right
these create an opening where the fruit
could fall down into a water stream
below and then they get
collected together into one spot
um the piston would move the end stone
block so the whole
plant breaks i'll show you i'll show you
how it works
all right
kind of like that so everything breaks
if any of them land on the end stone
like this one for example
when we trigger it back into place
over here like we would have a smart
piston set up
probably um any that land on top of the
blocks will get
they'll fall through basically into the
water below and
100 collection rate i believe
and then the reason for this minecart
track is uh
you kind of go along and
you know i never made mine cart i can't
really demonstrate it but yeah
it would help to speed up the replanting
because you just kind of go along
like that uh the only thing is if you
right click on a fence
it's going to open it or close it which
would be annoying
now the other idea i had was just to do
something like this and i think this is
what we're going to do
because that minecart idea is so
intricate to set up and so complicated
and expensive and
sometimes you know i like doing things
complicated but sometimes simpler is
actually better and
and this seems to be a pretty good idea
so anyway anywhere there's a end stone
block is where i would put the chorus
fruits right
and you just every every six blocks go
up a step
and then the water will flow down and
harvest all the course fruit
automatically and collect it all
together at the bottom
oh oh yeah okay
so when we release it we're gonna need a
longer
strip here at the start but yeah
basically all the coarse fruit is going
to flow down to the bottom where these
seeds are
and then we can just collect it and then
bring it to a furnace and
and automatically smelt it so that seems
like a pretty good way of doing it
i gotta find a spot to set it up and
then we can
uh probably get going here
all right well i've looked around our
world here quite a bit guys
and the one spot that's standing out the
most to me is uh
up behind the village uh we have quite a
bit of
open field here that we haven't done
anything with so far
so i would like to fill it up if we can
this area
and i want to build it somewhere that
we're going to frequent like somewhere
we're going to travel quite a bit so the
plants will actually grow and we don't
have to afk in the chunks
you know to get our fruit growing here
so yeah maybe right behind
behind here would be good you see how it
kind of gradually slopes downward
uh and then there's this big cliff here
i think we'll try to take advantage of
that if we can
and i'm planning on maybe
having a path or a river running down at
the bottom of this cliff
so let's see wait a second
wait a second maybe uh let's give a
little bit of space
yeah let's plan to put a line like right
over here
okay so we'll cut all this land away
all the coarse fruit is going to
probably drop off into a water stream
over here so we'll either make a fake
river or maybe a one wide
water stream and then a path beside it
type of thing
maybe eventually we'll reinforce this
cliff to make it look like it's
being held in place properly
i'm going to fill this water in
and we want this first step to be eight
blocks
long so four five six seven
eight all right
and then this one will be six and then
all the other ones will be six from
from here on you're you're gonna watch
in a cactus i know it's
i know it i'm so used to playing arc and
i just want to
uh press uh the whistle button when i
get off my horse here so it doesn't move
oh yeah check it out everybody things
are coming together now
they're taking shape i've been at this
for a little while just doing the
terraforming and stuff
i decided to do a test run here too so i
planted
whatever seeds i had just to make sure
they would grow together
uh where i put them here and it looks
like they get to
the full height for the most part like
if you put them too close together they
run into each other and then
then they stop growing you can see maybe
a few of these
that kind of happen when they turn black
like that
but uh generally speaking i think uh i
think it's a pretty good pattern
for the floor here and i got maybe a
little carried away with the size of
this thing
check it out like from up here um
there's about 30 per per step
and there's five steps total so that's
like 150
plants if each of them dropped one
course fruit that's 150 blocks per
harvest
like 150 per per blocks we'll get but
we're probably gonna get at least
three or four fruits so that's that's a
lot of blocks
per per thing here uh to make things a
little easier on myself i just set up a
beacon here we got
we got uh haste and speed
which will make uh replanting faster too
because we'll be able to to get around
quicker
and i think we'll probably stop
around there we're gonna have to do a
bit of work in this area to make that
look natural like i don't really like
this grass
next to the end stone the green and
yellow and purple
isn't really doing it for me uh i was
thinking
maybe we switch out the grass with uh
mycelium because
it's purple as well or or maybe a
hardened clay of some kind would look
good i'm not sure
we'll have to think of something though
um
but in order to fill this farm we're
going to need a lot of these
of the coarse fruit seeds so maybe we
should get going on the seed farm to
get out of my way i was going to put it
right next to this so on the opposite
side
underneath the village maybe we'll just
dig a hole around here
all we really need is like a too high
space basically so maybe all along the
farm
we will start to
chiseling out the land here and then
we'll like put end stone down here and
stuff
try to put lights in the ceiling and
like some way of releasing water as well
down here so that we can
quickly clean up any scrap that gets
left behind would be a good idea
okay so now i'm just doing some
experiments with this seed farm trying
to find the ideal way of uh
setting it up here uh ideally i would
like them all to grow like this plant
here where it has one on the left one on
the right
then you could have them together like
just one block space in between
and you could just run down a long a
long path you know with your axe
just go get get a ton of seeds
because each plant would split into two
but i don't know if there's any way to
actually force it to grow
like this one this one just happened by
chance
some of them like they went to the
rights a lot of these ones did i wonder
if we give it enough time if it's gonna
grow a seed over
over here or if it's if it's just done
growing i'm not sure we're just going to
let that sit for a little bit
i just realized you know i have no idea
if these plants are flammable
i have no idea what tnt does to them so
we're going to have some fun here
just want to see if they burn down or
what
usually mo jing doesn't uh remember to
do stuff like that though when they
introduce a new thing
because it's a plant it should be
flammable right
but yeah it doesn't look like it is okay
i want to see
what tnt does too if it's gonna harvest
the seeds or not
that would be interesting
all right let's put it right up
in the middle here it's really weird
like i tried jumping around on the top
here it's actually not too difficult to
harvest the see
seed pods just by climbing around on
here i was a little surprised
all right oh
there we go okay let's see what happens
and did we get any seed pods
coarse fruit coarse fruits
nope no see pods
all right well i left these for a little
while and nothing has really changed so
it seems like it's kind of just like
randomly chooses if it's gonna grow
a seed here or not here or not you're
not
if you block those spots it just
decreases your odds of getting more
seeds that's why a lot of these only
have one
instead of two or more so yeah i think
probably the best arrangement is gonna
be
like we have over here alternate like
this
you still have a straight line like you
can run down like this
get the seed pods the only ones you
aren't going to get are the ones that
grow in between
these two blocks might be a bit
bit tricky i had an idea though we're
going to try another thing here
maybe the secrets to coarse fruit farms
is the horse you know what
i actually have a good feeling about
this because we uh i tried jumping
around on top of these it wasn't
too too bad but if we have a horse
like you're not going to fall through
the spaces then right if you have a
jumping horses
especially maybe with jumping potions
like look how easy it is to get around
this is the way to do it
right harvest
harvesting speed is slower if you're on
a horse cuts it in half but
still
i don't know though i think maybe a seed
farm would be faster
because it's about two three seconds
between each one i'm i'm picking here
but while with the seed farm you could
probably just run down and get them all
all right anyways let's uh let's get
back to building here so one thing i'm
gonna do
is try the mycelium outs i don't have a
lot of this stuff though
i think that's cool right like they're
pretty close in color uh to get rid of
the grass i'm just gonna go by with the
hoe
it should turn back to dirt over time
and then my ceiling won't be able to
spread to it i hope
um the edges here though we got to watch
out because i think enderman will be
able to pick up these blocks we might
need
some special block on the edges that
they can't grab
and also lighting on the ground would be
nice too so this is
lit up at night
man i can't believe this guys i just
realized
the dumbest thing this is probably
common knowledge but i just
i just thought of it horse pillars
oh man the greatest thing ever you know
i'm pretty sure that black horse died by
the way i think he jumped into a jacket
so i was trying to figure out what to do
with this guy
and it just hit me why don't i just
build a pillar that's four blocks tall
because
the ai in the game won't fall if it's uh
it only falls if it's three blocks or
less sort of thing so if it's four
blocks
they just stay there they can't path
find their way down
so yeah why don't i just do that
i i have no idea usually what i would do
before that if i just wanted a quick
stopping point for a horse i would dig a
hole like this a two by two
right oops park the horse down here
then i'd i'd take away one block so i
can get out myself the problem with this
though is i often found
my horses were glitching into the blocks
and suffocating
and also if i tried to find my horse
again a lot of times i couldn't because
they're below ground right you can't see
them too well
if they're up on a pillar though it's
just like oh
i'm over here oh snap i'm gonna be doing
that a lot
from now on yes greatest thing okay back
to the course fruit farm so i got the
mycelium spreading
uh what we're gonna do this is the very
edge here this is where the water is
going to end
at this block we're removing right now
so let's get rid of this we'll change it
out with something more
permanent let's use stone bricks
i like these with my celium as well so
if assuming this is what we're going to
keep
i think stone brick is a good match with
mycelium
all right so water ends on this block
then the coarse fruit is going to fall
down to
this this row here let's uh balance it
out by putting more bricks on the other
side
and then in between here we're going to
run water streams or possibly a hopper
minecart i haven't cited yet
oops and then over here we got
i i measured it out so we would have
five blocks
and then the stone brick on both sides
right
this i may make into the new path block
i'm not sure
does that kind of go with the mycelium
i don't know it might be a good idea
because we have
like i want to transform this whole area
quite a bit not just like this course
room
fruit farm around the village and stuff
it would be nice to do a little bit of
terraforming
like we have for example a fence over
here fence over there
it would be nice to have a path running
down the middle here so maybe do that
out of the path blocks
sort of thing maybe make a nice gate to
our village to get inside
could do a lot of improvements in this
area
all right uh this i guess would have to
go up a block then if this is the level
ground
here oh
get out of here okay let's try this out
oh lots of mobs over there uh the 1.9
man i tell you it's scary i
actually fear mobs again
because you can't just spam click them
with your your tools you got to wait a
little bit
i am using the axe maybe i should change
to the sword again
oh i have started using my bow too
though
i find the shield is really hard to use
like
just in general gameplay though like
because it takes up an extra spot and it
blocks the screen quite a bit i don't
like that
all that much so i don't think i'm going
to be using it just in general play
i just love watching these things grow
after i plant them because they change
so quickly like they grow so fast
it's like non-stop you see things moving
it's pretty cool i like it so we got our
path down the middle here
and what we're gonna have to do is get a
water stream at the top
that will harvest these and also wash
all the the coarse fruit
down the slope here i put some stairs
to separate the layers here i hope this
works okay i'm not sure if it will
i'm worried items might get stuck in
this little uh
missing section but i think i think they
just bounce off right
if i'm not mistaken the nice thing about
using a stair is we can just walk up the
next level too
which will be pretty convenient when
we're we're planting that way i don't
have to jump all the time
uh i also am getting the seed firm set
up i'm still on the fence about this
whole idea
i'll tell you what let's go sleep real
quick here
yeah i'm not too sure if we're doing the
seed firm or not
we'll try it out in just a second here
i feel like it's almost too much work
for too little return with it
um the horse idea was decent
the other idea we could try is maybe
just setting up uh
one wide paths above the course fruit
farm that we can walk on and hopefully
reach some of the seeds and
break them before we harvest it
i don't know let's go try out the seed
farm see if it's got some potential or
not
all right so
if we look at these how did they do this
one has two
one two
one oh no that's a two one one
two one it seems like maybe one and a
half
profits roughly
so it's not perfect see what i wanted to
do is just to be able to run down a
single
line here and get all the seeds but we
would have to do that like four times
now
because you'd run down like this
we got eight from that then you'd run
down the middle
the middle you get a few more
all right and then you'd run down this
side
it's a little bit of work see now the
problem is getting the ones in the
middle
uh one thing we could do is just like do
this
and hope we get them be like a 50 50
chance
um or we could very meticulously try to
get them and make sure we do it
afterwards uh the best thing to do would
probably be have
water break the remaining stems that way
we don't have to waste time with it
and also uh waste acts durability too
that's another thing
with all the the braking you do it
actually wears up the axe pretty quick
all right
so yeah
that would have netted us maybe 20 seeds
bonus
15 to 20 from that amount to work i
don't know if it's really worth it or
not
um the other thing we could do
is just like have something above the
farm
and hope it grows around it maybe
like if you had something going like
this
all the way across you could probably
reach a lot of the seeds
oh maybe not like you could get all
these easy
i don't know i'm still thinking about
this i'm not sure i've
i've hit the right solution solution
just yet
well anyways guys i think we'll have to
try to finish this up next episode
we got a little bit left to do on it we
got to do like the
the water release and water stream stuff
auto collection
we gotta do the auto smelter room or
whatever
and just a lot of polish in this area
would be nice
my current thinking is to not do the
seed farm unless you guys have an idea
of how to make it better
let me know in the comments if you do
but instead we'll
have to try to figure out some way of
harvesting those on on the top there
because this is a lot faster to grab
those and to to plant those
get a few extra not too many extra and
then
break them replant them it's it's a lot
of work really
for not much profits all rights
uh i had an idea too since this is so
close to this uh blacksmith house we
built remember we were trying to figure
out what to put in the basement here
now i'm thinking this is where we're
gonna set up our
our chorus fruit smelter so we'll
get them to arrive over here and then
we'll have a bunch of furnaces down here
and some storage
for the purper blocks maybe could be
pretty cool
all right well let's get to the comment
of the day it says
how did he have full diamond armor but
not full
armor bar like the chess pieces down
here
so a lot of people are wondering in this
last episode i was wearing full diamond
armor but my
armor display looked like i was wearing
a lot less that's because in 1.9 they
were playing around with armor
degradation which is like we had in
back in the alpha days remember when
your armor took durability
then it would protect you less and less
and and you had to
like re-equip new armor just to get your
armor
protection back like leather armor you
would last two
three hits and then you'd have to
replace it type of thing
but in the latest snapshots it sounds
like they got rid of that thankfully
because nobody nobody really liked that
in the past as far as i know
so yeah just the temporary thing that
they're they're probably not gonna do
all right well i hope you guys enjoyed
the episode hope you have a good day
and i'll see you in the next one take
care
bye bye
you