I don't even know what's going on
it's just that awesome I'm in survival
mode and I am flying how am i doing it I
don't know um very slowly descending
towards the ground it seems ground
hasn't loaded yet my character was light
and now he's turned dark oh there's the
ground hmm which is going on I wonder it
doesn't look like it's loading properly
I don't even know but it's awesome
that's all that matters let's go over
this way doo doo doo doo doo doo since
it's the only loaded land hmm
kind of wondering what's gonna happen
when I hit the ground I think that I'm
either going to die because I've been
falling forever or oh okay well that's
what happened good to know oh we got
some golems over there freaky not too
hmm
things get weirder and weirder anyways
guys this is etho and here we are in my
let's play world today what I really
want to do is actually this doesn't look
quite right either does it like we're
the trees the mountains
oh is that Wilson what is that it's
getting louder
oh-oh-oh-oh
it's all just a nightmare oh that was
bad dream
I gotta stop sleeping outside oh man you
guys would not believe the dream I just
had I was like well it started out good
I was flying but then like spaz was
trying to run me down in his vehicle and
trying to kill me uh anyways always good
actually we should sleep though well I'm
a little scared too now I'm not worried
about these guys it's it's the dreams
whoo ah that'll put me in a good mood
yes anyways welcome guys we are while
we're here how else do you continue that
for today I think I want to work on this
area some more I really like this
actually and I've gotten used to it
really quick I want to try put the water
down there too
maybe we'll just grab my shrubs soil I
guess let's go on up I was really
looking around my teef systems and stuff
to see how I want to continue this
project and
it looks like there's a lot of potential
for branching off to other paths and
stuff I didn't realize before like like
for example even down here if we dug
straight this way and then made it go
right it goes right to a cave here which
which is pretty good and it just keeps
going around and around I think that
would be a nice place to expand to the
first yeah let's do the water let's do
the water okay so I think what I want to
do here is have or I want to try make
the water go in one block underneath all
the logs and that might make it look a
little better I'm also considering
whether or not we should leave some
grass here like a little a little bit or
if it just should just get rid of it all
oh there's a cave down there and I'm
trying to be careful not to flood
anything to when I do this we'll try it
with that first
I brought some ice with me I'm going to
make it all still water too
I think and we need a few more on there
and over here too
kind of a weird shape okay let's go see
what that looks like
mm now we should get rid of all the
grass yeah otherwise it looks a little
strange I hope this doesn't leak down
somewhere that would really suck we will
leave a foundation no for the face so
I'm not going to make it indented there
I should probably choose a solid block
type of some sort maybe we'll just
cobble their doodoo so I was working on
Wilson a little bit as well and we have
a slight weird problem with hoppers it
seems I don't think I'm doing it wrong I
think there's actually some some weird
quirk with them all right that's cool I
like that so excuse me how kind of
wanted to try to do a whirlpool thing
too but we'll we'll go to Wilson for
right now also we have stairs here I
want to put more stairs here and I found
them in the first chest I checked it I
went to the chance it's three four five
let's actually make the stairs start
going down here I want this to be a big
open room and I think we'll keep the
same theme in this Wilson room as we
have over here with the grass and all
the wood and stuff might put some trees
in this room and maybe one more block
okay so the problem we're having with
Wilson is with his food detection system
with the minecart setup we had before
that stopped working for whatever reason
hoppers started putting two items in the
minecart instead of just one which was
making it work one time then not work
then worked the next time then not work
so I came up with this instead now and
this seems like it would be a
good idea like it should work if if like
we can have we're using this as an item
detector right so it will go down to 22
items and stop and every time a new item
goes in there it will trigger the
redstone and we can take that redstone
signal and make it do something um and
it seems to work very reliably too not
much to it we can put two together like
this and and this one works and it
stopped but how here is the problem for
some reason when I build it over here it
doesn't work and I can't figure out for
the life of me why that is like this one
works this one works
but these edge ones it's like this
hoppers being powered down here even
though it's not so items are not passing
into it because it they're showing b22
items in this top hopper and it's built
exactly the same all right
and even if you like destroy all this
it's like it doesn't follow normal
normal hopper logic for some reason if
we get rid of all this stuff you know
the item should be going down into this
bottom hopper but they're not and I do
not understand why like if we if we
build the exact same thing somewhere
else not a problem
and the only thing I didn't think of is
maybe somehow I put a lever at the
bottom of this thing and I'm going to
check it now but I highly doubt I would
forget that
well I'm strapping this recording I must
have put those there for the power rails
ah now that was that was all a setup
guys that was totally fake I knew those
were there I didn't actually waste like
half an hour trying to figure this out
or anything okay well that's good news
this this is all set up now and much
smaller than the minecart setup which is
awesome and also more reliable so
win-win I'm glad it works even even
though so we can try this out from up
let's just look from this view so you
can see to hoppers there that one's for
the stake this one is for cookies then
we have two back here this one's for
Medicine the golden apples and then this
one is for junk items anything that
doesn't go another three and we will put
cookie there for right now you can try
this out we throw a cookie in to feed
Wilson this should flash I might have
missed it already yeah we missed it
happens really fast there we go
staked I don't think we can see it click
enough yeah anyway you get the idea
Apple we can see the Apple pretty easy
Apple goes to this one so then we put
redstone up to that and we can put like
a pulsar up to the other variables like
for food we'll just add to the food then
and so on and so forth ah Wilson
you give me so much trouble you wouldn't
believe it okay so we got our stairs
here this would be good and just put
some
some logs next to that before we forget
and then we'll probably do the fences on
top of them ah oh yeah by the way guys
in one of my recent videos I'm not going
to say which one I just so these people
don't want to know but there was a point
where I was burning in the nether and
everybody like my first reaction was to
get my water bucket but obviously or at
least I thought it was obvious to me
anyway that you can't use a water bucket
in the nether to put yourself out but
lots of other people disagree and I'm
not saying they're wrong they are wrong
in vanilla and I'm going to prove that
to you right now I tried it on minecraft
server tube just because I was shocked
by the reaction of people I want to
clear up the myth like before it spreads
let's see I need a flint and steel that
doesn't belong there mmm temperatures
none of my tool chest steel I'm going to
intentionally light myself on fire and
then try put myself out in the nether
just to prove that you can't because oh
man so the reason I could see it
potentially being true is maybe like we
were playing on a budget server in this
video and maybe budget servers have
different rules or something
that was weird but yeah in vanilla no no
can i light this no good find some
ground to to to do to do and some people
are saying it's a chance saying it it's
not a chance thing can't be done
rounds on fire I'm on fire you can't put
yourself out if you're on fire in the
nether the water cannot be placed and if
you think otherwise because of something
else it was just a coincidence and
that's all I'm saying on it okay anyways
back on to our creeper face guy so the
water I made two blocks steep now it's a
little bit more polished up dirt at the
bottom and cobblestone all the way
around even though you can't really see
it and there's one more thing I want to
do with him I always thought it would be
cool if he shot fireballs from his eyes
like randomly every now and then so I
would like to try and make that happen
ah if we go actually let's just rip
something I think to make it shoot from
his eyes we would have to put a
dispenser like right there and one there
and then hook up some some wiring to
that and it should work out okay we
would have to change the shape of this a
little bit so let's go upstairs
try to see if we have our stuff around
dispensers are one of those items I'm
never sure if I have because I hate
making them so usually I I don't make
them in bulk and it's not looking good
we got six cool okay we only need two we
have a redstone I have a lot of
gunpowder now so I don't mind wasting on
stuff like this um
is powder and use charcoal if you can
let's try that out I you can yeah any a
lots because you get three three per
let's see we'll need some sandstone
really much have to make do with that
okay oh and you know what else I should
grab is a fire resistant because how you
will probably die otherwise let's go
visit our lab oops and orange for fire
resist and drop that
how are things going guys mmm-hmm keep
each other in line the future of our
company depends on you I this should be
pretty easy actually go ahead and drink
this already let's see where are the
eyes they're right here so we I want to
put in the bottom left corner so that
would be this thing right there
hopefully it's not too hard to hide this
I could almost see there for a second
okay where's that oh yeah it is it is
where I thought it was okay
we lost the stare with other one right
there and we got to dig above that for
redstone
over here we'll have to hide some I
can't see should check the time on these
potions it might only be three minutes
oh no it's the minute one okay and then
we'll have to try make this work if we
remove these stairs up darn we lost them
like this then we could have half slabs
below I think that would look pretty
good still yeah there we go
that's not too bad we have a little less
space to throw our ender pearl but I'm
not overly worried about it I have lots
of practice by now I don't think I'll
hit the half slab cool off okay so the
hill shoot fireballs out his eyes and
they'll hit the wall there I think as
long as it doesn't have any ground like
like anything if there's if it if the
fireball hits here it'll catch the dirt
on fire but if it has nothing below its
I don't have to worry about fire and
then it's spreading up to my bridge
there or anything so I think we'll be
okay and I just cut a hole through here
where we can do the wiring this makes it
a lot easier to see compared to trying
to do it in the in the lava and the way
I want to do this let's let's set up a
5-minute dispenser clock but I also want
some randomization in it so
not always going off every five minutes
or something and the way we're gonna do
that let's see oh you know what we'll do
put a repeater here that'll go up to
there and then m-maybe we'll go in this
way
wonder what's over here I got lots of
stuff underground I'm always worried I'm
gonna hit it when I'm doing something
today we'll do a comparator and we need
that to run two blocks what I'm making
is a really cool randomizer I've seen on
a few people's channels the way it works
you have a hopper dropper combo with the
dropper below and the hopper above and
when you send it an item you just give
it you give it items that do stack like
in in 64 is like we could do one dirt
one cobble one stone and then if we give
it an item that doesn't stack like a
sword or something then these ones will
only make the comparator travel one
block actually we can try that out while
the the hole will make it go two blocks
because it counts as a full stack of
items that time oh that time it went
that time it was the the hoe and the
item like right away goes back down OOP
getting pretty lucky here actually
I'm going to go check out there because
I'm a little worried about fire I'm not
going to lie
we're okay whoo yeah so we'll have that
and then we'll hook up a five-minute
clock to that just like this so this is
a five minute dispenser clock these are
very common and well known but the way
they work is they shoot an item onto
this wooden pressure plates and it takes
that item five minutes to de-spawn and
when it does it makes this torch turn
back on and sends out another item so it
keeps going around and around in a loop
and with this number of items it takes
48 hours and to run out so it's going to
run for a long time on its own but then
this goes to another torch next to this
dropper we have to use a torch we can't
just use redstone that's because if the
droppers stays powered then this hopper
won't be able to put items into it so
that's why are you using a torch and
we're going to use three items total so
on average it's going to trigger every
15 minutes but sometimes it might do two
in a row sometimes it might not go for
thirty minutes so it'll be kind of nice
and random you know something I like
things that are unexpected that just
happened on their own so with that said
why should I should get this going right
don't want to forget that so jumpstart
it like that oh and we got lucky there
okay and I also hooked up a wire out
here just so we can see what it does
instead of waiting forever for it to
happen by chance and it doesn't work why
is it too far it is too far mmm okay you
can fix that are my repeaters okay here
we go whoa that's cool I like it it
seems to hit the same spot pretty much
consistently we will do a little bit of
terraforming here I don't like how this
is looking
let's go let's go up try hide the dirt
give it some more shape and structure
awesome so that's another fun silly
project yeah
okay well I guess we're done with that I
can lock this up my portal doesn't work
anymore this thing so I'm gonna have to
go through this wiring again and fix
that
there it goes again
we will cover this back up and we'll
probably have a create an axis way to
get back there eventually one day cool
so yeah I was talking earlier about app
apps I wanted to put here the stress try
try that out this wall really needs to
be fixed up because you got like ugly
gravel and pumpkins showing and it's
been this way for a long long time
so eventually sometime very soon we're
going to fix this this will go through
maybe go over another block
yeah we'll get rid of the ground we just
dig straight here to go to that G right
yeah okay and see what I would ideally
like to do just a sec let's clear this
out I would like this to eventually I
showed you it spiraled around downward
here but there's also another place I
would like it to go to the path over
here this is by our slime pond which
just sort of dead ends so we could make
it go underneath and connect to here too
which would be pretty good so I'm going
to work on that maybe and I'll be right
back
what you doing there guy set your hole
doesn't look very comfortable all right
guys I got that path laid out here and
I'm pretty happy with it so I want like
this Cape feel I might build this up
even more like have have the overhang
come out sort of diagonally here I guess
but I'll build on that later and it goes
through here goes down some stairs this
this little pad will branch off down to
there maybe go this direction too or we
can go straight through here and go
around our slime farm this was just a
dead end like I said so it's good we
found a way to make it go somewhere I
want to do something with the spider
fun's over this direction
we'll probably make the path come here
do like I think one of those spider
farms is right above here somewhere
other than that fixed up the side of the
cliff a little bit there oh it works ah
grass is still spreading I'll probably
make some tweaks to it and I sort of
polish it up around the bridge areas
because it was looking like a little
little choppy could see pumpkins and
stuff and yeah I'll probably tweak this
some more as well but it's it's looking
a lot better I think so yeah this this
is a shortcut here you can go right
through this is instead of going just
like this add another path you can take
and step one the roundabout way up here
then you'd have to the left down stairs
and it takes you back to the spot ah so
pretty happy with this I have picked out
two comments for today guys this is
going to be the end of our episode first
one a etho just food for thought I
remember you saying a while back that
you had so many creative worlds and it
was hard for you to find in past
projects that is true would you ever
think about building a creative world
specifically for testing stuff out maybe
make an ethos lab where you can keep all
your projects labeled etc and you can
put it up for download and we can see
all your projects that is a pretty good
idea that's that's sort of like what
sethbling does he has one main creative
world where he builds all his stuff and
then he just moves over whenever he
needs more space uh I've considered
doing that but I'm not that organized I
would never label anything in that or
build in a specific spot and quite often
I tend to blow up my creative worlds and
so
yeah I don't think it's gonna happen I'm
just I'm too derpy and I don't
necessarily want everyone to see my
creative builds because sometimes I
build something I don't show it for two
three months and I'll bring it out in an
episode and explain it properly then but
if you were to stumble on it in the
creative world you know like like the
bomb factory is an example that I've had
that built for six months that idea and
I'm just finally now starting to develop
it anyway next question or a next thing
dude you're awesome
I'm subscribing does that put that one
out thanks guy enjoy your stay uh yeah
alright that's it for today I've got
some bonus footage for you guys this is
the alternate dream sequence I had to
try record that several times because it
was a very difficult thing to record any
time I do anything with creepers where I
move far away from them they have this
habit of the spawning so I have to do
several takes until I get lucky and it
works so yeah here's the alternate dream
sequence thanks for watching guys spaz
man seriously
guy things don't have to be this way
between us we can work this out
all those things I said about your
mother I take them back fast come on man
I'm getting a cramp spaz I can't run
anymore it's best don't do it
No
oh I gotta record this using that oh you
flew next to the other thing every
wonderful you're fine
Oh fi there we go I'm gonna die I'm
gonna be here that is so good