hello all my wonderful viewers how are
you doing today we're going to start out
on a high note let's check it out we're
at level 50 level 50 all the way oh yeah
spider things working very well very
very well
got lots of wool to from it like mmm
probably close to 20 stacks now and
we're going to enchant a diamond pickaxe
to start out with I'm gonna do 47
because it's really hard to find a level
50 in this thing takes lots and lots of
time to find one so 47 is good for me
here we go I'm hoping for silk touch
will we get it will we get it I'm scared
to look efficiency for
that is a really good skill but I was
hoping for at least more than one skill
oh well I think when I do these
enchantments I'll probably only go to
about level 35 or so probably I don't
know it's tucked in to level 50 slows
down a lot as you get to as you at the
higher levels
all right well efficiency for that's not
terrible let's actually want to try it
out
I know it's insanely quick now if I had
unbreaking on here - that would have
been ideal let's go over here get our
sound up very nice I like it okay on
with the show so I thought I'd show you
guys my sand quarry here if you ever
wonder where I get my sand glass
sandstone from it's from here this
looked really weird naturally there was
grass and then a big wall of sand all
along here so I just started hacking
away at it and now I come here quite
often for sand and what I do this is
simple way everybody knows how to get
sand put torches down below when you're
mind it yeah you know the drill don't
have a whole lot of TNT at the moment so
I can't go
TNT mining for sand so this is the next
best thing and then when I when I'm done
here I just put down a bucket of water
to get my torches back and that's all
there is to it it's very nice very
enjoyable
oh I found a very nice gesture very nice
too blue shiny rocks two gold five iron
some pumpkins score alright everybody so
I've decided what I want to do for
today's episode and it's going to be a
lot different than what I usually do
we're going to do a lot of talking today
where I'm going to do a lot of talking
about about you guys about YouTube about
my youtube channel about Minecraft stuff
I usually don't talk about usually it's
all about the game about playing the
game but yeah it's going to be different
and while talking I want to try build at
something for everybody that's donated
to my channel it's going to be a giant
giant giant tree farm here and everybody
that's donated is going to hit a tree
and I'll give everybody a sign saying
how much they donated when they donated
and their first name and the nish first
letter of their last name I think it's
the way I'm going to do it that's the
way gu did it in for his donators and I
thought it was pretty nice so I'm going
to try it too but sorry you're not
getting diamond blocks you're not in
gold blocks or iron blocks or anything
like that and I would do that it's just
I would have to do a whole lot of mining
and I feel it would take away time that
I should be spend making LP episodes so
instead you're getting trees and in that
way you are helping me out because I
will be able to harvest your wood so
you're actually helping me in that way a
little strange yes okay so um we should
get started here so why the weird
episode today well today or tomorrow is
going to be my one year anniversary of
doing minecraft videos
like one year of my channel basically
and for those of you that don't know how
I got started doing this I played
minecraft for about two or three weeks
and I started to get a little bit bored
of it this is like a year ago and there
were a few items in the game I told
myself I'm not going to use until I
start getting bored of the game one of
them was fire one was my cards one was
redstone and I think there was a few
others so basically I limited myself I'm
not allowed to use these items unless
I'm starting to get bored of the game I
was saving them sort of like yeah so
anyway in my world I was having a
problem with my boats always getting
away from me and it got to the point
where I would have like 20 boats in my
ocean just floating around because they
always would just float away whenever I
would dock at my at my dock so I had the
idea that I wanted to make a boat
holding system so I could kind of park
my boats and they would be dispensed
when I wanted them right so I looked on
youtube high and low for I searched for
like two hours literally two hours for a
tutorial on how I could build something
like that and I could not find anything
so I started messing around with it
myself I finally used redstone for the
first time I used minecarts for the
first time and stuff like that and I
built myself a boat dispenser and that
was my very first video okay and I I
thought it was pretty cool so I posted
on the forums just to see if anyone else
had a similar idea and apparently it was
a very unique idea people really liked
it the thread I posted just exploded it
got
curds of responses I think was on the
front page and then I got a few hundred
subscribers from that on my youtube
channel I made the YouTube channel a
long time ago just blur of the moment
type thing I didn't really put any
thought into the name or anything like
that so yeah that shocked me and I
thought well what happened later is I
asked for people's ideas on how they
could improve it and I spent it like a
week or two
building the boat dispenser version two
that got a great response and so I just
kept making more and more videos like
that and I tip today more and more
subscribers I was enjoying it it was fun
and so I just continued but mm-hmm
yes I think I'm going to build this out
of sandstone maybe we'll start over here
at around the time I had four to five
hundred subscribers I started this to
decide that I wanted to make an LP
series for Minecraft and there's there's
a few reasons why I decided to do this
the main one is because I thought it
would be fun and that I'd enjoy it and
that's still the case today that's the
main reason why I'm still making LP
videos they are really fun I enjoy them
I love getting in the comments and
everything from you guys just it just
keeps me going
the other main reason is because I was
watching there's two people in
particular that made me decide I want to
do an LP and that the first one was at a
guy called a youtuber called Ezra bleed
I was watching his ROM is a mario rom
hack videos at the time and they're
absolutely hilarious I'll link them in
the description if I remember or at
least my favorite ones
and I know it just seemed like he was
having a blast doing it I want to try it
myself
the other main influence was co-star
that's right he he had like the one
minecraft LP I really enjoyed watching
at the time I didn't really know about
seananners or X those are the two main
starter ones that people watched I
didn't know about them at the time but
even after watching them I still prefer
co-star over them just my personal
opinion but yeah I was really enjoying
co-stars minecraft LP and I saw it it
was successful and I should try it
myself so that was the other those are
the two main guys that influenced me now
there's other reasons too I wanted to do
it one of them I'm not I'm not very good
at speaking period like I have a hard
time getting my thoughts into words and
even when I do my LP now I have to think
about what I'm going to say before I
start recording otherwise it I just I
can't find my words and I was hoping by
doing an LP that I would get better that
in real life and in minecraft of course
and it's helped me a little bit I feel
but I still struggle um see I got to
take a break again because I gotta think
about what I want to say if you've ever
done commentary before it's very
difficult to do something in the game
and talk about something at the same
time that's why I'm doing like very
simple stuff today in Minecraft because
I can't build something complicated and
talked at the same time so that's this
is a perfect project for today
yeah actually it just occurred to me I
should probably just do voiceover
commentary for this episode because I'll
be able to think about what I'm saying a
little bit more clear and the video will
be more interesting because I'll be able
to speed it up and yeah it'll just be
better but it's funny how the brain
works like if I was to compare talking
about something else
and building in Minecraft it's like have
you ever tried having a conversation
with someone like talking to someone on
the phone and then reading something at
the same time have you ever tried to do
both well it's like the brain just can't
do it it conflicts those two activities
conflict with each other and that's how
I compare building and talking at the
same time in Minecraft it's like that
even though the brain is able to
multitask pretty well there's certain
tasks it just can't do together it's
strange how it works and I watch quite a
few LPS it's pretty funny actually
because most people don't build and talk
at the same time and if they try to it's
like they'll get all quiet all of a
sudden so I don't think it's just me I
think it's something in general people
have trouble with but yeah anyway I kind
of talked about why I wanted to start my
LP already maybe I should also talk
about how I went about starting my LP
because this is something people asked
me about everyday on YouTube through
private messages in that so I'll tell
you how I did it like I said before
already I I didn't just start with an LP
right away I released videos first that
I thought people would really like and I
posted links to these on the minecraft
forums and lucky for me people actually
did like them and they came over to my
channel they subscribed and before I
started my LP I had like 4 or 500
subscribers so I had somewhat of an
interest already in my channel
and I just kind of went for it and I was
prepared for it to not be successful I I
wasn't expecting it to be successful and
to my surprise and to my joy it kind of
kind of was successful because we're at
63 thousand subscribers more than that
now so that's just that's just great I'm
still surprised
now before I started recording and
uploading let's play minecraft episode 1
there's some important things I did as
well one day I went on YouTube and I
just did a search for all all types of
Minecraft LPS I watched them from all
these different people and what I was
trying to do is take like try to figure
out all the things I really liked about
the LPS and all those things I didn't
like about them and my goal was to take
all the things I liked about the
different LPS I watched and put them
into my LP and tried to avoid all the
things I didn't like about them and not
put those in my LP so for for example
just one simple example here all the LPS
I watched that day they started their
episode one started with them explaining
how the game works like how you can
break blocks place blocks how you can
craft things and that seems like it
wasn't really needed to me because
that's what seananners did when he
started his LP and I think people were
just copying that because he had the
most or one of the most successful LPS
to date but the thing is if anyone does
a search on YouTube for Minecraft LP
they're going to get they were at that
time anyway they were going to get
seananners or somebody else that started
first their LP is going to show up to
not theirs so the only ones that would
really be watching my LP our people that
knew how to play the game already is
what I figured so there's no point
explaining all the simple game mechanics
that that wasn't really my intention and
really at that time I noticed that
nobody really had a minecraft LP that
was targeted towards people that were
already playing the game they all seemed
to target new players and I feel that
was the main key to helping my minecraft
LP get started in my minecraft channel
to get started because I targeted a
different audience another thing I
noticed that I felt was really important
was that nobody really had a technical
approach to their LP they were just
building basic structures or exploring
or mining whatever the simple basic
aspects of Minecraft
the things that make Minecraft great but
there's there's more to the game than
that and so also even like tutorial
videos at that time there were basically
only two types there were ones that
taught people about redstone or there
were ones that taught them about
minecarts nobody really was looking into
boat mechanics or I don't think farming
videos were too important or too common
at that time so I realized that if I was
to take a more technical approach to my
LP that it would help it to stand out
more so with people it would kind of
target a different audience as well and
it just so happens
lucky me at that time that's the way I
was playing the game because I had
basically gotten bored of playing
minecraft the traditional way if it
wasn't for redstone and mine cards and
all that stuff I probably would have
lost interest in the game a long time
ago they kept me going so that brings me
to my point here if you want your LP to
be successful you kind of gotta you got
to figure out what would be different
how can you do it different from other
people you should try to develop your
own style of doing your LP don't simply
copy
someone else on YouTube that successful
don't copy their jokes and their traits
and all that because they were there
first they have the audience already and
you want people to see you as different
so that you can attract a different
audience and you don't want to be in
competition with someone either on
YouTube so for example one type of LP I
would like to personally see on YouTube
that isn't really really common or done
well usually is I would like to see a
group of people playing SP in a vanilla
setting and just building projects
together with a clear clear approach to
it oh I'm going to use uber hacks or
Nova as an example here
he has his a Tree Hill series which is
pretty I just started watching that
recently it's pretty good he's hanging
out with friends
building together and they're joking and
razzing each other and that kind of
thing it's fun to watch now that's kind
of what I have in mind but I would
recommend you do more editing and have a
clear clear clear objectives in mind
like for building and I think that would
make it even better like I don't know
exactly what I want but I just the way I
would describe it you know those
time-lapse videos people do of group
projects on servers that's what I would
like to see except not a time lapse I'd
like to see the interaction between the
people building the project and I would
like it to be done in vanilla instead of
in creative mode I think that would be
pretty entertaining especially if you
have interesting people doing it that
are funny and you know what I mean
I think someone that makes videos like
that would be pretty successful on
YouTube because it's it's hard to pull
off well that type of thing but if you
can great I think you'll get a lot of
attention but anyway moving on something
else important too you should do before
uploading videos make sure you can get
your sound and your video settings
correct read up on it go to Google
read up how to do it how to get rid of
letterboxing all that stuff but frame
rate you should record at make sure you
have a computer latency cord at least 30
frames per second if you don't I would
recommend you don't even bother sadly to
make videos until you can get better
better equipment that is if you're
aiming to be exist a successful youtuber
if you're just doing it for fun go for
it to do what you want to do as long as
you're having fun that's what's
important right but yeah try to upload a
30 second video to YouTube see how it
turns out make sure the video and sound
is okay as well compare your sound
quality or your sound levels with other
YouTube channels make sure they're
pretty close you don't want it super
loud super quiet I would recommend that
you try your very best for your first
episode don't get to practice
commentating first get a feel for it
until you're comfortable and then then
record it and up upload it for real
because here's the thing your first
episode is going to get a lot of
attention if you are successful if you
look at my first episode for minecraft
it has it's over a hundred thousand
views and hits over 150,000 views
compared to use my 63,000 subscribers or
so so maybe if I get better like it's
not a dream ethicist maybe might did
better I having 63 thousands of dollars
maybe I would have 150 we don't know
they would probably have a better impact
because that's what people will probably
see first that's how it'll judge you
your channel so try to do well and of
course hopefully you will improve you
later you'll learn tricks but yeah
people judge you a lot on your first
episode so try try your hardest here but
anyway the most important thing of all
is that you are having fun playing
minecraft make sure make sure you enjoy
it a lot of people make the mistake of
starting a YouTube
channel with the goal of becoming a
partner and making money now that's one
of the perks but you definitely don't
want that to be your focus because the
quality of your videos is going to
suffer people will be able to tell
you're not really enjoying yourself so
yeah make sure you enjoy the game or you
know choose a game you do enjoy and make
videos for that sometimes people ask me
that question
you know am I getting bored of the game
and playing it for over a year and
making videos for a year I still love it
it's a great game I don't know I think
once once your imagination fails you
that's when you start getting rid of it
because you you kind of make the game
your own and as long as you're creative
with it I don't think you would ever get
bored you know there's always mods out
there if you want to play mods it's not
that difficult to make your own mods
even so I think I'll be playing
minecraft for a long time and I want to
thank all my all my viewers all my
subscribers thanks for watching my
videos thanks for leaving your comments
your likes really appreciate it makes it
fun for me and I do still read all the
comments pretty much it's just some of
the older videos I might not see for a
while but even those I checked every so
often and yeah video responses I haven't
been so good at though I admit I haven't
been improving too many of those lately
just because they they take a long time
to get through but I'm still trying
private messages I respond to
oh maybe 10 to 20 percent of them again
it's a time issue I would like to
respond to everybody but I just get so
many and I love it though keep them
coming just please don't be hurt if I
don't respond it's not because I don't
like you right ignoring you or anything
that's just there's only so much I can
do unfortunately but yeah um
now it's your turn I've been talking for
so long I want to hear from you I want
your feedback
how do you feel about my videos lately
do you find they're getting better worse
what do you think I want to improve
wherever I can if possible so let me
know what you think I know one thing a
lot of people have requested is that I
did a Twitter account so I can post when
I'm uploading videos and stuff I looked
into that a long time ago when someone
had taken the name ethos lab so I
haven't really looked into it since but
I probably will get one soon so I look
forward to that
another thing that worries me is that
maybe people aren't feeling as close to
the connection with me as it they did
when I was a smaller channel maybe so
I'm going to try to bring that
connection back if I can I've actually
created a twitch TV account which is
like online streaming so hopefully I can
get into that sometime soon and I'll be
able to communicate directly with you
guys while I'm playing Minecraft
I still haven't set up my twitch TV
account but if I if I get it going and I
get through all the technical issues
because it's pretty complicated and I'm
a little worried I won't be able to my
internet won't keep up but if it all
works out well I'll probably
occasionally do a Minecraft streaming
and you guys can check it out my account
is etho TV so ETH o TV ethos lab was
taken for some reason and yeah I'll be
able to play at a more casual level and
interact with you guys so maybe I would
do Skyblock there because I probably
won't yeah it definitely won't be doing
on my YouTube so could be cool
and of course I want to give a big thank
you to everybody who has donated to my
channel it's very much appreciated thank
you everyone this is kind of my way of
trying to thank you today this tree farm
here I may do the RGB machine still but
at the moment I don't have the resources
to do it so at the very least I wanted
to get your names and your donations on
a sign or something somewhere
I wanted it written down somewhere where
it could be seen so that's why I did
this today so I hope you hope you liked
it and I didn't quite finish it today
unfortunately it's like 2 a.m. here and
I wanted to get this video today if I
could but I gotta edit it yet and I'm
really really tired right now so I'll
have to try finish this up some other
day but this is the format I'm trying to
do it money your name last last name
initial because I don't want to give out
your personal information if you have a
youtube name or if you want me to use
any other name I'll put it on the third
line and then the date that I received
the donation and big thank you this guy
here because he has donated a lot to the
channel very much appreciated this guy's
awesome you all are awesome really I
want to let's just go through the ones
I've done so far I kinda I wanted to
finish this so badly today but it's just
so late here I can't and hey thanks for
trying to ruin the party here Oh we'll
go through it
maybe next LP when I get more done no no
no
son of a creeper you can blow up the
sign or the little stone it's fine it's
okay all right
anyway I'm going to edit you end it here
today I think I okay
didn't forget anything I hope I will see
you guys again next time
and we'll return return to our normal
format for the show next time hopefully
so just wanted to change it up a little
bit today because it's the one-year
anniversary and I hope I didn't bore you
to tears or anything okay
so I'll see you guys again next time