hello
everybody welcome back once again
this is ito as always thank you for
joining me
i got one thing to show you in this man
cave
to start off with uh we
have a new arch this one here woohoo
can't get enough arches can i uh that's
probably gonna be the last one i'm not
gonna put any in here or anything
but i i do think it looks good i like it
um so we will still have a waterfall or
something
just a small stream over here somehow
which will go down and i would still
like to have a portal room
down there or something too
uh but yeah i like this new addition
goes well with this parts and this part
i've also messed with this door a little
bit
it's not it's not perfect
because this was like here long before
any of this stuff
so it doesn't match quite right if i
was to do it again i would put it in one
more block or so
but oh well we'll have to live with it
gives it character i might change this
wooden planks with something else yet
though
this is where i keep my potion stuff by
the way
for for all you new guys goes in these
dispensers
and when you push the buttons in the
potion rooms
it shoots out and flows to the middle
and falls down
there's also a second layer
this is where the glass bottles are and
also the
gunpowder
cool anyway what i really feel like
doing today at least for a little while
is to go exploring so that's what we're
going to do
i haven't really gone exploring since
1.3 came out there's a lot of stuff i
still want to find so
i have prepared got a whole bunch of
speed potions and pearls ready so
it's gonna get suited up and we will
take off on our adventure
all right guys i think we are ready to
go i'm all
all set here uh one of the things we're
going to be looking for
is the rest of our villagers to finish
project pokemon
uh we won't be able to get this guy he's
not actually in the game
that's the green suited villager
but we can get these to the blacksmith
and the priest we need
so hopefully we'll find a village today
and finish that up
or at least have the prospect of
finishing it i don't know if i'd want to
transport them today uh oh wait
let's go this way
i am excited i think it's been like 50
episodes or something before we last
or since we last went exploring so it's
been a long long time
and i haven't explored off camera or
anything either the last time i went
exploring was with you guys
so i think we've been that way
and i know we've been that way a long
ways
so either should go that way what is
that
f where's the f
oh zero or two
uh let's maybe go let's go this way
there might be an ocean this way if i
remember right
but if not i am excited to see that
actually looks like planes
further ahead
that's not annoying oh yeah the f5
camera does not work well in reads
just uh just the fyi for you
i learned that while building my farms
am i going the right way i wonder how
long it's going to take the world
to load i think um
this is what exploring is like in 1.3
yes
just open world we can look at the caves
and the overworld at the same time
amazing okay so it's plains here
sweet desert
oh you know what
maybe this is the direction it's this
way i don't think i've been
oops
um i also get lost quite often that
or at least that's that's the rumor uh
you think i'd know my world a bit better
than that but i don't
yeah i think it's this way possibly
if i could see the world i could tell
you
well no those are the mountains you know
what let's do it we're going
this way ah i already used up one potion
just trying to figure out which
direction to go
yeah let's go this way i know i haven't
been this way very far
for sure just uh
the only reason i went this way was to
do the glowing trees
let's go check it out so yeah
this episode's a bit delayed i'm sorry
about that uh
stuff comes up as usual this is actually
one of the busiest weeks i've had for
recording in groups
i had three big recording days with
people
i did the vinyl fantasy recording ooj
with uh
uh goud and bw on monday
and so that took up that evening and
then also
uh just a couple days ago i did a big
recording session with the seth bling
captain sparkles and ant venom we were
doing the tnt olympics thing
and that when i first heard of that like
seth told me about that a long time ago
oh awesome and i
did not think it was going to be very
challenging because i figured you just
figure out the trick and then you'd be
able to do it every single time
no the games are actually they require a
lot of skill and it
it's very tough to do
okay sweet i
hmm grabbing stuff is going to be tough
i'm going to have to remember this i'll
come back to it later it's not that far
but yeah that was a lot of fun that took
up
a big part of the day
and video that should be coming out soon
i don't know exactly when
then uh on
friday we also recorded uhc
season eights and that was
so much fun oh i've missed uhc so much
the last time i did it because i missed
last season i was working when they
recorded it
so the last time i actually played uhc
with the guys was
at the end of april so may
june july august you know that's
over a quarter year since i last played
uhc and i have missed it so much
it's one of my favorite games to play in
minecraft like competitive games
race for wolves also one of my favorites
so i was real happy to play that again
with them
and like
that's the thing we can't record it too
much like play it too much because
if we flood videos of us playing that
uh people are gonna get bored of it so
we kind of have to space them out
which which is
which is smart but the thing is if uh if
i had the option to play that every
every week i definitely would uh like if
we
played it without recording even i would
definitely get in on that
just because i liked it so much but yeah
i had a lot of fun with that
and i've been anxious to try out my new
style of playing and i finally was able
to i
i went into it knowing that it could
backfire and i could die early or
something but
uh just wanted to try it out and i will
not tell you how it
turned out i'll let you watch to figure
it out
uh but this is something i had to try
this does not make me happy
why is the wall like that
okay we're gonna go to the slower speed
potions just because i'm
tired of constantly drinking them
that's jungle i've never seen this
jungle it did not
transition too well
this is new jungle yeah totally new we
got cocoa beans
um one thing i've never actually found
in this game
yet is the jungle temples not even in
creative mode
i've just seen like one or two videos of
people
looking at them i don't really know how
they're laid out or anything
so i would be excited to find one of
those
if we could
i do really like jungles the green grass
i love it
we should build something in the jungle
one day
soon but yeah we recorded uhc
also recently so just a whole bunch of
stuff going on plus
real life stuff so yeah a little behind
on videos once again but that means
since i've been doing all this uh
recording in advance
the next few weeks i should have a ton
of videos coming out
to help make up for for missing
snow biome
whoops
so exploring nowadays involves a lot of
waiting
it would load a lot quite quicker if i
wasn't recording
let's look at that enderman
i think he teleported
i wonder if i actually looked at him i
think he teleported when i did
or when i looked away
let's go over here
that'd be so cool if there was like
jungle villages too like
in trees and that oh that would be sweet
because they have the desert specific
ones now
they themed it to other other biomes or
if they did like mountain ones that had
bridges going across
oh it could be pretty cool
nice nice hills here too is this
jungle hills yeah cool stuff
what
that was weird was that a leg is that
leg in single player
um okay i'm going to pause for a second
let things generate a bit quicker
all right that should do let's keep
going here this looks like a really big
jungle
no end in sight yet so something else i
did last saturday i joined
kurt j mack he was holding his flopathon
100 100 percent uh child's play
charity goal stream on twitch.tv so
hung out with them for a little bit that
was fun as well thanks to kurt for
having me on that and congrats
um something else i want to talk about
too
m77 good buddy of mine he
uh he uh has
ended his current world tour he's going
to be starting a new world i think
uh probably in probably soon
but he's he's making that transition
from one world to the next which is a
real freaky thing
like when i did that
oh planes let's go to the planes i did
that a little while ago as well and i
was uh
i was nervous because people become
attached to a world
and i was worried people were going to
leave me once i switched to a new one
but thankfully that all worked out so
i'm sure doc is a little nervous about
changing too because you kind of get
into a groove of
of recording and and uh
just being able to go from one episode
episode to another and if you make it
make a big change it's a huge
huge shock to your rhythm but anyway
uh when he starts his new world make
sure you uh
show him some love leave positive
comments
help support him assuming you are
a doc m fan which i'm sure a lot of you
are
um what else what else i've also been
secretly kind of secretly been working
on a map
nothing big it's not major it's not the
big map idea i had
just a little thing i wanted to do and
i've been recording a series as i've
been making it which i'll
release once it's all done assuming i
finish it so
that's another thing that's been taking
up my time
but i'm having fun with it too
all right i don't think we're gonna get
a village
i think we've seen most of the planes
just so we don't spend the whole episode
exploring i'll probably start
cutting now and show you if we find
anything interesting as i keep going
here
so i will see you in a little bit
whoa what is this
load load
nope
go back into the jungle
big swamp biome
hey just watching me
oh look at that mine shaft that looks so
cool when you can see the whole thing
no come back
just wanna have a look just a little
look
what the
what is this this must be a cave
that's a freaky cave whoa what is this
it's like a straight down hole
that is really cool i have to check this
out
how weird is that
it's like it's not a ravine it's this is
something
maybe it is ravine
very strange for being if it is it's
like a perfect circle
to go down
i'm trying to look around whoa
i'm gonna mark this spot in case we ever
come back
hmm i like stuff like this too when you
just have these random areas with stone
exposed
that's character
oh
yes where are we at we're not that far
away
from spawn
hey hey nice to meet you
nice to meet you
i will control you yes
oh this is awesome we found a village a
second village
door is missing there's a blacksmith too
sweet hey always wanted one of you
um yeah just farmers
excellent okay so when night times comes
i'm going to lock them in their doors
then i can safely keep them alive until
i can
transport some of them i'm not going to
take all of them though i'm not making
that mistake again
i'm going to leave enough here that they
can survive but
i'll definitely have to snag me that's
that blacksmith
and there should be yep there should be
a priest here
ripoff that is awesome
let's check the blacksmith's chest
see what we got
decent-sized village
yeah i'll leave that here for another
day
yeah i don't like the farmer trades that
much
blacksmith and priest are the number the
two best
guys to get
and then librarians if you want to sell
if you want to get emeralds
so the librarians get they get these
fancier houses i guess
27 ouch pretty sick of these things
which i guess other ones go in here too
this isn't your house
oh whoa woah wouldn't be a bad trade
either it's easy to get wool
whoa yeah all right guys
there's a lot here so i'll wait till
night then we'll lock them in
it's 10 o'clock do you know where your
children are
i better get inside
very wise very very wise
and yep go ahead
no i'm not looking at you oh go ahead
are you trying to rob the place go
inside
dude i don't think blacksmiths ever have
a door do they
where's the priest
okay there and there
and there are so many villages or
villagers
in this village where where where
get out of here man i killed one that
jerk ah
so mad
get inside that's right go
go go let's go in
whoa
safe go go
door's gone where's the priest where's
the blacksmith cause if they die i'm
gonna be so sad
what the heck there's a skeleton in
there
there's several skeletons in there
oh
get lost you jerks
man this is like the first first time i
found a village where
they're actually at risk i was wondering
what you were doing
where is the priest where is the
blacksmith
that's all i'm concerned about right now
man i like how that door's gone
this door is gone
i guess we should check this house
that door is gone man i was only here
one night
how did everything die in one night
hmm
i think they died man
okay there's a blacksmith at least
we found the blacksmith i just don't
know where the priest is
hmm
nope nope
get lost
did he get him did i kill him
am i gonna die
oh come on
man i thought i had them all safe
all right guys i guess we lost the
priest but
everybody else should be safe it's weird
i think
i think this village may have generated
before we got here even because a lot of
the doors were missing
when we first found it so it must have
been loaded off in the distance
at some point
uh but we did the blacksmith did survive
he's in here
all happy so we can for surely get him
for project pokemon but we'll have to
find another village
to get the priest because we can't use a
priest that's been bred it has to be
pure purebred
first generation that counts so
i guess that's what we're going to do
i'm going to go explore a bit more i'll
keep this village in mind and i might
fix it up or something
at the very least we're gonna get the
blacksmith from it
all right we got another one just found
it
we are a little bit further out and the
sun is just setting so we have to keep
these guys alive
definitely
right off the bat you're sealed even
before night
this is sand village we got a blacksmith
awesome main thing we need now is a
priest though
you have a dark creepy house
fill that in hopefully i'm not blocking
them from getting
into their home this has two doors
all right
lock that okay gotta move quick this
time because i'm not risking it
don't want them to die again get inside
you're inside good stay inside
forever the blacksmith i definitely want
to keep him
uh the where could the priest be though
i don't
i don't know if there's going to be one
here
these houses aren't even lit like
it's uh the safest village
there's no door
better stuff in this one
yeah dark as can be
okay let's go through make sure we got
them all
that's one i just checked
did not see a priest
they're going for it get out of here
this isn't a game it's people's lives
get inside you stupid what are you doing
what are you doing
i don't know how you got in there
i heard the smash
yeah you just stay there
okay that one guy he has to get inside i
don't think he can
here you see it
oh you want in there just go in this one
it's perfectly fine
this one over here yeah just go
you can do it i'll give you a door
just fine
go ahead hurry
go what are you doing there's a door
over here
yep just for you you can do it
excellent
okay that one's safe i
think that's it
i'm going to put this on
okay this is pretty sweet we got the
village down there
which is all safe now it should be safe
there was no priest but there is a
blacksmith
and then we got these desert hills with
a floating
floating sand thing i want to try to get
on top
and there's also temple over there
i just want to see if i can ender pearl
it
that's going to be a hard shot i can't
do it from the side you have to
position it just right
feels like oh let's try
let's try this oh no it's too far isn't
it
ah too short
failed all right let's go check out this
temple
i haven't found one of these in my world
yet
some strange stuff
i have a pool these
they don't seem to be that random
they're all all the same
and i have found these before so it's
not
not as exciting as a village to me
but i'm still still would like to see
what we get
actually the tnt is something i would
like to uh
i can always use more tnt
okay take that out just before
before i do something stupid
sweet and
lots of gold
a little bit of iron
diamonds and no emeralds by the looks of
it because i think we checked the other
one already
yeah decent
decent cool
all right let's get out of here
with something like this though i would
almost be tempted to expand it
try make it my own for
some reason i don't know so
maybe in the future we'll do something
with it this is pretty nice too just
past
the sand temple in the epic mountains in
the desert in the floating island we
have
more amazing mountains with the cool
little arch here and i
especially like this it has like a ridge
over there
that's really neat natural waterfall
and some crazy caves down below too by
the looks of it
very cool generation now nowadays i like
it a lot
all right guys so i think that's as far
as i'm going to go today i had a lot of
fun exploring
uh we made it all the way up to
about negative 3 000 on the zed actually
let's just cross the border to say we
we have been this far
found two villages and
a sand temple and a few other cool
things
along the way all right so i'm gonna
start heading back and maybe
i'll go a little to the left through
this desert i might find something else
on the way back
that i missed found a dungeon another
dungeon
this one i will raid i'm going to take
the mossy mossy cobble from it
is a zombie one
and we'll raid the chests too
um
okay that's not my portal
i swear
i just was walking back and i found it
the ice isn't melted i don't know would
i smelt
not only it's bright enough um
okay
i wonder if that's a bug or where it
came from
where will it take us
that is so weird that seriously is not
my portal
um
huh
don't recognize this part of the nether
maybe maybe down here oh i've been here
yeah i don't know guys i did not put
that there this is a random portal
in my snow biome there
and it took us back okay heading on home
and we have made it back safe and sound
this is what i'm taking back with me
not bad not bad good stuff so we went
our cave is over there ish
sort of that area right there we went
this way though
three thousand three thousand blocks
this way pretty much
and then came back
so i came back to this village i was
going to start shipping that blacksmith
back i brought a bunch of tracks but
really
as i was making my way over here the
terrain was so far
and so so um
rigid and everything i had to cross over
the water at some points
uh it's it's not going to happen so
instead
if i do try to ship them back i'm going
to
just dig a tunnel at at y y12
back that way get resources as i dig it
and run a track that way
instead
um but while i'm here i'm going to light
up the place i forgot to light up inside
the houses so i don't
want any zombies spawning in them
seriously
killed them all didn't he
where was that
no no no no no no
there's a stinky oh there's a zombie in
there
you jerk get out of here guys
you a villager
three of them
you're okay get inside very good
i will light it up this time i'm sorry
about that
okay everybody so today's episode was a
bit of a chatty one again
uh next episode we will get back into
building
hopefully get a lot done but it is
comment reading time i picked out three
comments
let's check them out number one ito your
mob system is amazing
i built a mob system myself but it's not
working like yours
sad face i have cleared like three
quarters of all of the caves
maybe it's because i have a skeleton xp
farm connected to it
and it's an xp farm if i turn it to
drops only and the skeleton farm off
because i have a ton of bones and bows
and arrows
it's still slow sad face the skeleton
farm shouldn't interfere unless you're
using it like if it's not spawning
skeletons it's not going to interfere at
all
but i will say this the last little bit
of lighting up the caves makes a huge
difference
huge difference so finish it up do the
last quarter and you will notice a big
improvement on rates
all right next one etho ice freezes
faster if it
next to a block that is why your ice
tray freezes from the out
in yes indeed uh
there are quicker ways of harvesting ice
or getting it to freeze
uh just make sure it's next to a block
when i set that thing up though
it was meant to be something quick and
effective which it is or at least i
think it is
next one ito will you do more on the
silverfish farm
ah well i'll leave it up i don't really
plan to do
too much it's that was one of those
projects i've
i'm pretty sure i found it more
interesting than everyone else and i
i did a little too much with it people
got bored so i'm trying to avoid showing
it too much now but what i got planned
yet is to clean up down there
make it everything connect together well
and also
maybe improve my way of getting them to
the surface and maybe add some extra
tunnels for transporting them
underground
that's about it it's actually full right
now i need to harvest them or move them
and anyway that's it for the episode
guys i hope you enjoyed it
i will see you again next time