hello everybody this is Ito welcome back
guys
Oh No No
Oh oh wow getting some leg oh I know I'm
getting laid now I was using my gold
farm earlier today and I think I left
the portals on so zombie pigmen are
going in through
that looks so crazy I like deflected it
I hope at hyperspeed there so yes
welcome back guys how you doing
hope you're having a wonderful day I did
it again I'm trying to like gesture to
you by pressing shift and I keep hopping
out this is the worst intro comeback
No alright so we're going out here guys
I just I guess Wilson will just get to
it here we're going out to the Mesa
right now we're going to set up
something here just a little quick
project to start off with today I'm
going to try make my mining operation a
little bit nicer at the Mesa here to get
hardened clay what I want to do is hook
up this rail track to this portal so
that we can send storage mine carts
through the portal onto the track really
easily and then on the other side here
we're going to set up a mining outpost
like in just a room nothing crazy
we're going to move this portal
underground I think we want to go this
way okay where's my beacon have such a
hard time finding it always I'm still on
an old version of Minecraft so the
beacons are glitched where they don't
really show up not there it's around
here somewhere I know it's I've been
here today oh he's got an enchanted bow
I never carry a bow with me I think I
should I'm almost tempted till I get rid
of my sword and just use a bow only for
a while to see what that's like
okay where is it oh here it is
there we go I knew it was around here
alright so let's go down here ouch this
is where I get my clay from guys got
like a quarry going on and while I was
digging this out I ran into something
strange here just like it was empty
and I looked in here and look at this
this is crazy it's like covered up in
everything I think this is a ravine
in maybe but it's pretty wide to be a
ravine so we're going to go across here
I thought this would be a great place to
set up a room I like I like the feel of
this we'll make a bridge okay guys so
here is the basic plan for this place we
are trying to make it as wonderful and
convenient as possible so we are setting
up a room this is a mining outpost over
here I like putting it across this
ravine just so it's separate from the
mining operation and we're going to put
all our convenient stuff in there we
have a track running across the bridge
we just built we can extend the stretch
as far as we want like as we dig out
more and more blocks we can just extend
this further and we'll have a thing in
there that will send out storage
Minecrafts to the end of this track mine
stuff out put it in the storage minecart
push it up there and then we're going to
have a sorting system for all the
different colors of clay we're going to
have a bunch of storage chests just as a
buffer to hold a bunch of clay and some
other convenient things like sometimes I
come here and I mined for a little bit
my pick breaks or runs low and then I
got nothing else to or nothing here to
repair it or no other picks nearby so I
have to go all the way back home and
it's sort of annoying and we're gonna
try to make it look cool to hopefully
put some support beams there I made a
bunch of fences if you put those across
I want to put some leaves down here kind
of but I don't know if they would make
sense here I'm going to put safety rails
across here too and then the portal is
going to be down here as well so we can
load up storage minecarts push them
through the portal they'll go on the
track on the other side right to the man
cave basically and we won't really have
to do much to make that happen but
anyway I'm going to do
this off-camera and I'll show you the
finished product hopefully okay guys so
I just about got this thing done and
it's turning out fantastic if I do say
so myself very happy with it it's just
about done I just got to figure out a
couple more things yet and I thought I'd
figure out the unloading system with you
guys so to get the clay out of the
storage minecart I thought it might just
be easiest to Ram it into it cactus
we'll see if we can make that happen and
what happens if we do that I'm worried
stuff will get destroyed but I'm not
sure okay so we're gonna have like a
water stream down here you'll see it in
a second but there's basically going to
be a water screen below kind of want all
the items to fall in there somehow oops
there goes the cactus so let's see what
happens with the items here I brought a
storage minecart we're gonna put on the
track Ram it into the cactus hopefully
it even hits the cactus it might not all
right okay for items that's that's
probably good for right now
BAM all right because there's no way I'd
like there's no way to pick up a storage
minecart right so I have to destroy it
that didn't work so well they kind of
flew everywhere I don't think anything
got destroyed though let's try this
again I blocked all the spots except to
the left here is the only airspace
so hopefully the items go that way
instead of all over the place this time
I don't want them to go on this track
here for sure ah darn it the minecart
landed on the track I think the items
got destroyed yeah they did that's not
good at all
okay so cactus was giving me trouble
we're gonna do something like this
instead
this minecart is totally filled up with
red Play so we get it into the thing
here dispenser with arrows in we're
going to have to shoot it twice to break
it bam bam
whoa okay did not expect that is the
clay actually here it is oh that's weird
okay let me try this again I was not
expecting that I think we'll have to
block up the corners too apparently it
can escape that this time I got the
corners totally blocked off let's hope
nothing can escape again it's full of
clay alright so it'll go in gotta shoot
it twice and bam this game this game is
so truly so why is it doing that I
wonder is it because it's in the hopper
maybe you know what I'm gonna try I
think maybe because the hoppers a bit
strange I'm gonna just put a rail on top
of it and see if that does anything cuz
it shouldn't be able to get out of there
like am I crazy
this is totally enclosed oh man rail on
the hopper now let's see if this works
Bam Bam stay inside you stupid dang no
okay alright we're not unloading it this
way I don't like this at all I could
probably make it work if I'd a bit more
airspace around it but it's just turning
into an issue so what we'll probably do
is just make it sit on a hopper and
unload that way so this is it guys I
have finished it I am exhausted I had
had some issues with this and it's like
five six hours later now why is it you
guys have this problem - it's like I
always think it's such
simple project until I actually start
doing it and then it's like what have I
got myself into is it just me does that
happen to you too I don't know why it's
the details little details you overlook
I had a lot of trouble with this one too
because I had issues with unloader as
you saw and a few things I built I had
to rebuild because they were in the
wrong spot which is always annoying but
overall it's been a wonderful labor of
love I'm very happy with the result so
let's go check it out guys and see the
clay mining outpost then get set up now
alright so right off the bat this portal
is a huge improvement because we were
spotting above-ground before and I have
to like find the beach in go down the
hole to get where we need it to be now
it's all very convenient we're here
already got lots of tracks going on here
and yeah this is the basic look of it
it's nothing fancy but I think it looks
cool oh I forgot to close this wait a
second let's get the proper look before
we continue the door there we go oh so
much better million times better already
so probably the best way to demonstrates
or to tell you how this all works is
just go do it right so let's go get this
on get the show on the road we have two
dispensers here one is for storage
minecarts one for regular ones what you
would do is hit that for a storage one
could it send out as many as you want
there's like lots of space here for
buffer um then when we send out as many
storage mine cards as we want we go
our own empty one here and we can keep
extending this tract as far as we want
like if we mine up all the clay in one
area we can just keep going further and
further no problem all that stuff there
works the same and it doesn't get
affected by us moving right so what we
would do is let's just line up some clay
I guess show you how this works which I
did a few different colors here too
because we have items' sorters look and
make sure I don't break the track we got
items sort sorters that sort the colors
which is really nice and convenient too
otherwise I think I still have some here
this was my old set up by those two
double chests
nothing fancy what ended up always
happening is I'd fill this up with
random junk and like they would get
filled up with with all his random stuff
right and I've run out of space pretty
quick nothing was really organized I
couldn't tell how many stacks of what I
had because it was all tea Otakon yeah
whatever now everything is going to be
in its proper place okay so we get our
clay and we fill up our chit our storage
chests here alright and then when we're
we're ready to go back we just push it
on the track and grab our own empty one
and we go back to
aha
very cool so that goes up the left there
let me and hop out here there's a cart
pickup station so there's a switch on
the track here when it comes back hits
this detector rail it goes this way
right now this storage minecart is
unloading up here and it might take a
little while let's just go see where the
items are going first I guess so we've
got the item filters here lights light
colored clay or white clay yeah white
then we got the light grey brown yellow
orange red and then finally we have the
hardened clay this one's not actually
being sorted because it's last one so
there's seven natural colors in the Mesa
like you don't get light blue here or
anything like that obviously okay so I
decide to do the minecart unloading like
I usually do just on a hopper goes into
a dropper here if there's items in this
it activates this clock and sends it a
pulse every time and this minecart stays
here until this wire turns on there's
like a comparator that checks if items
are going through this hopper once it's
empty that turns on goes down the track
as well and I ended up using a cactus to
break it here because I got a break it's
somehow right you can't pick up storage
minecarts in any way regular mine carts
you can you can break them and and put
them into storage but you got to
recombine the chest and the minecart
unless I'm overlooking something and
forgot that they added a feature or
something happens to me sometimes but
I'm pretty sure you can't pick up
storage my cards so I just decide to
send them to this chest here we got
extra tracks if we ever need to extend
how far we're mining like if we mine out
an area we can just go further all right
cool so yeah then I got everything
color-coded here ends up in these chests
each color has three double chests of
storage so that is quite a bit way
better than just a couple random chests
place down like I had there a long time
before I fill these up I think and then
the over here is for the regular
hardened clay I have nine double chests
for that because I think that's the most
common one and the main one I want to
collect so these will fill up in order
this one for this row or this column not
row column will fill up first than this
one and this one
uh-huh and then when we are when we come
here to pick up clay or whatever all we
got to do is hit a button here storage
minecart falls out from the ceiling it's
amazing it's beautiful there's nothing
here even how does it work well we kind
of saw it earlier you can do a trick
where it falls between a diagonal with
minecarts I'm sure most of you know it
so yeah dispensers up here it shoots
minecart up here goes down through the
crack and can I break this I going to
wreck anything I can do that yeah so it
just falls in between the log and this
piece of clay diagonally very cool got
empty carts grab whatever colors we want
from here load up our carts as many as
we need to and just push it through the
portal and you saw when we entered here
we had the slanted track so it
automatically goes onto the track and
over to our nether hub so very cool I'm
very happy with this I do kind of want
to set up three of these outposts is the
thing so this was like the trial one I
want one for my sand and sandstone
collection in the desert and I also want
one for
or just my general mining I do like for
redstone in that this was a lot of work
though so I don't know if I'm going to
do it or not I might got a jukebox here
too just for for the funds of it
sometimes I'm I'm collecting blocks I
like to listen to music or whatever but
anyways guys we are over here now at the
arena believe it or not this is what I
was working on today it's like it oh you
know what I want to try some clay blocks
for the floor when I go check my storage
and we got none and then well one thing
led to another and we we built the clay
mining outpost today instead so I
figured we probably want a light block
for the floor here I'm going to try the
white clay and the light gray goes
pretty good with this and also the brown
goes really good with that I find and we
got lots of them so might try those out
and see if we can make it a pattern or
something I think it's going to be very
plain if we just do solid white I don't
want to build anything out of wood or
dirt or anything like that because the
stuff is going to get blown up regularly
from the creepers here and minimize the
damage if possible okay guys so this is
where you come in I really need your
help picking colors and stuff so it's
been trying different blocks for the
walls I do like the floor I think
White's white clay makes a really good
floor I'm not a huge fan of the pinkish
tint to it but I think it's okay still
so I've got a nice bright floor put the
light gray trim around it I think that's
good I might put a pattern in the floor
though I don't know is it too plain as
it is if we put a pattern in the floor
it's got to be something easy to copy
because if it gets blown up I got to
replace it rights might also go with
sandstone but it's a little bit weaker
than hardened clay
um I think this is good anyway
we got these different wall colors I'm
trying to decide what blocks to use I do
think Brown goes pretty good with it but
I don't know if I'd want it for a wall
it's kind of dark and good make a good
ceiling we got red got stone brick heart
and clay just the regular stuff here
let's try a couple other colors let me
know which one you think is best or what
what you think would be best if I don't
use the right one here let's go even
darker we'll go with the black clay just
to try it all right black clay oh that's
actually not that bad I kind of like
that it's like it pulls you in it's so
dark
reminds me of coffee I love coffee okay
yellow yellow wouldn't be terrible for
the floor either we can't do grass here
either because not only is it weak but
this is a desert biome so we can't just
like carry out the the forest D theme of
our man cave throughout here it won't
look very good if we do yellow doesn't
match these and I just did a couple more
colors here just to try them so this is
the green I don't really think it goes
well with these blocks and then I did
cyan here which I think does go with
these okay um it's actually not too bad
let me know what do you guys think
should we use any of these there any
other blocks you would recommend and
actually I'm going to be biased I think
this was my favorite actually I'm
surprised because I thought the dark was
going to be bad but as I think about it
um our focus is going to be on the
combat right so we almost want the whole
arena around us to be dark and like this
is the highlight here we want this as
bright as possible so the white is
really good for that and then our eyes
won't really focus on the outside
but that's just what I'm my opinion I
don't know let me know what you guys
think
I guess we'll probably have to get to
the comment of the day and wrap up the
episode though so let's go do that okay
so here we go guys mr. pineapple man
says hey etho you know the hole that
took me excited you know the whole time
you have had your LP you have never
really had your own bedroom I mean for
crying out loud do you even sleep in the
man cave by the way you are awesome ah
ha thank you very much
so here's the thing about the man cave
guys true story
one of the main reasons it exists even
is because on the old world I spent so
much time like you have no idea it's so
much time waiting for night time that's
what I would do I'd wait for night time
because I couldn't just start recording
you know two minutes before sunset if I
did that you know I'd have to stop what
I was doing go find a bed sleep away the
nights and go back to what I was doing
just didn't work out too well right so I
had to wait till nighttime stir so that
when I would start recording and be a
brand-new day and I'd have a full 10
minutes or whatever right so I made the
man cave one of the big reasons was
because day and night just doesn't
matter in here most the time I don't
even know what time it is in the world I
don't need to sleep when I'm in the man
cave it's it's wonderful
there's no mobs in here because we lit
everything up even though there's no
torches around uh-huh the only way I can
tell if it's nighttime is it by the
clocks I have clocks throughout the cave
there's a few places where I have
daylight sensors like here because these
leaves are dark I can tell right now
it's nighttime during the day it's it's
a bit brighter up here because lights
lights turn on and stuff like that we
got the day and night tune that plays
otherwise I just have absolutely no clue
that's the day tune
and now lights are on here
aha so it's it's a pretty sweet deal
what I got going on down here
I liked it anyway that's gonna do it
guys I hope you enjoyed today's episode
hope you have yourselves a good day and
I'll see you in the next one take care
my night