[Music]
well hello everybody
uh i made a mistake here i guess last
episode
i had a piece of cobble here i forgot
about instead of dirt
and when i went to kill the silverfish
they all fell
like i had them all in this pit here
that block
disappeared because there was one in it
and then they all fell down
there's i guess there's a hole down here
but uh yeah hopefully i get them all
with this
poison them already
there we go pretty good
didn't get all of them
like that xp looks so weird just slowly
snaking its way up here
can it make it up
i don't think you can no it's not making
it
oh did that be any more of those no i
didn't
i'm going down
i'm doing it hope for the best
can't see anything
just worried i'm going to fall in lava
like the ground's going to disappear
yeah i can't really really see anything
i think we got it all
get out of here where's
can't see okay
whoo what an adventure
so yeah i just wonder why
there's one block left in here the goal
is to get 100
silver fish but oh yeah i ran out of
pick two
oh well i'm gonna head back to the main
cave
we will probably do a little bit of work
over there today i just happened to be
i was testing this a little bit off
camera see if
it was stable or not and uh
don't really know yet because it just
jammed up i guess because this room was
full
so oh well
all right level 42 test again on a pick
turns out fairly good efficiency 3
fortune 3
and we're trying to get feather falling
on our boots again level 22 is a good
one to go for
and it works amazing so we got the fresh
pair not quite as good as these ones but
it's uh
it's a good one
oh man i just realized this isn't
symmetrical
it's a four wide over there and five
wide over here
so even numbers odd numbers can't make
it work
can't have to move the whole stinking
tree farm
to make it work so we'll just have to
live with it
it's going to get on my nerves a little
bit but what can you do
this is the last thing we really worked
on around the cave and i think we should
do a little bit more today
like look wise there's one thing i've
been putting off for a very long time
because i'm afraid to do it
i'm worried i won't make it look good
uh the ceiling here people keep telling
me to do the ceiling
it would add a lot to this the way i had
it planned there's supposed to be a
sandstone
lining all along the sides here and one
all around here which is pretty much
there already
and then this was going to be netherrack
kind of beveled up a little bit
i'm worried it's going to be too dark if
i do that
i think i'll just go ahead and do it see
what it looks like
and i'll let you guys
maybe give me some tips another thing i
want to do
too is kind of round out this ufo thing
i do hope to get it working again
maybe today or sometime at least
so instead of having a square corner
maybe we'll do this instead
like that just a little bit more round
um yeah this is going to be tough
to shape because it's kind of
kind of goes down in places goes up in
places some places are really wide some
are really
narrow like this isn't exactly a wide
area here
but i don't know i'll try and
hopefully it won't look terrible and i
don't know what to do about over here
because we got the the path for the cave
spiders
where the stone brick is it's kind of
important
but i guess we'll just have to figure
something out
so i'm gonna go ahead and we'll see what
it looks like
okay brace yourself the changes have
been made
big changes to the ceiling um
it might be a little bit shocking to
some of you viewer discretion is advised
here we go this is the new ceiling
get a feel for it think about it
i think we can live with it
do you love it do you hate it if you
hate it uh
what else could i do instead if you love
it
uh what could i do to improve it yet
those are the questions
that i expect you to leave answers to
um yes let's look at this in a little
bit more detail
had a little trouble shaping it in
places but uh
kind of made it work i did round out all
the corners on the ufo thing
and i put a sandstone stripe all the way
around
and i didn't go beyond that point
because i want some feedback
before i advance the ceiling any further
just to make sure it's okay with
everybody
and you know it is my world i have the
final save but i do like to get feedback
from people
and as far as looks go with things i
usually don't care too much
so i could go either way with this i was
fine with it as stone
before to be honest
um i did put a sandstone lining around
this
thing here i don't like uh
pretty sure i'm gonna get rid of these
waffles
but i don't like um not just that i
don't like uh
i do kind of like them but at the same
time they keep i keep accidentally
opening them
and then i have to close them more i
think the game still has
update issue yeah
which is bugging me too a little bit you
can see i got rid of them on the potion
room door just because they kept opening
and closing whenever i opened and closed
the door and i didn't feel like moving
the
wire around anyway back to the ceiling
so that goes around
uh i replaced remember i used to just
have the stone brick stairs here and i
had like a
quarter gap and then above that there
was the full
nether brick blocks now i have nether
brick stairs upside down ones
to kind of keep the flow going i guess
you could say
and these really aren't uh
for anything like they're not normal in
housing
in houses or anything uh it's just to
give
the wall a little bit more shape and
texture character whatever
compared to having a flat wall all the
way up i think it looks better
to have something at the top like that
over here i kind of beveled the ceiling
up a little bit
for the potion room door because it's a
really big door
and it kind of emphasizes that i would
say
some stairs are used upside down stairs
to kind of
smooth out the transition over there
i had a lot of trouble with this here
there's no way i can cover the sandstone
because i don't like how it's facing
there
because it's not uh it's not too wide
the sandstone on this side but it is on
this side
so can't really cover that
up without breaking the flow so i might
have to leave that open
and again over here i had trouble
shaping it because uh
this has to come down like this there's
water above there
did i ever see what i didn't like here
um
the glowstone's level with the ground
here but then it goes down and then this
one's just kind of floating in the air
so not sure what to do about that
um
so it might take a little while to get
used to the nether brick
uh i'm starting to like it already i
think it grows on you
after a little while it was really
shocking at first but now i'm
getting used to it also this brick i
replaced with upside down stairs
i might make this door might make it go
up a little higher like i have there
i may also still raise this door up one
block i'm not sure yet
i we should really start working on that
again
what else the reason i went with nether
brick
is i like the dark look to it it kind of
at least for me it makes me not
look at the ceiling it makes me look at
the ground and the walls
the important stuff so
that's why i kind of went with it
and
i guess the sandstone just kind of lets
you feel where the ceiling
starts somehow i don't know it's a look
i kind of like
it looks a lot better if you have a
higher roof i find a higher ceiling
but over here i think i'll
think i could get used to it but let me
know what you think
what your opinions are
all right so we should move on um
this thing here i'll i'm gonna try to
replace it with brick i'm gonna have to
get some brick first though
uh instead of the the stone brick i want
regular brick and see how it looks
okay i got some brick together here and
i've replaced the stone brick with it
just for a little bit more color nice
red look to it
uh i'm gonna get rid of the glowstone on
this thing all together i think
because i really like the way glowing
pumpkins look
when mixed with brick compared with
glowstone normally i always prefer
glowstone but
like in the tree farm i think low stone
would look better than the pumpkins
but with brick i seem to prefer
pumpkins with with brick for lighting
that and if you don't know what this
thing is this is just an infinite spring
i need i need one of them around here
and i kind of forgot to
put one in as i was building around here
so i just kind of put this here
to take care of that need
grab from there i don't know if you can
grab from like where the stair is
yeah you can't if you were able to you'd
be able to
wreck the infinite spring uh so
you can only grab from there the only
block that recreates itself so that's
how that works
i think that'd be okay um
how do waffles look on pumpkins
yeah see i um like the waffle look i
just hate how they
keep closing on me or opening or
whatever
yeah maybe uh maybe i'll keep them on
for a little bit anyway
all right so and for all my new viewers
and i get quite a few new viewers
every day and you might not know the
rules of the cave here
so basically the ultimate goal i have
here is to use no torches for lighting
so none of these the ones you see are
the just there temporarily
while i figure things out but once this
is all done
i just want either lava for lighting
glowstone or glowing pumpkins basically
anything but towards this
that's that's the ultimate goal the
other
goal of this cave thing was to make
everything i built kind of go with the
natural
shape of the cave so
if you watch back to about episode 100
and or so basically when we started in
this new world
uh this cave is really rough looking
but the same shape is basically there a
few few areas i have
cut out like the potion room but
this weird cow farm that goes down is
there because of
there was one of those square rooms that
you find in abandoned mine shafts there
so i tried to keep that shape
built that lower
and that was just the basic goal behind
this and so far i think we've done
pretty good with that
i think we've um went with our
main objective we do have to hear these
torches yet
i don't know how to do that
because it'll be too dark here mobs will
be able to spawn if these aren't here
um could put them
on top maybe
we would need another one here probably
uh it's one possibility the other is to
maybe put in the ground
instead
let's see
do something like that and maybe
it's tricky to sneak lighting in here
because it's pretty there's not really a
anything built here this is a straight
line of fence
i'll probably have to put it on top if
you got ideas let me know
maybe we'll just leave it plain for
today
get the torches back here
but once that's done i think uh we got a
lot of this area pretty much finished
like we got the walls done we got the
ceiling done um
rooms are built that's a big portion of
the cave that i can
fairly comfortably say is complete
but then obviously once you get to about
over here
it's a mess again and we'll have to work
on that
all right so now i think we're going to
take a few minutes to play around with
the
idea i had um for kind of like an
elevator
um it's not an elevator though just a
way of using ender pearls quickly
easily because i've i've mentioned this
before but i'm probably going to build
like a mine shaft somewhere
maybe a ways away from here that i can
freely dig for redstone and diamonds and
everything
without having to worry about lighting
up the tunnels afterward
and obviously i'm going to need a way of
going down to bedrock
level or close to bedrock level and then
back up quickly because i'll probably
be going up and down quite often
and i i do have an infinite supply of
ender pearls basically so i think the
easiest way or the quickest way of
making
a way to get back up is with ender
pearls
and we've played around with this before
i think they went up 33 blocks or
something
when we tested
so yeah the idea i have is to use uh
or try to use fences um
let's see we'll go up a little bit here
now we can probably just jump and do it
i think if we have two by two thing of
fences
there'll be a gap in between that we
might be able to throw an ender pearl
through
that we won't fall through ourselves oh
maybe not
okay that idea doesn't work
okay let me think here
i kind of want to do something where
we'll have a pressure plate
on a fence
and the ender pearl activates the
pressure plates
you think that would be possible
the idea i had there isn't going to work
after all so
too bad um
i'm going to put some pressure plates on
here and we'll just see if we can
activate them with an ender pearl from
below
or if it's going to hit the fence
i think it went through it without
um
hmm it's hard to tell
every time it clicks down is the time
when i
get in the fence um
don't think we can actually hit it
without yeah
hmm that's too bad
i was thinking like you could just put
some blocks over top
the gap there and just throw
ender pearl up and you would fall down
a block or so onto the fence again
um
okay maybe i'll rethink this a little
bit just give me a minute
so i'm thinking uh we might be able to
do something with a
boat possibly oh
if we have a boat over here not sure if
uh i'm pretty sure like the ender pearl
will hit the boat
and teleport us i'm not sure if we'll
get teleported above or below the boat
though
ideally i want to get above the boat
you know kind of uh
it's hard to see how high i'm actually
getting teleported
[Music]
oh that's where it changes your view
on its own
okay uh that's not gonna work i will
think of something else
what i'm trying to do here is uh have a
certain block you walk up to on the
ground
that's marked or something and then it's
you wouldn't have to aim you just move
your mouse up and throw the pearl
so i'm going to try water and a lily pad
now i don't know if you would make it
through the lily pad i kind of don't
think you can swim up through them
oh it does work awesome that's one idea
um you can get out yeah you can
okay that might work that's pretty easy
to build too
beautiful so you'd probably only need
two of those to make it all the way up
from
bedrock to the surface i would think
let's see i was going to try something
else too oh yeah trapdoors
might be worth trying that yet
awesome
okay i'm gonna do a trapdoor now
one minute now we're gonna try it first
with water below the trapdoor and see
how that goes
okay and yeah the idea is
you have a spot marked then you could
easily walk up to it and quickly
throw the pearl without having to aim
like sort of at an angle
or a specific spot
okay i didn't i wasn't swimming there i
just wanted to see if i would stay up
that time i'm swimming and i can get out
so it's much like the lily pad we're
going to try it one more
or one different way here too
which probably won't work just have the
trapdoor alone
get rid of that maybe put it over there
oh not too late i love feather falling
it's awesome
okay just fall through
oh how did i do that i was holding jump
that time
hmm let's try that again
maybe we'll be a little bit more
accurate on our aiming go first
the very center this time
um yeah that would be
that'd probably be inconsistent i'm
gonna play around with it a bit and see
if i can figure out how i uh
jumped again that one time
yeah it seems to be a timing thing you
gotta jump right when the ender pearl
hits the
the door or close to that time anyway
there we go it's hard to do every time i
can only do it maybe half the time at
best
so i don't think i'll be doing
this method probably do the lillypad one
seems to work the best
actually i'm getting really good at this
now
uh yeah but yeah lilypad is
there we go the safest way of doing it
because that's like a
i'll probably have it them 30 blocks
apart or so
uh that's a drop that would kill you for
sure if you didn't have feather falling
so definitely
got to do something safer than this uh
anyway i'm going to end the episode here
for today um
next video coming out will probably be
from the ultra hardcore series we did
a bunch of us from the minecraft server
got together to play that
it's a very lpsh type thing where we
start in a new world and get
gather materials and everything but our
goal
is to kill each other
we als we all start in a different area
on the map
the map was a specific size
with bedrock borders around to keep us
kind of close together
to encourage a conflict
and the real ticker about the thing is
you can't recover health in it by having
your hunger full the only way you can
recover health is by making golden
apples
or by making instant health potions
and those have been modified as well
where
the golden apples require eight gold to
create
uh like eight to eight ingots not
eight nuggets so it takes a lot of gold
to make a single apple
and the instant health potions take
a full gold block so nine ingots to make
so it's a real challenge to get uh
health in that
series and especially when you have
people trying to kill you so it was fun
we've we finished it and i'll be
uploading video of it very soon
probably tomorrow so i hope you guys
enjoy that
and thanks for watching for today i'll
see you again next time