oh hello again everybody
this is etho and welcome back go get
your snacks so what is he doing exactly
he's shooting all that one's coming for
me or is he trying to that one went up
into the ceiling didn't it ooh ooh and
dodged oh man like a pro so we are we're
back in the end here guys there's been
an update 15 w 42 a and this is a really
good snapshot I'm happy with it
it's very optimized in getting really
good FPS with it and chunks are loading
quick again you last like when the
glider wings came out that snapshot was
giving me a lot of stuttering this one's
pretty smooth and the big thing though
in this snapshot portals work again whoo
that means we can actually get the
glider wings in survival so that's what
we're doing here and I'm grabbing some
lights on the way to Lou you know I
thought this I thought those stuck like
within a block it seems like they're
going diagonally and stuff though oh oh
now they're still flying square just it
looked kind of smooth though you can't
deflect these Kenya oh oh I didn't know
that oh that's awesome there I've been
running away like a coward you just you
just hit them all sweet yeah we're
looking for the glider wings of the
boats is where you get them and the boat
is right there you see it's oh we got
hits darn it well we're going up and
we're gonna check out this fortress for
any chests - because did we get hit
again no ah they've introduced two more
enchanting
that I believe you can only get in like
treasure chest so we might only be able
to get them in fortresses such as this
so let's see if we owe this a guy - okay
where do we want to go let's go I guess
we got to go up right so let's go this
way
good throat yeah we're good okay let's
let's just bust into here oh that's what
we want to see okay there's some
treasure down there let's go get that
yeah these oh I got hit no I wanted to
fall down there wait a minute wait a
minute oh yeah take that physics alright
we got oh that's a really good helmets
ah
is there anything wait what's that there
that's another shocker okay I checked in
there there was nothing nothing in there
this might be the last tower to look
into bust open and anything nothing no I
thought there might have been some more
here oh that's a guy over there turn it
let's fall down and just double check
yeah it doesn't look like there's
anything else okay so let's go to the
boat yeah you can get the new
enchantments the mending and frost
Walker in treasure chests can get them
by fishing and by trading only you can't
get it just by straight enchanting I
don't think and this is the scary throw
okay let's let's go for it here if we
miss should just throw it into the void
right let's hope oh all right
that's a scary throw man this is really
hard the judge of distance and there
should be some chests in here - we got
the brewing stand still they change
brewing by the way so now you need blaze
powder as a fuel to actually perform the
brewing which means ethos lab might be
in jeopardy
okay there's the glider wings right
there I want them oh you got me darn it
it's fine we gotta take this gotta take
the sector out they actually do a little
bit of damage if you if you just have
basic armor on you can get hurt quite a
bit actually okay let's see what we got
here first
I'm breaking three protection three more
gold those are good happy about that
pretty decent diamond chestplate as well
Oh beetroot seeds okay oh that's awesome
I didn't realize you could get those
from chess I thought you have to find
them in the village like newly generated
villages alright pillage everything it's
a it's a pirate ship right that's what
you got to do alright and here are the
wings yes
we got lighter wings oh yeah okay and
was there anything else oh yeah there's
okay let's check something as well I
think there's the dragon head at the
front which I didn't realize which makes
sense like a lot of real life boats have
dragons on the front like the old ones
it was a superstition of some sorts so
it's actually a pretty fitting place for
it I thought you were supposed to get
this from killing the dragon but no it's
over here okay
just want to make sure we get it we only
got one shot at this
woohoo and yes alright
now do we dare to do it do we fly down
there let's make sure these work first
cuz I had one experience already where
the wings didn't work for some reason I
don't know what was up with that like
when I was playing around and creative
what they don't work hey oh no don't do
that
I've come so far for these wings don't
tell me they don't work it's gonna make
me so sad yeah they're not working darn
it
what's up with that okay no worries guys
because we have flights I got it working
here I just had to reload the world and
you can see I got my armor bars back and
we can fly oh it's so cool oh man you're
going fast
oh it's so awesome we can fly um yeah I
died too an Anderman earlier and I think
that's what messed things up my armored
bar disappeared and my items were
invisible and there was a bunch of weird
stuff going on with this patch I guess
just a slight little issue but a bunch
of things are broken in our world
currently like item elevators and that
there has been some things that are have
been fixed though like our piston
elevators for example this spiral one
hasn't worked in a very long time
and still kind of sucks but you can
actually get to the top of it if you're
lucky all right come on for the people
Oh same spot do it for me come on
people are watching there okay this is
the run this is the run tada
so it can actually get to the top now
it's still pretty crummy elevator though
if you want my honest opinion the ones
that are really good now though are the
zipper elevators oh it's kind of weird
going downstairs with the glider wings
it's a little bit like it kicks in but
it doesn't you know um yeah this one
over here so I wasn't able to get to the
top very reliably before unless I was
riding the horse now it seems to work
every time with my my player here whoa
try it again
even finally this I'm not really on here
properly and it still works so that's
awesome and those go ten blocks per
second which is a pretty good time
pretty good speed so what I want to do
in my world I like I want to fly around
you right so we need elevators all over
the place I want them spread out and
like if I want to go somewhere just go
up the elevator and then fly to where I
want to go and there'll be another
elevator there and I think that's going
to be the best way of getting around the
question is do we want to do zipper
elevators or do we want to do minecart
elevators because those are actually
faster they don't require redstone hmm
that's a nice perk of them but the
downside is you get like
to get to the top of the world we're
going to need like 30 mine carts and
everyone causes a little bit of lag so
there's a there's a trade-off with that
alright guys I just went ahead and built
our first elevator here off camera just
so we can get going and try this out and
I put it in the man cave you know this
area over here where we don't really
have anything built just added a little
bit on and we now have an elevator nice
and close to like our main hub here so
if I want to go somewhere it's going to
be really easy just come up to this spot
here and it's one of these minecart
elevators not not the kind with a track
you just hold right click get poured it
up to the top I decide to go with this
one because it is very fast to build
very cheap to build and I think it's the
fastest one like woah oh I fell already
whoops I think it's like the fastest
transport vertically right that that I
could think of the other ones are 10
blocks per second so if you're going up
like 200 blocks or whatever that's 20
seconds which is a fair bit at a time
and then we can just fly around oh it's
so awesome my little legs ticking in
there the one thing I'm noticing though
like I don't think I'm going to build
them all right up to the max height
because when you're up this high for
ideal distance you kind of want to keep
your mouse cursor flat like this and you
can't really see where you are like you
can't see the world below you unless you
look down and if you look down then you
then you lose your height you know so
you probably only really want to go 128
blocks up into the sky or so at the most
yeah this is so cool like oh man I just
love it I wish I could just keep it like
this height forever though I like flying
close to the ground and soaring over the
the stuff we built is really fun ok guys
so next up here I want to try to a
distance test as well so how far can we
get from the top of the world we're at
well pretty much the top of the
2:54 here we're going to get our cursor
nice and flat all right and we're going
to be traveling in the Z coordinates so
positive Z we're at 217 right now let's
go ahead and jump off whew
and just see how far we can get you
travel very fast don't you we've
traveled 200 blocks already the man that
is insane three hundred four hundred we
are cruising okay there's the mob Tower
so that's from the stronghold base the
ground is getting pretty close already
though but we've covered a good distance
just about a thousand blocks in desert
we might actually go out of bounds like
where I've been the farthest this that
island there's an island yeah this is
the one we tried to blow up to make a
passive mob spawner and there's a
there's a guardian fortress down below
there now I see an 1800 I'm gonna hate
walking back this is so far mm okay so
that's about 1800 blocks we traveled
going down to Wai 64 that's that's crazy
alright well I got to get back so I'm
gonna use the boats try them out I think
they sped them up they're definitely
going faster now okay we are still going
the wrong way which is the right way
opposite way
this way right yes okay oh there there a
little bit more all over the place
because they have more power now here we
go
okay let's check our our thing here so
we're moving at a pretty decent speed
not crazy fast but that's pretty good
okay so I'm building another elevator
right now and I wanted to show you guys
just how easy it is to to make
these how quickly you can do it because
a lot of people struggle getting the
minecart in that's all you got to do
it's so so simple okay and then the
minecart set the second block third
block fourth block fifth block and your
ladder and then you just pull her up you
can do it fairly quick to actually go
one above the ladder and then next
minecarts and just keep going all the
way up it doesn't take very long
actually so second third fourth fifth
ladder again I like to place that first
I know how high I need to build it up to
and I like to carry like a stack of iron
on me so I can make more minecarts and
like you have have stuff to make a
crafting bench up here and and then
nothing should slow you down now the
only thing about these elevators though
is they look pretty ugly don't take and
you can't hide them like how would you
hide that you could build that tree but
it's going to be a really giant out of
place looking tree you know so what do
you do there's the other one we built
over there
although beacons are ugly too I don't
really like beacons I should almost hide
them together like put the beacon in the
middle of the elevator so at least we
get rid of some of this vertical you
know lines in the sky I don't like them
um let's try this out so this one's a
little bit lower it's at 128 I believe
so not nearly as high up nice thing
about that is we can get to the top
quicker and it should do what we want to
do so we're we're flying and we can get
to this elevator from it so if we wanna
go further we just hop in this one but
we can probably get five hundred to a
thousand blocks distance just from that
little bit of height okay so I want to
play around with the boats a little bit
today as well guys we're gonna do a few
tests with them the first thing oh that
was the zombie right yeah that sizzle
scared me first thing we're going to do
is take it out on the rig
here this is going to be a really good
test to compare them to the old boats
because we were just barely able to get
through this but at full speed with old
boats and I want to see how comparable
the new is with the olds I guess it's
going to be tough to get through to
control so far not too bad actually I
don't know though are these I don't
think it's quite as fast as the old boat
still I think they need to bump up the
speed a bit more light I think it's
faster than running now but it could be
a bit faster it's actually surprisingly
easy to control this yeah we're getting
through this a lot better and I thought
we would there's also that new addition
we added on that's a little bit narrower
I believe so let's go to that just
around here which I don't know if we
were able to do with the old boats but
we'll try it out with the new ones
anyway
gotta go under the bridge date wait a
second so they're doing this thing which
I don't like
let me explain so when you were going
straight if I let go of D we start
drifting to the right when I reactivate
D it kind of pushes us back to the left
it shouldn't do that in my opinion okay
let go D activate you see how it drifts
to the left a little bit it makes it
really wavy feeling and that I find that
hard I don't like that I want it to be a
smooth like even just like changing
directions it's really jerky which I
have mixed feelings about I think it
should be smoother but it's got a few
things going for it like it's it doesn't
break you can move mobs around with it I
think they look better than the old
boats I just think they need to be a bit
faster and maybe a bit smoother and they
would be perfect but yeah they're easy
to control we're getting through this no
problem
uh-huh
anyway I want to also take this over to
that eats road we built and just see
what it does with that
I forgot we have like jumps and stuff in
it
I'll be surprised that this works with
no adjustments but we'll try it out here
alright so there is a dispenser we can
just put the boat in I can reach it yeah
oh it actually converted the old boats
into the new ones that's cool okay and
then there was a button somewhere around
here I thought I was it just over here
okay it's just over here so you have to
hop in as it goes by and that's not a
good sign that is not a good sign it's
not really oh wait it's not really going
just by the water currents is it it's
falling between them that one block
space it fits in it oh when it's on the
water though it seems to do pretty good
oh no fall damage huh oh it broke yeah
it broke I didn't I didn't bust it how
about we try this now we're gonna put
the boat down and then paddle so we put
it between no it won't let us put it put
it between because it's colliding with
that so we have to put it here and then
push it I think okay oh can we not push
yeah we can push push push it's like
pushing a stalled out car or something
all right
and now we want to paddle I can't tell
where I'm looking even we're facing the
wrong way okay let's turn around the
nice thing is that shouldn't ever break
which is a big deal alright yeah even
though we're going like with the water
now the boats facing like with the water
we're still falling between the cracks
alright let's try here is nice straight
away
get on that water whoa it doesn't seem
yeah you know when we're under the glass
it really doesn't work here okay let's
try this this is so bad I have some
ideas to fix it but yeah we'll have to
change it a lot so let's just get the
basic mechanics of these boats figured
out okay so first off if we do this is
that going to move the boat quickly
seemed decent let's try it again yeah so
it does boost it I don't think it's
quite as significant as the old boat so
we put it there it almost seems like the
more the boat is in the water stream the
faster it gets moved by it
uh-huh
because it sort of slowly pulls it along
at first and then when it really gets
into it then it then it goes let's do
this now we'll put a covering over top
that's the key to the eats road but
maybe that's not a thing anymore yeah
that didn't do anything it's just like
dragged along it
let's try ice I don't like it's I don't
think it's gonna factor in the slippery
effect but hey you never know it's worth
trying you wanted to run into my boat
didn't you I was about to place it and
he was going for it okay and same that
same okay we could also try put ice down
here I really dealt we'll do anything
but it's always good to be thorough
okay and give another go
so slime block like sideways slime block
launchers seem like they're going to be
the best way if you want to do a road
with boats
okay so I got alternating water streams
here we're going to try get the boat
right in the middle and paddle at the
same time and we'll see if that gives us
any significant speed boost or anything
so let's turn it around kind of got the
fencer to align us a bit better and
we're a little bit on the left though
mm-hmm how tough is this gonna be I
wonder we're still not floating you got
to be floating for it to really like
move you so we might have to get man
we're still not floating okay and then
we fell you gotta be really precise I
don't know if you could get like right
in the middle oh oh oh no
yeah the room for air is so small that's
not going to work here's a really
interesting test so I put water on top
of path box path blocks are a little bit
sunk down in the ground so when you put
your boat here the water pulls it along
right but never does it float so it
seems like if the boat is touching water
if it's in water it'll drag along like
that but in order to actually get the
real speed for it to like take off the
very middle of the boat and the very
bottom of the boat need to be in water
that seems to be the key so it went once
it hits this it should pick up and it's
a downward flowing water there yeah it
kind of
oh that's weird huh why did it go so far
away it kind of like just dragged for a
little bit there that was really weird
because normally like when we were
riding it on the top of the water it
would just fall right here and actually
went a block hmm same deal as before
here so it's going to be sitting on the
path blocks below its floating points
but it's gonna hit this downward flowing
water and what does it do it drags along
without floating it's very strange just
out of curiosity what happens if we
change it from downward flowing water to
just stationary water I'm going to fill
the bottom up here alright so there was
no water in the bottom there before the
top was just flowing down into it now it
should be solid water and do the same
thing is it going to go any faster do
anything different same thing okay
okay I should have done this first I
guess but it turns out if you place a
boat while underwater it just sinks it's
not like the old boats that would float
up it just sinks to the bottom like that
and if you hop in it just kicks you out
automatically no oh I'm very sad now I
wanted to make a submarine to be honest
that was my plan and this kind of just
killed it for me so yeah you can start
in the boat but as soon as it gets
invalid like when it detects you're
underwater in a boat just ticks you out
automatically so that kind of sucks well
it turns out it might not be a totally
busted idea so check this out
you have your boats it sinks oh no my
poor boats I can't hop in it no it won't
let me
alright then you push it into our little
track here so it's just ladders
underwater in a straight line and oh the
boats alive again and I don't know if
it's actually getting stuck under the
ladders but yeah you can actually row it
then and for a moment you can go
underwater before it kicks you out like
looks like one two three four four to
five blocks maybe I'm gonna try here
let's try this so we're going to add
just a three block gap and see if we can
skip a little bit of the track and
continue on here before it kicks us out
huh
I want a submarine man it's been my
dream in this game for so long oh you
see that it was above the the air pocket
there and it just kind of sucked it down
right into place which is kind of nice
it's really easy to position it at squid
bit or not oh I missed it darn it I hit
the block this episode's getting a bit
on the long side this is the last thing
we're going to try to date but it looks
like submarines could be pretty cool
actually so I used
upside-down half slabs this time for
better visibility the ladders you have
to have a block on the side right which
isn't as good
oops we got kicked out but with the
slabs look at this like it renders an
extra layer of water which blocks the
view a little bit but overall it's
pretty good we can see to our left and
our rights very clearly up and downs a
little bit more obscured but you can
still see like the mountains outside the
water so it's it's not bad and we can
breathe because we're inside the slab ah
it's really hard to keep it straight
though I'm finding so you need some sort
of launching an alignment stuff
otherwise it's pretty tough alright umm
it always wants to start facing the
wrong way - it's really annoying and it
doesn't turn on a dime so if you hit
left or right it'll actually push you
forward a little bit and you get knocked
out of the track oh ok good time to
leave our comment for today says dear
ESO have you ever done an episode that
wasn't in your usual setup like maybe
you were in a hurry and had to do the
episode on a laptop at Starbucks or
something as a pretty interesting
question so I have I have two old
laptops that I basically never use even
when they were new I didn't like them
very much I only used them out of
necessity like if I was on vacation or
something but yeah if I ever like took a
few days off I always tried to record
ahead of time instead of like doing it
on vacation so haven't really found the
need to to do that no I really don't
like laptops so like I'll never just go
to the couch and record on a laptop
because it's more comfortable or
something I just I can't do that I need
my desktop
and there's a lot of stuff on the
computer just to make these episodes
like recording software editing software
I need that stuff and I can't just
switch to another computer on the fly
sort of thing it takes a bit of time to
do that so on a whim I would never just
record on another computer I'd have to
really plan it and it I've never done
that so no it's always been on my
desktop I had an older computer and and
the current computer just two computers
all episodes have been recorded on
alright well thank you for watching
everybody I hope you enjoyed our episode
here and I'll see you again in the next
one take care bye bye