[Music]
wide load
coming down the stairs
somehow he managed to get to that part
of the cave and track me down
yeah what are you gonna do guy oh
uh-huh
uh so what i kind of want to do today
to start off with we're gonna go and oh
man he's got friends
we're gonna go enchant some books i
haven't done that
yet since that came out so we're gonna
go to the blaze farm and i'll probably
just do
a whole bunch of them off camera and
we'll see what we get
that didn't work out too well
so i think i got a bunch of books around
we can use
i'll probably just afk at my blaze farm
come on
hello can they not open the door
no they can't they keep stepping on it
too quick
oh sorry guys i can't let you out it's
you're breaking the signal
oh well enjoy your time in there
you know that was a big mistake uh
getting them in that room because
i don't have any damage potions and i
have to brew some and now i have to
listen to that
while i brew my potions how lovely
i don't know man your plan sounds a
little crazy but it might work
we should try it uh you said you brew
some up
all right i'll try them out you might
want to step back this could be
dangerous
yeah yeah there she's good youtube yeah
okay
nope i'm clicking defense speed
oh that was beautiful wasn't it
all right guys tell me what you think of
this idea actually i've been
mentioning this to a few people how cool
would it be
to have splash potions that you can
actually throw
crazy right you know what i mean like uh
where you could charge up your throw and
throw them further because the way
they are right now if you're running and
you throw a potion you're gonna hit
yourself
if they had a charge up effect like the
boat is
you know that could be pretty cool and
maybe you could throw it 20 blocks at
full charge or something
make them a little bit more useful
because as they are right now
that didn't do anything all right well i
got my potions let's head on over to the
blaze farm
and here we are at the duo blaze farm
once again it's been a long time since i
last used this thing actually i've been
using the
the enderman farm mostly lately but
uh today i thought this would work out
perfect because i actually have a bunch
of
paperwork i need to do at my desk here
so i can
just be afk and have this running
and it'll give me something fun to do as
i do my paperwork here because every
so often i can check it and
and see what i get from the enchantments
uh hopefully get a silk touch today
you can tell how long it's been like uh
where was that
yeah look signs aren't stacked it's like
man living in the stone age stone ages
over here
i was here and i had my full chanting
book set up here like all
all 30 bookshelves i moved them to a
little bit more convenient spot for
today anyway just a temporary setup over
here
i got an anvil there was no anvil here
even
and i'm going to try to repair some
stuff too
i'm going to store my books in here and
i'll probably
well i guess i could do one right away
can i just drop these off
i do like this farm i like it more than
the enderman farm actually
but it is a little bit slower
at the convenience you don't you can use
it while afk
kind of okay so i think
just we'll do one book to start off with
i'm gonna do all level 30s to begin with
anyway
knock back to oh boy not off to the best
start
and i'll probably do well until my
paperwork's done i guess
so here i go and i'll let you see what
we get
oh that's a lot of blazes let's get rid
of them
in a very leggy nature here so i've been
at this for
i think three to four hours now i got my
work done here
uh just every 20 to 30 minutes i check
in
and get rid of these terrible guys it's
actually pretty loud
and yeah i got a whole bunch of books
enchanted this is going to be our last
run though
finally finished my work
oh man
isn't that crazy it's really laggy
the first time but then it speeds up
although i am recording this time so
maybe it's
worse i'm at three frames oh man
oh man it's laggy oops went over
so yeah i i have mixed feelings about
these books i've gotten a few good ones
but a lot of
crummy ones so far well not crummy but
not as good as if i would just regularly
enchant stuff i think
but this is the only way you can get
certain features on your weapons
by the way i was like working three four
hours on this
on this project i need it for tonight
and i went to
i was like rushing rushing the time
started early took longer than i thought
but i kind of forced through it got it
done
with like 15 to 30 minutes done 30
minutes to spare
i was happy you know went to print it
and the printer was out of ink
so it didn't matter i'll have to
it's not a big deal but yeah i wasn't
able to actually finish it today
technically because i wasn't able to
print it oh it's frustrating
oh we got another thorns that's i think
that's my second one now
i should maybe try that out today
although there's i do want to work on
the rail line for the nether today i
think
a little bit 24 25
26 27
all right what are we
to get still haven't gotten my silk
touch power three
and there's probably not enough for
another level here or another enchant so
i'll show you what we got
it's a lot of books isn't it yeah i've
been here a while
knock back two flame one protection
three efficiency four smite four
sharpness three thorn stew that's a good
one
efficiency three being of arthropods
four sharpness three respiration three
that that one's kind of good actually
dial protection four
power four power three looting two
looting two
protection three knock back two back two
fire aspect one
power four efficiency four knock back
two
infinity one efficiency four feather
falling four that's a good one
sharpness three three three power four
efficiency three power four efficiency 3
power 4
smite 4 efficiency 4 fire protection 3
efficiency 4 power 3
thorns 2 and yeah
so not too bad not too bad but
i was a little disappointed there was no
looting threes in that
there was a lot of knockbacks
and you know what i really wanted
actually was unbreaking three
i don't know how the level affects
things i've heard rumors that
a lower level actually works better for
getting silk touch
but i think it's only slightly better
and
if you don't get silk dutch you get
something that you're probably not going
to want so
it's better to do level 30s from what
i've heard
although this is my first time doing it
so i don't know too much about it
uh i wonder i think you can combine the
books too
including two looting two with an anvil
oh maybe not i thought you could
okay well i think we're done here let's
go do something else
actually before we go we are going to
get ourselves a working pick because i
don't want to use
this on netherrack so
uh just a little tip for you guys in
case you didn't know
like if you were to repair this pick
with diamonds
you would need three would get you up to
that it's not quite fully repaired 28
levels
four would get it repaired all the way
but it costs 33 levels
or if you just use a brand new
unenchanted pick which costs three
diamonds
23 levels so that's the way i'm going
[Music]
our plan now is to work on the track
system for the nether hub here for just
a little bit
uh this is the nether hub so our
idea before we have 10 destination
selector
things here
i forgot where that came up so we select
our destination
and our cart gets sent there and the
idea was we were trying to
trying to send information
over a long distance without using
redstone wiring
or anything like that the plan was to
use the spacing
between two minecarts to tell
our rail line system where we want to
stop
at um because it's it's a way
of sending information over a long
distance the space between two mine
carts
now in order for it to work we need to
keep the minecarts relatively close
together
like we don't want one of them falling
hundreds of blocks behind the other one
want them on each other's tail
so to do that we either have well we we
have two options
on how to do that we can either use
power rails all the way
which would be expensive we'd better
we'd be
better just to use redstone signals
probably if we if we went for that
option
although i'm not sure how far redstone
would actually work
if it's going to unloaded chunks uh
what we want to do though is try to get
a mob in the cart so that the cart moves
the same speed as when we're in the
carts
and uh we need to choose a mob that
doesn't despawn ideally so
a passive mob would be good or a
villager but chickens are what we're
going to go with because
if something ever happens then we can
easily spawn another one with an egg
this was the track design we were going
with something like this
i never did finish my thought with it
though
but after working on the minecraft
uh rail system i found a style i really
like so i think we'll do that here too
which is actually very oh no oh he's
close
[Music]
dude it's right there it's actually very
close to what we had here
he's going to harass us
see you soon
those are a few blocks we're never
getting back
all right come on
oh that hurt
[Music]
oh i carry a bow with me i just don't
carry arrows with me
uh yeah we had a three wide fence
two too high and then this border around
it
on my drag server and then this was
half a block down and that was a half a
block up
so it's pretty much the same look i
think that's what we're going to go with
for our track but i think we got to go
to a creative world
we don't have to but it would be a lot
easier if we went to creative world to
figure out a few things with
the the mobs so let's do that
uh the issue that we gotta
work out is if uh
we gotta manage the mine carts like if
i'm if i take a
my mine cart and a chicken to another
destination
and then we don't come back through that
destination how do we get the chicken
back from there you know
so i'm not really sure how to deal with
that problem
but we'll try to work something out
alrighty guys here we are in a wonderful
beautiful
creative world here
that's so awesome uh generally speaking
by the way i tend to prefer
uh planning and you know figuring things
out in vanilla still
like that that applies to my lp that
applies to minecraft
and even feed the beast everything i i
do i pretty much
do in vanilla or in you know the actual
survival game
uh there are a few exceptions of course
but the one that i
pretty much always make the exception
for is when i'm working with mobs
like uh then i pretty much always will
do it in creative because they can be
really
frustrating to figure out
mechanics and that without spawn egg so
that's why we're here
uh with the our track it's going to be
really hard to
get working the way i want it to but
i think we got to build a couple things
here at i don't know if we have time to
do it all today but
i think we need a chicken
buffer we need a chicken loader we need
a chicken recycler
and possibly if we want to get real
fancy
a minecart buffer and an egg buffer
so those those five things are on my
mind what do i mean when i say that i'll
i'll break it down uh the chicken
recycler
is when a a chicken arrives at a stop
we probably just want to put him off in
an area so that
when we need him again he's ready and
available
a chicken loader and buffer thing
is if there is no chicken at the stop
for some reason then we need to create
one and put in a mine cart so
let's work on that first of all here how
are we going to do it
uh chicken buffer chicken buffer let's
get some glass
and i'll probably be fumbling around
here so just bear with me
uh we probably could do
this still i think if we
i think we need to pick whoa that was a
weird word stutter
i think we can pick up chickens through
corners still
but we'll just actually
instead of using chicken spawn eggs i'm
going to try randomly throw in eggs
just so this is more realistic
we do get yeah there we go okay so this
is our chicken buffer just a little
holding area
for chickens can we pick up through
corners still
yes we can okay
now i think there's a good chance if
they're not right in the corner
yeah it won't pick it up so we might
need for our buffer
some pistons to get them into position
that's our first step get out of here
sorry chicken it's not your place
uh this will have to be a solid block
because we'll need yeah we'll need
a power rail here
to get the guy out of the way sorry
fireworks i'll miss you right in my face
it's exactly where i need to place the
block he's just sitting there waiting
okay i'm gonna time i'm gonna set up a
little redstone off camera here i think
i gotta
do a monostable circuit that will pulse
one of these and then have another one
go and kind of stay out so
here i go with that
okay well we hit a big problem already
it's trying to set this up so that if
there is at least
one chicken in there it will definitely
get picked up in our mine cart that that
was the goal here
where'd he go
what the heck oh he is there
the problem is it doesn't seem to push
the chicken
properly sometimes the first time i did
it didn't push a chicken at
all that time it worked
interesting very weird
very weird guys
pistons don't work like they used to
that's for sure
chicken let's try this one more time
you got moved a little bit but not
it's not us it's not doing what it's
supposed to do though
we'll leave it that so that's not a
reliable way of doing it for sure
problem solved i switched to sticky
pistons and they
they're a lot more sticky they work uh
they move the chicken actually which is
what we want
uh even with the chicken moving though
if the chicken's in the corner it
doesn't always get picked up there's
also a requirement of
motion needed and the minecart will just
bump the chicken
when it's moving a lot of times so i i
need to try make the chicken move at
this
precise time the minecart pulls up here
which is
kind of weird uh
so yeah the chicken's in the middle
well actually i just said my cart wasn't
even moving was it
anyway timing is important is what i'm
trying to say so i have to make sure i
time everything correctly
also uh i'm using a detector rail here
i'll probably switch this
to a that uh directional trick i showed
you on the minecraft
episode where i built the rail line that
this is another
practical practical use for it right
here because it goes over it twice
and uh
oh what's that
i see what's happening i was wondering
what happened to my glass block
it's pushing out and that one's pushing
i see
so i'll have to time that correctly too
let's try it again
nope see what i mean it doesn't always
work
now the timing is different so it
doesn't work
but anyway i can make it worth doing it
that way i just have to make sure i time
it correctly and i'll try to condense it
as close as possible this detector rail
so this track doesn't have to be as long
so that will work as our chicken loader
i have not figured out how to tell if
there's a chicken
in there at the moment because if
there's no chicken we need dispensers to
shoot eggs and then we'll create new
chickens that way
but if i put a pressure plate there
these pistons are going to destroy it
when they move
uh chickens are too small to use trip
wires
so it's kind of a problem isn't it yes
indeed
okay even if we push a chicken right to
the very corner
it won't step on the pressure plate on
the other side
so we can't use a trick like that
another idea had is to have a clock
start going
once the cart goes over this detector
rail
and the cart will just stop there and
the clock will keep going shooting eggs
until a chicken goes into the cart and
these pistons will keep firing as well
so
thought of that doesn't seem like it's
gonna work though because the chicken
pushes the mine carts
instead of going in it you stupid
chicken
um
what else could we do we could prob
well another thing we could do is make
it
do that clock thing like i said where it
will keep dispensing eggs
then the chickens when it does create a
chicken it will float down into a trip
wire
and that will tell it to stop dispensing
eggs but we might get more than one
chicken
in that time and
the second time we try to get a chicken
it's still going to do the same thing
even though there's a chicken there
ready to go
unless we i don't know because if we do
this
the chicken will go in right away and
the clock won't go for very long the
second time right
well no because it's going to keep going
until it goes through the tripwire
or until we send the cart back
i don't know i'll have to think about
this for a bit uh maybe one more thing
we could do
today quickly is i had this idea for
a minecart buffer because normally
with dispensers this is an idea that's
going to take me a while to figure out
by the way there's a lot to it
um i'm just doing it for the challenge
mostly not
because it's a practical system uh
although it might be who knows maybe if
i can perfect it enough it could
actually be good look at all those
failed experiments
normally you only have room for nine
mine carts
right uh it would be cool if i could
stock it
like four or five dispensers full so i'm
gonna try set something up for that
okay we're getting somewhere here this
is a rough
demonstration and example of my
idea so instead of having
room for just nine mine carts we now
have room for 18
and this is modular too so we could have
as many as we want
so here's the demonstration we've got
detector rail
so if there's a mine cart in this
dispenser it'll go over that detector
rail
and then it does some sort of and gate
trickery here
if there is a minecart you'll notice
this torch does not
come on
that is important we're down to two
last one and now
the other one comes on so that's
that's the basic idea and we could do
that for as many dispensers as we want
but now i want to compact it into a more
you know practical way because with this
this is kind of messy
so hopefully i can get some kind of
circular dispenser setup thing
instead of a linear style and that
should make it smaller
ta-da here it is uh i ran out of
recording time for today so this is as
far as i got
might be able to make it smaller if i
spent more time but
yeah it seems to work pretty good i got
two mine carts in each of these so let's
see it's that's a total of 27. it's a
triple buffer
or triple minecart dispenser so it goes
through that one
that one's empty now goes through that
one
oops careful
careful okay so that second one is empty
now goes to the third one
and that's that's what we got so i might
use that
with our chicken set up if i want a
bigger minecart buffer because when
if if there's no mine cart in the
chicken recycler like if there's no
chicken and mine cart combo
i'll have to like we were messing around
with there create the chicken from an
egg
from a dispenser but we also need to
create a minecart from somewhere so that
will come from
a dispenser set up probably
unless i find some way to distribute
minecarts evenly
across my whole system but i'm not sure
how to do that
uh and this is the wiring so it goes
into this block the pulse
uh i had to be really careful with this
because there is that glitch with
dispensers where they can get
triggered if up if redstone updates
while it's powered
in in the area so
there's each of these has two wire
things
the one from the detector goes to this
block
and that block there prevents
or keeps these wires from connecting
but it goes to this block then
the wire here and to the left
powers this redstone torch and then
there's also an
inverted signal here on a two-tick delay
that goes to the same one
and then from that it goes to
this and then the cycle continues again
uh i think this is directional though
this setup
so if you want to make sure it works
every direction just make
this power rail there slope downwards
and it can be a little tricky to set the
rails like this
so do something like that and you might
even be able to squeeze in a fourth one
somehow
if you do that
all right well that was fun we are back
home here in our lp
world i did start our tunnel a little
bit
didn't get too far ran out of blocks but
something like this i think is what
we're gonna go for
iron bars uh lighting in the ceiling
possibly or
behind iron bars we could also put
lighting although
in the open areas where there's no
netherrack walls
we won't be able to put lighting behind
the iron bars so it would make more
sense to put it in the ceiling
or even in the floor we could hide it
but this design is gas proof
yeah yeah it is it's gas proof
and what was it going to say
should prevent zombie pigmen from
spawning fairly well
if we put if we do it like we have here
where we have a s
there there oh i use the stair
interesting
it's not a full block because that's
two blocks on each side of the rail at
least which is
decent zombie pigmen spawn on the track
though it's gonna cause a lot of trouble
cool well let's go read the comments
guys and we'll call it an end for today
hey guy hey hey look at me hey
hello it's been a long time you remember
me
strong silent type you know
nothing's changed here you lazy bum what
have you been doing
looks exactly the same
let's check on them make sure they're
still here
yeah there's one there's the other guy
okay so we still got our two villagers
here
uh still thinking of plans for this
place what i want to do
i think the mistake i made with this
place is trying to make a big open area
underground and
and to make it worse i made these very
large buildings
for the villagers so it's a double
whammy what i need to do
i'm gonna make a big open area here and
then start making narrow
like tunnels or caves with smaller
houses and i think that branch off from
this
i think that's what i need to do to fix
this project
but yeah once i start it i can't stop
because i'm going to open up all these
mine shafts and that and zombies will
come flooding in here
so i have to be careful when i start it
but yeah let's move on to
today's question
dear etho ever since i started watching
your videos i wanted to know
how you got on minecraft minecraft
server
ah this is this is a good question i
could talk about this for a long time
actually
uh i'll try to be quick though
the way it started as you know i've been
watching co-star for a very long time
and just a side note co-star is back yay
really glad he's back making videos
again so you might want to check him out
if you haven't
again um
watching co-star for a very long time
eventually
he uh he started this race for the wool
game with himself in a video on one team
and good and bwo on
the second team and when i saw that man
that was
i loved that video i could hardly wait
till the next one
and it was awesome is the first time i
ever saw a pvp game
in minecraft vex's race for the wall
and it was like a seven episode thing it
was crazy like
two three hours to play one game of race
for the wall it's changed a lot since
then
but awesome awesomely entertaining like
i i loved it so from that is like man i
really want to play this
it looks great these guys are awesome
they're you know
people i've wanted to always play with
well not good and bw i had no idea who
they were but i watched their video
and they were a bunch of funny guys
that's for sure
so i was excited to play with them all
and i think
i think i was discussing it with static
and dot dm
because those are about i didn't have
too many contacts at the time like i was
a very
to to myself kind of guy i think static
and document i talked to about though
about wanting to play with them and
like challenge them to a game
and i think static actually was the one
that asked them
uh he took the initiative and co-star
made a video where he
accepted it unexpectedly
and yeah we we got joker hd in on our
team we
played we did terrible good had this
idea all along apparently where he
wanted to make a tournament and a few
other people
joined in on the second second round we
played
um but yeah we had fun playing together
it was great
good times um said our goodbyes a few
weeks later
time like time passed and i think it was
around the time
good restarted the minecraft server like
siri season three with the new map the
one we have now
and i was watching that from the
beginning and it looked like fun
at the time i wasn't playing on any
servers and it looked
like something i wanted to do so
me not being the very forward guy i
never asked to join the server because
i don't know i i felt i probably could
have got on if i asked
but i wanted to be asked i guess like i
didn't want to ask and
always have that in the back of the head
maybe i'm not wanted here
or as wanted as is if good had actually
asked me
i guess uh i would have felt better
about being on the server if i was asked
i should say
that's that's the way i can sum that up
so i never asked to get on the server
but
eventually after a couple weeks of me
watching them play
uh through their videos uh good
actually asked me to join the server on
skype
kind of out of the blue i think it was i
can't remember if dot dot dot dm got on
before me not really sure because he
didn't really make any videos at first
um i think he may have gotten on and
then within that week i got asked
to or something like that something like
that happened i can't remember
but yeah that's kind of how it came
came to be and i've been on the server
ever since
and if you want on the server i am very
sorry for you
whoa dude
good thing that wasn't a creeper um yeah
we can't really let
any more people on unless you meet
certain criteria
namely you got to be friends with a lot
of us
and you need to kind of have experience
with the youtube thing and be good at
what you do
and if you have to if you have to ask if
you want to join the server
you can't be on the server you'll know
if if you can be on the server i should
say
i don't know we can't just let everyone
on though because there's only so many
server spots and it would just cause
problems so
yeah but anyway that's i i'm rambling
sorry
that's that's the story thank you for
watching the episode everyone i hope you
enjoyed it
i will talk to you guys again next time
and i will see you later bye bye