[Music]
hi
everybody this is etho thank you for
joining me again and welcome back
to the nether here i'm still here
been doing that stuff i said i was going
to last episode
i converted this side of the blaze farm
so it's the same as this one
and i got rid of the pistons blocking
the viewing area here
looks a lot better now again and it
doesn't seem to affect things much like
the efficiency it works
just fine without them so that's good
glad i did that um
a few people told me just to put glass
where i have those pressure plates and
stuff
thing is that is actually spawning space
so we don't want to block that off
uh like they said just to do it so
they'll fall straight down but
that is a lot of the area we don't want
to lose otherwise we'll get
lower rates from this which we
definitely don't want it's running
very quickly with these two going
i am actually losing it probably at
least half of them though from this
conveyor belt so we need to add a
regulator to it
because they keep suffocating
and jamming up because there's just too
many going through
at uh uncontrolled times so we need to
either put a clock on it or
some sort of delay system so that
that doesn't happen anyway
this is the big change here thing i'm
really happy about this is the new
killing and holding area for the blaze
you can see they swim up here there's
actually a hole open where they could
possibly shoot us through here but the
thing is
uh there's a little bit of a delay
before they can start shooting us
if they see us and they swim up before
they get the chance so it's not
dangerous at all
or at least it doesn't seem to be
i did play around with having like a
faucet style thing here where they would
swim up
go to the left and then fall down into a
second tube with no lava in
that didn't work out so good because
they really don't want to move those two
blocks over
all that well and you can't really set
up a piston thing to
force them to either and if i'm getting
low frame rates because there's a lot of
them here
they're gathering pretty quick um
yeah but this works really well there's
basically three pistons to control this
thing
we have one down here and then there's
uh two together up here um
yeah this one here is to cut off the
lava
so that when we kill the blaze none of
their drops will
get burnt or anything or xp won't get
burnt from the lava
that's important this one is the gate
it keeps any more blaze from coming up
and it also gives them
something to stand on and then this one
here is the crusher
it does suffocation damage to them
so i'm thinking i'll have two buttons
i'll probably
have one on the right here and one on
the left
uh the right button when we press it it
will
cause all three of these pistons to go
or to extend
the same time so this one would close
so i'm going to go down and at the same
time this one too
it would be hooked to a timer this
pressure and after a certain amount of
time
it will come back up
lava will still be cut off
and then the idea is to get them down to
one hit kill here
of course i didn't time this right
and then i'd be free to kill them all
i'd be free to hit them meanwhile we
still have more blaze below
gathering there's a second lava source
there
once i get all my stuff and this is
empty
then i would hit the second button on
the left here probably
and that will cause this to reset so
this piston will come up here let the
lava down i have this pressure plate as
a safety so that
it won't come pouring out here at the
moment
and then also this one will retract
the new blaze with full health will come
back up
well they don't actually have full
health they tend to take damage from the
conveyor belt here
so we'll be a little bit inconsistent i
might have to use stone
swords to kill them to make up for that
uh have them as a one-hit kill
another thing i'm thinking i'll probably
do is put
a dispenser right here maybe
and uh
fill that with uh poison potions poison
splash potions and i might use that
instead of the crusher at times
and that will get them all down to one
hit kill
even if they have inconsistent health
so i think that'll work out good too as
a second option of killing them
and yeah it's nice and compact i like it
turned out very well happy with this
design
and it looks pretty cool too one thing
i'm a little bit concerned about is i
think some of this light can actually
make it to
the this here because it's light level
15 then 13
there 11 9
7 5
yeah so like light level three
seeps in from that so i might have to
get rid of some of this glass or
something i don't know
doesn't make a huge difference really
but if i
if i want to be perfect about it i might
consider doing that too
otherwise this is working really well i
just need to add the regulators on the
conveyor belts
and i don't know if i'll do that this
episode i kind of want to go to the
silver
excuse me to the silverfish farm right
now and finish uh
getting that working so i'm gonna do
that
now and i might see there
all right here we are at the silverfish
again at the stronghold
and all seems to be working well this
thing is glitching up every
so often it's very rare but it does
happen so we're gonna try
uh fix it so it's perfect today
uh also with the blaze farm i have tried
logging out when there's
over 100 mobs in that too and they don't
glitch through the glass when i log back
in which is uh
really good to know too seems to be log
out safe
is he
anyway the problem with this is i don't
have a long enough delay
on the piston that goes up here
uh it needs to be a little bit longer
because it just goes up and down
up down real quick it's actually i think
uh what happens is this extends
you got one tick pulse there one there
and i think it's just a two
um what is it
yeah just a two tick pulse that this
stays up for this i don't think is
actually doing anything now that i think
of it
and i i believe i've tried extending
this
let's hope there's some repeaters here
we can try it
i've tried extending that a little bit
longer
down there oh please tell me i didn't
take them back
torches
all right i'm gonna make some
all right so i think what i tried before
is i had more of these
uh to try extend the pulse longer this
is like a cheat way of doing it
an easy way of doing it that's usually
pretty compact
so that should make it up to four tick
false there
but i think it was a double extending
oh and also glitching out you see how
the block got stuck up there
so that's not really working
so we need to make a proper uh
oh boy did i bring anything to kill him
no i didn't
that's great um we need a
a proper pulse sustainer extender here
we need it probably at least one second
long
so that's what i'm going to do but first
i'm going to go
to the end and get some mark speed to
enchant the sword
so i'm doing a level 50 enchantment on
the sword because i mainly want to get
looting 3
and at level 40 you have a 14.5 percent
chance of getting looting 3 and at level
50.
you have a 25.6 so it's almost
double the chance of it at level 50
and it's only about a time and a half
more xp
compared to level 40. so uh overall
it works out cheaper if that's what
you're going for so here we go
and i got robbed absolutely robbed
great
okay so we are actually in a creative
world right now i was having a problem
that i needed to figure out
redstone related and it was a lot easier
to figure it out here
has to do with these uh pulse sustainers
or pulse lengtheners or extenders the
minecraft
wiki page calls them pulse sustainers
and it shows two different ways of
building them
one like i had before there that
doesn't really work with short pulses
like i
also had there so we needed to replace
that with something
else and this is the other design the
wiki shows
using a piston rs nor latch
so pretend this piston here is the one
that pushes the silver fish up
okay so uh a pulse sustainer turns a
quick
on off pulse or
yeah lay a quick on off pulse into a
long
on off tight pulse
that's what it does see how long this
piston stays up for
uh the problem i'm having though with
this
is after it goes down like that there is
a
equally long time where you can't
reactivate this
so once this goes down if i give it a
quick pulse
it doesn't come back up it's still going
has to wait for
the repeaters to become unpowered again
and that's basically the problem i need
to figure out and i came up with the
solution it's actually pretty simple
here's another way of doing it with the
redstone or a snore latch
this is the same thing same problem
here's our piston to represent the
silverfish because
as soon as this goes down silverfish can
enter the blocks again
and it'll send out another pulse almost
instantly like within two ticks they'll
send out another pulse if that happens
so it's up down
it doesn't stay up when i do it like
that because it's still powered
these repeaters need to become unpowered
before it it's resettable
and if you know like my potion room the
door for it
after it opens and closes there's like a
two second
delay before i can open it again that's
the same problem i'm having there
so that the trick to it
i found is to create a branch off here
and connect this to here
and now look what happens
stays up way longer and it you can
reactivate it pretty much instantly
after
uh so it's actually doubling up the
length of the repeaters this way
so it's even it's twice as compact
repeater wise
and yeah it just works really well
so if i
if i was to make this longer
than this uh what happens i can't
remember
it's fine if you make this longer than
than this so what the time it takes for
it to reset
the our snore
it like creates a clock
so that's no good so
yeah anyway i got it figured out this is
going to be very useful for me in the
future because i use these pulse
extenders quite often
and this is a problem i always have and
this is so much cleaner
all right back to the real world
okay so i've made that change now i got
the pulse extender on
i haven't tried it yet i just finished
it i think with that this will be
working perfectly now i hope unless i
overlook something
uh so yeah this wire goes down from
the bud switch there's basically no
delay on it
and that goes right to
the piston below the silverfish like it
did before
and that happens before the smooth the
new smooth stone
goes to where the silver fish are so it
has to be quicker than that which it is
and then it branches off to our extender
here
and i just have um
just eight ticks here which doubles up
to being
1.6 seconds plus
these here as well so it should be long
enough
be close to two seconds of a delay
don't want it too long there's no point
it's too long
i just need to give the cobbles or the
smooth stone generator time to make
new stone basically that's the main
that's the slowest thing in all this
that we need to wait for so
oh that's not good
what happened
all right let's see it goes up
they're falling through somehow
always another problem there just might
be too many in there i guess
it's like 50.
it might be jammed it's
jammed man can't win
it does do what i wanted to though stays
up
oh there's a little hole
here for them
come on fallen yes
yeah i don't know
there's no real way to prevent them from
glitching through blocks
and
hmm i don't know what to do about that
oh the lag whenever they fall down that
hole it just lags the game like crazy
for some reason is working
oh where'd you come from
i guess it just can't handle a bunch of
them at once
that's its only flaw
because they glitch through the blocks
that's it's doing what i wanted to do oh
it's like double extending for some
reason
yeah you see that i got something wrong
here
okay i'll play with it a bit and i'll
start recording again
okay i figured out what was going on i
think uh there's this glitch in the game
it's been in for a few patches now where
redstone torches will just
burn out and then that's it
you can't fix them you can't if you
replace them they just keep burning out
you can't there's no real adjustment you
can make to fix them the only way of
fixing them
that i know of is to quit the game and
then reload the world and then they
should work again so that's what i did
and it seems to
i think this torch was burnt out maybe
and it seems to work okay now
stays up it doesn't double extend
like it was doing before i want to try
uh get rid of these
i don't know if they're actually
necessary
just have wire there oh
hmm
hmm i didn't expect that
okay unless it's
glitched out again
no it's good okay but i think i'm still
gonna have that problem with the
silverfish
going through the block maybe
i will uh watch it i'm gonna turn it
back on here and watch it for a little
bit
all right i've been sitting here letting
letting them build up and we got
24 probably 24.
uh we're gonna try this again
and again this is like worst case
scenario that we would have this many
uh normally that would never happen
unless for some reason
i was within tracking range of them for
a long period of time
so this is
ready there should be a block here
and i think i should have one
okay can i break this
i think i should make that a solid block
otherwise they can
go through the glass and one there
and let's just hope it works
see
so if that happens uh
at least it kills them
or hurts them uh they don't glitch
through and
come attack me
i got a few in this pit oh they do go in
i think they entered from underneath the
cobble
possibly i'm gonna put one more here
if i can this is just a test size doing
to see if they can
enter a block from underneath it
they're not going to let me put it
go down there
i don't know what i'm doing here um
yeah yeah
mess this up
oh no don't come out okay there's at
least
one in there can we get another one good
now if they enter any one of these that
means they can enter a block from
underneath
and these guys i don't know what they're
doing if they're still entering
ah they just keep giving me trouble
silverfish okay jammed up again somehow
don't understand why
you would think yet a block pushing into
them would move them but nope
yeah it was jammed again i just can't
because they if they get stuck in that
block they'll be able to enter
the other one anyway so
ah yeah
a few people have done other ways of
doing this too
zuma that's the way you say his name he
created a minecarts uh bottleneck
to make them hopefully enter one at a
time i think that would jam up too
though
uh under a heavy load on rare occasions
and also jl has did a pretty fancy thing
i don't know if his is uh stable i think
he was having trouble too
i don't know how you could make this
stable if this isn't working
oh well
i'll think about it for a bit more um
did they enter oh
actually they're probably oh they did
yep
so they entered from underneath the
block so any side they can enter from
i've seen them enter from above too
cool well
i think i'm going to end the episode
here this last little bit was a little
boring i'm sorry
uh but that's this part of this
next episode we will
probably build something
the reason i want to finish this is
because
i really i'm about 90 sure i'm gonna
build my storage room directly above
here
and also the mob system i have it
figured out in my head quite a bit
already
so once we start that i think it'll be
pretty quick progress
which is good and i think it'll be
really neat um
i just wish this was stable
oh well i'll think about it i'll say
goodbye for today thanks for watching
until next time