[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody welcome
back once again check this out if you if
you didn't know what was going on here
he didn't have a trained eye and you
would almost think just just maybe I was
standing on the glass right now it's
it's almost like an optical illusion
isn't it
and I'm like some kind of giant maybe
maybe not
anyway so last episode guys we built
this gold farm from scratch
pretty much finished it all in one shot
it was a project but we got it done then
after that I left my team running
overnight just to see if it would have
any problems or anything like that and
oh my goodness we are so rich now look
at this we got this all filled up look
look what I got my inventory here a
stack of gas tears I've never held a
stack of gas tears like this before and
not in creative mode got zombie flesh
there if we go down and check what's
what's in our chests down here some more
gold in this one is there any more gas
appears there's a couple they're
actually getting a decent amount of
gunpowder - oh look at this more gas and
more gas - yes
oh it's so crazy and that's not it of
course so this injection system thing is
actually working out really well
where I basically have five of each item
in the hopper and then when the the
minecart leaves the station here
after finishing unloading it will pick
up one of each of these and that seems
to keep it picking up the items I want
and ignoring like the gold sorts and
every everything else that's kind of
junk zombie flesh in there look at that
isn't that crazy we have over six stacks
of gas tears
from this farm oh man Oh today
donut pick up gunpowder I just not and
of course the main reason for the farm
is the gold and we have gotten over
three stacks of blocks of gold profit
here so we're gonna be using these on
beacons mostly that's that's basically
what I'm planning on using them for and
all in all it's working out good I do
think we need to get a second minecart
picking things up though it's not quite
doing its job it's I'm guessing about
1/3 to 1/4 of things Rd spawning because
it runs out of inventory space so I'll
probably set up some holding system for
a second minecart
but we'll do that some other time I want
to get out of here I haven't left this
area since last episode and yeah I think
it's I think it's time stretch my legs
go go see the world
Nazi world see the world so I guess I
will was I supposed to bring things oh
this is probably fine I guess I'll see
you at the man cave or some other area
okay guys so one of the first things we
need to do here is switch out the beacon
at the man cave with gold blocks we have
to reclaim the iron and the emeralds we
had here now that we have the gold did
that do it yeah I think it turned back
on sweet that's cool got that one
working and we still have oh it's is
just about enough for another beacon
currently you need like two and a half
stacks of blocks mmm I'm tempted this
beacon doesn't quite reach all the way
in the man cave you know what I locked
myself in here didn't I I think I did
all right I'm gonna go out this way
totally built that the wrong way from I
went down and up instead of up today
you know it's a funny thing perspective
when I built this thing originally I
thought it was the coolest thing ever
and so many of you told me I was wrong
and now that when I see it today it is
so ugly yep uh-huh
so this is about it right here that
about about this line I think if we
cross over to about here yeah now we got
beacon effects so a big portion of the
man cave is actually not under under the
speed effect and I find it so annoying I
want to run around quick all the time
and when I come come to this area I have
to go solo so we're gonna set up another
beacon some somewhere between here oh
that will cover the second half of the
cave that we've expanded on too before I
do that though today's a random things
episode I think I want to do like lots
of random things just just kind of in
that mood first up we're gonna try to
get a new new mule here I I want to set
up the the mule army sometime soon
I'm gonna build the shuffle shuffle
thing the horse shuffler in the nether
today or two of them or three I don't
know we'll see
okay you they don't you know it's been
so long since I did this I totally
forget how it works all right they they
need their own room here you and you
that's my quick horse and my amazing
donkey cart guy and we have the fastest
mule in the West right here all right
you're fully grown now I think so
oh man this guy looked all there because
he was right in my face all right
right away he's got 12 hearts I
basically just want a really quick mule
for a bunch of them this guy doesn't
seem all that fast so I'm gonna be
breeding a few of them today and I'm
gonna pick the quickest ones and we will
use them for transporting stuff well
hello there oh look at all the bats
what's this
there's redstone down here this is the
laboratory why don't I have a ladder
here
okay so our new beacon is going right
here guys this is about 100 blocks away
from from the other beacon so they have
a radius of 50 50 plus 50 hundred blocks
so this should be a good spot for it I
would say and we're just gonna have the
one for right now because we were short
on gold blocks but we can easily get
some more later and I mostly just want
the speed boost anyway oh yeah let's
make sure it works
yep oh that is so cool a lot of times I
have to run between here and the
stronghold base to so this will make me
be able to get around a lot quicker so
next up on our list here I want to do
the horse Schaeffler stuff today in the
in our nether hub so I figure originally
I was considering putting them in the
corners here or somewhere like that but
I think it'll throw off the circular
supersymmetric room we have here so I'm
gonna put them over here instead I think
I'm gonna make a spot like here and the
horse Schaeffler will be probably one
one block back here and like like this
basically I think that would be good and
I want one at this end of the track and
one at the far end of the track as well
and at every stop so if we don't tape
the rails we can park our horse or our
mule wherever we we end up here okay
everyone so I got one of them set up
right now we're gonna try it out here I
want you to have chest
will you accept chest how do you do this
again I thought was shift right click oh
just right click okay cool you're gonna
help me out here - you're gonna carry
potions let's
yeah we're up to like four or five mules
now I just have just made another baby
one there we want some more of these oh
you know what we're gonna have trouble
getting to the nether aren't we
here let's grab one of one of these - I
don't have the most convenient nether
portal and I actually don't have any
like a secondary one either so there we
go that's what I want all right course
you're gonna need this or mule I always
call them horses so we got to go through
the creeper face can you do it
this isn't gonna work all right
how about now nope one more block did I
not I didn't place that in the right
place okay
I wish you could ender pearl while I'm
on a horse just gonna catch fire - all
right come on there we go perfect not a
problem at all all right we got him here
yeah he's good he's good he's on fire
but he's he's cool all right so actually
we're both on fire it looks like he has
that diamond the shoulders doesn't it
that's pretty funny man while building
this thing the most zombie pigmen in the
world just were bugging me the whole
time like they all team into the wiring
all right we're gonna flip the leaver
drop you off snip it again and let's try
cycle them very good and perfect
yeah so that's doing exactly what I want
let me show you the insides here take
these away I've added a hopper and the
chest singing back here for speed
potions because I think a lot of the
times I'm going to want to go pretty
quick
oops here let's take these out he only
holds 15 inventory spots and I thought
it was more for some reason food alright
so yeah there's a there's a button here
I get this is closed I think I just
squished his face this is closed you
step back just a little bit and you push
a button there's string in there there
we go hopefully that that hit him pretty
good and it's like five or six minutes
that's with speed potion hey that's not
too bad it's not too bad we should try
to get like the quickest mules we can
possibly get though that would be a fun
goal so you want a really quick horse
and I think it's possible to breed
donkeys so that they're quicker too
although very difficult and if we get a
quick donkey and a quick horse will most
likely end up with pudding mules alright
let me get let me get some more mules in
here so we got this here what do you
guys think of this this little extension
I've built on it's not finished as you
can tell there's another rack all over
the place I was really worried cuz this
thing is pretty tall and if you're like
up close and and you got a tall thing in
your face you can't really see the whole
thing in screen so you kind of have to
back up to get the full effect
hopefully it's not too bad it'll work
out okay
ah man are you kidding me I guess I
never had the water here before did I
probably wasn't wise removing this door
so um donkey is gone he still he still
has some of his wonderful cookies though
ah well I'm glad I'm glad it wasn't this
guy but we don't have a donkey anymore
this is terrible I'm gonna have to get
another one oh and you don't even like
me 'don't you liked me hmm ah you know
what we have all these gasp tears now we
should actually turn this thing on I'm
gonna brew up a bunch of potions right
now because if we ran out of speed ones
I moved them all to the nether there
never thought I would ever ever actually
use this thing like all these all these
chests they have things in write like
they're all they all have some potions
in this one i disabled the regen potions
oh I guess we got a couple in there but
figured I'd never get enough gas steers
to actually use this thing so I put a
leaver in the back somewhere to disable
it I think it might be this thing right
here oh yeah I think that was stopping
the hopper so this guy has helped me out
quite a bit already look look at this he
has discovered he's helped me discover
there's a cave over there unlit cave
that I've missed I wasn't I wasn't even
trying to do it he just he was so
insightful he made me run into here and
suffocates but when I was doing that I
saw I saw what he wanted me to see there
uh-huh so that's actually lowering the
rates of our MOPP system up above here
which like it's pretty close so I should
get over there and light that up and
then this thing will run a lot better so
I found the cave this is our skeleton
grinder that was never set up and I just
dug straight until I hit it let's just
take a moment to light it up together I
actually want to talk to you guys
about oh this should be pretty
interesting to Global Water mobs in this
especially if it's daytime right now
here let's turn the sound down so steam
summer sales guys I bought so many games
this this Steam sale I totally missed
out on it last summer I didn't really
know what it was until later and then I
was really sad but basically every
summer Steam puts a bunch of games on
sale and they'll have new sales every
day and you check it regularly and you
get all kinds of awesome deals so this
time now that I know what it is
I got like over 10 games that I want to
talk to you guys about or just to tell
you about him so I got I'll try to go
through this sort of alphabetically - I
got battleblock theater which I believe
is made by the same guys that make
Castle Crashers the behemoth and I i
haven't played my xbox 360 in a long
time but I tried the pilot of this so
many bats I tried the the trial of it a
long time ago with a with a friend and I
thought it was pretty cool but I haven't
had a chance to the plate yet mostly
James I haven't played yet because I
just got them I got vast Bastion so how
you say it
I think I've seen a video of it looked
kind of interesting but I don't know too
much about it I got broforce it's like
an action platformer type of thing which
played that a little bit it was pretty
fun actually you play is like the
difference like hero like men in black
or mr. t or I'll Chuck Norris all all
these famous like tough guys and yeah
it's pretty cool I like that one I got
Castle Crashers even though I have it on
my xbox
it was under a buck dose I decided to
get it super cheap like 90% off and then
I got the dough don't starve expansion
so hopefully soon I will record that and
put it up on my channel again I know a
lot of you've been asking for its oh we
got a witch down there
I got edge of space I've never heard of
this game either I like all the games
that were on sale I pretty much just
looked at them and stuff
they looked interesting I got turns out
edge of space was made by the same guy
that made terraria and he used the same
artwork in it and I'm kind of interested
in that I don't know if it's gonna be I
doubt it's gonna be as good as terraria
but I'm excited about that one I haven't
played it yet though free Kerbal space
program I got as well I hope we don't
die here that was highly recommended
recommended to me by Z Stowe and I see
I've seen some videos of it it looks
like my kind of game although it it's uh
simply it has a steep learning curve I'm
not sure though haven't tried it I'm
scared to look down at my list here
because I might die okay I'm gonna do it
and we do it magicite I got magicite
that's the game I've played the most so
far I love that game it's it's almost
like spelunky through the platformer
type of thing there's crafting in it
which I like crafting systems and games
it's a roguelike game I was I wasn't
expecting much from that one but it it
turned out to be the favorite one I've
tried so far and got Project Zomboid
played that one a lot too that one's
pretty good
although I after playing it for awhile I
found it became very easy and I wasn't
dying in it anymore so I don't know if
there's difficulty settings I'll have to
look into it some more but you can
basically just run away from the zombies
and they can't get you rogue legacy
is another one I got I've seen a lot of
people stream that game so I'm assuming
it's pretty good but I'm looking forward
to trying it it's a platformer and got
transformers war for Cybertron even
though I had that on Xbox as well that's
that third-person shooter game that I
really like I want to see if there's any
community left to it on the on the PC
version because I I would love to play
that again but on the Xbox version
people aren't playing it really and
finally I got World of Goo because it
was under $1 I don't really like puzzle
games but I know that one was pretty
well received so should be fun to check
out oh and we've reached torches this is
actually there was more unlit here than
I was expecting honestly anyway that's
my little speedo is that the right word
spiel about the games I got hopefully
you guys picked up some - where else
hopefully you saved your money hmm this
is interesting so somewhere in the cave
here there's just these three chests
right obviously I must have placed these
a long time ago I have no idea what's in
them I haven't checked
I'm guessing it's cobble but we will see
- gunpowder
why on earth did I leave these here so
random eventually their chests I might I
must have got them throughout the
abandoned mine shaft or something and I
needed the inventory space so I rather
than tossing them I may have placed them
that's that's what I'm guessing
oh okay everyone so I finished up with
the caving and pretty sure I lit most of
it up it's not all of it seriously this
guy he's still here
when I was working on the wiring in here
like 15 zombie pigmen somehow managed to
mind their way in here
and we're in my way non-stop and there's
still a few of them here one two three
should I do it now I'm not gonna do them
I'm so tempted to hit them not this time
not this time it will distract me so
yeah back to the horse shuffler idea so
we're gonna have a mule and a regular
horse right and depending on which one I
want if I need extra inventory space in
my in my travels I take mr. mule here
and I've read quite a few horses and
quite a few mules so far this guy's
actually pretty quick and this horse I
got here is pretty good too
I may have killed a few because they
were not quite of this superior breed
but this guy he's got 14 hearts I wish
she was just a little bit quicker but
he's not bad and was he a good jumper I
can't remember he's a decent jumper too
yeah so if I just want to go from point
A to point B don't care about picking
stuff up or moving stuff I will take a
horse is a slightly quicker
otherwise I will take a mule and then I
carry stuff oops
I wanted to try it with the potion
whoo that's speed wuns b2 is insanely
quick alright guys so that is gonna do
it for today's episode I got our comment
picked out this one oh look at that pose
right there
these doing the splits this one's pretty
good because it's actually three
questions in one so it goes first off
hey etho have you been paying attention
to the World Cup if you haven't what
have you been watching we'll answer that
first I pretty much haven't watched
television in about five years
personally with eggs with the odd
exception here and there but generally I
don't watch TV anymore so no I haven't
watched the World Cup I haven't really
watched anything too much recently I'm
trying to think oh you know what I
watched recently was prison breakout
from start to finish i watch TV shows on
my computer while I play like Minecraft
or other video games I can't just sit on
a couch and watch TV anymore so I
generally don't watch sports
unless I'm at somebody's place or
something like that and if I am to watch
sports I only have interest in hockey
and tennis and pretty much no interest
in any other sport so yeah to watch
anyway playing is a different thing
second part of the question I haven't
turned my TV on in the year I'm pretty
sure it's uh yeah is is this so much
more entertaining playing video games
than it is to sit on a couch and watch
TV in my opinion especially since you
can watch TV while you play video games
it just doesn't make sense anyway and
also what happened to the minecraft
server so keep up the good work and
don't stop I I can finally talk about
this I've had so many people ask me
about the minecraft server I've wanted
to answer you guys but we as a group
kind of made an agreement that we
wouldn't talk about it too until a
certain point but as you may have heard
that minecraft server is resetting the
vanilla one I of course I'm playing on
the crack pack server so there's gonna
be a reset on July 19th I think is when
the videos will first come out so look
forward to a new season I am going to
try hop on the server and make some
episodes before it resets so just
because it doesn't feel right just for
it to end and not say like a goodbye to
it of some sorts Oh squid just fell so
yeah that's kind of the dealio right now
we got some plans for the next season
should be a lot of fun hopefully and
yeah that's it for today hope you guys
enjoyed the episode and I will see you
again in the next one bye bye
[Music]