well here we go again everybody welcome
welcome back do you do nu nu nu I've
been getting stuff done I've been
working on the mob system a little bit
we're up to two layers now doo doo doo
doo
I found a way to incorporate lighting
into it so I'll be able to turn it on
and off just curious how accurate these
guys are miss to mrs. O third time's a
charm
miss this is it like it's max range
another miss another miss oh right in
the face miss so if you're a long ways
away from them they do miss quite often
like even if you're standing still when
you shoot a net boy okay ah that's one
way of doing it I yes yeah so you can
I'm going to have lighting with this I
found a way to squeeze some wiring in
we're going to use the lamps okay get up
get off that view eat lamps per layer is
what it's going to be we'll go inside
here still haven't put the water in or
anything but this is what it looks like
- of course the day lighting which is
making it extremely bright in here
we'll just cover that for now so you can
get an idea of what the natural lighting
looks like although torches aren't
helping either
right anyway so those are light level 15
here one one down is 1413 right below it
which is two from the wall so right here
it's light level 13 there 12
what comes before twelve eleven ten nine
eight so right in the very corner this
is like level 8 so mops on spawn at that
and go on the other way it was 13 here
12 11 10 9 8 so everything is lit up
with these 8 lights so it will work out
really well
we'll be able to turn it on and off
here's another layer over here using a
lot of snow I can't believe how many
blocks it takes I should have figured
that out before but let's find it's
going good I just put that one there
because I it's a little hard to do the
wiring for this because it's an odd
number like oops each layer is an odd
number so it's 5 blocks between each
layer and get in the torches position
right because the repeating pattern is
every 4 blocks with two torches right so
I'll have to adjust it each layer and
have the wiring the same each layer so
what I'm trying to say so like for some
the wiring might be down a block like
that other other layers it might be even
some layers I have to add extra redstone
torches on the side here to invert it
but all is good I could run a glow stone
like a glowstone ladder all the way up
to is another option but I actually want
the delay from the torches so that it
will hopefully reduce the lag of all the
lamps coming on because it gives the
game opportunity to turn them on over
time instead of all at once if you have
a little bit of delay between each layer
umm yeah so that's what's going on so
far maybe we will work on the layers
here finish it up these levers here for
the redstone torch columns are just
temporary - when this is all done I'll
I'll hook all eight columns together
into a single wire so it's easy to
control
and this is the way I've been covering
over the lamps and the and the wire for
the next layer basically wall outline is
here and the next pad like for the next
layer would you'll like this and like
that so the wire
I'll get sitting away and next pad would
be over here like that so doesn't get
washed away there would be a water
source here and it's all protected now
but for these ones where I have the
block lowered a bit I'm going to stick a
half slab in there just so we don't get
any mobs spawning in our wiring that's
not a good idea to have a too high space
like that oh I thought the whoo for a
second there I thought that redstone
wire got cut from the half slab but it's
just dark it's like black but you can
see the particle effects still on it so
it's still being powered all is good and
I'm going to use these stone half slabs
I think for the middles because they're
the closest we got to whites out of fir
five or six choices I think we have wood
brick sandstone you know I was thinking
of having glass columns going from all
the way through this thing like all the
way up to the top you know and let
sunlight in that way optionally I tried
it it looked really cool but I'm worried
it's not going to stop spiders from
spawning that's what that's the point of
these half slabs to prevent spiders from
spawning because they need a 3x3 area to
spawn and so if if one chooses to spawn
at this block checks a 3x3 around so oh
we got a block on the way so it can't
spawn type thing
all right and now we will do our water I
think I've shown how to do this before
so I'm not going to waste a whole lot of
time on this I'm actually going to make
an infinite spring here who is that up
oh I did it yet it's hard to work in
this cramped area so basically one water
goes in those corners and one in these
sides like that for all these so that's
all there is to it it ends just short of
the hole here and I can safely do this
because I got the lamps in here I can
easily turn the spotting on or off so
this is really handy for when I'm
building this if I have to add more
layers or whatever it'll be really easy
to without blowing up my mob system all
right all right so we're taking a little
bit of a nether trip here I need more
glowstone for lamps for the mop system
and other projects too getting a little
bit low on supply and I found a couple
really nice veins here and try out our
silk touch efficiency for pick on it is
weird like I said this before but I
couldn't get silk touch couldn't get it
and then all of a sudden I got like four
in a row it's crazy I got a couple new
items too I got a good axe again which
is awesome I've made a few shovels been
going through them quickly and I got one
of these and I got another pick exactly
like this two in a chest somewhere so
good for picks for a while very good
doesn't shoot through it like I thought
it would
I wonder why I just was closed on you
gotta click to get it I find that I
definitely prefer using so fetch to get
it instead of fortune three guys I think
with fortune 3 there's a few times like
it still has a chance of only dropping
three dust instead of four so I think
silk that is still a little bit more
efficient but I could be wrong about
that all right very good how much was
that from 162 that's pretty good so we
got one there there's a big one over
there I don't know if I'll get that and
I think there might be more over here
it's weird how the nether does this now
I find this in a lot of maps where the
ceiling it's like really squished
together like that Oh weird I've never
been here before this is a whoop whoop
C's 91 so we're pretty close to the top
interesting easy to grab a little stone
here oh and another fortress I don't
think I've been to that one I want to
check it out but I don't want to do it
while I'm getting glowstone so maybe
some other day I'll check that out
I think I'll grab all the stuff though
and we'll head back
oh did not bring a bow that was a Miss
oh we're not all right so that run went
pretty good we got just about four and a
half stacks of glowstone from it I made
it back safe all is good and make a few
lamps we need 90
I think 96 total for the mob system
where they're at oh and I'm almost done
redstone it's funny on the server
everybody's giving me the redstone and I
don't know what to do with it um I would
love it here though
because I go through the stuff like like
butter
um I should make another half a stack
so the other day I said I got a lot of
good comments that one episode
continuing on from that people have told
me what the cause of the clipping
through walls issue was so I've done it
again I can walk through walls
I can run into them and take damage that
apparently is caused from sleeping in a
bed and breaking it while you're while
you're in the bed and you can reproduce
it every single time
so that's interesting I never heard of
that glitch before but apparently I
should did this before I'll get good
we'll just I hate to be out of order
here but I'm just going to toss it in
this chest for now and we'll come back
put that there to for now just in case I
die
so apparently out once you do that trick
you can walk through water like nothing
- which is pretty cool I want to try go
to an ocean or something it is really
hard to get around though oh thought the
ender pearl didn't work is like what ah
let's see know if I have any oceans
around though Oh what okay maybe it
doesn't work
it was just working down down there
right here we got a lot of water here
it's not like you fall through it that's
for sure
like air creeper blew up the top there
by the way
okay apparently I lost the ender pearl
that's what it was the ender pearl fixed
it that's what happened okay
well I'll have to do it again and then
head to an ocean okay this is how the
glitch works you hop in the bed break it
till the creeper and now you can walk
through blocks amazing let's see if
drinking a potion will mess it up also
you do sink really quick too
that's pretty cool hmm you can't really
swim that's scary
okay let's try find an ocean see you
guys see how this goes I should should
have grabbed my special helmet for
breathing underwater sea running through
the force and nights where everything
can hurt you including blocks is a
little scary oh it's too bad I can't use
ender pearls come on come on let me up
it's really hard to get up blocks like
that OOP so I'm guessing this has been
the game for a while so many people know
about it
that's pretty fascinating for me though
because I didn't I'm just curious to see
that's pretty crazy
I bet you I wonder if it works with lava
too
what happens if you run into a lily pad
go right through it interesting all
right I think the water gets a little
bit deeper this way I was so weird very
cool I liked it
I almost don't want it to get patched I
find if I make a video about a glitch or
if I take advantage of a glitch it gets
patched just kind of sad because in the
past I used to take advantage of them
all the time
oh there's a ravine and now I'm kind of
scared to like you think of the cow farm
that fence trick somebody told me about
it I made the farm and a few days later
it was patched and that happens quite a
few things not not because I'm
responsible myself but just so many
people hear about it and tell other
people about it and it becomes
widespread ok I'm going to hop in this
ravine see if the fall kills me where's
my position 144
Oh oh man
sad thing is I know where I am I know
this ravine okay oh wait no no we're not
done we're not done you know what we got
to do yes we have wood boat what happens
if you're in a boat I bet you it's and
resets your position to the boat put it
here Oh whoop whoop that was not what I
wanted to do yeah that fixes it too okay
funs over
I knew enderpearls could be affected by
explosions like TNT in that but water
really affects them too
that's kind of cool oh yeah and with
this village project I looked at it the
other day messed around with it a little
bit I got rid of the wall over here and
made a like a doorway so well this is
going to be the airlock here this room
will have one door there another one
there so if any villagers is steep from
the village and are trying to get out we
can stop them with this door and push
them back close this door and then make
sure there's no villagers here and leave
without them
escaping type thing that's the idea
behind the airlock and this will also be
the loading zone if we ever get more
villagers haven't found another village
yet just the one we do have two
villagers in this whole safely I'm
trying to keep them alive because the
village we took them from is empty ah
one villager is running around the cave
somewhere I see him every so often and
the other ones died I'm pretty sure also
we have this guy here I guess he's still
behaving he still hasn't made too many
potions though I don't know what to do
about him but yeah this area behind is
pretty much solid so it will be a lot of
blocks I have to clear out I'm waiting
for tea and tea before I start this
project or progress it any further so I
can clear out that land a lot quicker
which is what the mob system will
probably be able to get me pretty soon
okay so we're back at the stronghold the
mob system area once again and last
episode I laid out where I wanted the
EMP units but I also said I wanted them
to be raised a little bit and I think
I'm going to raise it three blocks yet
so at this level here fortunately this
room is hollowed out already so I'm
going to have
put a layer to build on over at this
height and then hollow out above well I
did that I got the floor here after real
looking at this so I think I need to
lower it one more block because it's
impro qing or encroaching what's the
word getting close to my 24 block drop
before I need for the mob so I can just
drop them and kill them I don't know if
that's going to be possible at this
height so I'm going to lower it one more
block and hopefully it'll work otherwise
I'll have to remove the bottom layer of
the mob system to gain an extra five
blocks or something
yeah that's much better I'm much more
comfortable with this so the next thing
we're going to do here first of all stop
the rain sounds got something to talk
about
and while I talk about it we are going
to start to laying out the face plates
for the EMP units to get the positions
in mind and the shape of the whole thing
the size figured out I'm gonna do it
with snow just to start out with it'll
probably be temporary and later we might
switch it to iron blocks or wood or
sandstone or something but just for now
we're going to set it out in snow so the
topic I want to discuss is my youtube
comments a specific type of YouTube
YouTube comments now I do read quite a
few of my comments I still keep up with
them pretty good I enjoy reading them a
lot and one of the problems with
becoming a bigger channel is the quality
of the comments tends to go down and you
still do get good ones don't get me
wrong but I think people kind of get in
their minds that I'm not going to read
them because there's just so many of
them so that they may not even leave a
comment or just a quick one if they do
which is okay but keep in mind I do read
a lot of comments still so I do enjoy
reading opinions about things ah
the type of comments I'm specifically
addressing here though are the ones that
are come check out the server or come
check out this website come check out my
channel advertising comments I don't
want those on my channel at all so
in the past I used to ban people
instantly if I got one just so that they
want to keep posting it on my other
videos because that's the only way to
get rid of them really but then I
started to feel bad because I would have
people messaging me saying you know they
didn't really mean it they their lid
they were legitimate viewers of my
videos and I felt bad for banning them
they didn't know any better basically
they were kind of ignorant about online
etiquette and what is considered spam
and whatnot so I had to unban a lot of
people now the thing is if I don't stop
them I'm going to keep getting them so
oh yeah and by the way if if you want
people to come check out your channel
but it's not proper to advertise that in
another person's video for those of you
that don't know how I got started on
YouTube I used the Minecraft forms I
made a video that I thought people would
really enjoy and I just post on the
forums to see what kind of response it
would get and the response is very good
ooh
that there so then I kept making more
videos I thought people would really
enjoy it and put a lot of effort into
the first videos too like that's really
important you haven't put a lot of
effort into your first videos to get
people's attention but that's beyond the
points there's better ways of
advertising than on other people's
videos and even if you do get subs from
advertising on other people's videos
they're not going to be very good ones
probably so you don't exactly want them
either anyway on to the points for the
next two or three episodes I'm going to
just ban anybody I see advertising in my
channel comments just to try weed them
out somehow if you are a legitimate
viewer of my check of my videos and that
you will have heard me
so you shouldn't do it this is your
warning otherwise you will be getting
bad because most people that do it they
don't care they just see this guy has
lots of subscribers I can post something
here and get a lot of attention just
because people are viewing his videos so
people take advantage and I don't want
that if possible see that's the front
yeah so don't advertise come check out
my channel don't advertise come check
out the server don't come do any of that
stuff okay
or you will be getting banned in the
next two or three episodes for sure and
maybe even further I don't know I just
want to reduce the amount of people
because at the moment there's quite a
few and they post in every video
basically so I need to try get rid of
some yeah so this is kind of what I'm
thinking as the centerpiece of
everything here for E and P units and
connected together diagonally maybe
we'll create like an octagon shape
they're fairly big but that's not
necessarily bad the space behind here is
for the wiring and it'll all be hidden
when this is done and I'm planning on
running the tubes like in each of these
there's going to be a tube so for
example right above here this is the
center of the mob system there's going
to be glass tube running all the way up
to that and all this land here needs to
be removed so that we can see it's going
up kinda because I think that look cool
then I'll probably have like three or
four block wide walkway around here with
the stairs going down maybe two blocks
or so
to another larger circle type thing and
all around that might be chess for the
storage room
that's sort of what I'm envisioning I
hope you can envision that as well in
your mind from that description anyway
that's it for me for today thanks for
watching everybody don't advertise don't
do it you'll get banned I'm telling you
don't try me
I am got the banhammer outs
okay because like I didn't really
explain this very well people that do
advertise generally don't even watch the
video they just put it in that space
they're not viewers of mine they just
they're just trying to get free
advertisement so those are the ones in
particular I'm trying to get rid of all
right evil etho signing outs