[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and we are
once again
in the nether i've been
hey the brave little guy
i've been trying to work on getting
wither
skeletons to spawn a little bit easier
but i haven't had a whole lot of success
i just saw one here
i think it is helping a little bit but
not as much as i had hoped
i got two skulls right now i just need
one more
to summon the wither again see what it
is is
all the land around here stuff stuff is
spawning outside of my
my area i'm building for them
um but yeah i extended the nether
fortress of bits
with smooth stone we are way up in the
air this is like
ideal lava all around
pretty much i would really like to tnt
up that
land there and i'm going to do that
pretty soon i think
but yeah look at all the zombie pigmen
just spawning outside of
our nether fortress so we're not getting
as many wither skeletons as i would like
there's also a couple overhangs i've
noticed
there's one up there okay yes we'll
check out um
it's a little dangerous too yeah
oh when we almost hit him yeah there's
there's this like little overhangs like
this every every so often
and tunnels and yeah
but anyway i'm gonna keep working on
this thing little by little and i'm sure
eventually it will work pretty good
this is this is like a perfect spot for
it though like with all the lava around
any more rounds
no yeah i think i'm gonna head back
pretty soon
i'm hoping to get one more and then just
then i'll head back but i'm almost out
of food
but i will see you back uh somewhere
in our main world
we're going to fight the weather again
we got three skulls
and i'm doing a little different this
time so the first time
i went under equipped got owned then i
went back
and the second time there i had i was
over equipped
no chance of dying really so this time
to make it fun i'm gonna try go
with this helmet which isn't really
going to do much
these pants which are going to help a
lot
the shirts which will do a
decent job and these shoes which won't
do much
um this is a sword only sharpness three
and we're gonna use whatever bow we get
here
it's gonna be a surprise even if it's a
punch bow
with no no power on that's what we're
using
oh that's not bad so that's our bow
i'm gonna rely mostly on potions this
time i made quite a few instant healths
and i don't know what's going to happen
we might
get owned again but i want to try to
make it fun for myself
so first time we were underpowered
second time we were overpowered this
time we're somewhere in between so we'll
see how it goes
and i'm going to go back to that sand
arena
we had last time
sweet i think we're already here i
think we'll either let's see
we got blocks or we have
cats uh let's do bloxy i always listen
to cat
that's pretty quiet
will help a bit okay
don't mess up don't mess up last time
the star fell on a cactus i hope that
doesn't happen again that was
really unlucky
i really want to star
okay final preparations eats
we're going to get that out of there um
i'm gonna drink these already it's a
speed potion eight minutes
strength eight minutes i don't think
it'll take that long
get those in there and our helmet on
here we go round two
what you got man what you got
he's gonna be right in my face again oh
oh i didn't drink regen what am i doing
ah
okay fire does not work on
and him health's pretty good still
kite does a ton of damage i hate how
he's right in your face that is so
[Music]
annoying
there's like not really any way to dodge
him
come on we got you we got you oh he's
converting
oh get out of here
knock back knock back truck back
i think we got him don't hit attack this
is none please
yes oh i gotta start finally
and we survived that was that was a much
better fight i would say that was close
i saw my hearts go down to like three or
four a few times there
pretty quick
what's it called even just another star
all right i'm going to head back uh we
might do beacons today or we might
just go build something i'm not sure yet
i decide we're gonna work on the zombie
villager
purifier thingamajig that we we started
on last time so
last time we got these switches hooked
up we got one for the junction
one path the one going this way goes for
the the zombie villagers and the path
that goes this way
is ooh burps is for the regular zombies
um and then we also have the switch for
the spawner to turn it on and off
pretty cool so we kind of need to
separate
the zombie villagers because when they
convert to regular villagers
uh if they're zombie villagers next to
them they'll start killing the converted
ones so
gotta separate them and originally i was
going to do that with mine carts but we
found that they
oh there's one right there that they
leave the mine carts when they convert
so then i thought about doing it
like a detection system for when they
convert
to automatically indicate it somehow but
it's kind of redundant because we're
going to be in this area anyway and we
can just eyeball it
but the idea i have now
we're going to drop them one and a half
blocks so they can't go back
this way and then we're gonna have
i think a half slabs like this all along
that's their path
and every like three blocks or so we're
gonna have a holding chamber for them
uh i guess we'll put our first one here
okay and there'll be a piston behind
there
one two three another one here and we'll
just
we'll just set up like three of them or
so to test it first of all and if it
works we'll maybe have
i don't know how many i would want maybe
five total
and another one there
okay so this is how we're going to
separate them a villager
will come in and he there's going to be
like a layer of glass
over here by the way so it's going to be
one wide they'll walk
they should fall down there on their own
because they they don't take fall damage
from that drop
um we need some pressure plates going
here
they'll fall down they'll land on a
pressure plate in a holding
chamber something like that
i'm going to have to adjust this a bit
though and when they step on this
pressure plate the piston will extend
and cover up the hole so that the next
one that comes will go to the next hole
and then the next one and we'll separate
them that way
and then when we remove them from the
holding chamber it's it frees up the
spot
so that's that's the kind of plan we got
for this
maybe i need to space them one more to
i want to set up like a rail system for
getting them out of the holding chambers
um see
well first let's look at the redstone
how we're gonna have to do the redstone
redstone will go here and
gotta get up to the piston
could use a torch i guess two torches
all right i don't have redstone on me so
i'll wire this up and we'll check it out
so this is one way we could do it just
to have redstone torch there and there
and if we put a block there
ta-da very simple uh but the problem is
i do want to get them into carts somehow
and
it's a little tough to do it with this
because we can't put a rail where the
pressure plate is
so i think i might do it like this
instead
we got tripwire
still does that but we can
put a power rail below and potentially a
dispenser with
with carts in right on that block there
so that when we when we power that the
power rail will power
and dispenser will shoot out a cart and
assuming there's a mob here the mob will
go into the cart i think
and pass through this trap door which
will be down like that so they can't
escape if they're not in the carts and
then go down our rail line that we set
up
yeah so i think that's what we're going
to do problem with using
the trip wires though is they take up a
lot of space and it's going to be
uh five wide per each
thing i think
five it's either four or five i'm not
sure i'm going to set up
three things here and then we'll test it
out and we'll put up
our glass uh wall here
it'll be glass going all the way along
here a glass wall
all right and yeah we'll we'll check it
out once i get that set up
i only set up two but it should be
enough to test it out
uh just to see if the idea works or not
this one's good
and that one's good okay
so we're just gonna send regular zombies
through there they'll
they'll work the same as zombie
villagers anyway um
so we'll flip that up so they go that
way
and turn it on
and switch it back let's see what
happens
will only one go down or we'll will a
few get stuck in one holding areas
one thing we gotta watch for
uh will their pathfinding allow them to
move
okay well i look pretty good ah he wants
to go back
there's nothing back there for you man
go forward in your life
oh does he see me he's not supposed to
be looking at me either
yeah they're looking at me
yeah i'm gonna have to cover that they
don't want to move
oh
okay i'll put a roof on top that and it
should work better
uh let's go again it should be
ready for a retry
i also brought a cart with me because we
can see what happens
if we put the card in there with them
i'm a little worried though their path
findings preventing them from
moving forward
come on man move
and disco dance dang
oh oh oh oh what's he doing oh beautiful
i like you you're you're a good guy
another guy it doesn't matter if it
takes a while to get there
if i really want i could put water
streams to force them through
i think but yeah let's let's put a
minecart here
okay and then we'll try power it
uh i don't think they enter its if you
just place it on them
it needs motion
is there no block behind there that
should make it move
what
that was weird
huh i wonder why the minecart didn't
move
that's not a redstone torch
we might have a problem with this
guys don't want can you not see me when
you're in there that's weird
oh yeah he sees me
well i guess we won't know for sure if
it works until we set up a dispenser in
there and try it
i should go back and look for one
but yeah i'm gonna have i guess two
chambers here they do take up a lot of
space each one
so i'm gonna have two chambers and then
maybe two
on this wall and two on this one for a
total of six
we'll have the minecart track uh
go through the middle i also wanted to
see something
if we have a i'm not sure what the
cardinal direction is
if we send the minecarts on the track
from here is it going to go right or
left
perfect that's the way i wanted it to go
um that's the way i plan on sending the
villagers
sweet that simplifies things a bit
uh
i'm gonna go get some dispensers
okay we got a test subject we got our
dispenser in place there's a card in it
um i think we're good to go here so
we're gonna push this button goes up the
dispenser and the power rail
and we'll see if he gets put in the
carts
very good okay
i just i don't know it's so weird that
it didn't move the cart before i just if
you power it from this end it doesn't
for some reason
i want to try that again
yeah that's really weird
[Music]
and now it won't move it huh i don't
know
something strange with that
anyway uh some other stuff i want to do
here
let's get rid of these guys so we have a
cart thing
i would like to set up a weakness potion
dispenser too for them
um
and i also want where's my laps
can't jump straight i think i'm gonna
put lamps
on the bottom eventually i'm gonna try
to make it look better in here too not
all stone brick
but until we get our block positions
figured out that's just
what we're gonna use how's it look if we
have a whole
row at the bottom
it's not too bad i was thinking of doing
it like
this where we
grab some of these actually
actually all we need is levers
all you need in life is levers
so if we power that one and then
oh no i did it again didn't i
when is that gonna get fixed top of the
list please
oh man
i think it's the most annoying thing in
the game right now
got out of it oh wait i did it wrong
and one there
so yeah i'm thinking i'll have two lit
up on the outside
all the time so this one will be lit up
this one will be lit up
and then if the trip wires uh
hit down the inside two will go on as
well to show that there's a zombie in
there
because you can't really see too well
from the sides if there's a mob in it or
not
so and
i kind of need a solid block here for
the trapdoor to connect to
um i could use like a half slab or
something but
it will cut down visibility a bit and i
don't
i also don't want to see the hooks
behind here like if this was a glass
block
um yeah that's i think that's what we'll
do
cool
all right here's a better idea of what
we're going to be doing with this
switch this to the stone slabs they look
pretty good
um i gotta duplicate like this half of
the room over to the right here that
we're gonna have a tunnel that goes out
here
and up to the surface or something
although i hmm zombies burn in the day
so maybe not to the surface
but there'll be a tunnel here um
we'll have this pathway that they're
following here it'll
it'll do a full full square around the
room
i think and then we'll go underneath it
to get to this
parts over here which will probably be
lowered
um this is the
the tripwire hooked up to these
glowstone or to the lamps
and i did that like this i have two
redstone torches that's
that's split off here and this just
connects up to the
the tripwire up there
so yeah i am
i gotta get going for today so let's go
read our comments and we'll call it an
episode
all right here we go so today's comment
is a
a doozy it's a sort of a personal one
hey etho in one of your first lp videos
you mentioned have you mentioned having
trouble speaking and you figured making
an lp
would help you solve this problem how do
you think it's going
personally i rarely notice and when you
do it doesn't bother me
keep up with the awesome videos man
smiley face
well thank you very much um
yeah you know what it is like
see i'm kind of doing it right now i
kind of get stuck with my words
uh what it is like i can
pretty clearly and fluently and
precisely
put my thoughts into like text like if
i'm writing something i can very clearly
express myself but when it comes to
speaking
i have trouble converting my thoughts in
my brain into words
that roll off my tongue like
and there goes again i lost i can't
think of something clever to say there
like butter
no uh if i was writing i could have
thought of something real clever there
i'm sure
anyway you know what i'm saying uh
in my lp you don't really notice it
because i have the ability to edit
and i tend to cut out if i really mess
up i'll cut it out or i'll even
re-record as something
if it's really bad which does happen
in fact just reading the comments i
messed up so i i restarted
usually it happens within the first 5-10
seconds though if i'm going to mess up
um but there's definitely a difference
if you watch my
first lp episodes and compare them to
now
there's a lot more power and confidence
in my voice
which is sort of a skill i've been
learning
hey that sounds weird when they're in
them
um that's a really important skill to
learn too like i know it's i know it's
with
a lot of new lpers it's they seem very
uncomfortable myself
i was one of them and they tend to talk
like this and
they don't really put any feeling into
it and no power and
you know you lose your audience if
you're like that you got to speak with
feeling
with power
okay it was invisible what the heck
anyway
i'm improving but it's a slow and steady
thing i think
so with on that note i'm gonna say
goodbye thanks for watching guys
and i'll see you again next time
[Music]
you