[Music]
hey how's it going everybody
welcome back how you doing i've had
some issues myself if you're wondering
what has happened to me
i'm loaded i'm i've taken a few shots
here
not those kind of shots no no arrow
shots
loaded with arrows do you know what
ninjas do
in their off time do you have any idea
we train that's right we try to get
better
and i've been practicing it was posted
on the
the minecraft reddit again the bow shot
trick where you do
see if i can do it here oh man i'm doing
it bad
after all the practice where you do this
basically you shoot yourself with the
arrow
and you can go flying because i have a
special bow here that i've made
the flying circus unbreaking 3
and punch 2. so the punch 2
knocks you forward a lot it's really
good for
getting a nice boost and if you
practice it if you if you kind of
perfect it it's actually pretty
easy to do it consistently
um it is a bit tricky though
so from what i've found out so far like
i'm still in the middle of practicing
but basically
you want to hold forward you want to
have it at about
what is it about negative 15 or so
you see the number over over about here
on the screen
you want that about negative 15 to 25
maybe ideally and you
pull the bow back if you just tap it it
does this it doesn't actually shoot the
arrow so you have to hold it for
about a second oh man it's going to get
night time
hold it for about a second and then
right after you release the bow you want
to jump you just want to give it a
little jump so you jump into the arrow
kind of
uh if you are on the ground when it hits
you it doesn't
boost you quite as much here i won't
jump this time
let's see if i can do it oh man i'm bad
at it
yeah it just gives you a little bit of a
boost nothing crazy but if you jump
you don't like get as much friction or
something and you go quite a bit farther
i think
i'm jumping after all these oh missed it
that time
aha but the other really cool thing with
this is you can double jump i did it
earlier
that might have been a double jump i
might have hit the ground there though i
can't tell
but you can you can hit yourself again
in midair and that's what i'm really
trying to get good at
or what i would like to master
oh creeper let's get away
come on double jump on camera
oh no i think i hit the ground again
if i could just i want to be able to fly
in this game
oh oh that happened too quick i couldn't
tell if it was a proper double jump i
did one earlier here though i'll
i'll just put it up on the screen for
you
oh man double i did a double
all right practical application time we
can use it sort of like a
poor man's ender pearl like if i gotta
hop over the fence here
i can just i can just do that you know
instead of ender pearling over which is
cool
right it's probably not very practical
actually
ender pearls are pretty hard to beat but
it's fun
it's actually kind of hard to do and
it's really easy to shoot the cows
whoa anyways let's get to it here guys
so
i wanted to show you this this thing is
pretty cool it's a port collis
designed by wolf decks i decided to
install it as our castle gate to sandy
city here
so this is with the door open right now
if we close it
bam isn't that cool this is the open
sand pops up pushes the fence gets out
of the way and then the sand falls back
down
after the pistons retract there's
actually quite a bit to it i thought it
was a really simple thing at first until
i started building it
and man turns out
i am very bad at following tutorials um
i have this this problem where i skip
ahead
because all i really want to do is i
just want to see the
where all the blocks go you know and
i'll build it i'll pause it and build it
um but after i did all that i had like
five repeaters set wrong
and good luck trying to find those five
repeaters because the whole thing didn't
work and i had to like
reverse engineer it and figure out where
i went wrong and oh my goodness
i'm just not patient enough guys that's
my problem
uh but we should be able to cover over
almost this redstone
let's put some sandstone down here and
then we'll put sand over top uh
but in the end we got it all working
here it is very large
though we're gonna have to hide all the
pistons and stuff
there's like four pistons down below
that pop up and then there's four
um at the top there that go down
yeah we can cover this so maybe what
we'll do
i've looked at screenshots of castle
gates and usually there's a tower on
each side of the gate
so maybe let's let's lay that out maybe
this will come out three blocks or so
then we can go
five maybe back into the wall
if we do that on both sides and build up
a tower
i wonder how that would look okay let's
get rid of that
um where was it no not there
or not not sand we want sandstone
yeah tell you what i'm gonna build this
up and we'll just get a rough idea of
what it would look like if it was
if it was plain although that's going to
be like a
fat oh man a fat
skinny tower you know because it's going
to go from here
to like here and it looks really
thin maybe we need to make it seven
blocks
at least like maybe come out to here
oh i don't know the problem is this gate
itself is not very big
because at the limitations of the
pistons
usually castle gates the gate is really
big and then the towers are kind of
small beside it and we got
a reverse situation going on here
but we'll see what it looks like
okay so this is what i wanted to see
guys what would it look like if we
covered over all the pistons and just
built up the towers everything's
flat-walled right now
doesn't look super great does it
but this is giving me ideas for how we
can change it so maybe
if we shave away the sides if we make it
five blocks wide
the towers look pretty bulky don't they
yeah let's do that and we don't actually
need to have the towers matching
the height of the middle like the middle
has to go that high to block out the
pistons but
we might be able to shave a couple
blocks off the top
oh can i get it wow that was great
nice if we shave a couple blocks off the
top on both sides
uh it'll probably look a bit better too
okay here we go guys this is what i
trained for this is what it's all been
about
i want to get to the top of that tower
there it's only one block
wide and very far away can i do it
no oh i gotta keep practicing
okay uh i'm gonna lower this side one
more block too i'm just playing around
with the
the size a bit and i think a little bit
lower is better
yeah let's just shave that off there and
there and there
cool put these in
i wanted to jump over there and i messed
it up that's better
right i think so and then what we'll
probably do is have some kind of cross
cross section over here perhaps
like a walkway between the two towers
and then
doors on both sides and maybe we'll make
it so you can actually walk up there
whoa yeah like put doors here and
here and if we do
the this whatever this is called
that might look good too
uh no it doesn't you can't see it
because there's sandstone behind
hmm it needs maybe some wood mixed in
with all this doesn't it
i don't know how to do it though
all right everybody so check it out i
know things look pretty rough there for
a while but i'm actually
really happy with how this turned out i
decided to keep it pretty plain i didn't
mix any wood in with it really
instead what i did is i tried to give it
shape with
or like shadows by by the shape of it
and also i mixed in different textures
so we got the smooth and the chiseled
kind of tried to create some patterns
with it like it kind of goes
with the flow of the shape you know and
straight line over there
and again a curve over here oh it's
getting dark
aha this is what the inside looks like i
decide to
fill it up with a bit of wood here all
in all it works pretty good i would say
you know i never did try can i go
through this while the sand is still
moving
like tonight no we gotta wait
i think we have to wait after after all
let's try that again
can i run through this oh
no not really um maybe we should hide
some torches back
here on both sides i wonder
is that good yeah i think that's okay
for a castle
sort of build i don't think it's so bad
having torches visible
usually i don't like them very much um
oh yeah and i built up the wall a little
bit too because it looked really bad
with this huge
giant gate thing and then like a teeny
tiny wall the wall was only up to here
before
like this like this is how tall it was
so i'm gonna have to raise this all i
think
unfortunately oh man okay
something very shocking has happened
here guys i'm gonna tell you but you
gotta keep it together okay
don't lose your cool this this is gonna
blow you away
i have done something today i don't know
if it's ever happened before
i have started and finished a project
all in one episode
can you believe it i this might be
unprecedented
i'm not sure oh man right in the head
have you been watching me this whole
time that's creepy yeah this thing is
done guys i got it done
and i'm very happy with it um i even
worked on the sides here
tried to make it look pretty good from
as many angles as possible we got a
little access to the wiring
and to these upper levels here i don't
know why
i don't think we'll ever use them but
they're there if we need them
i also hooked up the gate to a timer so
the way this is going to work
you hit the button to open it
like so and i decided to make it just
auto close on its
on its own after a certain amount of
time the reason for that
there it goes is because whenever i have
a door that has like an
open button and a close button i just
leave it open all the time
i don't actually use the door and for
such a big
project like this i want to make sure i
actually
use it so this forces me to have to open
it every time
uh if you keep an arrow stuck in it
it'll just stay open until the arrow
despawns too
i had a creeper blast over here so i
decided to connect this together
but we'll want to transform this area a
bit and a bit more and try to smooth it
out
better oh yeah i've added some fence
some fences here i thought that made it
look a little nicer
um what else i think that's about
it yeah so it's just like a hopper clock
type of thing over here the wiring is
pretty messy
yeah just a hopper clock i got 32 items
in there
keeps it open for a decent amount of
time
ah but here's the thing guys
i maybe want to build two more of these
or so like
i wanted one over here like we got a
path going out this way i kind of want
to
enclose the entire city and like have a
gate here
type of thing maybe one more
up over here it's a big project i don't
know
if i'm ever looking for something
repetitive to do i might
actually make it happen but for today
we'll we'll go on to some other stuff
here
uh had a lot of fun building this though
i love building castle stuff
it's really cool
dang it
i got careless oh man that sucks
okay let's get our stuff back here
pretend that never happens
reclaim our pride
all right very good you know what it was
something caught my eye and i had to
look at it
not the enderman i was not trying to
look at the enderman i saw the crystals
oh it's just a piece of bedrock isn't it
i thought i saw a crystal up here
and it shocked me because i thought i
destroyed them all and yeah i did
okay never mind so we are
in the end now guys what are we doing
here well we usually come here for
ender pearls but today for a change we
have actually come here for some end
stone
uh-huh it's all coming back clearly to
me guys i know why i don't like to use
this as a building material too often
it's uh it's not very fun to collect
it takes a long time and if i remember
right haste begins don't speed it up
like you can't instant mind it
i don't think uh but we're just gonna
collect a little bit of it here we're
gonna build another tunnel today
or design it anyway um
i tried putting endstone nether brick
and my mycelium all together and it
looked
really good so those are the three
blocks we're going to go with
and probably sea lanterns for lighting
and hopefully we can come up with
something cool we got to make a
track out to our sand collection area
because
used up all our sandstone today and we
need more
so we may as well get that done with
already
this is probably enough for for today
anyway so let me get out of here and we
will get to it
yeah so currently guys we need two
nether tunnels built we got the track in
this one
most of the way but we we gotta polish
it up right
uh but this one over here is really bad
we got nothing it's just this is raw
right now
this goes out to the desert and i
basically run it every time
so this is mostly for me because i want
to save some time
um i got mining fatigue so we can't make
any mistakes here
for a minute anyway so i think what
we'll do
maybe go out like this oh invisible and
have the track down one block
like so i always like to lower the track
one just so we don't get
as many zombie pigmen on the track helps
to reduce the spotting if you got blocks
beside it
um yeah then i guess mycelium would come
next i want that on the ground too
so weird having mining fatigue
uh let's go too wide with it
and then what we should probably do is
put in some vertical
pillars i like having something vertical
in my nether tunnels always that way
uh you can kind of get a sense of speed
let's do a two two wide thing
because if everything's horizontal
you'll go down it and nothing really
changes but if you have vertical lines
they whiz by you
and i just like the way that looks
making nether tunnels is like one of my
favorite things in this game i don't
know why
oh no can i break it oh 10 good
uh it's fairly simple it doesn't take
too long to do them and
you can usually come up with a different
design every time it's not too tough
yeah let's let's just like build these
up so we'll have a five block
gap between and then just repeat this
section over and over probably
uh we could
we should probably hide some lighting
here too
i don't know if we want to go in one
maybe over here now let's go in one
yeah over here we'll do sea lantern and
then
let's do another stair the other way
doing a little building with you guys
for a change
i don't know if you like that or not
something like that yeah and of course
i'll have to do the sides so you can't
see the gap
all right and
maybe we'll do a line at the bottom as
well
between here it's pretty close in color
to the mycelium i like that
um
okay i was having a little bit of
trouble designing this middle part here
so i decided to do it off camera and
this is what i came up with
uh-huh this is some random weird shape
uh i do have an idea for it though
something i've done in this game for
well since the alpha days even i like to
use wheat
wheat as decoration like just
throw it in random places i don't know
why so i went and got some
bones and some seeds we'll see what it
it looks like here
oh there's nothing in my inventory i
want to get rid of though
[Music]
i guess the arrows oh man
now i can't do the bow jump trick all
right
seeds quickly bone meal
all right hopefully it's not too too
yellow
yeah and we should probably throw in
some lighting here
i kind of made this in a way that we can
hide it
all right put it there and then the half
slab blocks it i believe
yeah totally blocked we can't see it at
all so i don't make it look like it's
glowing
then we just need some kind of batting
for that
i think that's kind of cool though right
maybe we'll change it to carrots
or something later if we want something
greener that's kind of yellow
um anyway let's work out the rest of
this we gotta do the ceiling now
which is always my least favorite part
of a build
let's kind of i love arches let's do an
arch
something like that and we can
probably connect it together over here
to this arch
oh see what this turns out like
okay let's copy it so one
two three back up like that
and then this goes out to the other one
as well
all right how's that we're just gonna do
one section here together and i'll i'll
just copy the rest of it off camera
hopefully
yeah that's pretty cool we got a bit of
a gap here
though that we can see through
so let's fill this in with end stone as
well
should we go up one more like on the
side here let's try it
oops just spam blocks let's fill it in
with something that's all we really
gotta do
yay
yeah that's good right um
maybe we could do some nether brick
stairs then that go
up like this and meet meat in the middle
as well
let's go one more here let's actually
let's put blocks here
oh yeah i like that okay that's what
we're doing
do it on this side and i guess that's
about it let me try to work out the last
little bits here
and we'll see it all done
okay guys so i just went ahead here and
i extended the track a bit further
uh the tunnel a bit further so we'd have
an idea of what it looks like when it's
all done here
and it keeps repeating over and over i
think that's pretty good right
i like it yeah i think that's what we'll
go ahead with
this is how i finished it up by the way
i
i did three of these arch things
in the center part and then i did a beam
running across the middle
and i like that quite a bit over here is
another brick
again i tried to keep the beam running
through
type of feel just through some end stone
in the back behind the wheat here
and that is
that is that's all there is to it i've
been watching this too to see if any of
the zombie pigmen will fall on the track
we are getting them spawning because
there's a lot of flat
space here um may throw in some
mushrooms or some bushes
see what that's like how did he get hurt
i don't even know
uh for some reason the horse over here
just like
glitched into the wall just about died
i barely saved it had one heart left
but i don't know why it happened anyway
let's wrap up for today guys the comment
says etho i think for the nexus terminal
you should scrap the map idea
sounds like a pain you said yourself
that by having a bunch of bits you can
learn how it's grouped and save time
i think that should be the should be f
focus
possibly learning what each bit toggles
between
instead of reading off a code for each
item would make the system more
usable example memorize which bit
toggles items which toggles food and
which toggles stake
etc etc
so i can kind of remember where stuff is
in the nexus
but we can't
we can't make it work off of memory
alone i don't want to memorize it
i won't be able to i know it and i don't
want to think when i have to get an item
out of it
otherwise it'll be too difficult um
so yeah we probably can't memorize it
that as far as the map idea goes it
sounds like most you guys weren't
too excited about me doing that in
vanilla anyway so we're not going to do
it some of you did the math and it works
out to about
like over a million blocks i'll have to
place and that's just
no i'm gonna play the life is too short
card on that one
and maybe use a paint program to draw
the map
and convert it and then bring in the
game
maybe um haven't fully decided on it yet
though
but we'll work something out but anyways
i hope you guys enjoyed our episode here
today
hope you have a wonderful day and i'll
see you in the next one
take care bye bye