Oh No
I can't see anything you know why
because it's dark in here
oh yeah detective Ito cracks the case
guys my observation skills are top-notch
as always hmm welcome back to another
episode of the let's play series how're
you doing today
seriously though the reason we are in a
dark room here is because I had a little
idea I wanted to try out might be cool
might be kind of stupid we'll find out
once we see it here but basically I want
to try make some fade lighting in
Minecraft so in this game there's
basically two states of lighting you
have on and you have off and even if you
use like a comparator or something it
doesn't save like the lighting doesn't
get weaker the further away the the
power signal is it's just again on and
off right boop boop boop boop on off so
what we want to try to do is make
lighting that can fade in and out or
pulse or something of that nature and if
it's cool we might actually use it in a
build but I expect it's going to cause a
lot of legs might take up a lot of space
and might not even look cool I'm not
sure we'll find out so I guess I have a
rough idea of what I want to do with
this
I guess maybe we'll try put a light here
and just see if we can do that so the
way we're going to create the fade
effect is by having a whole row of lamps
so if we have a lamp here at the lamp
it's going to be light level 15 and then
14 here 13 it's actually not going to
light up very much is it because it's
going to be light level 12 or so by the
time it finally gets out of the hole
here well I think this is the closest we
can actually get it so we'll try this
out first so gonna have a big row of
lights in
underground here and then we'll run a
comparator signal to this and try to
control that and see what happens so I
thought about it a little bit more here
and it's actually probably a lot easier
than I expected all you got to do set up
some lamps I have 13 of them here run
some redstone over top we'll go up to
here then the comparator into a hopper
kind of like a hopper clock thing where
you have two cooperates facing each
other and then depending on which one of
these is powered it'll control whether
the enderpearls we have here are going
to flow into this hopper or this one so
we'll put in quite a few hundred pearls
here right now that is bouncing back and
forth right so what we want to do is
probably set up like a sticky piston
with a redstone block and like if it's
here this hoppers locked so they all go
into here if we extend it then they flow
into this one and the light recedes how
quickly is that going to happen here
pretty slow okay so that might be one of
the challenges is how do we speed that
up okay so I thought we would detect it
out here before we do anything so at max
brightness this is what the floor
lighting looks like and then we have the
switch over here flip that and they'll
start fading out start fading out yeah
there we go so I think that actually
looks kind of cool I do like it but it's
it's way too slow right we want a faster
fade effect for it to look cool
I think that's neat you can switch it at
any time it will fade in or out also I
just wanted to try putting tools in the
hoppers instead of enderpearls so they
have that the advantage of stacking 1 /
1 / stack instead of 16 per stack like
enderpearls
which means this will be 16 times faster
but it's too quick
it's tipping every three light so it's a
very chunky fade in and out
ideally we would want something that
stacks 2/3 which doesn't exist so we
might need to do something fancy with
redstone to make that happen got ya all
right it's a very cool guy so I tried a
few different designs out here and I
think we came across the winner so check
this one out so I have it hooked up to
this pressure plate right now stare to
this torch so if we step on it mmm
and if we hop off mmm pretty good right
like that is the speed I was hoping for
on this and it's a smooth transition I
think that's really good and like
another thing about this we're in a very
clean sterile room right now like it's
totally flat floor very plain texture I
think if we were to put this in a room
that was a bit more chaotic um
and had like walls and stuff around the
fade effect would look even cooler let's
just try that out very dangerous to you
by the way I got a record just a moment
ago pretty happy about that all right so
now oh oh what happened there aha so you
can see the fade effect on the blocks on
on the side there looks pretty nice I
think so one downside about this design
is we have to make a sacrifice instead
of I'll show you that too instead of 13
lamps we're doing nine now and it's
almost not noticeable try to try to make
an episode here buddy get out of my face
I better eat something here quick if
you're wondering why I have the pumpkin
pie it's because I did the trading with
that farmer villager from our pumpkin
farm and had to buy some pumpkin pie off
of them done lock the trades yeah one
downside is because we're using nine
lamps we had to sacrifice a little bit
of the fade so when it gets down to near
totally faded out you see it just kind
of disappeared there didn't it fade all
the way down
it's almost not noticeable though so I
think it's okay but let's go check this
out so you weren't here a moment ago so
it's basically the same thing as we did
before with the hoppers except for using
droppers now and these are full of
swords so had to do like a zig-zag
pattern here with the redstone so
whenever one sword goes into here one
lamp turns on because of this pattern
because sometimes the redstone signal
extends by 2 or 3 and this is a pattern
that that works so I just came up with
this I've done this before but it it my
old method of this didn't work in this
case because we have the clay blocks
above here so I had to come up with a
different pattern and this seems to work
and one other thing about this is we
have a clock running here I cheated a
little bit I turn the sound down uh-huh
what we got to do is have some way of
shutting this off in the final version
of this so when this dropper is full or
empty then we want to tell this clock to
shut off I think and then when we step
on the pressure plates or flip a lever
we want to turn on again and also
control this piston you'll notice it
doesn't make any noise while it's fading
in or out so if we can just shut it off
when we don't need to be running then it
will be nice and smooth
aha another cool thing about this
because we're using a comparator clock
one way we can affect the amount of time
it takes is by just adjusting these
repeaters here so if we wanted to like
stayed in quicker than it fades out for
example we could set one of these two
two and neither one two one and I think
I broke this actually let's let's go
back up here I think oh dear
we're fine wow it really filled up in
here oh you'll notice I did not scream
like a girl there I said oh dear I'm
getting better oh let's don't lofty
okay I think I should actually like go
into CPM mode here for a second oh man
oh I did do it I knew it was gonna
happen
ah it's just a cat did you survive is he
peeks fall damage right oh he just came
back up here ah
yeah in recent versions of Minecraft
mobs can shoot through corners again
it's kind of annoying or zombies can get
you through corners I guess I think I do
have a way of getting down over here
yeah not the first time it happens I'm
gonna try to get through here
oh I missed oh he's got my stuff no oh
that was a strong hit I died okay we got
ourselves a boss monster to fight here
I'm gonna have to tear it up I guess
hey don't you do it alright we got the
we got the boss monster got my gear back
alright to drop anything non-essential
here
Oh Pistons I want those back um actually
tell you what let's block this okay
because we could have another accident
here otherwise okay so we're back to
business here the nice thing about this
design that I wanted to show you just by
changing those repeaters now we can
easily adjust the time it takes to fade
in and out so this is with the fade in
at 1 and the fade out at 2 you see it's
twice as slow to fade out as to fade in
so you can control it really easily just
by changing those repeaters alright
everybody so let's take a little break
from that and we're going to do a
follow-up on last
episode so you remember I was having a
lot of trouble with the minecarts some
of them were moving faster than others
and I did some tests I could not figure
out why I thought it was because mine
carts move faster when they have items
inside but when I tested it they moved
at the same speed and you guys pointed
out my test was flawed because when I
tried it I had nothing but power rails I
didn't have any regular rails and that
sounds correct to me so we're going to
try it again here two hopper mine carts
we're going to throw items in one of
them one of them will leave empty and
we'll see if they move at the same speed
or not I really messed this up did I
okay well well bridge the gap here
because we got to activate these at the
same time we'll put the leaver like this
okay this should work
okay so right now they're moving at the
same speed but they should lose speed on
the unpowered rails here right once they
get items is was the theory anyways so
give it a bunch of items and they're
still going at the same yeah they look
neck-and-neck to me maybe we needed a
longer track uh-huh okay so that seems
to be what it is guys these are both
empty right now we'll turn this on
they'll stay neck-and-neck but we got
rid of some of the power rails here so
they have a bigger opportunity to slow
down and it's when they're going slow
that they start to drift apart here so
with just one item can't really see much
of a difference right so it's not like
one item makes makes or breaks it it's
when it starts to get a bunch of items
you see they're starting to trail off a
little bit this one's slowing down the
one width item slows down and if we give
it a lot items then there's a big change
see that aha so we figured it out all
right anyways that's not an issue
anymore I did redo the track since last
episode so we got this all finished got
rid of all the T intersections and it's
one straight track all the way down now
so this should be good
alright guys we're going to check out
something pretty trippy here I just used
a rocket down this tunnel over here and
it creates a really weird effect it's
kind of hard to fly down here but if we
can let's get rid of the cursor - okay
here we go here we go
there we go Oh some of the the chunks
are disappearing isn't that weird I
don't know what it is it's I guess it's
a quick flash of stone that makes it
really odd I keep hitting my head on the
on the top here - not a lot of leeway
well that's my stop
ah-ha this goes to the guardian farm -
now by the way I put in a little
shortcut which we don't need to go to
but it's a way to get to the mushroom
farm quickly yeah so now that that track
is done I think we're going to do one
more run-through of the mushroom farm
together here because I got the
impression some of you might have been a
little disappointed last episode we
didn't see the fully finished thing even
though I thought we covered it pretty
well but yeah just to be sure here so
I'm going to try run through this pretty
quick grow the mushrooms then we chop
them down run along here both sides
oh I fall down again I do that every
time okay so now that we chopped down
the most most of the mushroom we got to
get the stalks I think it was this
button right we just press that once
then I run down the middle here take out
the middle middle stalks alright this
looks pretty good I didn't see any
problems I'm going to throw a couple
tracks on the ground here - that will
play an important Slater here but now
that we got them all chopped down we've
got we got a really hurry here
get the water streams running which will
push them all all the blocks to the
middles down the hole and then we got to
pick it up with our newly made minecart
track so that was over here press a
button they should run down and
hopefully not collide with each other
this time after the change
it didn't work now are you serious did I
break the redstone somewhere
what's going on I did do something weird
here but I didn't think it'd be a
problem oh okay I accidentally broke the
redstone line at some point and changed
it I didn't think it would matter okay
so these are writing down they're
picking up the mushroom blocks through
the grounds looks like hopefully they
are anyways let's just double-check here
we'll run ahead this one should have
something by now know if we can catch up
this one it should have in now yeah okay
so dig get some whoo
all right run down the line here so
they've been they returned back to the
PEZ dispenser stack and unload I think
they all finished
I made one change here since last
episode as well so they're unloading
here I added in a item filter so I was
worried I get those power rails land on
on the ground there or zombie flesh or
bones or something it would end up in
our storage chests there go to our
furnaces and then clog our furnaces so I
decide to separate the garbage so that
how our rails should end up in this
garbage chest instead of in our storage
chests here now but yeah this will fill
up with mushrooms and then that should
head off once it's totally full to the
super smelter down the track here okay
it looks like it's just about done
unloading here I left it for a while
okay just finished I'm going to throw in
some redstone torches here too just to
show you the garbage filter so if we go
down again they ended up in G in here as
well as our power rails and I guess
there was a mushroom somewhere on the
track so if all those items when it's
the storage minecart here they would
have clogged the furnaces so now we have
a safety net for that so that's good
from one harvest this is how my mushroom
blocks we got not quite a full minecart
chest here but just about these other
ones I have in my inventory was from a
previous chopped down so I'm going to
put these in here just to make sure this
works is
well let those go in so once it fills up
it should depart automatically on its
own hopefully there goes all right and
that's going to head off to the super
smeltery so we'll go chase it awesome so
yeah it looks like our unloaders working
here as well so the mushroom blocks are
going into storage into the into the
fuel for the super smelter I'm going to
go ahead and just speed this up I'm
going to throw the mushrooms in manually
most of them will leave a few here all
right put that in here and probably do
another full load and just want to make
sure this departs when it runs out so
we'll we'll speed it up here
okay last few and there goes alright so
ready for the next cycle so that is our
mushroom farm pretty much all done I
would say I heard that oh it worked this
time didn't work last time I don't know
why did it actually smelt them it did
not I wish I could build something it
would just work afterwards but it's like
I break something or some little tiny
thing happens and breaks the whole thing
why so it definitely delivered the stuff
which means the stuff is probably in
waiting to be picked up somewhere here
and the other big thing is like if I
leave something after I finish it I
don't remember how it works so it's hard
to fix it if something goes wrong it's
like it's like this stuff got stuck in
the furnace yes we'll check it
oh you can't wait so I don't I don't use
andesite a lot do not smelt it
oh you don't smelt it oh oh
yep looks like detective Ito cracked
another case guys I am on a roll today I
tell you what okay so I do have a plan
for the rest this episode now we're
going to get started on a project here
where do I want to start it I think that
was the spot this is that River by the
way you remember a long time ago I dug
this out connected the river all the way
so this is like an area we started but
never hit anything with I would like to
eventually maybe branch out this way
I've got our home sweet home here I
don't know how many of you remember that
so yeah we're going to start another
project in this vicinity on the
riverbank here I think right over here
so the plan is to take advantage of that
fade lighting idea I want to actually
use it in a build all right it's trying
to think what we could do what we could
do and then I remembered we never really
did anything with the Dragon Age in our
world here so we're going to make kind
of like a trophy room I guess for for
the dragon egg and I guess started here
so our goal is to make like a cool room
we wanted to have a lot of atmosphere
and seal epics and that kind of stuff we
don't really we're not really going for
functionality with this it's just for
life show more so and I did a little bit
of building and creative already you
remember on mine crack the cobblestone
t-rex I wanted to see if I could do that
with the dragon head and it's a little
bit goofy you'll see it but it's it's I
think it's good enough yeah so we're
just going to try to get the entrance
done for today guys it's going to be
like a 2 3 episode projects if I was yes
and of course I always lowball so it's
probably to be more
but yeah so just baby steps here so we
have a double arch amazing right
horizontal arch meets vertical arch I'm
very creative this is like the frame to
our entrance I the statue we're building
is three blocks wide so I want to put
that in the middle here and then we're
going to have a staircase to go down
into the trophy room all right that's my
plan and I think we will do a mix of
cobble and sandstone brick stairs here
do the line down the middle and I want
the statute to be a little bit lower
than the ground level here because I I
noticed it looks too good when you look
at straight on edits I think what we'll
do is go down here as well and we'll
hollow this out and do something like
this well create like a second level
down here I think would look cool yeah
we'll do it like that we'll meet up with
the arch here let's put another block
over here this will all be grass make it
blend in with the nature and then maybe
we'll do another arch another horizontal
arch here and this will meet up with the
statue and it will keep going down yeah
I think this is about the shape we're
gonna go for I think this is good we're
not going to do an arch with the Santa
site it's probably going to be a
rectangle but I threw in an arch over
there and it's going to go up into like
a dome shape I think would be cool
aha the reason we're using clay might be
a little bit of an odd choice maybe but
I think I think it's a good idea because
it goes well with a grey stone which we
have a lot of here and if we didn't do
this it would be a very great build
because the statues going to be gray
here it's going to be made out of
cobblestone and with this as the
backdrop I think it'll make the statue
stand out more because you'll be able to
see it against the
different colored backdrop that way okay
so we have our eggshell entrance
framework or whatever built and what you
would call it
I built a base for the Statue here maybe
we'll try to improve this a little bit
more pretty plain right now and then on
top is going to be the head then we have
our staircase to go down here this is
going to lead most likely to a long
hallway with lighting in as well
fade lighting and then at the end of the
hallway they'll be a room with the
dragon egg in and probably some more
lighting and stuff is the plan and you
can see over here behind the statute
we're going to put in fade lighting too
and hopefully make the head glowed in
different ways we'll see we'll have to
get into that next episode though
because we probably don't have time
today but yeah let's see if I can build
the head on camera here I tried to
memorize it because I built in creative
already I'll see if I can show you how
to do it not that you probably want to
copy it it doesn't look like it doesn't
look super good or anything it's the
best I could do though so this is what
we're trying to build right I already
forgot I think then we go stairs facing
this way for the eyes and over here okay
and then for the top of the head I think
it's just slabs if I remember right or
no I think it stairs this way stairs
this way oh yeah I do have dual monitors
but I never use them I got like a free
monitor when I bought my computer but
it's not very good so I don't like using
it like this the color and and stuff on
its not not good at all so behind the
eyes here we're going to put some
magenta glass so they'll have that
glossy look to them you know between the
eyes I think we go just cobblestone and
then this is our mouse the mouse I think
oh that's scary okay I think we just
make this come out one two three
possibly it's almost like an alligator
maybe not three like it does have a long
a pretty long mouth right I don't I
don't think it's three it needs to okay
and also this dragon head doesn't have
it but I think some dragons have a main
sort of singer I know you'd call it
crest kind of like lizard some lizards
have so I decide to put that on the
statue too to hide the glass box here so
cut up just like that and do it on the
other side and then on the top there's
going to be some fences some cobblestone
fences for the horns okay building
statues with etho isn't this great ah
that's pretty close I think I think
that's about right yeah we'll get some
some walls here they're not actually
called fences this surprised me there
called walls I've always called them
cobblestone fences and then I searched
for it today is like - wait a minute why
can't I find it okay this goes like that
put the fences on top walls on top and
finish it off like that I think that's
right okay let's double check here yeah
so that's our that's our dragon head
guys I don't know let me know if I can
improve it anyway but that's what we're
going to go for for today anyways and I
think we will try to improve this little
bit
let's stagger it so we'll do it like
that
bulk it up in the front give it more of
a 3d look and like that maybe
sure put one more slab here yeah
alright kind of a view from a distance
here I think I'm okay with that
what do you guys think you think it's
okay should I change it in any way and
do you have any ideas for the next part
of this the hallway and stuff let me
know in the comments
should we keep the shoulder mounts also
I tried them out here I kind of liked
them but they also pick your focus away
from the statue right I don't know
they're kind of fun though
aha so we're going to try work on this
again next episode but we're going to
wrap up for today so here is the comment
I picked out kind of an interesting one
it says hey etho I was wondering if you
could ever give us a small overview of
your viewer demographics just as a
curiosity I think it would be
interesting to see for example you could
tell us from which countries people
watch aha so I think I am allowed to
share that information certain things
you can't share about your YouTube stuff
I think that's safe so we're going to
check it out here and it's actually a
little interesting so the from ages 13
to 17 we have seven point four four
percent viewership eighteen to twenty
four is 36 and the winner is 25 to 34 37
percent then it trails off 35 to 44 is
12 45 to 54 is 5 percent and then any
older than that
2.5 percent of the viewership AHA
country's u.s. USA is a forty nine
percent then UK nine point three Canada
my homeland only eight point eight
Australia four point five Netherlands do
they speak English there I think they do
right a little bit 3.2 and Germany two
point five so us via longshots
and then there's like a bajillion other
countries too which small percentages in
each of them aha anyways thank you for
that question and hopefully you guys
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching as always I will see you again
in the next one take care bye bye
you
[Music]