you know what guys
everybody thought I was crazy why bother
picking it up why waste your time with
it you're never going to use it looks
terrible you can't build anything out of
it well I tell you guys you never know
done there you never know when you're
going to use something in this game
that's why I have like a bajillion chest
full of cobble you just never know don't
need it now
someday alright I want to try it out we
are in the new snapshot I'm I'm checking
it out I'm very excited about the
redstone updates lots of cool new
features sadly can't make the hopper in
vanilla as I think that's the thing I'm
most excited about and I can't play with
it today in the LP but I did play it
with it and creative a bit this is my
first time doing this as well give it
back
click oh there we go oh yeah
there's a new weird controls with the
shifting and whatnot anyway so that's
what it looks like huh guessing you need
four snake that one and Booya out get XP
that's good another break that's awesome
so in my LP I actually don't have a lot
of healthy world I don't have a lot of
nether brick containers is about all of
it actually yep
so that is really nice to have here on
mine crack I have tons of it so not as
big of a deal but I also have a lot more
netherrack there too but as for today I
was walking through here it's like what
can we do with the new features and I
saw this I saw this it's like how about
this first for a good redstone update
project let's let's try get a light
sensor that will light this up during
the day because it's it's pretty dark
these leaves light these all up during
the day and that night they'll go dark
because you know it's not bad if they're
dark like I don't mind it like this but
we can have a little visual indicator
because down in my cave I have a hard
time telling what time it is
I got a few clocks around the place to
help
yeah I'm going to head on over to the
nether and see if I can find some of
that quartz crystal I also haven't seen
that myself so I'm curious to see what
it looks like this might be a new
fortress I'm not sure I'm trying to
trying to Oh what is that it what is
that
I yeah I'm trying to generate new chunks
to find the stuff I think that's it I've
never seen that before
oh yeah there's lots of it oh wow
cool I thought it was going to be actual
crystals on not solid blocks like this
and do I have fortune no I brought silk
touch let's try silk touch
I'm scared the lavas flowing because
it's a brand new area oh you can pick up
the whole thing and the courts or yeah
so on my adventure here I I'm being a
little bit what's the word brave no no
no foolish I'm playing on hard and I
came here with just my just my boots on
so hopefully we need back okay so little
silk touch works on it gives you XP okay
and you get little quartz crystals
another quartz very cool so I'm I can so
I'll just grab a bit of this stuff seems
to spawn in pretty big chunks actually
one two three four five six seven and
fairly common
they must tad place actual quartz no
well that would be cool yeah I'm
guessing they're planning to have quite
a few uses for it if it's this calm and
although they might change that like
there's there's it's everywhere by the
looks of it
let's just go a little bit further I'm
curious to see if we'll see a lot more
as we go I others Streep's they're
pretty good in the ceiling yeah all
right well I guess I'll head back whoa
what whoa well what no the heck so that
glitcher is that something new I don't
know about you can't step on sole Sam
anymore or is it invisible fire visible
fire I think it's gotta be you know I
actually need glowstone too so I'm going
to grab this on the way back and look at
this it's like it's not giving off light
oh now it is uh-huh you know that is a
lot of glowstone isn't it that's like
that triple cluster all together in one
spot I'm I got 31 right now let's see
how many I get when I harvest it all and
the final count is two stacks and
twenty-one you had 31 so that's that's a
hundred and eighteen from that one
little spot here all easily all easy to
get to and I think a couple even burnt
in the lava so pretty good should keep
us going for a while
load world load whoo don't miss don't
miss whoo
and we are home yes oh there is a few
things I'm curious about with this new
or it's a new art we got to figure out
what you can and can't do with it since
it's netherrack I'm wondering if you can
actually light it on fire and have it
stay lit oh what am i doing
not in here let's go somewhere else
oh that was really dumb this looks a
little bit better
all right let's spread this up I think
yeah I got nothing that would burn up of
seems to be to be staying lit just watch
it for a sec I don't oh it went oh I
don't like the inventories all messed up
I'm having trouble clicking things I
don't know and I like legs weird like I
know they added that feature but I don't
really like it it's makes it's making it
very hard to do anything I'm finding in
the inventory so I'm wondering if we can
line it with a wooden pick yep cool give
us or well should we try I guess
can we smelt it take that out that way
and smelt it and oh yeah we should check
if I got a fortune pic around here give
us one right yep I didn't get XP but
there might not have been enough there
to get XP
um fortune fortune there we go
all right let's last one we will try
fortune on a plea by a fire in here what
am I thinking oh I think it dropped to
okay we got 2024 Oh baby okay use
fortune on it you can that's a big
difference although I guess there was
lots of it there doesn't matter too much
all right yeah
today I think we're going to focus more
mainly on the new features of the
redstone update snapshot because that is
pretty pretty cool and a big effect on
the game yeah I'm having like I click on
this and then it doesn't pick it up
sometimes see that being very
frustrating if it doesn't change I
thought that's how you make the
day/night sensor I'll have to double
check
maybe maybe let's try mixing with other
stuff too I tap pick stuff up oh man is
brutal I figured we should move to a
spot where we have a little bit more
space so we're up here now I made two of
these already but I'll show you how to
do it just in case for some reason you
are not playing this amazing new
snapshot that's how you make the
redstone comparator I guess let's go
through all the stuff that was added
there's the gold weighted pressure plate
that's the light one there's also an
iron plated pressure plate that's the
heavy one there is the reason I was
having trouble with the the daylight
sensor I guess I was using these old oak
slabs the ones that didn't burn I just
grabbed them from the chest they really
think about it if we use a new oak wood
slab then we can make it
and there's the redstone block oh boy
looks awesome then there's the trap
chest let's make a couple of those this
is a really excellent feature especially
for like custom maps and stuff oh man
CTM maps that's it I can't make the
hopper I think that's about it I'm
probably forgetting something it'll come
to me
all right well one I'll tell you what
happened when the update first came out
the thing I was most excited about was
the redstone block and looks pretty cool
it almost looks like it's giving off
light but it isn't it's got that glow to
it though just cool it's a way to store
redstone in a compressed way not that I
ever have any that I need to yeah I was
excited about because I thought I was
going to be able to make it some awesome
conveyor belts some cool elevator and I
might be able to but it's not as simple
as I thought it was but acts like a
redstone torch very cool you can move it
with pistons this is a thing that sort
of disappointed me the most so and I
hope they change it if you put a
redstone block in front of a piston it
doesn't actually move it like it doesn't
it doesn't power the piston which is
really sad because it's like a
mechanical redstone torch and the idea
is you want to move it places and it and
the easiest way of moving it places is
to put it directly in front of a piston
so it's kind of hoping it would actually
work but it doesn't it moves a player
fat yeah you know what I think it is I
think when Pistons first came out this
is what I remember there was that glitch
where if you put a redstone torch in
front of it it would extend and crash
your game remember that that's like a
year ago and not fixed it so that well I
think the way he fixed is by making it
not
power the piston so maybe that's why
it's that way still maybe there's a
technical reason for it I don't know but
I hope they change it and it applies to
any any angle actually let's try ASCII
yes it doesn't get powered I think it'll
push it up eyes I thought I was going to
make a cool elevator or something though
oh well tada
and it has that too by the way if you
take the power away it powers the piston
then so that's kind of interesting very
cool nonetheless I'm sure while there's
already been a few cool things people
have made with it um the date nights but
the daylight Oh daylight sensor not
day/night sensor that's right because
it's only the text day although you can
invert the signal 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
13 14 15 it's only making it up to here
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 this variable
redstone thing is a great addition to
the game I I kind of hope they go back
and change some of the older stuff too
like I think of glowstone lamps how cool
would it be if you could like have a
variable light adjustment to it like if
it's only sending power one block it
only gives off one one light if it's two
blocks away no no reverse reverse that
if it's extending all the way like fit
like 15 blocks and it's only light level
1 and 14 would be light level 2 13 would
be light level 3 kind of have adjustment
to that although we might want to block
for it entirely that was added or yeah
we got these weighted pressure plates I
haven't actually tried these the thing I
was mostly playing around with in
creative was the hopper I really want to
make an automatic broom stand
at some point so the more items we throw
on this the farther the signal is going
to go let's go on three four five six
seven eight
it goes pretty quick I think it's 57
items to get up the full power for the
gold one and then the can't remember
what the iron one was but it's like
several like I don't want to put a
number out because I'm going to be wrong
but I think it's around forty stacks of
stuff to get it full powered I know it's
more though
or or round there so I think if we throw
this full thing on it
I just let's just try one yeah one will
get it going what I throw there stack a
redstone makes it go to three pretty
cool only four items oh not players what
I kind of hope they do like we have the
stone pressure plates that detect
players and mobs and stuff I kind of
hope they apply this variable redstone
to it as well and maybe give each mob
its own special weight like like
chickens would be a light mob and cows
would be a heavy mob and we could use
that to detect mobs or like a baby cat
would be lighter than a an adult cow
that would be awesome
so yeah you can see it's it's nighttime
and this daylight sensor is not putting
out a signal at all throughout the whole
night it doesn't put out a signal it's
only like early sunrise to late sunset
that you'll get a signal from it oh is
this a creeper
speaking of that let's try this out I
want to I haven't actually tried it on
your ground and for what I wanted to
build today we'll be putting that under
ground all right so should might need a
direct line to this guy oh no yeah cuz
it's early early sun rise because we
just slept so it should get further and
further as the day goes on then midday
it's at full strength pretty sure the
two yet let's do it one alright anyway
moving on we have redstone comparator
compare that comparator I think I'm
saying that right another excellent
addition that adds there's a lot of
functionality to such a to a single
block which is what I like about what
words what Mojang does or what notch did
you know just takes simple concepts and
you can use them in so many different
ways so this thing it will compare two
redstone signals the length of the
redstone so this is the main side here
so that a II as people call it if I puts
right it if there's no power coming from
the sides it will go right through if if
this same signal is stronger than this
one it will cut off the signal if we
have it even it goes right through and
if we have it further away it goes right
through so you only
again this is another thing I haven't
played around with too much okay sorry
about that I got a little distracted
trying some things with this and it it
led on to a few other things and a few
more things and oh man I am I am
fascinated with it that it is really
cool uh okay first of all it sort of
works as a repeater sort of not really
alright so that only extends its yeah
you I'm still learning here now this you
can see the signal goes up to here up to
that soil block if we add one let's just
hat add it halfway down extends it to
blocks and none other two blocks if we
see here
OOP if we move it all the way back by
the torch does it go further I can't
remember now all right still only two
blocks and a two-box every time okay
this thing it has a little bit of a
delay to it as well it's very very short
though all right
but we can kind of use it as a repeater
like that like it's fast
can't tell if that's a visual it's
visually updating or if it's actually
pretty close to instant I can't can't
really tell maybe let's put torch at the
end here I like I don't want to use my
inventory at all anymore I hate it so
much it's so hard to do anything with
the being all glitched out alright yeah
there's a delay to it that's what I
thought I dad's doing some weird stuff
with it if you do you do this like that
you put a torch down stays powered right
kind of like a repeater does if you
remove the torch you can see them slowly
fades out really neat if you extend it a
little bit further though seems that too
far it'll start pulsing like this that's
that's really cool if we put repeaters
around it we can see that a little
better not all of them just just the
ones over here these two actually pulse
these ones stay stay on all the time
wondering if you can use it like as a to
wave or Peter it's not really meant to
be a repeater though oh yeah also you
can use it as a clock let's let's set
that up I'm wondering how it compares to
a redstone clock if you make it go
faster stay bleah alright do this
very neat if we shorten it I don't think
it works that's too fast I'm using a
torch so what else what else so there's
a negative thing too as well if you
right-click it that light turns on it
like does a subtraction apparently two
three four so this is it three we're
going to have a hard time demonstrating
this because I don't know exactly know
what I'm doing
I think be yeah the other side has to be
further out is it oh well that pulsed
you see that mmm
that's a monostable circuit right there
that's what I see that's a very simple
monostable circuit if you just want a
quick pulse yep
that's kind of cool but you can turn
that into T flip-flop and all kinds of
crazy things let's use a real piss a
sticky piston here learning as I go I
should probably just cut this up I'm I'm
not very focused at the moment I'm just
trying to random stuff okay what was I
doing just this yep hmm yeah here's a
pretty simple T flip-flop you can make
with it piston one if you use a redstone
block I have this on the subtraction off
on off on and it's sort of adjustable
like if you decided I don't want it to
be a T flip-flop anymore turn that off
and it's not or another thing you can do
is just change that and now it's not a D
flip-flop that's kind of cool
okay it looks like there is a way of
making a stable clock out of this that
is SuperDuper fast if you if you put
these on subtraction and do a loop like
this what so as long as getting power
it'll pulse like that it's very very
fast does cause a lot of lag though so
it's not really good thing also there's
another cool thing you can do with these
using dispensers if you just took up a
dispenser too it's put items in power
it's shoots it out extremely quickly as
quick as possible that's really cool I
think in this patch also they fixed the
dispenser bug which is I'm kind of sad
about it to be honest oh maybe not okay
sweet they did yeah I was worried they
did I thought I read they did whoo sweet
that means my firework show should still
work on the minecraft server all right
guys I came up with a pretty fun way of
doing an RS nor latch here as well just
two sticky pistons and two redstone
blocks if you press it nothing happens
if I go to this one switches does it
matter how many times I press it doesn't
switch again
uh-huh whoops
oh man is crazy this piston he wanted
this redstone block right but when he
went forth this guy he wanted it too and
they both reach for it at the same time
and and they're their best friends and
they can't decide who gets it so nobody
gets it uh-oh now we've really done it
mm-hmm yep there's your problem
nobody
I don't usually gets motion sickness
guys but even I have my limits and then
the three businesses they start to play
a game of keep-away the guy in the
middle he got the redstone block and the
guy on the Left he's like give it to me
give it to me and he puts his arms up to
try take it and then the guy on the
right he does the same he puts his arms
up to try take it and the piston in the
middle he's like no you can't reach it
Rainn get lost man seriously nobody
likes you
thank you okay I thought this was kind
of interesting these are like exact
opposites and you know what happens when
you do this right burns out what do you
think is going to happen if I do it on
this one no change
hello man that's a lot of guys I just
wanted to let you guys know I have been
working on this mushroom farm with
little bits here and there that's at the
point where all these detectors are
working oh oh oh oh dear one second
we're good for good that was pretty
close though I'm not gonna lie
yeah I've been working on that still
plan on finishing it all though with all
this automating automating of stuff I I
really want to start making new farms
for like everything but until it comes
out I'm not going to worry too much
about that
sorry I'm not going to actually get to
this idea today unfortunately I've
dripped around too long with the
redstone and I have to go to bed but
I'll try to get that done for next
episode and I'll show you but here is
the question I have picked out for today
which actually goes along with what I
was saying
II throw in some of your videos you
mentioned that that's all the recording
time you have for that day
do you specifically a lot time for
recording each day also about how much
time is between maybe we'll just take
this first part first of all I do I try
to start early in the day with my
recording so I can get it done I find I
keep I keep going though until I'm out
of time for the day I wanna when I say
that I mean it's past midnight I gotta
go to bed and I should not be recording
any longer but yeah I try to start as
early as I can it helps but usually I'll
just keep going and just do more stuff
in an episode if I have more time also
about how much time is between the
recording and editing process if you
mean like play time there's there's
actually a thread on the reddit today
about that how much play time versus
actual recording time I would say I play
at least 10 times more than I record
like play time versus record time if I
have a 20 minute episode I've played at
least 200 minutes I would all even more
than that I'd say at least four or five
hours per episode
but yeah editing I am I'm known as a
very lazy editor all I do is basic
cutting and stuff that's it's nothing
fancy I would like to get something some
fancy stuff eventually but yeah I don't
spend a lot of time editing usually five
to ten minutes max per video unless I'm
doing something a little bit out of the
ordinary like adding background music or
something like that which I don't do too
often or speeding stuff up keep making
your videos they're always really
entertaining why thank you very much
thank you everyone for watching have a
good day I'll see you again next time
lately
and then use it this time we're gonna
shoot out what oh alright
yeah bye guys