oh and this one
do-do-do-do-do-do oh yeah all done
alright so hello everybody this is Ito
and welcome back to the let's play
series now all my time playing this game
I don't think I ever did that with
trapdoors before there's like probably I
think four or five hundred of them at
least in this farm so yeah we are over
here at the the brown mushroom farm guys
you remember this I went to go use it
today and it's like oh yeah this isn't
finished is it because I think when we
built it I spent like two or three
episodes on it and a whole ton of
off-camera work on it and kind of got
fed up with working on it so I just left
it mostly finished but now I think it's
pretty much done for sure what I want to
go use it today is like wait a minute
there's redstone on the ground still
like there was for I think three buttons
and the lever on the ground is like okay
what order do I pull these or push these
I couldn't remember so I set up like a
control panel area here to kind of help
me out if I ever forget how this works
all just read the sign here and I'll
I'll figure it out so step one is the
plants plant the brown mushrooms and all
these little spots here we have brown
mushrooms in the corners right so
they'll spread to the middle there
automatically on their own but if we
want we can plant them to speed it up to
you guys an extras over here step two is
to grow and conveniently there's a sign
right next to this that says pressed to
grow so before we had to press or pull
lever to get the bonemeal to work and
then we had to press a button to push a
mushroom stalks out of the hole there
now it's all in one lease this button
will do both of those functions so if I
press this here the bonemeal going all
the mushrooms are growing
and then wait for it wait for it once
that finishes he pushes mushroom stocks
out of the hole there too so we combine
those two things into one thing and then
step three is to harvest and step four
is to collect so once we finish
harvesting here we just got press that
button and it's pretty much all done so
I just added some trapdoors here so that
hopefully when we walk along here I was
having issues with a couple random
blocks not getting harvested and stuff
I'm hoping this will make it a bit more
uniform and so far it's looking really
good actually let's take a gander down
here once we get to the end yeah that's
way more consistent now is these trap
doors because they bring us forward a
little bits and I can just like light
along them too as we go here I don't
have to worry about my positioning deal
being a little bit too forward or a
little bit too back now
so that's all good all right we've got
all the middle stalks chopped down so
now we run over here we we finished the
harvest process and we just have to hit
that button to collect all the drops
together so that does two things it
ejects the water which also retracts it
after a certain amount of time and then
it also dispatches the minecarts to pick
up the drops you hear him go down you
see the blocks disappear there so all
the minecarts get released now to pick
up the mushrooms in the hole there and
of course the whole point of this farm
is to produce mushroom blocks as fuel
for our super smelter which I noticed
was about out that's why I had to come
here to chop more down all right it's
very good very good how's this doing
oh we just about got a full load yeah
I'll help it along automatically
releases when it gets filled up over
goes over to the super smelter to drop
off the items and then they'll come back
and get more
Oh what damage me there that was weird
alright everybody so we're over in the
end now I had an idea here which might
be a little bit fun I want to see a
wither fight a dragon or see if they
fight each other right and who wins if
they do fight each other I'm not sure so
what I'm gonna do I'm gonna spawn in a
dragon then I'm gonna bust the crystals
and then spawn in the wither so that the
dragon doesn't heal um because I'm I'm
curious like what happens exactly and
hopefully the way there doesn't blow up
a bunch of stuff here I've never fought
a wither in the end either oh now it
turns purple oh I was wondering why the
night vision worked actually everything
turned purple again here's our chance
here's our chance go go go go go go oh
man I only brought four Souls and I'm
such an idiot
okay we did it we did it whoo it's also
a chance for us to get these new
achievements that came out too
so that's cool double boss bar check
that out I've never seen that before
okay and her dragons taking damage
oh he's fighting fight an Enderman okay
alright I'm gonna try not to get close
to him so that it doesn't get focused on
me hey you come on they're right by each
other oh now I think they're yeah he's
locked on he's locked on it here we go
we got a real fight now oh don't come
this way okay no damage really happening
where there took a little bit there I
think good blew itself up
oh they blew up my mind Kurt just get
him get him
you can do it you can do it his aim is
horrible he's never gonna do it
about now
oh this is not a good place to be
I've got to get out of here
okay I got an Enderman Emmie
wait if I stay oh no I still get hurt
yeah it's it's not really working guys
I'm gonna try to take the dragon out
first and then the wither yes
because they're doing no damage to each
other or if they do they just heal up
anyways wait the Dodge there that's 15
degree turn really threw me off you got
some moves okay what happened to the
wither I haven't heard him in a while
kind of worried he's blowing stuff up I
got a lot of stuff till to the end and
the final swoop and you are out of here
oh you're still having fun over there
right by the ice road okay I actually
don't know if I can kill the wither he's
the problem
please get away from here come on this
way please this way good job okay
[Music]
why didn't I bring my chestplate oh I
didn't finish eating why
got him whoa let's get out here before
Anderman kills us all right so that was
that was interesting kind of a mistake
but now I know what kind of damage did
he do here I got to tear this thing down
anyway so nuts you worried about that
but they the old ether out here I don't
want to repair seems fine seems okay
yeah cuz we we took this and rebuilt it
there the Enderman farm anyway you
really did any damage this is double
check down here Q looks okay yeah I
don't see any damage on that bridge
either so I think we're good
you know what I thought fighting the
wither in the end there was gonna be
really tough but I think it's actually
easier to fight the wither in the end
than the overworld like I thought I was
gonna look at all the Enderman and then
they were gonna kill me well while the
way there also kills me but they seem to
go after the wither more than anything
and the wither easily got distracted
with them and stopped attacking me and
plus like in stone has high blast
resistance so normally get stuck in
holes while fighting the wither and then
that's what kills you but anyways guys
I'm pretty excited about today you know
what's special about today it's my
favorite day its new project day that's
right
so by the way with his ice farm you guys
said if I real aughh it will fix the
invisible minecart glitch and yeah that
works
came back to it it was fine but I was
thinking about it there's an item in the
game now where you cannot possibly farm
enough of it I don't think and that's
ice like this farm takes a couple hours
to fill up I think to get the 10 by 10
by 10 cube 1000 nice blocks you know I'm
a blue ice you'll get from that when
this is fully filled up twelve twelve
blue ice blocks because it's 81 regular
ice each one
so our agenda is to build a new massive
scale ice farm that's what I want to do
so I'm trying to think of like how to do
it right now maybe we'll talk about some
some design aspects and making a nice
farm because I think it's a pretty
interesting thing actually so let's talk
about this I want to build the best
possible ice farm right well how do you
define best I think in Minecraft when it
comes to building farms there is no best
really I think that's a subjective term
it comes down to maybe five main
categories and then you pick aspects of
those categories you're looking for and
those are the size of the farm
how difficult is it to build how
efficient is it in terms of production
how efficient is that in terms of
harvest and use those two are kind of
related to each other so maybe just
efficiencies that category
it gets broken down and then there's
that creative aspect of a farm as well
so sighs let's let's give this as an
example I have a five by five by five
farm that produces a hundred items and I
got a four by four by four farm that
produces only one which of those farms
is the best well if you only have a four
by four by four space available it's the
one that only makes one because you
can't use the other one right so that's
that's how you got to think about it so
in terms of size with ice farms doesn't
really matter because you can freeze
water in a one by one just a single
block space right so it's just how much
do you want to scale the ice farm in
terms of difficulty to builds let's look
at this farm for example lots of bist
ins right it's expensive there's lots of
rails so in terms of cost it's not very
good in terms of like intricate design
does it take a long time to put together
I would say so
so this farm kind of isn't very good in
terms of building rights efficiency of
production let's analyze that we have
only 20 water spaces where that the ice
can actually be produced and then they
get pushed over and
up in like a 14 by 10 area so we're not
making good use of the space which
matters a lot when you're trying to
produce a lot of ice there's only a
certain amount of space around you where
the ice will freeze so how much does
that matter I'm not sure yet but this
farm is not very good in that terms in
those terms also when the ice is
produced it doesn't instantly get pushed
over you see that
so that spot right there is not being
used once the ice is made until it gets
moved to side right so it's not good in
that way either in terms of efficiency
of harvest or use it doesn't have any
auto collection systems like it doesn't
bunch the ice into chests and and that
you have to pick all the ice up manually
but it is really quick to harvest
because all the ice gets pushed into a
bit cube so you don't have to like run
around harvesting ice it's all in one
place all condensed right so it's really
that's where this farm really shines
that's it's its key aspect and then
creativity you know you might want a
really efficient farm but you might want
a farm where your farming slimes and
you're making them fall out of a nose so
it looks like they're boogers there's
there's things like that to consider as
well when making a firm right yeah so
with all of that in mind guys what is
going to be the best possible farm for
us what are we gonna design around well
we want efficiency of production and
harvest we want to basically produce as
much ice as possible with the least
amount of effort that's our goal and
anything like the size of the firm and
how difficult is it to build any
creative aspects of it are gonna come
second place
we just want a lot of ice okay so I
thought we would look at the original
ice farm here as well the ice tray as a
good example for us what do we need to
actually make ice we need that cold
biome this biome got switched to taiga
so this farm doesn't work anymore
actually so we need to find a cold biome
and then you need water with access to
the sky
you can't stack the water
on top of each other vertically and if
you have like any blocks above the water
then it won't freeze so you need you
need to spread out horizontally pretty
much in order to make the firm bigger
and then you also need a seed block so
if you have just a big open water source
like this the ice isn't gonna start
forming in the middle at all it'll start
at the edges and then go towards the
middle because you have to have water
with at least one non water block next
to it so if there's ice or something
else next to this water block here then
it'll freeze but if and horizontally I
mean so if you're standing here this
water block has water here here here and
here so it can't freeze but if you're
standing here water water nope nope no
good but we have a dispenser here so
this will freeze all right those are
kind of the criteria we got to think
about so this pattern here that I did
with this original farm is actually the
most efficient in terms of like every
water block has at least one non water
block next to it so all these waters can
freeze at the same time they don't have
to wait for the ice to spread at all
alright everybody so now that we got
that all covered let's start designing
our ice farm here how are we gonna put
it together one thing I realized is I
don't think we can have both perfect ice
production and and harvest speed I think
we gotta choose which one we would
prefer cuz perfect ice production is
that pattern we saw at the ice tray
there with the cedar blocks mixed in and
that kind of spiral pattern while if
we're going for perfect harvests speeds
we want like a solid sheet of ice here
with no other blocks mixed in we just
want solid ice rights and I think we're
gonna want it at at eye level here one
issue I had with the ice farm always if
it is if it's one block lower you got to
tilt the camera down and then you like
constantly have to swing the camera
around to like get the blocks right it's
it's a bit annoying so we want it at eye
level so we can just move that move left
and right and not worry about the
the camera position as we're harvesting
right so let's do let's do a little test
here how far can we actually reach
because I think we're gonna go for
perfect harvest speeds how far can we
reach here so it's four blocks one two
three four yeah I think yeah if we're
aligned to the front here the very
fronts we can reach one extra so we
might want to try get all five but let's
just see how a sweep goes here okay
you're ready for this
[Music]
okay so kind of like with the mushroom
farm we're leaving some blocks behind
we're not even getting all four four
rows there so I don't think we're gonna
try to get all five we'll try to just do
a solid four and just thinker with our
settings here so right now we have
efficiency five hey Stu and speed two
maybe let's try decrease down to speed
one so we go a little bit slower and
maybe we'll get all all four blocks
perfectly you know excellent alright
we're gonna do another sweep here this
time with speed one and haste too so
it's gonna be a bit slower okay we
almost got them all but there's three
stray box left here yeah so this time no
speed just tastes - and efficiency five
let's go again
perfect we missed one at the start there
but just because I think the clay block
was there and let's just do one more
test here this time I got rid of the hey
stop the beacons so no speed no haste
just efficiency five let's try it out
it kind of stuttered that start there oh
why are we getting even more now wait a
minute I did not expect that we
obliterated four rows and we're starting
at five even I'm guessing I just wasn't
aligned to the front of the the block
when we had haste to on so I'm just
double-checking again I'm gonna make
sure I glide along the front so we can
reach all five and see if it's the same
yeah so is this a faulty test so they're
they're the same winter without beacons
so that's kind of good we don't need to
have a beacon with our firm then that's
gonna save a lot of costs and set-up
time all right so next up here let's
consider how we're gonna do the auto
collection system because we don't want
to pick up all the ice drops manually
our inventory is gonna fill up very
quickly we want to be able to pick it up
automatically and drop it off in chess
without us having to think about it
ideally so I think there's gonna be two
main options either we use hopper
minecarts
or we use water streams so this is one
possible way we could set up the ice so
you stand on the trap the trap doors
here right and kind of like we did there
you just jump across or whatever all the
ice is gonna fall and trap doors and
then the hopper minecart will run
underneath them can I do the can i push
it around
yeah so you see it picked up the dice or
hopefully you saw that so that's one
idea let's try maybe a water stream
method as well because I kind of think
that's gonna be better hmm
you know I thought this was a good idea
I thought this is gonna be our final
final plan but now I'm thinking about it
it's got a couple flaws but we might be
able to make it work so I thought we
would have like water that doesn't
freeze over here running all along and
then when you remove the ice it'll it'll
flood the pool automatically right but
also hopefully when the water rushes
back it'll push the items over the edge
you might need to replace the red clay
floor here with the ice as well just so
the items move better but one big issue
with this I just realized is since
there's no seed block there it's only
gonna spread from this no it won't
spread from the sides it will only
spread and maybe from the trapdoors hmm
I don't know if trapdoors count as a
seed block though it might need to be a
solid block I'm gonna watch it for a sec
oh yeah we got ice here so trapdoors can
spread the ice well just for now let's
not worry how the ice is going to spread
and how though the water is gonna refill
here and all that stuff let's just try
to test if the water will push the ice
over the edge here after its harvested
so yeah so touch we're gonna do a sweep
across here
okay oh so you see some got stuck there
okay so I guess let's give this a try I
think it has some potential I got rid of
the wall of water that doesn't freeze
along the edges and instead we're gonna
try use dispensers full of water buckets
right so the advantage of that is the
ice will actually be able to spawn along
the edges so you can spawn here it can
spawn here and then it just has to
spread from here to here and from here
to here so to spreading --zz which means
ice production should be reasonably be
reasonably fast with this method as well
so as we as we run along here to harvest
when we get to the end of a section
we'll step on a pressure plate and then
that pressure plates can activate a
double pulse here which will eject the
water from the dispenser and then pick
it up right after that'll work right
yeah just thinking about it
and then the redstone goes all along
here's all the dispensers then we have a
bit of a weight here I got eight ticks
hopefully that's gonna be long enough so
that it'll just the water will just come
out on the the edge there first which
means they'll give it a bit of time to
push the items over and then after a
little bit's these two dispensers will
activate and then the the pool will
refill hopefully unless it freezes we
might need to add some freeze protection
to this to while the sequence is going
on but I guess we can give it a try
right did I forget anything I think
we're okay this automatically just step
on the pressure plate why hmm
maybe the timing wasn't right I get
dejected the water and picked it up
before it
look good let's do another test here so
I replaced the bottom here that used to
be clay with ice so the items will slide
across faster the downside so we gotta
be careful we don't mind it right so
we'll see how this goes
hopefully I got the water fixed now I'm
not sure yet
beautiful we see all the ice is kind of
scattered throughout step on this yeah I
got the water perfect now oh my goodness
hmm Paul didn't get flushed off all
right everybody so I think we're getting
pretty close to a good design here you
might have noticed some of the ice
blocks were jumping outside landing on
the trapdoors and stuff so I've added a
lip all-around raise it up one block so
hopefully all the ice stays within the
rectangle now I think that the water
streams figured out hopefully maybe
we'll see and kind of the idea with this
is we perfect one of these sections and
then we take it and we copy it like 50
times or whatever and hopefully by the
time we get to harvesting the fiftieth
section when we get back to the first
one all the water will be frozen and you
just go in a constant loop of of
constant harvesting rights that's kind
of though the goal is this so let's give
it another try here I've been doing lots
and lots of trial of their trial and
error here I think we're getting close
yep so they all got washed down make
sure all the waters are proper so again
I don't know if it's an issue with like
the water freezing before the dispensers
pick picked it up again
that's the one thing I'm concerned about
but if that's not an issue I think we
got just about figured out here so
that's cool if that is an issue what we
might end up doing is like adding
Pistons above the dispensers so that the
piston head extends while the water is
ejected and then it retracts when the
Spencer gets the water again so make
sure it doesn't freeze before it picks
it up because the piston head should
stop the water from freezing cuz it
blocks the skylight all right but I'm
not sure if it's an issue but anyways
guys I think we are about out of time
here for today so we're gonna wrap up
we'll try finish that next episode or or
at least build a lot of it unless the
update comes out then we might focus on
that instead correct me if I'm wrong
though does does update break any of the
water mechanics with what we just did
today hopefully not I don't think it
does right I should probably test it
before I go large steel but anyways the
comment of the day says you talked about
boat roads being the best for long term
long-distance nether travel have you
seen side crafts piston bolts they're
much faster than boat roads even blue
ice but they require huge amounts of
infrastructure and are extremely
complicated to build relative to boat
roads thoughts yeah I've seen them
they're really cool I think for the last
few years there's always been like a
fast method of travel in Minecraft like
a really fast method but they're all
like based on glitches right correct me
if I'm wrong so I've pretty much always
avoided them and even though Mojang say
they're not changing or tampering with
pistons anymore
they still are so I'm a hesitant to do
anything like that because I'm pretty
sure it'll break eventually I might be
wrong about
that that's why I've always avoided that
kind of fast travel stuff I'd rather get
something more reliable that I know will
work long term because this is a long
term world right uh-huh
anyways guys if you have any thoughts or
ideas for the ice firm or anything else
please let me know in the comments but I
hope you enjoyed today's episode thank
you for watching and I'll see you again
in the next one take care bye bye
[Music]