[Music]
oh
this guy this guy is ripping me off
he's locked out on the flesh trade
locked out on redstone
locked out on glowstone i have never had
it where it's
it's locked out on lapis afterwards
let's see if today is the day
it's looking good nope refreshed
all right we're back in business here
yeah so welcome back guys to another
episode
of the let's play series if you haven't
heard
something pretty exciting minecraft
1.11.1
four ones is uh is out now
and they released a snapshot the other
day with a bunch of bug fixes and i
thought it was for 1.12 i thought it was
the first snapshot
but no it's actually released already
and in it
they've they've introduced a new type of
flying using fireworks
it's pretty cool we're gonna check that
out later
but uh before we do they have also
nerfed bows you can no longer combine
mending with infinity so i'm gonna try
stock up on a few of them
uh before i update here all right guys
so let's do this we got a hundred
and thirty levels to spend here it's
gonna be the biggest enchanting spree i
have ever done
whenever i get over 100 levels you know
what i do i save them
i want to see how how many levels i can
get right
and then i always just die and i lose
everything
then afterwards it's like why did i do
that why didn't i just spend them what
was the point of that
it didn't make me feel good when i lost
them all
just made me feel bad so this this is
the first time i'm actually going to
spend them when i get over 100
and oh my goodness we're getting tons of
bows here
so what we're looking for is punch two
bows or anything within breaking on or
or things like that something i'm just
add mending to hopefully
oh yeah so i think that's 34 bows
we got from this enchanting spree and
let's just take a little quick look
through them
anything with infinity or punch two on
breaking three that's a great one
i don't have to do too much to that to
turn it into this is what i want ideally
punch to infinity mending unbreaking
three
uh if it has power on no can't use that
for flying
uh like this one for example that's
great except for the power four
oh wow look at that i should probably
also make a like a good wither fighting
bow
or a few of them if i can so yeah
let's just take a quick look through
here my concern is
like they nerfed the bows
uh people probably won't be flying with
bows anymore because the fireworks are
way better for flying
but they might decide that hey we gotta
nerf this as well
and if they do that they'll have nerfed
the bows and the fireworks and then
you know people might get sad so i want
to make sure i at least have the bows
just in case the fireworks get super
nerfed
uh okay so i got a few things to show
you here today guys
i've done a lot of work in the world off
camera here
i've been trying to get done some of the
boring jobs i didn't really want to do
or show too much on camera and one of
them here is the tree farm
so this is what it looks like with no
trees in here
it's kind of crazy uh for the longest
time i wanted to
finish the roof in here so we had like a
section of about like that done
uh and i wanted to copy this pattern
over to the rest of it and i
finally did it and i think it looks
pretty cool right
i tried to do it as random as i could
and i really like that pattern i might
do it more in the future
before it was just these little squares
throughout and it looked very uh plain
and symmetrical
but now it's kind of crazy and cool um
you don't notice it too much when the
trees are in here but
yeah wanted to get that done i also
added a
thing of dark oak all around here is a
kind of a separator
now we got to finish up the walls in
here that's the only thing i'm not sure
what to do with them i might try to make
a giant mural
all around of some sorts
could be cool this is like the oldest
part of the man cave if you didn't know
so it's it looks really bad
so this is this helps it out a little
bit
i can't change too much without like
wrecking
history you know so i'm just doing what
i can
hopefully i come up with something cool
for the walls but even if i have an
amazing roof and amazing walls just
because the floor is so ugly
it's not going to be a great room no
matter what i do oh yeah and i want to
show you guys
the netherward farm too before we uh run
off here
when i was building this i can't
remember if i tried it but i
i changed this over to path blocks
instead of the grass
it's much better right i think that's
what we should do so i'm gonna
i'm gonna get rid of the grass here
switch it over it's
it it doesn't uh stand out quite as much
that way it's more
within line of the colors we've used
yeah there we go that's a lot better i
think
we'll go with that for now also let's
try to change out the glass here
since we got rid of the green the green
grass let's change the green glass
we'll turn it either yellow or orange
probably look good um
yellow versus
orange i'm thinking orange is gonna be
the one because we have all these magma
blocks right
yep that's right you're never wrong
so guys something else i did here today
is i
finished fixing the zombie pigment farm
it's working again it's wonderful
i figured we've spent so much time
building
testing fixing this farm already you
guys are probably getting a little bit
bored of it right
so uh did it off camera here and
no joke spent over eight hours on this
today
eight hours fixing this farm on top of
what we did before
because uh the piston translocation was
was removed from the game so had to redo
a lot of the
functional parts of the farm and it took
eight hours i don't know why it took so
long but it did
um yeah so now here's how it's working
we have the xp coming
up to us in the middle here stand on a
trapdoor and you can pick it up through
it
and i just let's hop down below
you see that we have oh totally missed
everything
let's go back up now it's not perfect
you see all the xp
on the on the ice here
might do something about that still uh
it's because it's shooting the zombie
pigman with the slime launchers before
everything
settles i believe and when it does that
the xp doesn't always travel the same
distance
so you got to let xd settle before you
push it you see how it pushes it like
that
right to the middle usually it's fine
but over time
a lot of it does end up on the ice here
but i'm okay with that and then the rest
of it it goes up like that
we got two launchers on the way um
you see there's no wires connected to
them they're they're independent
from things and there's a lot of items
here you can see that
it's just because the hoppers aren't
fast enough to pick up all the items
um another issue with it but i'm fine
with it
uh because to get around that we have to
have two filters
double the filters and the farm's gonna
get way bigger
and there's not that many items there
compared to what we're getting i think
anyways ramble ramble so uh
over here is where the item filters up
over there
maybe we'll settle down and just take a
look at it real quick here
so the items funnel down from these
hopper mine carts there's two hopper
mine carts and
like together in each of these things
because
they fill up so quickly when items go by
a funnel down here we got our item
filters
items pass through along here anything
that doesn't get filtered out goes over
there and gets shot out
like all the golden swords and stuff
everything else
goes to these droppers here
you see we got gold knight it's falling
down here after they've been sorted
falls down the tubes tubes don't need to
be that
like all the way to the ground but i did
it anyways
this is all the gold swords and the
garbage for some reason
i think just because item filters aren't
fast enough the hoppers aren't aren't
quick enough
some zombie flesh is getting mixed in
here but
again not a big deal as long as we're
eating the gold
and then it gets sorted into our shulker
box system here
and when they fill up they go up in
these chests here
so every three of these shocker boxes is
i think one stack of gold blocks
so we have like two stacks of gold locks
in here so that's pretty cool
plus we have these and zombie flesh we
can trade for emeralds
pretty easily
but we're going to move on here guys
there is an idea i really want to try
out today
i had this stupid idea for a tree farm
a dark oak tree farm and if we
if we do build this if it works out
we're gonna build it uh probably over
here at the blaze farm area
um it it was a stupid idea but i tried
it out for a little bit and it seemed
like there might actually be something
to it so we're gonna investigate and get
some actual numbers here because i
haven't
figured out the numbers to this just yet
uh but what we're gonna do is set up
some
dirt it's gotta be a two by two with the
dark oak trees
uh if you don't know these are one of
the hardest trees to farm
in the game because they they
have to be two by two they grow branches
and stuff so it makes it
like uh all crazy shaped
and then also actually let's do it like
this
i'm just going to set it up like this
and then remove some of these hoppers i
think
and also they seem to have the worst
sapling droppage
of all the trees in the game like you
have to
pretty much break every leaf on the tree
to get your saplings back you might get
a few extra
but it's pretty brutal let's put these
back
okay so here's the plan i'm gonna drop
off anything important i have on me that
i don't
necessarily need right now my punchbow
don't really need my picks and my shovel
and the sword
we do need the axe though uh
we have our hopper net set up so any
saplings and logs that drop
should get picked up by that and the
idea is we're gonna use
beds we're gonna sleep our trees away
is the plan all the drops should end up
in this hopper right there
that's where i got them all pointing and
i think we're about ready here hopefully
we have enough headroom
uh if not it's about to get bigger so
we grow the tree oh come on
ah we might need more headspace darn it
how many is that one two three four
five six seven all right i'll remove
some more blocks
that should be good now so we grow our
tree
please yes right away good grow our tree
and then
this is kind of a semi-automatic way of
doing it
these hoppers have two functions they
collect our saplings and our wood they
also
prevent fire which is important here
because we're going to be blowing up the
tree with beds
in the nether now if you don't know beds
have a special thing that if you
well any explosion if you're out of the
line of the sight of the explosion
uh it doesn't really damage you so i'm
gonna stand here
and that didn't work at all what
oh no and
there we go guys so that's how you
destroy two stacks of iron in less than
a second
i've lowered the hoppers by three blocks
covered them over with slabs just in
case
uh hopefully they're far enough away now
so we got 27
saplings let's put our dark oak and
chest here
this chest is empty okay
so we got to do this in two steps two
beds per tree
grow another tree i made this room a
little bit bigger again so
two blocks up is where we put the first
bed always and i've tried this a few
times it never destroys the dirt below
that i've had happen anyways
oh this is why i didn't want to put
these here
what else could i use instead of
obsidian hmm
[Music]
oh and we lost the slab uh oh okay
how are we doing right now so we got six
and three so we're getting our saplings
back right and look at all the leaves up
there still
then you would have to do the rest of
the tree
with another bed and hopefully have some
way of like getting up here
actually there's not much left to this
tree sometimes they're a little bit
bigger than others
okay i should probably grab
my shovel where's my shoulder
oh it was purple i couldn't see it
it blended in too well okay
and then to get the second bed somehow
have a way of placing it up there i
haven't figured out how to do that yet
jump and then activate it and that's the
whole tree
so from that one tree we have six on us
it's only 12 logs four saplings
okay so that is not looking too good to
be honest i was hoping for better
numbers but we'll try a couple more
trees
we could use ender chests instead of
obsidian i just realized so these would
be blast proof
but they won't catch on fire so that
that's an idea
if this is if there's any merit to this
this is
i'll use enter chests this is the plan
let's let's try a few more though just
to see what happens
some trees are taller than others
sometimes the explosion does more damage
so let's just double check
okay first blast lost the slab there
um so we would probably want some sort
of piston device to bring us to the top
of
the tree and drop down on it like this
oh
not like that i just slipped off the
edge yeah like land on the top of the
tree
break a few leaf blocks place the other
bed
dig down it's not really there's a lot
to it isn't there
can i reach that from now from here
from now okay bunch of stuff fell down
let's check our
our chest again very bad
returns we got the saplings back but
only six
logs plus the two we we did ourselves
so yeah it's not it's not a good idea
let's scrap it
yeah so that was a that was a bust guys
sometimes that happens
my ideas don't pan out and rather than
cutting it from the video i thought i'd
show you the experience anyways
uh so we're going to move on to one more
project
also add some leaves up there huh a
little bit better right
i think so one more quick project here
and then we'll check out the
the new release and the features with it
uh over here this is what we call the
musical
mushroom farm and
it's done it's been finished for a long
time except for the musical part of it
uh when you grow the tree it's supposed
to play a musical note
that's what it does right now it's off
tune and and stuff
you guys were supposed to help me with
it i asked you for
for tunes and i didn't get any
so it's been sitting here uh but
i've gotten a little bit better with
note blocks okay i understand a few more
things about music now
and i came up with my own tune so
let's let's get to that i built it in
creative already so i'm just going to
copy it over
and when i say built it in creative
already some people are confused about
that i don't use creative in this world
it's in another world that i built it
and i got to copy it over from that
world to here
is is what i mean
so let's get rid of these underneath
here is where we'll put the
thingy and then i'll show you the
tunings and stuff to it uh once i get it
set up here
so i'm gonna go down maybe um
probably two blocks or so and build it
here
all right guys very cool very cool so i
got it all set up here and tuned
throughout my whole time playing
minecraft i've only tried uh
turning two songs into noteblocks i'm
gonna do it more from now on because
i kind of got the hang of it now uh i
did the cave story main theme
way back in the old world and now i've
done time lapse from the fat rat so here
it is
pretty cool right and i got a special
circuit here so it kind of reuses
some of the note blocks because at the
end of the tune only uh
either splits this way to these two
notes
or else it splits this way to these two
notes so rather than doubling the size
of all this we have a
specialty flip-flop here which
alternates the output
every time it activates so it changes
from locking that repeater to locking
that one
as it goes through the thing
you see that one's locked now that one's
locked
pretty cool right and we could we could
keep it going on a loop if we wanted to
so whenever a mushroom grows we want to
connect it to the circuits
whenever the bud switch on the mushroom
grower activates connect it right over
here and that's all we got to do
all all eight of the mushrooms will
share the same uh tune here
oh yeah and here's the tuning so the
first we have a group 13 20 this is the
number of clicks
to tune the note block then we have 18
16 18
16 13 11 13
13 11
13 and then at the split here at first
it goes this way
16 13 and then it goes this way
eleven eight
emeralds
very cool so we're going to finish up
our episode today checking out the new
updates so we're in 1.11.1
trying out the new uh the flying with
the fireworks
before i updated though i did get the
bose done so we got a few flying bows
here
and we also got a few combat bows
they're not finished but uh
i think we can still work on them after
afterwards hopefully without it breaking
so this is the last time i'm gonna be
able to combine infinity with mending
infinity doesn't last right
uh-huh you can still add infinity but
not with mending
anyways so let's uh let's go above
ground i guess i
got a few fireworks here from the
firework room they have stars on them
i think they should still explode when
you're using them for flight that might
look cool
and we'll also try it out this way
all right oh yeah and you get three
that's right oh that's actually not a
bad deal then
um let's deposit some of these i wanted
to try out
the ones with more gunpowder i heard
they make you fly
longer i don't think they're faster
though i could be wrong
actually let's split it then
yeah okay so we got some
longer duration ones oh it says flight
duration on it
oh that's cool so it actually takes into
consideration
right well i didn't try out the snapshot
so
this is my first time flying this way
i've just seen some videos of it
let's grab our duration ones
and i think you can just fly by jumping
right you don't need the launchers
yeah look at that oh man that is
fast how long does that last for let's
look
let's go into this view
okay so that's like one second right
let's try out
the the threes
yeah that's like three seconds i i think
that's what it means
one two or three seconds okay let's try
out
one with a star oh
yeah oh yeah and they damaged you too i
forgot about that
so maybe and this is crazy
why is it damaging me like when i'm far
away from the firework
because i'm launching this i'm launching
these and they should be far away from
me right
it's it's way back there i'm still
getting blasted though
huh all right let's also try uh
let's try swimming i've heard you can go
super fast in water
oh i messed it up darn it
and you can probably combine the flight
bow with the fireworks right that's the
other thing
oh yeah look at this whole snap
that is so crazy
oh but if you touch the ground that's it
you're gonna jump off the lily pad
though
dude now i kind of want to make a water
base if you can do that
that is pretty sick you can fly straight
up right
yeah we're going straight up
oh you can hear the wind stop when the
firework runs out too
dude this is this is a game changer for
sure
i'm lost i haven't been paying attention
where i'm going
uh what else can we do yeah let's try it
out with the punch bow
because you can get the boost effect
while getting the bow effect because it
kind of lasts for a few seconds right
ah it's not really no it's not really
doing anything
it's not like you go super sonic or
anything
okay okay i just realized something you
can do stuff
you you can't do with a punch bow with
this because that the flight is like
constant right
so you can do like loopity loops almost
oh wait a second like you would never be
able to do that with a punchbowl that
would be so difficult
uh it's great yeah i'm gonna convert
over to using these i wasn't sure but
after
after trying it for sure definitely tops
the bow
and uh let's just double check something
here i'm pretty sure frostwalker only
works when you're watching
but just in case it works when you're
flying that would be pretty crazy
okay here we go
no no ice trail
well i think we're gonna call it here
for today guys had a lot of fun though
hope you enjoyed it
uh we got our comment of the day picked
out it says
do those sand launchers still work
those are he means the launchers in
sandy city here so we we built these a
while ago it was like a worm
that like hopped from one launcher to
the next uh unfortunately though these
did break
i don't know exactly why
like that one's just shooting the sand
straight up i tried to
tried fixing them i think i had to
remove some of these blocks was
was the trick but even after doing that
um guess what happens it's the sand
doesn't launch the same anymore
yeah there it goes you see it broke
so that that kind of sucks before it
would it would fall down
land and then jump to the next one so
yeah anyways hope you guys
enjoyed today's episode we'll play
around with these new features more in
the next episode i got some plans
and uh until then thanks for watching
take care bye bye ouch
oh you can keep going even if you crash
oh that's amazing