oh man this is tough this is really
tough it just it just doesn't feel right
you know like me and Zenith we've been
together for as long as I can remember
now I have a really bad memory but I
remember we went on some good adventures
together we went we went to the nether
and tore it up conquering all types of
harsh terrain swimming through lava like
we were the kings of the world
we even humiliated wither and just
totally destroyed it
no Armour even together and yet it's got
to be done it's got to be done he's got
to be put down he doesn't belong this
guy he's just no no it's got to be done
oh this hurts you a lot more than it
hurts me trust me oh I don't know if I
can finish oh yeah we got to do it we
got to do it I know I know you're oh I
just felt so wrong ah but it was the
right thing to do it really was we can't
have that guy around here it's it's not
right
okay all right guys you can come out now
I took care of him I took care of him
then postures gone Zenith Zenith I know
I know it that was I don't know even
though he had your name it felt like I
was killing you
I didn't like that feeling I know it
wasn't you I wasn't hurting you but it
just kind of felt like it was you know
yeah all right well we took care of that
Zenit imposter he's no more quick quince
identity we have another black horse
here and a brown horse I brought two
horses back from those Plains where I
found Zenith originally I just wanted to
check out what kind of horses I left out
there turns out most of them are not
very good Zenith is probably the best
one they're all really slow a few of
them have like lots of hearts I found
one that had 15 arts but their speed is
very slow most horses
zena's can't jump I know that Zenith is
kind of like maybe above average speed
14 arts that's good something that can't
be matched though is the courage and
that of Zenith which we can't get in any
other horse he fought a wither for
crying out loud like he's good this
other horse I brought back this black
one I might call him second chance I
think he's a little bit faster than
Zenith he's got 13 hearts I think you
can jump a little bit better and I might
stick this guy in the nether and he'll
be our main transport I think I might
skip out doing the rail system and just
use horses instead because with rails
you're your max speed I think is about
eight blocks per set in with the
minecarts horses you can get horses that
go over over 13 blocks per second I
think so it's a lot faster and then if
you use speed potions it gets even
quicker I think that's the way to go
let's let's try this guy out
oops ah leads I don't like leads alright
don't mind this guy he's just
window-shopping that's got 11 hearts
pretty quick oh pretty good jumper
actually I didn't realize that so yeah
we might get into horse breeding at some
point here horse breeding isn't really a
good way of making a better horse but if
you want to keep a large supply of good
horses it's good to get into horse
breeding and I think I may try to breed
a super horse at some point if we find
two good ones we might try to make them
a little bit better it's very very
difficult to do though but we need to
set up the gold farm before we get into
that so that we can have an endless
supply of golden carats for breeding no
no no no no I thought my arrows I can't
shoot them darn it I usually I just
throw away the eggs I find and kill any
chickens that come out of them because I
don't want them all over the place we
are at level 33 here let's do it
let's do a sword enchantment to start
off the episode today we're going to do
a bunch of random projects I think a
little fixed fixer ups around the place
um this little stuff like that I think
would be good alright 33 come on
looting three looting too close only
looting two that's that's pretty rare to
get only that
okay oops I do that all the time I put
my my stuff in here thinking I clicked
on the ender chest and then it just ends
up on the ground and I walk away from it
it's terrible
okay five levels I'm going to name that
other horse second chance
sounds like a racing horse name I think
this is the most gals I've ever had in
this farm there's got to be at least a
hundred all crammed in the small space
and and they're all vibrating like some
atomic structure brand-new looting three
sword
whoa I feel like a lot more that's
awesome another side four and a half
stacks of beef from that harvest I was
nice that's how my cows I left right and
now for the wheat harvest got a nice
supply of leather growing here so I keep
my seeds all right we got a cooking here
and that's a lot of food it's gonna last
me a long time oh yeah
so here's what I want to do today guys a
couple couple little things first of all
this is slime farm we're going to we're
gonna put a switch so that they don't
always come here because I almost avoid
going to this part of the team now
because it's just so stinking annoying
like I I have no desire to build
anything here
just click the noise so let's go alright
and they get out like that
it's just a real real messy situation I
thought it was really cool at first but
after living with this thing for this
long I am ready to shut it off I don't
want to disable it I just want to shut
it off so yeah okay I'm gonna kill them
all before we start because otherwise
we're gonna have to do this one
it is kind of cool I got to say I do the
slime farm is neat it's just really
annoying much better all right so let's
go take a look inside here see what we
can do I want to set up a way to auto
kill them before they get to before they
go up here I think this is the escalator
that take goes up bends around goes to
here and then they start getting split
into their different sizes smaller
smaller ones go down first this is for
medium ones down here and then the big
guys go down the last 3x3 hole they're
looking at the ground though we kind of
need like a 3x3 space to drown them I
thinking mostly stairs don't have much
surface space so probably the place
we're going to have to put a kill trap
is if we cut out a 3x3 area here let's
just block the water for right now 3 by
3 here and a 3x3 area here will have
some Pistons that allow the bigger
slimes to fall down and then we'll drop
them into a bunch of water I guess
probably yeah we probably just need two
Pistons really one here that'll oh no no
no never mind never mind
we needed to go in one block further
actually if we have a piston here can we
do that here no we can't umm that's
because if if we had like a shape like
this the medium and the large slimes
would pass right over top that just the
small ones would fall down so that's one
option
a shape like this would work too
oh no no they want it yeah I think we'll
need two pistons I'm going to mess with
this for a second
well I think we're going to do it like
this
I moved the whole over two blocks this
way it's still a 3x3 hole so if we want
if we want to kill the slimes will have
the Pistons retracted this will be open
big slimes medium slimes small slimes
will be able to fall down there I'm
going to make the hole four blocks deep
so they should be able to stack on top
of each other like if there's a big
slime drowning in the hole another one
should be able to come in and sink down
on top of it so that this doesn't get
backed up or anything and then instead
of having like a piston here and one
over here I decide to do a double piston
extender that is joined together kind of
so we have one over here and one over
here and when we power this does this
alright so it puts a block right in the
middle of the 3x3 hole and since a
medium and a big slime are bigger than
then one block the mediums 1.2 blocks in
size in it a big ones 2.4 so medium
needs a 2x2 hole basically to fall down
and the big one needs a 3x3 so only the
small ones are going to fall down here
if if we have this extended this is like
a a junction in case we want them to go
up to escalator which at the current
time I do not want I don't even know why
I'm putting it in but you know more
options better okay and I ran a align
wire underneath the water escalator and
it comes out to here at the moment so we
might put a a lever out here or
something
to to switch the junction and this
should be able to reach good very good I
put a double chest down here to fill up
with slimeballs
and we're going to do a 3x3 thing of
hoppers I guess probably the easiest way
of doing all this so we'll make them all
go to the double chests and like so can
I do this yeah that works okay cool cool
let's try not to drop anything and I
can't access the chests with that with
this setup but if it comes to a point
where I want to I'm sure I'll change it
around so that it can but I don't really
need slimeballs I have over a double
chest full of them at the moment and
fill this in and since this is a slime
spawning chunk I do not want them
spawning in my wiring here so we're
going to make sure it's only one block
high and all the spaces we can yeah you
this is part of the wall fill that back
and they're there all the wiring sealed
up now let's go try this out so right
now 3x3 hole is open I have a lever just
out here at the moment which we can move
when we figure out what we want to do
but this annexed ends no problem both
sides that's good Oh almost fell almost
fell okay so the last thing we got to do
with this is get the water flowing once
again proper way and we are going to
drop these dirt blocks into the hopper
unfortunately but it's only one space we
lose not a big deal it goes down
all right so there should be solid water
now yeah cool
so the slimes will fall down there and
if the piston extends it shouldn't be a
problem
I'm pretty sure in terms of water flow
and all that stuff I don't think it
messes it up yeah it's good cool so that
is our little Junction now for the slime
farm
well that's cool we got another project
done and check it out 30 levels again
like hardly any time here I don't even
really use my XP farms anymore just
because you get levels so easily now
from other things it's crazy
Oh hooting three smite four knocked back
to fire aspect - that is a zombie pigmen
Z still killin sword if I ever seen one
before
that is awesome um alright that me I
have a big smile on my face now okay so
the next thing I'm a little bit
interested in doing actually no at first
first of all I was considering changing
the glass out of here with ice I don't
know we'll see what it looks like we've
had glass here forever but I kind of
feel like changing it for some reason
huh how about that that looks a lot
worse than I thought it would well it
was worth a try anyways now we know
glass is a little bit better so we'll
keep it with like that and check this
out
peace and quiet yeah
ah so much better I can actually come
here now and not be angry it's wonderful
the other thing I was considering
looking into today is the cave spider
spawners so these have been doing
nothing for a long time now they're not
it does kind of work this this thing
here still
the T spiders fall like so let they get
down to one hit kill and then you punch
them to death
it is it does still kind of work it's
not very well they get stuck in the
water pipes in places and we should try
to make use of this because I'm in this
area a lot and I'm totally out of string
pretty much I have only a few stacks in
the past we managed to get so much from
those two to spawners like I think all
this wall here is from from that string
then you got a little more there I think
there might even be another double chest
somewhere so we've gotten a lot of
string out of this thing and we need
string to finish the gold farm actually
so we should try to set this up my plan
for this thing I'm going to dig out this
8 by 8 section all the way down so that
does this fall to their death and then
collect the string they drop using
hoppers and chests and whatnot we won't
get any spider eyes doing it that way
but I don't mind I just want the string
basically and we might try to keep this
set up though with the water what I
would like to do is put signs under this
water and see when they spawn if they
will fall through the water or if
they'll keep going through the system if
they keep going like if they float on
the water through this we can have an
on/off switch for the fall trap - let's
have a little fun
- shall we um I don't know how this is
gonna turn out it just will see woohoo
you know that sound
Oh
Oh spawners fine spawners fine that's
all that matters
and we lived that's also a nice perk I
seem to have missed all the signs blew
up that's what it was
darn it so we got to dig a 16 by 16
block hole all the way down here we're
not 16 by 16 8 by 8 and 16 deep at least
um so I got up got a dig out the sides
yet and I just have to fix those signs
and I'll be right back that that went a
lot quicker and I thought Oh grass how
lovely I thought I was gonna take a long
time that actually went really quick
gotta love tea and tea grass how lovely
this was made for lamps which is why we
have this ghetto lighting piston moves
blocking frontal lighting makes it dark
spiders can spawned ah
of course he just had to spawn right on
me I'm gonna try not to die here
although I don't mind guy as much
anymore now that we have that cool
respawn area it's almost fun to die then
you skiing again there's actually oh you
know what I never did thinking there's
lots of lighting in here for some reason
there's still quite a bit I think most
of its coming through there that's fine
we're just testing right now so I just
want to make sure they're dying when
they hit the ground here which it looks
like they are I see string here very
good very good to be honest I'm not sure
if they died like if you have fences and
water above if they'll die on that I
think they did before but I should
probably try it out again that's that's
probably what I'll do if that works and
we can just have all that items flow
to one spot pretty easily and it'll go
into one hopper I figured it'd be a lot
quicker just to go into a creative world
here and check it out and it looks like
they survived which is sort of as a
suspecting I didn't make a spawner a
long time ago that did this and it would
kill them but obviously water has
changed where no matter how deep it is
mobs and players won't die if they hit
it hmm
so how should we do the floor in here
then like if we drop them on hoppers
that would work really well but it would
take 64 hoppers to cover the whole floor
we could also set up minecart tracks and
have a hopper cart go by every so often
pick up stuff or we could have ice and
ice floor and like a water stream that
pushes stuff every few minutes
um I'm not too sure in terms of lag and
stuff I think 64 hoppers on the ground
would probably be the best way of doing
it because water updates cause a lot of
lag
although the hopper minecart might be a
good way of doing it - well I'll think
about it
you guys have much suggestions let me
know and let's go check out the lab
that's another thing I wanted to do
today
I've been working on it a lot and it's
just about done I'm very excited to
start it up um I pretty much finished
the Redstone on it - there's just a few
little details like this door needs to
be done like I need a proper trigger for
this this is where all the slimes are
now great jokes with this door I want
like a Secrets trigger to open it I
don't want like a a button or something
I don't think
I'm not sure what I want to do yet
something something cool hopefully and I
did the back of the lamp here now and I
counted it out and it worked out
perfectly so that's the last remaining
ones of these we needed filled up the
rest of the space so I decided let's
just continue with with this wall look
and make it meet up here and we'll have
another door or entranceway or exit way
here that will let us walk through the
lab to a new room like it another room
over here and we'll do something with
the skeleton spawner over here I'm sure
and continue through with the lab I
don't want it like this the dead end or
anything either so this works oh good
and the wiring for all this is like done
actually at that I managed to get most
of it done even down below here I was
starting to hook stuff up just going to
do a few more things with it and we'll
be able to fire it up but pretty cool
I'm excited big project very big project
bigger and I thought I was going to be
when I started it and it will be nice to
be done it I have one more really minor
thing I want to show you guys a little
change up I've done with my my setup
around here I used to have wool in this
vest but I decided to make this my
colored clay chest and I might keep the
dives here I'm not sure but I've taken
all the wool out of there and instead
since I haven't been using this room too
much I just said I would make this my
wool storage room so this is where we'll
keep the wall and stephannie in that
other storage room just try to get it a
little bit more use um but yeah I think
I think that's going to be about it for
today let's go read our comments that I
got picked out here says ESO do you like
drawing or some kind of arts because I
see you have big imagination if you like
then tell
what's your favorite painting of yours
if not then try it out smiley face I'm
not uh I'm not very artistic I don't I
don't feel I'm not a good drawer music I
feel I'm not very musically inclined
either I when I was really young I tried
to learn the piano well keyboard I
should say and I could play a few songs
I never really got it though like I
couldn't compose music or anything like
that
oh um later in my teenage years I got a
guitar and I tried to get good at that
and practiced a bit and I could play
some stuff I never really could compose
music or never really got it I could
read tabs and and notes and stuff but
that's about it
um so not very good I'm not very
artistic I'm not good at drawing or or
music I can't compose music or play
music very well but I do enjoy stuff
people draw and I enjoy music a lot um
as far as what I like um I like pretty
much it voice crack I like pretty much
anything really I prefer like pictures
and an art of scenery I find especially
like computer-generated art like 3d arts
of like futuristic or fantasy scenery
space or you know there's some really
cool computer-generated art out there
paintings are usually about like
pictures of like famous paintings of
pictures of people I don't know and I
don't really care about that kind of art
I guess but scenery and and stuff is
cool so yeah I'm not artistic but I
enjoy arts yeah we'll put it that so
that's going to be all for today guys I
hope you enjoyed the episode
and I hope you have a good day I'll see
you again next time take care bye bye