[Music]
hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to my
let's play series
i am on top of the nether right now we
are about to go
kill a bunch of zombie pigmen i want to
show you how the gold farm is working
here i was up there for
seven minutes i'm i'm being very precise
with my timing here
i want to find the perfect number
because if i go too long there's too
many pigmen
and if it's too short it's not as
efficient when i go kill them so
hopefully this is my first time trying
it while recording
hopefully it's not too too bad oh it's
not too bad
frame rate's a little bit slow but it's
not like we're up to we're at 10 right
now
but i can still do things which is
important accidentally let it go
for let's turn this down for like 15
minutes once
and even without recording my game was
pretty much frozen when i went through
the portal
uh so i built just the cheap little uh
cheap little containment area for them
killing chamber
what are we at here we're at entities
687 so there's probably
maybe five 600 in there
and poison does not work on these guys
did not know that i tried to set up like
this where i just had
dispenser next to it this is gonna hurt
me
oh no it didn't get me but yeah they
don't take poison damage that was
surprising
so i have to find some other way to kill
these guys
might have to install a crusher
and you can see they do that thing where
they fly out of the corners
um and i just set up
just finished setting up this enchanting
area
the way i have it right now when i come
out of the portal up there
i have to drop down i'll probably set up
a platform over here
but for right now i just have a bunch of
instant health
splash potions in here my looting swords
so i equip that when i throw
the potion at them let's try this out
okay so i throw it and then i switch
real quick
and they are mad now unfortunately it
does not just take one to kill him
right now it takes like five or more to
kill them
oh i all forgot to switch here so
could be better you saw we killed a
bunch there
um but some of these guys are actually
at full health
so it takes a lot of hits to kill them
what was that that was number f
four maybe five
six it takes a lot right now so we
should do something about that
go again seven
eight
nine not that it's a big deal i have an
automatic brewing station so it's not
tough to get these
and we get gold from them which is what
we need to make these 10
11.
i don't remember taking this many
all right one more should do it look at
all that xp down there
nope still didn't kill him it's almost
like they avoid some of the damage i'm
not sure
because it shouldn't take that much
all right now i'm getting slow frame
rate
i'm gonna shop these little guys there's
a chicken in there
i like how the xb orbeez bounce around
like that too it looks so cool
um so if we want xp we can just walk up
to it
oh and we must be picked up some of the
gold there too
very good he's just watching us
there's swords gold swords jumping
everywhere
going crazy are they flying out of here
too somehow
um i got books let's do some enchanting
here
knock that two protection four all right
oh i picked up some more stuff so i do
have hoppers underneath but they're
pretty slow
oh man can i not click it yeah you see
stuff is
stuff is funneling through this is
taking a while
i think this is a good start to the
system we just need to make some
improvements to it
all right so let's get another book
going
i'm breaking three yes that's a good one
awesome uh all in all though
the gold farm is working very nicely
from what i've seen i get about a stack
of gold ingots
each time maybe even a little more i
clean it out
just before we start here so we can
check it
all right there's another one
and oh throw that junk away
here
i'm not gonna use it um
[Music]
what was that that's the third book now
they're changing and chanting the game
it looks like jeb posted a tweet about
it how he's
he might make it cost gold or some other
resource in the game
no that's it which is a cool idea
and instead of taking so many levels you
just have to get the level
30 i think and then uh try to stay at
level 30
but it only costs like three levels or
something to actually
enchant all right looks like we got
seven gold ingots
things are still funneling down it's
taking a while
oh there's more in there
so yeah pretty cool
okay everybody so i went through and i
organized things i got a total
telly of how much gold and it was about
a stack and a half of golden gets from
this run
so that's pretty good i would say
um threw all the gold swords over the
edge here
uh i kept the enchanted ones though i
wanted to see what we got
looks like most of them are pretty
gently but
there is this one sharpness three
unbreaking three knockback one looting
one
pretty good 25 durability it's gonna
break very quick though it's a problem
there's also a sharpness two one um
so that's cool these guys they drop 13
gold ingots like
the indian itself that it's a rare drop
you can get from zombie pigmen kind of
like you can get uh
iron ingots from zombies sometimes these
guys will give you
uh gold and gets every so often uh if
you kill them with player damage
so that's where some of those came from
um
we were able to enchant just about four
books so that's cool too
now to improve this thing we do need to
use
or we do need to make some changes we
gotta make the hoppers pick up stuff
faster if we can
we should set up a sorting system so the
zombie flash and the ingots and
all this chicken junk gets separated
maybe find a way to filter through these
gold swords quicker too
um and then we probably should get a
crusher in here the way i'm doing this
right now
the zombie pigmen fall from the portal
they'll get like pushed off usually
there's one guy that stays up there but
all the others they they fall down some
of them will fall to the right and then
it's
just a straight drop down into that that
area there
but some of them get pushed to the left
and then they walk down these like steps
another layer there and then down um
so that works okay but the thing about
doing it this way
the ones that fall to the right they
take more damage than the ones that go
to the left
and same with our spawning floor some of
them take more damage
than other ones so might
need to make a few adjustments i think
what we should do also though is punch a
hole through
the nether ceiling so let's go do that
i fell in this thing and i forgot this
guy is still mad at me
and yeah he he like one shot me stole my
boots and my sword
i got him back though all right let's
head on up to the nether roof
actually just set here as looking at
this
some of the zombie pigmen like they
spawn up there and they fall down
all the way down to here and they take
like 10
blocks of fall damage while others they
might spawn
up here and they'll just gently be
pushed off down to here and then down
again
and take no fall damage when they go
through the portal so
for the crusher to work the best we want
to try to keep them all the same
health levels or as close to as possible
and can't really use lava i don't think
because i don't think they're falling
far enough where they'll all fall
through the lava some of them will get
stuck in it and stay swimming in it
uh cobwebs would be a little slow so i'm
thinking
maybe we can try vines and see how that
goes
let's see this is the first layer here
so we would put i brought some vines
here we could put vines
here
and then we got to prevent them from
growing too as other things so maybe
we could either use stringer buttons or
something
put them over here should be fine and
can we do that on the other side
yes we can okay good so i might try that
out it'll be really hard to monitor if
they get stuck in that though
so we've jumped into a creative world
real quick here just to check
because i won't be able to see this when
i'm on top of the nether anyway
it'd be really hard to figure out okay
it looks like you fell down no problem
let's try different a few different
heights to see if they get stuck in the
vines
seem okay
yeah vines seem to be working when it's
a single vine there comes a point where
they fall far enough
they just kind of fall through the vine
i think
oh yeah there we go
[Music]
okay so that's at this height we're okay
here yeah we're okay there
so i'll have to check the heights and
make sure none of them coincide with the
spawning pad heights
but otherwise it seems to work okay
so i just double checked the heights
here of the spawning pads i don't think
any of the
the pigment will fall through the vines
like we saw at that one height
so that's good um the ones that spawn on
the rights they will fall
far enough to take a little bit of
damage here the ones on the left
won't uh but it's not a significant
amount so i think it's fine still
um we're not we're not aiming for
perfection here it's too late for that
i'd have to redesign
everything to get perfection so
got the vines in place got the buttons
in place oh man
add vine farm to my to-do list because
getting four stacks of vines is a little
annoying uh
i just grew a bunch of big jungle trees
and took them off of there but still
now i made a mistake i can't actually
put buttons here because the pistons are
there so they're just going to push them
off
as soon as these pressure plates get
triggered also
but that's fine even if the vines grow
like this
when they get pushed they'll they'll
break every time
so i think it's gonna work out okay like
we have it here
but let's punch a hole into the ceiling
we are at
negative 43 z11
and up to this point i've been ender
pearling through every time
and that's getting a little annoying to
be honest
um i would like to be able to go down up
and down as i please here
and also i want to someday set up some
beacons here too
what'd i say it's 13 knows that 11.
i think why 43. i think i have the
portal centered
um should i take it out i
i don't know i just i'm gonna remove
this temporarily
all right portal's gone we got some
space here to work with
i did bring a flint and steel with me i
didn't even think of that but i had one
on me so worst case scenario
i could reset up the portal if i got
trapped up here
um so i'm sure a lot of you have seen
this by now
but there is a trick where you can break
bedrock using the the dark oak saplings
goddam has showed us quite a few times
now
um pretty sure
you can do it just by putting blocks
over top but we might need to grow a
tree here
and this is a spot we're aiming for
right here
if possible um
oh no my bone meal i
could have sworn i had it on me
uh oh ah that's annoying
[Music]
it's not there right there's no bones
you know what i did
i i grew a bunch of jungle
trees for the vines i must have dropped
the bones off there
all right i have to reset up the portal
and get out of here
and then come back one more time
stupid bone meal wasting my time
you know it's not gonna grow now too
just to spite me
all right i got a stack of it we should
be able to pull this off
so here we go come
on might need to actually grow a tree
i've never tried this yet
all right let's try grow a tree i don't
think it's working
oh come on
it's because of that thing is that
bugging you
i'll remove it just
just don't be like that
come on let's let's do this here i'm
going to put this back
because if it was that it should still
work with the blocks
you know i don't want to get stuck
okay here we go there it is i don't mind
cutting down a tree
it's a little more work but i can do it
all right then we replace pretty sure it
would have worked
with just blocks
but now i'll never know alright do that
and
oh did it get fixed please tell me it's
not fixed
i didn't punch a hole maybe it doesn't
happen every time
oh no
oh i don't have that many saplings
no it might be fixed
well i ended up starting a tree farm for
saplings up here
i think we're doing pretty good now so
let's try this again i think that's a
random element to it
i'm gonna try
restrict it a little more this time and
hopefully
that will force it to grow down let's do
this
um should we put it
here to really force it
this might be a mistake we'll see
all right let's leave a little opening
um that's not what i was hoping for
let's try it again
oh there we go yay that's what i was
looking for
so that time it grew down i'm pretty
sure
double check oh is this it
ah there we go punched a bit of a hole
one block
one whole block of bedrock removed oh
wait
look at this oh snap that's something
it's not perfect but it's a start
looks like this might take me a while
i'm going to try a few more times here
ah yeah we got it guys we did it
nice perfect up and down no bedrock to
circumvent
on our way it's good it's not exactly
where i wanted it but it will do for
sure
if i get picky about it later i didn't
always try again
got the portal back in place so
next up let's head back uh to the gold
farm killing area
i'm gonna try something here see how
well this works we're gonna change
this portal oh man there's
i can't remember if they're mad at me or
not i'm guessing there's a few mad at me
still
how did uh how did so many
come to be again there's supposed to
only be like one or two left in there
you cool oh i don't want to teleport
though
ah i made a changes so that's
i want to see if this will work if we
block one of the sides
if they will still manage to push
themselves down
here if they're going to get a bunch of
them stuck up in there
so i'm going to head back up to the top
of the nether
spawn a bunch of them and see if they
get stuck
up there or if they continue to fall
down here and just ignore
going down this side from now on because
if that works we can simplify the
crusher
a lot
we're good good okay see you in a second
so let's go see how this worked i've
been up here for
nine minutes this time roughly nine
minutes
let's see if we can beat the ender pearl
down too
okay i think we can
oh you know what i didn't have slab on
top of that portal ah we almost beat it
if i wasn't so scared i could have
um this is also a test to make sure
those vines aren't messing anything up
too
because we haven't checked that out
probably should have tested that before
changing more stuff
all right come on come on come on it's
gonna be a little laggier than the first
time
okay there's a guy up here that's fine
ah still not too bad eight frames per
second
and yes oh wait a minute
you see some of the buttons are are in
the portal because uh
some zombie pigmen must have activated
those pistons and the pistons shot them
off and
they just happened to go through the
portal looks like there's
three stuck in there
i gotta be very careful i don't attack
these guys while he's up here
because he will he will attack me in
fact i can't
maybe i'll show you what happens to if i
throw a an instant health potion when
i'm down there i don't think i can kill
these guys to be honest
i don't have enough potions here and we
haven't set up the crusher
but yeah this looks like it's gonna work
if i try to
throw them the potion up over here
how many did we get we're about
that's actually pretty similar the first
test we did maybe
50 to 100 more uh they will
attack me through the glass though not a
problem
knock me off knock me off
at least they did why aren't they doing
it now
huh pretty sure
okay maybe not maybe
i tried i tried doing that when i was up
here before and they knocked me off the
platform
through the glass somehow unless some
somebody came down from above and
knocked me off
that could have been it too
all right so this is good i'm going to
leave the area and let them despawn
unfortunately
and then we will try to set up a crusher
system eventually i also would like to
get instant health potions getting moved
here automatically from the
the ethos lab
from my brewing room uh that would be
cool too that way i don't have to
manually keep bringing them here
stop trusting them i think they're okay
and i jump in with them
and then wait a minute
you don't like me do you uh
let's break the fourth or fifth time
i've done that now
come on uh i'm going to be tearing down
all this class in just a second
come on come on come on
probably shouldn't have done that yeah i
got my boots and my sword back look at
all these
chickens i wonder if the chicken's
gonna be a problem long term
oh he's probably mad too all right
give me my things oops
um all right gonna tear all this glass
down we're redoing it
uh this whole thing and give me a second
to prepare for that
okay everybody we're doing this new
starting out fresh we removed all the
glass we're going to move everything on
this platform up at some points
and even what i'm doing here i'm
probably going to change once i'm done
recording because it's really plain
right now
with all this clay blocks but i just
want to show you quickly before we end
this because we are getting a little
long already
how to set up a crusher system
it's surprisingly easy
and compact so
the mobs i'm going to make fall four
blocks
out of the portal going this way like
towards us
they'll land on these hoppers is the
plan
actually wait a minute right so
if they land on these hoppers down here
that means their head's going to be at
this level so we are going to put
the crusher the pistons back here can we
reach us
oh we can nice like this
those will come forward
push the clay into the zombie pigmen's
head
and suffocate them like they deserve
vile creatures um
okay so let's go over
all you really need is a hopper timer
it's so simple um
yeah let's do it like this we'll put
the redstone wire here and i think um
let's do it like this so this one piece
of redstone dust will power both
power both pistons like it'll go into
this block
or wait will it
i think it will i think this will update
this piston will ex
extend and update this one and then
it'll go because this block is powering
it diagonally as a bud switch
yeah i think that'll work it's a little
weird but it should work
um then we're going to set up a hopper
timer right above here
let me lay down a base so it's a little
easier
too high let's go a little lower
yeah this is the right height i think
yeah
okay so hopper timer the one i like to
use
is that one i showed in a tutorial a
long time ago it's just a six
by by two piston based one
um the way we're gonna do it
yeah this is this isn't one that runs
all the time it's only when you click a
button
and so the redstone block sticks to the
one
it sticks to the piston that is the
sticky piston so this is the sticky
piston
and i'm going to put a regular piston on
this side
so the default position of the redstone
block here is going to be
by the sticky piston over here um
so these pistons won't be extended but
if the block is over here
wait a second
let's get rid of this there we go you
see that updates both of them
yeah i guess i can't have a block there
otherwise it powers that piston
um okay
let's put this back oh
i said quickly right why am i fumbling
around so much
let's get to it here uh then
block here block here
redstone dust oops
redstone dust and the hoppers
you know what i could have made it go
let's make it go this way instead
be even more compact
what am i doing uh yeah
ignore this this line here that we just
set up
okay comparators
there we go comparators hoppers
facing into each other like so
and that's about it and i believe to
kill
or to soften up a mob like a regular 10
heart mob
you want about i think it's 25 blocks in
it
that'll run
um let's see they're going towards the
sticky piston that's the defaults
they'll end up there
yeah okay so when we update this
this sticky piston will push it so
uh we can actually set up a button down
here
very nicely on the right probably
which will activate the crusher
um just give me a second
see we got to send power to here i think
just to show you let's go back up
yeah so this is this is where the
redstone dust is if we
if we update it's not that we actually
power
um this piston we just update it by
sending a redstone signal near it
um so
tell you what let's do it like this get
the block
like here put a repeater
so otherwise the comparator above there
will send power down
and
yeah like this wait let's do it so we
can place it
redstone that goes through that goes to
there
get rid of that block we don't want the
pistons moving like that
and then that goes up to there and that
should
do it i think
let's hope it's working
so then the next thing is just fiddle
around with how many items you put in
the
hopper timer to get it suffocating them
as much as you want
everything's going back cool cool let's
get some more glowstone back here
oh you know i wanted to demonstrate this
too
um oh and i gotta light this with the
glass in front
yeah so it's pretty simple it's
basically just a hopper timer
cool all right i'm gonna get
a bunch of pigments spawning again and
then we will see if we can kill them
with one health potion
hopefully hopefully only one that would
be ideal
still forgot to put the half slabs on
there uh i just went
wait a minute am i gonna die if i go
through here no i should be fine
just went for five minutes this time we
want to see how things
work i'm okay please tell me i'm okay
i'm doing great oh yeah
look at this much better
okay where did i leave those instant
healths
i might have to adjust the timing on
here i might want 24 items in the
hoppers not 25
because they do take a little damage
getting here
[Music]
oh man down here i put them yeah it is
i'm gonna
grab the looting sword uh put some jump
in here
in case they get me
yeah i'm gonna take all these just in
case we figured something out wrong and
we need to kill or use a lot more than i
expected
[Music]
that looks so cool what are we at we're
at
2 260 give or take not too many
oh that is an awesome sound
oh some are dying darn okay that's too
long
i wonder why
[Music]
so if i figure things out right this one
potion should kill them all
i don't know where else they would take
damage
oh it did work good i forgot i forgot to
switch to looting though that was a
waste the baby guys seem to get stuck
up there more than the big ones
all right well that's pretty cool i'm
going to lower the items in there to 24.
we'll try it one more time
i went 10 minutes this time longest time
yet
so this is the real deal
nobody kill me please i know they
shouldn't but i'm always worried
oh yeah it's a little much laggier now
six frames per second this is the worst
yet
24 items in the hoppers are you on
are you actually here i don't want you
here because if i attacked him
he died right it looked like something
was like dancing
in front of me there let's let's turn
this down i'm sorry
sorry uh get our looting sword
splash potion
this thing is so cool 500 this time
we're looking at 500 zombie pigmen
roughly
uh so let's see everything's here are
they like i think they might be jumping
up and down
that could be a problem actually
if they are
i could probably fix that by having
blocks come out above their heads too
okay we lost a couple there it didn't
look like as many what are we at
oh no that was a lot that was a lot i
think we lost like a hundred there
okay so i'm gonna try 23 next time but
that's probably all the adjustments
we'll do this episode
let's hopefully still kill them all with
this remember to switch this time
[Music]
yeah i think we got them all like the
majority of them not the guys up there
of course
and the little ones seem to handle it
pretty well
there's always a bunch of them left over
too
all right awesome so that is the gold
form as it is now
uh i still want to make some more
adjustments but next episode we should
probably do something else
uh and i'll fiddle with this more off
camera
all right everybody so i think we should
celebrate our accomplishment reward
ourselves
uh for all the work on the gold farm
it's working great now
uh i'm going to make golden carrots
we're upgrading our food source from
steak to golden carrots from now on i
think
or at least i'm going to try them out
they have better saturation than steak
they don't give as
many food bars initially though they
only give three
which is fine um basically these
will make it so i don't have to eat as
often i'm pretty sure
sweet i've been wanting golden carrots
for a long time
um all right so
moving on comment for today just picked
out a quick one here it says hey etho i
saw at the end of your
video that you have a lot of floating
trees around
why are they floating uh
this is an old world and i played on it
for
probably hundreds of hours now i'm
curious how long i've played on this
world let's go take a look outside
though
and i have not repaired enderman damage
in this area once
so all this ground and stuff is just a
mess you would be surprised there's
floating trees anywhere there can be
pretty much actually i think i might
have repaired a little bit of damage not
much though
[Music]
like there's floating trees
walks missing there and there and
this was probably a creeper actually
but yeah lots of floating trees around
um just from endermen making a mess
all over the place like man
um so
they are very destructive i i still
don't really like how enderman can pick
up blocks to be honest
um i don't know
not a fan of its and i also think
creepers should drop more of the blocks
they blow up
just it's more annoying than anything
that they destroy
just about everything when they blow
stuff up it's one thing
to have to repair it but then not to
have the blocks needed to repair it's
pretty annoying to you
they actually got hungry pretty quick
there it's not a whole lot better than
stick it's just a little bit better
anyway i think that's going to be it for
today guys i hope you enjoyed today's
episode
and i will see you again next time
take care bye bye