[Music]
you know sometimes when you die and you
feel kind of bad
like oh i was so foolish this time i
don't really feel all that foolish i
feel like
i feel like i got cheated a little bit
on this one you'll see
it's uh it's bad in here
oh everybody despawned okay never mind
never mind
there's our gear place is on fire
he's got my sword and my my armor
okay okay there were about uh 50 blazes
in here and
like 50 zombie pigeon and stuff it was a
bad time
oh also the place burnt down i've been
spending a lot of time in this area
farming up gold at the
at the gold farm and and bones at the
wither skeleton farm
and also in this area is the gas blaster
and the other gold farm above the
bedrock ceiling where we have all the
villagers
i've learned not to try to trade with
villagers in the nether when they're
sleeping
because when you right click them
there's a good chance you're gonna right
click the bed
and blow everything up so what i do is i
come over here and i go through the
portal to sleep
and then i come back through um
this is kind of what i saw when i went
through before
it's a little bit toned down this time
but
like it just fills up with mobs it's
like i've created a trap here somehow
this area is totally spawn proof which
is what's confusing me like they can't
wander through the portal here
so i don't know how they're getting into
it there is one more portal in the area
i believe i think this is also spawn
proof yeah
way over here this is all slab though
like they're not gonna wander
through this portal so i don't know how
they're getting there let's check this
one
yeah we got a few guys here i suspect
you know how
zombie pigmen spawn on portal blocks and
they'll probably wander around and then
accidentally wander through sometimes
that's that explains where the zombie
pigmen come from
and why they're at the podzilla area
there but the blazes where are the
blazes coming from is what's really
confusing me
i think because portals only have a
light level
of 11 and blazes can spawn at 11 and
below
i think they also might be spawning on
the portal blocks here and instantly
going through
anyways let's get to it here so there's
a bit of an odd idea i've been wanting
to experiment with and with the new cave
update coming out
this might be a perfect time we're going
to be playing around with
maps today more specifically i've been
wondering
what kind of redstone devices could we
incorporate with maps you know we kind
of look at them as these static images
but i kind of feel like
they can be animated to a certain extent
right and used to display
information almost like a monitor right
and with people living underground with
the cave update you're gonna have the
whole surface of your world free
maybe we can make some sort of monitor
above your base so i'm imagining you
would put your base
in the middle of the map and then have
all kinds of wacky contraptions
on on the surface does that make sense
what are those wacky contraptions well
we're gonna experiment to play around
with a few ideas here just to see
uh how they work i think the very first
thing though we got to figure out what
is the
refresh rate on maps because i don't
know
aha so a fully zoomed in map is 128 by
128 pixels
and each pixel is represented by a
single block so we got a
a black background here black concrete
just to get a nice contrast
if we put a white concrete on top of
that
bam you see it took a little moment to
show up but it did show up and now you
can clearly see
that one block on our black background
now i'm thinking probably one of the
easiest and best ways of animating maps
is to do something like this where we
have pistons pushing blocks over top of
other blocks
so uh the white blocks are gonna get
pushed over the black box and they
should change on the map
and the maps only really care about the
top blocks so you can cover
over this with the black blocks and on
the map you can't really see that oh
these ones down here
are lower than these ones it doesn't
really matter it just kind of all looks
black to us
we don't see the white blocks hidden
there and then when we
start controlling the pistons with
redstone
it should change question mark
okay yeah stuff is happening
so i think it's too fast it can't quite
draw it quick enough
it's interesting the line is kind of
showing up
somewhere in the middle of this too so
let's add a bit of delay we'll double it
well pretty much double it okay
okay we're still getting kind of draw
lines on it
hmm oh snap okay we got some good news
here
everybody it seems to be consistent wavy
line
wavy line solid solid
then wavy line wavy line then solid
solid so it's following a pattern
which is good when you do redstone you
want stuff to be predictable
uh it seems that the delay is too short
or too long it falls out of sync
and i found the perfect delay seems to
be one more to this
and now it's like always in sync
look at that oh that's beautiful so what
is the refresh rate well
redstone torches take two redstone ticks
to update
and then we got seven on the repeater so
that's a total of nine redstone ticks
nine on nine off for the full cycle and
there's ten redstone ticks per second so
we're just shy of that so it's like 1.11
frames per second
for the ideal right here uh i say about
because the other thing to keep in mind
is pistons
retract instantly but they take two
redstone picks to extend
so that gets a little bit confusing okay
so now we're doing a distance test and
it seems like it updates at the same
rate no matter how far away you
are but if you get over 128 blocks away
from it
it'll stop updating we were just on the
border there so
only part of it was updating if we go
further than that it freezes
we get closer we're within 128 blocks of
it again
now we can see it updating and now it
froze now the other thing is
when you hang them on the wall like this
unfortunately it stops drawing it
actually has to be in your hand i'm
pretty sure
oh and now the cycle's off so the other
interesting thing about this is
now we're getting wavy lines right i
think if i go off of it and go back on
it
it fixes itself it sinks with our first
test here we kept it simple it's just
two frames of animation
white or black right but you can
obviously use your full world height and
stack
multiple pistons on top of each other
and get several different frames of
animation different colors that kind of
thing
so with this right now it's black
boop turned green boop
turned yellow boop turned red another
cool thing though
is even though we've been using pistons
for our animation there are other
methods we could use such as
dispensers and shocker boxes as a way of
automatically placing
colored pixels right you can see we've
got an orange dot there because our
shulker box is orange so it keeps the
color of the shulker box as well
it seems certain types of blocks get
ignored when drawing maps such as the
redstone dust on the sand here you can't
see that in any way
uh unfortunately redstone lamps also
seem to get ignored
you just see the black concrete
underneath them or like when they're on
the sand here you just see the sand they
don't
get drawn at all yeah so i feel like
there's a lot of potential for doing fun
cool things with this
i feel like a lot of them would be more
just to show off though
and i'm wondering what are some actual
practical applications of it where it's
actually going to help you out one idea
is the progress bar
so all we gotta do is run a comparator
to the pistons
it's pretty simple right you can have a
comparator chain going from like maybe
deep down underground
you run it up to your display on the
surface and it's like oh i wonder how
many sugar cane
until uh my sugarcane farm fills up the
chest right
so you can hook it up to an inventory
and now when items go in or out of it
you can actually see
on the map where it's at so that would
be kind of cool or maybe your sorting
system how long until it's done sorting
the items
or your super smelter how long until
it's done it's melting all the items
another idea is maybe you could hook up
some pistons to a minecart track if you
wanted to keep track of where the
minecart actually is
but uh i gotta say it would get pretty
annoying if you were riding it yourself
this is more like if you're moving mobs
around or a storage minecart i think
it would be cool to see whenever a mob
falls down in our mob system here that's
something we could do
that would be a good practical
application of it but i'm guessing
another problem here is
a lot of times the maps don't line up if
you don't plan ahead
yeah we're like see this we're like
right on the edge of it so
that's not the greatest right let's
check the nexus area here maybe we could
do something here
with it see how it lines up
uh the super smelter is kind of in the
center there
hmm yeah i got this problem though in my
world you see all the gray lines
that's from a snapshot a long time ago
when it messed up my height maps that's
why it rains underground
we're gonna work on our storage room
here everybody so look at this it looks
like
most of the nexus is actually within
frame and pretty much
center too it's not bad it's just like
we enter the map right over here
on this block we're out of it so just
the very
front of the building is cut off so it's
not quite perfect but
like most of the important stuff is
within frame here so that's cool
and here's the idea i had i realized we
could modify things
slightly to get an extra functionality
out of this thing so
for all these item filters that hold our
items
we can um
what are we gonna do here i'll show you
i'll show you
so we can build this up like so add some
redstone going up here
all right and then we attach that to
some target blocks or something
like this and then piston
and when the piston moves we'll have to
remove the blocks above us but when it
moves it'll show us when an item
is going in the item filter or when
we're out of storage space for that item
what if this is totally full the piston
will stay extended
i think we're gonna be using basalt for
this has a nice black color on the map
so it will give us good contrast
and uh it's easy to collect and it's
easy to tear down if we
realize this is a bad idea but we're
going to do is just highlight the
the area where the pistons extend it
when they extend it
it's going to turn red and that'll
indicate that it is full
so you can kind of see how it's going to
look on the map here i was thinking
about removing this mountain but
man is it thick that's like a 20 or 30
block
thick mountain it's insane okay let's do
a little test here so we're going to put
some basalt
into the system we're going to keep the
map here i think and then whenever we
want to check it we'll just take a look
right now we only
have 32 out of the 256 items set up
so just one row there and we should see
the basalt one trigger
oh it is working okay that took a really
long time to get there
so i switched it from the red terracotta
to end stone i think it shows up a
little bit better it says that one
little pixel
now the question is how useful is this
to us actually so if we were to put some
nether bricks in here
let's just do a little test um like can
we figure out
what the item is just based on the
position of them being lit up i think we
can i just don't think it's gonna be
very
intuitive okay
there it goes so we count from the right
to the left so that's on the fifth one
the fifth group and the third one on
that group let's check this out so we'd
have to use the menu to figure it out
here
that group of eight there goes from four
zero to 5
f because it's the fifth group and
third this first four here would be the
first group
this second one would be the second
these four would be the third these four
four would be the fourth and then this
would be the fifth group
and the third one in the four is the
nether brick so it does match up
so we can figure it out
there's a little bit of a mental
gymnastics though to figure it out
can you guys think of any better way of
doing this
oh man okay well i decided to go ahead
here and do it for all 256 items in the
nexus
seemed like a good idea to be at first
until i actually started doing it and i
was like oh
yeah this is uh this is giving me some
flashbacks
to building the nexus it's like even
though it's a simple thing we're doing
because you're multiplying by 256 is
actually a massive project and
my nemesis this mountain if this
mountain wasn't here i could do it so
fast but i have to clear it out and look
how thick this stupid thing is
there's a lot of land to clear out so
it's going to take a bit of time
plus we gotta farm up target blocks a
bunch of hay bales that's not easy to
get exactly
and uh yeah but we'll get it done we're
gonna do it
just because it's something new and
exciting i wanna try it out as i'm
working on this i'm discovering the odd
mistake here and there on the nexus
that's like i don't think those wires
over there are supposed to be connected
pretty sure that'll mess up the item
filters in total we're gonna need
256 target blocks for this upgrade which
is 256 hay bales that's a
whole lot of wheat so i got to thinking
why don't we go to our wheat field here
and uh
clean it up right nice and quick well
actually i think this is
a lot slower than using a mini farm like
i never do this i tried it out as like
it's not really all that great honestly
like i thought oh you know it's all
grown already it seems like it would be
good
but because you got to move around to
pick up the stuff and to replant and
you end up wasting a lot of time just in
the little little gaps in timing between
planting and stuff
that a mini farm is like two to three
times faster i think
if you got it mine broke in the last
update so i'm gonna build a new one i
think
this kind of stinks all right so we got
one observer going up one observer going
down to the redstone down there and
that's pretty much all we need to do
here
pretty simple uh the thing about mini
farms though is they
seem to break every single update i
think this is my sixth version now
stand here right click that's all you
got to do you can afk
and look how fast we're getting the
wheat like there's no way you can
harvest it that quickly and replant
all right everybody so check it out i've
been at this for a few hours now and i
just wanted to catch you up with what's
been done
and uh you can see cut out a lot of land
here
the mountain is in a bit of rough shape
now we gotta decide what to do with it
as well but yeah we cut some slits out
and
on the map this is what it looks like
currently so
you can see the top layer kind of
overlaps with the bottom layer
the block over here and they kind of
just look like they're side by side on
the map so i think that's kind of cool
good way of doing it and
likewise on the other side we also
i couldn't hear anything i just realized
my speakers are off it's like uh oh
there's no game sounds what's going on
and i look at my my speakers aren't on
and kind of explains it anyways yeah so
we cut out the
the mountain on this side there was a
lot less land over here so it was easier
now we got to decide like what do we do
with this mountain i'm thinking we
probably should shape it so it's a
little bit more natural looking
also um should probably build some more
walls on the nexus
i know that's like a never done project
right but look at this i think you'd
look a lot better if there was a wall
that went up to
at least the basalt there and then like
connected to the building there
would be good uh also we cut out a bunch
of land in the middle of the mountain
over here
we got more of the displays right there
right
all this has been cut out oh boy
this mountain i hate this mountain so
much
oh man but it's all it's almost done
here possibly
so here's here's the real question what
i'm thinking
the thing is this pattern over here
actually looks really cool
like where we're standing on the map
anyways it looks like it would be really
cool if we got rid of
the land above here too um
and likewise on the other side and if we
do that then there's pretty much nothing
left of the mountain and we should just
get rid of it right
so i'm deciding if we should do that or
not again it's a lot more land to clear
but i think it might be worth it i think
i think it would be good if we just got
rid of it
and like tried to refine the area
because it never really looked
proper even the way it was before i
always debated if i should get rid of
the mountain or not
but i think i should wait for you guys
feedback before making that decision
so i'm going to wait on doing that today
let's finish what we were working on
here
we have six out of the eight rows done
just two left
just two more rows and
uh we hit a snag a huge
snag it looks like
uh it might be near impossible not quite
impossible i did figure out a way of
doing it but man was it a head stretcher
okay so the thing is we have to
where is it yeah these are the item
filters down here we need to connect to
these
and then somehow
have the map see us how on earth are we
gonna do that it's actually possible i
did figure out a way
uh it's a bit weird though okay so for
one thing let's see here
the way i've been doing the other ones
for the most part is like this i took
the target box over here
and then you can put the piston on top
and that's pretty much all you got to do
right nice and simple
end stone in front of that and then when
it extends the map sees it
but guess what if we do that it's gonna
be right in the center the map will see
it but then the other side
is also gonna end up over here and when
this side extends they're gonna be in
the same place and that can't happen
all right there's not enough space is
what i'm trying to say
again this is an afterthought i didn't
plan to do this the nexus i just thought
hey let's see if we can do it today
um and yeah so what we're gonna do i
figured out another way of arranging
this
actually or did i i can't remember
it now something to do with torches
uh yeah okay i remember i remember so
what we're gonna do is put the sticky
pistons above
the arms will be extended we're gonna do
like reverse pistons
so when they retract then we'll be able
to see the end stone
so on the map the piston arms look grey
which is fine because like the default
color is gray on all the other ones as
well
what we're going to do is hide the end
stone underneath the piston arms and
when they retract
then we'll see the end stone
and by doing that we save one block of
space
it doesn't go to the middle anymore it's
one block short and
we'll be able to do that on both sides
now again the problem is we have blocks
above that
and there's redstone on those blocks we
can't exactly get rid of them
so what are we going to do if we look
from up above here we can kind of see
what's in our way there's
this stone brick with the redstone on
top and then this stone brick
and this stone brick actually serves a
function as well it keeps the wire from
connecting there
remember how not all blocks are visible
on maps
well lamps have a special property where
they're a solid block but they're
invisible on maps so we can use that to
cut the wire
and then for the lower one we don't
really want these lamps flashing on and
off constantly because that'll create an
insane amount of lag they won't be
affected on this top layer
because the redstone's beside it but for
the lower layer here if the redstone's
on the lamps
we don't want them lighting up so on the
lower layer
we're going to use glass which is also
invisible
on maps and that
should do it like that
i think and then the map will be able to
see the end stone below here when the
piston is retracted
uh let's do a little test here the
torches
and yeah i can see the end stone
put this back and now it should be gray
yeah now it's gone oh snappers
all right everybody we got her done it
was tricky but we did it
we got 256 single pixel displays on the
nexus now to show us the position of
where the items are going in
when they're going in and also we can
see when the inventories are full
with just that single pixel so it would
be cool if we had more information on
on here like what the items actually
were at each of the positions you know
uh if we could see when the inventories
were empty when they were
20 full 40 you know have a range of
fullness but with the nexus being
like so old and unplanned for this it's
not possible this is about the only
thing we could do
there's not the way the redstone's laid
out we can't add any more onto it really
because it's all like clumped together
you know
so you'd have to plan that out from the
start of your storage room but it is
definitely possible
now i do know how this is laid out so i
can figure out the where the items are
just based on the position
if you look at the top right there it's
on the fifth
row third from the right third group
from the right and
fourth item so these three chests here
are for rows one to four
these three are for rows five to eight i
might
number it on the map actually might make
it a little
clearer uh but since it's in the fifth
row
third from the right and fourth item
is a group of one here group of two
group third group here
fourth item is grass so it's a grass
block that is lit up right now
there's no space for it in the nexus so
i can't figure it out this is not
the the best right uh you know what i
realized though i probably got a bunch
of comments on this
we can add text to this as well using
banners
oh man maybe we do that too
at the very least we should use that to
number the rows then that would be a
good idea i think
but we could like name the items maybe
too with
with text so i want to play around with
that just real quick here this has been
in the game for such a long time now and
i feel like so many people forget about
it myself included
even though i've used it a few times now
i always forget about sil
um let's just try do that is that how
you spell netherrack i don't even know
let's try place it somewhere and see
what it looks like i think the more you
write on the banner the smaller the text
gets
i think you gotta right click it yeah so
it'll show up
but that text is pretty big right
and also oh yeah the banner gets marked
too as well as the color so that we got
a big banner there now too
so maybe with some clever shorthand
writing there would be a way of
like marking each one but uh i have to
be very compact
aha so i think that's all the map stuff
we're gonna be doing for today but
before we wrap
up i'm gonna try to sneak in one quick
build project here as well
so we've uh added paths and stuff around
our world right i wanna
try polish things up a bit more this is
a good start i think having paths like
this
is great but these are very very plain
very simple at the moment still
we want to add more onto them this area
is a little bit more developed but even
this can get even more developed i feel
so let's work on
this area over here we got the trees on
the left which is nice we kind of got
something around the water
but it's uh it can be improved quite a
bit still
um what i want to try to do is add like
a retaining wall
along here so it looks like it's holding
the grass the dirt from
you know falling over we're gonna go for
bricks just so we have a different color
the gravel is kind of grayish and
this goes well with it but it's
different color so it'll help
add a bit more to the area here and we
might want to mix some panda site in
with this as well
let's do andesite slabs
and maybe we'll just add these all along
the path on the outside one mistake i
made with this though is i made my paths
too
thin i think we should try fatten them
up wherever we can there's not a lot of
space over here
but maybe one or two blocks thicker
would be better
so on this side we're gonna go
right on the path but i think on this
side let's like try to
build it out by at least the block here
man i gotta say i would love to get
better at landscaping in this game like
if you think about it
probably at least 95 percent of your
world is the land right
then like five percent or less is the
buildings and then the redstone the
stuff i do the most
you don't even see that you try to hide
that stuff right so
a very small portion of my world feels
developed at the moment
but if i got better at landscaping like
that would cover a lot of the world
um but yeah it's one of those things i
probably just got to do it a bit
and i'll get better at it you know um
yeah you learn tricks and then once you
learn those tricks you always have them
good stuff all right so we just did a
little section here
nothing too major but i think it helps
uh quite a bit actually we gotta do uh
more stuff like this i feel like if you
think about it if you do too much
redstone in your world
your world kind of sucks because it's
just like uh almost like a
a creative world like it is got random
stuff everywhere that doesn't really
look too good uh if you do too much
building you got nothing functional in
your world it's not
not all that great either right if you
do just farm building
it's like you got all these farms and
you never use the resources on on
actually building anything
or if you don't do any landscaping your
world doesn't feel like it's tied
together at all so it's like a
a bounce minecraft is a balanced if you
want a really good world you kind of
gotta master
everything and uh yeah
maybe one day right so anyways let's get
to the comment of the day it says how
did he get
like a stack and a half of sand from a
tnt explosion
in the desert so last episode we did the
resource gathering
and yeah this confuses a few people so
for one thing i've heard that
bedrock edition didn't get the change
uh mojang made a change over a year ago
i think
maybe in 1.14 i don't quite remember but
they made it so tnt
in the java java java whatever you want
to say
addition specifically will always get
100 of the drops now
which is great now don't get confused
though that doesn't mean creepers
will will drop everything when they
explode or
or gas balls or any of the other
explosions just tnt
will drop everything and just in the
java edition
so yeah and it's great for farming stuff
like tnt is amazing in this game now
use it for everything everything
or you're a sucker all right everybody
hope you guys enjoyed this episode thank
you for watching until the next one take
care have a good day
bye