[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys to another episode of our let's
play
series is today the day i walked into a
creeper
no we're good sometimes a creeper can
spawn on this bridge and it's a little
risky walking like that actually
so how you guys doing today hopefully
you are having a wonderful day
we have a couple things to check out
here to begin with in our episode
uh starting with the musical mushroom
farm here so
i think it was two episodes ago we made
this musical
noteblock sequence thing time lapse from
the fat rat we
we got it set up here except i didn't
actually hook up the redstone to it
until today
so i replaced all the bud switches we
had here with observer blocks
and they just have a wire connecting
them all together
on both sides runs down to the note
blocks there
so if we grow a mushroom let's try this
out
it worked before hopefully it does now
so it's working pretty good i would say
and they work separate from each other
so even though this observer block was
triggered
it uh still played the song this after
we grew the second mushroom so they
didn't like cancel each other out
and if we remove the mushroom block here
in here it it untriggers it doesn't play
the song when you remove it though
otherwise it'd be too much music a
little bit of music is good but too much
no bueno all right so that's that
i think this farm is complete now i'm
willing to say this is done
to finish projects so i'm happy about
that
the other thing we did i think last
episode was we worked on
we worked on the mushroom forest thing
right
uh i ran a little low on time wasn't
able to finish
too much of it so i went back and i
built a couple more mushrooms
so let's take a look from a distance
here first
so we got three three of the big
mushrooms built there now
i ran out of the red blocks so the
nether wart blocks
fairly quickly here and also you guys
suggested i should bulk up the gaps on
this thing they were
i think two blocks tall and they had a
flat top now they look a little bit more
rounded except for the
the big caps on the top could use a bit
more
um nether wart blocks possibly they're a
little bit small
looking maybe but overall i'm pretty
happy with these
would like to add a lot more of them
somebody suggested doing
little mini mushrooms like this too i
think this is cool
have a little patches of them around the
place would look neat
oh ah so close whoa
we're fine
there's our other dog
don't worry i'm a very good driver
okay we got ourselves a non-tamed dog he
shouldn't teleport
we have the llamas hidden away so
they're not going to come kill them
and we have the stairs in our water
stream thing instead of slabs
so we just got to watch this guy really
hope he doesn't die because then i don't
know what to do
oh no no no no no
okay i made a mistake right away here
um um come this way come this way
yeah okay this isn't gonna work the
spacing between the stair and the slab
is not enough for him to fit through i
guess
what if i keep pushing you i try not to
kill you with my axe
yeah and then you go in you keep going
in
he's in he's in okay so now we put this
back
and now it's working like it should okay
so i replaced the slabs
really you can't fit through that
oh no he's gonna die he's gonna die he's
gonna die he's gonna die he can't fit
between a slap a stair and a trapdoor
how chunky are you yes
yes it works
chest and trap door that is the answer
oh man i could have done a full block
and a sign as well
in retrospect now that i think of it but
i think having a chest there is a little
bit smoother because it's smaller block
right so he seems to be fine we're gonna
let him do his thing let's go above
ground check out the llamas
just think guys in a in like a few
episodes from now
in the comments people are gonna be like
how did he make his llamas walk around
the city like that
and i'm not gonna tell them and you're
not gonna tell them i'll never show it
in a world tour
and it'll be our little secret forever
they'll never know
hopefully we'll see um what was there a
stair
i don't even know that's a lot of stairs
in one spot
now i'll fix it later that's my little
catchphrase i'll fix it later
all right are they walking they're
walking they are
walking around the city
yes now i could have more
wolves in that system and each llama
could have its own wolf and they'll kind
of walk independently
but just getting this one guy here was
pretty tricky but maybe eventually
i'll do it later uh that could happen
all right very cool so i'm happy with
that seems to be working he hasn't
died that's probably the biggest thing
uh what we're gonna do today guys we're
gonna do a couple random building
projects
first off and then we're gonna
experiment with a technical build i've
wanted to do for a while
probably for the second half of this
episode
that's desert grass right it looks a
little bit
uh yeah definitely desert
i'm going to replace these hay bales in
here uh because we got path blocks now
and i think they
look a little bit better for animal pens
than hay bales
they look like muck and poop and stuff
you know
let's switch these over
oh you ate you ate the grass block are
you kidding me
all right tell you what let's put dirt
blocks in too
it'll look better good idea sheep
all right so that's the simple thing i'm
gonna do something a little bit bigger
now i want to change out this wall
a fair bit i firmed up some acacia wood
i think we should try to add some more
variety to this because it's very plain
um i thought about maybe using
prismarine
i tried it it looked pretty good
but i think we're going to go with
akisha i tasha wood
throughout this wall it's it's one of
those hard calls like i could
use prismarine
but because it's so colorful
a lot of you guys are not gonna like it
this is like a neutral
safe choice i think
okay from a distance here prismarine
versus acacia i'm giving it a second
chance
i want to show you guys what it could
look like
um but it's one of those art is in the
eye of the beholder things right it
sucks
i want a definitive one is better than
the other but i i know it doesn't exist
because one of you guys will love this
and hate this
and one of you guys is gonna love this
and hate this and
i can't please everybody i think more
people in general
would prefer that but some people would
strongly prefer that instead
this is more like a meh and that's more
like a
yeah and yeah reaction
uh maybe we can mix them maybe we can
mix them though
would it look better if we put dark
prismarine at the bottom here
no i don't like that what about the
brick
could that be a thing the brick i can't
place blocks because i've played this
game for seven years
aha no don't like that either what about
this would look better with brick though
for sure because it works with it
right yeah i think so that one's better
with the brick on the bottom
okay so i found on a larger scale
like after i did a few of these both the
acacia
and prismarine looked really bad
and i tried a lot of other blocks too i
tried like yellow clay orange clay red
clay
orange sandstone nothing i find very few
things look good with sandstone
one of the things i do like is green
clay with sandstone and i like uh
the light gray clay as well looks pretty
good with it
but anyways this is what it looks like
all finished up here it goes all around
the city
and keep in mind we are supposed to put
more buildings in here
we just have that one complex sort of
thing there's supposed to be a complex
over there one over there
one over here and that will hide a lot
more of this green you won't see as much
of it once
once they're in they'll block it right
so
yeah i think it's an improvement
personally i know some of you are not
gonna like it but it adds color it adds
variation
and i don't think it looks super bad
it's the best i could do guys let's move
on
okay so we're gonna go down to the man
cave now there is this
little sliver of a problem that has
shown up
because i i worked on that roof for the
tree farm
or ceiling ceiling is the correct term a
few episodes ago we finished this up
now we have this little three wide gap
here between this part of the man cave
and this part of the man cave
we could leave it as stone wouldn't be
terrible
but i think we'll do what we do in a lot
of parts where we put in these jungle
leaves
just to to give it that nice green feel
you know
so let's try that out and
i think we are gonna have to
how are we gonna position this i think
we'll put green leaves there
should we do staircase style one there
one there
and we might even try to do a little bit
of droopy leaf leafage
could look good too i'm gonna change out
a bunch of this and just see what it
looks like i think
so have it running all along here
and all along here and maybe put some
lights behind it too
okay so that's what it looks like right
now with no lighting behind it
and now that's what it looks like with
some hidden lighting it's a little bit
brighter
a little bit nicer i think you know what
i just realized
this is odd number right you see it's
three blocks there
this is odd number over here and then
ah this should be three blocks wide here
it's two blocks wide i i've always been
a great builder guys
always yep that's gonna bug me
let's not think about it let's not think
about it what i'm gonna do in a few
places here is try add some oak planks
as well just to break up the
total straightness of this centered
of course so this is the very center
maybe we could try a few blocks out
let's kind of make it do something like
that
maybe i should use some stairs
oh okay guys so check it out
we uh we got a solution here i think i
did try out the oak bracing
like the oak slabs and stairs but it
stood out so much it really didn't look
too good
i looked out of place so instead i tried
the droopy leaf idea
and i like this a lot personally i think
that's good
we had this very long straight section
and this breaks it up like it has all
these height variations you can't really
tell now
how straight this was before or still is
this is
kind of blocked by the leaves um also
this part of the manta is
a lot less green than like over there
and this helps to add some more greenery
to it
and nowhere else in the man cave have we
done something like this so
it's unique and i like that i've tried
to make every single part of this
man cave unique instead of like copying
something i like over and over
so yeah i'm happy with that
one thing we might try here should we
get into the walls
of our our tree farm here i think we
should
try it i had the idea of maybe doing a
mural right
try to represent
oh try to like do different
landscapes and stuff in pixel arts
it's a little hard to explain i think we
should go three blocks deep though
do i have any clay on me
i don't have any inventory space luckily
i have some chests on me i can just dump
some of this off for right now
yeah i wanted to maybe use light blue
clay for the sky
where is my clay box there it is
by the way guys if you do this ender
chest shulker box trick like this
i highly recommend you keep more than
one ender chest on you at all times
because you'll put it down and you'll
forget it somewhere
and then when you go for your stuff it's
like oh where did i leave that stupid
thing
if you have like several of them you
never have to worry about running out
and also you always make sure you have
room in your inventory for it when you
go to pick it up again
all right so there's going to be a
foreground layer here
background and then sky
okay let's uh let's do it over here
instead of over there because our
our haste beacon doesn't reach that far
uh
okay so even just like that just the
blue clay i don't think that looks too
bad i i like that
i would be happy if the whole wall was
that i think i could get used to it
but we're going to try to add more to it
make it look a little bit cooler
uh so we want to
do like landscapes if we just use grass
blocks
to represent grass it doesn't look good
from the side right so we're going to
use lime clay
for grass and stuff so this would be
i don't know if this is going to look
good either guys i'm just trying this
so we'll try it out then we'll make some
changes and
and stuff and until we find something we
like
but that would represent like totally
flat grass right there but we'll add
things like hills in the background and
stuff too so maybe
in places the terrain's a bit rougher
we'll make mountains and stuff
maybe we'll make a desert area
snowy areas you know
we can even add more to the foreground
and stuff and hopefully that'll look
cool
add some clouds lots of little things
like that we'll probably
hopefully look neat
all right looks like i threw some blocks
against the wall
okay what about trees let's try trees so
let's say
we we wanted to make a forest right we
could put down some some logs
and then some leaves make a round tree
or something
actually won't get look good if we put
leaves on the side of it we'll want to
put it above
the the wood here we'll do a three by
three tree
or something how about that that would
look good right
sure and then we could have one in the
background
uh-huh uh-huh this is a process guys
it's not gonna be perfect right away
well you know what guys i had my doubts
at first i wasn't sure this was gonna
really work but i think this looks
pretty cool honestly i think that's
pretty unique
i'm happy with that the only thing that
like gave me a lot of trouble was this
house
i tried to make a house like just your
standard derpy village or house or
whatever
and struggled a little bit with it but
i don't know like i tried putting wool
in there and all kinds of things
this is probably the best i can do um
but yeah i think that's neat i actually
checked and everything is
like mob proof right now like the
lighting is okay as it is
and uh we might continue here and build
like a desert themed area maybe a forest
or
cold snow and stuff
kind of area glaciers it's really easy
to do this too i was surprised
like you don't need to do much just a
couple blocks here and there and
it makes a huge difference i wanted to
try with you guys i had an idea of how
you could maybe do a lake
so water should flow towards the hole
right we're gonna put some lighting
hidden lighting here
like so and then if we put water
right here it should flow towards that
hole
oh did that stupid enderman there was an
enderman walking around i think he stole
my sandblock
all right is this going to look like a
lake
question let's take a step back
maybe i think or a river could that pass
as a river maybe
i could see it you know it would help to
sell it though is if we put a boat in
there let's try put a boat in
see if it'll stay in place or if we can
even put it down
all right oh yeah there it goes water
kind of pulls it in
uh-huh all right it's a little strange
but
i do really like this i think it's cool
let's look from a distance here
this is meant to be background though
like we're gonna have the trees growing
in here so you won't really see it too
much
it doesn't need a lot of detail
but i'm happy with that so far let me
know if you guys have any ideas for it
or how it should be changed anyways guys
uh unfortunately i did spend a little
longer building than i should have today
that doesn't leave us a lot of time for
our technical build we are going to try
to get into it though i'm going to
introduce it to you guys
you guys are going to give me your ideas
of how to do it
i'm going to steal those and then i'm
going to make millions that's the plan
uh yeah maybe you guys will help me out
with this and
we'll get something better out of it
here's here's what i want to do though
so we have been using this furnace room
here for a long time it's been great
it's been wonderful we have eight
beautiful for an eye
in this room um and it's good for little
projects and stuff but
some projects i've been doing lately
guys oh i don't know like the zombie
pigment farm the other day
i had to wait around probably half an
hour to an hour because we used like 3
000 to 5 000 glass on that project i'm
sure
and eight furnaces just don't cut it
anymore
when you're doing things on that level
and you don't want to just like stop an
afk
for half an hour for your stuff to smelt
like when i'm in a building mood i want
to build
so let's get out of here
uh we want to make a new smell tree
guys like a super duper crazy op
smell tree hopefully um for bigger
projects we'll still
use that uh eight furnace room i'm sure
if i'm just need one or two stacks or
something
but uh what i want to do is use 64
furnaces at least
the very minimum and i want it to work
where i can just put my stuff
as much or as little as i want into a
chest
right and then within seconds
have it shown up smelt it in another
chest
like seconds i'm talking seconds if i
put a stack of cobble in it should be
in here as stone in seconds that's what
i want
i wanted to be able to use different
types of fuel hopefully if we can pull
that off
so if if we can make it use planks coal
lava budgets all that stuff and not
waste fuel
that would be cool but this is going to
be a technical issue
like doing all i want is not going to be
easy
and that's why this is going to be a fun
build to try to figure out too
like if you put a whole bunch of stuff
in a chest how do you
deliver it to 64 different furnaces
that's kind of the challenge and how do
you get them out and bring it back
quickly
um if we just use hoppers alone
grab our redstone at most you can hook
two hoppers up to a chest
right you see it takes two items out at
a time
not good enough we need faster i think
so i think we can use hopper minecarts
to get it out quicker
and hopefully spread it uh
how how do we want this to work exactly
i'm not sure
i haven't like pre-built this or
anything
but we can stack multiples
within the same block and it should
still pull out two oh
wait a minute i just learned something
new i did not know these were so fast
has it always been like that
okay that's interesting that is very
interesting
okay so one of the big problems we're
probably gonna have with this
is how do we split the mine carts apart
like if they
are all picking up items out of that
chest
we don't want to just use one hopper
minecart because it would take forever
for it to go from
over 64 furnaces you know we only wanted
to deliver
one item to each furnace as it goes by
so we'd probably want to use at least
four maybe eight hopper mine carts
to deliver the items so this is possibly
a way we could
easily do four let's see if it'll pick
up the items out of the chest
if we get it right up to that fence i'm
not sure i haven't tried
it doesn't darn
okay what if we take that out uh maybe
there's another block
let's try just the normal fence they're
a little bit thinner
we don't want it to like go on the block
just like as far as it can without
getting stuck
should be able to go a little bit more
oh
now it still can't pick up out of the
chest okay
um well let's get rid of this i think
glass
are glass panes thinner than fences i
can't even remember
oh too far yeah it has to stay on the
rail
otherwise this gets way more complicated
but anyways guys i'm gonna keep thinking
of ideas here and then we might
uh build the super smell tree for our
next episode
and uh might be a fun technical build
for you guys too if you're looking for
one
i don't know if i didn't oh oh that was
weird
it's gotta be a graphical glitch right i
think so
if we break that
no it's not actually there
anyways guys i think we're gonna wrap up
the episode here for today
so here is the comment i picked out it
says
hey etho why don't you have old
tutorials like your mob system and
brewing in playlists
also is there a specific reason why you
don't do more tutorials like them
so my playlists are a mess as a lot of
you know
that's high on my to-do list i'm hoping
i've actually been planning
to just sit down and spend a couple
hours on them
and hopefully sort out some of the
problems
[Music]
such as that uh the reason why i don't
do more tutorials
like them i
[Music]
why did i go there it's like i can't
talk while it's making music that was a
terrible decision
can't go anywhere oh where'd he go
oh no
what he's gone i didn't just kill him
did i i thought that was a different
creeper
i didn't switch to peaceful or anything
i don't know
he's he's not there he that was a named
creeper
and now he's gone
unless he's wandering around somewhere
um anyways getting distracted i don't do
more tutorials because i'm not very good
at tutorials i find there's a lot of
other youtubers that are much better
at tutorial videos than me um
so yeah and also every time i do do a
tutorial
um it kind of takes away from my let's
play series
because i like to do new and crazy stuff
in my let's play series
and then like do i make
do i do a tutorial on it and just copy
what i did in my let's play whenever i
do that people are like
i just saw you build this two days ago
in your let's play series why are you
making another video on it
you know so i kind of got discouraged
from doing tutorials
anyways hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching
and until next time take care
bye bye