[Music]
hey how's it going everyone
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode of our let's play series
if you're wondering why my elytra wings
are transparent i'm not exactly
sure to be honest was that uh
i kind of remember seeing that in the
change log something about them
going transparent but now i'm not so
sure
whoa uh yeah we we're over here at the
guardian farm again
guys and uh we're just gonna do a couple
more things on this to start off with
today
you might notice spawn rates are looking
pretty good right
that looked awesome i i did a bunch of
cave lighting guys i lit up
the caves around this area for a couple
hours and man
it made a huge difference like i think
we're almost getting twice as many right
now
which is pretty awesome um let's head
down to the killing area
good throw good throw yeah but i saw in
the comments something i did not know
you guys told me
that if i cover over the water
apparently it makes the spawning rates
go way
up which i never saw anything about that
before
we're gonna try that up here in a little
while
but i'll just show you what it's like
right now i think i think just about all
the caves are lit up
so pretty much all the time we have four
or five of them burning up down here
if it's daytime if it's nighttime that
this totally stops pretty much
it was night time out there i just went
and grabbed the bed we're going to want
to have a bed down here so we can
uh like if we're semi afk i want to be
able to sleep and skip the night
that way we get good mob moderates again
uh but yeah what i want to do here guys
is maybe just try to make this tunnel
look a little nicer you know
make it more uh polished so that if i
ever have to come down here it looks
half decent
we're gonna do the dark prismarine uh
diorite nether brick
and the other prismarine mix that we did
in the nether i really like that combo
hopefully it looks good here too
i never do anything like diagonally i
don't i don't like the sharp corners it
creates you know
if i ever do something diagonally i
always find i have to like do this
otherwise i don't like it but if i do
that
yeah i'm gonna have to make this wider
if i want to do that
okay actually i only have 34 diorite
left nearby i think i have some in my
speed mine but that's that's
a little ways away and i am feeling lazy
so let's try to make this
work let's try come up with a cool
looking pattern here if we can maybe
we'll go five blocks and then
another brick and
sea lantern sea lantern this might be a
little too simple simplistic but we'll
try it
uh i don't know how many of you are are
following the mojang updates i'm not
going to spoil it in case you don't want
to know
or not spoil it too badly but uh
yeah they've been doing work guys um
yeah they're gonna be adding a lot of
cool stuff in this next update i think
like they've shown i believe or they've
hinted that they have
three new mobs total which
is pretty incredible like i don't think
in any
patch have they added more than two and
they just started working on this one
and they're already up to three so this
this is gonna be a good good patch for
the mobs i think
okay i think i found the style we're
gonna go with here guys
uh it's got quite a bit of 3d depth to
it like it goes in then it comes out
and comes out comes out kind of layers
as it goes up here gives it a nice curve
feel
uh it's i'm happy with it it's nothing
crazy amazing or anything but
you know it's a tunnel it's just a
tunnel guys we don't have to go too
crazy with it
uh i am because i put the diorite at the
top here though i am going to run
out of it so i'm gonna have to go go
look for whatever i have
in my uh speed mine after all oh no
sea lantern sea lantern
and then i'm putting bricks like next to
the sea lanterns
and then the other kinds away from them
here i'll show you guys where the speed
mine is too in case you're wondering
usually i just like cut and i'm i'm at a
place sometimes it's nice just to show
you where
stuff is give you a frame of reference
of how the world is built and we have
this tunnel set up too
which may as well show it off
all right so one of these portals it's
not the first one it's the second one
first one
was obsidian farm this is a speed mine
area
and i'm hoping there's dye right there
i'm pretty sure there is though
okay yeah i built the speed mine right
next to
like where it switches to the amplified
train because it has the new block types
there
um
oh there's a beacon over there yeah i
think i moved that way
there wouldn't be any diorite over there
so it must be down here if we have any
let's go check it out okay we still got
some chests here good
oh yeah awesome how much do we have
empty a little bit more over there i'm
gonna grab all i can
because i i'm totally out of it uh
yeah good good
all right a decent amount not not a ton
though i thought i would have had more
all right well check it out guys we got
the tunnel done here
let me know what you think of it too if
you liked it or not i think i'm i'm okay
with it i'm pretty happy with it
actually i like these colors together i
know they're not everybody's like
favorite though they're they're extreme
so some people are really not gonna like
this i know
already but i i think it's okay i'm
happy
uh yeah we we have a little viewing area
here where we can see them fall down
so this will try to make nice looking
and then over at this area here i left
some space we're gonna put the
chest down for storing the items we get
and we want to set up like the whole
item filter stuff
and all that too so i'm i'm thinking
let's just fill it up with chess we're
gonna go three tall
probably like that trap chest regular
chest
trap chest three tall four wide because
there is how many items there's
there's a prismarine shards we have the
crystals
fish uh might set up a cooked fish maker
thing
and there's squid ink and like garbage
items we'll
probably want to put into chests in case
like something
like a skeleton somehow gets into the
system and drops bones
kind of deal with that too and then on
this side we're going to do
more chests we're going to have tons of
storage here three tall again
uh this will be for the blocks though
because there is i think
four different types there's the sea
lanterns there's the bricks
the dark prismarine and the regular
stuff
so yeah those four will probably go over
here then we have this little extra
space too which
i do need a spot for the bed
so maybe that will go there uh also like
ender chest
and crafting all that kind of stuff we
kind of need a little workstation you
know
so that will probably be in this little
section
so the plan is to do the item filter
thing so
probably go something like this where we
don't have our hoppers i think i left
them in here
yeah i ran out of iron so fast like you
make a stack of hoppers and it's just
like
you feel bad after because you're broke
again
um yeah just like do that in the back of
all them
have the item filter uh before that and
then somehow move the items up
probably with a dropper elevator or
something we'll
see then on this end we have the
elevator
which we kind of need to do one more
thing here
maybe in this two by two space we'll
make a little drop zone to fall down
here because we have no way of getting
down here now
that i've sealed this all off so where's
our position minus 267
676 you think i didn't remember that
i should maybe like where the pistons
are maybe i should try to make that look
nicer too
i forgot i know 676 was one of the
numbers
i'm gonna dig down here and hope
hopefully i got that right
aha i got it right all right everyone so
i've been
working on this project for a bit here
it's just about done now i want to show
you the changes i made and
kind of like the finished look of it you
know it's it's
at that point pretty much so we go up
the elevator you can see i got
prismarine blocks all the way up now
it's
it's more polished and our drop zone is
done so i just did like uh
the the brick and the regular prismarine
with sea lanterns every so often on the
way down
kind of a cool effect right sometimes i
take fall damage sometimes i don't i'm
not
sure why it's inconsistent
but yeah anyways that time i i think i
did
and run down here this is our killing
zone this is the cool part of it
uh uh so we got a little viewing thing
here for the the guys falling down
still could polish up like down there
because you can't actually see it and
and up there could use some work we got
our chests i decide to do
three columns of the shards uh one for
the shiny stuff the crystals
one for the squid ink uh at the moment i
don't have it hooked up
um to bring this wood ink down here the
squid farms are up above like pretty
much
actually where are they i think no
they're not above they're
that way almost at
our level actually now that i think of
it
all right so maybe i'll set up some
minecarts to bring the ink here or just
manually move it i'm not sure yet
got two columns for the fish those are
also pretty common
one for cooked fish in case i hook up a
cooker
um i don't have that hooked up at the
moment and then on this side we got the
blocks
like i said these just have to be
manually crafted and put in here
it's kind of a big storage form though
because
this farm is producing like crazy
like more more than i'll ever use
which is good that's what we want all
right let me take you
i think we saw everything here oh yeah
the bed system uh this is kind of cool
i got a daylight sensor hooked up so
when it's daytime the blocks are over
top here
and at night time they they retract
and it kind of shows that it's time to
sleep you know because when you're down
here you have no idea what
what the time of day is out there
all right so back here we just have our
item filters for the different things
pretty standard standard stuff here i
got the hoppers running across the top
here
i didn't do any water streams or that
kind of thing i just wanted to do it
nice and clean with the hoppers
um this side we have the shards and
stuff
crystals the items get brought up here
from these droppers and
i have not quite finished this yet i
wanted to
start it up with you guys um
you can see we're losing a lot of drops
at the moment they're sitting there
but yeah they funnel in down these
hoppers to the droppers
and then up i did notice while i was
running this is making the clicking
noise a lot i'm hoping that goes away
it does that sound you know i hate that
sound
hopefully once this is finished that
stops otherwise
not sure what to do about it all right
so the last thing to do
is just run one more staircase up
all right to here should do it
oh and i gotta put a block below
all right hopefully the clicking stops
clicking stop please
i don't think it's gonna stop
really was hoping it would
nope all right
uh that sucks
oh it might be because these are full
though i wonder
yeah because it's clicking because it
can't shoot the items into the next one
because it's full
maybe it just needs a little bit of time
to catch up and then it'll stop
hopefully yeah i'm not sure
anyways items should be going through
through the system here that's so
annoying
i wouldn't mind if it was farther away
but i think you can hear it even when
you're when you're in this room
yeah it's too loud all right are they
going in the chest
looks like they are they're getting
sorted some of these i manually put in
i guess i'll just wait a while and see
what happens with that
okay so i want to show you guys this
it's night time now the spawn rates are
kind of decreasing
still get a few every now and then but
it's not like during the daytime
and the blocks disappear above the bed
so it shows it's night time
it's time to sleep if i want to make
things pick up again so go to bed
it's daytime block blocks extend again
and then at night time they'll go back
so that's kind of cool uh you will
notice
there is no more uh dropper sound
sound of torture it's like one of the
worst sounds in this game like even
after two minutes i was starting to feel
anxious
and like angry and irritable and
oh there's something about that dropper
sound it just drives me nuts
but yeah now that the droppers are
cleared out they're kind of going
through
items are going through one by one and
it's stopped making that clicking sound
which is great ah let's see
but yeah the only thing is it can't keep
up with the rate we're getting the drops
i don't think like it
maybe at night time it catches up i'm
not sure
no i don't think it does honestly i
think this is kind of stuck
yeah like you see how we have 64 fish
two two shards
it's not none of these fish are going
out of here like it's
yeah it's just getting drops too quickly
you know now that i think of it that's
actually a really big
problem possibly because it's like this
farm is almost too good now
if it gets items too quickly
it will get stuck on one item like it'll
never
like let's say it's fish let's say fish
is first
it will only ever put out fish it won't
go
it won't move on to the shards it won't
move on to the crystals it's just like
constant fish flow through this whole
thing
and you know we can't really just add
more
another row of hoppers or something like
that because we
we only have like the item filter here
can only process
it so quickly unless we add more item
filters which i don't want to do
um
i took out the items here manually just
to see if it could catch up or
keep up and it's sort of on the
fence maybe maybe it is keeping up
actually
it's hard to say it might be night time
now though
oh man i didn't even cover over the
water yet i don't think we're gonna do
that if that's the case
because then this definitely won't keep
up if that increases the spawn rates
all right let's go over here is it
nighttime please don't be night time
it's it's daytime okay
so it can keep up i think it can keep up
it's good
okay yeah now that it's totally caught
up you can hear the droppers again
that's confirmation that it can keep up
uh which is good but it's also bad
because now we can hear the droppers
again
every so often
which is annoying uh but yeah anyways
we're gonna add one last thing to our
system
uh for today anyway basically we're
gonna want to add
in uh a lava kill machine
sort of thing so any drops that don't
get filtered
are going to end up in this dropper here
like any garbage
goes into there also like when those
chests fill up with shards or whatever
we sort of have to deal with them
otherwise it's gonna back up and all
these hoppers
all the way down the line and then
nothing will be able to
get filtered through it's just gonna
stop the whole system
but if we have something like this where
we deal with
items like if we have any garbage
just automatically get automatically
gets ejected in there also helps to
reduce leg hopefully
although it causes a bit of lag because
of the clock
but we won't have all these items that's
kind of sitting around either
that can't be picked up it'll it'll pick
them up and deal with them
so yeah i think that should be good
all right very cool guys so we got that
project done
really happy about that i was trying to
rush it though like
i wanted to get done in the first half
of the episode
and we're about 18 19 minutes in now
so it took up most the episode
unfortunately
uh but we will try to get into one more
thing here before we end it
um so this is a new area in the man cave
this this section here we built the
snack-o-matic already
very important build to our world
now we have this little empty space here
what i'm planning to do
is build an armory in this area just
like a little fun build
you might have seen this already like
where people have armor stands they put
their armor on it
and then they have several armor stands
with armor on and then they swap between
it
usually they use slime block launchers
and like pistons
um to switch between the sets uh what i
want to try to do is set up a minecart
thing
that will allow us to cleanly switch
between our
our wardrobe you know also we're gonna
put like
tools in our armory too like have spot
for
swords axes shovels you know
picks that kind of stuff because
don't really have enough space in our
storage room in the man cave
fills up pretty quickly so let's do a
little bit of theory crafting a little a
little fun with minecarts
i want to show you a couple cool ideas
so
we have our armor stand right with our
armor on we're going to want to be
able to switch between them in a very
nice way so probably
just have a button or something hey you
have a button we press when we press the
button we want this armor stand to go
away
and then we want a new one to take its
place okay
so probably what we'll do is have
one more in or so no i did that wrong
probably do something like this so we
press the button
when we press the button this piston
retracts
something like that it'll drop it down
out of the way
go away arm stand and then
when the button unpresses the block goes
back the next armor stand falls down
and lands on top of this area or
something
to deal with this armor stand will drop
down
my plan is to use minecarts to move it
so we could have like a power rail sort
of situation
maybe a dispenser here full of mine
carts
right or do we not want to do that
um dispenser with minecarts in
trying to think of how to do this i
haven't exactly figured it all out or
anything
oh i think that is the sheep farm down
there
so yeah press oh
my bad my bad that did not work because
the power rail wasn't powered i think
let's try that again do we have
yes we do we can make levers
never leave home without levers they're
so useful
okay that did not work why did that not
work guys that's supposed to work
let's drop this one down
okay there that time it worked i guess i
nudged it a little bit into the
side of the block and it didn't pick it
up then all right so we can have uh
armor stands and minecarts and we'll
move them around that way
and you'll notice the minecarts kind of
stack on top of each other we're going
to take advantage of that
pez dispenser mechanic with this build
let's go back up get out of here oh man
i'm wrecking all the ground
okay just want to leave this hole
all right so the next part of this the
pez dispenser thing is where we're going
to store all the armor stands
uh i figured out something kind of cool
here today this might be a well-known
thing but i didn't know about it
basically
we can still do pez dispenser setups
like if you have a sheep farm
and you want to keep them in a pez
dispenser like all the sheep
stacked up you can do that still um
there's a really cool trick
for separating them basically
okay so here's our armor stand right
minecart goes into it
falls down let's do one more
okay so they land directly on top of
each other stacked very nicely
the only problem is if you try to move
them with a piston or something
that happens and i think if you
have a rail there let's just try that
actually
relearn some of the game mechanics here
i think when you have a rail there they
kind of stack
together if i'm not mistaken
okay go go mine carts do your thing
do they go together yeah they go like
right inside each other that way
so we've got two mine carts there so you
can't have a rail you have to have
no rail here's the trick though
put down a slab like so with a sticky
piston
and now when we we stack them
let's just put a few of them down maybe
we'll do three or four
this time i wish i could do this a lot
faster though
wasting time on the on the recording all
right
and there we go four is good enough
so they stack very nicely and now when
we
activate this piston check out what
happens
it only pushes one and then the next one
lands on the piston arm so it actually
doesn't fall any further then when it
retracts
goes on and that way we can do it one by
one
it's a good way of separating them which
is pretty cool
and here's another cool trick i don't
know how many of you know this
but if you have a power rail and a
minecart on top of a slab this
the minecart will actually fall through
the slab watch this
or not a power rail any rail just
automatically falls through it
it's kind of a cool thing
so i just set up a quick example here of
how it's going to work guys we'll finish
it up next time though
but basically i got a jet piston thing
over here so
when you pull a lever armor stand falls
down
goes away gets picked up by a minecart
put back on the top of the
pez dispenser top of the stack right
then another minecart is going to come
by with a different armor stand
and this will be gone
let's get rid of it and it has to get
out of the
the minecart though right it has to be
ejected from the mine cart so we're
going to use
activator rails to do that
so from the pez dispenser it's going to
come down this line
and basically
it's a pretty simple thing actually
for some reason it doesn't let me place
an armor stand here i have to break the
the track first
don't know what that's about we are very
limited on space though like this is
this is the path right here so i got
like a too high space to work with here
i'm not exactly sure where the pez
dispenser is going to go because it
needs a bit of vertical space
but yeah watch what watch what happens
here when we place the minecart down
it's going to pick up this armor stand
goes over the activator rail which
ejects it
then the minecart goes over this
detector rail which causes the piston to
push it off the track it lands right on
top that
the track here so really quickly it's
going to happen pushes it down the hole
lands on our spot down there and
that's our next next one uh basically
my inventory guys my inventory is so bad
right now
all right so this one falls down and
then
push a button cycles to the next one
same deal
goes down like that so that's that's a
general idea to it
we'll finish it up next time though yep
so let's finish up our episode here guys
with the comment of the day like we
usually do
we got a nice simple question here from
joshua
it says etho why don't you overclock
your cpu
i've done that in the past like when
overclocking first became a thing
and i had a nice fast computer but it
burnt out on me it did not last its full
length of time it only lasted like a
year or two
and then i got like a blue screen of
death and
basically fried the thing i think um had
to get a new computer
ever since then i haven't wanted to to
really try it again i know
like there's a lot of science to it
there's uh safe ways of doing it
and i could probably read up on it and
figure it out but
um at the moment i don't know how to do
it it would be
take a bit of time to figure it out but
the big thing is well
with my videos i try to eliminate all
background
sounds that i can like i try to make
sure there's no humming
i try to make sure there's no banging i
make sure i close my window before i
record so there's no like
street sounds or anything like that um
unless it's absolutely unbearable
and hot you know that's the other thing
if uh if you overclock your cpu
your computer puts out a lot more heat
too so it becomes more uncomfortable in
the room you're recording
um but yeah the big thing is i don't
want my computer fans going crazy trying
to cool this thing down either because
that would add a lot of
background sound
but that's gonna be it for today guys i
hope you enjoyed today's episode let me
know what you think of
the build and all that kind of stuff and
thank you for watching as always i'll
see you in the next one
take care bye