[Music]
hey there
how's it going
now do you realize what was wrong with
what i just said do you know why i
sounded like an idiot just now
i'll tell you you probably don't even
think about it but if you're me
you can't stop thinking about this all
the time
why do people say hi there hey there
hello there when they greet you
it doesn't make any sense i tell you why
are you giving me a location
after you greet me there
there and it's so unspecific too just
there
my name isn't there why are you saying
there after your greeting
i'm assuming okay let's assume it's
short form
for hello person over there okay
that's that makes the most sense at
least right
even still it's not like you point when
you say hey there hey person over there
pointing at that person
you kind of do with your eyes i suppose
but generally you say hey there when
you're looking right at the guy two feet
away from you right
so why are you saying hey there hi there
hello there
say hey etho or something like that
makes a lot more sense
anyways hey there guys welcome back to
another episode
of the let's play series you know i just
occurred to me
i don't know if i tried this what
happens if you use a water bucket on a
coarse fruit seed
does it give you the seed
it doesn't okay it turned it's like man
i bet you i could automate this farm now
no you still don't get the seed that's
too bad
yeah so currently this is the way i
gotta harvest this farm it takes about
five minutes or so
and then we have a button down here we
just press it lets the water out
breaks all the plants pushes all the
seeds into our
our flow flow thing over here
our water channel there that makes more
sense and it does take a while a while
for the
graphics to update here every time i do
it it's kind of weird
uh-huh and then they get sorted and then
the course fruit gets auto-smelted too
there it goes
yeah so basically i'm working on our ice
road in the nether guys i want to extend
it about 700 blocks
and then it's going to attach to that
woodland mansion we found
and then we can bring back the the
vindicators the johnnies and there was a
whole bunch of llamas
in that area too all right so that was
uh that was a long time for me but just
moments for you guys but we got the path
done
in the nether and i'm gonna start
transporting these guys back home i
think we gotta go
this way it's weird like
the other day i was flying around
looking for llamas to to do that
firework thing with
i flew so far and like only found eight
or so
there's over 50 in this mountain range
i'm sure of it there's so many
it's unbelievable oh all the mobs have
spawned now
okay there must not be many caves around
here either there's like 20 mobs up
there
we gotta get them through the portal
there you go uh-oh zombie went through
okay so now we find out if they're all
gonna die as soon as we go through here
are they stuck in the portal the frame
like horses always get
oh oh i think maybe a few of them no
they're okay they're okay
oh man there's a lot of them all right
guys come on
okay here we go here we go here we go
this is the scary part
i didn't have enough per per blocks
there wasn't enough i tell ya they seem
fine though
no
bad
wait did he take away the ground no the
ground's still there good
all right that pigmen needs to die he's
breaking up my caravan
go around you stupid llama
go around he will not walk on that track
ah they died are you kidding me
they went to the wrong portal and died
after i set up the portal tested it
worked and then they
teleport over here
okay well we got three anyway
all right guys well i think it's
official i got some weird glitch
in my world here with the portals like i
i set this portal up here i
tried it it worked both ways sent the
llamas through
and then they ended up way over there
for some reason even though all those
portals were broken
and it seemed to send them underground
and they just like
suffocated and died can you not
i thought this is what you used to breed
them did i forget
can you not breed them wait a minute
uh oh i might need to look this up
okay you know what it is it's hay bales
hay bales we were close
they might need to be tamed as well
these guys aren't tamed at the moment
we'll try them out without
tainting them yeah looks like we gotta
tame them
okay and you and you
do do do do do
there we go we got a little baby llama
awesome so
phase two of this i got these guys over
to sandy city like i wanted
i have also caught a wolf and he's
sitting in the nether tunnel right now
i don't want to bring him over until i
got this all set up but basically i'm
gonna
underneath the path here set up a little
crawl space room where he can run around
where they can't get him
and then we're gonna leave them free to
run under the path here
the llamas will chase them above ground
and
it should hopefully look pretty cool
like they'll walk along the path here
and it will also be a method of storing
the llamas without
having to worry about them running into
cactus or something stupid like that so
i'm going to try
make a path underneath the path here
all around the city
all right very good very good so we got
that all set up now we're ready to move
our dog
into place here this is a cool trick by
the way
if you have a mob in a boat and you know
sometimes when you try to get them out
yet you whack the boat and it hits the
animal instead
this is like a safe way of doing it just
use a lead pulls them right out
and also in minecraft 1.11.1 they made a
change a bug fix where you can actually
lead
hostile wolves this is not a tame globe
the hostile one which is what we need
because those stupid tamed wolves
they always teleport to you and die
even if they're in a minecart they're
like totally useless
so this guy he's going to stay
underneath our path here so i basically
just chiseled out an
area all the way under and i made it
fairly wide just to include
increases uh pathfinding chance
uh so hopefully he doesn't sit around
too much we'll let him go and to see how
he moves
i would love it if he would just like
run straight all the time but that's not
gonna happen
and i could put him in a minecart and
force them to move but it would be very
loud
and also they tend to fight minecarts
anyway can't really control them oh
please move at least a little bit though
okay no that wasn't very good
hopefully hopefully he moves
a fair bit we might
might need that minecart though
oh i heard the wolf all right we'll let
them go
some of them found them yeah they found
them okay cool
so the idea is wherever the wolf goes is
where the llamas are gonna go
they won't break off from the wolf ever
so
i don't have to worry about putting
these guys away they'll just
gravitate towards the wolf always
and i would like it if they would like
walk along the path here so that's why
we might need a minecart
because that wolf isn't moving very much
[Music]
whoa okay that's a wild
wild rest right there so here's the
other problem
with uh using a minecart though i think
we're gonna have to
but we can't just run it straight
through here if we do
the wolf is gonna be faster than the
llamas and then
they'll break the connection if if he
gets away from them
so we have to do like the zigzag thing
and hopefully
they don't zigzag as well hopefully they
walk straight
and also hopefully the minecart doesn't
get stuck
a lot of possible complications with
this
okay he's moving pretty good i can hear
them moving above ground let's go check
him out
we cannot let the wolf see the llamas if
we do i think he'll get aggro
and then this is all done for possibly
i'm not sure though we might be able to
reset it somehow
um okay what are they doing
one of them one of them broke the
connection over here i guess he was too
far away
so bring him closer those guys are
following them they're kind of
zigzagging a little bit though it seems
they look like they're drunk got a pack
of drunk llamas
oh he did a spin even oh snap
we could probably move the wolf a little
bit faster than that but that looks kind
of funny too
all right so it's kind of working right
now but not as well as i would like it
to
you see they keep breaking the
connection the wolf gets too
far ahead of them lost another one there
and then when it goes by they'll pick it
up again but uh
i think i'm gonna try to switch over to
water streams instead of the mine carts
see if that's any better
okay so i think i think i figured out a
pattern that'll work here
what we're gonna do is half slab and
then slab over there so it's gonna push
the wolf
up on top of the slab and then we're
gonna have another water stream over
here
it's been a while since i did anything
with uh moving mobs around with water
okay and i'm not sure i ever did figure
out a way of doing it with a one
tall mob like a wolf but this should
work
right maybe i did i just can't remember
um yes so if if he's stuck in this water
for too long he'll drown but he should
get pushed
through right away unless he gets stuck
on the stairs up there
hopefully i think he's bigger than that
the spacing between the stairs though
right
hopefully okay so that's kind of working
it's pretty slow though
it would look better if there wasn't
four of them all grouped together like
there is
but it's a lot more consistent than the
minecart for sure
okay so i decided to go with the water
system after all
so little guy it's been great this time
we've shared together
i know i love you but this is the last
time you're gonna see the sun
you're gonna go live with the sewer
people now say hello to the ninja
turtles for me
they taught me everything i know
seriously oh no you jerk
all right let's see you fight this go
go go inside okay oh we got him we got
him
yes all right dog is locked and loaded
we are ready to try this out now there
seems to be an endermite somewhere too
i just got it around a loop right now
just a small loop to try this out
okay okay so i got some bad news
that guy didn't make it he's not with us
anymore
uh i sent in one of my team guys to try
this
yeah why are you doing that that's not
good you're gonna die
that water is pushing you is it not
oh nope
[Music]
hmm
i should have used oh i should have used
stairs maybe
all right guys well i tell you what for
the sake of variety we're going to move
on here for today and i'll try to get
that fixed up for next time i think i
can get it working just by changing
those slaps to stairs but i could be
wrong and this could drag on forever
so uh what we're gonna do here
is start setting up our mushroom forest
and here
is a good trick for you guys this is a
common knowledge for a lot of people but
if you don't know this is like one of
the best ways
of quickly crafting blocks just shift
click
to get the netherward out of here or you
can do this with snowballs or whatever
you're
trying to craft together and then just
one two three four
five six seven eight nine wherever your
mouse is hovered over is where it goes
in the crafting grid and then shift
click its
there we go easy crafting so these
blocks are crazy expensive by the way
i have been saving up we got seven
stacks
it's not very much so yeah just outside
of the man cave here to our right is
sandy city
and then to the left we have this swamp
that we haven't really done anything
with i did a little bit here just to try
you know spicing it up a little bit you
guys seem to like this so i'm gonna
leave it and
it might stick a little bit to this
theme as well but then we got this whole
area out here
which hasn't really been touched and i
want to do this biome enhancement thing
right well i have a
flat boring swamp we've seen a million
of
uh right next to my home here we should
try to do something a little bit cooler
i made one custom mushroom when these
first came out i think that looks pretty
good but i also want to try make some
big mushroom trees
to go along with like these smaller ones
um
so maybe we'll put one right over here
let's see if we can we can build one of
these together so it's kind of like
building a custom tree you just put down
like
a base a trunk of some sort
give it a crazy random shape and then
start building it up
fattening it up as you go
and it's going to be amazing
i have a rough idea of how to do this
the cool thing about
building mushrooms compared to custom
trees is uh
with mushrooms you don't need to place a
million leaf blocks
you just you can use a symmetrical
pattern even and it will look
good while custom trees you gotta place
down so many leaves and it takes forever
to build them
because of that yeah i'm gonna make this
fairly tall
and probably about two three blocks
wide i would say maybe
how's that looking all right it's a
start it's a start
um now what i want to do is start
branching out as well
so like this looks a little weird over
here this is like
hanging off it looks like so we need to
change that so maybe
let's try to create a bit more continuum
here
well why is that broken that was weird
start bulking this out
yeah oh actually see like this is bad
when you have a
block here and a block here you should
always continue it
so i'm gonna put one more block right
there
there that looks better um maybe even a
block here
you don't want any like big flat spots
like this either you want to always put
a block here or
or something like that and then we're
going to start making branches
so mushroom trees have branches in case
you didn't know
we're gonna probably just go out three
or four blocks
start curving it up like that gonna keep
these pretty thin
and then maybe go up one more and then
we're gonna do a
three by three thing of this this stuff
and i'm not even really planning this
out too much as i go as you can tell
but i think it's gonna look pretty good
i tried making some of these in creative
and it was very easy and each one only
took like 5-10 minutes
so i'm pretty excited about this
okay another trick i've seen people do
is they grow
jungle trees and then they replace all
the leaves with uh
with these netherward blocks and then
the the trunk of the tree they replace
with bone and that looks pretty good too
but
you can't really do that in survival
because the tree will start dying as you
start replacing
the blocks yeah that's what i want to do
just like that
probably have like two of those two or
three of those branches on each of these
mushroom trees
sticking out so then i'll probably put
one a little bit higher up and
maybe one more and then a big cap on the
top
yeah so i'm trying to give this main
trunk a little bit of character so you
can see it kind of curves out to the
right and it's starting to curve
back and i think that looks pretty cool
and wherever you can take advantage of
the the depth
of it uh try to so you can see it like
goes in over there and
and over there and it's out over here
it's not like a big flat thing
uh on this other side though we got a
bit of a flat thing going on right so
you got to try
try to break that up wherever you can
uh where does it make most sense so it's
it's thin here so maybe we
we bulked it up here all right
yeah i think that'll look good nope
it needs more if you just have like
little things like that sometimes it can
look weird too
um we could try to
maybe do that awesome so i'm pretty
happy with that for the trunk
i think that looks good nice and organic
uh looks good for most angles as well
you always want to
take a look around just double check
this angle maybe not as nice
but you know you don't want to get too
crazy overboard or it'll spin forever on
this kind of stuff
um so now we gotta add maybe two more
branches and
the cap on the top and it's done i would
say
so the main
trunk goes off to the right curves to
the right and then we have a little
branch
um so it's kind of going up and then it
starts curving to the left so i think we
should put another branch over there
it's kind of how plants grow if you ever
like look at them and study them
if the main branch curves or if it grows
a branch then the main branch kind of
curves away from
the branch it just grew for a lot of
plants
okay so maybe
we don't want to just do it straight
either we want to add a bit of variety
to it
um it won't look as good as if we do it
straight
but our eyes will kind of correct for
the
odd shape i think and then maybe we'll
go over here
yeah there we go i think that looks
pretty good that's the one we did
together
and it comes out two blocks uh forward
compared to this one
we also never want to have them on the
same height level so it's also two
blocks higher up
and just creates a staggered effect
looks good that way i think
i added one more on the back here
maybe not so good it looks weird it just
comes straight out maybe let's add one
more bone block
right there does that help it
it looks it needs to look structurally
supported
uh yeah that would work except
now it looks weird over there you see we
have that block
and that block on the same height we
always want to stagger things if we can
and we definitely can here
maybe we'll go up two
and should we take that out let's take
that out fix that
okay so then at the top of the trunk
we're going to do the big mushroom cap
on
on the very tippy top we're going to do
pretty much the same shape except uh
we'll
make it come out on the sides here make
it a little bit bigger than
the little ones and then we're going to
do two rings
down from that so come out one block and
one block down
like this uh yeah kind of keep that
shape and then come out one more after
that
like that
okay so how does it look from a distance
here
oh yeah i think that's pretty cool right
yeah i like that a lot awesome
so i'm gonna try build a few of these i
have uh two of them pre-built
in a creative world i'll copy over here
uh this episode is supposed to be up
already though
so we're gonna have to wrap it up i
don't have time to build them and show
you
but we'll check them out next time
another thing i would recommend
is uh putting some end rods underneath
that way they'll be lit up at night
and also kind of looks cool like they
got little dangly things
that mushrooms sometimes have
uh-huh you know i was watching a youtube
video the other day and apparently there
are
actually glowing mushrooms they're green
they look amazing
luminescent mushrooms check it out man
so cool but anyways guys i think we
should call it here for today
so here is the comment i picked out
it says hey etho be very careful in the
latest updates
pistons now count as solid block
so for your pop-up sheep farm the sheep
will suffocate when they go down to eat
grass
i copied your farm design into my
single-player world and had to replace
the pistons
that the sheep stand in with glass
okay well thank you very much for that
that warning uh it's a little late
though
oh yeah as soon as i updated i didn't
see it happen
but uh well some of them are still alive
how's that possible
i did find the remains though here
there's most of the sheep are dead some
of them are still alive
but i'm going to have to get rid of
these pistons and i'll probably put
stained glass there's
corresponding to the color of each of
the sheep
but it's going to be a big thing getting
them all replaced
unfortunately one more thing to add to
the fix list
but hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode
thank you for watching if you have any
ideas for the mushroom forest uh
biome enhancement project please let me
know i want to like redo the whole
ground and everything give it a custom
look
probably a lot of this path block and uh
a bunch of leaves vines i maybe some
dead trees that
that grow over i don't know i i need to
get some inspiration for it
but uh should hopefully look cool and
then we got to think of what
to put here for a feature as well like
should we put houses in here maybe some
big building
i don't know should be fun though thanks
for watching guys have a wonderful day
take care bye bye
[Music]
you