[Music]
oh I got a big smile on my face right
now I knew if I went out every
thunderstorm it wouldn't take long you
see that guy over there went take long
and we would get one I am getting
ambushed here though so this is gonna be
challenging Oh didn't do it oh go go go
supercharged creeper baby
Oh spider jockey no no everything in the
world by me right now don't do it don't
you do it I'm just gonna run around this
guy hopefully he won't be spun my musics
really loud I just updated like
seriously sorry I don't know if you even
heard that I said I just updated to the
snapshot I know it's been out for a few
days but I've been very busy and I
haven't had a chance to play it yet
little buggers in now he's getting too
far away any closer oh and I stopped
healing he's not named yet I haven't
named him yet dude of all times and I
think he's enchanted or he's got potion
effects he's still alive I am not doing
too hot here i tempted to do a pillar up
why do I not even have feet on my bar oh
wow that was close
come on let me heal on I took my bow off
my bar went at genius I am today getting
the food ready this is the hole I fell
down by the way after I filled the
Enderdragon and it's just they're
taunting me like it's gonna happen again
yeah I could just get rid of a few of
these guys he's still there
look at them all probably bad idea to
switch use the different number whoa
zombies got hit by lightning oh my
goodness come on fight of a lifetime
here I think I'm finally in the lead
though not S&P I don't get hit back it's
wonderful skeletons gonna help us oh you
shot through them I'm not healing
anymore there we go finally Devils Oh
getting this guy back that's gonna be
fun oh we got another that's a strike
right by here okay let's try to try to
get him coming closer I'm not really
ready to name him yet just the case
something happens I almost want to go
this way just in case we got another one
that lightning sounded really close I
noticing with the new snapshot already
the world is having trouble loading a
lot
I might pause for a second here and get
it to load just a second
oh and we're back there's still a
thunderstorm there's still tons of mobs
around this little guys falling
did I just see a charged creeper in the
background there I thought I did I'm so
tempted to just name this guy except I
just brought this nametag from from when
I couldn't name Jeff it's like a dud one
I've had around I might just name this
guy Jeff I swear I saw some blue flash
over there okay we're gonna name him
quick oh that was that was sketch okay
I'm gonna go check your room quickly cuz
I could have sworn a maybe not
this is a this thunderstorm has been
going on for a long time I think it was
two in a row and I just thought creeper
here let me be spawned okay
I think that's Jeff I'm too scared to
get close summer hey oh snap oh snap so
I almost think I should wait till it's
like nice out before I try to move this
guy because I'm having all sorts of
trouble with these mobs around
all right I'm just gonna move this guy
it's taken too long I think the the
desert here should be pretty safe it's
not raining mom should burn up here no
man where is he
tried to lead him through this field and
he's in it somewhere
look for blue sparkles there he is
come on guy don't get too close I cannot
Oh No Oh No
Janina I don't know if he can see me in
here actually hey guy
hey how's it going look at him look at
him hey how's it going no oh is he
locked on I think he locked on no he
lost me hey you can catch a glimpse of
the wild Jeff okay now how do I get him
out of here this might have been a
mistake
mmm I think I have a fishing hook around
somewhere yeah let me go check I
remember what I recorded that one intro
by the sheep farm I made a bunch of
fishing hooks around here
that moves those yeah it's not looking
like I have them all on its final day
and fishing rod awesome let's go get
that guy
alright Where's Waldo
where is he he's probably in the reeds
still get up a little bit higher I think
it's easier to see him then ha I see him
the fun things you can do with a
supercharged creeper
all right guy come on oh did we get him
it almost looks like we did now I hit
the aah
okay we got a beaten hook did he run
is he ready oh he's got his eye on us
okay
oh it's almost nighttime ah let's
hightail it out of here mm-hmm I got a
speed potion this will help us in case
of emergencies let's go come on towards
the beacon actually we want to go this
way
so forgetful know what come on don't do
that he wants me to get backed up into
something then get stuck and then it's
all over
oh this is about that choice of fruit
let's go come on come back this way
let's go up this way trees are in the
way okay and then can he get over this
I'm gonna make it so he can get over
okay very good
let's come on guy you're so close I
should have prepared a spot for him
maybe but as long as he's down here I
can keep an eye on him my very own super
charged creeper I've been waiting for
this for so long question is where
should we put him 8 mm hmm come on down
the stairs good boy actually I should
maybe you've put him in there or we'll
put him in the potion room I think we
could pull that off let's get some inter
pearls ready we'll lock them in the
potion room with Tom and then Jeff and
Tom can be together once again oh just
don't blow up please Tom get away from
the door Tom now is not the time come on
yeah dude I'm worried if I open the door
Tom's gonna run out he's right there as
a thing take come on Jeff oh oh I have
this thing on a timer I forgot all right
welcome back home Jeff OH
oh snap let me out holy smokes I can't
believe that works that was amazing what
did I just do let's go check make sure
he's there and I better heal
things so derpy tonight it's wonderful
hey Jeff and Tom right now we'll keep
them in there anyway is either the
potion room is still here so that's a
good sign
maybe I'll get an invisibility potion
and go on in there just that's the more
fun so we got some invisibility potions
this guy's really interested in us he is
in there that's confirmed
yeah good I'm doing an invisibility
potion I'm like really messing around
with my sounds because everything's out
of whack with the new updates definitely
a good feature I just got to get used to
it
and anyway we'll look at this later he
still sees us of course get rid of this
still sees us it looks like now if we
leave his target range and then coming
back okay I don't think we're gonna go
in there I think yeah I think we've
messed with this guy enough for today I
don't trust this I did want to do that
though okay that's so cool
all right yes a new update very excited
I wanted to check out a few new things
because I haven't had a chance to
explore yet we are gonna go exploring in
my single-player world here I don't mind
if boarders and stuff get a little
messed up from it and I do I had whoa
speak clearly I have made a backup
before I update it too so if there's
some serious world corrupting problem I
will be able to go back but I wanted to
show you this this is the fishing shack
project and and cavern and stuff
I think it's going pretty good here I'm
actually ready to fill in the water and
then we'll shape it some more afterwards
but we're gonna put the waterfall here
and that splits to the right here and to
the left it goes around the back and
then I have another pillar coming down
here water will go around as well so
maybe before we go exploring I'm gonna
fill this in with water and we can check
it out because I'm curious to see what's
gonna look like here and the fill it's
gonna be using a nice block nice and
simple easy to do okay that might be a
sign that we've crossed over here to the
new terrain chunk border is messed up
there look at all the flowers roses have
a new look now and I believe you can
make them bigger let's see if we can do
that nope
are these not roses anymore they all
those are poppies now ah they look very
old new flowers okay
yes this is new terrain oh it's
something cool coming in here with a
waterfall it is a second I killed three
sheep so we can sleep here this is
awesome new terrain is something I've
wanted for a long time as I'm sure many
people have cool ok let's go check out
this mountain that gene that's spawned
in here I think there's a lot of exposed
stone stuff now oh that was tall grass
too tall tall grass let's go take a look
at this
very nice very nice go up higher what is
this exactly extreme hills just extreme
hills because this looks a lot different
than normal extreme Hills we got snow on
top now that's difference again more
exposed stone and that definitely looks
like the chunk boarder there so it's
gonna be my world's gonna be a little
messed up from that but there's no
helping it and if they change it again I
don't really mind too much I actually
really like this hill here okay
the way it's shaped it's like a nice
gradual and then we got a big cave there
you got some plains here we might find
some horses
I want to go about well we're almost a
thousand bucks
two thousand bucks out here maybe we'll
set that as our new limit let's not
let's try not to go past 2,000 see we
got a forest
very cool our flowers biome specifically
can we get that's a new flower right is
this ox eye that right did I say that
right
oxide Daisy we're just about at two
thousand oh we got sunflowers I can tell
already I see the back of them let's go
up here
okay sunflowers very cool I like these
we're gonna take some of these back
weird very weird oh it almost look they
didn't have a top tool very weird icon
for these things doesn't really look
like a plant it's like a pellet of some
sort they're popping off very nice okay
let's keep going
whoo
got some nice mountains over here
swamplands perhaps oh look at this
that's pretty cool you got nice
waterfalls in a river and then it's I
think that's a ravine with a mountain
range over top let's go take a better
look at this all those circumstances
came together to make a very cool
picturesque scene here look at this
that's cool especially from that angle
that we were just at let's go look from
the top of the hill Wow
screenshots I like that that's cool
alright and is that is this because
we're still in extreme biomes here that
we have that tree close to the swamp or
is this something different extreme
Hills plus I'm really worried I'm gonna
fall into some lava or something not
paying attention here okay we're at
2,000 okay let's let's not go any
further it doesn't look like there's
anything new there so so there's tall
ferns too there's there's tall grass and
tall ferns aha okay we'll keep this
place in mind this is the like the
biggest jungle I found in my world here
neverending except for over here there's
an end over here but I've been walking
for a while through that thing and this
is Oh what is this stream Hills got some
good overhangs going on I actually have
a lot of things like this in my world
where there'll be a big mountain and
there'll be a big non-supported overhang
just sticking out the top so something
I'm noticing with these new biomes I
don't know if they changed or not but I
know before it was very difficult to
like find a spot where everywhere you
look was that one biome unless you were
playing with extra large biomes I almost
think either I'm finding really large
ones by chance here but I almost think
they're bigger than they used to be
because this is all this taiga take a
tango whatever biome it's all visible
from this one spot and it probably keeps
going aways too good there's no Enderman
chasing me I I heard the sound but I
don't think it actually counted yeah
this biome stretched on for almost a
thousand blocks I think this is a swamp
swampland yeah
Oh what is this uh-huh
see I don't even think I saw pictures of
this kind of swampland that's pretty
cool
swamp breeds looks like this is
different biomes bro they're different
colors anyway and then this looks like
the regular swamp up this way
that's cool stim print very small though
I finally found a like a biome I wanted
to see this stuff here and it's so small
all right well let's keep looking
that's pretty neat the way these two
form going opposite of each other that's
cool mountain with a big hole through it
right through the center let's go look
on the other side here there any mobs in
here no we're good
got a waterfall lava fall and ravine
down here what do we have here ah this
is a new one okay what is this this is
roofed forest so there's there's
mushrooms in this and very very cool
trees very dense forest from what it
looks like hard to walk through but I'm
guessing I don't think they came out
with any new saplings though like I'm
sure this is dropps okay there's no way
of planting these trees unfortunately
now or do we get oak sapling yeah what
are they they're they're two by two
unless there's two by two oak sapling
trees now
there's even a mushroom up on top that
mountain let's go look at that I wonder
if the force made it all the way up
there I'm running out of ender pearls oh
wow that's a cool view
that's really nice yeah there's one lone
mushroom on top the mountain here
extreme Hills Stream Hills and must be
right here where it's changes no I just
had just crossed over to extreme hills
it goes all around I liked this biome a
lot what color is it you know I didn't
even look at the grass color is it green
is it green green mm not quite it's
almost like a prairie actually no it's
darker than prairie grass I think a
little darker a little greener
wolfies wolf just killed something
killing all the sheep oh wow we found an
angry wolf I did not know you could find
random angry wolves oh he cured himself
when he saw that the food that was weird
oh and it's almost nighttime again no oh
what's this what's this ah very nice
things are getting interesting again
hello what is that get closer
oh that is a pretty weird it's like a
very thin strip i shadow anything it's
connected there I think it's all coming
from that side going over yeah even with
a lake like this it looks really good
very nice not really any Hills but just
the water next to all the trees and the
dark grass is pretty cool well we are
back home here once again and just
turning day I'm noticing like previous
mountains that didn't have snow on
before now have it so I guess all
extreme hills get snow from what it
looks like cuz glowing tree Mountain
that one all have snow on now even
though they never did before which I
guess is okay I don't know so I didn't
walk back I decided this was a bit of a
tough decision I decided to load up a
backup I made just before we left on
that trip we still have Jeff but all the
work I did on that River I'm gonna have
to redo I don't know I I'm a little
concerned there might be some issues
with the the terrain update I wasn't
quite ready to make that step yet cuz I
went through about eight Plains biomes I
think after walking about 5000 blocks or
more
in that little adventure we did I didn't
see a single horse which has me a little
worried I might have just been really
unlucky but from my experience every
Plains before this usually has at least
one horse in but now to go through eight
and not find any makes me think either
they really lowered the rates on purpose
or there's some kind of bug there that I
should wait on here also like even
though we saw a lot of cool things I
found a lot of the terrain was pretty
flat so I'm considering doing that
amplified thing even more now but again
I think we should just wait a bit and
see what comes out of this at least
another patch or two before we go
exploring again yeah we're gonna get to
the comments for this episode I'm gonna
write write it down I forgot to do that
before I start recording here so I'll be
right back
oh yeah and the fishing rod we lost the
vision rod actually no it never existed
this is this is my first fishing rod I'm
enchanting yeah this exact same thing
what okay well I guess that works out
doesn't it perfect okay so here's the
comments I picked out Oh is there a
quotation one books or did I add those
in I don't think I added those in wait a
second I'm gonna check some older ones
oh yeah they often quote Asian marks on
that's new interesting okay so the
question in this is one that came up a
lot in last episode I saw a lot in the
comments it says etho with the new jet
new terrain generation reminds me of
when you started this world would you
consider a new world please put this in
your next video thanks okay so when I
started this world a lot of people think
it's because of the new generation that
came out
actually it's because just about
everything in my old world broke when
that patch came out when that new
version came out wasn't just because of
the new terrain is because everything
was wrecked and I didn't want to spend
forever moping and trying to fix it and
you know I just wanted to have gone too
well with this update yes we have new
terrain generation but nothing's really
broken and I'm not really ready to say
goodbye to this world just yet still
having fun with it so we might just go
farther out if we want to build
something where the new terrain
generation is we we definitely have that
option it's not even that far it's like
less like we can probably get to it
within a thousand two thousand blocks as
we saw today so this world still pretty
new feeling to me
I have even built a lot of the farms you
can build like I don't know we're not at
that point yet so I don't think that's
gonna happen but thanks for the question
everyone and I guess I suppose that is
the end of this episode right Jeff
that's right keep your back turned on me
Normie like the jerk you are okay well
thank you everybody for watching
much appreciated I hope you enjoyed it
and I will see you again next time
take care bye bye
you