hello everybody welcome to another
episode of our let's play series and
today guys I thought we would have some
fun at the beginning here there's a
concept in this game that's fairly new
I'm sure a lot of you have seen it
before though if you have Elijah wings
you can like jump and then activate the
wings before you hit the ground and then
you can do something like this where if
you have a one block I'd gap you can
actually like get stuck underneath it
and start crawling around I was playing
around with this today and it's actually
a lot of fun I'm gonna refer to it as
tunneling here I don't know if as a
fishel name but I start asking questions
like let's say you have a flat surface
like this is there some way of making
like a bunny hole to get down into a
tunnel and turns out there is and
there's a lot of cool little tricks you
do with it it's a lot more of a flexible
thing than I realized
until today so for example let's say we
want to go underground and do something
like this and go into crawl mode and
let's say you want to get out well you
can't jump out of here right if you put
a slab down still can't get out if you
put two slabs down you can but you can't
actually fit between that little gap
there anymore so a cool thing to use is
snow slabs you can set them up so you
just barely get out of here like that
and then you can still fit between that
gap to get down which is cool and it
turns out I didn't realize this but you
can actually like play the game when
you're crawling around like this it's
it's really cool so you can expand your
tunnel as you go if you want okay tell
you what let's go try finding the zombie
for example you hear him let's go get
them so you can you can dig very easily
while you're while you're in this mode
it's no problem and you can build while
you're like this to basically do
something like that we can go keep going
here now you'll notice here if I try to
forward right now it doesn't let me it
actually look will bump me back if we
look in our camera view we're actually
standing up still we're not like
actually crawling so that one of the
rules to this is your head has to be in
like a non solid block in order to
continue if we try to go ahead here our
head is actually hitting the stone block
above here but we can put either a glass
block or a sea lantern or or something
there instead that's not to consider it
like a opaque block you know where is
this zombie I think keys I'll regain
closer we're getting closer actually we
don't even need to replace the stone
here yeah it's it's pretty cool I would
be curious like you could play the whole
game this way if you wanted what kind of
base would you end up making if you did
that I bet you that'd be a pretty cool
challenge think we're getting closer oh
there he is we found him something I
played around with a lot today was the
staircase design um I tried to find one
that actually used stairs instead of
slabs but I couldn't find anything that
works
unfortunately let's look at a few more
rules to the tunneling here get a clear
idea of how it works so if you're
already tunneling and you enderpearl
you stay in a tunneling mode here you
don't you don't go out of it so that's
kind of cool also your player is 5/8 of
a block tall that's really important to
keep in mind with this so a slab is four
eights we're five eights so that means
we can't fit underneath this little
space here
there's only a few blocks in the game
that actually go to this point 375 if
you look at our y-coordinate daylight
sensors are one of them and that allows
you to fit underneath here so this is
five-eighths tall where we're at right
now that's the tightest spacing you can
get so you can do that with snow slabs
you can do it with daylight sensors and
another one is flowerpots oh darn it we
went out a tunneling mode to get back
into it can be a little bit tricky oh
there we go we're fine usually you have
to break the blocks above you to do it
yeah these are also points 375 oh we're
in danger
quick to the bunny hole all right I
installed the door to our place here
pretty fancy right two-way door very
simple uh-huh I've got some chests in
here just goofing around with a few
things here
so another thing to keep in mind about
tunneling here is you can you can jump
when you're like this so for example you
could go underneath here or you choose
to jump to the second layer like so and
like a normal minecraft you can only
walk up half a slab or four eighths of a
block at a time so you can do like stair
chases where you walk up like that for
example
yeah just lots of lots of really weird
things one of the things I haven't tried
yet I wanted to do with you guys is what
happens if you set up minecart tracks
here can you like go in them and still
see I'm not sure oh okay I didn't expect
that we're even lower to the ground now
we're right at the rails all right now
if we leave are we gonna stay in
tunneling mode oh you fall through
blocks okay cool but anyways here is the
main thing I wanted to show you guys
with the tunneling so I set up a little
little tunnel over here and go sneak
inside the hole the whole reason I was
playing around with this today is like
man I wonder if you could do the ice
speed boost somehow and it turns out you
can you can do the speed boost failure
while you're tunneling here kind of cool
so I put a tunnel from from over there
to the village a little fast faster
method of getting here Oh
might have to change out a little bit
and I use flowerpots just because I
don't want the redstone activating with
the daylight sensors I'm not sure which
one's more leggy than then each other
though oh yeah and before I forget guys
I want to give you a big thank you for
your response on that last episode very
encouraging and much appreciated
I think that might have been the best
received video of this series so far
actually it got like just about 6,000
comments and what was it I think about
18,000 likes but if I remember right so
that that was really awesome thank you
for that in that video we got something
to check out here while we were checking
out the shaders I went down this path
here and some of you observant viewers
noticed that I did actually finish this
area so before the path ended about here
now we have a guardrail on the side some
requested that we get a better look of
it here so that's why we're checking it
out
I've got a guardrail over here and I
tried to transition this hill as
smoothly as I could kind of an awkward
thing but I think it turned out pretty
good so got a nice gradual Hill down got
some droopy leaves hanging down I had to
do a little bit of terraforming to get
the shape and then I also made a bit of
a tunnel here to go through the hill and
all in all I'm pretty happy with it
there's also hidden lighting throughout
there and in the leaves I believe yeah
like there's a little stone down there
whenever I do hidden lighting I always
like to put the glowstone one block
below this surface I think it looks a
lot better and then you just put in an
extra leaf block over there instead of
putting it like flat with the surface or
flush with it aha
and also I have pretty much finished
this fence around the village so it goes
all the way down the side here and all
the way down that side there I can't
really see it there we go that's cool
and I got one more thing to show you
guys here aha so it always bothered me
like we had this big reed field here for
so long and it never really had a proper
border to it the sand just kind of ended
and I
so they had a bit of a problem with it
because Anderman were stealing the sand
blocks and every now and then we would
lose another replant like the soil was
slowly gradually receding in as Enderman
took it away so now we have a proper
fence going around it and it should
protect the reeds I think that's pretty
cool and put a possible date over here
this is more of a placeholder I wouldn't
say that's finish but I thought that
might look nice there some or something
over there might look nice we should
probably put a path through here would
be a good idea and I also was playing
around with the what do you call this
trodden dirt yeah so I got that kind of
going around the whole wall
it's like fan skate well that's the one
so it helps the transition from grass to
the sandstone I think it's a little bit
of an in-between that kind of works with
both the blocks oh and by the way guys
minecraft one point eleven was
officially released as I'm sure a lot of
you saw ready
so we've updated in the series here
we're no longer on the snapshots which
is awesome and with one point eleven
there has been some changes in the game
so I will say it's probably like one of
my favorite updates but unfortunately it
has broken a few things in our world
here number one I would say is this
build over here this is to convert
zombie villagers from a zombie spawner
into villagers and then you can move
them around the world honestly I haven't
used this too much maybe two or three
times but it was a cool build it
nonetheless so the change in 1.11 is
zombie villagers no longer spawn from
zombie spawners which kind of sucks so
this is officially broken cannot be
fixed and likewise this little build
over here is also broken unfortunately
not a big deal though I don't use this
too often probably maybe five times or
so it's it's been really crucial this is
by our underground village if all the
villagers die which has happened like
five times then I use this to spawn into
the zombie villager cure it and then
then bring it over to the village down
this tunnel um but we'll keep it
both those builds just in case they riad
that feature later all right guys so now
I hopped over to our gold farm in the
nether and I just want to check if this
is broken or not this is that item
loading system we built there has been
some observer changes so I don't know
that did something to it could go either
way I'm gonna try to fill this up though
and just see what happens okay here we
go guys we're going to load up one by
one and when it's totally filled up it
should switch to the next box if it
still works yeah I look good to me cool
so that seems to have survived now I saw
in the Minecraft reddit today someone
uploaded a video of their gold farm and
the zombie pigmen were spinning in it
for some reason so let's see if that's
an issue with this like they were just
spinning like a ballerina oh not problem
there Oh didn't keep going though that's
fine that happens sometimes
definitely though our conveyor system
using piston translocation is not
working as well as that elevator to the
library is going to have to be changed
and probably a couple other things I
can't think of all right so this is good
this is still collecting the the gold
and the zombie flesh it's just not
bringing the XP to us so I'm gonna have
to redo this I'll try to that today oh
can you not get XP anymore
no no there is XP there I just couldn't
see it actually one of the problems with
this build as I put this one block too
high and that's why we have a bunch of
pigments stuck here so I'm gonna be able
to fix that too I want to make the
changes surprise whoa-ah-ah-ah here we
go
alright guys so are you confused
you should be I'll give you a little
backstory on this project though this
was something I started way back in 1.8
and then it broke in 1.9 just after I
got like the start of the stun and I
haven't fixed it since and today on a
whim is like I wonder if I can get this
working again in 1.11 and sure enough
got it going here basically a bunch of
command block stuff changed from one
point eight to one point nine which is
why it broke but it's definitely fixable
I just kind of got distracted from it
and this was supposed to be like a
cannon run video basically after that
last part there they were gonna jump
down and start chasing me but as you can
see I haven't built any more to this so
that's like a little teaser intro to it
and maybe who knows one day I'll
actually finish it but if not at least
you saw the start of it alright guys so
we are back to reality here back in our
let's play world this is a few hours
later now and this has been a bit brutal
this whole redesigning and rebuilding
thing so I'm starting to tear it down
now
I I designed each of the aspects in a
creative world here and now I'm starting
to piece it back together and hopefully
it all works like I like I want it to
but as anybody's guess whether or not
this is actually going to work when
we're all done here
it seemed seemed good though and
creative okay so let's maybe hope that's
not where that goes let's try to build a
little bit of this together give you an
idea of how it works so what we're gonna
do is two sticky pistons here in here
bottom one's going to be a slime block
top one is going to be a glass block so
this is going to be extended most of the
time and the zombie pigmen will fall
down on top of this glass block and take
damage enough to kill them hopefully and
then every so often this is going to
retract and then extend to have the
slime block pushes stuff down the icier
right to the middle alright that's kind
of the general plan to this and now what
do we want to do let's grab some string
here
now two blocks above this I'm going to
put a piece of string there and I think
an observer block over here is what I
did I'm doing this similar to what Snow
Crash did in his gold farm he kind of
has like the best gold form at the
moment if you're looking for a tutorial
originally I tried to vary mine by using
the piston translocator trick but that's
gone now so I kind of have to do what he
did because there's no other real way of
moving XP except like with cauldrons or
something stupid so that's a little bit
too crazy for me
so we're sliding it across ice is the
plan which seems to work pretty good so
I just built a hopper clock here so the
observer goes right into the hopper
clock and this is what's going to
control how often it shoots the items in
the XP across the ice and just in my
testing it seemed like 16 was a good
number here we'll try that out but we'll
be able to control it later if we want
and now we want to go down building this
is going to be tough though because we
can't fly all right where do we want to
go I think we want to go over here yes
can we get down a little bit more okay
I'm just going to put a little bit of a
floor down for now also we can't have a
block under the slime there otherwise it
won't be able to move all right so from
that then we are going to grab the
signal over here so from that then we
want to use a sticky piston will do a
monostable circuits that'll go into
there and then go over like this
redstone repeater set it for all right
so this whole hopper timer thing here it
controls how frequently the slime block
shoots the items across the ice but we
also have to control how how long the
Pistons are tracked for and then before
they extend again we it needs to be long
enough that items can fall down and land
on the note block there if it's too
short of timing it's just going to like
bump them with a glass block or
something and if it's too long then
zombie pigmen will fall down on the note
block and their drops are going to splat
all over the place so we want it to be
just perfect and from
let's see from where we left off there
we're going to branch down here
okay repeater set this one at four this
one at one block over here repeater set
at one and we got to get two Pistons
here for some reason slime blocks are
acting really weird with sticky pistons
you kind of have to activate them with
redstone dust if you'd use a repeater it
leaves the slime block behind it's
really weird with this update okay we
got to get a torch here so yeah by
default these are going to be extended
so we'll do that so if this if this
redstone dust wasn't down there I think
it's going to leave the slime block
behind yeah very weird that's something
new I've never seen that before so we
got to keep a piece of dust down here I
guess alright so then what do we do here
good question good question I think we
go up like this and then in like that
all right
so yeah this extends a signal to be a
little bit longer so that these are
tracked just the right amount of time
get rid of that get rid of that's and
that and I think we are good alright
finally just the prevent zombie pigman
from spawning I'm going to cover this
over with glass oh man I'm getting
really tired here that huge projects a
huge renovation but we're getting close
to done got the four sides all complete
and it's really cool like they're all
self-contained right so there's no clock
that runs it only runs if zombie pigman
are falling down that chamber there and
it shoots items to the middle and now I
got like the middle part done here
you've got a cool wrapping of hoppers
around around the middle section you can
see right there like on all four sides
there is a hopper minecart that's really
important so as like the gold and the
zombie flesh goes across the ice here as
it passes over top that block thought
the hopper minecart is going to pull the
items down and go into these hoppers
it's just here now unfortunately I was
really hoping this would line up with
what we built here already but we are
like five blocks lower already so this
all has to be moved down if we want to
keep it because we don't have the item
filter set up yet that's going to take
up even more space here all right let's
go up here and we should be able to test
the seller already I think we should
test it out I got to make sure this
works before we continue ahh so here's
here's kind of the weird thing as items
slide over here we got trip wires on all
four sides so if we go down here yeah so
as items pass by they do that it gives
it enough time for them to settle in the
slime block in the middle there so
they're not moving when it flings them
upwards and what else does it do good
question
oh yeah there's a delay timer on this
too so I'm hoping like if if a bunch of
X B comes from this side and then a
couple seconds later from that side ah
it doesn't like mess the thing up but we
will have to see when we actually test
it here oh I missed a slab darn it all
right let's go up here we'll try it out
it's not all fully complete down there
either there's still some stuff that
needs to be covered with glass but do a
little first test here and then I got to
also have like a secondary elevator or
maybe even two of them on the way up to
to bounce the XP again please work
though please so it activates right away
at the beginning oh wow it shot like the
baby oh I was kind of cool I see some XP
on the ice there that's not yet
there's XP XP over there Oh big like
spike okay one problem possibly oh no it
shot it shot it good
it's going to shoot it upwards there's a
big pool that in the middle there I
don't think that's running though is it
what's wrong here Oh a piece of XP got
stuck on one of the trip wires and
messed it all up
ooh that's not good
it's getting laggy it's getting really
laggy let's go down and get it all the
mmm I wonder if our chests filled up all
the items are over here now items and xD
okay so I've been watching it that's
what it's supposed to do it seems I
messed up the design a little bit though
this delays system I setup isn't
actually doing anything like I wanted it
to what's happening is because like when
that slime block goes up it brings four
ice blocks with it and those ice blocks
are right next to the tripwire so if an
XP orb comes flying by when those ice
blocks are up it stops right on top of
the tripwire and that's what's messing
it all up so I'm gonna have to fix that
unfortunately though I'm like really out
of it now I've been working on this too
long so we're gonna have to wrap up
episode 4 today and hopefully get this
finished another time let's finish it up
here with a comment of the day which
says hey etho if you get a new PC with a
gtx 1080 will we finally get 1080p
videos as well maybe even 60 frames per
second i would really like it if your
videos got better in a visual aspect
content wise you're among the best but a
boost in video quality would be awesome
so yeah actually i've been uploading a
1080p like all my videos for a few
months now it's kind of hoping people
would just notice but maybe i should say
something here we are uploading in 1080p
we are not uploading in 60 frames per
second i've tried a few
videos at 60fps but overall I just I
don't know if it's really worth it you
guys will help me help me decide I guess
but like for modded minecraft i cant do
60 FPS I could do 60 in this series but
modded I don't have the performance to
do it one problem though with it I'm
worried like people on phones I don't
think you get the option to downgrade to
30fps do you I think I saw a few
complaints on that so I think I'm gonna
try to keep it at 30 unless you guys
convince me otherwise but yeah my
Internet's actually gotten quite a bit
better than it used to be like it's been
doubling every so often which is awesome
I'm up to a 10 upload now which is
really really cool back from like like I
used to be a point for like a few years
ago we're up to 10 that's a big
difference actually I think it's 14 I
just need a better router to to get 40
pings from it so yeah I'm pretty excited
about that happy about it can upload in
any video in like like 20 second not 20
seconds 20 minutes now which is no time
at all the longest part of it is
actually rendering now surrendered in
1080 takes a lot longer than 720 like I
used to upload but it's not too bad
either maybe about half an hour to an
hour per video anyways guys hopefully
you enjoyed today's episode if you have
any feedback for me please let me see it
in the comments and until next time take
care have a great day even a good day
bye bye
you