[Music]
hey guys how's it going
uh yep we're doing it again more
silverfish testing
because it is minecraft 1.4.3
lots of bug fixes which is great and one
of the ones i saw
was that mobs don't instantly teleport
in portals anymore
which has me very hopeful that this
might actually work now so let's try it
out
let's see what happens
i got it prepped and everything so
are you guys gonna cheat oh look at him
go
look at him go oh i'm so happy
spend so much time trying to get that to
work it finally works
see i knew it was a problem or a glitch
or something
yes um
apparently the ground looks weird now
holy these guys
they're like half in the blocks you can
only see when they jump
well that is very cool i am excited
about that
i can actually finish the silver fish
farm now the way i
intended it anyway
oh no i missed the jump
uh let's oh why is that so hard to do
i guess i gotta jump before nope
slid past that's a really hard jump
what the heck i'm going to run out of
ender pearls
i don't want to hit the pigment
maybe if i don't sprint that's the trick
don't sprint
okay well that's good news that is very
good news i'm
really happy about that thank you
dinnerbone and jeb and whoever
made that happen um
been working a little bit around here
just trying to fix things up
um i've added
come on frames there we go i've added
this
along the top what i want to do is have
a walkway that goes
sort around the silverfish farm at some
point
and i'll walk away over here and
something over here where we can
view them nicely um
oh yeah i cleared out a big chunk there
in case you didn't notice
and i've worked on the afk stream
that's not working anymore because of
another change with 1.4.3
where mobs i think anytime they land in
water now
uh they don't die so
that looks really crazy
uh but before the
items were coming down here
it was working pretty good
so yeah i'll have to i'll have to fix
that today too
um anyway uh give me a moment i'm gonna
do some stuff here before we get going
uh okay um
trying to get the afk stream working
again oh look they're doing it
i saw this gunpowder bouncing and then
it's
it flew out this far
and it's real it's really there
this is some strange stuff
i wonder if the slime balls are going to
shoot out too like the gunpowder did
they probably do it when i stop
recording
well for the time being i'm gonna use an
iron bar anyway
um some drops will land on it but the
majority will go
off and down into the water and
this should work like it did before
let's see so i'm gonna get rid of
going to get rid of this fence below
and change that with ice
gotta be quick here
that always scares me
put that there um
[Music]
i guess that's sandstone too
let's do that
okay all right that should be good
yeah so one thing i was thinking about
is the items uh
in the afk stream since every time
an item goes in to the end here the the
world loads the chunks load
eventually if i left it forever um
the items would start despawning just
from its being loaded for five minutes
but
from what i can tell so far that's not a
problem
yeah so this place is starting to feel a
lot more complete to me now like it's
it's actually feeling like one of my
bases instead of a
incomplete project uh there's still
an unbelievable amount to do to it but
it actually feels
pretty good now um
let's see what did i want to do oh yeah
uh somebody left a good suggestion for
these walls because i mentioned i wanted
something some kind of border
on the bottom the leaves
oh let's see what the leaves look like
oh hello
still some dark spots around has me a
bit nervous
yeah leaves i don't think they're gonna
work out too well they're they're really
dark
i do i did want something green though
and a pretty good suggestion
was to use wheat for decoration
so let's see what that looks like i got
everything we need here
um that's probably gonna dry up before
i'm ready
yep it's drying up
growits it's a bit yellowish though
isn't it
that might not be bad
let's just see what that would look like
another idea is to use sugarcane
i do kind of like that that looks pretty
cool
pretty cool if we use sugar chain we can
have secret passages
too though behind it
i did want to mess with water just to
see what it would look like
i love having water in my bases
um
it's probably gonna look really out of
place so
i just want to see what it would look
like if we had water flowing down there
right there
have to have it
maybe here too
just for a little bit of decoration it's
probably not going to work though
don't have many blocks
okay that'll work
i don't know
i don't know it's a thought
if i did that i would have like a secret
patch passage that would go down there
oh no i did it darn doc warned me about
that today
if you go on a downward stream you can't
swim out of it
oh yeah like not at all like i can't
swim up it actually pulls you down
man i wonder how you know what let's try
that with boats
i'm curious to see if that would push
boats down too or if they'll float still
let's see
get a boat uh where should we try this
he's still there he's not moving though
i think he's trapped
now maybe we'll just do it up here
okay i will contain it
sure that works
that's not gonna work
okay so if we put a boat on there do you
think it'll float up still
oh no it did not
you think it's still there what do you
think it actually went through
can't click on it down here
man that's going to be tough for that
really sucks that means you can't do
boat elevators anymore
well you can with source blocks i guess
but it limits you a bit more
huh all right anyway
yeah i do really like that wheat i think
we're going to do wheat
in each of these areas the water doesn't
really work though i don't think so i'll
probably get rid of that
and with the wheat we should try to make
it into an actual
or make it actually farmable so i'll put
a piston
on this end and like a smart piston and
a
piston on this end and it'll just move
the soil back and forth and make them
pop off that way
uh but something i want to try now
is do that three-quarter circle thing i
talked about last episode so make a path
that goes
around this way and connect to the
stairs on that side
so see if we got to figure out
where the center of that would be then
figure out how big this circle is
so the center is right
let's see two right there
yeah right there then it goes out one
two
well
one two three four five
six seven eight
nine ten eleven
probably make come out one more 12. so
we need a circle
with a radius of 12 plus 11
23. that goes around so
i'm gonna go look up the shape of that
and i'll
i'll dig it out and just see what it's
like
i'm in diameter by the way not radius
don't worry
i know the difference i did pass fourth
grade or whatever it was
where you learned that stuff but yeah
this is what it looks like with that
area
mined out so this is a 25 diameter
circle
um it's kind of cool
it might work trying to decide if i want
to keep it or do that
the only thing that i might not like if
i do
is i don't want to see all that open
space from down here i don't think
so uh one thing i did want to have is
like
a column here at least the five by five
column that goes
goes up probably to the ceiling or
whatever
whenever we decide where the ceiling is
um but maybe i could have a
a second wall kind of come out
like this
oh
um
oh wow i made that shot that was nice
it's probably gonna look really bad
yeah have like another another wall
there to
hide anything back here and then over
here we'll have
more rooms or something that we can go
to
um and
we'll probably bring the wall out on
this side up to
you know just make it a little thicker
i don't know it's hard to hard to
envision it until i actually do it
but that's what i'm thinking i tried put
some more wheat down
tried putting some more wheat down and
it i like that i think that's really
good
i was thinking maybe for under the
stairs i'll just have a
hide this underneath stuff a bit better
do
get that torch back maybe do a sandstone
wall like this
oops
oh wait a minute i can't make it go any
higher
because that is an upside down half slab
hmm
well maybe i'll change the stairs up to
make that work because i would like it
at too high
like from this side that would look good
if it was light it's pretty dark there
right now
maybe um what else
for for in here i have these ender
chests
so i have it this way with it being a
full square
and over on these sides i have
a stair like this i'm not sure which i
like more
and i also think i want to have an anvil
on one side so maybe
i don't know we'll pick a side uh we'll
do the right side
with the anvil oops
just see how that looks
yeah that's pretty good still gotta
organize this i haven't put the
the items in the frames yet or moved the
stuff
but i will be doing that i'll show you
the afk stream i never showed you that
um so it's been running a little while
here let's see how much
much we get for going through it's gonna
drop off some of the items first
and that and
okay i think that's everything
so with this i have a fence uh
connected like this so when items flow
through here they hit hit
that fence and fall straight down
because i was having trouble with them
landing
like over here and not going into the
portal
so that works out much better yeah let's
see how many items we get now
so almost a stack and a half of
gunpowder which is pretty cool
because you don't even have to think
about it and just every once in a while
come check this and you'll get tons of
tons of items which is awesome
so i just had this dot instead of having
it just straight like that i would bring
the wheat
and have it curve around like that so
that it uses up the rest of the land
here
i think that's better
the whole piston earth mover method
probably won't work with this even even
with it straight like this
because when the tilled land goes under
a block it's going to get untilled
and since it's mostly for show
that's not going to work out too well if
if one one block on the end isn't isn't
grown it's going to look bad
so maybe instead
we'll just use a whole ton of pistons
and
put one under each each soil block
man everything is such a mess around
here
all right yeah so we'll just do
do this all the way along
and we got to get the water in we'll
probably just put the water under the
wall here you'll never see it
yeah so a little a little off topic
um you know i keep hearing people talk
about honey badgers and i never knew
what
what that animal was i've never seen one
before so
event the other day i finally looked and
looked and
saw what it was because i always assumed
it was just like a weasel or something
similar to a weasel
and man i have found my new favorite
animal
those guys are so cool
uh there's this video on youtube of a
guy
he's like trying to capture it and he's
he's sort of
just seeing how the honey badger well i
don't think it's a honey badger it's
just a badger but badgers in general are
awesome
he's seeing how he'll react right
as he lunges at him and he kind of he's
circling around him and
the badgers is standing its ground
and at one point in the video he
actually runs at the badger
like a badger is only maybe 20 pounds or
so
and you get a full grown guy running at
a badger you would
think the animal would take off but nope
he he like starts running at him and
then the badgers
runs at him at full force and he just he
takes off
because those guys are vicious
and they have no fear
there's other videos i was looking at
too they're like taking on wolves and
taking on bears
just insane
how cool that animal was i think i think
my favorite animal before that was
probably a tree lemur just because they
they look so cool but yeah i think honey
badger is my new favorite
okay back on topic if you've never seen
a
a honey badger or a badger go check it
go check it out because they're a really
cool animal
um but yeah i'm going to put
uh what are they called
detect detector rails underneath
all the pistons and then those will
power them
when we send a minecart down so that
should be
pretty simple
again if you guys got ideas or
suggestions let me know
this is a weird glitch with the new
patch like
anytime you try to place a torch on a
on the ground and there's a wall next to
it it just
snaps to the wall
really annoying it'll probably get fixed
soon
uh huh okay
what else i think uh
let's go let's go to the end again and
we'll work on the eats road some more
there's there's something i wanted to do
with that
i really like going to the end now
because it's always a surprise
seeing how much gunpowder i mean yet
when i go in
let's let's check it out oh
20 yeah it's 20.
all right well you what i want to do is
make
make it connect to the road up there
right at the platform i want to i want
to be able to
have a boat go up to it
so see it's going that way
nothing too fancy at least not to start
off with all i really need to do
see so we gotta link up with that path
there that's one that's going that way
so i guess we'll have to put it here
right here
yeah uh really all we need to do
let's see how should we do this
maybe fix it up a bit before
put this here
just want to try it out now we just need
to
this we just put the water here even
see start like that and
we just have to alternate all the way up
like this
and then melt it all
and we should be able to just plop a
boat down and
ride it up to underneath there
yeah so we need to open up a three by
three area for the boat to get up
oops and the waters come up here so
we'll put
oh i yeah i put that in the right place
it's hard to see
so ice block there
then we'll put a sign here
and one over here
hold the water up and then break
those three
and that should work
yeah just missing one ice block there
now i'm going to set up a whole bunch of
torches near this
and we'll we'll try melt this all
that one melted on its own good
see
oops so just give me a moment this will
take a while to
all melt
alrighty it's all melted let's try this
out i'm a little worried some of the
water
like when you do this the water can get
this flowing thing and i think it does
actually flow
yeah it's pulling me to the center
as long as it doesn't pull me off the
edge we should be okay
because that is a fall down there
and if we start going that way i'm going
to bail
yeah it's okay it's not crashing not
going crazy
oh did i position it wrong
oh oopsies
that's all right i just placed the boat
in the wrong spot
i guess
very nice so now i have a way of going
right from the platform up to the eats
road
again i want to set up dispensers and
stuff full of boats and
just make everything nicer but all in
due time
cool well i think that's gonna about do
it for this episode let's go read the
comments
and we'll call it call it an episode
dude where'd the zombie come from i can
guess where the slimes came from
i have no idea where the zombie came
from
so i got a comment picked out for today
it's from chip nick
long time subscriber of mine he says
etho i actually really like it when you
have several different projects
going at one time it adds more variety
to the show
one thing i don't like however is when
you go a long time without working on
something
as in your man cave or if you go a long
time working on the same thing
i think if you tried scheduling your
episodes so you work on something new
each couple of episodes that'd be a good
alternative
thanks for the comments um yeah variety
variety is key it i would like to have a
good variety
uh it can be hard to do sometimes though
i don't know making schedules and stuff
is something that's never really
appealed to me so
generally i just do what i feel like
doing for that day
and i'll probably continue to do that
but i usually don't go more than three
episodes working on the same thing
like the man cave i i've been planning
on going back here i actually want to
make a chicken farm here
but haven't decided what i want to do
exactly
but yeah it's a delicate bounce trying
to add variety and actually
completing stuff and starting new stuff
and
but i try anyway
thanks for watching guys i'll see you
next time