hello guys how's it going what's going
on this enchanting room it doesn't do
much anymore with the one-point-three
stuff it's down you got 30 if one of
them is up you've got 30 they have two
of them are up you've got 30 and if
three of them are up you got 18 and only
18 so this is pretty much just a bunch
of bookshelves all around anyway we're
going to do a sword enchantment here get
these down in here we go hmm hmm
what I like looting but oh well
okay so this is where I'm going to be
putting one crafting table I think just
outside the storage room it's a block
swapper pressure plate over there before
you cover it all up so what it'll look
like all right cool
so the grass will die if I leave it
covered for too long but it'll regrow
even if it turns to soil pretty quickly
I'm sure I'm over here working on the
sheep farm and I keep paying all these
pleasant surprises with the 1.3 patch I
forgot some something cool with signs
they stack now I've totally forgot about
that so this is a
this is making building this a lot
easier and you get three now when you
make them all they stacked by sixteen
okay
that's still pretty good sweet and so
what I've been doing I need a better way
of getting in here and out of here I've
cut these things out over here there's
going to be a water source here and here
that the wool is going to fall in from
above and that's going to push it down
here we're going to put signs here and
here so the water doesn't flow down and
then right below in this tunnel I just
dug all along at this height there's
going to be ice with water streams in
that are going to push the ice or push
the wool this way and then join together
somehow from the other side so I got to
go all along here placing signs and then
placing the water and then placing the
ice and the water streams and all that
fun stuff all right very good we got
that all done now took a little while
but we got it done so we got water
streams below each of these drop zones
and they go this way and then there's
another stream with ice below it that
goes that way and we got these all the
way down and then these all end up right
over over here yeah they all come to
over here and same with other side they
all end up here now I got to figure out
how I'm going to join these two together
but first I want to make sure they work
I haven't tried them yet so let's just
do a quick run-through shearing the
Sheep
we'll try out the automatic water system
hopefully it still works I haven't
haven't used the Sheep firm very much
yet but I do plan to once it's all set
up okay good enough I've made a backup
just in case I kill some sheep here that
is never a good thing and always forget
which button is it's either that one or
that one it gets this one yeah excellent
so the Sheep I sheared should go down
and the ones I didn't it stay up mmm oh
dang it Jay seems to be some flaws a few
sheep did not go down or whatever let's
just check the water streams first
that's what I'm also concerned about for
right now I think it has to do like with
the randomness of where the wool jumps
when you share them I fit if it's too
far away or not too Brown oh yeah most
of my shirt on the side I was like
where's all the wool what's wrong there
we go
yeah so it looks like it's good so we'll
join these two together probably in this
corridor here I just mined out and then
the thing is in this game for the
longest time there was no good way of
making items go up like they can only go
down as far as I know there's still only
one way of making them go up and that's
with pistons I don't think there's any
other tricks to it and using pistons is
not very clean really so I may try to do
what what what height is is that what
accidents my height is assets we are at
our eyes or at 47 where the items are
and way up here 53 foot six blocks
higher we got this section here with
nothing in I'm thinking we should use
this as a collection area for the wool
but it would maybe be a bit weird if I
went down six blocks like if we had a
six block drop from here mmm
I'm going to mess around with it a
little bit yes I dug the hole and it
comes out to here this is level the ice
would be at so I could either make a
room down low or I could try make an
item elevator to take the items up and I
did a little bit of research and it
seems there are there is another method
people use for transporting items
basically well if you have an item in
the hole like that and a block gets put
into it it gets pushed up so if you have
an array of vertical Pistons firing one
after another all the way up the block
will keep getting pushed higher and
higher until it reaches the top so I may
do something like that it's only would
only be six blocks to get it level with
the ground here or no five blocks only
five blocks because there's ice block at
the bottom so I may do something like
that I'm not sure okay
let's let's take a little break from
this for a second there is a rumor I
heard in my last videos in the comments
somebody said you can brew both extended
and tier two Pope oceans potions now
and I just want to try that out and yes
I know you can I know neither work grows
in the overworld now that looks crazy
okay so what should we do here let's
grab some pre-made potions to speed this
up if we can okay these are extended
speed potions and I think I have some
loose glowstone yeah so can we make
these extended and tier two that is the
question and yes I think yeah
shift-click t-shirt you should be able
to click in yeah oh that's so nice
shift-clicking is the best and
shift-click armor - I forgot about that
so many good little features in the 1.3
patch just improve the game so much okay
is this gonna corrupt it or are we going
to get something new and awesome you are
the experts
I guess head follows even when you jump
that's awesome it's like he's nodding
mm-hmm is it done mm-hmm nope okay false
tip uh it seems because now we just have
to your - oh well that would have been
cool though if you could both extend it
and your to it you can you can get those
of you if you use editors external
editors but I guess it's not true
alright so I'm thinking about building a
little room here for storing wool and
stuff and for collecting it but before
we do that I wanted to play around with
arches we might do some arches at the
top here similar to what we have down
here and just see how it looks and if it
looks good we will keep it so yeah let's
just do this
and maybe go to full blocks here well
you know that is that's where I drop the
sheep down I was wondering what the deal
was okay
how weird does that look a little weird
is okay just really weird is not good
and down below I did that so maybe we'll
keep this look looks off doesn't it
what's wrong oh no no that's centered
okay I'll do I'll do the rest here and
we'll see what it looks like so let me
know what you guys think of this I like
the width and the height of these arches
really makes the place feel open and it
looks like they're holding up the
ceiling or will if I feel on that
ceiling which is also cool for the the K
feel this side will be different though
because of the sheep farm entrance it's
not the same and I don't really want to
change it either we just might have one
side that's different if we keep this
I'm wondering if it's too bulky like
these out
fill that in it might look too flat then
too square
I want to try something else to let me
know what you think of this this is the
other look I had in mind I think it's
pretty good
and I did the the leaves in the ceiling
so we might keep this again I'm worried
it's too bulky like it doesn't make
sense to have it thin at the bottom and
then really fat at the top but oh well
this is minecraft it doesn't have to be
perfect so something I want to do here
there's only one proper way of getting
out of the cave it's this elevator here
but I would also like to have some ender
pearl ways of getting out so I'm going
to do the water and lily pad thing like
I have at the at the mineshaft area so
maybe let's just go up and see where
this takes us outside and one one will
be for going up and one will be for
falling down type thing oh okay we're in
the water do I have any ladders I do not
darn okay well let's swim up and just
check it out
all right we can make it work okay I got
that installed this one here has the
lily pad and this one is the dropper so
we just get our ender pearl hold space
bar and we are out and if we want to go
in just fall through and it should be
mob proof I'm pretty sure one major
trouble I have with that elevator it's
it's really surprising but the mobs can
actually make their way down it like if
I'm by the slime area for example they
can see me all the way from the top and
make their way down the staircase and
get into the cave it's happened a few
times okay one more thing I'm going to
do today is probably going to be a short
episode I actually have a very busy week
planned and I can't treat cord until
Friday or Saturday again so this is
unfortunately all you're going to get
for a little while and an urge of course
every second day but I wanted to get
this episode up anyway what I want to do
we get our potion room thing here going
to try replace all this stone brick here
with ice so that the potions go through
a lot quicker and I'm hoping I can do
that I might have to go harvest some
more ice Oh
okay yeah as where it is only going to
be one thick so that's what I'll do and
we'll probably call it a wraps after
that yeah love it refill the ice tray it
actually it takes a long time for it to
freeze I had to wait a little while for
them to all freeze over but it's still
pretty cool let's try this out now so
spider eyes used to take like ten
seconds to get here let's see how long
it takes now they're one of the farthest
away and I wasn't able to replace all
the blocks just a few because we had
like glowstone around and some stuff
wasn't really easy to change and I had
issues with water spilling into my
redstone wiring and I had to fix stuff
and but I changed like 50 blocks or so
and that took maybe 2 or 3 seconds less
than it used to so it's not a huge
improvement but whatever good enough and
I'm going to get going here guys sorry
for the short episode today but it was
either either a short one or no episodes
for like four four days or so um so I
hope you enjoyed it thank you for
watching and I will see you should be
back to recording Friday or Saturday
again plus edge in between
you