hey everyone this is etho I'm just in my
mines here doing some digging I wanted
to show you something there's a lot of
block breaking tricks in this game like
like ways to break blocks quicker like
some people say if you click a balk
instead of just like holding left-click
down if you just tap it you can break it
quicker doing that that's kind of cool
it's you know it's not as enjoyable
mining that way of course on beat double
O's video I saw he was doing this thing
was with is a efficiency for pick where
he was just running along the ceiling so
I want to point that out to you guys if
you haven't seen it before it's kind of
cool if you have just the right angle
and the right distance see if we can get
it I think it's like this you can just
walk along and it breaks it instantly
otherwise like if you have more of an
angle it's like this it's a lot slower
it's not watching speed that's for sure
I thought that was kind of cool good
trick to know if you if you didn't
already you can also do it on the sides
if you get the right angle too it's a
little more challenging I haven't
mastered it it let's let's see if we can
do it yeah you see how it's breaking it
quick I don't know if I can do it on the
bottom I've just been messing around if
they trying to perfect it but that would
save a lot of time mmm turkey it right
this picks stir and we're out there we
go so if you get just the right angle it
seems to work in the right distance
no it's really easy to do on the ceiling
though I'm finding if the block D is a
one block above your head OOP and that's
another common trick a lot of people
know like if you were to mine rabble if
you start at the top work your way down
it's slower than if say you let's let's
just make a statue you'd start at the
bottom one first and then keep holding
left-click didn't do it maybe I haven't
mastered this one either
so you probably need the right angle on
it too ouch oh I did it just for a
second there let's try it I think you
need a sharp angle like this maybe there
we go
see how it's much quicker when you do it
like that that's another trick in case
you didn't know I also got just going to
show off a new pic I got finally got
efficiency five I went to the where are
you at oh there's a tube up there oh
he's up there probably whoops
started on that what this is my yeah
efficiency five let's see how quick is
never had one of these before
not bad not bad at all I want to show
you how I'm doing my mining so I bring a
water bucket with me like I said before
I mined at ten point six but you're to
two levels below the lava level so
occasionally you'll run into pools like
this usually I'll just flood them like
that
then I'll mine out the top block first
with the efficiency pick just to speed
it up it gets faster with efficiency and
then you'll usually have lava underneath
this is a bad example there we go then
I'll just put water next to the block go
down be very careful of course and
that's how I do it so I just go over
here same thing and that way you get up
sitting into because maybe some projects
need it it's not as big of a hassle
using it anymore so I don't mind having
a stockpile think I got three stacks of
it now just from doing this um what else
there was something else I was going to
show maybe we'll head back I want to
show off my awesome axis thing is
incredible oh yeah I was going to talk
about the efficiency 5 apparently
getting a high level when you do the
enchantment is really really important
if you're going for efficiency 5 and a
diamond tool and thanked at level 47 I
can't remember quite right but it's like
eight percent chance then if you go to
48 I think it's 11 percent then 49 it
jumps up the fifth
Dean and then if you do a level 50
enchantment it goes all the way up to 20
so it increases really quick you really
want to have a high level if you're
aiming for efficiency 5 but if you're
using a gold tool getting efficiency 5
is significantly easier I think that
level 50 there's a 49 or 50 percent
chance of getting efficiency 5 so big
difference um yeah let's head back and
in the description if I remember I'll
link you to the website I use for all
the efficiency statistics ok ok here we
go
we're going to try it out show it off
I'm really happy with this axe because
it's going to last forever and it's
extremely fast ah
oh yeah and people are wondering if I
actually use a tree farm or if it's just
for looks Oh trust me I've been cutting
you guys down some more in here so it's
not just for looks I do use it now the
problem with this axe oh it's almost
it's almost too good because I if I just
raise these pumpkins it takes them out
like instantly and it I don't know I
have to be careful with it because this
is so crazy
I leave this it's like so fast because a
pumpkin harvest quit just with an axe I
think so might actually changes with
glowstone just for that reason some
people said they like the pumpkins more
umm I don't I like low stone more that's
just me but the pumpkins are a lot
cheaper and you know me I'm a cheapskate
but I don't mind using glowstone I got
lots of little stone now yeah we should
try see if that trick works with regular
tools - I bet you it does on my potion
ran out where should we do it need some
space
to me trees in the way oh we should try
to do that trick with the Pope with a
swiftness potion - okay here's a good
place let's set up some of these we're
just trying to master the basics of
Minecraft here that's what we're doing
no that was pretty slow felt like the
right angle there Oh does work
Aereo incredible clean that out a little
bit we'll set up another one this is
actually a really bad spot for it though
oh we got a nice wall here let's do it
here so set up a long line and then
we'll do the swiftness potion on it
because if you can go at super speed and
have an instant that would be incredible
just try that the mines actually okay I
think it's about was working what
happened I must move my mouse a little
bit Oh wrong angle I will master this I
promise okay let's try again
Oh terrible we had it going for like
just a split second there there we go
there we go when I got to the cobweb it
seems to kill it for some reason
you notice that both times it was at the
cobweb ah there you go no did it again
same spot strange I don't know I'll play
with it more
oh man we're leaving the cave again I'm
gonna be a Sun Tan at this rate all this
sunshine where you've been getting
lately right
okay the mission for today is to find a
stronghold
it's another exploring episode I'd like
to do that sometimes I hope you don't
hate it the reason I want to find a
stronghold today is because I got an
awesome tip last episode on how to find
it by a guy called Hound of Darkness in
the comments he said you can use
trigonometry to find strongholds and
that makes perfect sense so normally the
way people normally do it is they throw
an ender eye it travels in the direction
of a stronghold you follow that
direction and then like every you know a
few hundred blocks you'll throw another
ender IED and see if you should still
keep going in that direction but it
should be possible to find it I drink
one of these it should be possible to
find the stronghold throwing only two
under eyes and that's the challenge for
today I want to see if I can actually do
it so I'm going to pick a spot this is
our first point we're going to use try
to use trigonometry to do this okay
let's see which way it goes where it
lands throw it up right there don't land
on the cactus okay so roughly this angle
here I'm going to mark my coordinates I
don't know if I can do this this is a
challenge for me a lot of people think
I'm smart I really am NOT in fact when I
finished high school I within a year
I've completely had no idea how to do
trigonometry the only reason I know how
to do it today and even today I don't
know how to do it very well is because
of programming video game programming
it's the only reason I know it still but
I might not figure this out we'll see so
now I'm going to mark this point
- - I'm not sure if I need this point
actually I might okay so I think I might
need it to figure out the angle now I'm
going to run you set to run at least 100
blocks away like sideways of the
direction the ender eye goes so maybe
over here and doing that we should be
able to figure out using the angle and
the points two points where we throw it
we should be able to find the Third
Point which is where the two lines will
intersect and that's where the
stronghold should be if I understood
that properly
I'll there's a village over there tada
hey I found a village
oh yeah exciting we'll put the ender eye
thing on hold just for a second Wow my
first legitimate village right here
please be please be terrible freak
people where are you
awesome we caught one already what's she
doing with that pig - in the lemon house
no no a white robe dude hey you what are
you doing out in the fields and get lost
there's something I want to do with
these guys I'm not going to tell you
what it is just yet quick just something
for fun but if I don't seal them off
they might wander away and I'll never
see him again what are you doing in here
it's got one cut grass in his house
grass drawn grass in his house that's
weird
and one more over here nice thing about
these guys is they don't walk around
lunch no no no come on cheer ah
low-class trash get in the hole here hmm
green eyes they all have green eyes get
in that hole no no no no of course when
he lands in the hole he decides to run
right away
oh you're worse than the cows seriously
tada um man we'll just put a torch on it
okay I'm not cruel this is this is
perfectly fine behavior on my part
we will throw another end right now now
that I totally lost my directions I
probably can't even get home now and
X is negative 223 and Zed is 604 and I
say that because I am Canadian and Z is
not in our dictionary QC didn't know
that oh you
okay this looks like a but about the
right angle like I said I don't even
know if I need this extra point here but
just in case they do I'm going to take
it okay oops
so now I'm going to pause the game and
see if I can figure out where this
stronghold is from that and I'm sure
it's possible but I might be too dumb to
figure it out so we'll see what we can
do
I'm king of the world
yeah woo ah I figured it out I I hope I
did I guess you do you do need those
second points they're important I should
have been more careful or more accurate
figuring them out but hopefully we'll
get it right it seems the lines
intersect at X 236 what's that noise
coming from there is a lot of creepers
out here they intersect at X 236
according to my calculations and why
there another one why can it be out why
a 190 so 236 and 190 is where we need to
go and I'm just going to throw another
ender eye just to see that's the general
direction it's taking us so let's figure
out where the numbers get bigger
no we need Zed to get smaller so that
way and we need Y to get our X to get
bigger
I think I said why before I meant said
because this team has goofy coordinate
system so we need should be roughly this
direction dang it
wait how did I get that wrong unless
we're picking up a different lunch and
let's do it I'm going to let that point
anyway and we'll see what happens
there's the glowing tree over there
welcome to the mountains they are pretty
amazing and we have a friend over here
hey buddy
pretty easy iron armor diamond armor
just invulnerable awesome check that out
Wow yeah I'm pretty happy with the seed
crazy okay I gotta go further this way
I'm guessing I got one of the signs
incorrect so probably have to do it the
normal way anyway but I just want to I
want to get there and throw one and see
what happens all right so this should be
the spot this is what I figured I've got
the bad feeling though that I was wrong
I mess something up I'm sure I don't
know what I also made a huge mistake I
went to drink a potion and instead of
landing on the potion I hit the ender
eye hotkey and when I held down right
click I shot 3 off
and they just disappeared somewhere so I
lost three under-eyes I know it sucks so
that I'm in trouble I got one shot at
this
should be five blocks in front of me
yeah I knew it so yeah I mess something
up I'm going to I'm going to find one
the normal way and just see where the
coordinates are I think that's what I'll
do so I'm curious to see if I at least
got the numbers right even if I may be
mixed up the signs or something the
positive or negative it's taking me back
oops day because I don't think you can
find a stronghold this close to zero
zero I think it has to be always away I
should check the wiki this is walking by
and Skelton came out this cave so I
checked it out how perfect of a starter
home is this it's got a nice door
perfectly cut out near the surface
that's a good hidey hole right there
little baby
fighter nest yes I'm kind of hunting
Enderman now get some more eyes I got my
looting sword no strength potions though
dang it
Oh at four that's awesome and I brought
blaze powder with me so I like to make
more I stumbled across this village
again so let's let's throw on I here go
their direction it hold this to
originally so this way when it's a lucky
date
so for you smart people out there if you
can tell me what I did wrong
don't need a million people telling me
what I did on this one or two I would
appreciate it and let me know in the
comments going to throw another one here
that still wants me to go give it to me
give it to me yes let's do it again
quite a bit farther was this direction
before oh let's just go back now okay
and check out this [ __ ] tree
incredible
alright I'll keep searching we're
getting really close to it now go down
to sit we got it let's check it out and
hope for the best
so even in creative mode I've never seen
a stronghold so I'm really excited to
find one come on oh what's that noise
what is that noise that's a new
silverfish noise we found it
awesome oh dang it
why why here it is oh dang we found it
guys got the end portal weirdos
silverfish go I don't know if you can
disable the spawners with light probably
tada
chief mantilla their achievement for
that I should check there might be one
for going through the portal what are
you guys broken still interesting chase
cool new block mossy mossy stone bricks
nice to have daddy's awesome day how do
we check achievements ah we have to this
tape yeah achievements zero zoom out no
potion local brewery into fire the end
okay so there is there's one for it I
think that and then that's probably for
completing the game interesting but you
got to do the precursor ones first and
since I keep switching my a version
number I'm never going to get that done
because it gets reset every time so why
are you guys still spawning unbelievable
we found it and kind of broken I don't
know
it looks broken there's iron bars
everywhere yeah doesn't doesn't have
much flow to it that's for sure
so I generated this world in Oh
shovel in 1.9 I don't know if that
affects anything spiral staircase and
I want to find a chest that's what I
want that one goes down and if I you
know what
I guess there's cold air we can you get
cold still and bring any supplies with
me really I wasn't expecting to find
this I just stopped to get some more
torches here so we're ready to go for a
little bit longer yeah do it
oopsies
no don't tell me the stronghold ends
what the I missed something there's no
way it's that small where didn't we go
okay just we didn't really take care of
these guys bugger okay I think that's it
so very strange shape down here it's
nothing so you go back this way we came
up there oh yeah there's a staircase
here let's go down there hope for the
best
and by the way about that add approval
problem I'm having uploading my LP
episode with a different name didn't
help still had the problem took two days
to get ads on the last LP episode which
was today finally they came on I'm going
to try upload this one as etho craft
like a lot of you suggested probably
won't be the official name I'm just
experimenting to see if I can get it
working because once again my last
letter
their episode had no problems at all
it's just the lp episodes I have no idea
why okay what how do you hit me
this place is getting bigger and if
ether craft doesn't work I'm just going
to the episode after that I'm just going
to call legendary and see what happens
even though it's an LP episode I'm just
very curious to see what the problem is
let's see if that would fix it and I'm
never going to need iron doors or
anything after this place okay we were
at a library or something we should head
back to that where was that I saw a
ladder going up somewhere here it is huh
what was that saw something green there
it is very strange if I ever need more
bookshelves this is where I'm coming
that's a weird place for a chest let's
check it out very cool it's kind of sad
that there's only three strongholds per
world I wish it was infinite so once you
explore all three then it's like I don't
know it's just out of the game then
where does that chest was a pie very
well-hidden
there it is Lane Lane yeah I had TNT I
blow that up right now
okay I think I'm just about to end this
episode I'm sure you guys have seen
stronghold exploring before I don't
think there's what I don't think there's
a whole lot to see once you have found
that the end eat I think that's a mean
out date thing I can one-hit kill them
let's see find the end date I think
that's the most exciting part and I
found that right away and there's a lot
of these games I like to get them how do
you get in there oh this is kind of
getting kind of cool here he's got a
fountain hello we're missing some water
on this side sounds like they're above
here Ariel Oh
somehow you hurt me there and I like the
redstone but it's kind of a lean chest
yeah okay I think I'm going to end it
here guys thanks for watching and I'll
see you again next time