hello everybody this is ESO and we are
playing some more minecraft today trying
to get the skeleton to shoot the slime
it's you're impossible though I tell you
there we go here we go nope
the vines vines are in the way you
wouldn't think it would be that hard but
I don't know I've been at it for like
three minutes here there we go yay I can
be happy now I've been working on this
more I'm trying to get it done just so I
can finish something but like all my
projects that really is no end to it so
I got these item frames on the
dispensers we got them pretty much full
apples on that one I got one for the
furnace minecarts here we should kill
that guy because that's not going to
stop that noise is not going to stop I
still need to do something on the
outside here though it's not going to be
flat like this should be some kind of
building oh man all day long with this
they never stop I really got to like
this place up there I go now we can
record but yeah I got stairs going up
here stairs on the top I made this come
out a little further so we don't hit our
head on this top parts and I never did
this before I tried a diamond pattern on
the sides on the diagonal sides here I
think that worked out pretty good
there's I'm going to do it like this
there's a center Center block - it's
just the way I have it with this spacing
worked out pretty good so I'm going to
try
shovel stood we can't use it don't try
this and see what it looks like I want
to have these and then lamps for lights
in the middle and we'll need some levers
okay get that on how's that look that's
pretty cool
behind these we should also have them
because you can see through just ever so
slightly I can't get to the position I
want huh and some there yeah so I'll do
that all along that'll be good over here
we have the wiring so I have to do
something about this I'll probably have
to make this solid over here still
haven't done out dug out this way I
don't know where to make it go this is
all loaded though we got weakness in
there we got minecarts it's all sets and
I started working on this roof just a
few moments ago what I think I'm going
to do my place both sides there we're
going to have a three by three thing and
then I think we should do it like this
have have this indented of bits well
that's it that's the dress up there
we'll stick a lever there try this out
like that have those going all the way
along here see what it looks like from
below that's pretty cool the other
option is I could have like stairs and
half slabs but I think it looks better
with the sharper
and then we could try it though we
should try it if we did it
where are we over here so it's step full
blocks we could do this and then have
these running across maybe we'll just
remove this one so we can see properly
that and then the shovel it's too good I
tell you okay that there and cover it up
let's see there you go so that might be
cool to know I think I like I liked it
the first way first the first time most
so we'll do it that way this thing is
ready to go I think we can actually get
some villagers move finally so let's get
it going turn it on and I just gotta
stand here and sort out the villager
one's got a eyeball it that's a zombie
zombie zombie it might take a while so
I'm gonna skip this alright there we go
guys we got to finally I was really on
unlucky with this because I went through
about 70 of these guys before I finally
got to and it's supposed to be a one in
ten chance I think so not the best odds
there for me now let's give this a try
we haven't tested it yet
give them their medicine so if we wired
this properly these ones that don't have
a guy in won't shoot only only these two
will actually we need our apples - lets
get our apples first it looks weird with
the item frame it looks like the Apple
comes off off the frame somehow and
another and replaces it
medicine yeah they got hit those ones
did not shoot they're still full that's
good so we give them their Apple oh I
didn't know they got new sound effect
for that that sounds crazy my sounds way
down though because of these guys so it
takes them between three and five
minutes to convert and speed up with
iron bars or beds slightly possibly ah
but three to five minutes random time
and I'll get back to you when they're
done I'm going to kill these guys while
I wait though any moments now I can feel
it one of the guys already converted
yeah Mon he's trying to get them through
the wall there we go
sweet oh they're both farmers though
that sucks
ah still got a few of these guys left to
kill so I'm going to do that I'll get
back to you guys
because they are really loud and I can't
talk over them ah much better much much
better I can hear again
I can hear silence I love it so this is
the moment of truth this is the
transportation stage I'm most worried
about this one not working actually
before we do it or not necessarily not
working but that we might have some
unexpected problems and this is one of
them we should close this off so they
can't escape if we have a problem
yeah that's why I'd like up there I want
a building with some kind of piston door
on I would I would be good but not today
not today
so we hit the transports which they
should do in minecarts and these ones
should not fire let's check it out and
hopefully they move forward No
the power went off really quick on the
power rails so they got stuck
interesting I might be able to push him
myself I'll have to fix that I guess or
find a way to fix that do it was that
way I'll help you out boy wheats there
you go this is the other problem getting
them through the portals I I wanted to
set up an automatic way of doing that
and I still might but for now just
breaking up the minecarts myself you
went through so did the minecarts No
yeah my cart went through okay you go
next and hopefully they won't come back
through you went through okay someone
was wondering how I made the portal one
wide if there's an extra hidden spot
over there that's covered there's no
magic trick to it I'm sorry now they're
going through aren't they oh well we got
one guy join your friend no I don't want
your treats do we get them we got them
we got them both awesome this part is
still pretty rough I didn't set this up
all that fancy but it should work I hope
push them up there I just will have to
do it one at a time shoulda brought a
furnace mine Kurt here we go to your new
home that I once robbed you guys of a
long long time ago you're allowed to
move back well not not those guys just
your relatives still can't come back you
you guys will get the home all to
yourself so the I has having trouble
with the pigs now going through the
portal little worried these guys are
gonna that same problem he went through
awesome so we're done and the minecart
go through yet one of them went through
I have no idea what happened to be
double stuff in that prank I he was
either afk for too long or some weird
interdimensional stuff made his items
transport to the roof of the nether
possibly or it just got deleted somehow
I don't know wow they found the home
real fast you that's awesome but yeah
you got I guess you gotta be really
careful with portals and items I was not
expecting that works fine here at least
we got our mine carts we got our guys
here they're settled I think the village
is up and running again
and everything's lit up enough I think I
got all the doors on yeah so this will
be our little project we'll keep an eye
on it and to see what goes from here but
I think that's all we'll spend on it for
this episode let's go do something else
actually I'll show you this one more
time real quick since I worked on it
some more I got these in I think that's
pretty cool I like that then I worked on
the ceiling bits and I got this going on
so I'm still thinking about if I want to
keep that yeah it's got that factory
feel to it like overhead fluorescent
lights or something which is actually
pretty suitable for this building but
one thing I am noticing is it's not
symmetrical that's that's the center
there
you got three blocks to the right and
four blocks to the left so my adjust
this I don't know we'll see
okay so we're over here guys and there's
this idea I wanted to try out today
remember how I said I wanted a chicken
farm around here like a proper a proper
chicken farm but I didn't really know
what to do for it's why I got an idea
for it now so let's check that out I
actually got this idea watching vintage
beef the other day he had a bunch of
chickens in a fenced off area and when
one of the chickens laid an egg it like
flew a mile out of it onto the ground
outside of the fence it's like oh you
know that would make a good chicken farm
an egg farm mainly is what I want to
make so with the recent patch let's just
rise up let's get a piston down just see
if this works
first of all get get that that that and
that
so in a recent patch they made it to
where items will just go upward if
they're inside a block so if we have
that in there and we extend this I think
it'll go well actually we got to make
that solid one second
it's got to be solid blocks all the way
up okay so now if we extend that I think
it'll either go up it might shoot out
through the piston area here I'm not
sure that's what we've got to figure out
first of all okay well it went up I'm
pretty sure it went up anyway let's just
try this one more time with eggs like
it's going to make a difference I just
want to see it again make sure all is
good ooh let's throw them in front of
the piston there we go yeah and Dada
they really fly out though I thought
they would just sit on top but they like
fly they like get to the top and then
they go whoa okay so that's that's the
basic idea I'm going to get like
chickens inside
that area and then squish them and they
won't suffocate in glass when they lay
an egg it should just automatically go
straight up and the nice thing about
that usually with chicken firms you got
to keep them in water and when they lay
an egg the water pushes it to wherever
you want it to go and then they sort of
just jump around in the water and splash
around and that's okay but it does cause
extra leg because there's sound files
that have to play and unload and and
that when they're in the water
there's particle effects from the
splashing water and the chicken
splashing and to make a less laggy farm
or egg farm this will work pretty good I
think
okay we know what's and how we're doing
its but now we got to figure out where
where are we going to put this chicken
farm so this area is pretty much full
get the sheeps over there sheeps sheep
over there this is one possibility in
this little spot here we don't need what
we don't need much space might have
stuff below that interferes though still
haven't figured a definite use for this
room I think it's too big though
everything else is pretty much hello it
else is pretty much full around here I
guess I'm sure we could find a spot
though there is this area here that
might work right now my chickens are in
there splashing around um
see if we were to let's just try over
there I think I want the chickens over
16 blocks away from me - if possible and
if we do that I don't think we'll get
the sound from them for just like
walking by here I'm not going to hit the
cow face yeah that's that's the cow face
the wall right there so that's not going
to work too bad
that would've been really good you know
what I go no I don't have my lamps darn
I thought I had my lamps maybe I put
them in the ender chest yes finally
we're gonna fix this guy's I keep saying
every time I go by it I'm gonna do it
yeah and there we go no more torch there
wonderful ah what a relief I've actually
thought about replacing a lot of this
clothes stone with lamps because I I
like the lamp look a lot more and maybe
getting rid of these trapdoors I'm just
having lamps in those corners I don't
know
it'd be worth doing um there's this spot
here - I've always wanted to do
something with I was thinking about
putting a snow golem here mmm probably
too cluttered though whoo this is stuff
I thought I would have found a spot by
now piston elevators on the way there
hmm
and it's going to be a place we can
easily access I don't think there is any
free spots left anymore well I guess
there's this right
that's the drop-down I use for the cows
I don't think I'll ever need that again
though so we could maybe just seal that
up and use this
you know what this worked out pretty
good I think his idea I wanted to fill
in a small empty space around here that
I wasn't able to do anything with and I
think I got it I looked down and where I
dug down and there's actually nothing
below I thought I would hit the portal
room so that's good we got to go down to
why 25 I think is where I want it so
pretty far down and just see what
happens we don't need much space because
all all it's doing is transporting the
eggs up we found gold and we'll probably
build some other room down here at the
bottom where we can load in chickens and
we can maybe fry them or do anything
else we want but just the egg delivery
area needs to be up there and we'll
probably have some storage chests if we
dig this way what we hit this is two
towards our base okay that's the portal
room that's what I thought it's going to
hit but it comes in word enough that it
doesn't excellent and this is just caved
down here I got nothing built below
below that so we're we're in the clear
here cool and get back up no oops
when at first you don't succeed try try
again
right there we go okay how should we
design this what should we use for the
backing maybe I think the main thing
I've been using is this stone brick so
if we want to keep this look going on I
just have to stone brick up here too if
we don't like it we can always switch it
so get some of this and fill it in now
there's probably going to be some
believers - maybe two levers one of them
we will want it to turn off the egg
delivery so if we if we do or if we have
that power that lever
it'll be like let's see do we want it
there or do we want the eggs to come up
here or here
maybe maybe inside this little yeah that
looks good we'll have it in there so
we'll just make just go out one more and
we could probably put some lights back
there put them away again I keep doing
that I'm scared I'm gonna lose these
things because they take redstone even
though I have 50 repeaters on me I'm not
afraid of losing those for some reason
okay
he's powered actually we got a power arm
from behind for running a lever free up
some space
I don't oh I had a bunch I don't know I
don't think I have to use blast for
forgetting the eggs up I think in these
other things too any solid block okay
and goods legs will come up here
that'll give us lights we want chess
also for storage mmm
oops could maybe put a chest there and
one there we got to get the levers
though levers don't forget about the
levers so probably have a lever here for
turning the delivery on or off should we
have one there too what would that do
what else could we make that do if we
set up if we set up a killing thing for
them we could maybe move the chickens up
here with minecarts somewhere over here
and have an automatic cooker thing for
them or something I don't know we
probably need one lever yeah so this
will change with wood I guess like
planks and I've I've been using jungle
wood now I don't really use the regular
planks for making sticks and stuff one
sec okay I got some ideas here ah gonna
make some of these first I think they're
just having a sign that says fresh eggs
or something up here whoops
whoopsies
okay fresh eggs or something like that
but I forgot we have item frames let's
use item frames why not
yeah yeah that's pretty cool another
option if we have the lever on that side
we might want to just put it over there
bounce out the look then the other thing
I'm not sure what to make this block
like if it can be solid I might just
make it glass after all the chess is the
other thing we got to think about we
could have them like that these fences
we could either pull back to there
keep it open or another option I guess
this will depend on how the eggs fly
when they when they reach the top here -
like if they're flying out over here or
something crazy we might need to contain
them with a fence so the other options
we could have a fence gate there and
when we want to get eggs just open it up
and close it or something like that I
don't know I think for now let's just
keep it open though feels a bit better
we could have the chests there or I also
thought maybe what we should do oops
holy C it's going to be tough to do I
brought some of these yeah we got to do
it from underneath don't we remove this
block and instead use a stair going that
way I think would be best and same for
this side
oops okay and then what we could do is
have a double chest there extra storage
if we want to do it that way use the
chest on the ground and then just have
this let's see what this looks like
that's that's another possibility better
for function you get more storage not as
good for looks so I don't think if you
have a chest here I think they change to
the hitbox can you actually click you
can click through them oh wow I didn't
know that
ci is able to click the double chest
below yeah because I think they made
these smaller let's just check that
right now now we're at Y 52 if you go on
top it's eight point eight seven five
tall
instead of a full block now hmm we could
have super storage and it would look
pretty much the same then I'll think
about it anyway I think I've used up the
time for today so let's go read a
comment or two and we'll call it an end
well I got two short comments picked out
for today and I guess we'll look at our
new egg delivery system while we read
them actually that brings up an idea -
what like a lot of people still want me
to build that library for the books
right now I'm keeping them just in here
with the library if I do get around to
building it what should I have going on
in the background when I'm replying to
the comments like I thought I'd be able
to go and look at the sheep while I do
that or while I read these but they make
noise and that gets boring quick another
idea that was posted was that I should
set up like a nice fireplace area with
jukebox music going in I know can you
think of enter anything entertaining
that could be going on in the background
while I read comments because there's
usually a minute or two where nothing's
happening in my videos anyway onto the
comments eath though what is this story
behind your skin me and many others are
probably wondering thanks so my skin is
Kakashi from the Naruto
it's a Japanese anime that I started
watching when I was
is in my early teens I think and the
reason I started watching it I heard a
lot of people talking about it and I
always wondered what is anime what's the
deal with that and I saw it posted on a
website like all the episodes and I was
sick and I was like you know I want
something to watch I guess I'll check
this out and this is actually more the
story how I got into watching Naruto
anyway I watched the first season and
while I was watching is like man do
people actually watch this garbage but
then by the second season that's when
the story really develops and it's
actually become one of my favorite shows
and it's still still running and they're
all really good now pretty much all
really good except the filler episodes
anyway when I first got into playing
Minecraft I actually had a Muriel skin
Mario Mario skin for about two weeks
while I had the Steve skin then Mario
when I started playing on servers for
like two weeks or so then I looked for a
new skin and this guy was absolutely
most detailed skin on the website that
had like thousands that I could find at
that time nowadays there's probably a
lot of really detailed and good skins in
fact there's some improved versions of
Kakashi even but I'm going to keep this
guy so I I mostly picked it because it
was a character I recognized and it was
very detailed and I thought it looked
really good so that's where that came
from
second question hey II thought you liked
cheese I think everybody loves cheese
like cheese is one of those foods like
bacon that everybody in the world just
seems to like even people that can't eat
cheese because they're allergic allergic
I think they like cheese too they just
can't eat it and it pains some greatly
even if they eat it too it pains them
really V I love cheese provolone
mozzarella not a huge fan of cheddar
to be honest but you know mixed with
other cheese's or like I can't just eat
straight to yellow
it's it's way too strong anyway I love
cheese and I hope you guys enjoyed this
episode I'll see you next time