[Music]
well hello everyone and
welcome back once again to another
episode with
with me etho um
so we are back at the stronghold here i
just wanted to give you
a follow-up of the mob system because we
worked on this last time
show you what's going on it's kind of uh
good news bad news
sort of uh situation
you can see it's it's kind of working
it's working pretty good we got creepers
skeletons zombies there's a creeper in
the skeletons
um the mobs are still trying to
pathfind out of there like
they're looking this way i i changed it
up so they fall four blocks now
thinking that would fix it and it didn't
um this is not something i can replicate
either in a creative world if i rebuild
this
in a creative world i don't have this
problem so it's something to do with my
cave here they're seeing something they
want to go to
and i don't know what so it's
really tough to uh to stop it because i
have no idea what's going on
without looking at how the pathfinding
code works i guess
and even then probably pretty tough to
figure it out
but the good news i have made a few
adjustments to it and
it has helped it quite a bit i have
you see where that sloped rail is i have
a glass block
right above that now which means
when the minecart goes through up there
it cannot come back anymore
so even though they're trying to fight
and go this way
they can't and also i put up
another piston up there which makes sure
they can't fall off that hopper until
until it's time to which is good i've
also lengthened the timing on
uh how long that block is out for so it
gives the creepers and
and the zombies a little bit more time
to figure out which way to go
and that seems to help quite a bit
although skeletons
also get more time to figure out where
they shouldn't go
so sometimes they go to the creepers or
the zombies but
it's working a lot better it's working a
lot better
so i am happy with that very good
um yeah
but i've been here for for a few hours
adjusting things and trying to
figure out the problems uh i am ready
to go do something else so we're not
gonna work on this uh
at this moment anyway we're gonna go to
do something else because
i need a break from this
so i decided let's hop over to our
village here today because
i got some plans for it uh as you know
i'm
in the new snapshot and there has been a
lot of changes
with villagers and trading and all that
there's new villager types
new trades you can get and i want them
i want to get them in my world here um
i looked into it a little bit there is
there's one villager type called the
cleric
which uh you can sell him zombie flesh
for emeralds and then i think the last
trade he gets
always i could be wrong i haven't really
done it enough to know for sure
but i think the cleric always gets
glowstone as their final trade
so you can you got good synergy there
you go you can sell them zombie flesh
which you really don't want
and then you can buy glowstone from them
to renew the zombie flesh trade
and glowstone is an awesome thing to buy
so it's a nice uh
back and forth synergy going on there um
i also saw there's name tags you can get
from librarians now which
looks pretty cool oh man look at all
those guys
we're all the white guys where's the
librarians what's going on here
there's gonna be comments about that
because i said white guys okay so
um where are they all
i thought i had like four or five at
least
wait a minute where'd they go
no not there either
they've been uh they've been excluded
from the village it looks like
oh there's one okay we're good
just one that guy
uh oh i think we may have lost a few
yeah because there was at least three or
four unless they're hidden somewhere
[Music]
anyway so there's new trades available
and i want to
i want to take advantage of them in my
world here and check it out to have some
fun with it
but we we don't want to just kill these
guys off
is that a different guy oh yeah that is
a different guy awesome
because we won't be able to get these
trades back ever again either so they're
kind of special even though
a lot of them aren't very good
um so my plan is let's move them
we're gonna evacuate the village so that
we can get new villagers in here
sounds very close that zombie he's back
here isn't he
there he is
clear out the village we might leave
like two here or something
but we'll try to
make room for a whole bunch of new guys
and we're gonna move them
to my other village which is actually
kind of
empty feeling there's not enough guys
there
um and then we'll have a nice separation
of the two
let's see so i'm not sure where this
portal is going to take us
i don't want them going through until i
know for sure so we'll just check it out
but i i have the the portal open for the
other village right now
and if we get lucky this will link up to
it and then moving them
should be oh i didn't bring flint and
steel
oh please tell me i have some here
there's flint
ah yes very good got lucky there
um oh man
i'm all out of space here i'll get rid
of that i guess
these guys get annoying pretty quick
there's too many of them
village needs to be emptied
[Applause]
i can't even stand being in here because
they're so annoying
uh we'll turn it down i guess all right
so light it
let's go through please link up please
please link up come on
i went through to here darn okay
i'm gonna break this
can i break it if i break it uh
yeah it should be fine i'm just
wondering how to get back now
so i got another portal to the village
over
not too far from here
i think there's a shortcut to it through
this wall somewhere but i can't remember
where
so we'll have to go the long way um
this is just a one-time move so i don't
have to do anything too fancy here
see i think it's behind get over here go
up through here
we're just in all that fire
there it is that's the portal that we
want them to go to
all rights i really thought they would
have went to it because it's pretty
close
to oh no
dispenser it's pretty close to uh
the other village they're not far away
from each other
so this is where we're gonna try and
move them to
and this area is all fenced off i
haven't had any zombies in here
we do have a few villagers running
around
but not too many there's a lot of space
that could be filled
so i'm gonna head back there and we'll
try it again
oh man look at this guy go that's the
new uh the harvesting
i thought they he's not picking up the
weed i thought they picked it up unless
they changed that
you better not just leave that on the
ground guy because i could have picked
it up myself
oh man they're going to town here
huh
that's actually kind of a bad thing for
this village because i have a switch
oh oh man they did it all
oh no and they're not picking it up that
is
bad bad news because i have a switch on
all of these
where i can just harvest it myself and
pick it up anytime i want
so if they're just if they're just
chopping it down and not doing anything
with it that's uh
that's not so great for this village but
you could automate it
for sure but uh not with these ones
because they've already been automated a
different way
but you could get a hopper minecart
running below
all right are you gonna replant
he's thinking about it thinking about it
if i give you some seeds will you
replant for me
because you kind of wrecked my crops guy
yeah yeah you did
no no he's running away dang
guy come on yeah you harvest my crops
and then you don't
pick them up
wow
okay let's try this again i think i got
all the straight portals
shut down now hopefully oh come on
i hit my head let's try that again
this is a really tough jump right here
there we go that was so difficult
like a one in one thousand chance of
pulling it off
okay oh i think this is it yeah we got
it okay
awesome okay okay okay okay
um okay now
okay so we're gonna go back there and
we're going to
push the villagers through and they
should make their way to here
on their own i think
so this is kind of the tough part now
it's trying to get them through here
because they have a mind of their own
it's not like i can dangle uh
some emeralds in front of their face and
have them follow me or anything like
that
they they will not cooperate too well
although i find if you're standing next
to villager they usually don't run away
from you which is nice
you can kind of nudge them to where you
want them to go
all right that's our first one the
problem is there's so many
there's over 20 in this village oh
here's here's a guy that came a little
too close
oh so long farewell say goodbye to your
home your family your friends you'll
never see them again
well actually they're going to come with
you okay get this guy out of here
let's just do a few to start off with
and just make sure this
works and i'll do the rest on my own
don't fight it it's nicer over there
there's more space
there's sunlight you're gonna have a
good time
do this and there you go
all right that's probably good so let's
go through ourselves
oh the zom zombie came through from the
other side that we saw i think
[Music]
oh no he can't he can't because
if they go through again they'll go to
the village right
so after i think 40 seconds their
cooldown wears off and they can go
through the portal once again
i hope this
might take too long to show on camera so
oh wait no one of them
no he just looked like he disappeared
he's actually still there
oh i just pushed one through so i think
they're ready to go
ready to go there you go one more
come on guy i hate when they go against
the wall like that you can't push them
at all
get stuck in the corner come on
all right well forget about him some
other guys will come by and
they'll get him to move all right
to your new home it's going to take a
long time to get 20 guys here i think
oh no especially with the door
i think i didn't lock it open though or
was it lock it closed i can't remember
i think it was lock it closed i guess
oh wait no i think that does it
yeah that's how you do it ah
okay maybe not i think it locks it from
you know what i don't know if it works
even
huh i guess it's a one-way lock
yeah i think that's what it is one way
lock that's kind of useless
i could get rid of the pressure plates
for now
there we go okay let's go round them all
up
all right i got all the guys moved uh
through this portal here
i left three or four at the other
village so we can use them to start the
new generation
of new villagers
see are they kind of thought we would
have like hundreds
outside here did they make it in
or did they somehow glitch through
somewhere i don't want them to be
here let's lock this for now there
should be a lot of villagers in here and
i don't see very many
oh okay they got they found their way to
the houses already it's night time
here let's let's sleep so that they can
run around outside and we can get an
idea of how many there are
oh man i've never had a zombie in here
so i think we're safe
they should be fine this village is
actually safer than the other one so i
think they will
be okay oh he found his way to the
backyard
cool and they're all coming outside
we still got our pigs and chickens in
here in our well
wait did that say cleric cleric was it
cleric before i thought it was priest
huh huh and they are
wrecking my wheat awesome i think they
finished wrecking it all
yep did not replant
man all right so let's head over to the
other village and we will try to get
the new generation going
yes villager chief i got rid of all the
scrubs we are ready to start
the new generation of overachievers
show
i've been here a little while and they
haven't bred they don't auto breed
anymore you have to
it requires player interaction now which
i think is a good thing because
those villager breeding cells could get
out of hand pretty quickly on servers if
you're not
careful and even if you are they still
sometimes do
so i think it's good they changed it so
you have to interact with them
and i think you can do it either by
trading
or you they also added a thing where you
can give them bread
maybe not i read you could do it i
haven't tried it myself
take my take the bread what's wrong with
you
bread potatoes or carrots is what i saw
hmm
okay i might need to look into this a
little further i don't have any potatoes
or carrots here to try
either i'm gonna go get some
uh you know i've been in this world for
so long and it turns out i don't have
any potatoes
how do i not have any potatoes um
i'll have to i'll have to farm some
later i guess
but i do have carrots i got wheat i got
bread i don't
think this is working though i'm pretty
sure you just throw it at them and then
when they get enough they will be able
to breed
i think because they're the old
villagers it might not be working so i
think i may need to get some of the
the new ones going which means these
guys aren't going to do it we need
we need to go up to our our place here
if it's
oh i didn't get ender pearls i'm i'm
like all out of ender pearls too
uh where is it over here right
or is this guy in the way i can't
remember where it is oh my mouse battery
just died
darn it my mouse battery come on
come on ah this is terrible
all right if you look up though
you see this hole up there this is where
our our
zombie purifier thing is so i'm gonna go
up there and get some new villagers
going i guess
but first i'm gonna change my mouse
battery be right back
there we go that's much better i can
move again
uh there is oh
no wrong kind there was a villager here
that i left before and
i never freed him and apparently he's a
shepherd which
is really weird because i think he was
from before the patch
and he had he's called a shepherd he had
two trades unlocked two
which is not not something the old
villagers have when they're
first created so that's very weird uh i
bred two more we got a weaponsmith
and an armorer i was hoping for a cleric
but
i guess these guys will do and i think
the other
the other two guys came down on their
own i hope
where'd they go daytime night time
okay that that was a shepherd guy that
was there from
from probably a month ago or so whenever
i bred them last i left one up there
let's see if he will let's go get our
our wheat and stuff
get rid of those all right i brought
some wheat
carrots and bread
okay so these new guys i'm pretty sure
they'll pick
pick it up this just says villager so
this is one of the old guys
that's weird it doesn't even say like
blacksmith anymore it just says villager
weaponsmith that's the new guy that's a
new guy
you want wheat there we go that's what
you're supposed to do
you take bread too
and i think they can share bread between
each other too
yeah you see he just threw a bread at
that guy
all right uh
so it's probably going to take a while
still
i don't think i don't think they do it
right away it takes some time
just throw a bed yet right in his face
all right where's this old guy i want to
check him out so this guy just says
villager so
any that's just a villager probably
won't work
let's see if this one's good though
shepard no i think he's broken too i
wonder why he's called the shepherd
though that is really weird
because he is one of the old villagers
but for some reason he got the name
shepard with two trades unlocked
oh did you pick it up or was that me
here have some wheat
no okay he's broken so it's just those
two
all right well i guess we'll give them
some time
and hopefully it works i could trade
with them too i think that
would help
so apparently this iron golem
he was standing over here he was trapped
here he couldn't get down the stairs
so i had to clear out some of the roof
here for him to get down
uh he was making it so people couldn't
get in this door
and he also had this guy trapped here
forever
like any time i'd walk by i'd see that
guy up there
uh but even now that he's moved it's
been a few minutes and that guy still
still hasn't gone down it's like that's
his favorite spot or something
this guy's patrolling which is good uh
still no baby villager we'll give those
guys a little bit of time hopefully
hopefully we get one uh if nothing
happens in a
in a few minutes i think i'll try trade
with them and see if that does it
although i think it's like a one in five
chance of trading will make them ready
to breed so
probably have to trade a lot which is
kind of why i didn't want to get
like an armor or a weapons guy because
they
cost a lot to trade usually
um but while we wait i had an idea for
another
uh just a little quick build we could do
i think i'm going to put it over here
one of the trades you can do with with
the librarian villagers
is written books and i think that's a
good trade like a really good trade i
almost like it more than
the paper trade to be honest um
with the old villagers you could get one
emerald per
written book with the new ones i think
it's two for one emerald might be one
for one emerald if you're lucky i'm not
sure
uh so if you if you get these
book and quills
there's this thing now of course as you
probably know you can
copy books which is really really cool
and they stack up to 16 16 books per
stack
uh so that is
a good way of getting emeralds i think
because that's that's
really easy to copy books and it's only
three paper
per book you need one leather which is
not too tough to get
feathers you can get really easy uh
ink sacks if you have a squid farm
they're
they're easy to get but even if you have
a looting sword
you can get quite a bit of ink pretty
quickly just by
hunting them in the water so
we're gonna build a
book duplicating not duplicating a way
of copying books easily i guess
is the best way of putting it so i think
we'll just have like a dispenser
up here or a dropper let's do a dropper
that will shoot the book and quills at
us
and we will stand like here
and as they the book and quills drop on
us we can easily copy it as we're in the
inventory i just would need a
crafting table around here too
maybe we'll get a crafting table over
here
um and anytime we drop a written book
into this hopper we're going to make it
so that another
book and quilt gets dispensed on us and
kind of keep the cycling going until we
stop making coffees
sort of thing so i just let me do the
redstone for it
and i'll show it to you afterwards and
we'll try it out
ah yeah we got a little guy
hey little fella you going outside to
play
going outside to play some street hockey
oh don't get in the way of the the
grown-ups
he's moving so slow
why are you moving so slow guy you
should be you should be quick
going down the stairs so i did not have
to trade with them they did
uh they made a little guy with uh
just from feeding them the bread so
that's pretty cool
actually i don't want to eat that that's
for the villagers
eat the steak look how slow he's
watching what is going on
what is he what is he doing oh don't go
in there
don't go in there little guy you can't
come back once you go there
it's dangerous here here i'll save you
i'll save you i'll save you no don't run
away
don't run away listen to strangers
listen to strangers
okay maybe we'll leave him be but he
might get stuck here
uh so while i was waiting i did go back
to the purifier by the way
and i think i created two or three new
ones there
uh two of them were i think armor armor
smith's and we got
one librarian one new librarian guy
which i think might be this one yeah
this guy he's a new guy
pain of arthropods five for 53 emeralds
is that
the trade though so that's going to be
really tough to do
i don't know about that
i lost track of the little guy i don't
know where he went can't find him
anywhere
hopefully he's okay
the guy that was over there finally
moved i think one of the guys like threw
bread at him
and maybe bumped him and then he decided
to run away
um yeah so at that other village i guess
the reason they weren't picking up the
wheat is because the old villagers
from before the 1.8 or whatever
uh i guess they they can't carry stuff
like these new ones so they they won't
pick up bread they won't pick up
wheat you could use them for farming the
wheat really easily
because you don't have to worry about
them picking up before you can you can
steal it from them you know
you could also even set them up where
if if you position them on top of a
hopper the other villagers
will throw bread at them
and you can turn it into like a bread
farm
um because because other villagers will
make bread from wheat
and then they'll chuck it at the old
villager and then the old villager won't
pick it up
and the hopper will get it instead so
that could be pretty cool
i think he's gone man i think the little
guy's gone
wait what did i just see
i saw something appear here and then
disappeared there was a villager
not him
anyway hopefully he turns up let me show
you what i
was building in the yellow house there
hopefully that works as well
i haven't tried it yet um
oh is this him
this might be him no this is an old guy
where is it yeah yeah i think it was
uh so i built this little thing here
this dropper has
book and quills in and this is for
the books the written books we're gonna
have to make a few
oh hey how did you get up here did you
climb the ladder
i think he's trapped here
uh this is all reserved for the book and
quills because those
don't stack and uh
you drop them off in the top chest and
you can have a huge reserve
all the way down there then if we cut
through here
this is basically just a standard
storage cell
sort of thing where
where you got three hoppers here uh this
one we're gonna put the books in
so it'll sort through them i think if
you have one more
yeah it'll go down oh i heard a book
fall
which ended up in there because we
weren't standing in the right place
um then the written books will get put
into here and i'll
put some way of being able to collect
them
and this wire also goes up over top here
to the dropper which is behind this
block
so i think if we let's try it out
hopefully it works
get that back okay so i think if we
stand here
we'll have to get a few books to get it
started
yeah if you throw a book down it'll
dispense them check it out i got an
upside down button here
that's new as well just to get started i
think i want like eight books on me
um kind of free up my hot bar here too
would be good
so i can use the hot keys
and yeah let's get a
couple more i suppose
okay so you put the book in the middle
now i can use the
the number keys so four five
six seven eight nine and quickly get
them going there
treat the books drop them is it going to
pick it up again
only oh i've only dispensed two oh
oh uh there seems to be a flaw
somewhere it only gave me two
they're not there that's not messed up
okay not quite working right
let's try this again i'm going to throw
10 and just see how many it gives me
just two again okay hmm
hmm what's going on guy what's wrong
with the redstone
[Applause]
i think that's fine i'll have to
i'll try have to try work this out give
me a second
so it's a very subtle problem but i
think i know what it is
this comparator behaves differently
depending on on what's going on
above this hopper so uh if this is a
chest it will work properly
or if the hopper is facing towards a
block instead of down
it will also work right otherwise it
doesn't detect every item passing
through
so we're going to have that facing
towards the clay block now
and i think that will do the trick let
me get my books back
try this again
didn't i have more books oh there they
are
that was weird i only saw one when i
first looked was there only
did it say 10 because i didn't see the
10. i might be losing my mind
that was weird all right so
uh when i throw this five we should get
five book and quills
two three four five perfect that's the
way it's supposed to work
so now uh this should allow us to craft
the books
pretty quickly i hope
so you want eight spots on your bar and
go two three four five six seven
oops seven eight nine get that one back
pick them up put one back in there throw
the other eight
yeah that's that's exactly what i wanted
that works out pretty good you just keep
doing it over and over
and in fact if you're quick i guess you
could just press the 2 key
really quickly you don't have to keep
yeah just press two
i like it yeah that's the way to do
written books
oh and we're out i ran out of the ink
pretty quickly i gotta say
so that's good though that's
probably i think i did 64 there
just about 64. so that's that's like 64
emeralds right there so that's pretty
cool
um so just a nice little machine to have
around our village because we will
probably be trading the books for
emeralds
quite a bit
yeah actually i think uh
i think we should probably call it an
end here for the village stuff and
probably go do the comments because this
has been going on for a while
um and it might take a while for this
village to really get booming like i
want
but we will check it out next time
and do some other stuff too of course
where's the little guy is it i think
that's not him
no it's a cookie guy where's my little
guy
i have to go save him
see there's zombies that run around here
still they can't get into the village
but if the villagers run out
then they can sometimes get attacked
actually baby zombies can get into this
village which has me worried quite a bit
actually i haven't sealed it totally
all right anyway let's go do the comment
thing and wrap up the episode
so here we go everyone this is the
comment i picked out for today's episode
and i just saw it we're at 321
321 we're really getting up there in the
numbers
which is good uh so here it is
it says hey etho i've been wondering do
you play chess or any games that
requires
thinking that requires lots of thinking
anyways keep up the good work
smiley face minecraft requires lots of
thinking because
it's entirely creative you're always
thinking of new things
but i i don't think that's what he means
like complex difficult games
require lots of strategy uh i have
played chess
i know how to play chess it's uh it's a
good game
not too many people play it though it's
not like you
you go over to someone's place and
you're like hey you want to play some
chess
sure set up the board uh that doesn't
happen too
often but uh
it's a good game uh i'm not very good at
it i could probably be
a beginner but there is like
like common moves good moves in the game
that you
you have to learn from what i understand
oh yeah by the way if you're wondering
about this
when i update the latest snapshot all
the
items in my item frames popped out
including my map and all that
so i freaked out a little bit about that
because i lost my map
and a whole bunch of other stuff so i
loaded a backup
and i put everything into storage before
i updated
so didn't have that problem this time
[Music]
um what was i gonna say oh yeah
he also asks about other games i think
of all the games i'm playing currently
scrolls
is the most complex and strategic and
thought provoking
lots of decision making in that game i
really really like scrolls
and recommend you try it if you if you
like that sort of thing
um i also play
hearthstone but that is it's kind of a
similar game to scrolls
except it's aimed more at casual players
there's a little bit less decision
making in it
but it's still pretty fun too
if you if you're good enough at the game
where you don't have to pay
to play um which thankfully i finally
got to that point um
or i'll see don't play it very often and
you can you can get by from daily quests
in the arena but uh yeah check out
scrolls
i strongly recommend you check out
scrolls if you like
strategy games um takes a little while
to get good at though
but give it a try anyway
that is all for today everyone i hope
you enjoyed today's episode and i will
see you again
next time take care bye-bye
[Music]
you