[Music]
so hello everybody this is
etho and welcome back guys to another
episode I see you over there mister
sneaky Sam he was like hiding behind the
bushes for the perfect opportunity I I
just wanted to farm a few records here I
got a couple new ones I didn't have
eleven before and I might not have had
LOX I think I had Strad and ward my
favorites so good here let's put this
one on already actually oh that's a cat
in there the song is so good guys so a
skeleton got lodged in the creeper one
though hopefully that doesn't cause any
problems here
it might shoot me a few times but I
think you'll die eventually long as he
hasn't hit one of the creepers
why she if he does hit a creeper he'll
just kill it right maybe it's not too
bad I'm really dying here look I should
be blocking that wasn't too bad oh that
was a heart
maybe we will recover a little bit
[Music]
it's pretty loud does that stop it
completely when you when you pause no
did I turn it down Oh
[Music]
all right come on just a few more I was
kind of hoping this skeleton would get
shot first there we are
so that would stop but it took a few
guys Ahmad I need some new records oh
we're gonna have to push these ones into
place because they tend to bunch up in
the front there oh yeah records for days
again there's two maybe one more one
last nudge all right this is this is
gonna be a pro shots Kelly nice very
nice Oh Moll I do have mall ready yeah
let's go see what we got I know oh man
that's a lot of Records we got three
four cats from that three malls wait did
I have weights remember I know I had
Melo hi Oh got another chirp that's my
second one I had to stall already not
sure if we got anyone's weight might be
new
oh man that worked out really good guys
I just checked what we had like our
record collection before and we got
chirp I had one of those but it's out by
my sand pit I sometimes put it on when
I'm digging sand to keep me company I
guess keep me entertained
blocks we didn't have we didn't have
weights Strad or eleven so that means
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve
we got all 12 record collection
completes oh yeah
let's try put Scrat on I guess hoops
that strats a pretty nice one I like
Strad so there was new music data to the
game I'm kind of hoping they add records
for that to like see c418 added a whole
bunch of new music tracks to the game I
usually play with my my music off just
because it's a little easier when
editing it's not as jarring so I haven't
really heard the new songs too much so I
wanted to show you guys what I did with
the spider farm what I ended up doing to
get me every time I don't know why they
love this spot so much but they hit me
every time I come and pick my head out
here basically had a good a suggestion
to a
[Music]
why are you down here how did you
survive that fall
is it cuz he was grabbing the wall cuz I
was by here or what but what I ended up
doing somebody suggested putting half
slabs above the track that the hoppers
running around on the hopper mic hurts
it'll pick up items through that like
anything that lands above here it'll
pick it up and I figured out a specific
Heights where the cave spiders will fall
and most likely activate the strip wire
here let's head back up it's actually
pretty hard to make that happen it turns
out there's there's one height where
well like they spawn at three different
heights there they'll spawn one block
above the spawner or level with it or
one block below it so three different
heights and I have it 14 blocks below
like where they spawn so
one block above the sign sign 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 11 12 13 14 walk spacing then the
trip wire and the ones that spawn at
that the highest and level with the
spawner will activate the trip wires the
ones at the bottom row won't there's
only one position where where to two of
the heights will work otherwise it's
only one I'm not very very good at
explaining things but it's very
difficult to make them hit the trip
wires this is the perfect height to do
it where will have the most success so
that works out pretty good and I did it
for this side too I feel like I'm
talking really loud I think the playing
the record is not a good thing I feel
like I'm shouting with it like I'm
talking over it
man I don't think I've heard this one
all the way through that's kind of cool
ending to it
alright guys uh what should we do today
let me think of something
so I decided let's hop into a creative
world very quickly here I just want to
show you what I mean about the spider
thing cuz I I wasn't too happy with my
explanation honestly so pretend this is
the level where the tripwire is if my
spider activates it these lights will
turn on and we gotta find a height where
they will die when they fall and
activate that so he didn't die that's no
good he dies at that height but the
lights didn't turn on so the tripwire
never got tripped ah see that's what we
want he died and the lights turned on
uh-huh go a little higher nope
higher nope do it there hey it works
again but only for this one height you
see you see how the spacing works I got
the red clay blocks where it works the
way I want there's very few places where
you have two of these red blocks
together where it does what we want and
there's no place where there's three of
them together so basically it's at this
height here this is where the spawner is
so one block above it works level with
the spawner it works but the block below
it doesn't and I'm not going to find a
place where all three of the Heights
work so this is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 14 block space between the trip
wire and the spawning space for the
spawner okay I have an idea for a
project guys this this is mostly gonna
be my project though it's cuz it's gonna
be repetitive and very large-scale so
I'm gonna work on it off-camera but I'll
introduce you to how I'm doing it but a
long time ago I made this tree farm and
as soon as I made it I was like we need
a ceiling for this thing yet I'll do it
later
and all this time has passed and I feel
bad I never put a ceiling on this thing
it's still dirt and cobwebs up there and
it's it's kind of nasty I never gave it
a nice ceiling so I think we should do
that today this isn't just any tree farm
as the thing this is a very important
tree farm it's it's the donator tree
farm which is and was and forever will
be important to my channel because
without the donations I got from people
before I was a YouTube partner I
probably would have like made a lot less
videos and never would have become the
YouTube channel that I did today without
the support from from all these guys and
all the people in the mineshaft that I
gave science to as well so I made this
as a way of saying thanks and and to
show appreciation for what people did
for me so I should take it this step
further and finish the roof actually
make it look nice for them so basically
I'm it is a very large project so I
can't get too fancy with it but my plan
is like it should look nice I don't
think I'm cutting corners but I think
it'll look good but basically I made the
wrong type of wood there spruce I want
spruce spruce and birch wood looked very
good together I kind of marked out a
grid here oh man this is tough all right
so I think I got to go up just do that
I'll have to shave a whole layer off the
ceiling at least and in some places more
and I think well press shift instead of
control I'm still getting used to my key
switch I think I'm gonna do a grid of
like 2x2 squares and then afterwards
come by here and connect them to try and
make it look not so uniform try to give
it a cool pattern let's see like that's
so yeah like I'll have a grid of all
these like 2x2 squares here I'll do a
few just just to show you what I mean
doot doot doot doot doot
Birchwood like so so imagine the whole
ceiling like this and then I better put
torches up in these areas that I'm
removing them too otherwise I'm gonna
have trouble but basically oops I should
probably do it and then show you because
just setting up a tiny examples taken
forever here just been mining away it is
a very big project but I'm getting close
to done removing all the stone so
awesome having the trees because I'm
using them as scaffolding basically and
it's it's making this a lot easier
otherwise I can't reach the ceiling and
I'd have to pillar up all like every
like five blocks I move I would have to
like pull her up and that would just be
a nightmare um but look at all this
space so it goes all the way from well a
little further out here yet even all the
way from here to that wall back there
and all the way from that wall to up
there oh no I've made a mistake guys big
air the world is ending there are mobs
everywhere this little zombie can't
figure out how to get by this block it's
hilarious why are they they're all
getting stuck on the blocks
why can't they figure out how to get
around the block wait a minute oh man
this is so bad there's some I left some
dark spots you see up there when I was
digging and I went to drop off some like
cobble and when I came back is just like
so many mobs swarming me all right all
right
where'd that creeper go run I thought he
was around that corner
yikes no no um here let's get up there
I'm worried about those villagers I'm
not sure if baby zombies can attack them
actually I I never really thought about
that
No oh there's two it was the Virgin Oh
all right all right we gotta light this
up I'm using this as a scaffolding is
the thing I don't want to take it down
just yet I should just light it up all
right all right you got this we got this
mmm well why can't I hit him that was
some bad aim right there oh there's a
slime a giant slime gun up here oh snap
okay
should be good I'm gonna check on those
villagers one more time I'm a little
worried about the baby zombies I think
they would have died already if the baby
zombies could figure out how to kill
them just a few more torches all right
that should do
alright let's head down carefully
be very careful they're alive they're
alive good I hear a baby around here
though I think this guy's looking at him
he's like down would be down over here
somewhere yeah he's very close mm not
too sure though nope no clue where he is
okay I think we're safe though
aha I got it done guys it is finished it
is complete so here it is are you ready
to see it
uh uh so it's it's pretty decent I like
it uh it's got a nice mixture of the
dark and the light to it so I feel the
compliments area well is it doesn't beg
for your focus too much and I think it's
I think it's pretty good I'm happy with
it
looks a lot better than the the rough
stone and dirt I think it looks really
cool like from from this Heights you
know where it all kind of blends
together and even from like here it
looks pretty cool so yeah I'm pretty
happy with it it's not quite done and
like it's fine the way it is but there's
one more thing I want to do to it that's
gonna make it a whole lot better I
believe I just ran out of time it took
I've been at it for over three hours and
it's it's still not done so I can't
quite finish it to date but I'll show
you what I plan on doing with it just
yet and I stuffed the mine this out this
last chunk but I've been using it as
scaffolding so I don't quite want to get
rid of it until I finish the ceiling
here so my plan with this get all these
like two by two square things and then
kind of play connect the dots and create
patterns
well not patterns but like give it
variation because it's pretty plain the
way it is but I think I'm gonna do like
this like take outlines and then and
then like do this so now we have this
like I don't know what you call it what
is that called
not quite triangle thing I don't know
yeah so I'll do that throughout the
whole thing like maybe I'll do another
one over here and just add a little bit
of variation to the thing a little bit
of randomness and I think that's gonna
make it a whole lot better once once I
get that done maybe let's just take a
look at this yeah I think so cuz as it
is right now it's very repetitive it's
not it's not too fancy but once you get
get it like that it's there's a lot less
spruce this way too as well and I think
that's better and you'll just I think
it'll look a lot cooler anyway that's
all we're gonna do with this today I'll
maybe finish it tomorrow or something
one more thing we're gonna do this
episode before I end it a little bit of
research for the Nexus you guys aren't
supposed to be here so I asked I gave
you like three ideas last episode I
asked what your favorite was and it was
a surprisingly close poll I guess like
most people seem to prefer the next I
would say about 40 to 50 percent said
they wanted to see me build the Nexus so
that was the favorite then it was kind
of evenly split between
well a little bit of lag there between
the Ender zoo and the redstone castle
museum thing but a lot of people said
they wanted to see that too so for the
Nexus I know where I want to build it
already and I'll show you kind of what
the plan is with that it's gonna be a
lot of planning a lot of resource
gathering with with the Nexus is the
thing it's it's gonna be the toughest of
the projects to get rolling because I
need a lot of iron a lot of wood and a
whole whole ton of planning and research
for it to turn out well is the thing so
we're doing a little bit today on that
we're gonna go to the end my bed is
right here is it nighttime let's sleep
okay and then I'm gonna break it
so my spawn gets reset so I'll put it
over there let's go up do the ends whoo
all right so the plan is to build the
Nexus around spawn by the way I put down
a whole bunch more snow golems in the
end here just so they cover the whole
place with snow I think once they do
that the Enderman are mostly gonna stop
spawning it's kind of like a chibi way
of of preventing Enderman from spawning
in the end is this put down a whole ton
of snow golems and let them do their
thing because they can spawn on the snow
slabs but only if there's air spaces
nearby so if it's all solid snow there's
a lot less Enderman spawning oh please
tell me I didn't look
I'm not ready to get my butt kicked here
ah
I press shift instead of control because
I'm not used to this sneaky darn it
I gotta go all the way back I'll be
right back
we're back that was an accident so I'm
still getting used to switching my my
sneaky with my sprint key once I do
though it's gonna be a lot better I'm
pretty sure so control very good we're
doing that test here to see where the
items come through at spawn and then
we're gonna mark that location I think
they will stack together
I brought some angles as well I think
that'll help I'm gonna put two well that
didn't work
hey don't be mad I'm gonna do let's give
her that one anvil there another one
over there
let's try one on this side oh really
oops
can I have the anvil back please that's
that's a mistake okay I'm gonna try to
throw some items down oops
oh I'm holding controls so now it throws
the whole stack and this is really gonna
take me a while you used to I can't like
throw a single item anymore when I'm
sneaking getting my throw some ender
pearls through maybe let's go to another
spot and throw some food through
hopefully when I go through I don't pick
up all this stuff um let's try to get my
anvil back if I can
that way I went through okay so you can
send items through the end portal and
they'll go to spawn true spawn on on
your world during on your server you can
and send like animals through it
Enderman all kinds of stuff all right
please tell me I didn't pick it up so
okay there we go that's where it ended
up all in one spot it looked like the
items keep their velocity when you throw
them to or throw them through to through
into so that's why I tried to throw them
straight down so they didn't go off to
the side and it looks like they all end
up pretty nicely in a pile so it looks
like between these blocks that one
getting priority okay I'm gonna I'm
gonna mark that actually I'm gonna leave
it handle here then I'm gonna come back
I'm gonna put hopper underneath here and
see if we can pick up items when we
throw them through the end portal today
we're back guys and I've been throwing
some items through the portal we got the
hoppers on the other side now I'm gonna
throw a few kind of like this I've done
this already by the way so there's gonna
be items all over the place we wanted to
see if the hoppers will pick them up and
in case you were wondering I know I sure
wondered about this if you are playing
on a multiplayer server and one guy
drops an Ville through the end portal
and somebody else is standing at true
spawn the anvil will land on them and
kill them because if you do it from high
enough just in case you were curious and
it is hilarious I've been wanting to do
it on the minecraft server just just to
do it but it requires the person to
stand in the exact right position and I
wouldn't be able to see it so yeah okay
so why did I do this oh yeah I want to
get a few intermn to go through just
for the the walls of it too although
they probably won't come up here will
they
nope they're not gonna teleport up here
yeah alright we're going through
hopefully he forgets about us next time
home bed missing your obstructed okay
that's where the item should go through
picked it all up awesome even the stuff
I threw sideways so that's good so the
idea is we're gonna build the Nexus
somewhat near this area here any farms I
want to set up I can set up in the end
and just send items through right to the
storage room pretty easily and animals
and all kinds of stuff so that's that's
just one one thought I have well while
planning and building the Nexus kind of
linked it up with the end and also
probably gonna try to connect it up with
the nether through the portal network
somehow so good to see that works but
anyway it is that time again everyone so
here we go hey II thought I was
wondering if you had ever considered
making an entirely different series
purely about redstone and how your
devices work apart from your LP and
minecraft videos I know you do make some
videos about your redstone work such as
the blaze firm and hopper timers etc I
just think it would be cool if you made
a different series going more in depth
about how and why it works that being
redstone so a long time ago like maybe I
wasn't that long ago maybe half a year
to a year ago I tried recording a
redstone series like specifically like a
redstone tutorial series it's probably
gonna be about 5 10 episodes total if I
was the guess and it wasn't so much
about like how to build the T flip-flop
in this and that and you know how to
build a redstone door and that is more
like looking into how redstone works
specifically how it connects to the
different devices how how the timings
worked all that kind of stuff defend the
fundamentals of redstone
but I wasn't too happy with how the
video turned out so I just kind of
strapped it but maybe again in the
future I'll give it another shot because
with redstone it's not so much like
memorizing how to build stuff that is
important but it's also just knowing how
it works is crucial and and why like
people tend to get frustrated with
redstone because they don't understand
why it's not doing what they want it to
do so it's kind of important to
understand why it's not doing what they
want it to you know understand how it
powers stuff and and that kind of thing
so anyway I have considered it short
answer so I hope you guys liked today's
episode once again and I will catch you
next time catch you next time I'll see
you again next time bye bye guys
[Music]