[Music]
hey everybody this is etho
how are we doing today we are going to
be working on the village
for a little bit here to begin with uh
but unlike other episodes
i'm not going to be as bwo says fiddle
farting around i have
a plan for today i went into creative
mode
came up with a style i really like
really really like for the village
we even have a name for it it's going to
be called emerald city
not a village it's a city emerald cities
where these guys are going to live
so i'm going to take you through how i'm
building the houses
um so let's begin uh first of all
the houses are gonna have double doors
and
we're gonna we're gonna build one right
here i have it all ready
uh we want i want the doors
here
so we are going to put sandstone there
and let's see
that that
okay double doors so that we can get
more villagers
i i hope that doesn't conflict with
their ai at all i don't think it does
but i haven't seen too many people use
double doors in villages so maybe
there's a reason for that
okay that's that's the start of it we're
gonna put
some stairs
sandstone guys we're using sandstone
you know it's going to be good
that's that
and we gonna whip out our emerald blocks
put two in front of the doors
and we're gonna put one here one here
and let's mark out the other corners too
i think i need
what is it
uh one two
i'm going by memory one two three four
well it's an eight by eight right so the
other corner would be
right at the end of where i marked this
i guess one two three four five six
seven eights
okay it's eight by eight and
five blocks to all these houses so
uh what's let's do this next
i'm gonna put that there
and iron bars
over there another one there these
lights
i think what i'm gonna do with them is
make them detect when the villagers are
inside for the night
these lights will come on uh not
entirely sure how i'm doing it yet
though
but that's kind of the plan with those
that that
uh-huh so
with this circle in the middle i'm going
to try i'm going to put grass where i
have the stone bricks and
nether brick where the glass is and
we're just going to cover up the lava
i think that will be pretty cool uh
because i
the grass will be dark green and the
nether brick is like burgundy and i
think those are color
opposites so they'll really contrast and
it might look
might look good
okay we do that and
same with over on this side we're just
going to copy that
there there
stairs
okay i'm starting to forget what i need
to do
next
for where i have these iron bars there's
going to be lava behind
so maybe maybe i'll just get these set
up
go get a bunch of lava and recheck my
design to make sure i don't mess up here
uh but i have iron bars here to hold it
in place
also oh yeah and then there
right that's right i know what i'm doing
i know what i'm doing
or maybe not
that that's lava in each of these spaces
and here and then
i'm guessing i did this over here as
well
and one of those over here
hmm
that and then i had a like a big window
here
a 2x2 iron bar window
all right so that's kind of what we got
so far i'm going to recheck what i have
and we'll continue
all right excellent we got the lava in
here um i'm going to put blocks over top
as well just there's a safety thing
um yeah we got our lava check it out
outside looks pretty cool
over here
so really the only thing left is the the
roof
so let's get working on that i
i'm going to get some more emerald
blocks in
i think there was one right here
wait how did that go
oh right it stuck out one block i think
like over there
i think that's right okay so then i had
some stairs
running along like this
another one over here
okay and
as sort of a highlight to the emerald
block i put one of these on top
and one below
huh all right um
i guess this is taking a while so maybe
i'll just finish
this off camera oh that's never a good
sign when you have mobs
in your village i wonder where he came
from
but yeah this is it guys this is a
standard
emerald city house pretty much all done
i really like it i put sandstone for the
the roof on it
and would like to get some lighting up
there yet somehow
but i like how this this block this one
this one and this color all kind of come
together
uh even ice goes well with those blocks
too like the light blue tinge
looks awesome but i didn't find any way
to
incorporate it
but yeah good size house i'll probably
have
four of them one there one there
one there and one there and
expand the village from there i'm not
sure yet how i'm doing that
but also with these roofs there's one
important thing i want to include
we're gonna do
one of these on every single house
so if we build above this it'll look
cool
even from above have have a little
something
uh just for now i'm gonna put some
torches
until we figure out a better lighting
trick to it
um but yeah i think the next thing i'm
going to do
is put the grass in here and the nether
brick and we'll see how that looks
oh i don't know what do you guys think
of that
um i like it more than anything we've
done so far
but i don't know if that's the nether
brick is really working
i really like how the emerald blocks
look next to nether brick
they almost like they look neon almost
they're so bright compared to
the nether brick um
but one other thing i may want to do
instead of another brick is sandstone
but we'll let this finish growing and
we'll figure it out later what i'm going
to do now is i'm going to build three
more houses
for these guys exactly like this one and
just get get the town going here and
then we'll let these guys out
well emerald city is out of emeralds so
we're going to do a big paper trade
three chests plus my inventory of paper
uh and i still don't have a good setup
for this so we're just gonna
close it in go underneath break the
chest
and trade as quick as we can
and take this out
all right this guy he wants 29 paper per
emerald though it's a ripoff
you can get a lot cheaper sometimes okay
here we go
oh man um
good they popped up all right trading
time
and that'll about do it we got just
about four stacks
emeralds was hoping for more
i guess you don't need to be on the the
paper screen to trade even
because that's on the books
ah if only it was 17. we got way more oh
ooh oh it's not going to give it to me
oh he's fine he's fine
i was only one stack all right so
that's what we got three stacks plus 37
don't have to do a lot more trading it
looks like
awesome emerald city has three houses
i still need to build this fourth one
but these guys are in the way so it's
it's finally moving day we got our
skylights
dug time to get out guys
foreclosure on this place
all right you found that quick
how about you you want a
it's house turning light out so all
right they got a place
so they may start breeding at this point
i don't
i don't know if there's enough doors i
think we need a few more doors yet
but yeah gonna get yeah i almost forgot
let me get some of these guys down too
just in case
always good to have them around
even though they don't always do much
sweet alright last house
i may have taken on more than i can
handle they almost killed me
man oh man i was just doing oh
she's doing a whole bunch of paper
trading again i think i need a bigger
paper farm in my lp world
especially if villager trading is
changing in the next patch i won't be
able to
exploit it like i am now which i'm only
doing
really for the emerald blocks uh
i'm not using those emeralds for
getting diamond stuff or anything like
that whoa whoa whoa
uh this minecart thing keeps breaking
i think i'm going to add an and gate to
it so
i can turn it off that way big slimes
can actually build up here like this
because up before they would just always
take off if i have an andy that i can
choose if i want them to
go around the track or if i want them to
stay here
so i was actually able to trade with
this guy three
massive paper trades uh before it went
away
uh now he's got this clock deal and it's
it's the worst i don't want a clock
that's expensive um
let's hope we get a new trade the first
try
i bet you with those new uh picture
frame things coming out
that you can mount items in i bet if you
put a clock in it you'll be able to see
the time when it's in the frame that
would be cool
i would actually have those all over the
place dang it
just went through all this trouble to
get these emeralds and
gonna have to sacrifice them if i wasn't
exploiting it
you know i would never get 11 emeralds
for a clock
oh
well don't really need that either
sand isn't tarted yet
let's try get a new one i want the paper
one back
and hopefully get a low a low rate this
time
ah 27 that's that's still near the max
but at least we got something back
yeah we got all four houses done
but there's still only two villagers and
it's gonna be like that way for a little
bit
um each door each valid door only counts
as 0.35 of a villager
so 8 times 0.35 is 2.8 so
one more door and we could get another
villager in our village
uh it's actually surprising how they did
that because you need so many doors like
i have
i have four houses here each with
two doors and it's still only enough for
two villagers so you need a whole
bunch of doors man to really get a
village thriving
um i don't think i mentioned it but
these houses
uh i talked about these indicator lights
before
i left a space
up here i can run redstone wire up there
to the lights
and connect it down below or at this
back wall somewhere
like i i could run a redstone torch
up there there's lots of different
places i could do it so
that's how i plan on wiring it um
yeah we need we need a lot of houses
let's go let's go back for
up up the hill view um these houses
though they're pretty big
bigger than i thought it was going to be
um
and they they blocked the view a bit but
that that's okay
if i was to redo it i would probably
lower this
a few more blocks actually just so i
could see more but
it's fine like this i plan on having a
walkway
up high here that we can kind of go
around
the top layer here as well
sometime but what i'm going to do now
i'm going to replace this nether
brick with sandstone and just see how it
looks because i think
i will prefer it's more
in the long run
oh man here we go again fiddle farting
around
i switched it over started switching it
over i can already tell i'm not going to
like it as much as another brick though
so
i'm going to have to switch back
what would probably look best is
emeralds but i don't have that many
so we'll keep it as another brick
unless we find something else we like
more later
awesome so we got some lamps in here now
we got rid of the torches
nether brick is back it's looking good
looking real good
the place is a bit cluttered right now i
got to remove a lot more land
and we will be expanding the village
it's not going to be
just this it's going to
i'm not sure i might go down lower or i
might go
like start making pathways going
diagonally from these
these four spaces here but anyway
uh this is all we're going to do with
the village today let's let's take a
break from it
because we've we've done a lot with it
lately
i wanted to make a portal room today too
if we can or at least start it
i'm going to build it mostly out of
sandstone
and take some dispensers
let's see what else do we need
should be it
all right well maybe we'll do we'll take
the stack just in case we need it
and maybe this okay
let's head on up uh
the portal room we talked about this a
long time ago and it still hasn't
happened
it's gonna go behind the creeper face
may actually want another portal room
like somewhere
around here too just because they're
it's starting to be quite a distance
between
this part of the base and that part of
the base but yeah we're gonna
try put it behind here
not sure how this is gonna work out
very easily i think
i think this lava's intact
oh that's freaky yeah so we're going to
put it on the other side
we can get through to it by ender
pearling
right above is that bridge
and
let's clear out the creeper face
oh wait we can't see the creeper face
can we darn okay well i'm gonna start
laying a room
uh figure out where the creeper the
creeper mouth is
and line it up with that
ah that's scary to do
got 29 levels i got 11 blocks of emerald
on me and all kinds of stuff
uh once i do it a few times i'll get
used to it
so i got a floor here i'm going to put
the portal
right here
and just just for the sake of
completionist i'm going to do the full
full portal with the corner blocks even
there okay but i don't want to see the
obsidian
frame
so tada
i'm going to try to cover it with
sandstone and i had this idea
this is mostly going to be this room is
going to be very similar to those houses
we just built actually
um
see if we change this
going to be going 300 pearls like like
mad here
hmm what do i want to do
think it would be cool
i did that
just i just don't want to see the
obsidian so i'm going to try to cover it
with sandstone
and i wanted to put emerald blocks in
uh maybe yeah let's put let's put one
there
one there and one above two
that and uh stairs connecting it
that's cool oh yeah and the corners
i left empty because i want to get some
of these chiseled
with the creeper faces put those there
and there
okay
now i think i'm gonna do this
and i'm gonna have buttons to control
the portal
uh one of them will shoot a fire charge
which will light it and one of them
will shoot water into this portal so
it'll disable it so if i ever want to
shut it off i can
and re-enable it i can
so that's what the dispensers are for
i'm going to put one right
here uh i will be able to see it
if i have the stair like this which
isn't a good thing but i can also
refill it real easy uh with
oh crap oh oh oh
oh oh that scared me
oh my goodness oh
my heart's bumping that really did scare
me
oh okay
continue continue on here uh
let's do one of these walls i want to do
see there is this
i'm gonna put lava in the sides and
maybe fill this in
so like we did before
stare there stare there there
and then this is the chiseled
no
that's chiseled do that
i'm scared of that thing now
okay chiseled
there and there regular
okay we'll have lava right where this
gravel is
and either iron bars or glass panes
there
so i'm gonna do that for this side as
well and
maybe just do a little bit off camera to
get this going because we're almost out
of time
now this is actually my first time
making fire charges
in this game i had no idea you got three
i always thought it was just one
that's awesome sweet
those are gonna go a lot further than i
thought they would
um okay what else did i need
well this is i'll show you what i got
down there so far it's just about
done
um i think i'm getting better at this
oh oh no i did not just do that
oh 29 levels
none of this stuff went in the lava
we're good
oh
i'll have to be a little careful when
using this thing it seems
or disable it one or the other
um this guy's got to die though
hmm didn't think that was going to
happen
oh yeah and i can't even fall i don't
have my boots on just about died again
ah he's still there
oh i need pearls i can't even get back
in
there are some issues with this thing it
seems but we'll work
through them
all right should be able to hit them
through the portal
or through the the mouth
i hit him
i think he's dead okay let's try again
yep ah that stupid pigmen
just had to be there oh that's what i
need i need lava
but yeah this is the room so far it's
looking pretty cool
uh i still do not get the lava or the
glass panes uh for the fire charges
let's go ahead and put those in
all i really have to do
put redstone on top the dispenser here
and then
[Music]
that there and
a button on it and it should work
what did i spill no okay i'm gonna i'm
not gonna put a backing on it just yet
um let's try this out
sweet so it'll shoot through this
obsidian block
and hit the bottom of the frame and i
think it does it every time
um i'm going to go get the lava and
we'll be back
let's try this again
safe no pigmen okay got the lava
built a little holder for each
let's not piece so close
good decide to go with the pains
all right and that'll about do the look
of the room
still got to do some wiring though with
our portal mechanics
sweet that's pretty bright uh what are
we at
11 10 yeah it's good
very bright um
so basically we're going to have another
button on the left side
this will control water
let's clear the portal again
um and there's gonna be
i'm gonna put two dispensers just for
the look of it
but we really only need one
and in that one
we need the water bucket it'll shoot
water out
which will make the portal
disappear and
then it has to scoop it back up so two
pulses
something else i kind of want to do when
i hit the fire
it'll light the portal then after a few
seconds i would like
it to trigger this maybe
maybe so it'll automatically disable
itself when i
when i reload this region when i come
back from the nether
that way i don't get pigment in here and
stuff like that
maybe maybe
okay so i did the wiring for the water
gun or whatever it is
um does that
it's pretty good doesn't spill over or
anything
uh what i've done let's take you back
here
this is the block that the buttons on
and then i just have a repeater here
to make it go out a little further
and then it goes to this monostable
circuit here
this this uh triangle right triangle
shape thing um torch
then that powers this wire here
goes to another torch and in between we
have this repeater
have to set that to four otherwise the
pulse is not long enough for the
dispenser to register it
and from there one wire goes directly to
the dispenser and then another
this repeater goes
down to this wire here and
it has a spacing of two ticks so right
after this pulse
this one goes two ticks later and scoops
it back up
and that's all we got to do
so i'm gonna maybe put
these here just for looks as well to
bounce out the look
and put that there
yeah it's not not ideal
but let's try it out anyway
fire water
cool
yeah i'm not entirely happy with how
that looks the backing
but i'll i'll mess with that later i
think that's all we're gonna do for
today so let's get
to the comment reading thing and wrap
this up
we got two comments for today guys
number one
etho i was thinking about a style for
your village seeing as how you like
green grass
and such maybe you could make like a
huge
tree in the middle of the cave you dug
out for them
with the branches kind of holding up the
ceiling and you could
pumpkins hanging from the tree which
would look naturalish
and then you'd use leaves and other
materials and grass blocks for the
ground
and the houses could also look like they
are hanging
maybe with wood etc that is a pretty
cool idea for village
and um maybe i'll use it one day in the
future
or somebody else will use it
he he went on to say in another comment
that it wouldn't really work here
because of
the dark green grass but i could see
doing that in a village and it would be
pretty cool i think
number two etho you should make a
villager fountain
that is to say a fountain that villagers
pop out
of after you trap them in your houses
and suck them underground
that is a cool idea too because we could
put a water fountain here or something
and then like i do know how to trap them
underground once they go into the
houses at night and then
have like a day sensor that would
trigger them all to pop up
through the fountain that could be cool
might do that
so thank you for the suggestions thank
you for watching everybody
uh i hope you enjoyed today's episode
and like the styles i've come up with
here
i'll see you again next time