hey guys I was doing some cave exploring
looking for redstone and some slime
balls and I came to a bunch of zombie
noises so I'm thinking we have a dungeon
good way to start out an episode so
let's check it out
I did just recently died actually I fell
into slava after having an insane amount
of goodies on me so I lost a bunch of
stuff and hopefully I don't lose my
redstone again or I'll be very sad I
lost about a stack these stacks when I
died so difficult to find them always I
think they're above almost I'll get my
brightness up here too I'm hoping it's a
dungeon we'll see ah see my wise weren't
my wise idea was that just by the sheer
numbers he can't get up
easy disabled I very heal I'm still not
wearing armor when I go exploring that's
a little bit risky oh that's awesome
they all fell down the teeth there and
couldn't get back up but there's a lot
of them Wow
if they wander away from the spawner
like this and they just keep spawning
endlessly otherwise there's a limit cool
dad hey that's last guy I've been there
one more Stilton we'll leave them alone
for now check out our goodies
yeah dungeons are still relatively
disappointing
yeah I've been finding some pretty
amazing caves around here cool stuff and
lots of goodies that gold coal ah and
even some iron and redstone and that's
right we got redstone I'm happy an
Enderman in my farm there's that
Enderman in my farm oh I want my fishing
hook so bad right now if I leave will he
follow me that's what I'm worried about
what you doing down there I'm gonna try
to get my fishing hook oh oh I hate
Enderman yes so XP is still very bugged
by the looks of it because I gained
three levels recollecting my XP from
what I died oh well and just thinking if
I hit him with a fishing rod though he's
gonna get mad at me isn't he if I can do
it without looking at him that is I
should accept it equip the line shows
where he was come on let's get it over
with where you at I hate under it
hmm there is weird doesn't seem to want
to fight yes so XP is still very bugged
by the looks of it because I gained
three levels recollecting my XP from
what I died oh well and just thinking if
I hit him with a fishing rod though he's
gonna get mad at me isn't he if I can do
it without looking at him that is I
should have kept it equip the line
showed where he was come on let's get it
over with where'd you had hit Enter
hmm hilarious weird doesn't seem to want
to fight anyway this is the farm there
are a lot of animals in it too many I
believe anything over 20 is too many for
the size of a farm I'll show you just
how scary it is down there they do this
clumping thing which is really yeah like
if I try to harvest my wheat and replant
it there's no way I can do it with these
guys down here
so it's just the small farm this is too
many now I checked it out Oh
and with our thing above I have raised
it two blocks so now the fishing rod
should pull them farther I have also
made it wider it's before it was nine by
nine now it's 11 by 11 so two extra
blocks there and there's the waters too
deep here so let's let's check it out
not in the right spot there we go and we
have a cow up here just like that now I
need to hook up some way of processing
them I'll say so one idea was to have
them drop into some lava above me when
I'm standing in the center here but that
will be hard to set up so I think I'll
do something simpler and thinking either
an EMP unit or something like that not
sure
oh yeah one other thing people have told
me I have my brightness way too high and
I definitely agree I've had it at a
hundred percent this whole time or plus
a hundred so tell me what you think it
looks good we'll go down to 75 now a
little bit more natural I'm thinking
around 50 is gonna be great for YouTube
it'll still have that light quality
without it being too dark
let's go down more though just so we can
see tell me which you think looks best 5
and this is what it is really supposed
to look like it is really dark down here
apparently I had no idea cool
okay well I'll go up to 50 for this
episode anyway and I'll show you what
I've done here I've added pumpkins in
the middle for lights I've also hidden
them behind these leaves that added
these leaves and bumped him back there
glowing pumpkin one back there so
there's eight all around and I believe
what I am going to do with the cows is
just set up some half slabs all around
here the old school type or something
different and then let's see we'll have
water pushing them to these edges the
cows then they'll fall down to this ring
all around they won't be able to get out
and then I'll choose one spot to hook up
a killing thing yeah and they'll just
wander into it on their own eventually
does it have to be
super automated it's just the basic farm
okay so the water is going to be a
little tricky I will put some more
leaves here leaves maybe now let's do
glass some glass and then I got four
buckets on me good I will put these at
each of these points to push your cows
towards the edges I really wanted to
build something else today guys by the
way I'm being good though I said I try
finished projects before starting new
ones so you got to give me props for
that okay now I need to get out of here
okay my water is back there yeah and
I'll just have a block and a half height
clearance here so only towels will fit
through and I won't because I don't
wanna get trapped down here and grab
some water
this here temporarily and now we need to
update our water so that's a little bit
of a pain but basically if we pour water
next to it and then make it disappear
not thing I feel we can get it to spread
like so and then we can make it take
shape leg going on here so I'll do that
I'll see you in a second there we are
I've added some more leaves I'm going to
probably fill this all in like
everything up there all the way this
whole ceiling and I'll just have a
little chute that I can walk in above
and then fall down here to my spot and
the cows they should fall into this ring
all the way around and then I'll just
have to pick one spot where I want them
to fall into an EMP unit or through fire
or lava or something to kill them or
some kind of compact holding chamber but
I need to test first of all that they
will actually walk onto these half slabs
here that they'll be able to get out of
the water otherwise I will have a
problem so let's figure that out
mmm I'll get better at it there's some
skill involved oh no it's a baby I'm
sorry you're gonna wander off get your
butt off my latch okay let's get a few
more up here
Gophers pigs nice miss who oops
then see what happen that guy hmm yeah
okay they walked off oh don't tell me
you're just gonna stand there you better
wander
okay good he's wondering if they don't
wander it's not going to work either
cool cool okay so I'm gonna work on this
more and I'll see you again soon
all right so most of everything we need
to do up there is done now a little bit
of polishing to do and maybe some more
lights could be added I fell down there
you back down and it's cool you can see
the animals walking around the ring
through the leaves just kind of cool now
the next things we need to do we need to
make a way of getting up there for us
we're getting down there for us a
holding system for them to fall down
into
we also need a way of getting down here
that looks good everything and I would
like to add like I don't know maybe a
chest or something down here to hold the
wheat and everything we collect and
actually without I would also like to
add some doors in the font I don't like
that sound just put this here temporary
gets the doors
I brought some redstone with me because
we also need to finish the wiring hearin
spiders and everything so I'll just oh I
hate these guys you have no idea how
much I hate them
all right so I have to stay away from
the lab lawyer of those mops
this area still isn't very little fare
too well I'll just put our door here
yeah I'll have one over here and one on
the other side cuz I don't want to use
this ladder to get down here always I
want a nice clean ultra professional
thing call the door awesome
okay so I got a connect I got a make a
path and stuff in there oh I can't stand
much more of that sound
it's a nightmare down here okay well
what I would like to do is have an
opening on the side where I could
possibly feed them from but I will need
a block here or the output a block there
and then we should be able to take this
down they won't be able to get up here
at that height you got to remember
though our lava is right underneath
these blocks so be careful there goes
some more ladders okay we do want a
block over our door
and maybe give her this
I brought some pressure plates with me
right over there
nice door open then that is working
terribly that the heck's going on the
door in Reverse or something
should it be swear if you guys come in
here when I'm doing this I'm gonna blow
that ah no bad door need the hinge on
the other side
they have to break this and these guys
are gonna be so annoying that's safe
oh yeah I forgot about the water
clicking door door works see door work
it
ah so much to do down here the same
we're here
good I'm going to replace these with
stairs they don't light up very good
very well new lighting system is cool
but it still has a lot of bugs to the
side
let's see if they'll come to me oh I
don't have any meat who's hungry
oh so scary
what now they're gonna eat me
whoa I will do that and I will do
that
clear these outs and we'll put other lap
staircase over there
and our doors over here so we will put
our blocks like so stare kind of not
terrible all right making some progress
there I feel it's too cramped though we
need to make this at least 2 wide up
here so I'll work on that now and making
it too wide was a huge improvement feels
a lot more comfortable up here so I
started working on over here
this is hollowed out for our wiring ok
we have to do yet at a crafting table
here excuse me I will finish replacing
round here with pumpkins it fit which
way they need to it looks right Jay and
I will have another chest probably have
four chests down here to bounce it out
there's lava right above here which I
might use for lighting
if we take this out then we can have it
flow down
I believe chess don't burn they might
catch fire but I don't think they burn
but we will hide that off right now so I
don't die okay what else do we have to
do I notice we have a problem with our
wheat yet there's two one there and one
there that aren't growing still not
enough light so I'm just gonna try put a
pumpkin over here stop pushing me there
that should take care of those two I was
worried that the animals would come
through these doors but I I remember now
that they can't fit through because of
the hinges that's that's not bad and
I've also added two shoots here this one
has a water break for coming down and
this one is a ladder for right now I
might eventually change it with a piston
elevator but for now let's we'll just
use a ladder get down around here so not
too bad but we need to run our redstone
yet I'm thinking I'll just have a lever
for it over here okay so we need to run
redstone underneath that actually what
we'll do is harvest our wheat because
it's pretty much all grown let's do that
go to the other side oh man feel the leg
feel the leg that's nice very nice
Wow it's not a bad wheat farm really it
does get stuck in a few places I've
noticed but not too much lost not too
much loss from it
okay so just I already highlighted the
path I wanted to take although we will
need some repeaters my little stick one
here and that goes all the way up here
and then the same for the other side oh
man so much like yeah and we'll be just
about done our farm here we just need to
make an EMP or something and that should
be the end of it
cool okay oh yeah I want to try put some
iron bars here it's getting really late
here geez can't tell by my voice didn't
getting sleepy now I'm gonna go good
good okay so our frontier is polished up
pretty nice now actually I'm happy with
it I've added lap lighting here it's a
great over here
let's buy your water break and also on
the other side there's another great so
lots of lighting we have lava lighting
here now and on the other side as well
okay I had to fix our wiring though
because the repeater didn't reach to the
end there so now before it was over
there now I believe we're somewhere
around there and now it's moved a little
closer give it a safety here for the
lava which is pouring down now
another repeater here set the one this
one set the one
the other side is set to two so it
bounces out so it's all wired just a
simple lever one else so yeah I added
lighting here I was going to put some
flowers just for looks I might put
something up here yet down here looks a
lot better we got our lap lighting both
sides
oh my should have done that I just
killed all my crops I might have been
quick enough oh darn it wasn't thinking
it's getting late ah but yeah I'm I'm
pretty happy with it so I will end it
here today
and I thank you for watching next time
we'll maybe do something else I don't
know
spent three episodes on this now or so
isn't bad but I like to do other stuff
as well so yeah I'll see you guys again
next time