ah man I tell you guys I tell you learn
from my mistakes don't don't do what I
did like before you go to bed don't
watch scary movies don'ts don't drink
coffee or or get caffeine or sugar into
your system any other way because when
you go to bed you might find yourself in
the same situation you might have
yourself a redstone nightmare like I
have here and then you got to solve it
before you can move on and wake up this
this is quite the nightmare but you know
what Wilson is coming along here I have
I've been working on it I probably won't
show too much of the red stoning anymore
just I'll just show you the basic steps
I'm taken to finish it probably because
it's it's pretty slow going here but
basically it what I've just added is
this this thing here which allows me to
lock the hoppers and each variable now
has these two wires I can connect to
basically this one is for addition if I
send power to that's it will unlock the
hoppers and allow items to flow through
this way or if I do this one then it's
subtraction so now items can flow the
other way into this hopper now what I
got to do is connect each of these
together all three of those plus plus
this and this and that will be a master
reset line so if the pet dies I just
pull a lever or or something I send a
signal for probably a minute or two to
clear everything and then we have a
brand new pet basically so that's the
next step I don't know if you guys can
tell but I'm still kind of sick from
from before
I'm doing my best I'm trying not I'm
trying not to talk like this you know
but I can't quite help it mm-hmm work
off like I just did there yeah the
sickness you know he got bored it was it
was content in my my throat for a while
but then I got bored and decided to
migrate down into my lungs a little bit
so now I got a little tingle every time
I breathe in which is not very pleasant
that's how I feel right now
yeah but yeah you know it's I'm sure
I'll get better it's not a terrible cold
or anything it's just mildly annoying
and not thrown away but in other news
I've been doing a few other things
around here I checked out the slime farm
I've been trying to figure out why some
of this stuff isn't working these guys
like why this minecart thing wasn't
working anymore oh it didn't work
he just picked up a slide let's go in
there just show you what's going on
ah yeah that guy had a slime in OOP oh
it's picking up more guys cool yeah but
basically empty mine carts they they
move a lot further than they used to is
one issue so my lazy junction right here
you just saw it it's it's having a
slight problem detecting empty carts now
before I had the detector over here well
sorry about that this episode's going to
be a bit choppy I think just because I
gotta clear my throat every so often
here so my apologies sorry please
forgive me but yeah I had to detect a
rail on top of the pumpkin before right
and since empty carts lose their
momentum quicker than then carts that
have something in it takes to the empty
cart longer to get to this Junction and
by that time this Junction would switch
back so it would go this way but now
since empty carts looser momentum a bit
slower they're actually getting by here
before it switches so they go further
quicker which is a good thing that's a
good change I would say but yeah I've
tried moving the detector rail back I
moved it here that didn't fix it then
when I moved it here instead of all the
carts going straight regardless of
whether they were empty or full now they
all go this way regardless of whether
they're empty or full so there's no real
change in the speed of the carts whether
they're empty or full with my setup here
so I think I got to move this power rail
back a little bit and hopefully that
will will do the trick
because empty carts are still slower or
they lose their momentum quicker so it's
still possible to do a junction like
this I just step to tinker with it a bit
well we hit level 30 again it's time for
another book enchantment what are we
going to get I don't know let's find out
efficiency 3 whoa all right I think I
got it fixed here cart goes that way you
saw the track switch twice there
and since it was moving so slow it was
able to go that way instead of going
straight because they gave it enough
time to switch back and so I moved the
detector rail one away from the pumpkin
and the power rail two away from the
detector rail before it was detected
rail there and power rail there and that
seems to work with my setup now um yeah
accidentally had a big slime go up here
now my karts are all messed up but it
does seem to be working again which is
good there is a few other things I
spotted though that I could improve this
I think let's see all right that's all
reset I tried it out the big slime still
get picked up which is good from the
corner here now that we can turn stairs
like before I had it like it was like
that and there's this little gap you
could see into here from I think I can
cover that up now if I switch that to a
sideways there let's just try this out
real quick
Oh nope went the wrong way um I might
have to get one more stair I should
actually put stairs here too because we
got these little corners it might look
better see prepping table real quick
here doo doo doo doo I've kind of just
been going around and looking for little
things to fix around in the cave here
because if you don't if you don't fix
stuff eventually everything gets broken
and then you don't like you don't like
your world anymore oh I see the problem
is facing the wrong way I'm supposed to
put it like this there we go perfect so
I want to make sure I keep maintaining
things let's see what this looks like
too
I want to do this instead yeah yeah I
think we should do that give this little
updates I tried one more thing here I'm
not sure if it's working but I was
finding a lot of times the little slimes
were falling down and and somehow not
falling into the water they were just
landing right beside here and then we're
able to run around my teeth or hop
around my cave so now I got these
trapdoors just to make it a little bit
tougher for them to get out I hope we'll
see if that works
oops there we go cool this would be
covered beautiful here comes a big slide
and I decide that in one more little
feature to our our track loop here it's
a it's a safety feature if for some
reason a card starts going the wrong way
around here there there really wasn't a
way of it fixing itself so now I've
added this extra detector rail over here
and if a car goes over its empty or full
it fails darn it you know what I did I
forgot to put a block here so I can show
you the circuit but there's a redstone
torch below the junction and detector
rail goes to that by doing that alright
so I'm going to cover it up if we can
build this quick enough the carts going
to come around and we can see orc doodoo
it's going the wrong way should come
around that corner any second I hope
still no sign and by the way this is
awesome they they fix the map flickering
thing I'm not using that patch yet but I
will be soon
there's still performance issues as far
as I can tell oh here comes the cart
so that works out perfect for me there
we go
and it goes back on the stack and
hopefully that won't have any trouble
with carts going this way don't think it
will this is mostly just for decoration
this this giant map I'll probably have
more maps now that I have them you know
it's easy to copy them I might have more
where we can actually get up close and
look at the details because you can't
see a lot from this but it's still cool
to see it from a distance yeah and also
I didn't point this out before but
there's hoppers oops
filled that water there's a hopper here
now for for the small slimes too and I
should do something with the mediums but
I don't really want the mediums the
large ones I like to go make go around
the track but yeah um let's close this
up and one more idea
oops area yep that looks good this wall
always looked really plain to me like
where our elevators here ah
maybe we will just see what's behind
here yeah we got space over there and
this is probably wirings in it that's
scary to do it's fine it's fine okay
there wasn't worried huh that makes this
easy let's uh let's put like a plant or
something here let's see what this looks
like here oh yeah
whoa what do you guys think actually
that doesn't even take two blocks does
it
let's put put some stairs oh yeah I
think I like that maybe we will fix this
corner who it's better than a flat wall
at least big slime going up let's go see
if it works still should work ah yeah I
didn't like how it looked with just the
one here so I put two and put a
different type over there it looks
better
all right guy yeah it works again that's
awesome these guys by the way they can
hurt me now
like before they would just pass by if I
was standing here right now they can
actually hit me for some reason so it's
a bit more dangerous now uh but yeah
what was I gonna do let's see let's see
let's go I'm going to tell you guys
about my Safari idea it's a little crazy
I think you'll like it though I talked
about this before I want to make a
shooting range of some sorts in this
game in my world here and I figured out
how I'm going to do it I I'm pretty sure
we're going to do a safari like a nice
fenced area we're going to do a bunch of
terraforming get a nice wood land area
maybe some some water and and all that
kind of stuff I got this big forest area
here it seems that quite a few elevation
changes to which would be good this this
would be a nice spot I think this big
forest area and I'm going to set up
targets in the forest I think two
different types one type I'm going to
have chickens like an aerial targets so
I'll have like a dispenser in the air
with chicken eggs in and that will be
that will shoot randomly and if a
chicken falls down it'll it'll hit a
trip wire and that will will tell the
system that it should
was released and if I don't kill it by
the time it gets to the bottom it will
hit another tripwire and I lose a point
basically if I don't kill it and that's
I'm going to attract that then I have
another idea though for a boat target
and we're going to try build that I
think it's it's going to be good so I'm
gonna get some stuff together all right
I got a bunch of stuff together here I
think that's pretty much all little need
let's run through this this boat target
idea so what I would like have like a
dispenser with boats in maybe maybe a
hopper with a chest above to fill it now
that won't work we would need to hoppers
yeah the thing about shooting a boat
from a dispenser it's pretty picky it
seems like you can't just make the boat
up here it checks a few conditions I
think one of them is it needs water for
sure like you have to have water that
the boat will get dispensed into let's
just set that up that work yeah that
works so now there we go we got a boat
so that would be our target and of
course as you know you can destroy a
boat with arrows so that's that's how
that would work and the beauty of it is
it's a moving target like a horizontal
moving targets the chileans would be a
vertical moving target okay now the
other question I have is if you have
something blocking the boat will it
spawn it does but it will land on it
okay
so ideally we want that area clear so
maybe to hoppers like that and then the
chest will put on top like here for
extra storage that's a trap chest it
seems and then if you put a few boats so
they'll feed into that okay
so that's the basic start to it let's
let's go a little deeper now so ideally
I want it to work where if I send the
dispenser or the set up some power it
will have a chance of randomly
dispensing a boat I don't want to happen
I don't want it to happen at a specific
time I want it to be random I think if
we just do that and then power its needs
power but the trip books will randomly
and they'll randomly sorry I'm I'm
thinking here
they'll randomly make the dispenser
shoot if it's being powered okay another
idea like behind the safari I'm going to
be riding around in a mine carts
there'll be a track throughout it then
they'll be fast sections and slow
sections maybe the cart will stop in
places for a certain amount of time and
and only targets within the area will
appear randomly then I'll have to shoot
at okay so then we get we get our moving
boats hopefully this will activate at
least once let's let's see let's put a
couple more trip pokes at least one more
unless that was patched I think it was
an idea is I'll have to destroy the boat
before it gets to a certain point
otherwise it's going to go over pressure
plates let's just sleep here and if it
goes over the pressure plate then I lost
the point basically so if I break it any
time before that pressure plates it
won't go over top it okay so that
updated that's good to know
or learning things here we have to have
ground or weights maybe let's just
let's see what could we put here I just
assign or anything would work really we
want it to look relatively good too
though daddy can't use that could use
stone pressure plates to hold water in
place they won't get activated yeah all
right anyway so go over the pressure
plate and then I got to make it so the
boat gets recycled as well so I want it
to hit like a cactus at the end of here
and go into a hopper or if I destroy it
then it will wash down to the end and
then come back to the hopper so I'm
going to I'm going to play with it a bit
off camera here see where we get all
right a couple important discoveries
here half slabs are wonderful they slow
the boat down so it gives me more time
to shoot at the target which is a good
thing if I want and it also holds the
water in place cactus does not work that
boat just got randomly dispensed it
breaks the boat into planks and sticks
again which is not going to work so yeah
let's see but when I broke it with the
arrow I'm pretty sure it gave us the
boat which whoops well that's one way to
do it yeah that gives us a boat if we
break it I'm going to try dispenser with
an arrow and I think that will still
break it into planks if I was to guess
that's what it should do but maybe maybe
it gives it back to us okay this is
arrow in a dispenser test
okay so boats in here let's release it
it'll hit the pressure plates and that
will shoot the boat and it breaks it
into oh wait a minute
it broke before it even that shot I
think you can only shot once right all
right just to be sure we're only going
to put one arrow in this time we're
going to try that again that was a
little weird I think it crashed crashing
it deuce blanks so we can't do it that
way either and I'm just seeing lava with
your planks as well yeah I think it's
shot oh okay let's just cut this off for
now and we'll just manually do it I'm
pretty sure anything that the player
does will give you the boat back but
anything natural you won't get it back
oh and it takes more than one shot - you
won - oh come on stop regen health
stinking boat all right all right all
right fine
we will put down a lever just to try
this oh it does give a boat oh so we
would need to shoot it twice but that's
one way we could recycle it if if we
care be a lot easier not to recycle and
just have a big buffer here we are going
to do a lava test because I am curious
that's I didn't think that would give us
a boat but it did so maybe this will - I
can't place it there let's put that
there ah
really hmm that's the easy way that's
what we're doing I decided to do the
cactus test again because I figured the
reason it broke into planks before is
because it actually crashed on the
cactus not because the cactus gave us
that so turns out that's what it is we
got a boat there so if it crashes it
gives us planks but any other method of
destroying a boat seems to just give the
boat itself from what I can tell that's
that's my Jes of how it works since
we're doing the Safari thing these slabs
will most likely be some type of wood
that make it blend in a little better I
want to show you this so like I have the
slabs the full length here and that
makes a huge difference on the timing so
we'll have a lot of control how long we
want the target to be random dispense oh
they're going to collide but yeah it
like up to like this point they'll ride
the water but then they they settle on
the half slabs and the water slowly
pushes them with a lot of friction and
it takes a long time for it to drop so
we can make a quick target or slow
targets it's a little glitchy at the end
though but then it falls down and we can
drop it on a pressure plate or through
tripwire and maybe into a recycler if we
want to do that if we don't do the
recycler thing we can have a comparator
on one of these hoppers and then we're
free to cover this up and then that can
power redstone lamps or whatever when
the lamp goes off that means there's
like between 0 and 15 or whatever boats
left in the system and we got to refill
it so it would be a good indicator light
yeah I think this is a good good idea
should be fun
I don't know when we're going to do it
I'm still focusing on Wilson but it's
going to be a lot of terraforming if we
do it it'll be a good mix of like
redstone
own in terraforming and decorating will
probably do other stuff in the thing too
like have little structures just for
looks as well and that sort of thing
well that's going to be about it for
today everyone but I did pick out the
comment as usual and this is what it
says
ESO do you keep your video files of the
videos you upload if you do where do you
keep them on hard drive and then you
move them to an external hard drive or
online storage after a while do you know
what other people do differently good
question good question I do have a
backup of every single video I've
uploaded to date so far it does take a
bit of storage I might need to get
another hard drive soon I'm not sure if
I want to keep doing it but I have it a
2 gigabyte no not to you buy 2 terabyte
external hard drive I have a bunch of
videos on that and I also have my main
hard drive here which is also 2
terabytes I believe for 1.5 and I have
some videos on both just in case one of
them fails I'll I'll be able to have it
still and then of course videos are
backed up on YouTube itself in case I
need to grab it from there for some
reason although it would be lower
quality so if for some reason my channel
gets closed down or I accidentally
delete all my videos it's possible for
me to make a new channel and re-upload
everything again that's why I've been
saving it because otherwise that would
be a devastating loss to me if for some
reason it happened I've talked to other
people about it and I know like you
asked what other people do differently I
know quite a few people actually delete
they're the originals just because they
take a lot of space that's one of the
advantages of me not doing HD is my
backups were a lot smaller now they're
going to be bigger so you might need to
get more hard drives or start deleting
stuff I'm not sure
but yeah good question good question
thanks for watching everyone I will see
you again next time
I might have a new series coming out
none
that's not minecraft I've been trying to
get this old game working it's like 15
years old and trying to get it to record
I got it working fine I just can't
record it because it's so old but I
think I know how to now there's a patch
for it but yeah I think you guys will
like it when it comes out if I do it
just a little little prep for you to
know it's coming but yeah take care guys
have a good day bye bye