hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another glorious episode
today is gonna be full of glory guys
lots of glory glory all over the place
so I've been I just loaded up the 14 w
26 B snapshot and I've been checking it
out just came out today and it's a bug
fix one so I I wanted to see if the
world was stable now it loads up without
crashing which is a good sign and I've
taken a look around and yeah things
things seem pretty good actually there's
a few new features released as well just
a couple minor things but yeah I think
we should I think we should go check out
the ocean dungeons today what do you
guys think sound like a good plan well
no it's a terrible plan no there's still
a couple issues with this this snapshot
so I think we're going to wait at least
another week before we do that red
stones behaving a little weird okay stop
stop please oh no stop stop
I can't stop it
Oh God this I stopped your last time
there we go okay we're good whoo
Symes are spawning again which is good
lighting bugs I had in here seemed to be
fixed like for a while now and a few of
the snapshots there's been lighting
errors and with the latest ones they
seem to be fixed in this room a few
things look a bit darker than they
should though like these this nether
warts and yeah it's close to ready but
not quite ready so I think we will
downgrade yet again and do some other
stuff there's like some block ID stuff
going on oh I thought it was a chicken
jockey I just not like this is a
different mushroom block than it should
be I've noticed as well today just like
trying things out mobs have very
different knock-back for some reason in
this latest one it's almost like floaty
like look at this you see that it's like
I don't know it's interesting anyway so
let's let's downgrade and we will go do
some stuff all right guys so we are back
in 21b I loaded my my back up here and I
am totally out of ender pearls so just I
thought I'd show the Enderman farm again
it's been a while I don't know why but
they keep playing as soon as one of them
gets free they try to go down these
ladders for some reason it's like they
liked it down in this room let's let's
do this sorry if I hope if I have my
looting sword selected they drop tons
and er pearls I tried it without I only
got ten ender pearls from them if I have
it selected though I get like six or
seven stacks each time which is pretty
cool
let's see what we ended up with yeah
four five six seven eight nine oh okay
I'm not very good counter just out at
URI ah s'ti I want to see what happens
if I do let them loose it seems like
they were pathfinding that one spot yeah
look they like to go down the ladders
will they all do it this is a terrible
idea by the way I'm going to get killed
let's make a few more holes well guy I
did not want to look at you was so weird
they're fighting to get down the ladders
alright anyway so I'm going to get a few
more ender pearls here and we will
probably head over to the amplified
drain and do some work there oh man oh
man oh man what is he
he said he's oh man they had an accident
and they're conjoined twins now or
something you the poor chicken look so
funny
ah I was just uh I was just taking a
look at this thing I think we might set
this up officially today that the
chicken farm thing and this guy came out
of nowhere
oh yeah beards
oh no no dougie
it's okay it's okay he didn't mean it or
did he uh he forgave them so here we are
again everyone and last episode I'm not
really sure why but I had this
inspiration to do a bunch of
terraforming here and we made this pit
and it might have seemed really random
and like why is etho making a pit that's
that's dumb sometimes sometimes when I'm
recording these episodes I actually I
have a plan I like playing chess I think
four or five turns ahead of myself now
um so the reason why I dug this is I
thought this would be a good thing to
Center the chicken farm on so at the top
of this mountain here is where I'm going
to put that machine that shoots the eggs
and creates the chickens and then we
will be able to see them float down as
we pass by this pit like as we're
walking by every so often just randomly
we will see a baby chicken fall down and
very slowly sink down there and then I
don't know what we're doing at the
bottom of that yet but I'm guessing it's
going to involve like ocelots and
chickens and like lions being let out of
their den to kill kill the chickens for
sort of thing every so often but we will
worry about that more later
so let me I'm going to set it up off
camera since I showed it already and we
will continue and here it is everybody
it's all set up seems to be working okay
so cool now I I have to just try I want
to see what it does this is a stupid
idea but whew oh man oh man oh alright
cool so I'm gonna get some chicken eggs
together and we will see what kind of
trajectory they take when they get
launched out of there the items move
farther than then entities dues like the
mobs will the chickens will so we got to
try with them specifically oh yeah and I
decided not to put it on top of the
mountain by the way I put it over there
instead the reason for that is I checked
and the top of the mountain was over 64
blocks away from from down there and you
cannot see like cows and chickens in
that if there are 64 blocks away from
you so you wouldn't be able to see them
Denny launched here which I kind of want
so that's why we have it down lower and
I would like to kind of just make it as
small about
opening as we can do over here so we'll
try close it up little by little here
dinner eggs in this is all the eggs I
brought so Oh chickens already okay in
close a little bit more
that's three by three is probably good
enough whoo-hoo okay that's good
I'm had chickens for days let's go down
make sure it's all it's all good
oh they're so cool oh no we can't see
chickens
why can't you see chickens wait a minute
you can't see baby chickens from 64
blocks away I just not they have a
shorter range then maybe I did that test
wrong I went to a creative world and
flew above it like a sheep or something
you had cows n' and cheaper different
that definitely different I don't know
if chickens have a shorter range but
baby chickens definitely do huh well
then maybe we will lower it even more
because I do want to see them getting
launched out of there I was watching
that video and I was tapped out The
Creeper got me so I moved it from about
there to over here now it's it's a lot
closer to the pits we should be able to
see them at this range so let's try it
out just to make sure put a few all
right let's not fall down I just want to
make sure we can see them getting
launched Oh No still can't see them why
is that
that is really weird I thought for sure
we would be able to see him now it's
almost like it doesn't want to render
them right when they get launched for
some reason still going yet still going
oh oh the poor chickens are taking
damage
well darn what do we do now so I guess
I'm just going to put the the chickens
in here and they will randomly drop eggs
over time and we will randomly get baby
chickens falling down and we will
revisit this again later though because
I I do want to do more with this this
idea this is not it but I don't want to
I want to spend the whole episode on
this either trying to do the slow so the
way don't rock him out whoa that was it
that was a quad oh man I'm getting so
many quads lately it's amazing
all right that's probably good oh don't
look don't look everybody all right
everybody so next up we are going to be
checking out my building plan for this
area which I'm not too confident about
as you know I'm not a very confident
with my building skills but this is my
plan this is what we're going to do so I
have a really hard time just building
something from scratch it's it's not it
usually doesn't turn out well um so I'm
going to be doing like these wireframe
setups before I do a build that way I
have like I can I didn't put random
shapes together like this that's
something I can do for sure and then
from that I can tell like what what I
like with the shapes like I'd make sure
there's depth to it I can make sure
there's varying Heights and and whatnot
and if you do that usually get a pretty
cool in-depth building with if you have
a lot of shapes to it
now the actual building theme is going
to be possibly
it possibly a disaster I had this idea
today that we would try n stone and
let's just see what it looks like here
okay so the N stone would be sort of the
back color because I don't want just
great the thing about just gray is it
doesn't look very good from a distance
so if we have a color mixed in with it
that would be awesome so I want to try n
stone and stone looks good with green
colors as well I find it also looks
really good with that new prism whatever
their Brisbane or whatever the new
blocks it looks pretty good with that
stuff too
what am I looking for there we go we got
our leaves on us yes okay so somehow
this will be like the background to the
builds we got to put stone in front of
that runic stone because we're kind of
doing a root ruin theme right umm stone
goes pretty good with n stone I would
say and just like somehow I don't know
break it up enough that it looks good
and then have like little bits of this
showing in places and then dress it up
with leaves afterwards we're going to be
using jungle leaves I saw this really
cool thing in some of that inspiration
stuff you guys sent me and one of the
things that was sent to me somebody had
jungle leaves mixed with birch leaves
and oak leaves and it just looked really
really cool so I think we'll be doing
that a fair bit oops now to do it those
might be a bit painful but yeah just the
three different types when you see it on
a large steel it looks really cool um
and yeah it looks pretty good with n
stone I would say oh but to do runic
stone stuff is what I'm gonna have the
most trouble with I haven't I have no
experience with that thankfully we're in
a forest biome though
the green actually looks pretty decent
oh yeah and if we want to use wooden
places I find spruce wood looks really
nice with n stone as well and we could
even use slime blocks in places if we
want if I ever get mycelium it that
looks really nice with n stone if I go
on and change it up in areas so it's not
always green grass around yeah so I
think we'll have a lot of options with
this and hopefully we can come up with
something that looks cool okay so this
is my first attempt on the actual
structure and not going so well this is
way too random we need we need more
order to it okay so what is this what's
going on here this is my attempt at
making an actual method or technique to
my building style I'm not just going to
place random blocks and hope it turns
out good this will give it a bit more
order because you can see what I'm doing
here is I'm giving it a structure to the
building and then I'm in regular
intervals revealing pieces of the end
the end stone every so often and not not
always in the same shape the way I say
there's two ways we could do this we
could either have a like real order like
like pillars every few blocks and then
try to deteriorate those or we could do
something like this where it's pretty
chaotic and this I think I will find
easier to do actually this almost looks
like it's peeling in places like a bunch
of blocks fell off here and here and
here this is not the final version
though this is just like the first pass
I just want to get the shape of the the
ruins in mind and now I'm going to go
over it again with the other blocks and
give it a lot more detail so what I've
found so far is we can't have a lot of a
lot of different types of block so we
have to narrow it down and maybe change
it up in different places to use these
other ones but like if I'm to choose
between this and this these two don't
actually go
together all that well I find and I like
this one more because it's more green so
I'm not going to be using this mossy
stuff I do really like the cracked stone
though so we'll probably be using that
cobblestone is great as always
chiseled should we try chiseled maybe in
a few places that would look good and
then of course we got to use the stairs
and half slabs Oh
but anyway let me try this again I'm
going to do the second pass on this and
let's see what it looks like and here we
have it after some detailing so it still
has the same basic patches in it right
but we have stairs and slabs mixed in we
have the cracked and the mossy mixed in
and it gives a pretty random ish and
chaotic looking structure but it still
has structure to it like you can see I'm
creating a flow from the bottom here all
the way to the top so it's almost like
it's a pillar of strength there and you
know there there is a some logic to it
but I feel I don't know if I'm gonna I'm
gonna keep it like this what do you guys
think
I almost feel it's still too chaotic
like there's blocks all over the place
maybe that's not weighted the way to do
it maybe we should set some further
rules like mossy must be near the ground
or um maybe a special type of decay to
it like from most the Kate the least
decay I would say it goes cobble maybe
we set a rule that we can only have
mossy if it's by cobble and then it
would go cracks I feel is less decayed
then then that and then finally not
decayed would be that so we may want to
try that like to have specific patches
of the J and then keep that flow to it
might make it look better might be
difficult to do those well but I'm going
to go through this and stand to see what
it looks
after I add the leaves and stuff also I
will say something else here areas like
this where there is a big cluster of
stone together especially near the
ground like this I want to add further
depth to it like maybe I would do
something like this here and just create
little extra pieces of 3d depth you know
that I find is the secret to making
things look better I'm not a good
builder but I do understand some
technique to it like having lots of 3d
depth is really important it gives all
kinds of shadows and stuff and if you
can find places like right now we
basically have two layers we have this
front one and then we have that end
stone behind it which is good but if we
can add even more to that and bring it
out further all the better and that's
also why leaves are awesome because they
give a lot of depth as we can see here
so this is basically the run-through of
making the structures if we go through
with this plan I want you guys feedback
what you think does it need more or less
of something like more leaves less
leaves more order less order you know
kind of the different points we touched
on today I want your feedback so this is
it with the leaves and you can see I got
the three different types of the leaves
mixed in there's lots of variety to it
and that's why it looks so organic and I
also have flowers we add grass we add
vines I'm considering also using the
spruce planks for the the ground the
pass you know that actually looks pretty
cool and try to keep it organic as well
like just random ins and outs to it
raised areas lowered areas I think that
would look pretty cool um but yeah let
me know what you think again I'm trying
to develop a technique so when it comes
to building if I know the order to do
things it'll actually be really easy for
me and I can I can big I can build
structures all
over the place I got the wireframe thing
figured out I got the colors figured out
like that's the order of development all
figured out basically here so it's it's
pretty easy actually yeah anyway that is
it that's that's where I'm going to
leave it here until I get your feedback
and then later we will be able to build
and as as we do things of course we'll
have redstone devices mixed in
throughout and those will be sort of the
focus points okay one more thing here
before we move on I just realized I made
a mistake with the leaves here so
whenever you're building something it's
also really important to every so often
just take a step back look at it look at
how it's going maybe imagine how you
want it to to flow and all that you want
to check it from a distance as well as
important things with a lot of detail
that are very chaotic generally don't
look as good from a distance unless they
have some flow to it like these leaves
give it a lot of flow there's a lot of
order to them because they're basically
all the same color and you can see a
pattern to it that way from a distance
I'm saying with the the blotches a
yellow there and it would look better if
from a distance if I didn't have all
this chaotic cobble mixed in with the
stone if it was more like groups of
stone with groups of cobble it would
look better I think but the big mistake
I want to point out looks pretty good
from this angle the thing that doesn't
look so good is from this angle here we
got these big patches of end stone
totally exposed like that I need to move
the leaves a little closer to them
because when it's like this you don't
have the depths anymore the leaves
aren't in front of them which doesn't
look as good compared to over here which
from this angle this these leaves here
just happened to go in front of it
actually a little bit scared of this
door now Oh
all right these are the lighting errors
I was talking about earlier too by the
way they seem to be fixed in the latest
snapshot which is great but anyway here
is the comments for today I picked out
two first one says a etho how do you
come up with title names do you find it
difficult oh my is so difficult title
names descriptions and video tags are
the bane of YouTube for me it is so
difficult I many times now I actually
find I use the same title and just
before I release it I'm like you know
this seems familiar right then I do a
search and like oh yeah 100 episodes ago
I used that title and it's like okay how
do I come up with another different
title that explains basically the same
thing I did in this episode um yeah
like for example episode 2 of my was the
episode 2 I think it was of my let's
play series was called mob farms and
I've made at least one more mob farm
since then so I have to be more
descriptive and I've made more than one
of like blaze farms and whatever so it
does get a little bit complicated
today was easy because we had a focus
thing we were doing but a lot of
episodes I do a lot of random things as
well small little things all over the
place and then it's like well what did I
pick for for a title we did lots of
stuff today not a lot of focus
so yeah it's challenging it's definitely
challenging how do I come up with them I
don't know I I struggle anyway citing
comments says I don't know etho I'm not
really feeling the new base maybe
returned to the old base every now and
then so we will be returning here and
we'll be doing projects here as well
I've been really pushing the new base
because I want it to get it going get it
on its on its feet basically so that
when we do stuff there people will enjoy
it I think not everybody's going to like
it right now honestly a lot of people
didn't like the main
to here when I first started it either
it's not until it starts to get some
actual structure to it when we get a
theme developed which we really focused
on today when the development actually
starts then I think people are going to
start liking it more right now we're
still in the early stages so hopefully
you guys like it more as we continue
anyway not not to say lots of people
don't like it currently we've been
having fun there too of course but
anyway that's it for today guys I hope
you enjoyed and I will see you in the
next one bye bye