okay okay I see how it is I see how it
is you want me to speak first is that
what we're doing here you want me to
speak first you know just once I thought
maybe just once you guys would introduce
episode but it's okay it's okay I don't
mind it's what I do I don't mind this is
Ethel plays minecraft I am etho I'm
playing Minecraft I got shot in the face
twice okay maybe not
those look a little lower than I thought
they were yeah so here we are guys I
don't know if she can tell but I'm
actually kind of sick today and yeah my
I got like a sore throat it's kind of
bugging me I kind of hoping you guys
would speak for a change but no that's
not how this gene that's not that's not
how our relationship works is it I have
to speak I have to do all the talking
you're good at texting though like don't
get me wrong you got the text and
covered you you you talk in the comments
very wonderfully more than I do in fact
but yeah I think I have to do the
speaking so
let's head on down to the cave and that
here's the dumb thing okay so like two
days ago I was tucked in to be the low
in generic be on skype and I was kind of
teasing them because they get sick a lot
like especially recently they've they've
been sick a lot and I kind of pointed
that out to them and then be down low
says oh you now you've done it or
something like that like cuz that was
weird
because you guys remember back is a long
time we're like episode 80 or something
I talked about how I never get sick and
then of course the very next episode I
got sick and then veto laws basically
said you know what you're gonna get sick
now cuz you talked about how you hardly
get sick so of course two days later not
feeling the best but oh wow it's nothing
serious it's not too big of a deal I'm
sure it will pass soon but yeah we are
down here in the cave just doing some
minor minor things out off we'll keep
these we'll just try it out
got a little path on the right here I
don't want anything too big this is the
river we built last episode by the way
I'll probably have to do something here
make this come out a bit more just doing
some minor touch-ups till we get it
going we'll get some grass along here
we're not gonna really work on this so
today we're gonna do some other stuff oh
yeah I updated it off to fix that later
okay I better not grow this grass and
that was good thing I didn't do it up
here that wood it is wrecked everything
I think I can do one here the rest I'll
manually place so why would it that's
weird it updates the grass block itself
not like on top of it with the actual
grass block itself get a couple of these
that didn't update it good I was a
little worried I get a couple of those
down maybe put a tree here for future
yeah anyway let's get out of here it's
good to do something today is I'm going
to mostly focus on touch-ups around the
cave probably we might do a little bit
of exploring I'm not sure because it
kind of goes along with one of my plants
actually you know what I've always
wanted to try with these guys and by
always I mean like since today I've
never tried just taking the water away
and see what they do like how crazy they
get because then they can jump that's
not too crazy I thought it would be like
this awesome show but it's not a big
deal all right back it goes what about
these guys I can't do it
yeah so what I kind of want to do is
work over here a little bit to start off
with we really need to touch up this
area it's been this way forever and just
start off with I think I'm gonna put
some leaves behind here and then some
fences in fronts or like we did at the
mushroom farm give that a little bit of
a touch up there's really not much space
that we need to fill over here to
complete this wall so not doing anything
major this wall this lower part is okay
but everything above that line there we
need to kind of fine-tune and then on
this wall see what this thing originally
was was like a cow chute to get mobs
down here if we ever need to get more
cows down I have this thing that goes up
to the surface and then there's a water
drop we have a new chicken farm
so their service is no longer needed
sorry guys but what are you gonna do man
feels wrong they've been with me for so
long
it's alright alright so yeah this goes
all the way up to the surface we don't
really need this here though I don't
think although we can leave it what I
want to do we got - we gotta fill that
space with something and I've asked
about this before in the past and the
common thing people recommend it is I do
some pixel art like a sheep face or a
chicken face or something like that to
go along with our cow face but this
isn't really you know sheep farm or a
big firm or anything like that one idea
I had though is maybe let's get some
maps going on here like a big map of my
worlds and try Center that on the wall
and then we'll put a frame around it
like we have with this and just see what
that looks like
so maybe the center of the wall is right
there where this fence is so that would
be up around there maybe if we think as
it's cut off here maybe we will try hmm
no we could probably put something there
let's put like a seven by seven big map
of our world there maybe I'll start
laying it out and see how it goes
they hop faster well it's hard to tell
that is scary how does a scary sight
this is probably not my brightest of
ideas and yet I still want to try it so
here we go let's just see what happens
I'm wondering if I can like anger him oh
right right oh yeah okay that doesn't
work because monsters are nearby
all right that was a quick test and
let's get back to work
all right this works pretty good
actually uh I said I was gonna do a
seven by seven array of maps but this is
a seven by five and that's a pretty good
dimension I would say I think we'll do
the glowstone thing and trapdoor at the
waffles just to mimic the cow and then
we'll have our maps there and the center
is gonna be here basically where this
cow farm is and we're gonna do the high
detailed map let's go down I gathered
some materials to do this so I got my
fences I put down one block here and all
the towels went to the other side really
quick so no cows on the side which is
fine makes it a little easier to work
here I just want to do this I think very
simple
due to its framerate issues and then
what we'll do is replace most of this
plain stone with the stone brick like we
have around the border there and yeah
we're doing fences pretty sure I really
like that look having leaves and then
fences in front or iron bars or
something
okay how's that might have to break it
up some more but let's just see what it
looks like from up here and now that's
we don't really need this drop chute I
probably put a ladder that goes up to
the UFO as well instead of just like an
enderpearl root up because I don't
really use it I find because I don't
know how to get up I think I think the
way I have it right now I have two ender
pearl up they do this oh yeah and that
doesn't work too well does it right
we're gonna look at this don't die let's
look at it from different angles yeah
you can still see the water that's
interesting that's not too bad the
fences look a bit strange oh yeah we
should change it a bit we won't worry
too much about though I'm gonna work on
this some more I broke up the fence by
putting a split there in the middle but
even then it looked a little strange so
I'm trying these cobblestone fences and
I know the choice is between that and
that and I think I like that more
although I'm not sure I like the mossy
now the choice is between the mossy and
the cobble fence and guess which one I
like I like that one more the plain one
that one seems a little strange not
gonna lie one more thing to try here I'd
put iron bars so it's between iron bars
and the cobble fences and I am going to
choose don't actually know yet let me
think about it
very bad at making simple decisions uh I
think I'm gonna go with the cobble yeah
although we might do something different
if you guys have ideas what I should do
with that spot let me know but otherwise
I think we'll just do full cobble and I
started setting up our our giant map
over here
it looks a little strange because of the
stone brick and also there's no actual
maps in it yet so it's all it's all
planes so we will work on that as well I
think for the background let's just try
this out although there will be like the
colors are going to change once I
actually put the maps in but probably
will use either planks normal planks
because that makes a good background for
these item frames the other other idea I
had is maybe jungle planks or birch
planks let's try both of these and see
which works better or even even soil
might look good because it's a pretty
close color let's just try a few of
these okay so that's see that's really
close to the border color so that isn't
too bad either
and then we have these which is closer
to the the mat color and then soil
hmmm I think I think this one might be
the best actually just because it
matches the same color as the frame yeah
yeah I think we made the right choice
here that's the winner really hides the
borders around the item frames nicely
and it seems to it it'll help make all
the maps join together better I am
tempted to change this wood and get rid
of these waffles but today I will leave
it like that for now I will see what you
guys say in the comments I saw it right
at posts other day actually someone made
or changed his team so the item frames
joined together sort of when there's
maps in them that looked pretty cool but
we'll see how it goes once we start
putting them in hopefully it's hopefully
joined together pretty decent so now on
this side what we'll do we won't do it
all today but instead of having like we
used to have water elevators here to go
down low and to get up
we might actually put in a staircase
back here somewhere to go up and down go
all the way to the end here and we're
gonna put
oh that is not a good thing that is
never a good thing I hope I never go
sign whoops that's another thing I want
to work on soon is that Spyder firm
thing that could use an update as well
but yeah we'll do change this and then
we'll put some wood planks here all the
noises man I'm so sorry so sorry but
there's nothing I can do about it I have
to live with that you know it's terrible
ah but yeah we'll have planks and then
we'll do a fence again one level above
on that side we used upside down stairs
decided we're just using full planks
like that let's see what that looks like
Oh Oh actually you know what we'll get
rid of this then we'll have to work on a
room for over here and decide a purpose
for it as well oh oh I did it again
darn it was that serious I don't think
that was serious let's put that back
like it never happened
yeah we're gonna put you know these on
top as well okay let's just step back
and see what get going on yeah okay it's
something it's a start to start to
something what we should do I'm gonna
try out the maps
truth be told naps are one of the least
or one of the things I've used the least
in the in this game I've only crafted
like three Maps total since they've come
out so yeah I actually forgot the recipe
I have to look it up I thought it was a
compass and and like four pieces of
paper but it's eight pieces of paper
see so we'll make a few compass compass
says we will need what is it a whole ton
of a whole ton of of naps here won't we
it's gonna get pricey because you need
one compass per map right or can we
I wonder can we clone like an empty map
with just paper cuz I know you can clone
maps now that I have paper please tell
me at paper I bet you there's some over
here ah perfect
you're doing a fine job keep up the good
work
unlike Jeff in there take crafting table
let's just try this out now the other
thing I'm not really sure is
I read you have to right click to
activate the map let's let's test up
this cloning would be really weird if
you could do this but maybe you can know
so you can't clone an empty map that's
good but I think you have to right click
to activate it so let's do I'm hoping my
position doesn't matter too much here
like I said I don't have much experience
with maps okay so I think I created its
map numbers here hope never made a map
here Oh does it load the whole thing oh
that looks so cool you can see the
snowflake oh you know I thought I had to
explore it all oh maybe this will be
really easy okay and yeah our player you
see our player positions over there so
we're not in the center of or create we
created it so it's I think it's every
128 blocks what is I'm wondering what
this is up here I can't figure that out
oh that's for I dug some holes to get
villagers down into into our city here
that's what that's from cool so I'm
gonna well let's let's put this in just
get one in anyway oh that was weird
now I'll have to be careful not to enter
peril to this spot because odd thing cuz
if I hit an item frame or if I'm
careless this is my last ender pearl oh
boy
okay I'm gonna make that one town if I'm
careless I'll knock the item frames
right off the wall awesome sweets so
that's our first one I'm gonna make a
bunch more here and try to piece them
together I'm really low on health Oh
does it flicker please tell me it
doesn't flicker no odd flickers don't
like that hmm well I went out and got a
few more maps done I have six total
there and they are all flickering I
don't know like do you think that's a
bug that's gonna get fixed I'm not sure
to be honest and it's not like the item
frames are are being drawn in front of
it or anything like that it's the map
itself is not getting drawn properly
depending it seems to depend how close
you are if you're close it never
flickers but if you're far away it does
depending on what angle you're looking
at you'll see difference like if I'm not
moving it doesn't flicker but if I move
it keeps changing
uh-huh so with that in mind what do you
guys think I should do should we keep
that hit there or should we think of
putting something else there and maybe
just move the maps somewhere I can look
at them closely because as long as I'm
close to them they're fine and it looks
awesome but yeah it's an idea overall
though we got some stuff done here which
is good I guess
yeah comment ready or two and we will
call it an end for today my voice is
starting to give out so we should end
this all right here's the question for
today it's kind of a personal question
but I don't mind answering its he says
yo hey did you get any competitions and
I T internet technologies and arts also
what subjects did you take I'm English
so subjects mean means classes Thanks I
did not take Internet technologies or
arts in school I also never went to
university or college or post-secondary
education of any sort so I'm purely high
school graduates as far as what courses
I took in high school is of course the
core subjects that you have to take like
like English social math science that
sort of thing and as far as options go
like the courses I actually chose I took
chemistry
what was it chemistry ten twenty and
thirty I believe and I took let's see
what else did I take I took a bunch of
life skill management courses like you
know how to keep a budget it's how to do
taxes that kind of stuff and then a big
bulk of my extra classes came from or
extra credits here in Canada you need
where you did need at least when I went
to school you needed one
credits to graduate along with a few
other specific qualifications and 35 of
my credits out of the hundred came from
work experience so I did that for grades
10 11 and 12 I think it was how'd that
work out I can't remember how that
worked out I think it was like 10
credits when you're attending to another
and then 15 maybe I don't know I forget
but yeah pretty pretty basic education
actually but it serves me well I don't
really need to be smart to play video
games I find just I don't know if I need
if I need more education for a job I'm
looking for in the future I will
possibly take secondary education or
post-secondary education for a specific
job if I'm looking for one otherwise
that I'm not too worried about it to be
honest but that's just me
you do what you want to do but yeah
that's that's all for today thank you
for watching everyone I I need a hot
beverage clear my throat here so I'll
see you guys again next time
you