hello everyone this is Ito and hello to
you too good fine sir
how are you today oh he doesn't want to
talk welcome we are in the nether at the
moment I'm doing a little exploring I
have been looking for nether quartz
there's a lot of zombie pigmen around
here holy smokes looking for another
quartz for that lab project this is
about the border where it starts to show
up in my world we're about a thousand
blocks out there's none over here but
then it's starting to show up if we go
further this way but the thing I really
want to show you check this thing out
unreal this has got to be the biggest
most enormous vein of glowstone I have
ever seen in the nether like I am
guessing that's almost two stacks it's
just insane I'm gonna mine it up and and
see what it is I compare that one to
that one and that one's a pretty big
vein on its own but that one insane
alright I had 19 glowstone before I
started mining that I have 154 here so -
19 135 135 is the number to beat guys
I'm entering it into the Guinness Book
of Records see if he can top that
alright it's back home here's how we did
on that run it was pretty good
we got one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven twelve stacks of
courts pretty much I did harvest some
for XP already so this should keep us
going for the day I would think I also
went on another caving run just a quick
one I got five stacks of redstone from
that we'll need a lot of redstone for
our lab we're building ethos lab today
some more hopefully get that up and
running show you guys how it works I
also want to work on the look of it a
little bit so see what what did I want
to do with that do we have any I saw
this thing on reddit someone mixed it
was light blue clay what did i do there
I think it was light blue maybe it was
blue as well let's try that and make a
bunch of that also 30 levels let's get a
pic going I have been reduced to eating
melons again I do actually have bread
maybe I should use bread today my plan
was sort of to have that gold farm
running by now and I was going to start
eating golden carrots for good instead
of like steak but haven't gotten that
far with it yet it is getting close to
done let's see some chanting going but
yea golden carrots are a very good food
source if he can get them they just need
a lot of gold if you use them a lot they
have a high saturation value higher than
steak so when you eat a golden carrot it
lasts for a long time before you have to
eat again what else yeah clay clay going
so I want to try mix quartz and I think
light blue will bring some regular blue
we might also want to try red red clay
see do we have any of that
not too much hmm bring some orange maybe
a little purple let's try all the colors
I have any red flowers red dye yes we do
okay let's make a little bit of this
we'll do four and four okay
I'm very excited to get this lab up and
running though because it's going to be
really cool to have all the potions you
could ever dream of
without really any effort on my part
they'll just always be there pretty much
okay what are we going to get running
very low on worked picks actually so I
wouldn't mind just efficiency for
unbreaking it's good to cool let's go
get some more food really quick here oh
good old melons alright and let's head
on over to the lab I think we got
everything we need so I want to work on
the looks of it a bit today and I want
to get up and running if we can do -
alright here we are
so somebody on reddit they had like
quartz pillars and the walls were blue
it looked really really nice so we might
try to adopt that look for this it was
kind of like this except they use actual
quartz pillar blocks but those two
colors together pretty cool there
example looked a lot better than mine
here just cuz I put this together real
quick but maybe for the floor like we
got this five block wide floor we want
to work with maybe let's I got two
suggestions really like two main
suggestions use clay on the floor or
else
maybe color-code each station here with
the specific color for the potion like I
did my other potion room like maybe for
healing potions have red on the side if
this was the side that made healing
potions and if this was speed potions
use light blue stripe like all the way
along here so we might do it that way or
we might just keep a blue theme
throughout the whole lab let's just try
this out did I make the deep blue I did
okay I do like those two colors together
yeah okay another idea is to have ice in
the middle could be cool you could put
something underneath the ground that way
something to look at and also you could
run and jump on it quickly let's try
blue here what do we think of that that
is pretty cool I'm guessing I should
maybe put the dark on the edges so
instead of in the middle the hunter
becomes the hunted in this exciting
conclusion - there is that creeper
because running away did you see that
you knew it was coming um I do like this
quite a bit we're gonna try a few
different things so I'm gonna clip or
cut away and try with ice and with wool
and with different colors and stuff
we'll figure out what we like the most
one thing you will notice though it is a
little dark in the middle goes down to
block lighting eight and I think that's
coming from a block up so it's actually
seven so in the middle stuff could
probably spawn so we want to get more
lighting in here and with my design I
think there's a room for one block we
can hide there so let's put a piece of
glowstone that will increase the
lighting around here
just a little bit if we do that for all
of these course want to cover it up it's
a little darker I think oh maybe not I
thought it would wait a second nine
eight nine mmm it's the same 14 13 12 15
14 should be to lighter shouldn't it
I'll work on this for just a sec I'll
figure out the lighting all right so I
was able to get the light level one
higher it turns out I had torches behind
the broom stand there so I just replaced
the torches with glowstone glow stones
one light level higher than the torch so
that's about as best as we can do
because all this stuff here is critical
we can't move that we could hide it in
the floor if we wanted more lighting or
in the ceiling but that's I think this
is OK mobs won't spawn at this level so
that's good with these with these like
panels these quartz panels they are a
little plain I find so I was messing
around with maybe changing the bottom I
have chiseled quartz at the bottom on
this one I got the pillars facing
towards us on this one just trying to
add a little more texture to it
and this is a sideways pillar could also
do a vertical pillar I guess where did
that go
it's actually not bad I think either
this vertical or the chiseled is the
best
I almost feel I need some of that on the
top part of this to bounce out the look
though but what we won't worry about it
too much I'm going to mess with the the
floor a bit here show you a few
different things I try first step let's
switch the dark to the outside the light
to the inside uh-huh-huh-huh
alright so after much careful
deliberation with my highly trained team
of villager decorators we have decided
this is the look to go with yep very
wise choice I'm going to get the
redstone on some of this stuff working
so I can show you how the potion brewing
is going to work - and as far as the
color coding idea goes it's a nice idea
but I'm going to use item frames with
the proper potion type in them to
identify what potion gets made where and
we might also use signs so it'll be
clearly labeled and easy to figure out
what's what's what around here alright
everyone well things are going well I've
been working on the redstone and at this
point in the project I'm just winging it
I haven't figured it out to this point
so from here out things can go wrong and
they probably will but I'll run you
through what we got
so I've added this little device here
these lights tell me if we are out of
water bottles in the system and I've
also added a bunch of like buffer chests
at the top here to hold water bottles I
knew you were around here
I heard you wait is there another one I
heard the arrow fall no okay we have
three double chests to hold water
bottles so that's that's going to make
quite a few potions we could go as as
many as we want but I think that's good
and I have them sort of sneaking around
in such a way that they have very little
space wasted here and I'm even using
trap chests for some of them so that I
can jam it all in so if we run out of
water bottles these lights turn on
there's none in the system at the moment
and what it is maybe let's take these
out I want that quartz back though thank
you
what it is you see there's a comparator
next to the hopper and that goes
directly to the brewing stand so water
bottles go in here and then they wait to
get put into the brewing stand if we're
out of water bottles this hopper is
going to be empty this comparator is
going to be off oh and I have a I have
an override switch there what I say if
these lights turn off and then then
we're out of water bottles that's that's
what I meant to say so we can
demonstrate this pretend we put a water
bottle in the system that light turned
on and that makes these Pistons to go
down as well
from this comparator or powers the
Pistons and that pushes this block into
place so that's power from this line can
pass through and that goes to the
droppers then for the left side I don't
really need to
do this like this is a gate to let the
redstone signal go through or not I
don't really need to do this the reason
I'm doing it though is because if we're
out of water bottles we don't need to
brew any potions anymore we don't need
to tell the system to to change your
redstone so that it's brewing potions it
won't cause any problems if it does that
but it does cause unnecessary leg
because it's activating all these
repeaters and and redstone torches every
cycle and if we're having like 10 of
these things or or I think it's even
more than 10 and you can imagine that's
a lot of unnecessary redstone updates
happening if we don't control things a
little bit and there's a manual override
here oh that didn't make that go down
that's not good okay um I'll have to
make a note of that so yeah if we one
way we're going to be able to refill the
water bottles for this is we could just
access this double chests and drop them
in here if we want that is not what it's
getting power from somewhere it's not
supposed to do
mmm-hmm slight technical problem like I
said things are going to go wrong for
some reason this chest it's supposed to
be dropping my floors all torn up I
can't really access things properly
let's rip this out this chest is
supposed to be dropping cobble or water
bottles into this hopper but it's being
powered Oh from that torch there okay
how big of an issue is that one moment
please
I diagnose the problem here this isn't
going to be an issue because the clock
is supposed to be running so it's going
to be switching on and off every 20
seconds where it will allow the water
bottles to pass through one problem I do
have here though is my data's reversed
here for some reason I messed that up
this is supposed to stop brewing potions
when I power it and it's it's allowing
potions be brewed when I power it so
I'll have to fix that but with the way
it is right now I can actually
demonstrate how it's going to work I
think let's see let's let's get it ready
let's fire it up take this one out okay
so the way I want to do this oh and
first of all I'm going to be rambling a
bit here just to warn you first of all I
just want to show you this this is
something I didn't know until just the
other day actually as you know you can
get hot you can get items into a chest
using a hopper no little problem but if
you have the chest blocks like where you
can't open it then the hopper also won't
put items into it I had no idea that is
new to me
I just never never knew that detail
about them so if you didn't know that
now you do which is kind of cool it's a
way you can control things a little
better but that is important to me in
this situation because darn I don't have
any glass we can use this because the
way I want to do the water bottle setup
for this I'm gonna have to put blocks
overtop the chests and I have to make
sure I use a block that will still allow
me to open the chests otherwise these
hoppers at the top here won't be able to
put stuff into them like if this is
blocked and I try to throw a water
bottle and it's not going to go through
so my plan will just demonstrate this up
very temporarily at the moment just to
show you my plan is oh yeah you can
still walk off of chess if you're
holding shift my plan is to set up a way
where I can go on top of this thing and
get some water going go on top above
these hoppers here and all I have to do
to fill the chests up of water bottles
that three double chests is get a couple
stacks of these potions hold shift and
right click and held it'll toss the
potions into the hoppers and the hoppers
will pick them up put it into the chest
that's pretty simple easy way to fill it
up the other option is of course like I
said I can just manually drop them in
from here but my thing needs to be
reversed and I have so much stuff um
like I said rambling just bear with me
for a second here
I'll get it together it's got so much
stuff going
on here all right this for right now I'm
going to switch this normally the clock
would allow that to switch on its own
alright so that opened up the gate so
that these water bottles and flow
through into the brewing stands and
they're being held there at the moment
all is good let's get a few more potions
going I wonder if some got stuck someone
I thought I'd through a lot more than
that in let's get a few more going we're
about to fire this thing up oh I hope in
and drop cobble in I probably did okay I
get a few more potions in don't know
which one I want them in we're only
going to turn one of these on not both
of them alright that's how you fill it
nice and simple nice and quick
won't have to be filled all that often
yeah I did drop cobble okay so down here
I have a clock that we're going to run
maybe we can disable this for just
straight now show you how it runs this
is a hopper timer it does two things it
sends one signal here that will go to
the middle line and that that reverses
the brewing stand so it'll either allow
potion bottles to go into the brew stand
or it'll take them out from the bottom
and then we have this other line here it
goes to a pulse extender and a
monostable circuit here that makes this
redstone signal go for exactly eight
ticks is the idea and that goes to this
pulsar which sends out four pulses to
the droppers every time this updates
all right lots of stuff going on I'm
going to take these out this running so
the magic number of blocks we want in
our hopper timer is what is it it's 56
this will make it run for 20 seconds
each interval which is really important
so get those in I'm going to get my
brewing ingredients in so first of all
awkward potions then we'll go
let's make strength potions we'll put
that to make it strength and then we'll
extend them wait
I'm missing another step here awkward
potion strength extended strength I
guess we could do splash potions for the
last one anyway so we'll do those three
and we'll get this up and running should
work the way it is even though I have to
fix a few things so let's get this moved
okay this is really really
nerve-wracking it might break everything
here we'll find out
so everything's reconnected oh those
potions we had in there are in the
droppers right now so there they're
being there waiting to go into this
brewing stand and since I left them in
for 20 seconds they should be awkward
potions so when we fire this up
everything should work I think
water bottles waiting to go in do two to
just give it a little bit of time 20
seconds per step takes 40 seconds to
brew 3 potions with this setup
ok so let's switch Oh where's my other
potions and on the hopper ok they are in
there somehow water bottle got through a
moment those finish brewing they get
pulled out they get put in the hopper
something is I bet you it's my stupid
gate here that's broken oh I didn't
connect this woops
oh no it was it was something's weird
here
that's pulsing oh it's because these are
torches and they can't handle that speed
that's or could they
man I thought I had it I thought it was
all good I don't think these torches are
flickering gotta wait ten more seconds
here let's see if they's nice which ones
that pulses next time doo doo doo doo
doo how's it goin
come on out did
and these aren't getting powered that's
for sure though why are they not named
powered shouldn't really have to switch
that but maybe it's about the pulse
again something here is not switching
this is either staying on or that torch
isn't changing that's what it is okay
this is this is pulsing here but this
torch is not changing and that's causing
the problem okay
usually I don't like my video so sloppy
but I know some of you like to watch me
do some problem solving and that when it
comes to redstone so you saw it today
yeah there's this weird quirk with
redstone where sometimes if you have a
very quick signal like a one tick signal
the redstone torch won't change because
it can't handle at that speed even
though the one earlier this one here was
changing and there's no difference in
delay speed this one wasn't so because
that one's seconds down the line this
one's first it can it can do the first
one but not the second one or any any
further down so yeah
redstone is fun uh my solution to that
problem is creates twice as long
pulse extension here we still have this
pulse ER but I'm using a repeater now to
take eight pulses from this because we
double the length so it's creating twice
as many pulses instead of four it's
doing eight and then this converts it
back down to four but they're two ticks
long instead of one tick yeah so now it
should all work
let's hope it's all complicated now but
once it's up and running it's going to
be so sweet
look at this we got awkward potions
going in they're going to convert to
strength water bottles are getting
convert to nether or to awkward
this goes for just long enough where
they can get converted and then they get
pulled out the bottom 20 seconds oh but
it's letting one extra through what's
that about man
another problem start it something's
wrong with my timing or something you
know what it is I had my redstone all
figured out before I started building
then I was like you know what I can make
it even thinner you make one block thin
only and I changed it to use all these
redstone torches and now things are all
messed up
see it's going to give it an extra one
isn't it Oh me or not that was fine at
sending out an extra awkward potion
every time and water bottles are getting
sent to that one I'll have to keep
working at this
the idea is though it's going to fill up
the chest at the end of the line
nothing's going to happen with this this
chest is going to get filled up and that
gets filled up this one's then get
filled up and that's filled up this will
get filled up and eventually it's going
to get to the point where no brewing can
happen and we will have each of these
chests full with a different potion that
we can take at any time and when we take
it out then it creates space so that
when we turn this back on it will refill
any empty spaces we create in the
storage engine Tori yeah man I'll fix it
don't you worry yeah so part way through
when I was building this I decided I
would change my design that I could make
it smaller this is my original layout
for some reason I decided I didn't need
these repeaters anymore that they
weren't really necessary so I changed it
to something like this which takes less
space but you can see we got five push
or five water bottles in there ready to
go into the brewing stand we flip it
changes the redstone alright they get
put in they waits then we when we flip
it again
we see a total of four potions got
through instead of just three because a
redstone torch has a one tick delay to
it so it takes one tick for four to
reach the power up to here to compensate
for that delay I was using repeaters
before where it bounced out where this
one would be two ticks and then this one
would be one plus one two ticks as well
so it would be equal and you can see
five potions
does the same thing fills that up but
this time only that's 3 potions through
and with my setup now I don't think
there's any way I can fix that exempts
redoing it all with my original redstone
and making it two blocks wider the
advantage of doing that is I can get rid
of a lot of these repeaters and redstone
torches with the old design the downsize
it downside is it takes a little bit
more space and I have to redo it which
will take more time but it will work
well it's that time again everyone end
of the episode time to read the comments
I do apologize I was hoping we get more
done today but we ran into a lot of
problems a lot of problems I we got it
figured out now just basically got to
use my old design I can take care of
that no problem but here is the comment
for today
heyy so I've been watching some of your
older videos and you sound very
different I was wondering why this is I
was thinking maybe you were nervous but
it even continues into your first couple
episodes on the minecraft server but
then I noticed you sound like you know
you normally do when you prank dude with
Doc I was just wondering why you think
you sounded different or if you can even
tell the difference there's definitely
the difference
between my older episodes and my newer
ones with the way I speak I wouldn't
really say it was because I was nervous
I didn't really have many people
watching back then sort of inexperienced
with recording I had my settings wrong
in the past I used to have the
microphone very close to my mouth and
the recording volume was a lot higher
that meant I couldn't really make loud
noises because it would make the volume
peak and it sounded terrible so I would
I would speak very softly and try not to
make the microphone peak because I was
worried and because of that I sounded
very monotone as well I still kind of do
that's just my voice but now I record
with microphone more down at my lower
chin I can speak a little more freely
and it's it sounds a lot better the
other thing is it is very unnatural to
talk to yourself or at least I find it
is so when I first started I wasn't very
comfortable speaking into the microphone
and to really express myself and it was
different when I was with good or not in
the prank videos because that's more
like normal speech here you're speaking
to someone and set it to yourself
although I'm I'm not really speaking to
myself it does kind of feel like that at
the time of recording it's a mental
issue you gotta get it yet get into your
head you're not talking to yourself
you're talking to people stinking slimes
but yeah that's it for today guys thank
you for watching I'll see you next time
you