check this out
there's a minecart in the mob system I
didn't put it in there I think it was
when we were doing the the junk
unloading tests with the minecarts
somehow it fell down off the track or
something I don't know that's crazy ah
welcome back everybody to another
episode of our let's play series how're
you doing today
I was trying to decide what we're gonna
do here and I just took a little walk
around we might end up doing some
smaller projects today I'm not sure like
there's a lot of little things in our
world like look at this for example that
needs some attention we do these big
projects quite often and then there's
all these little details that don't get
worked out later because that's just the
way I am so maybe we'll tackle a few of
those today such as this little issue
here so I've actually been afraid to
touch this because as soon as I break
this fence and and stuff there's a
chance I mess up somewhere and then
zombies are going to get into the
village and kill them all I don't know
you have to be really careful when you
start breaking torches and adjusting
things with your villages but maybe will
lay down some grass here put up a fence
here come make a couple changes front
make it look nicer alright it's very
cool guys so I just did a little bit
here I haven't even done much and it
already feels so much better but you got
a smooth transition now nice and open
here walk down into the village it's
pretty smooth there's an area like a big
area down there I'm going to leave a
fence here so you can view down there so
that if we ever do add something it
should look pretty cool and we might add
like a spiral staircase going down and
then to the right here to connect to
that if we if we expand out that way
eventually got a fence over here
look down there we should also can we
protect it a little bit better the
zombie could get over that easy let's
make this go up - oh I cannot I cannot
aim properly
it seems make that go up - there how's
that look sure why not and then let's do
a little something like that I guess
actually let's get rid of this totally
huh a little baby zombie will fit
through that no problem okay so I had an
idea like before we had a fence kind of
blocking zombies from getting into the
village over here we're going to try to
keep it open like it is right now what
I've got is a villager sort of a caught
over here and try move him back one more
without killing him uh he's going to be
like a villager sentry so if a zombie
should ever come down the stairs here
which they do occasionally and before
they reiden call my fence but they've
come down here I think they'll focus on
this guy first and that should protect
the rest of the villagers because they
won't be able to get them they'll just
stare at them and then if we put some
way of killing them like a magma block
down below there the other villagers
shouldn't walk down into here but the
zombies I think will as they try to get
the villager hopefully that's my thought
anyway I'm going to test that out so as
I come down the stairs here this feels
pretty cramped I'm gonna maybe open this
up like all this open up a big space
here maybe plant a little tree or
something that way it's not so
claustrophobic okay here we go guys I
finally got a zombie to spawn here I've
been waiting for this I'm gonna try to
get far enough away that he'll switch
targets and see if he goes after the
villager hopefully this works I've been
doing a little bit more building here
and see we got bushes and stuff is he
gonna make his way over here I can't get
too close so otherwise he's gonna go
after me but like he should see that
librarian before he sees me
um is he after me did you know he picked
a different villager now darn it
hey it's not working it's not working
all that sucks so he was after one of
these guys I guess when he switched he
didn't go after the closest target here
like I thought he would maybe I got a
because he's blocked off or let's just
get rid of let's just fill us in right
now oh here he comes here he comes
okay who's he gonna go after he's
deciding he went after the right one no
wait did he see me again
always going after always going after
the iron golem no who is he after Jeff
Ellis I think for me ah darn it he's
after Mia now I reloaded my game and
everything like reloaded the world so
that he'd lose lose me as his targets
but he seems to prefer me over the
villagers so I can't really test this
actually alright everybody so I think
we're about done with this now I get
finished up with the building and the
decorating and I even did the lighting
here you see I got rid of all the
torches so we hit lighting in the leaves
here I like to go one block below the
surface so you can see underneath this
leaf block is another leaf block and
then the glowstone I think that hides
the lighting a lot better otherwise it's
it's really easy to see it and as far as
this guy goes I'm gonna try it like this
like it seemed like the zombie was going
after him and then he saw me when I was
over there and then he switched targets
umm yeah we'll try it like this
and if I come back one day and all the
villagers are dead well then it's pretty
obvious it doesn't work like I want it
to and then we will have a problem but
yeah anyways so I think this looks
pretty decent to some random logs and
leaves and stuff I decided to use red
brick here for like the structural stuff
and he
the village here this used to be stone
brick I switched over to red brick just
that more color I think it looks good
and we will move on now to something
else let's do another little project oh
yeah they were they were getting back
like they were standing on the stone
block and then on the fence and then
falling here so I added one more fence
to hopefully stop there pathfinding from
doing that and if they try to walk here
they can't yeah that should be good now
so he goes down let's add a piece of
string here to sew this vine doesn't
grow there look better okay so next up
on our list guys we're gonna head over
to Wilson a long time ago I asked you
guys like what what would you add to
Wilson you told me and then I never did
so I haven't forgotten what you said
though so I today will do it here I got
the stuff ready to go okay and I'm going
to do one other thing here too or a
couple other things actually grab our
our goodies here yeah so I don't like
all the pink here with Wilson so I'm
going to get rid of the floor this pink
floor and try out the bone blocks nice
cheap alternate to quartz and we're
gonna try Heights and lighting in here
too so that's what I made the red glass
for let's see how this would look you do
yeah I think that'll be okay and can we
hide lighting here is my question so if
we put it like a sea lantern red glass
does that blend in enough yeah I think
we could get away with that otherwise I
got to have torches here somehow and
that's that's not going to look good
alright so there we go we got the floor
switched out to the boom box now I do
like that a lot more than the pink clay
still should probably add some texture
to it though like some something else
mixed in with it I'm not sure what yet
though we'll leave it like that for
today now these I don't know still nuts
like I would rather not have them but we
and I have to have them does it look
better if we cover them with red carpets
yeah it stands out too darn it
there's not really anything to do about
that yes all right anyways let's move on
to your number one that most requested
Wilson feature so this is what you guys
wanted right now Wilson can eat three
different things you can eat cookies
which give them a little bit of food a
little bit of happiness and also make
some fatter ads on to his weight you can
give him steak which adds a lot of food
no happiness just a little bit on his
weight or you can give them golden
apples and that's his medicine if you
ever get sick it cures them if Wilson
gets it killed
he'll die very quickly if you don't
treat them but the other thing is you
can also throw garbage at Wilson and oh
I shouldn't have done that I'll break
that for right now if these are all
garbage nothing happens so your guys's
most requested feature was that I make
them get sick if I throw them some
garbage items let's do that that's a
really simple thing to add here
so yeah garbage at items go into this
hopper at the very end and into this
chest as storage hole that keeps
happening it's like I go out of the
speed - and then I the camera switches
and it's making me feel sick I don't
know I think I changed location some
beacons are something that I'm not sure
what's happening all right so now any
time we throw I didn't see it did that
light up it did not light up oh I didn't
throw it in yeah it lit up okay good so
what we'll do is detect whenever an item
goes in there I send it to a repeater so
it can carry on the signal actually
let's go up one block and do that we
have to get this wire to connect up over
to there I ran a wire to his sickness
control and that's that's where we got
to get to here okay so the wiring is a
little bit on the messy side here but
it's the only way
going to work basically it goes from
here from the garbage detection and goes
up here up a staircase and let's enter
Perl up to that other spots and get its
old just cleared it's sweet yeah so the
thumbs up here then up over to here so
it merges together with this thing this
is what randomly controls when Wilson
gets six so based on his health the
lower that his health is the more likely
he is to get sick and now he's got two
methods of getting sick because they
both joined together here and basically
if the redstone block is over here this
is an RS nor latch then he is not sick
and if it's over there he is sick so
this this pushes that redstone block
over it's pretty simple um yeah so let's
go check it out
I fired up Wilson he's running right now
I'm some testing on him and yeah he's in
a happy mood still very good so let's do
them give them some grass
there you go Wilson still happy oh oh oh
something's not right I got 38 grass let
me do get stuck here somewhere oh it did
darn it mmm I picked up the grass block
so I think it's sent through some for
some reason there Oh
so y-yeah so that aligns it to this edge
oh I think it worked that time I heard
it yeah he's sick right now okay so if
we feed him a Golden Apple that should
cure its we recently redid as feeding
thing here yeah that works okay I think
items are getting stuck somewhere though
on the hoppers
now that one went through okay cool so
he's sick again yep so I think that's
doing what we wanted to do here and one
more feature add to her buddy Wilson and
your guys's request I'm going to try to
keep them alive here I think the next
feature I want to add is a reset button
form so like we press a button his age
goes back down to zero health goes up to
five food up to five weight to three
health to five because right now to
reset Wilson's kind of a pain this thing
takes a long time to open all right it's
gonna top off his food before we leave
or is that only gonna get it to four oh
I did get to five okay good so he's he's
pretty happy right now he's overweight
though right now should be at three
lights ideally but yeah we're gonna move
on to another project now Oh a long time
ago actually let's go check this out
first
we built this firework machine which is
actually a really neat thing I almost
want to make another one of these more
complicated but we never even got this
first one working the way I want it to
so let's let's finish it off here today
if we can but basically we have a
randomizer that we just saw there and if
we stand underneath the dropzone here
let's unload a few items as well before
we do this because I think it gives us a
lot of stuff yeah stand underneath here
to get it going you just press the
button here and it randomly dispenses
various ingredients to make a firework
star here so different colors different
modifiers and ideas you keep your hotbar
clean here so then it you add them all
together you get your fireworks start
you throw it into the hopper randomly
gives you more ingredients and you just
keep doing the same thing oh I forgot to
use it green uh-huh so that works really
good actually I'm happy with that but we
never okay I'm going to stop doing it
now we never finished the second part of
this
because once you get the firework star
that is not the only part of making
fireworks you then take the star and you
have to combine it with paper and
gunpowder - to make the firework now so
it's one vapor one firework star and
either one two or three gunpowder the
more gunpowder you add the farther it
will fly up in the sky and it's a good
thing we never did finish this because I
don't know if you guys know this but
they actually changed it recently where
you get three fireworks instead of just
one three four one amazing value so if
we built this previously it probably
wouldn't work today
aha actually just the wait a second here
I forgot you can actually combine more
than one fireworks start together can't
you let's just double-check that or am i
imagining that no you can have more than
one you can have up to five maybe more
fewer than gunpowder oh you can oh man
seven stars I remember what that does
does it make seven explosions oh it does
oh alright
that is a little crazy isn't it um that
kind of changes my plan here alright I
think what we'll do I was going to have
three controls if this like we're
guaranteed we need one gunpowder at
least to make the fire work right it's
going to do it so that if this is down
then you get due to gun powder if it's
down you get three gunpowder or if this
is up and this is down you only get two
and then this is going to be a
randomizer option so between one and
three gunpowder if that's down and I
guess maybe will randomize how many
stars we get to mmm like we don't have a
lot of space to build this honestly um
yes let me prepare this area and then
we'll figure out what we're doing
exactly what's behind here like how much
space
looks like this face oh did I break
something but what is back here oh I
broke something now that's the thing
about working around the man tube
there's always redstone like everywhere
if it be so careful you know this is
actually a really good opportunity here
for me to step outside of my comfort
zone with redstone like I I have a
certain number of circuits I use all the
time and I don't like diverge from that
too often something I very rarely use is
these item frames actually so this is a
good good place to use it I would I
would think because you could have one
star two stars three stars four stars
five stars six or seven stars eight
stars you have a nice selector panel
that way and depending on how that's
rotated it affects how far the signal
goes here so two three four five six
seven eight back to one
alright so somehow we need to make a
circuit here so that's if it's that one
it shoots one item out of the dropper if
it's a two it shoots two stars three
three stars how do we do that I'm not
sure I'll try figure it out awesome so I
got it figured out here guys and it's
actually fairly simple you can see the
whole thing flat out on the ground here
not really much - it's the key to this
is the comparator clock so depending on
how long night it's powered for its
affects how my items get shot out right
so all you got to do is make it stay
powered longer the further out the
signal goes here and you can do that
just by adding more and more repeaters
as it goes on further so I want this
activate by a pulse like by a button
press sort of thing and that makes this
piston extend okay let's just break this
right now
they it makes piston extend for a short
amount of time and then retracts I got a
monostable circuit here so it doesn't
state it stay out for very long and
basically this is sending out the signal
here so every time the block goes in
front it sends out a pulse to all these
repeaters so let's let's give it a try
here so this is one and it shot out one
very cool this is two one two three oh I
didn't switch it i right-clicked if i
didn't work we've got three that time
four one two three four five and you get
the point one two three four five so I
don't think I need to go beyond five I
don't want more than five five firework
stars that's hard to say so this is
eight seven six so up to five is only
this big so it's gonna be a pretty small
circuit really okay guys so it's
probably been about an hour now I've
been setting this up and seemed like a
simple idea but it's gotten a little bit
crazy but it's just about at the point
where we can try it out here so I got
rid of the whole random idea just
because we don't really have the space
here I ran into three projects three
redstone projects while building this
there's something over here
there was a door over there and also a
wheat farm my mini farm is right over
there so yeah I decided just to get rid
of the random aspect of the whole
control panel here because that would
add a lot more to it so basically that's
down it adds an extra gunpowder that's
down adds an extra gunpowder so both are
down that adds three in total and then
this is our selector for how many
firework stars we want to include in our
recipe
so we're basically choosing everything
here and there's five to five droppers
not dispensers so one of them is going
to have gunpowder in that always gets
dispensed these two
it's optional and then these are our
fireworks stars and that one and the
paper and this one just going to
manually refill these because it'll
probably last quite a while and to get
those to us I was going to set up a
water stream here probably and see when
I flip the lever makes the piston extend
over there same ones over there
so basically if it's extended the block
is forward here and then the repeaters
can set send the signal into the block
and up into the droppers here is how
that works and a lot of this is kind of
crazy this is the yeah this is a
selector thing with item frame that we
saw before it's kind of messed up
looking as I tried to make it fit here
and yeah this probably looks like a
jumbled mess that's basically what it is
it's a little hard to see anything
specific here same kind of deal we did
over there got a button to start it and
as we throw the fireworks into the
hopper it should keep the chain going so
we'll get more and more firework stars
and stuff yeah axis of fireworks there
we have a detector here whenever we
throw a firework in it'll send the
signal out or when we press a button
here you can see oh I'm losing my voice
you can see it goes down into here mom's
table circuit and yeah oh yeah yeah all
right anyways let's try this out oh yeah
item elevator here so the this is
actually pretty important I should show
this from here I think I can figure out
how to see it again well I just put some
garbage into this system
oh so you hear that clicking that's the
item elevator so this sentence stars
down the stopper chain into an item
elevator here there's any items in here
it activates this circuit which which
sends them up the to the top there to
that chest and then they get funneled
into that dropper we saw before so I was
originally planning on sending the items
through the half slab here in the mid
but I didn't think this through I guess
I got the hopper down here now so it's
just going to send items into the hopper
if I do that maybe I'll put it off to
the side or something so let's try this
out I'm just going to do do it like this
probably and in case this like a so
alright make sure the water doesn't
spill into the redstone if it does I
will lose my mind because I don't want
to do this again all right do something
like that like that that should work so
I'm going to put my water bucket right
here I did this right right double-check
okay I hate putting water next to
redstone but it has to be done sometimes
cover this up so the droppers don't
shoot the items out over over the edge
or something like that one star right
now and one gunpowder let's see if
that's what we get I should put some
some kind of floor there maybe mmmm
that's an idea
all right let's do that so what do we
get we got one start one gunpowder why
didn't I get my paper and stuff that is
what I'm wondering all right very good
we got this fixed up I think I made the
mistake of thinking this comparator wire
was turning on all the way every time
and in reality if we only have one star
selected it's only going to reach up to
here two stars up to here three stars up
to here and I had some stuff hooked up
to it like my gunpowder for the for
making the fireworks and the paper was
hooked up to it so that was not getting
activated unless I had it set to five
stars or more alright anyways I think
this is all good now I'm trapped there
we go let's start off with the firework
stars at once again just to make sure
this is all good just make a couple here
all right and it was running a load - I
saw do that we should hear a bunch of
clicking from the item elevator being
activated
yeah so those are going right up into
the dropper I don't have to manually
load those because that would be a pain
because they don't stack really unless
you let you and they happen to have the
exact same ingredients all right anyways
that's probably good do one more here
Oh invalid star really oh because I had
two modifiers Christine okay that might
be a little bit mistake with the system
so if we have it set to one star one
gunpowder we should get one paper as
well there we go
we got it cool and all right let's try
two stars two gunpowder and we'll also
try out the yeah we got two gunpowder
two stars oh I can't do it in there I
got to use the crafting table now we'll
try out the hopper system here too so
once we graph this we should be able to
hold ctrl Q to throw it yeah I don't
even have to drag it out of there so
that's cool only problem is I can't like
hotkey the gunpowder because it stacks
yeah this is definitely working this
that's sweet
all right let's try I'm probably running
low on stars oh I wasn't I didn't want
to do another one
all right let's let's make this last one
here and then we'll up it - let's just
do them off here cool let's do maximum
stars 5 stars is what I got and 3
gunpowder
make sure it works it's going to fill up
my inventory isn't it one two three four
five good three gunpowder good and one
paper perfect that's what's supposed to
do and there we go it's almost a fully
automatic fire workstation now so that's
that's really cool what I would like to
do beyond this is hook up my storage my
cart to bring the fireworks from here to
our firework display at the lake that
way I don't have to fill that even that
would be really neat and it has just
occurred to me that in that hour of
building I did not check on Wilson even
once so he's dead let's check out the
comment of the day it says hey etho you
like tongue twisters well here's some
okay guys here we go here we go number
one the sixth sick Shephard six sheep
sick I can't say that one fast the six
six six sheep sick daro number two I
wish I washed my Irish wristwatch I wish
I washed my Irish wristwatch I wish I
wash my Irish which not that bad that
you eros eros eros all right very good
I'm good at saying things I approve of
anyone that starts their name with an e
anyways guys I hope you enjoyed today's
episode if you have any ideas or
suggestions or plans for future projects
things you want to see let me know in
the comments thank you for watching I
hope you have a wonderful day
take care bye bye
you