[Music]
hey how's it going everybody this is
etho
wow welcome back we are in our wonderful
world here in our new area
and it's raining it's going to stop
raining
right now
right now i meant i meant right now
it's been raining for about 10 minutes
it should actually be stopping soon
i would think so we're in our new place
here
last time we were just goofing around
with flying boats with this
little contraption um
i just set up a floaty water thing i
don't know if we should do things like
this but i'm i'm gonna
try at least one i think variety is
gonna be the key to this place we want
lots of different ways of getting around
and we're gonna need lots because
oh my goodness it's so tough to get
around here you guys are not kidding
about these amplified terrain areas they
are tough
i'm almost out of ender pearls we're
gonna have to get more i think
um so i get this asked all the time
whenever
i do this but to get floaty water like
this you need
to melt ice that's what the torches are
for i had ice
running all along here and over time the
ice melts from the torches
and now i have to remove all these grass
blocks and we'll have nothing
but floaty water and a boat
i'm so tempted to ride it wait let me
get my health up
maybe we'll do it just for the for the
fun of it
but we'll probably have to bail and
ender pearl all right you ready for it
whoa we're taking damage quick
little too quick okay and i can't
uh can't enter pearl because that'll
kill me too okay this was dumb
uh should survive in the water
well darn now i have to go all the way
back up and we have no way up
and it's nighttime and it's still
raining i'll be right back
okay so we got rid of all the dirt and
the torches above the water and i think
it looks
quite a bit better now um oh there's a
boat there again
i i've been testing this out so we got a
boat launcher here
uh these slime blocks if you're
wondering how high they launch you
if it's just you they'll launch you five
and seven
eighths of a block so that would be one
two
three four five you could get on top of
this block but you're just a little bit
short of six blocks it's five and seven
eighths
uh different entities though get
launched different amounts and boats
they get launched uh like
eight blocks like we could have this
water or this pad
two blocks lower i think anyway let's
let's go
for a ride
so you see we got launched maybe a block
above the water here oh
snap we'll live we're good that wasn't
that far
that was pretty far is it gonna fall
come on get off the path
no it's not gonna fall stupid boat
bumper boats all right let's try this
out again
we'll have to uh knock this boat down so
let's go slow
very slow
stupid boat whoa all right we got rid of
it
so this is our our water path it's it's
pretty nice
i really like how you can get different
angles
uh of the area as you cross these
bridges
turning around is a little tricky but
it's it's possible too
all right so i think we'll put a tunnel
like a hole through the mountain over
there and then from that i'm not exactly
sure what we'll do
but i kind of like this you can drive it
off any anywhere you want to so as we
expand
our transportation network here we might
be able to like
fall down into a river below and have it
take us somewhere i don't know
with boats so there's so many
possibilities it's amazing
there's like just one random floating
dirt block there i didn't place that
that was just there naturally
but it's driving me crazy we gotta get
rid of that thing there's like a few
other little pieces
probably should go too but anyway when i
fall down
this is where i usually end up in this
area here right
and as you can see it is really really
really tough to get back up because not
only is it super high up
but the way the clip is shaped it like
comes out this way so
it it blocks any ender pearls i do it's
not like i can just
uh mountain goat my way up it completely
blocks it so it's really tough
uh so we're going to focus on maybe some
ground
transportation i'm not sure if i'll use
it much but
i would like to have it regardless so
yeah let's just take a step back again
it's really tough to
plan paths out too but i noticed this
area here it
kind of like works its way up the
mountain up to like
there anyway and then we can probably
get over there and then up higher
and then make our way back there um
lots of mobs around here so the way we
should do this
i think i'm going to kind of straighten
this out a bit
yeah how high is this this is five
blocks
i may regret this later i'm not sure i
want to be really careful whenever i do
terraforming
um but i'll have like a a proper wall
here not just
dirt wall like this all right
and then we're gonna have these uh jump
pads all over the place too is what i
want
so let's see
we get launched five blocks up so we can
do that and i think the limit is
was it two blocks away from a wall or
three blocks can't quite remember
but over here should work out okay
so we'll put down sticky piston
slime block and then there's only a few
blocks in the game that won't get moved
by the sticky piston uh you can do like
watermelon you can use pumpkins you can
use obsidian
leaves i think it's a choice between
leaves and
furnaces though and i'm going to use
furnaces
i kind of like them the most so put
those all around
and let's see let me do some pressure
plates i like the furnaces because
you have to use pressure plates or i
like to use pressure plates you don't
have to
do it like that and then all you got to
do is put a piece of redstone underneath
like there put another one on this side
over there bring this back up
all right and that's all you really need
for a jump pad
so i want like lots of these that will
bring you
oh
oh this is like just on the verge of
being possible
but i'm gonna have a wall that comes out
one more block so i think it's fine
but yeah i want like jump pads to bring
you all the way up the mountain here
so probably have another one here um
let's see let's just follow the path a
little bit give you guys an idea of how
it goes
yeah another flat spot then another wall
probably
bring you up to here and we'll go this
way this looks really cool here look at
this
i want to do something with this like
hanging houses or something i don't know
amazing view again over there i love
this flower forest
oh and there's a lake too oh lakes are
awesome
we gotta build something over there it
goes all the way up here
and then i'm gonna have to get a a
beacon here too i would like a speed
beacon actually i came up here before
yeah and i dug this tunnel let's just
follow this tunnel for a sec
uh this didn't quite work out like i
hoped i thought i was gonna come out
uh through a hill somewhere and then go
on from there but it just kept going and
going and going
our portal is right above here i found
out
but it's like 40 or 50 blocks up yet so
i don't know if this is actually gonna
be a way to go
oh man this is so cool guys you gotta
check this out this is so much fun
we got like 10 jump pads now let's see
if we can run the course it goes up
to about over there i think is where it
ends
right now we'll extend it more but yeah
check it out
see if we can do this goes over here
go over here
oh creeper we're good
isn't that so cool we started down there
and we got all the way up here
in no time oh yeah
i like it a lot so it's nothing too
fancy right now because we haven't done
anything with the path but we're going
to go through this and we're going to
try to make it look nice too
i'm just trying to get the functionality
all figured out first
and then if you want to go back down too
by the way
see if i if i can do this
you can like run off i think oh no not
on that one
only on some of them yeah oh no
it didn't uh huh
when i ran down before i i hit the slime
block every time
this time i didn't
okay so we're back up here again this is
like where we left off with our jump
pads
and i want to show you this so we have
this little
it's got to be maybe 10 blocks gap
we could put a bridge here or we could
try to jump it with something
i'm not sure what we'll do let me know
what you think
then we gotta try to figure out how to
get
up there how do we get back uh
up to the top of like where the portal
is is what we're trying to do here so
what path should we take
we could try go through that tunnel
there or
i wonder i i like uh hollowed this out
myself over here
um maybe even i wonder
we could try to get like around and then
up here and then up there and i think
that would be close to the height we
need
uh or we could go across here i don't
know if there's any way to get back
if we go higher let's go check this out
oh oh man
stinking endermites
there's not a lot of land here actually
oh man
i feel like we're on a tiny little three
wide
cliff thing yeah that's what we're
that's exactly what we're on here
oh man okay uh then it goes up to here
let's go up a little more
i wish we could see the portal where is
our portal
um all right
let's take a look again so that's that's
at the bridge area there
oh there's the water road so that means
the portal is probably at that height so
that is actually
pretty close isn't it if we were to make
a tunnel through the mountain
there i bet it would go to the portal
that might work
if we go let's see what kind of view we
got from the top here i don't know if
we're like uh
gonna stay on just one island here we
might go like build a little bit here a
little bit over there
kind of go go all over here because
there's so many good places to build
actually
let's just do one more enterprise oh
that might have been an overshot
it's not landing i'm gonna throw one
straight up because i have a feeling
yeah right down to the bottom
oh man
okay yeah i think i see what we should
do
okay very good we actually have a way to
get back up here now if we
if we fall down like and we have no
ender pearls or anything
we can make it all the way back up uh so
we're gonna go give it a try let's uh
let's head on down
uh this thing i'm not sure if we're
keeping this or not yet
i tried it today and i actually had
trouble uh landing this jump again
yeah i don't know why i can't do it
today
oh hey we got our vote back
oops totally loaded on things
okay and these
these water streams they all meet
together in this one spot
one two three four of them
uh where is it it's just up here isn't
it
yeah okay so we're going to try to do
this in one sprint without breaking it
if we can
so here we go
man i love this it's so cool it's kind
of like a
slime blocked elevator but not quite
a little more control to it alright this
is the new expansion
oh broke the sprint i decided to do
stairs just for the end of it
i don't know i think it's fine
because i may build something up here
and i i want something a little bit
slower
comes out to here and then
uh might need another one or two over
here but it
the portal is just right over there
so that is pretty cool
okay everyone so that's probably all we
will do at our new base for today
uh but we're gonna take a little time
here to experiment with some ideas for
future projects at our new base
uh we need to we mainly needed a big
flat spot so this is perfect
so all all our farms and all our stuff
at the new base i'm going to make a rule
that we have to use slime blocks
like for the farms so
each farm is probably going to have
something unique to it but
if we can't think of any way to use
slime blocks at the very least
with the farms we can use them to
throw items around so let's try to set
that up
let's see let's get some dispensers
okay so if if there's items they'll be
into
the dispenser here and we'll set this up
so that the slime block
is one below i think like that
and it'll it'll go up and shoot the item
upwards
uh we'll have to frame this in
with some blocks
okay so that'll go up and then we need
another sticky piston to shoot them
sideways
like that no not like that move it one
forward
we'll try this we'll see if that works
yeah let's get rid of this one
okay so
probably need a one tick delay between
the two
um maybe we will do it like
like oh wow my depth perception did you
see that that totally looked right to me
too
and it was way off um
i'm gonna do this off camera how about
that we'll try it out
yeah that was a good call because this
took a little while to work out after
all
uh there's it became more than i
expected
let's let's just put it at that but i'm
pretty happy with it
this will be our staple design for
launching items i think
for all time maybe i don't know we'll
see i don't know if we could improve it
i don't know it might be possible to
lower this i never did try that
actually but anyway so
if this was in the ground it would
actually
be pretty pretty easy to hide it
all you would really see especially if
you
did this actually you can't put a block
there
unless it's a special type that doesn't
stick to everything these things they
like to stick to everything they're
really
they're really sticky you gotta be
really careful with them
uh anyway let's try it out so the idea
is
any item you oh did i not leave a space
for a hopper i guess i could put a
hopper here
to go into the dispenser yeah that's
fine never mind
uh the idea is you put an item into the
dispenser
and it shoots it out see if we did this
right
where are they going or are they going
in the pool
that is terrible but yeah it does it one
by one
it looks like they all go to the same
spot doesn't it
i thought it would be more random that's
good that they
that it's not random actually
oh that looks cool so items they get
launched way
farther than like players and and boats
and stuff
let's see if the base of that is two
blocks up i kind of want to count how
far it actually
throws them
if we if we made them land on ice they
would probably slide too which would be
cool
we got to get some of that that special
ice
uh that you can place pressure plates on
and stuff
you gotta look for that spike dice biome
so yeah they're all landing right there
aren't they oh that is pretty cool
pretty cool uh here i'll do a little
overview in case you want to build this
yourself
okay and actually we should try tweak it
i never did do that
see if we can speed it up
so it's got a built-in clock
that's two ticks quicker now looks like
it's working
oh man it's going so fast
try wait was that what it was at
i think i think it was at that wasn't it
still going
no not anymore okay that's our limit
oh oh oh what did i do
what did i do i broke it
oh no oh i moved it forward not back
whoops
can we reset it there we go
let's throw some more items in
yeah that's the max speed right there
it's pretty quick actually
all right cool um
what else should we try with this
okay i'm gonna count how far that is
oh and let's uh let's try put some eggs
in there and see what it does
see if it'll like hatch the chickens and
throw them away
that would be pretty cool for a chicken
farm actually
i counted it and it actually launches
the items
30 blocks which is not bad at all
not bad so of course you could put a
hopper over here
and uh collect the items then put them
into chess or whatever the items from
the farms we build
um or if we wanted we could even
automatically send them back
and juggle them back and forth or you
know you could have a lot of fun with
this
so that is pretty cool um i wanted to
try launch myself
if we can i don't know if i can let's
see let's go right here
put a put an item in
oh yeah it does work okay one
two three four five six seven eight
it was probably eight or nine blocks uh
it dropped us down two blocks so it's
not
quite accurate um
let's see the eggs yes that's what the
main thing was so we're gonna put this
bunch of eggs in here hopefully we get
little chickens that
get sent flying
and this might be a really cool farm
ah come on
one in eight one and eight chance here
don't do this to me
little chickens where are you
wow are they dying or something what is
going on
just my luck you know we're not gonna
get a single one
are we there we go whoa
oh man oh he does an explosion particle
effect when he lands too i love it
so they landed whoa
did you see that
oh we got four in one egg
oh man that is so cool they're landing
here
they fall straight down to when they
lose their
their horizontal speed right so we we
could put that at the top
of our mountains and they would just
like float down for
for a long time and we'll put in a place
where there's a lot of layers so we can
see them at different heights as they're
falling down
that could be pretty cool and then when
they get to the ground
i don't know what we'll do with them
we'll have to think of something cool
oh i like that though so cool hey
good job
oh it looks so funny
uh that's gonna do it for today guys but
let's check out our comment
before we end it it says you should make
the place
look like a forgotten kingdom with vines
everywhere and maybe some bits crumbling
apart and then have some hidden
futuristic things aha
good suggestions i like that i have to
be really careful if i use vines
because they could easily get out of
control we don't i don't want like
vines growing a hundred blocks down or
anything like that that doesn't look
good ever
um and it's such a pain to place string
in mid-air so i i don't know
but we will use them in places i like
the idea of things crumbling apart in
places though and looking kind of
runic we'll probably do that and
a little hidden futuristic thing is
another cool idea
so a lot of people are asking about the
theme that we're going with
uh i did want to try industrial
and i i looked today for like an hour or
two for
inspiration on the on the internets and
like fantasy drawings and
like actual things people built in
minecraft and
a lot of things i liked of course
texture pack
so no go there you can't really do
industrial themed stuff i find
in this a lot of people have suggested
steampunk as well
and i agree that where we're building
there is perfect for steampunk
um but i don't know if we should do it
because
everybody does it's like the most
popular style in minecraft and it's
it's almost getting old like i see
a steampunk build and it looks amazing
it's like
whatever i've seen it feeling so i don't
know if i want to do it
but we might we might um
i did experiment a little bit today with
a building style that i think will use
um not like an actual theme but an
actual technique
to building anyway we'll look we'll
we'll think about it more in the future
that is it for today guys though
thank you for watching and i will see
you again next time
bye
[Music]
you