[Music]
hello everybody this is Keith oh and
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play series and we are starting
off today at the goon farm we've been
working hard on this last couple
episodes
it's our golden iron farm here so the
iron golems spawn on the platform here
they fall down then they fight the
Pigman below but we get iron we get gold
it's wonderful so we're not actually
gonna be working on this today no no no
we actually got it finished now
basically I just want to show you a
couple tweaks we made to it since the
last episode here so I added some
lanterns under the glass this is the
stock gas from spawning on this platform
if I was to rebuild this I just lowered
the glass by one that would do it as
well but every 5 blocks I just put a
lantern and something I didn't know
apparently they made a change not too
long ago where torches stopped zombie
pigmen from spawning like light level of
12 or higher so I span this platform
with torches and now we don't have to
worry about zombie Pigman spawning so
that's pretty cool and check this out
it's definitely doing its job here we
got so much iron like when we started
building that we had like none and I've
hardly even used it it feels like and we
got like eight stacks just sitting here
lots of gold as well we even managed to
finish off that nether tunnel we built
to the crimson keep all the power rails
are down there now since the last
episode I've been doing a bunch of
organizing again as well even around the
man cave here you might remember like
the last 20 or 30 episodes even I've had
chakra boxes just lining this path in
the storage room in this veil tree I've
had boxes and stuff all over the place I
think that's something everybody
struggles with in the game now you just
put down the Shanker box and then you
ran out of space you make a new one you
put that down and you just you just pile
them up right not anymore they're gone
where did they go did I get them too
Uncle Leo no Uncle Leo doesn't have them
you actually saw them there they're just
up here now
I mined out the roof in here and died
them like great and stuck them up there
okay so I want to take a moment to show
you guys my new ender chest system so
I've pulled all my shopper boxes out of
here this is basically my main storage
room my ender chest right I just got to
refill it every so often so I've spent a
bunch of time reorganizing getting
things super nice here and I'm so happy
with it so you might want to copy this
and I'll just show you how it works so
we got fences for one Shanker box this
is every fence and wall in the game plus
iron bars I put in there then we got a
slabs chest
stairs one and then there's a few slabs
and stairs beyond that that don't fit
into a single one so I put those
combined in another one here the stairs
and slabs I got a light work box here
this is pretty much all the lighting
options you might want to use plus all
the workstations in the game then we got
a flowerpots Chalker box I'm missing
ferns apparently that's what I wanted to
put here but this has flowerpots all the
things that can go in them couple bone
blocks there because a lot of times when
you're out doing things you want some
bone meal and it really stinks if you
don't bring it with you then this is the
rest of the plants plus some of the
other ones that can go in flowerpots
like the fungi that wouldn't fit in here
but I thought they look looks pretty
good next to the other another plant so
that made sense to me then I got an aqua
kit so this is coral turtle eggs lily
pads seagrass prismarine blocks this is
my sandbox so that's all the glass in
the game plus all the sand types all in
a box then the nether stuff oh look how
look how orderly that is I love it this
is my money chest so this is all your
available valuables redstone box
probably missing a couple things in
there clay Boggs terracotta
it's my stone box I like to put a stone
cutter in there because a lot of times I
don't have one around wool box concrete
this stuff needs a bit of reorganizing
I'm about 80 or 90 percent done though
this is just all four logs and trapdoors
odd blocks there's probably a few I'm
missing here like honey I know
and then dirt and I can pretty much
store all the items in the game in my
ender chest now with that system in a
pretty orderly way I think if I was to
ask you to find drear evil in my world
you think you could do it you think you
could find it honestly I'd be surprised
if you knew what jury bill was even so
let's go check something out here just
the little thing well I passed it this
is our clay mining outpost over here
this is where I did all our terracotta
from let's go through the portal so I
added in a path here the fine jury bill
a little bit easier because it was up
above here somewhere and even I didn't
know where it was really so I put this
path in now look we can go up and we've
got a bit of dirt road here we can look
out at the mountains over here we go up
the stairs and then the stairs and then
the stairs there's a lot of stairs and
then finally we reach the top here and
this is dreary ville ah you guys
remember this place we like never come
here it's not really that important to
our world but I thought like if people
are exploring they might want to check
it out you know now they'll be able to
find it hopefully
I also added in a bypass button over
here this is the trigger the drawer evil
catastrophe instead of having to go
through the Rube Goldberg machine which
I never finished this will trigger a
minecart that goes down the path here
and and then starts the whole show but
anyways let's get to it here so today
we're gonna be working on that crimson
cheap ah so I got a lot of ideas with
this thing I still want to try out a
couple things you guys suggested as well
so for one thing I would eventually
maybe like to get a piggelin village
built around here that's that's for down
the road though like this land over here
be cool if we built a bunch of small
houses and some kind of town sort of
thing and instead of filling it with
villagers I want to fill it with big
ones though I like that idea
you guys suggested down here I should
put like a Strider stable I love that
idea cuz it's like down at the lava and
we can maybe pass underneath the bridge
Oh
oh yeah probably not doing that to that
today either though we're gonna be
working on the inside mostly but I did
want to do one thing you guys suggested
with the bridge you guys seem to like
the bridge except for the bottom here
you said I should walk it up a little
bit and I agree I think we're gonna
replace the basalt with some crimson
wood this shouldn't burn from the lava
right pretty sure then I think we will
put some walls down this is really hard
to build the lava I think we're gonna
have some walls to bulk it up a bit and
then below and on top of that we'll put
the salts now this is like actually
impossible Wow
I thought I was gonna just build this
real quick on camera and I can barely
move in this thing or see this is
wonderful but yeah kind of like we did
at our doors same exact sort of style we
put that on top and then more walls
running up and then we'll probably put
another piece of this basalts like up
over there
and I think that should look pretty cool
okay well we definitely bucked up the
lakes quite a bit here maybe a little
too bulky now but I think I might leave
it like that I'm not sure I think
ideally what I would like to do is space
these another 2 or 4 blocks apart from
each other like additional to what we
have right now and then keep the same
legs but I don't really want to rebuild
the bridge so we might just leave it
like this I'm not sure anyways I think
it's about time we head inside the
crimson key so our goal is to renovate
this place and like try bring it back to
its original state right so we don't
actually want to change too much of the
design if possible just where we
absolutely need to or if anything looks
really out of place
so I noticed there's a room over here
like a sort of a cage structure sort of
thing with some fire on top of
netherrack and then there's a hole up
there and a pig 'ln or two trying to
kill me it's very dangerous in here
right I don't really want a weird cold
I think I'm gonna stick with the diamond
stuff while I'm working around here so
what I thought would be cool is maybe we
turn this into our beacon right we got
the two by two with the fire
maybe we upgrade that right or the fires
let's let's make that our beacon blocks
maybe we'll do a two by two and I'll
build the probably an iron pyramid for
right now and later we might change that
to gold we got the beacon pyramid built
here but it's not working the beacons
aren't shining I think because we got
some black stone above here I might just
need to replace them again for them to
figure it out let's see if that does the
trick huh huh no might be the
netherworld blocks here stopping it
maybe no is the nether right I thought
it could shine through netherrack or did
I get that wrong
I never build beacons down below I
always put them on the roof I thought
they made it so he could shine through
netherrack though I guess not
we're gonna go for the full deal here
hey Stu we want resistance for sure
resistance to do we want speed to we'll
try it out and then finally we'll go for
strength and region and with that it
should be much easier to work around
here now unfortunately that beacon based
does stick out quite a ways so we'll
probably want to wrap the black stone
around and underneath it but let's try
figure out how we're actually building
here before we do something like that so
looking around block pellet what do we
see we see a lot of black stone and a
lot of the salt and that's about it we
have some orange with the lava in
general though these structures have
nothing for the eyes to focus on they're
very bleak it's black stone floor walls
and ceiling pretty much with the salt
mixed in randomly so I think the biggest
improvement we can make to this place
right off the bat is to put in different
materials for the floor so we're gonna
get rid of the basalt and black stone
floors here
and I've messed around with a few
different things here I found
really don't like brown mixed with
basalts and black stone too much
and since we're calling it their crimson
keep I thought let's try pick a red
block for the floor so I tried it a
couple different things here this looks
too clean to me
this looks okay but it's kind of dark
and it's got a bit of a purple tinge to
it so I actually think the best floor we
depict is the nigh Liam strange is that
it might be so we're gonna replace a lot
of the floor year with nigh Liam it kind
of gives like a royal carpet kind of
feel to the place I find we're gonna
have to do something about the spawner
very soon it's driving me crazy
but yeah I think I like the style um a
lot actually I think it's pretty cool
huh look at this this feels pretty good
to me we have the option of bone me
owning a two if we want I'm not sure if
we want to do that but it's an option Oh
actually another thing we could do with
this is just break up a couple pieces
every now and then and mix in some
crimson wood is to add a bit more
texture to it as well
and rather than firming the nily I'm all
we got to do is put down netherrack and
then bomyeo like to spread it oh I'm in
trouble I'm in trouble
okay we're dealing with that spawner
that was almost a death right there we
don't actually want to break the spawner
though it's producing tons of these
magma slimes and that's free magma cream
2x2 magma cream I believe makes metal
blocks so yeah it's not a bad thing to
have running the way I see it we only
really have two options these guys are
actually really hard to kill cuz they
don't take ball damage and they don't
take fire damage so what do we do with
them right you can move them with lava
so that's one option
you can move them around and out of this
area I think I just want to pull them as
soon as possible so I'm gonna put down
some nily 'm and then I think we'll do
wither roses on top of this oh we can't
put where the Roses on this stuff really
okay change of plans
can we put it on I doubt it
might be able to go on netherrack though
actually okay okay we got our answer so
I believe that kills these guys yeah
okay and then we just run a minecart
under that hopper minecart took up two
drops I think we're gonna mine out some
of this nether brick as well it's in the
way okay so we got a bit of a decision
to make with this I think ideally you
would want to have 11 by 11 room for
spawning these guys in we might only go
to 9 by 9 actually because if we go one
two three four five blocks from there
we're gonna have to start tearing down
some of those black stone and and bust
up the natural design of our structure
which I don't think we really want to do
but like if a big slime tries to spawn
here and we got a wall I think that
might cause it to fail then and probably
get a little bit less cool so we got a
bit of a cage setup for these guys we
got glass around it and it's just a 9 by
9 and I don't have enough with the Roses
to fill the whole thing so I just put it
around the edges and a bit in the middle
and that seems to be killing them pretty
quickly though just as it is now we
gotta run a minecart track under that
for the hopper minecart so that is
tricky to install I'm going underneath
the nether rack and I like bust it open
and then lava pours in my face and I put
down a couple blocks and then hopefully
get rid of a bit of it okay so we got
the track installed here this is where
it starts in it zigzags its way down
there and then wraps around to the end
and then bounces back and comes through
the zigzag over here so we got to build
some kind of unloading station and
storage system over here or the magma
cream so I'm gonna put down probably
just three double chests of space
starting here there's lava all around
here by the way you can see outside oh
maybe you can't see outside but that's
the bridge out there so we're at the
very edge we're gonna put down some
hoppers OOP OOP OOP into the chests and
then one more over here
then this is where we're gonna do the
unloading right here we just need a
comparator then the redstone torch
that'll go to a piece of redstone up
here and that'll stop the minecart if it
has any items in there here comes and it
stops very good uh-oh I don't know what
happened so while I was building this I
wasn't really watching things I see some
magma slimes jumping around outside of
the glass and I don't know if they like
came from higher up in the structure and
fell down and the lava here or somehow
these guys are spawning outside we'll
have to watch it a bit more maybe we
need to expand our area well yeah I just
set up some scaffolding to get down here
right now and this is our storage all
automatic should be good anyways I think
we should get out of the nether for a
bit here and change things up maybe what
do you think of my concrete maker here
pretty fancy you know what we don't have
in our world yet is a concrete maker I
just realized like we have one but it's
a manual mind one I would kind of like
to set up a TNT one so I've been
thinking we should make the most
ultimate amazing concrete maker yes
alternatively though we could just make
Ethos janky concrete maker oh yes that
sounds more like it so it's been a while
since we did any projects in the man
cave and we want this thing covered out
we don't want to see it it's it's gonna
be pretty janky and so I thought we
would put it over here actually I've
been looking around and I found a
skeleton spawner over here so maybe we
could sort of take advantage of that as
we're making concrete's not today well
we won't set that up today but maybe
eventually this would be an odd number
over here yeah okay this is gonna be our
spot right here this is where we're
gonna stand to make concrete this is
level over here maybe we should go down
a couple blocks to change up the terrain
a bit - all right let's go down at least
one maybe two
all right everybody so we got a bit of
an area cleared out here I think we need
like a 15 by 5 by 6 tall area roughly
maybe a little bit more than that but
this should be pretty close um anyways
let's get started on building this thing
so the back story behind this is like I
do actually know how to make a good
concrete maker but we're making this
janky one just because I love it so much
I was messing around in creative the
other day and I got to thinking I wonder
if I could use the noteblock smart
piston trick to create like a weird
concrete maker and I messed around with
it for a bit I wasn't sure like how it
would work how it would function all
that kind of stuff and it ended up
working actually pretty decently and
it's among one of the easier concrete
makers to build I would say so
I kind of liked it ok so yeah we built
these noteblock smart Pistons like this
in order to do and because concrete
changes the note on the note block when
we put it there it actually activates so
all of these are smart Pistons so then
we take our smart piston thing here and
we stack another one right on top of it
and I just realized it's actually seven
blocks wide and not five and so at the
note block level here we go out four
blocks on the side I think we can use
glass for this but we'll find out I
guess and then we're gonna put water
right in front of these note blocks and
we do that up here as well for these
note blocks you can see I made a bit of
a glass holding area for it
there we go all our waters in okay so
check this out this is the fun part now
we just spam our concrete powder in here
and it kind of builds itself and you see
once one of them fills up the next one
goes and it passes underneath the water
there which turns it to solid concrete
all right that's totally full now and
now we're gonna go up three blocks here
I'm going to put two ladders on the side
here for climbing up to this level and
we do the same thing all right so that's
all done now next step we're gonna do
the redstone on this so this is the
pressure plate to trigger the device and
then I think we run redstone to mana
stable circuit here sticky piston with a
redstone repeater at one they're gonna
wash away it's gonna wash away isn't it
I think we gotta put that there for
right now and then a trap door whoa all
right
and then we got to build some observers
up from that we gotta go to up washed
away
I know it's another one on top and then
more observers going this way into a
dispenser this is where the TNT goes and
then two more observers going this way
now we're free to remove this I think
what did I say seven blocks wide I meant
eight of course I forgot we got four
that hopper clock here all right let's
get an opera clock set up so we're gonna
go comparators from the hoppers base the
hoppers into each other double block
double redstone sticky piston on the
side with the observers and then regular
piston on the other side redstone block
between and we're gonna go for six items
in here one two three four five six BAM
all right and then it's probably a good
idea to cover over this too with a
couple blocks so nothing falls in there
and then from the hopper clock we're
gonna put a trapdoor and I think we're
gonna want to jump in here actually just
to make this easier but the observer
next to the trapdoor then one two three
four five pieces of redstone over top of
that and then from here we take another
observer and go up into a block into six
pieces of redstone over the observers
again now we're gonna build the blast
chamber and collection system for this
thing so we shave off the ends of these
as far as the Pistons will reach shave
off the final blocks here and then
either with obsidian or
some other blast-resistant block like
crying obsidian we're gonna a solid fill
this we also want to put up sitting
above the second layer of the concrete
here just to stop it from jumping out
places we don't want it to and then
again we just cover the sides here or
blocks from the end and do a 4x4 thing
we got a two block gap here we're gonna
fill that in with concrete to stop the
water from flowing down probably can
load the TNT in here but a lot didn't
careful
and then let's fill this two block gap
as well and now we're gonna dig
underneath here and start adding our
collection system unfortunately because
I'm in the man cave we've got stuff kind
of all over the place in our way rying
obsidian actually looks pretty weird
doesn't it it's almost like it's round
like the dark areas look like they go in
more you see what I you see that it's
almost like a bunch of dragon eggs
stacked on top of each other they make a
big dragon egg here anyways I put a
bunch of crying obsidian around here as
well and then on the floor so that we if
we have an accident it's not gonna blow
up the wiring below hopefully now I'm
gonna punch these four blocks out we're
gonna set some hoppers into a chest both
in facing in and these ones will goes
sideways into those then I think we're
ready to put our water in awesome so I
think is ready now we're gonna do some
testing I just want to point out one
thing with this water it actually does
three different things three different
functions it turns the concrete powder
into solid concrete it's also gonna move
the TNT like the TNT is gonna fall over
here and then it pushes it over to where
there's no water and then the TNT
explodes over there far enough away from
the gizmos and stuff where they
shouldn't break and then also the water
will push any drops any of the concrete
that lands over here off into our
collection system so that's pretty cool
now we're looking for when we hit the
button here we want the TNT to explode
the stuff we want the stuff to go into
the chest but we also want this concrete
powder to get moved over so that we're
free to put new stuff there because
right now it's like hacked up it's full
let's this hope all that happen
he's a teen he moves over oh just making
sure nothing got destroyed it looks like
okay oh yeah any heard the Pistons fire
afterwards so now this spot is free for
new concrete powder so that's cool and
now let's see what we got four drops 49
okay uh-huh
so some concrete makers they can get
over a hundred per TNT but let's face it
those are show-offs we don't want to
show off fully automatic a table
concrete maker
none of that garbage we want the manual
do-it-yourself so we load up the top we
fall down on the pressure plate and
pretty much the time we finish it pops
and then we go back up we climb the
ladder ideally you don't want to be
moving your mouse around and ideally oh
how am I gonna feed myself more powders
the question
I didn't think about that anyways this
is kind of how it's supposed to function
it's pretty janky I love it we go up we
go down we hit the pressure plate get
the next one going run out of coffee
powder anyways it's kind of cool I liked
it we actually do have quite a bit of
space around your free still so it is
possible we could add a way of moving up
and down automatically and refilling our
concrete powder but I'll have to think
about how to do that if I really want to
do it I don't know I kind of like it the
way it is too but anyways let's get to
the comment of the day guys it says he
eat etho he didn't say hey you thought
they'd always say hey etho hey do you
still like competitive pokemon if so you
should play pokemon showdown it's the
best way to play competitively would be
fun to see aha
so I actually did like back when I was
playing pixelmon I did get into playing
showdown quite a bit my most fun in
Pokemon I made a troll team for Gen 7
just before it ended it had a beat up
Weavile
with the kings rock it had triple scarf
volcanion was scarf I had scarf art Anna
and scarf pure and black the idea was
like a bunch of heavy hitting guys to
really tone up the beat up then I had a
mega medicham and a Landorus on the team
and it was meant to be a troll but it
did amazingly well I got to the top
hundred at one point on showdown like
1850 in the ranking and I had so many
people raging in the in the chat it was
amazing so much fun with that
I did play gen8 a little bit on showdown
whoa but not as much I haven't played in
quite a few months now
ah so I just checked here I couldn't
find any replays for my gen 7 team saved
uh I think they might have expired but I
did find a couple from my gen 8 troll
team it wasn't nearly as good as my
Jensen
but it had some fun too so I'll try link
bills in the video description if I
remember and you can check them out if
you want but that is gonna do it for
today's episode guys so hopefully you
enjoyed it thank you for watching until
the next time take care have a good day
bye bye
[Music]