hello welcome back how's it going
everyone
this is Ito we are just about at level
100 here guys I've been doing some gold
farming I don't know if this will do it
here but we're getting really really
close and I'm gonna get level 100 just
so I can lose it all and die in some
stupid way as I usually do umm yes I'm
trying to get a beacon for our new place
so that we can get jump boosting and
speed boost and all those kinds of cool
things 95 oh man we might do it 99
one more level just one more level ah
it's not gonna happen we need to do one
more I think so close so close oh we
might actually get it I've been trading
with the villager and the XP is flying
everywhere let's see come on come on
come on oh yeah but I still have a
little bit more all right I think we'll
do it is it enough oh you there let's do
it
yeah level 100 whoo
I haven't reached level 100 in this game
I think since I beat the dragon in this
world and we all know how that ended
zombie attack Lumbees everywhere oh my
goodness
oh man if I uh I do the crusher thing at
night these guys come out from
everywhere they turn on me got one angry
guy all right I waited till nighttime
just so I'm gonna show you guys how this
works again so turn nighttime I think
the only place they could spawn was in
the back here but if you attack a zombie
pigmen since they're considered zombies
they will try to spawn extra zombies by
them in a dark spot because I am on
hardmode the local difficulty here is
3.38 and the higher that is the more
zombies you will get maybe we'll try to
pick up some torches to see if that
increases it so you take out a few there
maybe we'll take out this one you give
them a few more extra spawning spaces
now when we activate the crusher
although those might be too close to us
and here they come Hey oh no no you're
not mad at me want the villager you want
the villager it's so weird that like
they just come out of nowhere
Oh some of them some of them want me I'm
pretty sure they're spawning here though
and we just can't see it because it's
behind the wall
let's try throw a potion see if we get
more well okay I don't know why I
triggered again oh did we get more
yeah I don't know if I actually killed
them there something activated the
pressure anyway get out of here guys
oh snap under Nate levels and rising
this might be the last time I need to do
this I think we have pretty close to
enough gold now okay Oh Oh excellent so
we got our gold guys for the beacons now
we need the beacons I thought I had two
spares at the man cave that we could
just snag and bring over to the new base
but it turns out we don't thankfully we
do have 19 wither skulls though usually
I like to have a wither fight out in the
open and try to make it into something
but we have so many of these I'm just
going to grind out this battle that's
different I uh I know why because I
click the block next to it not actually
on the soul sand it alright what was I
supposed to do so I'm going to go until
I run out of potions here or until I die
or something and being the master of
four four thoughts we're doing this now
that we have a hundred and fourteen
levels instead of it before because
that's that's wise
help myself that I have I'm still good
I'm still good and he's dead okay that
was quick
I know you can do this in another too by
the way
it just takes too long to set that up
though alright I am going to do a bunch
more here and hopefully record each one
and include a short clip of each one oh
that's not good
get back down here yet darn it I might
have to use a bow on this one
hopefully no region is in a problem oh
that was fast that was really fast and
we got it guys
five nether stars should have been six
should have been six I didn't leave one
on the ground don't worry I'm not that
foolish sometimes I am NOT today though
well I'm kind of foolish because I
couldn't find the ender chest I brought
with me so I wasn't able to do the last
one I got lost in the abandoned
mineshaft there because I kept going
further and further away each time I did
the wither fights so that we would have
an area that wasn't blown up anyway we
got our beacons so now we're going to
head out to our new area in the
amplified terrain and hopefully do some
fun stuff out there
aha there it is everyone solid gold
24 carats of amazingness pretty cool
except for over here we ran short
unfortunately so we had to dip into our
iron supply but we will reclaim this
later as we get more gold we had enough
for one beacon but not for two and we
sort of want to here so let's get this
going yeah this was actually a
suggestion on last episode a lot of
people said we should get jump boost to
for our new base here because the whole
feeling we're going for is that we're
like moving effortlessly through this
rugged terrain that's that is like
really crazy and hard to maneuver and
like defying gravity and yeah so this is
perfect because jump boost to I believe
let's to jump two blocks instead of just
one I'll leave this here actually we got
lots of ender chests so let's head on
out I'm not sure if the range is going
to be good on this we might need more
beacons in the future oh no whoa there
they are I heard so many of them oh snap
it's hunting season advert your eyes
children this is gonna get gruesome turn
your speaker's up though because the
sound is amazing whoo oh one more just
one more there we go okay now we can
continue I hear one more now we gotta
save some for the future though don't we
okay so let's head on out and OH some
people that are due to to our channel
here or probably like this guy's a
monster he just murdered so many bats
for the fun of it it is for the fun of
it I do really like the noise they make
when they die the little sweet is so
adorable okay yeah to jump right to
block jump I think is what we got now
just about three maybe we'll make a half
slab um or wait almost needs snow slabs
to figure it out exactly I never really
use jump boost I find it kind of
annoying most of the time but with our
base we're going to design it with it in
mind so that it won't be annoying
hopefully like yeah you do two and a
half okay oh wait is that that's two
that's two that's two and a half oh and
you can do two and a half that's good to
know
that's actually quite a bit can't do
three though uh-huh
um yeah so I just put it in the middle
here kind of by air our jump pads
oh these might need to be done redone a
little bit oops oh man I'm gonna have to
relearn how to run this now with with
the speed it's a lot tougher actually
huh
maybe I won't sprint maple just walk it
yeah it's easier much easier cool
alright so I got two projects in mind
for today guys the first one again
another one of your suggestions you want
me to make a flying machine so I'm going
to copy one that document it on his
channel recently like a few weeks ago
alright everyone so I have our flying
machine all ready to go here so prepare
prepare yourselves to be amazed because
this thing is incredible you ready for
this okay so check this out if I want to
go to that tree over there
this BAM right there not a problem if I
want to fly back oh baby so cool so
quick now it's it's over here yeah so
we're going to go from this mountaintop
over here to over there I think is a
good place to set this up because we do
have that boat launcher we did a couple
episodes ago there that takes us to
around there right
but this mountain isn't actually
connected to this one so we have no way
of getting to over there currently so we
should we should have something so we'll
use this until we need something more
fancy because this will do the trick I
think I've never actually used one of
these and I'm hoping I set it up right
okay here comes our ride long story
short it didn't work I had it set up
wrong so we now have it set up on both
sides I think I got it right it returned
which is good you really got to pay
attention to detail when you're building
one of these make sure you have the
right type of pistons in the right place
and on the right side and all that kind
of stuff so regular piston regular
piston this one here is the cause an
update to the one below here by the way
for triggering the start of the whole
thing and then on the right side is a
regular piston sticky piston on the
opposite side and then reverse it so on
the right side here again is regular
sticky is on the left and then this is
regular uh-huh anyway we're gonna go for
our ride finally I got it got it going
hopefully we don't fall through oh man
how cool is this though this is really
neat I love it oh man this is this is
good it's slow this is more like if you
wanna a Sunday Drive to the other Island
this is what should take type of thing
really really cool really stylish way of
getting across to another mountain and
it's actually really simple to set up so
it's good for our start here I wonder
how long of a ride this actually is uh
maybe we'll talk about something as we
go here so I've been reading the reddit
by the way and if you missed it there's
some exciting stuff coming - survival
minecraft Jeb is working on like an
ocean biome type of thing with
underwater mobs and new block types
water scene blocks and oh oh oh oh what
the um think we fell down I think we
were up here oops oh my okay let's the
switch sick oh and we got an endermite
great
can't believe I messed up that throwy
every time
114 levels are still good or still good
yes there's an underwater update or a
water update coming to minecraft soon
which is awesome for 1.8 and that has
opened up some discussion I saw today
somebody was talking about adding
seahorses I think that would be awesome
like have habit so you can saddle them
and ride them underwater I like that
idea a lot but also since it's a water
update the topic of boats came up about
how glitchy they are and they need to be
fixed and yeah I hope this this update
has that happen
because I would love it if boats worked
the way they used to and also it was
brought up like why do boats need to
break it's been that way since the start
of the game but is it really necessary
and I don't think it is and I don't I
don't ever remember not giving a reason
why it is that way oh you know what I
have have that in the wrong place should
be one back
not that I need a furnace because it's
not going to go through the ground
anyway but still anyway I'm looking
forward to the new update should be a
lot of fun I want to see if that I can
ride this just oh wait yeah how we're
going to start this we might have to
manually oh and I didn't even have a I'm
missing a piston here - oh man this is
terrible I'm going to strive manually
kick start it if we can so I'll have to
flip these to the other side mm-hmm
which is what these Pistons do but since
we're not using them and then we have to
update what can we update it with let's
grab just a piece of stone whoa wait for
me wait for me No
since how we die oh okay I'll teach the
next light we're fine
we're good okay everyone so I decide
let's head back to the man cave here
before we end up getting ourselves
killed with the flying machine we'll
play with it more another day I want to
get to our next project here though and
this this has potential to be really
amazing if we can get it working right
but it is going to be a little tough a
little complicated we'll get into the
introduction of it today though and
maybe next episode start setting it up
so here it is this is our first main
project at the new area we're going to
be trying to build a storage room ah
not just any storage room though the
goal is to make a modular storage room
well not really modular mobile mobile
storage room that's what I want yeah the
idea is I think about 25 storage mine
Kurt should do the trick I want to make
it though where we'll have several of
these set up throughout the islands not
the island the mountain areas right in
various places like a layer I want like
at least four or five of these and if
you go up to one of the storage rooms
that doesn't have the storage minecarts
you hit a button and then all the mine
cards from what from the storage room
they're at will decide to move out and
make it make their way over to the
storage room you're at and hopefully get
there within a minute or so I don't know
exactly how it's going to work out but
yeah and basically if I'm working in one
area hit the button all the storage mine
cards we have arrived there and then if
I'm working in another area hit the
button
all the storage mine carts move over
there and that way it's nice and
convenient is I find with the man cave
here I have to run around a lot running
back and forth between our storage room
here I really like this design
that we got going on here and that's
what kind of what I'm trying to imitate
up there this is
what is it six twelve twelve Ches per
side 36 total and we're gonna try to get
it down to 25 maybe I think would be
good we'll have one storage room though
that's the main one so if we have extra
of anything we will drop stuff off there
like we'll have a cart area and a and
chest area so extra supplies we'll end
up at that one but to make this work
it's a bit complicated because we have
to set up a call button but also the way
to organize the carts we want them all
to converge down into one rail so it's
nice and simple and then like transport
them from Mountain to mountain so it'll
be flying through the air and and doing
fun slime block stuff and then when they
arrive at one of these stations they
need to arrange themselves in the right
order so that they line up with the
signs we have that categorizes what's in
the cart so there's two ways to do it
we could have item detectors that detect
what's in the cart and then arrange
thing is based on that so that we could
send them in any order we want or we
could try to do it in a logical order so
that it's sort of based upon time so
that like maybe this minecart goes first
this one second third fourth fifth six
seven eight nine ten and then follow
their way out and then we have to
arrange it so that swoops this one ends
up over here again when it gets the next
place mmhmm right so out of those two
methods I think doing it in order is
going to be the easiest way of doing it
and I do not have this worked out or
anything I just had this idea today in
fact and I'm going to work it out later
between this episode next one will
probably spend some time in creative
mode and and see if I can work out
the little details to it we can do a
little bit of that today though I got it
a simple experiment set up here first
thing we got to see is sort of the
spacing between the minecarts if we just
let them go on their own with no control
so I have power rail here mine carts
will fall fall down and we will see the
distance between them and if if they get
in each other's way or anything like
that so sticky pistons going to remove
the block and they'll fall down okay
that was what I was afraid of that
didn't dykes we want it to be quick but
they kind of got in each other's way
there I don't know if we could get away
with that we might have to control it
more mmm darn I was really hoping it'd
be simpler so to be thorough we're going
to try this again
with a pretty similar setup the only
difference is I change this to a slope
track I'm not sure if that will have a
different result and I got rid of that
first curve because I'm sure that messes
things up too it probably won't work but
I wanted to see for sure so here we go
yeah they stole
they still merge together they were fine
until they'd went around the curve too
but we definitely need a timer to space
them up a bit oh I have something to
show you here it is possible to separate
the cards it's not too tough just need a
quick pulse you see it only sent one so
we need a timer to control the spacing
between them that's pretty easy to do
actually and then one five of them go
down we need to switch to the next
column do that five times and switch the
next one five times and we need like a
redstone thing to control that ah
and then when they arrive we need like
another redstone thing to control them
going into this slot and then falling
down into this one and oh boy what have
I got myself into it'll be really cool
when we get it working though trust me I
have a I have high hopes for this thing
so I'm going to work on it again for
next episode but I just wanted to
introduce this idea to you today and if
you have ideas on how to do it don't be
afraid to leave a comment and hopefully
I'll see it ah well it finally happened
everyone we got creeper din my base it's
been so long since that last happened
blew up on the stairs here well I was
like walking to these stairs and I swear
there was no creeper anywhere anywhere I
pause for a second to do something I
can't remember what and then I heard it
and I turned around and he was like
right here and and boom and of course
the one thing he blows up is the
mushroom which I can not replace without
regrowing it and I can't regrow it
without a 7x7 area so I have to tear
everything down to get the stupid thing
fixed ah
creepers creepers creepers
alright guys here's our comment today's
it's a really quick one but something
I've been meaning to bring up again says
when will you when when will your next
world download be out I'm bored a 302
that was my last world download aha so I
do want to get a new download out for
you guys of the world before we start
slight doing a lot of building in that
new area um the thing is I have to be
really careful about this from now on
because last time I put out the 302
download we crashed a website and it's
it's a pretty big website I and they
couldn't have a little load and since
then my world has gone from about 160
Meg's
that it was at the 302 to about 340
so it's it's over double the size it was
at the last time I put it up for
download so that means two things when I
do put the world up for download
I will not announce it you'll just have
to keep an eye on the description if the
number changes you can get it that way I
don't want to like mass spam people
downloading it from a site and crash
your website again I have to be a little
more responsible and from now on just
because there's so many people and the
size is so big and second of all I will
probably have to mcedit the world or
something and cut it down in size a
little bit deletes like explored areas
that don't have anything built in them
and then hopefully get the size down
that way but I don't have a date set or
anything and I won't announce it but
sometime soon we will have a new world
download so keep an eye on the
description if you are interested ah so
that is it for take it today guys I hope
you enjoyed and I'll see you again next
time bye bye
you