[Music]
greetings everyone welcome back to
another let's play episode
i've been spending most of my time in
the nether
since last episode working on this area
working on these blaze spawners here
and they're getting done i was just
starting the wiring on this one
and i kind of had a change of plans
but we'll get to that in a sec you can
see i got the
the blaze shut off set up now so i can
turn them
on or off using this lava pouring down
and you've seen how to set this up
before in the tutorial in in previous lp
episodes so
it's pretty basic simple wiring and
everything
but yeah what i want to do with this
area it keeps changing
i have a hard time making up my mind on
certain things so
that's just the way i am i was doing the
wiring and it's like i don't want to do
this anymore
so i kind of stopped and thought about
it for a bit
originally when i started this people i
i was kind of
had to choose between combining
two blaze spawners into one farm or
separating them like i have here and i
chose to separate them because i like
the looking
i thought it would just be better but
a lot of you guys wanted me to put them
together and
thinking about it more i probably should
combine the two because it's gonna get
annoying
having to go to this one kill the blaze
and then go into this one to kill them
they really should be together the
holding areas
so that's what i'll do it's also playing
with the design here but i'm going to be
tearing this all out
but instead of combining the two blaze
farms together like at the top there
i'm going to keep them the way they are
here and i'm
going to make the blaze fall down into
lava
so give me a moment as i
demolish a lot of this stuff i'm gonna
get rid of all this wiring
and get rid of all these lower pistons
here
and this thing here is probably going to
go
and then i'll then i'll be back
all right so i got that all taken care
of i'm going to be using this blaze farm
a lot in the future so i want to make
sure
i'm really happy with this area when
it's all done
because i'll be using a lot and chanting
is a big part of the game now
it's a fun part of the game in most
aspects
and having efficiency tools just will
speed every
every project i do up
so i want to make sure i have good
enchanted tools
and a good a good xp farm so that's uh
that's why i'm giving this a lot of
attention
so we will be using
lava much like we use water in other mob
systems
mobs they don't burn in lava so we can
use it
to move them around the one thing we got
to be really careful about here though
uh let's go up lava emits light
so we can't let light into the spawning
area or it'll lower the spawning rates
or completely shut it down like you can
see here the lava is preventing
spawning because of the light so
at this level here the one block below
the spawner
is where mobs can spawn so we need this
at light level
zero at this height but
anything below that can be whatever
light level we want so
we'll want to count 15 blocks below this
so one
two because lava has a light level of
15.
so one two three
four five
uh wait a sec one two three four five
six
seven eight nine at the glass here
10 11 12.
13 14 15
so at this level here is where the lava
needs to be
at the absolute highest that is so that
the light won't be able to reach the
spawning area above there
so blaze dealing with blazes much
like like creepers and skeletons and
and zombies i'm just going to extend
this tube
all the way down to that level
and this will look pretty cool when it's
done too i think
the only difference really with them is
they
instead of falling they kind of float
down
so we don't have to worry about them
taking fall damage which is actually
nice
in this case um
they will fly around and target you
if if they see you but as long as
they're in their cage here that won't
ever happen so we don't have to worry
about that
all right give me one moment to get this
lower
yeah so the plan is uh to try make the
blaze fall down this tube
there'll be a lava stream at the bottom
that'll push them
towards the center from both of these so
they'll meet at the center
down below here and then we're gonna try
to make them go
probably that way a little bit and then
there'll be another tube that they swim
up and they land into a holding area so
they'll all be together in a holding
area
and then we'll have a crusher and all
that for them there
and it'll probably be a one by one
holding area instead of a two by two
like we have here so it's gonna be a lot
simpler
wires the wiring is going to be easier
and all that too
okay yeah
it's been a while since we did anything
like this
some mob tubing
so this will be the ground
and this is just out of range so that
the lighting from the lava won't affect
the spawning at all
and um make that
go up here so the lava will go right
over here
and then i'll spread out we'll have
tubing here
and in the nether lava can spread
farther so it's just like using water
pretty much
it doesn't burn the mobs another
difference is i don't think lava will
cause mobs to drown
in it which is kind of interesting
i think in the past it used to but not
anymore
okay that'll do it let's check this out
let me out of here okay
all right that'll do it
so we'll probably build over top the
these tubes we might keep them
partially visible just for looks
it's kind of cool to have a flaming
stream for mobs
um we'll have to extend this so we can
do the stair and sign trick
which i don't think i no i don't have
any on me so i'll have to make some
uh give me a moment start setting up the
other side here too
so we're gonna hook them together if we
can
we'll see how it goes
all right and let's put the lava down
okay uh so i got the stairs in the sign
i'm going to
drink one of these so we can safely work
around the lava
fire resistant potion we'll set up the
stair right here and so
the blades are the same size as us
basically so if we can't
go somewhere they can't go somewhere so
we need to get rid of this block
above to get up the stair and
we'll set up a sign over here
and
it's hard to see when you're on fire
go like that um
and then we'll do the same on this side
yay put that down
i haven't actually like tested this
though guys so don't
don't take what i'm saying is fact just
yet because
we need to see if it actually works
[Music]
but i imagine it should work okay
okay we'll set up another sign over here
like that that'll hold the lava keep it
from flowing back down
and we'll have more glass here
and the lava will go right on top the
stair
and we'll have another one on the other
side
and they will meet right here
then we'll start going that way
and make sure it's too high everywhere
two blocks high so the blaze will fit
um
should work
good okay um
i'm gonna clear out some more ear area
here and i'll see you in a bit
so obviously there's a big disadvantage
of doing it this way of
moving the blaze and connecting these
two together with the lava stream
instead of them falling down and being
in the holding area already they're
going to have to
take a few seconds to travel down these
paths
oops which isn't a big deal but it is a
disadvantage
it's a little slower we are going to
set up a lava mob evader because i'm not
sure how the blades are going to react
to it i don't know
if it's going to i have a feeling it's
going to be different than the way water
works
i'm not sure so we'll we're just going
to set up a quick test here
we'll have um
maybe we'll build this out another rack
we'll have a
tube here because this is only temporary
we'll have a tube here
uh sign here to keep the lav in place
actually you know what we need to do we
need uh
we need the lava like this and it'll
flow this
direction one block and that'll kind of
suck the blaze against this wall we're
making
and let's see
i think we need this to go up one
something like that uh just on this
front we'll make glass and the rest will
do netherrack
because i'm cheap so normally to make a
mob vader you would need
like a sign then a lava source block
then a sign that will have a source
block
all the way up i'm gonna see if it works
if you just have
lava at the top or if the downward
flow from the lab is gonna cause
problems
so um i'll just put it there
okay and we'll tap the top here
and i think we're ready to run our first
test
let's check this out um
yep i think it's good let's do it
awesome okay here we go first test we're
checking to make sure that they'll
actually go with the stream there and
also was we're checking to see if
they'll swim up that
or if they're just gonna sit the sit at
the bottom there
so we'll enable blaze spawning again
and then we'll head on down
and the quick way
here they come so they should just start
falling down yep and what's he gonna do
oh
he's ignoring lava that is not good
why is he not in it or is he just not
affected by it
it looks like he's in it
um yeah i could have sworn these guys
got pushed by lava
um
oh okay i think they're
they're hovering just a little bit too
high i think that's the problem
it's hard to tell
um let me place this down so i can get
better
view
yeah there
yeah that's what they're doing so i
might have to make this three high i'm
gonna
make that adjustment um
shut off blaze spawning and walk away so
it'll despawn
and then uh we'll be back
okay so we're gonna make a few
adjustments here we got silk touch on
this pick
so we're not going to lose the glass
which is always nice
uh we're going to lower this
and then we're going to put pressure
plates down
and the lava will flow on top of these
i couldn't quite tell what was wrong
there either
either the blades weren't actually
touching the rabbit or else it wasn't
affecting them i couldn't
tell and this will help us to figure
that out
i i hope it's that they just weren't
touching it
otherwise this whole
episode we won't get anything done
so here's an example you can see blaze
not drowning in lava
and also it seems a
he might have swam up the downward lava
flow
maybe he could have flown i'm not sure
but they tend to do this you get stuck
at the top when you shut
when you shut it down and you can see
another mistake
i made with this i did not put the block
over top this spawner so
uh blaze can sometimes spawn there and
then they get stuck
so i'll have to fix that sometime
but we're gonna turn this back on
we're off i should say it's opposite day
and we will see what happens here
oh
i hope come on
so that they should fall into the lava
now i would imagine
he's still hovering on it
almost looks like he's getting pushed
now though
this guy will help us see for sure
i don't know almost seems like it's not
working
yeah okay
so you can't push these guys with lava
streams
ah
yeah better close that quickly
i can't see the glass it's too confusing
okay i don't know what to do with this
i better drink one of these
okay i'll be back in a sec
okay haven't given up on this yet uh
we're just doing some more tests
i got uh
i got a simple test set up here i want
to see if they can enter
a too high area and if they will jump
into this lava
i almost think they're hovering prevents
them from getting into too high areas
but maybe not
oh he's going he's going so they can't
fit into high areas will you jump now
jump for us come on
they're jumping why won't you jump
no there we go
that works um because if they're
hovering in the lava we can
maybe push them with lava still if we
uh push them from their head
oh what did i just do there okay i'll
set up another test
okay so this one is set up much like the
last one
except i just added this little extra
piece here
we want them to go up and then to the
right
um so let's hop over here
finish bringing the lava this first lava
here will tell us if they can swim up a
downward
lava stream
and right above us is glass so it's only
too high here
they'll swim up their head will hit the
glass here
and where their head is is where the lab
is going to be
so they won't be able to avoid it by
hovering or anything like that
i hope we'll see what happens here
so something like that and we're just
seeing if
the lava stream actually pushes them
like if they're avoiding it or if it has
no effect
all right here comes the first one he's
making up the downward lava stream
and he is not getting pushed
darn it so it doesn't actually push him
ah that's disappointing
i wonder i wonder why they wouldn't make
them get pushed by lava
that would have been a nice feature
so i guess the only real way to forcibly
move these guys
is with pistons or with mine carts
that's the only way i can think of
and neither of those is really
all that practical to use
oh well i guess i'll have to clean this
up
so i went ahead and ripped out all that
experimental magma
tubing we had here it's a shame that
didn't work that would have been really
nice
um we did learn a few things from it
though it wasn't a total waste of time
we know we can't move blaze with the lab
occurrence
that doesn't work now if we want we can
force them to swim up using lava but
that's about it
um instead what i'll probably end up
doing
possibly is like a conveyor belt system
i set up a little
prototype here how it would kind of work
we have
open fence gates with blocks in between
and we'll probably drop the blaze into
the holding areas
and then have a piston
thing that goes around on a clock let's
see i gotta hit this one next
and that'll kind of push the blaze
around let's go around like this
this guy's trying to kill me still
and then this one
and that way we'll be able to move the
blaze where we want
using relatively few pistons
i'm gonna make a few tweaks to these
blaze farms yet though
all right so we're inside a blaze farm
right now i had an idea
on how we could really improve this and
simplify it
uh the whole point behind these
repeaters and pistons
that push well oh crap oh no
no no no no no
oh please don't kill me please don't
kill me
oh so it's okay it's okay
i didn't lose my pick in any or anything
like that
oh that sucked
like i was saying the point
of these pistons is to push the blades
to the center so they fall down quicker
and get out of range of this spawner so
that more can spawn
uh but there's another way we could
probably do this that would be better
instead of using oh see that was a good
thing i did that
right uh let me get rid of these
and then we will do that
normally with this farm design the blaze
will
tend to walk around this top ring here
and occasionally they'll see that they
can go down below here
and then they'll walk off but generally
they just keep walking around this ring
for a while before that happens so a way
to speed that up
is to have fence gates
like so and it creates a fake floor
for their pathfinding to see and then
they're more likely to walk
towards the center here and fall down
because these will be open
and they'll just fall right through them
and
and that's all there is to it so at each
layer i'm going to do this
and it'll it'll just increase or
decrease the time it takes them to find
the center
so it's really simple actually
okay it's done let's try it out and see
how it compares
uh there might be a little issue here
because i have
on the second layer there i think the
blaze heads are going to be inside the
fence gates
so that might make them get stuck there
we'll see what happens
i'll have to probably adjust the shape
of this thing
if i stick to this idea
but i just want to see what happens
okay let's go down i did close it right
yeah it's closed
let's see what are they doing
yeah i see he's stuck on the second
layer now because his head's inside a
fence gate
an open fence gate and he can't see
through that
but as soon as this guy starts moving
he'll probably walk off
yeah so it's definitely helping
but i'll need like a three block drop so
that their head
isn't in the fence gates
because they can't see anything right
now
yeah cool all right
um i'll think about this stuff some more
if you guys have ideas let me know in
the comments
as always and i will see you guys again
next time thank you for watching
having fun here this is cool