[Music]
hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
welcome back guys to
another episode why am i so close to you
it's making you uncomfortable isn't it
isn't it
i'm sorry i'll back off it's okay i have
to be close to you guys
how else how else could i do my very
special
burst out of the door and start your day
full of energy intro here
you ready for this bam
i don't know why i just love how that
looks when the camera switches
you ready yeah all close and personal
and bam out the door
oh yeah these intros are the worst i'm
sorry
so guys welcome back to another episode
we are
out at the sand village to be i looked
at the response last episode a lot of
you guys seemed to really like this
house
actually i was even got better response
than i expected
i threw this thing together in a couple
minutes it's great
well it's not great the response is
great all right
so something you'll notice about
youtubers we start out our videos like
all full of energy and then
towards the end of the of the scene
we're like
and now i'm going to place the sand here
and dirt there and then there's a
seamless transition almost and i'm full
of energy again it's amazing how does it
work i don't know
usually though if i i cut my videos it's
because i'm about to do something either
very boring
or i i messed up and said something's
incoherent or stupid and i
i had to cut it out
your mother is a nice lady okay
so today let's let's get to it here
enough goofing around
we are going to be working on the sand
village
uh first thing i think we should do is
set up the path so that's what these
torches are about
it's my preferred way of lining
lining paths figuring out where to put
them it's easier to adjust
them later if it's like oh i don't want
i don't want to go this way i want to go
more this way
just take out the torch boom then you
connect the dots nice and simple
um so we're going to go through the
reeds here i think we'll bulldoze some
of these reeds
make the path go through here a little
ways and it should connect
it's actually pretty far still but we're
going to try to connect it up to this
path
and like create more unity in our world
here because that'll connect
the sand village all the way up to the
windmill pretty much
and then we are also going to let's head
back
quickly all right all right so then
this torch path also goes
up and this way over to here and this
will take us right to the man cave so
it'll actually connect our man cave
to like that windmill area and stuff
properly which is cool um
then we got a couple other brand
branches going here one of them is going
to go to the pyramid
uh yeah over here over this way and then
the rest of it is kind of spread out
sort of evenly so this is like the
main intersection i think here and
kind of an intersection here too i guess
all right
so what to use for the path is the next
question i've been trying to decide
i kind of want to use something brown i
think dirt would look pretty good but it
doesn't make sense right because we're
in the desert there's sand
where did the dirt come from um
oh yeah i brought mushroom blocks too i
wanted to try these
at the end where did the mushroom blocks
come from i think i'm going to have that
problem with everything
um i want to use these more but i don't
know if they really worked as a passing
material
wood though also has that problem
because it's like where did the trees
come from we're in the desert
what what can we use we got to decide on
something
spruce wood looks pretty good though but
we could also try actia
but anyway i'm not gonna waste too much
time with this i'll try to figure it out
off camera
so i'm gonna lay out the paths and then
we gotta lay out the foundation for the
houses
and then build them up the basic shape
and then we got to go and add detail to
them all that's sort of the process i'm
going to take with this
all right everybody so check it out i
decided to go with birchwood planks for
our path here it's
kind of a subtle block it very similar
to sand texture
um i'm not going to keep it solid like
this so don't you worry
no what you do or what i do
i lay out the main main block i want to
use for the path and then i go
and and like break it up and we'll mix
in some sand again
and then maybe some sand stone maybe one
other type of block
and it should make it look pretty nice i
think
um but that's sort of the method i go
with this
look how easy this is by the way like to
make the path
making organic paths is something i used
to struggle with quite a bit
but it's just like connect the dots
you just go out next torch is there all
right
and next one's up over here
[Applause]
and you just kind of go along pretty
simple
it only is like one block wide at the
start and then you go through and you
widen it
however much you want and it ends up
looking pretty good usually
this is what i did when i made the horse
track anyway and i was pretty happy with
the result
aha there we go guys we got the paths in
for a pretty big portion of this already
doesn't go out past there yet but uh
yeah look at this
i'm pretty happy with that it looks
really chaotic
now because you're comparing it with
like the super consistent sand
that it's next to once we actually get
the village in though and there's lots
of
like detail it's not gonna look quite as
crazy
uh i did try something as well i tried
to mix in some darker colors
like oakwood let's just experiment with
this once more
uh but i thought it looked just a little
bit too crazy a little too much going on
then
but we'll just do a small sample here so
you can get the idea
all right yeah if we do it like that
maybe it would look good but i think
it's just
drawing too much attention it's the path
it's not what you're supposed to look at
right
okay so anyway we are going to move on
to the building now
the structures oh yeah by the way if you
haven't been keeping up with mojang
they have been tweeting a lot they're
working on the 1.9 update
now and uh well maybe they have been for
a while i don't know but now they're
like
giving information about features and
stuff and one of the things they're
adding is a new
sandy well it's like a path block
is what they're calling it i think it's
like a mix between
dirt and sand color which probably would
have been perfect for this
but uh oh well i decided just to go
ahead and use this because it's not out
yet
but also there's gonna be some
new crops i think jeb said he's making
corn and
dinner bone has been working on some
wither stuff
so pretty exciting can't wait to see
what's going on
um anyway i looked at some pictures like
some real life pictures of
desert villages to get some inspiration
and got some
some pretty good ideas one thing i saw
is they like connected all the
sand buildings together like they were
basic little shapes like this
but then they were all kind of connected
together which i might want to try
let's see so let's pick a side that
doesn't really have much to it like
maybe
maybe we'll do like here
here and here so we would do
like another square connecting to this
building so they're kind of part of each
other still
and we would we would cut this part off
like these little fences and stuff
and we'd have another building here and
then maybe another one
over here
like this um
yeah just trying to think of interesting
shapes to this
could do it like this and then here
perhaps
that would leave a little empty space in
the middle
i don't know stuff like that but
basically we got to fill in all the
space between the paths now
i'm going to save going up to the
pyramid for last though
because i might want to do something
fancy at the entrance i'm not sure yet
let me show you inside of it by the way
and again the outside's not complete
uh lots of stuff to do always of course
lots of unfinished things but yeah look
at this i thought this looked kind of
cool in here
there's actually not a ton of space to
work with this thing is pretty big
um but we will try to fill it with
something we'll put like floors and
and walls up in here and try to make
something cool too
okay let's try connect this all together
now
piece of cake right this this looks so
simple uh while we do this i want to
tell you guys
i want to give you an update on my
sleeping schedule because i talked about
this
a few episodes back and a lot of you
seems pretty interested in the whole
thing
uh so i did that thing where i stayed up
about
28 hours every day to try fix my
sleeping schedule so that i would get to
the point where i was
going to bed at midnight and waking up
at like 8 a.m or whatever
somewhere around that ballpark um
so that failed the first time because i
didn't set my alarm
and i ended up sleeping 16 hours or
something crazy that day
uh the next time i did it though i did
it again i set my alarm and that worked
i got up at the proper time i woke up at
8 am or whatever
and since then i've been able to keep
the schedule
um i've been going to bed at midnight
waking up at 8 a.m
every day pretty much give or take an
hour or two
um the weird thing
though like i'm happy i'm able to keep
these times now
but it has had one weird
not so nice side effect before i was a
very deep sleeper like
nothing woke me up pretty much like
uh my alarm would go off and i wouldn't
hear it's even like is this
super deep sleep which i think is the
best type of sleep i think it's the most
efficient
uh in terms of like time spent sleeping
to actually feeling good
um since i switched my
time though to like a normal person's i
have
been so tired i've been sleeping very
lightly every night
usually wake up in the middle of the
night and something
i haven't done in a long time remember
my dreams
has been happening too like when you
sleep deeply you don't remember your
dreams or at least i don't
so i haven't remembered one of my dreams
in like
months and months because i've always
slept very deeply right
with my old sleeping schedule and no i'm
not going to tell you a dream or
anything like that that's not that's not
where i'm getting at with this
so yeah i don't know if i can keep it up
for very much
longer because i am so tired now like
so so tired
um but it did kind of work i just i
don't understand why i can't sleep
deeply anymore
because i am tired but i keep waking up
at the
in the middle of night it's stupid even
though i should be super tired and
sleeping deeply but just the change has
messed me up a little bit i guess
anyway here is the result of what we
just did
let's take a little loop around the
building and get an idea
so this is a basic shape now the next
step is to add the detail right
i'm pretty happy with this though i
think it turned out pretty cool
i like it i like it we didn't really
wreck this building either it still
looks the same right
this is the most important view over
here now when we go up to
the top here the second or this roof
axis
actually makes a little bit more sense
because we can
for example start connecting these
together at the roof too
going to turn this into spruce over here
like so they kind of connect together
that way and we probably even want to
have
a bit of a second floor to this building
so we may
like put another one of these rectangles
running across
like this
and just have a couple of them up here
not totally solid or anything not like a
full second floor
but just in places i think would be cool
and you'll notice the way i laid this
out this is pretty important
not many of these walls actually line up
like this wall does not line up with
that one there
it's i did that so that it's sort of
more interesting to look at same with
this one
this one was over there and i just moved
it back one block
because i don't want them to line up it
looks more organic
if they don't um also none of these
posts are visible from
inside the building which is kind of
nice it worked out that way
so yeah let me get a little bit more
done here and
then maybe we'll add some detail or go
do something else i'm not sure
ice cube break
oh oh do i dare
oh i got him oh that's always risky
alright so guys i've been building like
a madman here
i got quite a bit done
but not quite finished still need to add
more detail more polish to it but
i think it's going pretty good i'm very
low on recording time though now this is
taking a few hours
it always seems so simple and then when
you get to it it's like oh yeah there's
there's actually a lot to this project
lots of blocks to place
but uh pretty happy with the results so
far
so yeah let's just take quick a quick
look around here this is the second
floor
it's got a good feel to it uh there's
another staircase to go up
to the very very top pretty nice view up
here too
i like it
and then i realized i didn't put a door
on this building so i i just punched a
hole in the wall
just now um but this one we gotta weigh
in
got sandstone slabs for the floor i'll
probably mix in some wood slabs
and yeah that's that's basically it so i
left all this space in the front here
so that we could add some outside
details to the building as well i want
to have
like a marketplace feel to the city so
we'll add some
some stalls and whatnot outside as well
uh should look really cool once we get
more buildings done like on this side of
the road and
and like up over here it's got a good
height
to the building i would say feels like a
a good city i guess it's not taller than
the pyramid so that's that's important
as well you don't want it taller than
your most important structure
but yeah anyways let's go do a few other
things and then we'll wrap up the
episode
uh oh zombie pigmen on the track get out
of the way
here's a trick if you ever have this
problem just hold forward on your
keyboard
you can kind of fight them
as long as you don't move your mouse you
should be fine
and hopefully he gets out of the way
they usually do after a certain amount
of time
but yeah look what happens if i move my
mouse oh there's another one
oh actually i'm fine if i move my mouse
as long as he
doesn't uh like stop
oh thank you all right we are off to
mushroom island by the way
and uh we're gonna try to get some
mushrooms these guys
never make a a minecart tunnel like this
you
always always want to have
solid blocks next to the track or
something like
like blocks like over here otherwise you
have way more zombie pigmen spawning
you don't necessarily have to put slabs
over top
um
give me the back you're gonna make me
hit you aren't you
yes you are you jerk
[Music]
okay well this dead ended i don't know
how to get to my mushroom island anymore
i forgot
i thought this was the way i hate when
that happens it's like there's a
another tunnel and it's like you don't
know exactly where it goes and you
follow it and it's like
two thousand blocks and dead end
uh it's i think i remember though it's
actually over here
way way closer which is good because
it'll make
transporting the the mushrooms a lot
easier
yeah it's this portal out by the nether
house
pretty sure i gotta get mushrooms across
this bridge
oh i did not plan ahead i brought one
fire resistant potion
i don't think it's going to be enough
oh and it starts us in a cave
that's not good either and there's no
way up to the surface man my memory is
shot i don't remember
i guess let's follow the torches here
let's make a path probably went
up to the surface over
no where's my tunnel up
all right well i couldn't find it i had
to make a new tunnel
but this is where it comes up at the
surface
so might be able to find it down below
here
are they going to follow me yes very
good
aha guess where the tunnel was right
over here
right by the portal and i missed it
all right you fools let's go we got a
long journey ahead of us
that's right let's go let's go let's go
i reinforced the
bridge there so that they won't die
hopefully
hey that's right
come on in you go
why is he not going through
what oh there we go that was weird
usually oh i just maybe i was too close
to them and they weren't moving
because of that that was kind of strange
yeah we should be good here though as
long as they can fit
one at a time one
at a time there you go very good all
right
there we go nope
nope nope nope no no stop it
okay and good okay
forward forward we go only forward
okay so i just double checked this rail
line goes all the way to the nether hub
so we can use it for sure here
so i put these guys in mine carts i'm
gonna hop in one myself
oh no please don't die
please just just live
alright this is the furnace minecart
strong enough we will find
out oh baby
holy smokes they took off wait for me
oh man i'm no
oh hit hit the ground hit the ground oh
oh no
no oh and i hit the pigmen
i was fine and then i panicked and i
threw it back in
oh no
yup that really stunk
lost my boots lost my amazing sword my
my picks i had two picks on me
oh
i haven't died like that in a long time
oh and i had a fire resistant potion on
me too
just realized i should have used that
instead
all right guys well it's going to take
me a bit of time to get organized here
again to get my tools together
so we will probably just call it here
for today
unfortunately sorry about that um
here's the comment i picked out for
today it says hey etho
i just wanted to point out that it maybe
wasn't the brightest of ideas to put an
afk farm in the village
because of the zombie sieges that's
that's the wheat farm we built last
episode
or however they're called unless you
just got fed up with the village project
and want them to die
yeah um maybe not the best spot for it i
think it'll be okay though
it's i think it's about 30 blocks away
from where i think the center of the
village is
so i don't think they'll actually
trigger the zombie siege
unless i get like 30 villagers in the
village
which i don't think is possible but uh
yeah i don't know we'll see it's not a
farm i would use all the time anyway
it's only like once every
week or two i would probably use it so
it's very unlikely it's gonna actually
happen
but we'll see uh anyway guys
again sorry for that abrupt ending uh
that's that's it for today though thank
you for watching i hope you enjoyed the
episode i'll move those guys
off camera on my own i guess they're
almost all the way home
um and i will see you again in the next
one
have a good day bye