[Music]
oh
yeah i love the sound of sizzling bacon
so yummy so delicious
mine has turned green though it's
molding
all right here we go here we go will we
survive
what do you guys think this this one in
particular
is extra sizzly all right here we go
here we go
nope
[Music]
all right we're gonna try one more time
i think these guys are a little more
friendly
and here we go
whoa
[Applause]
oh the sneaky little creeper he ran away
from the other creeper that was about to
explode and it changed
changed his running path on me there
all right i was all set up for a bravery
test and now
he messed it all up and blew up my chest
all right come on yeah take your best
you shot how the creepers run away now
that is so awesome
we gotta get a few more
all right this is it i got five
creepers this is the true bravery test
right here and a zombie that won't leave
me alone
all right come on will the zombie run
too
okay that guy he did not blow up in the
right spot
here let me build the platform for you
no no no let me build the platform
oh come on guy
come on come on the platform oh
[Music]
there we go no you're not on the
platform
stand on the platform i wonder if i can
like hit them and try to place one under
them
quick enough
nope that was worth a shot
oh a little zombie whoa
all right guys so i'm not giving up yet
we have to get this trick
or at least die trying one or the other
because this will be the greatest trick
ever seen
although i don't really want two
creepers there just one creeper please
okay here let's try on this guy uh
they're all so close together
oh so the problem is i've been
panic placing i think i have to wait a
little bit before i
go for it
yes i did it oh that's awesome he did a
little damage to the ground still though
i think if he's perfectly centered on
the slab it will do no damage
that looked like a creeper on it on a
spider can we do it one more time
one more time come on guy i saw you go
there
oh that was bad zombie got wrecked
though
make your move oh i thought i had it oh
no
he wasn't uh ah he wasn't quite on it
properly
all right guy yes
thanks spider you made that even better
he knocked me right into him
all right i think we finally did it
there i'm happy with that one so we
we can move on enough of the silliness
so welcome back guys to another
minecraft episode this is etho
these guys are going to be helping us
out later i think
uh yeah so oh
keep up the good work guy this is my new
security officer
he's making the rounds i was getting
really tired of all the slimes around my
teeth so
i decided to enlist some help and he's
doing a good job actually
i haven't seen too many slimes around
so last couple episodes we had a lot of
fun exploring
alpha minecraft and beta minecraft in my
older worlds
lots of fun also kind of gave me some
ideas for future projects too which is
good
it was refreshing so today i think uh
i think we might work on one of those
looking at the older worlds
it's like i was really into cactus farms
and then i was
really into boats and then uh
like chocolate island days i got really
into mob systems and i don't have a mob
system
at the man cave here so that's what
we're gonna be doing today
and oh security
security guard we have a problem he's
he must have spawned there because he's
inside the glass
ah so this might be where we're putting
it let's just take a look
at what's in this area
we're going to be doing one of those
mob systems the new ones now where you
can
make the ocelots chase the creepers
around
wolves will chase the skeletons around
and villagers will attract the zombies
and
you can make a really simple mob system
with very little work with the help of
those guys
so that's cool so we're going to try to
make one of those i've never done one of
those
styles before and
this might be the spot
see where do we come out on the surface
or do we run into anything here is what
i'm checking
for looks like this is the desert
let's see desert yeah desert hmm
uh ideally i should probably build it up
in the sky somewhere
i would get me the best rates but
i really like having like the mob system
down in the cave here i think because
uh i'll i'll see it all the time i won't
be like i won't have to go climb up
somewhere in the sky to go
visit the mob system it'll be running
all the time kind of and i can keep
checking on it
uh if i want um so i think we'll just
build it's maybe on the surface
here even
hmm yeah that might work out okay
okay everyone so i've been thinking
about how we're gonna do this
trying to work out the details in my
head i don't know exactly what i'm doing
as usual but i have a a general plan in
mind
we're going to build most of the
structure of this harding clay and if it
turns out well and we like it we may add
more
detail to it later and maybe change the
colors up i don't know
but i think it's a little nicer than
just using stone bricks like i usually
do as a
as a bulk building material and
this is going to be sort of the center
if i figured this out right and i want
to go
what do i want to do guys i don't know
maybe we'll go up a little ways
is that a good plan
this is challenging because there's a
lot of intricate details and
if i just if i get it wrong by one block
it's gonna bug me so much so i gotta get
it right here
i kind of feel no i think that's right
that's right so
because not all the caves are lit up in
this area it's not going to be
super duper efficient this is more of a
practical mob farm
than it is a super efficient one which
means it's easy to build
and and quick to build
of course as well there's no pistons or
anything which is nice
it would work a little bit better if it
was up in the sky because then
i wouldn't have to worry about lighting
up caves or anything but i would have to
move
my my character up in the sky for it to
function
properly uh to get the max spawn rates
um all right think for a second
i i i'm trying to make a 13.
well i guess we should go 15. 15
by uh
let's do i guess 8 is the number i'm
looking for
one two three four five six oh
seven eight and we may need to tear out
some of this uh sugar chain farm we got
here
and this is gonna be our first pad over
oh like so
and then there's gonna be a water stream
in this middle running
this way towards the center and then
this way uh and then we're gonna have
another pad
on this side same size and shape
let's see one two three four five six
seven
oh eight there we go
um we're gonna have to go find some
ocelots and tame them which is the worst
thing
in the world to do because it requires
fish and they run away and they
give you a hard time
and i don't really have any close by
jungles either which
which makes it fun but we'll get some
ocelots pretty quick here
there we go okay
this will be our first layer i'm going
to fill this in
put up some walls as well around here
and in total i'm gonna probably want
five layers to this farm at least maybe
six to get about a thousand spawning
spaces
but we'll just try to set up one layer
here to start off with
okay well that's the first layer there
we'll have to do something with the
outside
because we're gonna go at least four
more layers on this thing so it's gonna
be a giant eyesore
with the way it is so we'll have to
dress up the outside somewhat
if we can uh but let's not worry about
that too much
just yet who hurt you boy
who hurts you i don't know why their
health is so low
i take good care of my my my pets here
okay so let's go up inside
i got the walls on i just about finished
the ceiling i'd left it a little open
here so that
we don't lose all our light but this is
one two three four five six seven eight
nine 10 11 12 13 by
one two three four five six seven and
this
13 by seven is pretty important to the
design i'm going with here
due to the way uh the ai works in this
game
all right wait a second three six seven
so this is the spot right here right in
the middle
i'm gonna put a half slab there
all right let's go back up i wonder if i
can get these guys to follow me up
because we need them
this is their time to shine now uh so
basically i want to get a wolf
in this spot right here hey
thank you for coming up here
sweet oh wait here let's put that there
and he's gone i don't know if
this is going to give me trouble or not
like i think
dogs or wolves may still teleport
randomly
uh when you don't want them to i don't
know exactly i've had it happen a few
times though
um so he's he's there though
we gotta get a half slab on that level
you know what i need those a piston to
do it
because i can't place it with him there
oops yeah so we need a half slab above
that and then we'll put
a cat on that an ocelot which we'll have
to get yet
um the way it works with
the wolf and the ocelot ai if there is a
creeper
or a skeleton within
six blocks out six blocks this way or
six blocks this way from
from them or alternatively six blocks
back
behind this wall but we're not worrying
about that um
then they will try to run to a safe area
so it doesn't matter if
like a an ocelot or a skeleton not an
ocelot
a creeper a skeleton spawn here uh it's
not like they try to run away
from the wolf like it's not like they're
gonna try to run this way
they will try to run to a safe area so
they
will consider all of this the ocelot and
the wolf territory
so they'll try to run to this other side
to get away from it
um is the way it works and it's not a
radius thing it seems to work in a
square shape um so it's not like if they
were eight blocks out
um that that they would see this guy
it's the full
full square shape so yeah
hopefully i'm i'm coming across clear
enough here um i'm rambling a little bit
so then what we're gonna do we're gonna
do the trap door trick
so they will see this as a full block
and they'll try to walk on it
with their path finding but as they try
to walk on that they will fall down
let's get that going all along oops
and that is about it so we got to copy
this
at least four more times above here uh
the nice thing about this
is uh the next level can start right on
top of this
if we want or i may try to
hide some lights in here but that would
make it a little taller so i don't know
if it's worth it
uh to enable or disable the system
all right one second i think we should
also
we'll put half slabs down this will
prevent spiders from spawning
because spiders need a three by three
area to spawn so if if they try to spawn
on this
block here for example it will check
this area all around it and since
there's a half slab here
it cancels the spawning when it attempts
to do it
oops not there right there and
i think i'm going to do it like this
the only problem with these half slabs
is they kind of block
uh the mobs like sometimes they can get
in the way most of the time it's pretty
good though
they don't seem to cause too much
trouble from what i've tested anyway
uh so then we'll cover this all up and
for
for while i'm building this i'll
probably put torches inside
[Music]
fishing fishing
it is very very boring boring
boring but i need some fish for the
assad
ah what are we at red eight i got a
saddle
three salmon two buffer fish
deer three luck of the c3
come on one more one more we're gonna go
get some ocelots
hopefully uh
i guess that we we only really need two
right then we can just breed
the other ones together oh i got one
yeah
okay so we're gonna go on a nice little
adventure here shouldn't take long
uh try get some ocelots
you are you're the horse of choice today
let's go
try out our horse elevator
still works that's good i haven't used
in a while
and we need to head out kind of where my
stronghold base is
i think there's a jungle sort of in that
area
but instead of like the stronghold bases
that way
i think the jungle is like that way
oh man that sunrise is so nice
so cool looks like that is the chunk
border there
so this is new stuff um
this is only is that like 100 1 000 my
world so it's not too far away actually
oh oh i'm sorry i'm sorry i'm sorry
he like stops on the cactus
not the wisest move so we gotta find
some ocelots in this jungle
i have not seen any yet
the chicken they usually draw them out
uh
all right well i'll have to look around
for a bit it looks like
nope not seeing any
oh what a nightmare there's like no
ocelots here
i cannot find any
that it's so hard to maneuver these
trees because leaves are killing me
and it's raining and it's nighttime and
there's
mobs around we'll have to go to another
wait what is that it's a mushroom darn
it
i might have to go to another jungle
this one is not being very fruitful
uh i did find one and i tamed it and
then it teleported
and died in a tree somewhere
so that was kind of dumb
okay here we go here we go we got one
finally found one this is a different
jungle hey little guy
hey i have something very good for you
here
freshly caught
[Music]
doing that thing i don't like when they
do that
it's a good fish oh i think he's i think
he sees it
i hope oh he was coming oh man
there we go here we go yeah
that's a good kitty yes
we got him uh oh game crash
so i think this guy might be defective
he uh he doesn't like me too much
hey guy yeah he's like a real ocelot
he runs away uh but he is tamed
but he really doesn't like me
i don't know i think this patch might be
a little glitched out with
oh did he get the you got the chicken
that's so weird
all right that's fine as long as i can
sit him down that's all i need
hopefully i think he's teleporting to me
too which is good
oh let me tell you guys about one of my
chats i had a few cats growing up
uh outdoor chats and i had this one
called its knuckles absolutely
awesome cat super smart it would like
she'd look both ways before she crossed
the road and
and uh lived a very long time
uh just seemed to have a good sense of
like what was dangerous and what wasn't
and wait are you are you my friend now
no not my friend or did you want the
steak
but snuggles did something i've never
heard or seen a cat do before she would
uh
well she she had kittens at this time so
she was trying to feed them right
and she actually
went into water
to catch a duck she caught a duck
actually caught it it didn't fly away
she got it and
brought it back to her kittens a giant
duck so she swam in the water to kill
this thing
and she brought it back which i thought
was amazing because cats usually don't
like water too much
but she she was special i guess
ah why do you have to make my life so
difficult
so we have a bit of a problem because i
don't have a lot of jungles in this
world i started this world before
jungles were in the game
so a lot of this nearby area doesn't
have jungles
and we went to two of them today and out
of those two we only got one
ocelot and we need one more so
hopefully sometime soon i'll be able to
find another one maybe next episode i'll
go
try to get one before that um i just
want to show you before we end the so
what my plans are with this mob system a
little bit more
uh so i built a couple more layers i
still need
like two more but uh the way i'm doing
the water stream i could make it so that
they
like flow to the middle have it going
this way and
and this way but i'm going to be making
it go sideways instead so
i'm putting water all along here
uh just for a change and also it will
help reduce travel time
because uh the mobs don't have to get
sent to the the middle the pretty much
as soon as they fall down here
uh fault fall again um
yeah i was just thinking is this even
necessary
but yeah it kind of is and then what i'm
going to be doing is uh
i'll be i want to set this up with a
portal system too kind of like we did
with
the zombie pigman farm the gold farm
except in reverse so we'll be sending
mobs to the nether
just for an experiment i don't know if
i'm going to actually use it that way
but i want to have the option so we're
going to put a giant portal here
oh darn it
there we go right
which we have the option of having on or
not uh if it's off
i want the mobs to flow and then
fall down a strip here and this will
go down to a room that i plan on setting
up down below here about 32
blocks down um
that we saw at the start of this episode
in the man cave there
um so yeah that's kind of the general
plan to it
it turns out good this is kind of like a
just a fun experiment
try a new mob system out it's always
cool
and i guess we'll have to have signs
going all along here to hold the water
in place if the portal is not there
although if the portal is not there it's
going to fall down here
[Music]
see i may want to lower this one more
block because of that
anyway so that's that's the general plan
for this
okay so here's our comment for today
everybody it says
the alpha slash beta a redstone is very
simple you have to make
all kinds of things such as repeaters
huge redstone things were
that were snow now we have command
blocks and all that quick stuff
takes a split second to send a signal
from spawn to the world border
anyhow i did like the fact it was
awesome
if you could did i copy that wrong
anyhow i did like that like that fact it
was awesome if you could
make a calculator in minecraft now we
have command blocks any redstone project
will be much easier
uh there's a lot of i picked this
comment because there's a lot of
comments
uh on the last video people reminiscing
how much
they liked alpha and beta minecraft how
they liked it more than
the current versions some people felt
you know i i think uh i think if the
game never did update like if
we were still in alpha or 1.7.3
the good old beta patch i
do feel like people would have got bored
of the game a lot sooner i
i think the updates have been good for
the game
even getting like a new building block
every now and then
just adds so much to the game because it
makes buildings so much more interesting
and
and and refreshing whenever yet an
update
redstone changes are nice there's been
some huge advancements in uh
map making in this game which
i haven't seen a lot done with yet but i
think it has a lot of potential
because you can basically program now
with map making in this game
and they even recently added a feature
where you can do
arithmetic operations with command
blocks so you can do
adding and subtracting multiplying
dividing and
yeah i see a lot of potential with
something like that that's something i
really wanted
in this game and i think a lot of cool
maps will take advantage of that in the
future
along with all the other cool new
features so
it's true redstone and that may have
gotten easier and it's not as
challenging for certain things
it does allow you to take it to another
level
which kind of adds the challenge back
into it because there's
even cooler things you can do with it
now so
yeah i think i think updates are good
for the game
and i hope mojang continue to update um
adding in biomes every now and then new
mobs every now and then new building
blocks
new survival features would be awesome
so yeah updates are good change is good
i find all right guys that's it for
today
thanks for watching bye bye