hello how's it going everybody this is
etho welcome back to another episode oh
man my stomach is grumbling so bad right
now guys I just wanted to record a quick
little intro here check it out I was I
was doing some chords hunting and I'm
gonna be breaking this all down while I
eat my my lunch here cuz I am so hungry
oh man oh you know that that feeling
what like when it's when it's beyond
like just oh I'm a little bit hungry
when it feels like you got a black hole
in in your stomach that's where I'm at
right now like the walls are caving in
and everything is gonna get sucked in if
I'm if I don't eat soon alright so I
don't know how much this is I just keep
adding and adding to it and it's it
looks like a lot of courts it's probably
not going to be much though is it it's
always deceptive because each like I
think to two blocks on average works out
to one quartz block so it's not much but
we'll see what we end up with and I'm
going to do some building on the Nexus
here so in total from all that quartz we
got nine stacks of quartz blocks which
is not too bad it's not too bad but I'm
using that very quickly here we're just
about out in fact and we got a lot left
to do
unfortunately so I put the border of
quartz all along the floor here we got a
run all right we got to do the sides
here as well which is what I've been
working on as well so I put clay all
along I put in the wire that was giving
us trouble last time and sort of figured
out what to do with that
this one here we got that running all
the way down and I'm covering it up by
doing this this is the design I settled
on so it looks a little bit different
now but I think that's okay
because the wiring is right behind this
quartz stair here so I had to bring that
down a bit
anyway it's coming along
today we're going to try figure out how
to get the item sorter working here so
let's go take a look we got a run here
let's get up here sure wish I had a
jetpack
yeah see this ice here we got to run a
strip of that all the way down and then
we got to put water on top and like
fences over these hoppers and see if the
items will go on the ice as well as the
hoppers if we can align it properly so
that's that's what we're going to try
set up so I kind of got this set up now
we got the ice down we got some glass to
hold the water in place so it doesn't
leak out and signs now I got to decide
which way should the water flow either
this way or this way not too sure so
maybe let's plan that out this is for
putting items into the chest right the
item items storage and sorting so I'm
guessing we'll have a chest somewhere on
this end of the building we'll put our
stuff in it and then probably will want
an elevator to bring the items up high
right and then they'll go split to the
left and to the right to the four water
streams up here so the items will
probably flow down this way and then
we'll drop why she no that doesn't work
we need the items to pass by all eight
of these sections like eat all eight of
these sides this one this one this one
this one and those four over there right
ah maybe I thought we would like make it
go that way drop down then go this way
but no we should take care of the top
layer first so maybe the items will go
to the left then like that way then back
on the second row towards us then on
this row back to the wall then this way
so then this one would go this way
because it would drop down then this way
this way this way and this way and that
will complete the cycle hopefully
um yeah okay so we what did I say this
way let's go this way all right so I'm
going to break the ice good all right so
I got the water in here and I'm just
doing a test now this is a trick the zip
crowd guys came up with I believe where
you you have to enter chests and since
they're just a little bit smaller than a
full block the item can move a little
bit further so that it's both on this
block and this one so it's like right on
the line and when it does that it will
still have this speed boost from the ice
but also be able to go into the hoppers
so just show you that I'm going to throw
a torch into the wall there
hits the ender chest and then you see
how quickly it keeps going even over top
the hoppers there I put some items in
the these first four just to test this
so it'll be able to pass over top but
yeah just watch the torch zips on until
it hits these hoppers and then since
there's no items and these ones that's
where it ends up so that's pretty cool
and it turns out to ender chests is very
important for this like if you just have
one I was noticing it doesn't seem to
work yeah it's just sometimes it goes
over a little bit even if it does hit
the ender chest properly Oh even if it
hits it properly and it's aligned
properly it'll just go really slow
overtop the hoppers with just one so
that's why you need to and that's that's
how we're going to do this so hopefully
the items will be able to go through the
thing in less than five minutes so they
don'tthey spawn because they have to
travel like they're back they're back
down they're back they're back if that
takes longer than five minutes we'll
have to refresh them somehow but anyway
we got a lot done on here today I think
we'll go do something else I did build a
little bit more here but we ran out of
quarts pretty much so that's all we can
do all right guys so next up here I
think I want to work on our our
wheatfields here
I've been walking around trying to think
of what needs to be done yet and I think
it's actually pretty close to done I
don't think I'm gonna make it any bigger
it's a good size it looks pretty cool
too right but there is one thing missing
well and some weed is missing but
there's something in particular I feel
this split this sectional and needs to
finalize it a bit better what is it tell
me look around you know aha I think this
looks really strange here like when you
when you walk up to it just to have the
wheats there with no real border now not
so great so we're going to put a fence
around it and I think that'll be a good
like conclusion to how far it should
stretch so that that's what we're going
to do we're going to put a fence around
and then it'll be pretty much done I
would say so it's playing around with
fence ideas I think we'll do it like
this just fairly simple I don't want to
make it too complicated because it's got
to cover a large area here and it'll
take me forever if I did carry it away
so I just brought a couple logs with me
so that we can add some posts so just
like adding a couple logs every so often
just a little bit of detail adds a lot
to it I think like look at this compare
that to what we had just the regular
fence much much better I think right and
then you can go a little bit further I
was considering putting slabs on top
like so and maybe even let's do the
glowstone and trapdoor thing I do like
this a lot like when you have the
glowstone like this and then we put
trapdoors all around I don't think
people do this as often anymore it's
like an old I don't know there's
probably better ways of making like
light posts type of thing but I think
that's okay so we'll do that maybe every
second one and that will add more detail
to it and I think that'll be pretty good
hopefully that doesn't take too long for
me to build
oops all right so how's that yeah I
think that's good
ah actually maybe I just want to try
something maybe we'll lower this one any
slight variation just makes quite a
difference even to a simple pattern like
this yeah let's do it like this this
little so we'll have the different
heights to it - uh-huh so I'm going to
go all around the property hopefully and
then we'll extend the wheats up to the
fence however I lay it out and that'll
be like the finalized look to the place
so I've been building the fence here
guys got a little section done here and
I took a step back to look at it and now
that I see it you know what I don't like
these lights anymore they look they're
too Balti aren't they yeah you probably
called it before I even did it we're
going to get rid of them I think I'm
going to just keep all the posts the
same height - ooh because otherwise it
looks a bit strange I've been finding
all right
aha so little by little piece by piece
guys I feel this area is starting to
come together pretty good remember it
was just empty plains before nothing was
here it was this flat flat land and
grass and now we got some trees we got
that you've been ethought over there was
just a mountain before got the lake that
shoots fireworks out of it and a little
bit further up we have our wheat field
so this is the fence goes all the way
around and now we need to start like
just filling in the rest of it like
these little pieces here I think I'm
going to make them come all the way up
to the fence probably but we can't do
that today I don't have enough seeds to
do it all this is the last of what I
have the fence I think does look better
simpler like this it's more it's easier
to tell it's an actual fence right
before was a bit wild and all over the
place and I kept two lights in at the
very front here here I just had an idea
as well it's it's nighttime right now so
maybe we will put in a couple lights
over here maybe one over here we'll just
do this now we'll change it later if we
want something else okay that's good it
makes it makes the Wheatfield
look better when certain areas are
lighter than others No darn it ah ah
ah first time I got creeper today I was
I was on such a good streak and now I'm
I'm sad that was a bad spot for him to
blow up
all right I'll fix it give me a second
let's do this first before we lose the
night time we don't really get a lot of
mobs in this field just the odd one here
and there
perfect okay guys so we have moved over
to the man cave and there has been
something I wanted to do with this room
for a while you have any idea what is
missing huh we have a pond pretty much
covering the whole area of the room
there's no fish we need fish guys so I
want to get some guardians in here I'm
going to set up a portal that will name
them and hopefully they will stay put
and like jump around and splash and just
kind of be entertaining to look at I
didn't place that yeah it was giving me
trouble so I'm going to set up a portal
so we can get them here easily hopefully
I got to go up one more all right and
there and there good good they'll most
likely fall it into the water
as soon as they come through here and
it's raised so I don't know if they'll
be able to jump out I don't want them to
jump out because then they'll they'll
get lost and die somewhere we might want
to block this just for now though so
they will be able to escape here I'm
just gonna do that till we figure
something out
these lily pads might need to be removed
as well I'm not sure but anyway so where
does this take us in the nether we have
a portal set up at the guardian farm oh
it takes us here
okay I wonder I always get lost in this
place this is a portal we set up last
episode for moving the potions if we
ever come through here I can get out
with this the guardian farm should be up
here I think I left the portal on there
so we'll have to move the fish from from
here all the way there oh it is awful
okay let's see should I turn this on is
he going to be able to get out I hope
not
oh I have it stopped there we go okay
don't don't come through the portal guy
oh did I knock him he's good he's cool
out
alright so I'm gonna get some Guardians
spawning and we will move them over oh
yeah before we move those guys we should
get some name tags ready here so they
don'tthey spawn on us I've been trying
to think of fish names but I just will
name three it's trying to think of like
pet fish names and then I realized
people don't really name fish do they
it's like the one pet that that isn't
named maybe if it's a really special
fish but these are the names I've
decided on loopy
that's a fish name right sure
blue pee bubbles ah ah ah I would call
it fish bubbles and finally the poor the
poor fishy is going to be named magic
herb alright so those are the three guys
ah I just did something really dumb guys
I had I'm just mortified right now oh
yeah yeah I had some muffins here that
that have been sitting for a little
while and I went to go eat one of them
and as I took a bite out of it I I saw
the rest of them were all moldy so I I
just ate a moldy muffin but I spit it
out but it tasted terrible and now I got
that taste in my mouth I was just
waiting for these guys to spawn then I
had a bad snack
alright let's go through so this guy he
got through and he's he's not going back
so I'll have to move him later
anyway we should have a few here the
more the better
they'll be more likely to go all the way
up to this portal that we need them up
these stairs and then over it's really
hard to control these guys is a problem
oh and I can't break blocks okay I gotta
be careful what I do well they're going
back no don't go back guys come up here
I really shouldn't put that there yeah I
broke it um how do I get them up the
stairs they don't want to go oh one guy
went one day I went okay let's let's
nudge him the right way okay
he's going he's going keep going you
will be you will be bloopy I named the
blue pea the great actually if I leave
those guys are gonna be spawn darn it
this is this is gonna be tough I don't
like you can't lead these guys right so
they're really hard to move unless you
put them in a minecart and even then
okay nope nope to the right yeah we got
them sweet okay we'll see what this one
guy does this doesn't work we'll know
where'd he go I'll come on oh there he
is hey you
blue pea
loopy yes I got them okay now ten you
get out of there blue P are you going to
be a good fish did you just open my door
or is there a mob in here blue P no blue
P you gotta stay down stay in the water
blue P okay how did you jump out bring
get rid of lily pads just in case that's
what's doing it you might be able to
swim up these waterfalls - I'm not sure
give her this one and this one okay good
he's not really jumping out of the water
I just say wouldn't right cuz they have
no reason to like try jump out he's sort
of depressing he just sits there does it
move around it very much oh there he
goes he zipped by uh yeah I think that's
gonna work
yeah okay I'm gonna move two more here
then and we'll name them don't want to
hurt you bubbles but you're making me
okay there he goes loopy and bubbles AHA
and oh I missed oh you're so close
you're dancing around it there you go
you got it alright ever the last and
definitely least we have magic herb well
turns out they tend
which might be an issue Oh bubbles no
why did you do that I guess that was low
in life I didn't see that oh darn it I
can't go that way I blocked it off
ah man I try to figure out how I could
get back I need a pick um I can't make a
pick Oh stupid bubbles uh what whoa hey
what that's quite the hiding spot you
had there he was inside the door all
right
serpentine serpentine we might be able
to get in this way oh man that guy
scared me I can't remember where this
will go oh darn it goes here mining
fatigue darn it okay that's not going to
work all right so I decided just to ride
here probably the easiest don't die oh
yeah get my stuff's there good
leave me alone guys not right now not
right now please don't hurt me problem
is I walked here so the other guy we
just brought your despond for sure so
we'll have to get another one all right
well I managed to get all three of them
here it was a little tricky hopefully
they stay put sometimes they'll jump out
and bounce around for a bit but usually
they land back in the water when they do
that let's just make sure all three are
still here one two uh-oh
that missed count one two three okay
guys don't scare me so we got blue pee
bubbles and Magikarp ah so I think it's
time for the comment of the day let's
get to it this one says I was playing
super flat survival for
for a while myself this is with regards
to my question last episode I asked what
fun things people are doing very
challenging simple things suddenly
become rare and with slime spawning
constantly you are never safe might go
back to its what with the 1.8 villager
trades expanding the variety of items
you can acquire for a price
yeah I've seen people play super super
flat survival it looks fun a little bit
grindy but definitely challenging I've
never done it myself though but maybe
one day
I think racing to get all the
achievements in the game would be a fun
thing to do too I've been considering
doing that but anyway guys that is going
to be it for today a couple people are
asking why there's been fewer episodes
lately I I don't know my voice was
really raspy really raspy boy scratches
I say that for a few days and I was
having trouble talking but hopefully
it's getting a little better now I don't
know if I was sick or what and maybe I
just strained it but anyway that's it
thank you for watching see you in the
next one bye bye
you