[Music]
okay that's not how I wanted to start
this oh hey okay one second one second
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back to another episode of the let's
play series how're you doing today I'm
doing great I just saw another one like
gal over here too let's let's figure out
this guy before we do anything
AHA yeah so check it out guys last
episode we messed around with that fade
lighting idea and then we got started on
this project here we're building a
dragon egg trophy room so we built the
entrance built a very cool dragon statue
that everybody loves nobody hates it
doesn't look like a koala either for
sure yeah there wasn't a lot of love for
the statue but it's a three by three
like what am I going to do with with
this amount of space or I guess it's
five wide technically because of the
quality yours but yeah it kind of
reminds me of like a Metroid chozo
statue thing which i think is cool
that's why I built it because I like the
chozo statues sounds like though we're
going to get rid of these these shoulder
things a lot of you guys agreed they
don't really suit it so let's take those
outs and I just hooked up the randomizer
so it seems to be pretty cool or I think
it looks neat anyways and yeah so this
is what it looks like during the daytime
the effect isn't quite as noticeable
it's a lot more subtle but you can still
see it alright I think it looks pretty
cool still right now it's stuck on it's
fading out nope it does like stay on
sometimes for quite a while and
sometimes they'll stay off for a while
but for the most part it changes quite a
bit it's random right it's a pretty good
level of randomization I think let's go
take a look at the the inside of it how
it's all working and stuff so I did end
up using a super fast randomizer like we
used when we built the ender ender 3.0
and I threw in a bunch of slabs here so
that if it gets dark we won't have mob
spawning and stuff too
but yeah right now I just have like an
on/off with a lever activates a
comparator clock that goes to a
randomizer here the superfast randomizer
guess we can like break this up so you
can see it again and that triggers this
comparator the sword is in here then the
signal goes to a distance of two makes
the piston extend here and then that
alternate switch dropper gets activated
and that changes how many lights turn on
and off so it's pretty simple actually
but it's a pretty cool effect anyways I
think we're going to work a little bit
more on this today again I'll try not to
spend the whole episode on it though but
what do we do next what comes next with
this well I want to be able to go down
the stairs here then there's going to be
a hallway with lighting in fade lighting
and then there's gonna be a room with
the dragon again that's that's my plan
was this build I feel like we need to
throw a door in somewhere though because
like if this is where the dragon egg is
it should have some sort of security
even though I'm the only person in the
in the world here and I'm not going to
steal it just for the feeling I feel
like it needs some sort of a door so
either we put it here at the very
entrance or before we enter the room
with the dragon egg I did mess around
with like trying to retract the stairs
up to this level here that's really hard
to do though like I can do it with I
think three stairs but not four or five
like we have here that's too much it's
hard to move them that much using just
Pistons so we're going to do a different
type of door I was thinking it would be
a lot of fun if we tried to make a blast
door like a door you open with TNT
instead of distance so it feels like
this dragon egg is sealed away
underground here right and we've got to
blast our way in using TNT and then we
have to make the door regenerate somehow
so that's going to be our starter
project here so you can figure that out
okay so I think this is our rough plan
here something something of this Nate
I fall down hole so we have a bunch of
Pistons vertically stacked vertically
like that we'll have to try generate the
cobblestone here in like a column then
we push it up to 12 blocks away then
that will fill in our door frame here
with cobblestone and then like enter a
password or something and then the the
cobblestone will get exploded Wien walk
through and then I'll start refilling
the door frame area here with
cobblestone as it regenerates so how do
we make a cobblestone generator that can
make it in a column like this that's our
question okay let's see what happens if
we put water here
will it make oh okay so I didn't make
any cobblestone I thought maybe we would
get cobblestone here what about if we
update it nope nothing happens then so
what happens happens if we put water
here okay so it still say it still stays
water there doesn't turn to cobblestone
down at the bottom here those where they
mix so I think what we can do I got one
more fist in there let's grab our
redstone blocks I think if we activate
the bottom Pistons oh we can't see can't
really see here so that made one
cobblestone there and we activate the
next one makes one there I think we just
got to go from the bottom to the top and
it will make cobblestone and then we
push the ones over here outward and it
should be good steep steep so very good
guys very good I think we got a rough
idea of how to do the door I think we'll
be okay with that
I moved to beacon over here so we're
gonna have some east mining well while
we do this and let's get to holding out
a spot here so I tried going straight
that was my original plan right and then
we got piston noises we got picking
noises you just barely hear it from over
here so I think what we'll do instead of
going this way we're actually going to
go this way we'll do like a split
staircase then we'll branch off this way
start going straight and I think is oh
yeah there is a cave here look at this
oh boy I didn't like that up really too
much would it make it more interesting
why instead of going straight down here
and then straight down here maybe we
also have some stairs on this side and
like leave this area three blocks wide
and then stairs on this side three
blocks wide and then try to merge them
together in the middle here
would that make this more interesting I
don't know that just like playing
staircases seem a little bit boring
though for this so I think that's what
we'll do and I don't know exactly what
style well I know the rough idea of the
style for the room I haven't picked out
the exact blocks yet though I thought we
would try to make it end themes but not
necessarily with blocks you find in the
end so I think in purple right maybe we
do purple concrete powder for the floor
and then maybe yellows would be good
although I know love it you guys say
like yellow and purple really don't go
good together I kind of like them
together though like I think the nether
hub looks cool I know a lot of you guys
don't like it though so maybe maybe not
yellow maybe we'll find another color
like orange instead should we use stairs
here probably could do per-person stairs
oh no oh I just thought of a really lame
joke really lame what did the cat say
when you petted it purr purr mm-hmm I'm
sorry okay guys so check it out so this
is like our first attempt at the stair
layout here it's kind of okay I think
there's some things I definitely want to
change about it
not really feeling the purpura blocks to
be honest it's this is the first thing
here I do like the split stare taste
like I go into the left and the right I
think it merges fairly well although
it's a little bit tight over here
so maybe we should try to like make it
merge more like over here all right and
then like bring the wall out here a bit
more would probably be better what else
what else
yeah perper blocks not not really
feeling it I think we'll get rid of them
we will probably put andesite here
instead try to make that look good if we
can and then over here brought over some
fences and some some wool so I think we
can just do the carpet trick here
instead and wool is very close in color
to the concrete color so what we can do
is just put fences down here put carpet
over top oh I'm gonna have to go repair
my tools here pretty soon
yeah carpet on top like so and then we
should be able to walk up here yeah so
see that's okay that will make it work
okay an other thing here though I
brought over some prison Berean blocks I
thought we would try those out purple
and green kind of go together I think
alright but let me know in the comments
cuz you guys think about our color
choices here afterwards we could try try
some prismarine and orange also goes
with prison area until maybe we can mix
the three together lets us grab some
clay here maybe orange clay has a little
a little test
now orange doesn't go with purple does
it no I don't know about that one
I know blue definitely does and it goes
with green I use blue all the time
though yellow doesn't go that's too
yellow sandstone looks better with the
purple couple in purple Oh purple and
purple huh yeah that's actually really
nice isn't it I like that
that it's not it's not quite the same
kind of purple it's more pink right and
it goes with the green that might be
what we use aha okay so I tried out a
little sample here guys give us an idea
of what it might look like so these are
three colors or our blocks we kind of
picked out here it's pretty pretty
colorful maybe too colorful didn't
figure out what I'm doing with the roof
here or the ceiling yet either and the
walls look maybe a bit plain still so
could get around that with hanging up
pictures or something of that nature
just they need a little bit more detail
all right also I widened out the stairs
here and I think this is a pretty good
good feel to it now I like this a lot
and then I started on the hallway here
oh we're okay so we're going to use a
little bit of TNT to speed up the mining
and for fun
oh hey Mia was that really dumb all
right that didn't work out so good
okay I've had better tea and peas oh man
that actually wasted a lot of time it's
fine it's all good looks like I
connected to the water above too so that
probably used a little bit too much
oh no oh no oh no oh okay that didn't
work out either oh we got some blocks
here we can pick up all right so I've
been cleaning up that mess with the TNT
blocked off all the water so you see
it's nice and flat on the ceiling there
and after I did that I realized we
didn't really have much vertical space
even though we we we've gone down quite
a few stairs here all right
oh my aim this three times one feels bad
okay
so I added enough another little
staircase here to bring us down like
three more blocks or so no water bite it
and now we're going to start the long
hallway here so at the end of the long
hallway that's where our our special
door is going to go as we walk down this
hallway what I want to happen is that
we'll probably step on step through some
trip wires there'll be three trip wires
they'll probably one like right around
here when we walk through that it's
going to turn on some fade lighting
we're going to have six fade lights in
total they'll be like one over there and
one on that side and as we walk through
here there's going to be a dark hallway
that slowly lights up as we walk down I
think that's that's going to be our our
plan here and then that when we leave
we're going to hit those trip wires
again and the lights are going to turn
off as we leave is what I want to happen
so um mm what do we do here maybe I
don't know if I'm going to keep these
purpura blocks here I just wanted to try
put some perper blocks next this kind of
highlights the walkway a little bit more
yeah because then you got this little 3d
effect with it I think that's good okay
so I made it really dark in here down
this hallway so we can kind of imagine
where we're going to actually put the
lighting and I've been thinking about a
few things like for one thing I was
going to put the lighting like right
across from each other like this but
when you do that and you have like a
long
hallway and then you form a line when
you put it like that right and there's
going to be another line ahead and
another line ahead it's not going to
look super great actually so we should
probably alternate the torches so if
that one's there then on the other side
we go ahead like three blocks or so put
a torch for our fade light I mean then
on the other side go ahead three more
and put another one and that will create
a better looking pattern on the floor
with the lighting yeah so it'll do like
those little u shapes instead on the
side I think that looks better in total
we're only going to do six fade lights
so I think our trip wire is going to be
over here and rather than having a trip
wire for each like set of lights we'll
just have one trip wire and then we'll
hook them up to repeaters maybe to
adjust how much delay we want them
turning on with but yeah I guess we're
about 50 minutes into the episode
already so maybe we pause this here for
this episode continue it again next time
and let me know what you guys think
about like the color scheme and stuff
might change it depending on what you
say and if you got any ideas for this
too
let me know but yeah we'll go try do
something else here before we wrap up
the episode so I was thinking maybe
we'll work on our mural again today guys
we'll try to get one more side done on
this there's three sides total we worked
on one we got our forest biome in place
and now I think on this side we're going
to do deserts we're going to go for a
desert theme as well as probably the
Mesa biome so first thing we're going to
do put down some sand here and see what
that looks like so our goal is to like
make a little miniature desert and Mesa
so for the desert I think we're going to
put in one of those desert temples in
the Mesa we'll probably do some like
Mesa hills and stuff probably look
pretty good and we'll switch over to
like orange orange sand for that alright
so how's this looking right now do too
oh it kind of goes with this sandstone
hmm is that a problem I think it'll be
fine right I also just went and I got
like some some dead bushes and some
Gatos and that kind of stuff do I think
we'll make this look a lot better okay
you might facepalm a little bit on this
so I'm trying to build the the desert
temple and it's really hard to get like
any any level of detail like with the
size I'm trying to do but that's kind of
what I got right now we got our two
towers and then there's like a pyramid
in the middle right so that's what I did
here um we'll give it a bit more detail
and see if that helps it helps it out
these towers they kind of need to be two
blocks wide though I feel but if we do
that then we can't have the orange roll
right unless like what happens if we
just shave off this the edges here
maybe it'll still work but it won't be
centered mmm
gonna be tricky I think it's gonna work
okay let's take a look yeah it looks
goofy hmm we might actually be able to
get this to work you just got to believe
in me a little bit here what we'll do
you ready for this
first thing is I think the pyramid part
is too steep like it's a no I don't
think it's actually that steep I think
what we'll do is raise this up all right
then we will slab there instead that
might be more more the shape and that
way it doesn't look as tall either
because it was kind of close to the same
height as the towers which isn't right
either now I think it'll be a little bit
more proportional all right and then
with the towers they have like a little
thing at the top here too it's not flat
at the top it's a little bit that sticks
out so what we'll do is change this to
stairs and connect them together if we
can so do something like that go over
here and then all they'll connect
together like that possibly we could
possibly still keep the orange wall and
have it centered if we do something with
stairs here and then recess it a little
bit
but then on the sides it probably won't
work right let's see we'll try it we'll
see what it looks like so you do that
and then you can put the orange wool
back here somehow cover that up maybe
all right well this was like the best I
could do guys this is a 9 wide at desert
temples 9 by 5 all right
I think the proportions are pretty close
we got the orange roll in including in
the middle there because there is a
little bit in the middle and we have our
entrance I put a chest in there I don't
know if it's better with the chest or
without it right I put like some dark
dark clay here to sort of make it look
like it opens up inside and it's better
without the chest right probably and
then to cover up the orange on the side
there I just piled up sand kind of like
like desert temples are usually
underground a little bit right so I
think that kind of works put in some
cactus and I think that's our desert
roughly done so we're going to move on
to the Mesa now now are you ready for
the Mesa plan guys this is where things
get crazy what I want to do is have two
cliffs right so I want to cliff like
there will probably go five or six
blocks tall and another one on this side
and then there's going to be like a
bridge between them and maybe a river in
the middle kind of like we did over
there the way we did the water there
might be cool so to do the Mesa we're
going to do layers we'll do some like
hardened clay to begin with and we'll
try stack it up and make some sort of
cliff formation maybe we'll do that for
right now then we'll go up with and the
next color and I don't know what shape
to do it I'm just going to do it random
and change it if it doesn't look good
we're going to be harder than I thought
hmm okay we can improvise let's just
change it around a little bit maybe
it'll work it would almost look better
if it was all one color this is almost
too crazy looking right maybe we'll do
it all out of hardened clay
all right so check it out guys I fiddled
around with this thing for quite a bit
actually I made it all out of hardened
clay and it looked okay but then I
decided to try like mixing the stripes
again and I just did the the colors
closest to the hardened clay so it
wouldn't stand out quite as much like
instead of using yellow and that that
kind of thing then I mixed in some dirts
and that really really helps the salads
and a little bit of plants and some dead
bushes we got our drawbridge a little
bit on the low details and now I want to
try puttin the whatchamacallit the river
here so without the river it looks like
this all right that's where the flat
ground would be with the river what
we're going to do is put water here I've
got some lighting here as well like this
and there's our river so yeah I like
that I think it's better with the river
right I've got some lighting hidden at
the top there and throughout the whole
thing too so it would it won't spawn
mobs hopefully we should probably check
that actually so this is ten nine eight
ten twelve yeah that all looks good
there's a torch at the top of that and
the top of that so I'm not worried about
that over here looks a little dark oh
it's a six hmmm where to hide more
lighting is the question it's kind of
hoping that glowstone would be enough
anyway I'll worry about that a little
bit later I guess yeah I think besides
pretty much all done okay you're rid of
the torches and stuff on the ground BAM
I'm happy with that I think that's cool
I'm guessing most of you guys don't know
but I actually have a chicken farm in
the world here never show it we built
this a long time ago it was supposed to
be for some chicken game where they drop
down and we're supposed to shoot them
but like the way I set this up is
terrible it never would have really
worked out so those things that's been
filling up with eggs every now and then
I will try to kill the chickens to get
some feathers so I can do the comment of
the day this is my first time harvesting
them with sweeping edge
so I'm not sure what's gonna happen yeah
hopefully it doesn't kill them all oh oh
we got some feathers right off oh oh I'm
dying what what weight does mob cramming
work on you ah ha ha ha revenge oh did
kill me all right we got we got lots of
eggs though it's fine we can we can
reboot it I was a little worried about
that okay let's put this deck how many
feathers did we get none they must've
went into the hopper does oh they're
just sitting there okay yeah I think
they just pushed me into the blocks
right I don't think mob cramming
actually kills you I'm not too sure to
be honest and actually it looks like we
ran out of ink here so I had to come to
the Guardian farm and pick up some more
there was only 22 in this chest go so
I'm not sure what's going on here like I
don't
afk at this farm ever and it doesn't
seem like there's a lot of stuff here
though I kind of thought there with
anymore to be honest and the rates seem
a little low so we might have to look
into that next episode because these
aren't full at all kind of thought they
would be by now anyways let's get on to
the comment of the day guys it says
ethos whole channel can be summed up by
that one quotes we're gonna start
another project here guys aha hey
starting projects is a lot of fun I love
starting new projects finishing them
takes a lot of time it's it's not easy
this is broken right yeah okay that's
one more thing on the list the old
piston translocation thing but we got
fireworks now maybe we don't need to
think of it but to be fair guys like
come on I've been finishing stuff to
like the super smelter
and that furnace thing and the mushroom
farm like stuff like this with the sat
around for years before kind of like the
library right but we started it we
finished it within a reasonable amount
of time I think so I think I am getting
a little bit better with the newer thing
as we start some of the older projects
though still haven't been finished but
yeah anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
as always and I will see you again in
the next one
take care bye bye
[Music]