hey everyone thanks for joining me again
I'm actually out of that whole last time
so I didn't die but you know what we
never did is we never tried out the
sword the looting one so we're going to
do that now it has smite 5 - which I
almost think I could one-hit kill these
guys with if I do a critical we'll try
it out
never use looting before so that one hit
you see that sometimes seem to be
getting more one two one two I think two
gold nuggets is it perfect for these
guys oh I got no money check it out
normally they drop 0 to 1 so we got 4
that time looks like that one dropped 3
not a bad way of getting gold a lot of
people keep telling me to make a zombie
pigman gas firm in the nether trust me
guys it's in the plans has been for a
long long time
like over half a year already even in my
old world I started making the mob
system in the nether but yeah just never
finished it I was actually surprised
when I uploaded my last or when I put my
world up for download the last time I
thought I was gonna get a lot of
comments about the half slabs in another
but nobody seemed to notice
so we'll get to it eventually
it's a big project though
but today we're going to be working on
the potion system or our brewing room I
guess you'd call it so I'm going to get
out of here how do we do we got 36 from
that and that's pretty good
what is that that's for gold and gets
why isn't this working
come on yeah I think looting I would
most like to use on the zombie pigmen
and on creepers for gunpowder seriously
why isn't my place farm working there we
go at the mill on time awesome okay yeah
let's go back to the potion alright here
we are again home sweet home I think
next time I go to the nether I'm going
to get some strength potions and bring
that sword and we'll be able to one-hit
kill him for sure by the time I got back
I had two stacks of those gold nuggets
because I killed a bunch more on my way
back
wenting really quick but yeah last last
episode we were talking about our potion
room here we figure 10 brewing Stan's
was a good number to have for mass
production because by the time you get
to the end the one you started with
should be about done we also figured out
that we're going to have a water source
block above in the center so that
filling these with water bottles will be
a lot less tedious they'll all be where
we're standing so we won't have to go
pick them up and put them in the stands
they'll just be right there for us but
now today that second key of the puzzle
or the second main plan I didn't look in
this chest last time because they didn't
want to spoil it but yeah we're going to
be
you we're going to be using dispensers
yay figured this out on paper here
there's seven main ingredients for
making the potions I think there's seven
main different potions as well with
different degrees of the potion of each
potion but anyway we will have blaze
powder gassed here's with glycerin
melons
how you say it magma cream spider eyes
sugar and fermented spider eyes those
are the seven basic ingredients for
making potions and then there's a three
additional ingredients to enhance the
potions redstone glowstone and gunpowder
if we want to make it a splash potion so
that's a total of ten different things
so far but then there will also be
dispensers for the nether warts so
that's 11 and then they'll also be
dispensers for the glass bottles so this
is what I want to happen when I walk in
to the potion room there's going to be a
bunch of storage chess probably for
double chests or so for each potion type
so out of the seven potion types the
main the main branches so that'll be
about twenty eight chests or more all
right when you walk in then you'll walk
to the end of the potion room and we'll
have this semicircle of brewing stands
they'll be one off the ground underneath
each of these I'll have a button the
buttons will go up to an array of
dispensers so most of these will have
ten dispensers each so you hit a button
then ten dispensers get activated and
ten let's say nether wart will fall down
the water above us on to us then we'll
put the ten in the brewing stands and
then say we want it to make haste
potions we would push another button to
get 10 sugar to fall down on to us
I don't know that's the plan we'll see
how it goes here I'm going to move this
stuff over more to the right though
because I will need a bit of space for
the wiring and I'll probably go further
back too so we'll have some area in the
front to put our storage chests because
it'll be a lot of them you can't stack
these potions so we need a lot of
storage space for mass production
alright so I got a bit more space
cleared out here we'll probably have to
clear some more I just want to show you
what I've been doing here though because
I I want to finish this wall up kind of
before I position the potion room just
so you know we're not fidgeting with it
afterward so I punched holes through it
put some iron bars and and it just kind
of copies the greenhouse or whatever we
have over here the pumpkin farm so it
goes lab of water lava lava water lava
all right and then over here I'm going
to explain this to you around my world
every so often I'm going to have these
dispenser stations and they will have
potions inside and I'll walk up they'll
give me a potion chug it good to go when
I get more established I'll be filling
these with the splash potions so if you
didn't know this already maybe we'll
make some see how this works make sure
it works too you can make any potion a
splash potion by just putting gunpowder
and so this will become splash splash
potions of swiftness it does reduce the
length that it lasts slow by I think
it's 3/4 of the original so yeah I'll
have yeah it's it's a redstone and
redstone dust here powers this block
which powers the dispenser so that's how
that works and we'll have one over here
as well for instant health
just to I need to I need to make this
some space here have to put something
for decoration so this is a good
functioning decoration and I'm going to
color code these two so let's make this
light blue so I don't mix them up I'll
get some light blue dye I would use it
on a sheep but I don't have any sheep
around
yeah this will be light blue then the
potion of instant health we will do red
because that's what color it is and
we'll have that over here a little
dispenser station and I have these in
set one block just so that if any mobs
are wandering around they're a lot less
likely to step on the pressure plates
and I didn't wire that anyway so then
I'll have the wooden planks extend out
here further oops that's not a plank to
the potion room and then I think what
we'll do just kind of figure out the
shape we should put some clothes down
here to just to brighten it up see how
this looks it's a little bit better
might put some signs on these blocks
then we will try get some curve going on
here so we'll curve it in maybe like
that
actually I don't know if I want the door
that small and I did count there's
actually eight main potions not seven
like I thought so we'll probably just
have ten sets of chests and like mmm
maybe four double chests for each potion
type so we'll have two extras for like
glass bottles and stuff and then out
whatever you'll see you'll see what I
mean I'm rambling a lot here yeah I'm
going to make this wider maybe we'll do
yeah let's do sliding piston doors I
like those there then the wall continue
this wooden stuff will go in now
thinking of maybe doing a scheme similar
to my original storage room in this
potion room like with the checkered wood
and planks or or chess maybe I don't
know yeah whatever so walk-in will have
chests on the right and left probably
and further back we'll have this stands
so let me work on this a bit because
don't have much done yet and hopefully
it'll get better all right guys I
thought I'd give you a little update of
what I've been doing here just been
messing around trying to figure out a
good layout that I'm happy with I'm not
building this on camera just because
this potion room would drag on over
quite a few episodes if I did and it's
still night because it's a big project
but I'll show you this dispenser thing
we got our energy drink slogans run
faster for the swiftness potions and we
have live longer for the instant health
potions so let's walk in dispense it
both empty stare prevents you from being
able to walk in the middle here and it
looks nice wasn't happy with how the
glowstone looked it didn't seem too
light or brighten up the area very much
for some reason I don't know why so I
put lava here and that I it won't burn
the wool because I have blocks on all
six sides of the wool so even though it
looks like it's exposed it's not so
that's the trick behind that and behind
it we even have a crafting bench hidden
which is very nice because I always
always run around looking for crafting
benches I need to start putting them
around the place more often alright so
then this is the layout for inside
that's going to do a sliding door type
thing I realized though that I need to
make it an odd number I can't have an
even to block entrance here either has
to be one block entrance but I thought
that would be very cramped feeling so
I'm going to try and make a three block
3x3 door sliding door entrance never
done that before so it'll be fun you
walk in and then we'll have chests on
the right these will get stacked on top
of each other
Dada Dada slurring my words together
so in 1.0.0 you chin stat chests on top
of each other now it's really awesome so
I might go three chests I see how that
looks I was thinking for originally but
that might just get crazy and something
like that kind of want to color code the
chest tube but then that would take more
space hmm
I don't think about it this is what's on
the back behind the dispenser area okay
and you can see we're running into the
pumpkin farm here so might move this all
over one or two blocks to the right
this looks really sharp this edge too so
it should be oops
should be probably three blocks wide
here and then he'll start caving in and
then the potion stuff the half the
semicircle will be here type thing okay
oh and yeah let's try out the potions I
almost forgot so it was three minutes
before now it's 2 minutes and 15 seconds
what can I toss let's try it I've never
shot one of these of a dispenser before
yeah three quarters of time that's what
that is here we go did it hit me it did
and we got we got the full 215 good cool
so I'd like to have a few of these
dispensing stations around my world
every every so often so that if you want
a speed boost to just walk into it and
then take off type thing and they look
kind of cool in my opinion right so I'll
work some more and hopefully get a bunch
more done I'm going to show you the 3x3
piston door I made it's it's pretty cool
it's still in rough format I left it
open so you can see what's happening
closes its opening I might slow it down
like half that speed because I had it
slower before it seems to open a lot
better it's cool how it closes but when
it opens it's not it's not really even
you know so there'll be a row of
pressure plates here to walk on and then
when you go through they'll be another
row over here like that and you can do
this kind of fancy when I walk in door
will open then I walk when I walk on
this set of pressure plates it'll close
and it will also lock the door so if
anything on this side tries to get in by
walking on the pressure plates it'll
stay closed it will only unlock when I
walk back out that's the plan I'll run
through the wiring quickly here if you
want to check it out I'm not going to
explain it it's just basic delays and
obviously this isn't set up right I need
to add T flip-flops and our store
latches and all that fun stuff but
there's a eight Pistons total and the
center is going to stay open I don't
think it's a big deal it's more for
looks than anything it goes up here and
I think all the wiring is out of the way
so it shouldn't interfere with anything
I hope and that's it
can we kill it seems to be pretty
resilient okay good yeah I should have
known this door giving me a lot of
hassle spent a lot of time on it and had
it almost working right but the thing is
I'd walk on the pressure plates and it'd
take like three seconds to open the
wiring was pretty slow so I decided to
just do a button you press it it opens
for four or five seconds and it closes
there's a little bit of a delay before
you press it again to play but it's it's
it's a lot simpler this way big problem
I had was space this stupid thing was in
the way of my wiring but it just comes
down to an RS nor latch here with a
delay on it I think it's a four second
delay if I remember right and that's it
and this is a layout I've kind of
decided upon chess over on both sides
it'll be probably three high three
chests double chests stacked on top of
each other and then we have the
cauldrons or brewing stands over here
and I probably won't do this out of
stone brick like I have here just use
this for the layout I wanted to try keep
it more wood --is-- if I could so I'll
play around with it some more and I'll
see you guys in a little bit
actually before I play around with the
looks of this place I'm going to try set
up a actual station here I got water
above already I just added that
buttons lots and lots of buttons so yeah
there's about eight different types of
potions like main types and different
degrees of each of those of course and
that's not counting based potions like
awkward potions so I've got eight of
those and then there's ten brewing
stands here but there'll be 12 buttons
total for the twelve main ingredients
we're going to need here I've already
decided that I want this button here to
dispense glass bottles so when we press
it thirty will fall from above onto us
here
and we can fill them at this water here
they'll be thrown straight up and then
we can just go around place them inside
nice and easy I can reach all these
right yeah so all the glass bottles will
be here it'll be easy to fill them and
then each of these will dispense a
different ingredients I know this one I
want to dispense nether warts so if you
press it then ten nether wart will fall
down and you can make awkward potions
and say you want
make haste potions maybe this will
dispense 10 sugar then you go around
fill them all up and that's how it's
going to work ideally so I'll have to
wire this I think I should set up the
dispenser area above here but yeah I'm
going to do that next time maybe I
should really be uploading this episode
right now so we'll just maybe do a
little bit filler make that happen it's
a bit short I wanted to try what was
that strength potions in the nether with
that sword so give me a second to get
that together
yeah all right here we are this is going
to be fun we got we got an awesome sword
we got strength potions swiftness
potions and fire resistant potions so
we're just gonna dominate this place
shut down if you can they can use more
than one at a time and unstoppable you
still gotta trick them and we do this
run through the fire not a problem so
overpowered then we got our iron armor
on that won't break ever take the most
no damage is it's so imbalanced in 1.0.0
oh here's an army don't even have to
dodge awesome this levels of man buddy
india buddy yeah I like it
alright guys well that was fun I might
stick around and do that a little bit
longer but I'm gonna say goodbye to you
for now and hopefully next time we'll
finish the poem or something um my
school yeah still invulnerable
mm-hmm but for today I'm going to say
goodbye like I said already and see you
next time thanks for watching