[Music]
hello everybody welcome back
this is etho we got some problems today
guys i figure
figure i'd bring you along on my little
journey here i don't know how this is
going to turn out
i lost all my stuff i went caving and
found some ravine i went down it's just
started exploring and a creeper landed
right on my head
boom dead lost everything
um my silk touch picks
and i had a few good picks i had my good
boots
oh and it's raining darn okay
so this is a challenge trying to find
the ravine again
it wasn't that far from here it's got to
be within a hundred blocks or so
uh got some more problems too if you can
if you see my arm my skin it's it's not
my normal skin because
um it's not because the skin server's
down or anything it's because my
internet is down once again
which is really really frustrating it's
been
i don't know i waited a week for it to
get fixed last time
and they came and they fixed it and they
removed my backup line
like two or three days later it goes
down again so if you're watching this
it's back up because i was able to
upload this video but right now for me
it's down and i have no idea how long
it's going to be down for
but hopefully hopefully it's fixed soon
okay it wasn't a snow
biome i remember come on
we're running out of time we're running
out of time
come on ravines are so hard to find
[Music]
oh is that it is this it oh this is it
yes i remember i remember
okay so it was it was right where that
skeleton is darn it
and there's two creepers up there just
waiting again that's wonderful
i should have brought some stuff this
was
okay i'm gonna try ender pearl to it
come on it's it's supposed to be right
here
don't kill me don't kill me
what the heck i died right here
i swear
ah
[Music]
okay i'm gonna re-gear up and we'll try
that again that was pretty bad
okay rescue mission 2.0
this time we have a real armor real food
a real sword
ender pearls and even torches
we're probably at the three minute mark
we gotta get the stuff quick
and if i remember correctly we did a
loop around
that way i think we gotta go this way
it's right by the plane or the forest
go go go even got speed potions come on
i have chosen poorly let's go this way
oh darn it where's the forest
man it must be this way then
we gotta really hurry now i wasted a
bunch of time doing that okay there's
the forest i see it
so it's gotta be right here
got feather falling boots on that's it
there we go okay um
i messed up somehow was i in the wrong
spot
oh i see stuff here maybe i died here
yes okay sweets
now we were pushing it on the time there
is that everything
i think that's it okay i'm gonna run
this stuff back oh here's a little bit
more
and we went
to this spot here last time i think
yeah we died over here when we came back
i thought it was here for some reason
oh you don't do that again
no that's probably the same two creepers
that were there darn i forgot about them
all right i'm going home
let's have a little fun shall we
oh come on i wasn't even by it yet
ah
i didn't want that to happen
uh not not a big deal though i didn't
fix that wow it took out a bunch of oh
no
oh no
that's not good let this water go
okay you dodged the wiring that's good
oh and look at that perfect
stopped it right there
all right so i decided to swing by the
mob system again today to try to fix
some of those problems last time we were
here
and i've been watching it for a while we
have we have a lot of problems this
thing's a mess
and maybe we should try to fix some of
these so zombies are supposed to go that
way this is a mob sorter creepers are
supposed to go to the right
he just barely made it skeletons are
supposed to fall
like that that's good that's good
seems to run pretty good if there's not
a lot of mobs but once there's a lot of
mobs it starts to mess up
creeper ran good so far we're batting
ah there we go there's our first problem
so sometimes this trap door is sending
two mobs at a time
when it gets backed up like this
and that causes problems usually they're
still sorting 100
though that's actually surprising
yeah oh well there we go we saw a
creeper fall down the skeleton way
and again i think something i'm going to
try today is
to get more than one cat in this thing
so they're more likely to run
because we just have this one one kitty
cat here maybe if we had three or four
in that one in that spot there they'll
run more likely
i'm also going to try to see if i can
adjust the timing on the strap door make
it a little quicker
although it looks like they're just
getting in
each other's same space because they're
getting pushed so hard so maybe
i'll have to add some way of regulating
this if it gets backed up
stop sending mobs to it
here's another big problem we got this
thing gets backed up
and we have uh water sources up in the
air so the
creepers will just start drowning in
them and the skeletons
uh this thing too this is another big
problem
um where to begin so
i wasn't sure what was wrong with it
last time like
sometimes the creepers would blow up on
the skeleton sometimes they wouldn't
and you guys a lot of you guys suggested
that it was because
the snow golem was shooting the creeper
which
is partially the problem but the thing
is the snow golem was shooting the
creeper
every single time so it doesn't explain
why sometimes the creeper would
explode and sometimes it wouldn't on the
skeleton
um this thing's really messing up now
because it's
because of those other problems
um so i went into a creative world
actually to try to figure out what was
going on here
and i i learned a lot of things and i'm
gonna share those with you so let's head
on over to
uh my creative world and we will we will
check out a few
interesting facts about mob behavior
okay here we are and this is the
experiment i set up to try to figure out
what was going on
we got a skeleton we'll have a creeper
in the middle and the snow golem
and i just wanted to see how they
interact with each other and i learned
to
a few interesting things about mob
behavior from this
and in this experiment i have a button
which makes these pistons retract
for a very short amount of time
and then they go right back so that
gives the snowglobe line of sight to the
skeleton
and the skeleton has line of sight to
the snow golem so
one thing you'll notice this snow golem
he doesn't have a care in the world he's
kind of just
turning his body around he's looking
around
not too interested in anyone at the
moment same with the skeleton he's
he's looking around he's happy uh when i
hit this button though
this snow golem instantly targets the
skeleton
he saw his head his head turn and then
his body turns with him
and then he stays locked onto the
skeleton for
a random amount of time it's it's pretty
short
he instantly focuses on him um he's not
able to shoot at the skeleton until his
body fully
turns and faces a skeleton
so he has no chance of shooting the
skeleton if
if he's not targeting him when i press
this button
um if he is targeting the skeleton
though
i press it there's a there's a random
chance he will actually
throw a snowball at the skeleton
he tried there try it again
and now now that he hit the skeleton
this skeleton he's not so careless
anymore he's he's got
his eyes set on the snow golem but the
snow golem even though he hit him he
still doesn't really care he's still
turning his body around
he doesn't view the skeleton as a target
he only targets them if he gets line of
sight to him again
and just for a certain amount of time
afterwards but this skeleton
he can shoot any time this opens now
and again that's random too
oh okay snow golem shot first and
skelton just shot the snow golem
now if we have a creeper in here this is
where things get interesting
so he's caught in the middle between
these two
let's do this a few times let's try to
try to watch which one
shoots the creeper
come on yeah and it's random
rainy day now
so i think the skeleton shot him first
there
yeah and so what if what it boils down
to
is whoever whoever shoots uh the creeper
first is whoever he targets
and even though he's targeting the
skeleton for some reason creepers don't
look at their targets
necessarily he's still wandering his
around
but if he has line of sight he doesn't
turn to the skeleton but he still
does his sizzle move
now if the snow golem was to shoot him
again it it
doesn't matter he has his target chosen
the skeleton
doesn't matter um
doesn't matter if a snow golem hits them
or another skeleton he's going to set
his eyes on that
that skeleton i think only person that
can make him change his mind is me
maybe we'll try that okay now he sees me
as a target
if i take this out
he's no longer sizzling at the skeleton
so he chooses me as a target over the
skeleton
so this experiment teaches us two really
important things
that we need to keep in mind with our
mob system uh first off
what really matters is who hits the
creeper first
in this case the snow golem did doesn't
matter if th
the skeleton hits him afterwards he
wants
the snow golem he needs the snow going
so he skeleton shot him doesn't care
wants a snow goal now the second really
important thing we learned from this
though is
we get priority over whoever hits them
all right so he wants us even if we go
game mode one he still sees us and look
at this
these two can wail on him he doesn't
care unless i move out of his target
range
then we're no longer seen as a target he
can find a new target and uh
he blows up on these guys
now the challenge with all of this is to
find some way
we can allow the snow golem to shoot the
skeleton
but then when the creeper gets added uh
we need the skeleton to be able to shoot
at the snow golem without the snow golem
shooting at the creeper
so how do we do that well this is what i
team up with here just this little half
slab
is all we needed shove it right in his
face now when we
give him line of sight to the skeleton
you can see he tries to shoot that way
but he's hitting the half slab um
so he's not going to hit the creeper if
the half slap is in his face
uh with mobs they actually see from the
top of their head so if we stick that
like that
now he's blind he can't see anything
that's
as blocking his vision his pathfinding
um
so what we need to do basically
is when the skeleton comes by
open this up let him shoot close it
have the creeper come into place and
then have this in his face
and then open this again you see he
tried to shoot first there
but this blocked it and then the
skeleton shot him
and now he's locked onto the skeleton
and then we just need to make sure that
the trooper can't see me too
and if we do all of that it should work
okay we're back in the let's play world
here and i just want to point out
something
i'm working at revamping the mob system
making bunch of changes to it
uh one one thing i did is i extended the
length of the creeper and the scalping
pipes here
to try to prevent them from clumping up
and uh one thing i also did here is i
added a whole bunch of bends
at the end here it does like a couple of
jig jags
and i did that to try to keep them from
clumping up as well but look what
happens
i've never seen this before if you have
too many bends in the pipe they can get
stuck like that
like there's not nothing in front of
this guy but they keep bumping each
other
which prevents this guy from getting out
of this
this corner because that guy's bumping
him there
and they seem to just get stuck
permanently here
so i'm gonna have to redo this and
straighten up things
wow this is a real problem actually i've
never
i've never seen this before it must be
kind of new
behavior but uh
they can get stuck on any right angle it
looks like in a water system
um i tried adding a trap door here in
that corner
to give them less space to get stuck at
but they still
are getting stuck there for some reason
um the odd time a couple will get
through but then they just get stuck
again
uh only if there's a lot of mobs in here
though of course
but i'm gonna have to regulate it
somehow i'm not really sure how to
though
what i did is i just added up
like an extension to the water stream
here to give them more space
to gather up so they hopefully don't get
uh clumped up and stuck but
that's not that's not working i'm gonna
have to get rid of this
because they're getting stuck on all
these right angles
you can see it a little clearer when
we're inside the tube basically i had
them going straight across here
originally
and they would wait here and this would
open up and they'd fall down
but then i added in this this bend just
to extend it a little bit
but that's causing problems so we're
going to take that out and just have
them go straight through
and find some way to slow them down
uh the main problem we're having with
the mob system is we're just getting too
many mobs in it at once it can't sort
them that quickly
and it gets backed up and then two mobs
start going through at a time or three
and it just
totally wrecks everything uh normally we
have a switch
to to switch between killing the mobs or
sending them through the mob sorter
over here so my plan on to on regulating
this
is i've added a tripwire here
now so if there's if the mobs get backed
up
from like this is the front of the line
here
if they get them up if they get backed
up four blocks to here
uh this truck tripwire's gonna get
triggered
that sends power to all these pistons
and then any more mobs that enter
are gonna falls down to their death
until this this line decreases
so hopefully that
let's works to get this back the way it
was
it goes there let's get out of here it's
really hard
working on this on hard mode
okay so this first time is going to be a
huge mess
because it's not supposed to deal with
this many all at once but
that filled up quick
all right i'll clear this we'll
hopefully see it working properly
but you can see since it's jammed up
it's backed up
uh to where this line is any new guys
are falling straight down now to their
death
instead of going into the line as well
so he just fell
no that's a little short-sighted i
forgot it cuts off the water too
so these guys are just stuck now
let's just watch this for a little bit
shall we i've added in
another piston over there now which
pulls a block down
and there's a second water stream hidden
underneath the
the trap wire there so
so if this stream gets broken here then
this one continues it
and that seems to work okay
i need to make these guys fall further
though because if they stop here
it's not a far enough drop to kill them
when they land there
um this thing's getting kind of crazy
that the actual like
creeper blowing up on skeleton is
working really well now
like just about every time it works
uh ever since we added in that half slab
for the
snow golem let's go up here down to my
last stick here i gotta get food
quickly oh i'm getting some lag
there's so much stuff happening oh my
goodness
okay
skeleton got hit here comes the creeper
snow golem can't shoot him because he's
got the half slab in his face
so skeleton always hits them
awesome um
the way i wired this is actually really
simple too all i did is i hooked
uh from this tripwire there if there's a
creeper in there it
sends power to this and pushes the half
slab
or if there's any mob in there um
so that's working really well we just
need to fix the mob sorter and the
regulator and all that
and this will work like a dream and then
we can figure out what we want to do
with
the mobs exploding afterwards that the
goal is kind of some kind of tree farm
but we might do some other stuff too
we'll see how this goes
but it is working a lot better
blow up oh yeah
all automatic that is so cool
yeah and i added in an rs nor latch
there for
releasing the mobs there's a tripwire
that when they fall
trip i over here that goes to there when
they fall down the tube
it switches that that redstone block
and uh resets it
i don't know i'm gonna put my world up
for download sometime soon again and you
can check this out in more detail
there's a lot of stuff going on here
it's kind of hard to focus on it
well unfortunately that's probably going
to be about it for this episode everyone
uh i know it's on the shorter side but
i don't have internet and i said
if you're watching because i got my
internet back uh maybe not maybe not i'm
gonna try
upload this episode through a cell phone
plan
through data plan and there's a limit of
five gigs on that
so uh this episode i want to keep on the
shorter side because it's probably going
to be about a duke to two gigs
and the upload speed is probably going
to be really slow and there might be
problems so
i don't want a long episode um i wasn't
really able to check my comments too
well so i
got a very special one from someone
that's been involved on the channel for
a very long time it says
hey etho when do you get your internet
back
uh so i said some guy was coming by
later the
in the day that was a few days ago he
never came
he said said he's going to come next
morning and he apologized
next morning he never came all day and
now it's the next day it's friday and
no word apparently it's supposed to come
saturday
but at this point i don't believe a word
that the
that they're saying i don't know when
they're coming
it's supposed to be saturday let's hope
uh so probably no videos till sunday
except this one which might get through
on the cell phone plan
and uh yeah it sucks not having internet
you know it's like every every game
these days needs internet to some extent
like if you play anything on steam
um to get
to get logged in and all that even
minecraft to get your skin going and
that you need to
um you need internet of some sort i
can't play on minecraft server i can't
play feed the beast or anything
but i'm going to try to get a few
single-player things done maybe another
lp episode in that before i get it back
and hopefully have a few videos for you
once i do get it back
so i'm blabbing on here that's the
status so with my internet
but regardless i hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode
and i will see you again next time if if
it comes back
bye
you