[Music]
hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode here
in in our village
[Applause]
look at these dodge skills this guy's
got nothing on me whoa
ah darn it okay enough of that so
something very terrible has happened
guys i've spent a lot of time here doing
the horse thing
getting the horses uh up to the level
they are
we're at 4.25 on the jumping scale
we started all the way down here like at
three
point something another anyway
so it was nighttime i went to go sleep
i've spent a lot of time afk here to do
all this right because every few minutes
like every five minutes i have to wait
to breed them again
um just went to go sleep here notice
that
the house was kind of empty
you know what that means so i looked
around the village
there there are some villagers here
still but a bunch of them
died like i think at least half of them
died
i noticed for sure like there was a
librarian in this well here
and he's gone there's no way he would
have got out
so some somewhere i must have had just a
tiny little dark spot in a zombie
spawned
because i've spent hours and hours and
hours
mostly just like afk in this house here
letting time pass
ah oh well it happens
it happens our poor village though those
were our original villagers we can never
get them back
but i guess we probably shouldn't
exploit them either
not that they really had anything good
[Applause]
um but yeah been doing the horse
breeding thing it's going pretty good
i'm finding it's getting really really
difficult to get any improvement with
these horses now though
and we're not even close to the end of
our line here
all right this guy should be ready don't
shoot me skeleton i said don't shoot me
don't shoot me good job he missed
ah darn it
uh gotta get back to him
get the saddle on whoa all right let's
get out of here
wow i totally missed them all right
let's go check the jump wall
so yeah i think it's been about 14 or 15
breeds since i last got any improvement
with the horses so it's getting a lot
more difficult
that's like over an hour of waiting
uh between breeds and stuff so it takes
quite a while to do this
no no because we're at 4.25
a lot of the times they're far below
that whenever i breed them
this guy is terrible oh man
all right i have not been saving all the
horses
either because there would just be way
too many at the end of this
so i've just been keeping the good ones
this guy
i'm sorry you are not up to code
okay so here's what i want to do today
guys i think today we should
do some stuff in the man tape i i have a
few new projects i want to work on
but also i feel today is maybe
a day we should do our annual
maintenance sort of thing it's not
annual it happens
quite often actually but every so often
i just like to go through the
every little thing i've built in the man
cave and double check it still works
that everything is good so maybe we'll
just check a few things here together
uh this thing is okay
uh let's go i know the storage room is
fine the furnace room is fine i use
those quite often so
i should move these chests so they're
kind of in the way what's the face
lots of books and some random armor
okay this sheep farm i think is working
pretty good currently except for one
thing i never did fix
the blockage where was it i think it was
the white and
gray the water stream is messed up that
carries the wool back
let's just check this out
we'll do all the way down here just to
see what color is making and which ones
don't
oh there goes the shears okay uh water
buckets
i right that's right
okay maybe we'll empty this just so that
we have a clear
idea of what gets there and what doesn't
those take a little moment um
see this room is fine you got light blue
red blue orange
how oh those must have been stuck in the
dispenser
right because i didn't even share those
colors even
okay i think this thing is broken what
green wool why is it not going down
okay there's been some change with the
fences obviously
they're connected now and they weren't
before maybe
okay i'll have to look into that was not
expecting that
that's why we do our our annual check
which is more often than annual this
pearl thing
this works but i have no real good way
of loading it i have to break inside
and then i have to manually put the
ender pearls in the chest here maybe
i'll try to make some way of
of accessing that a little easier
all right i'm going to leave it broken
just so i know
if we go down pretty sure our jukebox is
still okay
yeah mushroom farm
all good melon and pumpkin farm
looks like it's all right
um this thing i know is broken i can't
really fix
it oh that's loud
wait jukebox and no blocks
um that's empty
potions back there if i want to film
okay does this door still work i think
we just tried this last episode
no tom no no
get back get back okay one sec i gotta
get this guy back in there
where are you going stop oh he hasn't
been free in so long and he wants to run
no tom tom dude
look at this guy take off like he is not
stopping
oh come on you can't even go that way
no settle down tom
here i'm gonna trade with you stop
running
stop running i'm never gonna get him
back now
look at this guy he wants in there so
bad
yeah so he sees emerald village over
there and he's trying to get to it
it must count as a valid village still
so there's no way i can get him not to
go there i have to use a minecart to get
him back
or he will fight me the whole way
oh come on furnace minecarts
i know you used to be able to handle
that oh it ran out of coal already
okay don't crush don't crush tom
okay i'm gonna give you one of these
this door is a little brutal
go go go go go go go go go go go go go
go
all right you're good you're home
and he's still trying to get there oh
man
okay uh ufo i know is kind of broken
slime farm i think they're swimming over
the water now so i'll have to look at
that
this elevator
hey the elevator actually looks still oh
well it did that before too though
they must have been like this before
though right like the fence is connected
i wonder if water is just pushing the
the wall further than it used to it's
landing on it instead of like
falling between the space here
not too sure i'm going to change out one
of these with
nether brick fence that way there's the
gap in the middle
and we can still put the pressure plate
on that and then we'll try it out
okay we're gonna try this again see if
it gets stuck again
all right i sheared them all get the
buckets
and what's gonna happen
oh they're they're dropping down that's
a good sign
that is a very good sign let's just
double check the grates make sure
nothing is stuck
that one's fine oh there was some pink
wool stuck on that one
um yeah i think it's the water streams
are pushing them farther than they used
to
for the most part it looks like it all
washed down just
probably a couple lingered yeah i think
we're okay
all right let's run back and
what else was it gonna do oh yeah let's
check the chest here and see what color
is not in there or colors
pressure plates white
i wonder if i put that in there's no
light gray
i don't think the white is supposed to
be there what comes next dark gray
do we have dark grey in here no dark
gray
but we have black so i think those last
three on the left row are
are blocked by something i'll have to
take a look at that
i just added in this thing over here
little secret hidden chest up there so i
can drop
in ender pearls up there pretty easily
don't have to go in behind the wiring or
anything and
it just all washes down doesn't wash
down it flows down
so chest the chest is up there
hoppers chest goes down to these chests
lots of extra storage
and it goes down to the dispenser now oh
that's pretty cool and
let's check to see if this door works
looks good cool
so maybe uh let's take a break from this
fixing stuff and we will go build
something
actually before we can really build
anything i just realized i am totally
out of redstone again always run out of
redstone
stuff is so hard to get speed mining is
the best way i've found of getting it
though
uh if you don't know what speed mining
is it's just this thing where you have
efficiency 5 on your pick and a haste 2
beacon
and then you can pretty much instantly
break stone
and if you go down to like y-12 you can
uncover all kinds of goodies really
quickly it's really
it's actually really enjoyable to do i
like it um
oh we're outside of range of the beacon
but yet getting lots of redstone
which is great look at this
oh it's amazing oh yeah and void fog
checked it out no void fog in the 1.8
release there's not going to be any they
removed it because it was
taking up performance and also it's it's
one of those things
you can do some kind of cool stuff with
it if you like
if you try to use it with your build if
you try to make it
like spooky but uh for the most part
it's just kind of annoying you know
oh well um so i'm kind of glad they
removed it
to be honest you can see all the way to
the other end it's pretty cool
anyway i'm gonna get some redstone then
we will uh
get back to it so i want to build
something here that i'm calling the
flowers on demand farm which is
basically like a little gimmicky farm
for these two tall flowers
in the game of course these are really
really
really easy to farm you can either just
like spam bone meal on them and you get
tons
or you can put dispensers next to them
and and hoppers and it'll automatically
grow and collect them and it's
super easy to get these but i want to
make a farm where you just walk up to
the flower and it grows it right in your
face
you step on a pressure plate and it
grows it and it's it's amazing it's
flowers on demand
yeah all right it's just a little
small little thing here so looking
around the man cave this wall looked
pretty plain to me so this is where
we're gonna build it
this is like the nasty part of the cave
guys right here
look at this it's like just a mess
totally ignored
some people tell me the man cave is is
done you should
move on to something else start a new
world or something like that
we got gravel walls guys look at this
gravel walls we are far from done
uh yep
all right so basically we need a four
wide thing
i just want to put it here all right i'm
gonna build it
out of this spruce wood i think
get we should be able to build this
pretty quick i hope
oh you know what i don't have his dirt
let's just take some dirt from here uh
make the place look even better
all right so do that
and then just going to put that there
temporarily
build up some spruce walls
over here the cave spider spawner is
right
there
um you have to be careful about that i
guess we'll bring this out
do the same for this one
build it up one more block am i out of
spruce no
okay
let's use stairs across the top here
and that's basically the size of the
thing
we're gonna have dispensers at the top
and below these is where the flowers go
so these these dispensers will be able
to grow the flowers
and pressure plates
should we use wood ones i guess we
should use stone ones right because
otherwise if the flowers land
on top of them uh they'll trigger it
without me wanting them to be so we'll
put that there
and now that we place the dirt here
we'll remove it because we gotta go down
um
below these see let's hope
let's hope we don't run into something
here we're gonna put redstone all along
i think
yep i think that's right and then
kind of level with the redstone we want
sticky pistons which i don't have on me
one sec all right guys so i
i just went ahead and built it because
it took like four minutes to build
and it's redstone stuff not everybody
likes redstone
because they're crazy but uh
yeah i'll just give you a quick overview
of the farm and the redstone
so it's the flowers on demand farm
check this out check this out i demand
red roses right now and they get grown
right in your face fresh flowers on
demand how amazing
incredible i want sunflowers look at
this
how could anybody survive in minecraft
without one of these
it's i i have no clue i don't know how i
played this game up until this point
everybody needs one of these
incredible absolutely incredible
uh so yeah it's just like a little
gimmicky farm uh
i'll show you the redstone just really
quick so
uh each of the the pressure plates
corresponds to
each of these rows right and it kind of
goes up
and around there's some repeaters up
there that go to the dispensers behind
these blocks
um basically the pressure plates power
these pistons diagonally
in like a bud switch sort of thing and
then
underneath the pressure plates is this
line of redstone as well that
updates the pistons so that they get
pushed down
um this line of redstone from the
pressure plates also goes to a
clock lock which is just a fancy
term for a redstone torch so when you
step on the pressure plates
this torch goes off and then this clock
can run
uh it's just like a basic redstone clock
nothing fancy
every time it goes around in a cycle it
sends a pulse to this wire here and then
depending on which
piston has its block down the signal can
pass through and it goes up to the
dispensers for
whichever flower you are demanding
and that's it there we go so let's uh
let's go ahead and do something else
here
last episode i asked you guys what
should we do
about project pokemon here because we
have some issues
a bunch of the villagers died when i set
it up originally
i had six slots here even though there
was only five different types of
villagers now there's 11.
oh it's just a big mess and i wasn't
really sure
what to do and you guys
gave me absolutely terrible advice the
worst
ev no you gave me uh the perfect
solution actually
so i think the way we should deal with
things around here
like a lot of the things i've built i
would do differently now
like even even these fences i would
probably build
everything wood in the man tape out of
spruce wood now instead of oak
because i like it a little bit more and
we have spruce fences and whatnot
so i have to kind of question how should
i deal with old stuff
like this should i totally renovate it
or should i
never touch it what's the deal i think
the way we'll
we'll approach this like little
little renovations we can do around the
place i think is a good good idea like i
noticed this today
obviously i'm trying to i tried to make
a smooth transition around this corner
and
it's just terrible isn't it so just a
little detail like this
we would uh definitely redo because at
the time i couldn't bend
or stairs couldn't be bent around
corners like they can now
actually maybe we'll leave that one
does that make sense um so little things
like this i think are okay to change
around the place
but i don't like that
how did i do that i guess i would put
oh you know what i should do i just
should put a full block up there
instead um but i don't think we're ever
going to totally redo something like
this
because i would rather build something
in a new area
than like destroy and reconstruct
something
unless it's totally totally broken um
so the perfect solution you guys gave me
is just to use
doc's switcheroo thing that he has on
the minecraft server
so we have six slots here there's 11
different types of villagers
if we put a switcheroo in we can have
two villagers per slot and that gives us
room for 12.
so yeah we don't have to change a thing
we just have to
hopefully get those put in here
so we let's just check something because
i do have these little pressure plate
things where
it shows these chests i'm not sure if
the wiring for that is going to be in
the way
let's just take a look
all right there's the torch can we go
straight down
oh no look what's down here this is the
clock for the
the potion room door
i might have to move this
[Music]
all right i'm going to try to set up one
of these cells
and see if it's possible or not with the
amount of space we have
so i've looked into it here for a bit
started setting it up i don't think
we're gonna have
much trouble this does not interfere
with the switcheroo thing
which is amazing because they're like
look at these pistons they're all side
by side
but because this redstone torch is going
directly to this piston it won't
power anything beside it which is nice
the switcheroo is very simple we just
need like a block
redstone torch block piston
and then set this at two we've got a
sticky piston down there with the slime
block
and yeah that's it we just gotta power
this block from behind
so i'll probably hook them all up in a
chain
uh added some glowstone for lighting
here the thing that's giving us
trouble though that i'll have to redo
the redstone on
is this door
uh i'll have to change it so it opens
vertically like the
it goes up and down uh because
this oh we can't get to it there
this door these pistons look at this
like
this is for the switcheroo here this
piston and
the wiring is right next to that that's
not going to work
so the only way we can get get more
space is if we move these
sideways pistons and make them vertical
and i guess this is a t
flip flop for this door so i can
tear this out make it smaller and and
what not
i got four of these set up now i just
have the last two to do but these guys
are
kind of in the way i'm wondering if i
can get them to swim
up without killing them
swim up you're aquaman
hmm he didn't seem to like that
oh there he goes
did that actually work you're not
drowning you're good
so this water is to keep him from dying
when i drop him down
so i think he'll just hang in there
until i'm ready for him to
to come back down i'll just remove the
water and he'll fall
i think good good
villager on the loose get back in
yourself
get back on yourself stop playing with
my pressure plates get in there
good good boy
oh man all right i tried to nudge him
he's like right next to this thing
can i
man guy you're making this so difficult
for me maybe i can move them with water
if i'm quick do this so it doesn't leak
out
it should run down and hopefully move
them
that work yeah he's in place again good
so i got it all hooked up and there's a
button here now which will activate all
the switcheroos for all six of these at
the same time
and let's see if it works
gets them down press it again they
should go up
dope oh no
yeah i gotta get rid of that water above
apparently
because they got stuck in it
they got launched into the water oh man
all right let's get rid of it
that one's down oh now this guy's gonna
be out of position
he won't let me out of here guy i'm
trying to
ender pearl don't want to trade right
now
i'm trapped i can't enter pearl
no no
oh that's not good man
what a troll can i get out this way
oh yeah i can get out this way
yeah just have to aim it right there we
go this time it should work
okay
very good everything should be working
now let's give it one more
try yep
so really important this block here is a
upside down piston which doesn't
suffocate them when it crushes
their head which is kind of important
otherwise they would die eventually
um it also lets light through and it
just i had glass there before
which didn't look so good because you
could see like the redstone and the
sticky pistons
so this kind of hides it all which is
nice kind of blends in with the stone
look as well
very cool so i tested this in creative
before i built it and it did a
switch of villagers we don't have two in
here that we can see it just yet but
eventually we'll get them
all in here so i redid the signs as well
we're going to have two librarians in
this one
be a cleric and an armorer in this one
weapon smith and tool smith in this one
leather worker and butcher then farmer
and fletcher
fisherman and shepherd so these two
uh both have brown robes or all four of
these i should say
um so there's the most brown robe ones
there's four of those
there's two of the butcher type ones
there's
only or there's three of the black coat
ones
there's only one purple coat guy
and there's only one type of white coat
so
that's sort of how i decide to arrange
this our goal is gonna be to try to get
as good of villagers in here as we can
in terms of villager trading there's not
a lot of variation anymore just like
little slight variations with the
amounts that they sell and buy and and
the price
um but not too much the only real
randomness is with librarian
villagers because they have the book
trades those can
the cost of those can vary a lot and
also
uh which ones they unlock can vary a lot
so i think somewhere else in our world
we'll have a special area for uh
collecting librarians but uh just
just in general we'll try to get as good
villagers here as we can
oh man i felt like i rambled there i'm
sorry
um moving on let's get to the comment
for today
it says etho by the way this is a was a
comment i got
a lot on the last episode so i wanted to
mention it it says etho the first horse
you tried actually jumped three blocks
he jumped up the full snow block
on the two high section it just couldn't
jump onto the
three and one two five section that
getting late here i'm not doing too well
with my words on to the 3.125
section the three blocks and 1 8 snow
block
math is not good for me right now edit
in fact
all of your jump sections are off by 1
8.
you mark the one high area with 1 8 snow
slab
on top as one the two high area with one
eighth snow slab on top is two and so on
so basically what he's saying is my all
my jump heights were off by 1
8 because of the snow slab but just want
to point this out this is really
important
and it's kind of what makes the jump
wall confusing
when i set it up there right now we're
at 44.0
y over there if we go on a snow slab
nothing changes this doesn't actually
move you upwards
if you have two you get move up moved 1
2 8 3 8 4 8
5 8 6 8
7 8 and that's eight eight of these snow
slabs
uh if we put a block of snow next to it
they're the same height
but if we go on this one we're 1 8 lower
aha so it ignores one of the snow slabs
with
the thing so all the jump bytes are
actually correct
it's just kind of confusing um
anyway so we got a lot done here today
i have uh i didn't quite get to
everything i wanted to do though i
wanted to
fix that door and i know there's a
couple other broken things
let's see what was what was on my mind
let's just go through these i might do
some of these off camera
snow farm the snow golem keeps dying i'm
not sure why
where is he there i do see something
there wait a sec
oh get out my way horse
maybe let's break this oh he is there
he's just not his snow isn't going
through the block anymore
so i got to fix that probably use iron
bars or something
spider farms seem to be working fine we
just built the bunny farm and i think
when i built that bunny farm it's
wrecked this one here
yeah messed up some wiring because it's
supposed to open and close
the gate hey no you don't go out
uh so i wrecked that this elevator i was
supposed to do
today but i never got to it these slime
blocks are supposed to
move up one block um but they're
sticking
and maybe a couple other things but we
got
a fair bit done today i did fix the
the collection thing for the white
light gray and gray wool on the sheep
farm so that's good
um but yeah that's gonna do it for today
guys i hope you enjoyed our episode and
i will see you again
in the next one take care have a good
day
bye
[Music]
you