[Music]
hello everybody this is
etho and welcome back to another episode
of that let's play series if you
remember last time we worked on the bee
farm and we worked on the witch farm and
and what well I did a bunch of work op
camera here I did a bunch of caving in
the area so now the witch farm if you
remember last time was barely functional
now we're actually getting a decent
amount now that the caves are are lit up
pretty well and I did some work on the
bee farm the plan was we were gonna work
on finishing up both firms today in this
episode but the new snapshots out
change of plans we're gonna go check out
the nether I am so excited I decide to
install the snapshot usually I don't do
that you know there's always risk of
technical problems and whatnot but I
think we're gonna be okay with it this
time
all right everybody so here's the deal
with our world our nether hub is roughly
at 0-0 in the nether it's a little bit
off this is the center of our nether hub
like where I'm standing it's like minus
43 and 11 why I didn't just build it at
0-0 I will never know but it's pretty
close to zero zero that's what counts
right um we're gonna go off I think this
Way's our best shot at getting to the
new nether terrain here so we generated
this world during the pre-release that
introduced nether fortresses there
hasn't been many nother updates since
then but there was one that added nether
quartz and the lab of pockets before
that update came into effect I went
around my nether like that's that like a
2000 by 2000 area centered on the zero
zero so I know once I go you see we're
about to get to minus a thousand on the
Zed coordinate once we hit that point I
know that nether quartz is gonna start
showing up in lava pockets when I'm
within that area I'm safe to dig in the
nether and I'll never have to worry
about dying from lava appearing out of
nowhere all right I have gone outside of
this 2,000 by 2,000 border though to
hunt the nether quartz and unfortunately
I've done that in kind of an unorganized
way so with this new update that
introduces new terrain I'm kind of
curious how it's gonna happen if it's
gonna have like a bunch of chunk borders
and stuff we'll find out
but from what I've seen it it doesn't
actually change the nether generation it
just kind of spins it with the new
biomes so I think we'll be okay but we
should we should get to it like just
over this way and just go for a bit I
think nothing yet
maybe I've gone this way I can't
remember should show up pretty soon here
though I would think here we go Oh
hohoho oh yeah the biome switch this is
the warps is it work does it say work
forest that's what's called okay this is
the work force the blue biome with the
warped nether warts right oh there's no
no tool for it dad I didn't expect I
thought there was a tool for it might be
getting added still this doesn't craft
anything so I know a fair bit about this
update but not everything and so I'm
kind of kind of exploring it a bit today
okay so it turns out that was a very
tiny section of the new terrain so I
fool around for a bit I think now I
found where it actually really begins in
our world here so this is what the chunk
border looks like so you can see the
terrain matches like it's the same
height on this side on this side there's
no like big wall or anything so it's
like exactly the same nether terrain
it's just skin differently and yeah so
these are the new trees what are they
called
we got to get used to all these new
names now warp stem this is like like a
would you enter into planks and stuff
which is cool I've heard it's fireproof
we'll test that out maybe later what's
this thing
crimson roots you know I don't think
I've seen that before even I never
noticed that I know there's a vine and I
know there's the mushrooms and this
stuff but I've never noticed the roots
and all the videos I've seen all right
yeah these are the two different shrooms
so we got the Crimson fungi that grows
the red trees and the warp
guy the blue one here grows these blue
trees when you bonemeal them and inside
of these there's a new type of lamp as
well what's it called oh you can harvest
it there's shroom lights looks like you
know I thought they only generated like
one inside but it looks like there's a
lot inside some of these this one I'd
like and inside I don't know if that's
cuz okay bunch of trees merged but okay
interesting interesting
let's try do something here so look look
over here like this
this ground is different than this are
they the same no okay that's uh that's
one of the tree blocks isn't it is that
in the ground in places yeah over here
too ok so they mix it into the ground a
bit to give it a bit more texture yeah
so this update adds a whole bunch of new
sounds to the game as well like block
placing and breaking sounds that sounds
pretty crisp this is like squishy though
and both with like the new blocks and
some of the old ones as well so like
planks these are the same as normal
planks nothing exciting about that but
the new wood is really weird listen to
this it's like kind of squeaky and it
kind of sounds like you're taking
pebbles or something or you got a rock
in your shoe
it's it's a bit weird the shroom light
sounds amazing
kind of echoes when you place it a bit
like her reverberates
oh I think that's the same sound as this
stuff the nigh Liam so it's cold night
Liam yeah that's what I'm going to call
it mycelium and now Liam they're kind of
pairs that yes yeah this stuff sound
sounds kind of firm but it's also got a
softness to it like you are walking on a
fungus or something or a fungi
then netherrack sound is very weird now
listen to this it's like I'm hearing
voices at the the end of the the walking
sound I don't know if it's just me and
then this tree stuff is a little bit
softer it's almost like walking on sand
oops it's also a bit squishy you know it
sounds it sounds pretty good I like it
let's do a couple more tests here so we
can still touch this stuff for sure can
we if we fortunate do we just get
netherrack no we get it as well okay so
you always get that stuff no matter if
I'm still touch it or not I brought over
some goodies with us as well to test up
some things so I believe you can spread
this to the netherrack if you bonemeal
it it'll go down a step does it go down
- probably not doesn't look like it
okay okay does it go diagonal I kind of
doubt it but we'll try it oh it does I
was a good thing we tried it uh-huh okay
that's neat and then when you harvest it
let's double check we get it yeah we do
let's see I want to check out this
crimson root stuff because I actually
didn't know about it cannot bow mail it
okay so it's probably just decorative
but these these you can grow I'm pretty
sure with the bow meal oh you can't
place it on the tree blocks just the
nice see Liam not nice see Liam oh I'm
gonna do that a lot aren't I it's nyam
alright can we grow it yeah so this is
the red tree and these will generate
with the vines on them even which is
pretty cool they also will generate the
shrew might stuff shroom light not true
might uh-huh and this is just nether
work nether work blocks so there's an
easy way to farm nether word now like
tons of it all at once because even
or did they change
you used to or is that something only
you can do and modded you can uncompress
this and mod it for sure
I just maybe not in vanilla I've been
playing too much modded maybe unless
they made a sea-can anymore and I'm
going crazy okay Crimson's damn
so you get a different kind of wood with
it let's listen to sounds probably the
same sound same sound ok and you get
this kind of rune wood actually looks
pretty good I like that stuff a lot the
blue is cool too but it's like really
weird right it's gonna be hard to use
that in builds I think although it
probably looks good with spruce wooden
stuff - I don't know it's gonna be gonna
be fun trying out this new stuff in
builds oh man we got to move a little
quicker here we're like 10 minutes into
the episode already hey we've got a
bunch of biomes to see here still but
yeah this one's pretty cool I like it a
lot like having the blue mixed with the
red it just looks so good alright uh
also important to note we have only
Enderman spawning in this biome so no
Pigman I haven't seen any gasp spawn in
it let's go ahead and check the night
vision here oh that makes a lot easier
to see actually so at one comment I
would like to make maybe like one
improvement I would like to see the
biome like the ground looks pretty full
I think that guy walked in from the old
section by the way but like underneath
the nether egg is kind of plain I would
like to see some some plant growing
underneath the netherrack especially
like if you look at the roof it's really
in from still there were more vines and
growths on the ceiling it would look a
lot better I think but definitely huge
huge improvement as is let's go look for
for the other ones here now
[Music]
little never fun I'm surprised
and we're gonna turn the hostile
creature soon all the way down to one
because we are now in the soulsand
Valley guys which only spawns gas which
is pretty interesting
oh and does he know animals from the
worked one I should have brought my my
bow or something yeah let's see if the
fire goes out on that actually will let
it will let it sit there yeah this is
basalt guys kinda I really like the
texture like on the top part of it
it's got like this circle ish mixture
I'm sure the sides don't look bad either
do they kind of like steals or bark sort
of we can break it with a pic not with
the axe or the shovel and this has no
crafting uses as of right now I believe
this is double check yeah nothing
nothing just for decoration so it kind
of like forms from the ceiling and looks
like it's a pouring down so cool
the fire turns blue when it's the
neutral sand what is it called soul soil
aha so you can't mine it with with the
shovel not yet not with pic not with AK
so i'm guessing they're gonna implement
that before the final release probably
old yet with the shovel if I was to
guess how deep this is basalt go like
where it strips it's just one layer
thick
I guess okay let's try plant the work
fungi you can plant it on the the Seoul
soil and you grow it we're gonna be able
to grow it guys you weren't able to grow
it why is it because it doesn't have
enough space because I'm a bad gardener
is that what's happening or what is this
what is the reason let's try maybe it
needs light and out it needs light I
can't place torches on soulsand
wait has that always been a thing yet
I don't think that's always been a thing
hasn't maybe has I don't use Sol Sam
very much I'm starting to realize I
don't know this game as well as I
thought I did something about this
updates bringing out a lot of questions
in me I can't get the girl I don't think
you can grow it on the this whole soil
let's get a bit further into this he's
nasty thing okay so we got some
structures in the biome as well boom
blocks which got a new sound by the way
oh yeah and skeleton spawn in here I
love that skeletons and yes your two
favorite mobs in the game definitely not
annoying at all let's get out of here
the further you get into this thing the
more annoying it gets now it's like only
guests and skeletons if you're by work
for us they'll get a few Enderman metal
pick up the mob gap but now it's just
like the nightmare
make it stop wait there's an Enderman in
here I don't think you teleport in okay
maybe Enderman spawn here too or unless
listen to profile soul sand belly still
huh oh man I'm getting I'm getting
pummeled how's my armor doing we're
doing okay okay so blue fire does hurt
you by the way
this is an easy easy way to get bone
blocks now like I know we had the
fossils before but like those were
underground right now we actually have a
way to get them above-ground that are
pretty pretty frequent this is gonna be
the worst biome for sure like I can't
stand it here it's a cool biome I love
the blue fire but the mobs the mobs guys
it's brutal and survival it's bad
yeah so you can place torches on the
soul soil it looks like it's important
to note it doesn't slow you down like
soul sand or slow sand as us oh gee
players like to call it it does have a
drop down to it as well so this is a
whole block in height okay I'm out of
here
we gotta go sees other biomes the
Crimson forest the crimson forest dark
crimson forest crimson for dark crimson
fire wins
Horace the Crimson forest the die
crimson yeah so I think out of the three
biomes that got introduced the crimson
forest is probably my favorite it's very
similar to the work
so honestly it's just different colors
right but I do think the would like the
Redwood here is better than the blue
would like I love how that looks so cool
we have the vines here and these are
amazing I'm gonna be using these like in
the overworld a lot too I think
cuz they look really good they grow on
their own like if you just leave them
they grow I think up to 20 some blocks
can weibo me on the max let's check that
out I'm gonna have to investigate them a
little further but yeah these things I
can't bomyeo can't bone meal them really
I thought we would have been able to I
think when you harvest them only gets
one block but if you break the top one
it gets them all okay does it drop them
although that's let's check that out
so we got weeping vine sets they're
called so if we break this block there's
one two three below it so we should get
four right we got four okay so it does
collect all them if you harvest from the
top that's cool I wanted to show you
this though let's go back to the I'm
gonna forget it again
Seoul San Billy didn't you stole the
names so the basalt by the way it does
like it can drip a long ways like it
goes all the way from there down and
when it hits the lava it actually
spreads out on the lava it doesn't like
just go like a single one by one pillar
down into it you know it actually
settles on the lava which is pretty neat
yeah so check it out in the crimson
forest we do get zombie pigmen spawns
and I don't know if it's me not being
observant or what but have they always
had glowing cloths or is that new I just
finally noticed it today I don't know if
that's been the game for a while yeah
these are the new guys over here these
are the hagglunds brand new mob that
only spawns in the crimson forest I
think they're supposed to be aggressive
eventually if I understand that right
but right now there there is a glitched
out they're weird their hitbox is
smaller than it should be
what how do we do that again f3b
it boxes shown look at timing that thing
is same size as a big one there there's
a little there's a little good stuff you
hit them their feet fly like crazy right
now they don't fight back they don't
really do anything if you kill them
right now they're dropping zombie flesh
it would be cool if they got a unique
drop or something but spirit mallets
that's what it is
but yeah look at this place it's pretty
nice so we mostly have the red fungi in
the red forest but we do have some of
the blue ones scattered in kind of the
inverse of the work forest and you guys
might find this funny this like it's
kind of blew me away just now
I never go exploring in the nether right
because like I got it all pre generated
and stuff I haven't seen ravines before
it until today they got added in a while
ago though like in the 1.13 and I just
like I think I've seen tiny ones but
I've never seen anything like this like
a big giant or being cut out
he's new for me so I thought this was
kind of neat actually we got is that
them no that's a assault there is a new
or in the game as well the nether right
with new armor new tools better than
diamonds and I would like to try get a
set of that apparently it doesn't spawn
exposed to the air though so if you want
it you have to hunt it down and only
like four of them spawn per chunk like
from ground to the ceiling and a 16 by
16 area I think only four will spawn in
there so it's extremely rare and since
you can't see it you you're gonna have
hard time finding it I'm just looking on
the walls to see if the ravine would cut
it and make it exposed but I'm not
seeing any yeah even if it did like
you'd have to still get pretty lucky
with that so I would like to try to get
some of that the cool thing about it is
it's blast-proof and I think Mojang did
that on purpose like I think they had a
they had something in mind
I honestly think like the best way of
getting it is gonna be with TNT um
you're gonna have to be careful of you
do it though cause like we got the
hidden lava pockets all over the place
you might be setting up your TNT and
then it suddenly catches fire but like
netherrack as a very little blast
resistance though TNT works pretty good
in the nether and we're gonna just blow
it a chunk here and see if we get lucky
I still think it's gonna be hard to find
even even with the TNT though this stuff
is so stinkin rare all right let's do
two stacks and just see what happens
they both run it run it down here yeah I
like how it's blast resistant that's
that's a really cool feature and you can
move it with pistons so it's a blast
resistant block that can be moved which
is brand new that's gonna be big in the
game I think okay let's let's do it here
let's get our flint and steel
let's get another night vision going I
actually like that a lot here last one I
brought flint and steel I have been
trying to share some stuff too and it's
not really doing anything special
I'm scared okay we're gonna live who
guess another courts only problem is the
lab of pockets man I hate lava pockets
so much oh they're gonna make such a
mess if you use a TNT all right let's
see if anything got exposed with that
like I'm pretty sure that's gonna be the
way to do it otherwise you gotta spend
so much time mining like it would be in
the middle of the air most likely if it
did work but yeah I don't see any I'm
gonna do a few more blasts and see if I
get lucky with it I've been like I knew
I'm gonna go a little lower
oh wait a minute wait a minute wait a
minute what is that is that basalt
basalts gonna be tricking me the whole
time I think no that's one we found one
it didn't really fully expose it but
yeah that's that's it right double-check
the blast resistance on this thing yeah
if a tnt was there it wouldn't blow it
up yeah that's our first nether right
guys the very first one Oh new recipe
I'm gonna frame it
I might take special care of it ancient
the breeze so you got to smelt it and
then it turns into nether right
[Music]
not seen I know we blasted through
and nothing the thing about it those
it's like a brownish color and it looks
like soulsand a lot of times or basalt
so it's really really not easy to spot
did you see it there is one we actually
got another one it's up over there so
that's pretty cool the deity's is not
too bad not too bad because it's
blast-proof though like if tnt does hit
it kind of shields the blocks in urine I
think so it might make it hard to well
you might not get exposed a lot of the
times the air it might just be on the
surface I want to make sure I don't lose
it here number two no I got no idea
where that was
no clue all that stupid yes
don't don't setup TNT in the sauce and
belly whatever you do dang it
ah is there any way I can figure out
where that was any way at all I had to
on me and they're gonna be gone forever
[Music]
actually no all my stuff blew up right
like there's no way even the stuff in
the chakra box this I think dang
horrible horrible way to end it anyways
hope you all enjoyed I'm out of here
no I'll do the comment of the day I am
I'm a little butt hurt right now though
that was one of my worst deaths ever
it's gonna take me a while to recover
from that one gotta get all my tools
back we lost two nether right lost my
Trident my beautiful Trident
it wasn't our first Trident though
thankfully I should probably put that in
a special place we lost our first nether
right though and he's for sure let's do
comment of the day let's take our mind
off of it so oh yeah actually wait a sec
wait a second so I was fighting on
crafting a set of nether right armor and
playing around with it not gonna happen
now this episode but I did want to
mention something I feel very strongly
about this and sometimes things I say
actually reach the Mojang team-colored
beacons you know it took took a couple
years and probably a few other people to
mention it to them but eventually we got
colored beacons and a few other things
worked that way as well so I'm gonna
really push my case on this and I want
you guys to push me Mojang on it as well
they need to make the nether right armor
diable like the leather armor can be
died like I felt this way very strongly
about them doing it with diamond armor
as well but it didn't really make sense
with Diamond armor cuz diamond armor is
blue right it doesn't look good with a
lot of other colors also diamond is a
real world material and we kinda don't
associate dying with diamonds but nether
right is their own made-up material it
can have whatever properties they want
right it could be diable and it's gray
so it works like with every color in the
in the world right and if they could add
some way of like adding symbols or
different textures like customizable
different textures
to the armorer Oh even better and that
would be what it's colored amazing
people pay big money in video games to
customize their avatars it's a
no-brainer
Mojang need to do it with the nether
right Armour because late game minecraft
that's what everyone's gonna be wearing
from now on it would be a real shame if
it's just gray and forever gray and
can't be customized that's my case
that's what I'm putting out there
hopefully you guys can get the Mojang Oh
Ethel and your insistence on pure
vanilla data packs for easy dispenser
crafting they make everything easier so
last episode I mentioned they really
need to change the dispenser recipe
somebody I couldn't find the comment on
it but somebody had a great suggestion
they just need to change it to I always
forget which way do it it's like that
right something like that if they did
that use a dropper three sticks and
three string then you don't have to
worry about like doing it one at a time
you can do stacks at a time this way and
it's the same exact amount of materials
in the dispenser recipe so I think
that's the solution they should just
change the dispenser recipe to that
problem solved as far as like keeping
things vanilla still planning on keeping
clean Spagnola
no data packs ever in this series and
the only other rule is I'm not allowed
to use dupes even if they are vanilla
and I'm gonna try stick to that one as
well
oh and just to clarify I didn't word
that the best like I said people pay big
money for customizing their avatar and
Mojang need to get on that I don't mean
like Mojang's should charge people for
it I think it should be free I'm just
trying to make the point that people
it's something people really want to the
extent that in a lot of games they're
willing to pay money for customizing
their avatar even so like it's something
people really want Mojang's should make
avatars more customizable we have our
skins which is great but they covered up
by the armor most of
right so yeah hope you all enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
until next time take care have a good
one
bye bye
[Music]