[Music]
hey what's up everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode here in our let's play
world
i'm having trouble with my voice note to
myself don't eat ice cream before
recording anymore i have i've had like
this frog in my throat and i just can't
get rid of it
ah it drives me crazy you know like when
you have an orange or something you get
that sticky saliva
feeling in your in your throat no matter
how many times you swallow it doesn't go
away
kind of got that with the ice cream
right now
all right i think i think it's going
away maybe not
how you guys doing think things okay
things
things all right with you things are
very good with me
yeah i know you didn't ask but i'm doing
fine
uh i wanted to show you guys this check
this out uh
what do you think about this idea i
decided to try
um like this was just all grass here
before right
and it goes from like green to to yellow
like a really sudden switch here is it a
good idea to
mix in path blocks here to try
ease into it a little bit is that is
that a good look
i'm not sure i thought i would try it
though let's see what you guys say about
it
path blocks i really didn't like them at
first i thought i would never use them
but i'm starting to like them more and
more
more the more i use them
around the place here and they're really
easy to like just put in you just right
click
you have to break and replace anything
which is nice
uh so to start off with here today guys
let's head down to
uh the tunnel again we're not really
gonna work on it today i just wanted to
show you
one of the changes i made with it since
last episode because i asked you in the
comments
like should i just fill it up with
leaves or something
i don't even know where it is it's so
hidden
there we go
like should we do this and some of you
like this
some of you didn't it's uh a lot of you
wanted me to like change out the the
ground with grass and
and all that kind of stuff so i did it
um i also experimented with the path
blocks down the middle here which
i think is a pretty cool look we're
gonna we're gonna go for the details i
tried to get away with uh
not adding details but it sounds like a
lot of you guys want me to just do it
and uh long term i'll probably
regret it if i don't so
so yeah we're gonna probably widen the
tunnel in places a little bit like on
the sides here
so we can add a few uh random things to
it like
some trees maybe some little structures
like little houses
someone suggested i should get some
villagers in here
maybe we'll do that we'll see
uh some rivers would be cool like kind
of winding throughout the place
uh but again we have to do do it kind of
quick here
don't want to spend forever on this
project oh man it's coming back
i still got the frog in my throat i
took a drink of water here so i think
that that'll help
feeling a little better now i can talk
all right so we're gonna head up to the
library here
aha it's been a while i know
one of the most requested projects is
always
for me to finish the library etho
are you going to work on the library
when are you going to finish the library
etho it's been a while since you worked
on the library
i see the comments i know i know this is
a tough build for me though i don't know
why
it's like a fairly big structure and
i'm not very good at building big
structures
like the nexus is easy for me because
it's like all redstone but this is
actually like decorative stuff which i
i struggle with uh but i figured we
would start working over here today
so it kind of goes up the stairs and
then nothing here
nothing here nothing here
maybe we'll try to make a section up
here for the comment of the day
because the idea one of the ideas with
the library was that we would uh
make a a place to store those
right now they're all just like in the
man cave and chess they don't take up a
lot of space
but we'll give them a proper spot here
we also have all these villagers
oh right okay it's like what
there's no way something killed them
they're encased in glass but i don't
know if i had
yeah i never filled these ones
that my heart just stopped there
honestly
it's like where did they go
how did this happen all right we're good
okay so let's see how should we do this
so this is going to get built up it also
snows here so i really want to put a
roof on this place because uh
is this going to keep snow in here no
matter how many times i remove it
there's always going to be snow on the
ground until we actually get a roof in
here
uh maybe we will do
sections for chess like a little
little like three wide sections maybe
so we'll do this and actually
maybe we should start here all right
let's try to figure this out
we'll just put down a big floor here for
right now let me put carpet over top
this or something else later
how is this going to meet up so i feel
like we need
we need to have another post over here
okay i think what we'll do here i'm
going to try put in a window on the side
here i kind of want this to be the edge
of the building i don't want it to get
any bigger
because it's already a little bit on the
big side
and it's so easy just to just keep going
but every block you add is so much more
work
so i want to like end this building now
it can't go any further
and like like we did before here
the windows these big windows we did
light gray stained glass
and oak wood on the sides i had a little
trouble picking
picking those blocks but uh
like i'm not sure i'm totally happy with
these colors but we'll do this
for right now anyway just to keep it
consistent so we got oak on the border
and then light gray for the window
all right can i place this yes yes
and can i do it while falling
no i missed it i tried okay
i don't know how tall this building is
gonna be just yet so i'm not gonna
tap it off just yet uh let's do this
make this go up then and now we know
where this post is i kind of wanted to
figure this out
so if that post is there let's go every
third block maybe
so something like this there'll be one
section here
go again do another section here
and then we got kind of got to curve it
around
so could we do this
and maybe we'll stagger them oh but then
it's only two wide here
that's no good okay what if we
do it like this then
i'm imagining something i just realized
you can't see what i'm imagining
and my commentary on this is terrible
isn't it okay
yeah this is what i had in mind here so
we have four sections of chess
six chests in each these are trap chests
in the middle so they
they go together that's 24 right
and then we're gonna mirror this onto
that side over there when we build it
so in total that's that's uh what is it
chess which is quite a bit of storage
um my plan is i just checked it out
apparently we started comment of the day
back in episode 204
the most comments we've ever done in an
episode
most we've ever read is five usually we
only do one or two though sometimes
three sometimes
four in the past try to keep it to one
or two now
just because uh i only want it to be
like a one or two minute section of the
episode
and uh getting more and more repeat
comments the longer we do this so
it's harder to find a whole bunch of
them um
yeah so i think what we'll do is kind of
break it up out like this every 10
episodes
we will dedicate one chest to all the
comic books so
this one here will be episodes 200 201
all the way up to 209 and this one will
be 210 to 11 to 12 all the way up to
219.
all the way up to two 230
no 229 you know what i mean
kind of like that and episode 260
all right 260 270 280 290
300 310 so then we'll start 320 at the
bottom here
320. i think it's better to do it
horizontal like this instead of like
200 210 220 230 i like it more like this
i think
okay so with this section here we go all
the way from episode number 200
all the way up to episode 439
which we haven't hit yet so all the
episodes we've done up to this point
with comments of the day will fit into
this area here which is pretty cool
and then i started uh mirroring this a
lot of the stuff we built onto this side
so guess how far it goes up to are you
good at math it goes all the way up to
episode
670 if there's ever episode 670
we will have a spot for the comment of
the day now
so doesn't need a lot of storage and we
have tons of it now
um so yeah got this section done here
i was going to try something we still
have this empty area in the back here
instead of just putting like wood back
there or something i wanted to do
uh the whole or the old stained glass
trick
all right i did this on the
the tree i built on the minecraft server
i liked it a lot
we're gonna do like green stained glass
behind here
and then green clay
you can actually mix like two colors
together doing this like you can go
green glass yellow clay in the back and
it makes it a unique color you know
a lot of uh a lot of choices that way
all right but we'll just do green and
green here
dude i'm over here and see what this
looks like and then just so it's
nice and lit up we're gonna put some
glowstone in the bottom too
maybe we'll go one more layer down here
or is that overkill that might be
overkill i will just do it
okay then fill this in
all right let's go see what that looks
like
oh and is it cool yeah i like that
it just creates a cool effect i liked it
a lot
all right so i'm going to do that with
all the chests here and then
i had an idea for this middle thing
my wings are like pushing me into a wall
there
it's like making me look at the log all
right
yeah so i was trying to i've been trying
to decide what to do here for a long
time i had an idea of maybe
having an elder garden bound elder
guardian bouncing up and down
i i had another idea today
i don't think everybody's gonna like it
though i might not like it either
we'll see um but i have an idea for a
statue
i feel like it should be something that
stands out a little bit this might stand
out a little too much we'll see
and bam so there we go
uh it's a little bit of a corny idea but
we'll see what you guys say about it
meets uh what was what was i gonna call
her
uh or him her or him you know
villagers they're not male or female
they're just villagers so it's
this could be a guy or it could be a
girl it's kind of like a
grandma haircut or a crazy professor
haircut it could be one or the other
i was gonna call let's see granny
grannypa wither bottom
yes that that was the name i thought of
legendary
legendary librarian of the villagers the
very first
librarian all the villagers
know and respects him or her so it's
only fitting that she would
look over this library right
sure why not so it's like
it's a villager head i had to shrink it
down a little bit because villager heads
are kind of like an eight by eight
i made it five wide here so some of the
details were a little hard to
bring out uh but i just made the the
mouth and eyebrows
three wide and instead of having like
one block for emerald one block for a
quartz block i just
did like a stair and emerald combination
here
and then to to bring it home i added a
wig
and grandma grandpa glasses
let's uh let's check it out from a few
angles too i didn't really do that yet
from down here can we see it
you can see it's especially if we back
up over here this is like that
the prime spot though a little bit hard
to see it from this angle actually
uh what about from up here
oh yeah and i i did do all the stained
glass stuff so that's all in place
i think it looks pretty cool uh we do
have
like red carpet in this place i might
change it out with a green carpet i
haven't decided that yet so
if it is green carpet this will probably
match it a little bit better
can't see the eyes the glasses you
really see those glasses
uh-huh anyways that's the idea that's
probably all the work we're going to do
on the library today we got quite a bit
done here though
so uh next up here guys there's
something i've been wanting to do for a
while and i just haven't gotten around
to it yet
gonna need that it is the 1.9 updates
right
the combat updates let's do some combats
oh baby i wanted to try fight a wither
with the changes that they've made let's
grab a shield i don't think the shield
would
really work though right we'll try it
screen blocking with the shield there we
go
yeah so like last time i fought a wither
in my world here it was actually
pretty difficult i had to use all the
potions
like it's easier if you fight it
underground obviously
because uh can't get away from you we're
gonna want one point
yeah those are the long ones okay we're
gonna need instant health
just kind of want to clean out these
potions if i ever like grab too many
potions i usually drop them off here
instead of running all the way to uh the
lab
i guess we do want strength eat or no we
want that we want the better ones okay
let's go to the lab
grab some potions there all right
because yeah we want to we want to get
fully decked out here because i
don't know if i'll be able to do it
because the sword swinging is a lot
slower now so
it's anybody's guess if i'm gonna die
here or not
okay we get some speed potions okay so
we're gonna go for
eight instant two potions we got three
regions
two speed potions two strength twos fire
resistance
golden apple uh shields
i have a power five bow and
oh what happened to my sword i put away
all my
like good stuff like my elytra wings and
all that stuff i didn't want to bring it
with me i forgot to put away my axe
actually
and i want my i want my sword back okay
so we got a power five
bow only a sharpness four sword but it
should be fine i hope
all right and i did take one of my good
helmets because i have two of them
protection for chest piece blast
protection i think we really want blast
protection for this fight
actually we want smite for the sword
don't we
maybe i'll double check maybe we do have
smite i'm gonna put blast protection on
my pants
all right so that should be pretty close
to maxed out on the blast protection and
protection okay
do we have a smite sword we can use
you know all those garbage swords you
don't want eventually
you might actually you want to use them
no do i really not have any smite swords
i am surprised okay smite four
i am correct in thinking that smite is a
good thing right
i hope so all right we'll take a smite
four
smite is good right
i i'm thinking it is but now i can't
quite remember
and i don't really want to look it up so
i just will just roll with it
okay so we're gonna we're gonna take off
here i think we got everything we want
yeah we look pretty fully decked out
here uh we're gonna fly on over to
i think it just turned day time too this
is pretty good we're gonna fly over to
the desert where we usually do the fight
and any second at the top okay here we
go
oh i took my wings off oh no oh i forgot
oh are you kidding me did i really just
do that i told you guys it's gonna
happen
people are gonna do it that's the first
time i i did it
oh i had ender pearls i didn't even
think i'm saving myself this is like
nope i'm done
all right i'm gonna go get my stuff back
and uh
delete this footage okay guys this is it
we're gonna do it uh we should heal
faster in this fight though even though
we attack solar we should
heal faster in this update that gives us
absorption regen two we still want to
take the normal region
actually let's do the fire resistance do
the speed potion
uh get the strength ready instant health
region
okay yeah i think we're we're good to go
it's been a long time since i last did
this a little nervous
all right back up regen
strength and get backups ready
just killed my horse it's all good it's
all good as long as not me
all right here we go
i haven't taken any damage i've taken a
lot of damage
taking more damage okay but he's almost
down
yeah oh okay taking really lots
and lots and lots of damage now
oh please don't kill me i have so much
blast protection
i died no way
i i didn't expect that
really so why was i taking so much
damage
um because i had like just about maxed
out protection and blast protection
was i oh i might have been hungry and i
just didn't notice i don't think i eat
at all did i i'll have to watch it back
i'm surprised
by that outcome actually oh man i guess
we can't even fight him again here the
the other armor i have
is pretty much junk fire protection on
this one
i thought i had more armor around
protection three that's not gonna work
i have one more statue down here let's
check it
um couldn't find any diamond pants
though
there's a chess piece okay that's good
uh that's decent too i wonder like
i had protection on my top two pieces
and blast protection on my bottom two i
i always assumed that they could work
separately
without maxing each other out
maybe i'm wrong on that like it almost
seemed like blast protection wasn't
working there
to me i'm gonna do some more research on
that
i checked the wiki and uh it wasn't
really clear either like
did i calculate my protection from the
helmet and then the chest piece and then
it saw
like i was maxed out and then the blast
protection got ignored i don't know
because you can only have like four
or two uh level four things and one
level
three and then you're maxed out for
something
[Music]
i don't know anyways i'm gonna do some
research i'm gonna do some grinding too
next time to get some new armor
we didn't lose our tools thankfully
and we do have this stuff too which is
good uh but anyways i think we'll have
to call it here for today guys
here's the comment i picked out and we
now have a place to put it
it says etho why do you still have a
geforce gtx
770 you could get a gtx 970 for about
the same price
or go even for a 980 980 ti
every youtuber i watch has gotten rid of
their gtx 700 series guard and upgraded
to a gtx 900 series
i don't play a lot of like triple a
games
uh minecraft doesn't need a good
graphics card
and pretty much all the games i play
don't really need
too much of a graphics card ark survival
is probably the hardest
hardest game for me but i can still play
that at 30 fps even with my
770. so i'm
i'm not really anxious to get a new one
just yet
yeah i'm at the two-year mark now with
my new computer i usually get a new
computer every three years so in one
year
maybe even sooner i'll probably get a
new computer that'll have a good
graphics card again
uh-huh so there's no real real need to
do it yet
uh anyways hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode
and i will see you again in the next one
thank you for watching
have a wonderful day take care
bye bye
[Music]
you