hey everybody this is etho how are you
doing we are at the library agent today
and we're going to work on this little
bits and maybe do some other stuff but
first I got a new trick to show you I
was just playing with this this is fun
you ready check it out it's awesome here
we go ah let's start over here and the
cool all right
yeah so I was looking at this library
check this out we got a little bit of a
problem which is definitely going to
have to be changed like I like how it's
going so far I start adding some I don't
know what you call like little tower
areas here I was going to build up a
little bit higher length to the second
or second story or maybe even taller who
knows there's gonna be Windows and these
nice diagonal windows and that kind of
thing but if you go to here that would
make it a total of like 60 blocks from
here to all the way to the other side
which is way way too big let's get real
here this is going to take me forever to
finish if I do that and even if I don't
do that it's continued forever probably
so we got to make a library smaller this
is uh it's getting a bit crazy so what I
think we're going to have to do is let's
let's take out one of these sections
even though I really like the window
this wide I think we should take out
like cut it's here that will bring it
down at least 4 blocks both sides so
that's a total of 8 that I'll bring it
down to about 50 I would like to have
something like this in the corners like
a tower but we should make it some
or so we will maybe only make it come
out to here and instead of having this
nine blocks stretch we might make it
down to five or so yeah we just got to
make things smaller this is this is too
crazy so I'm going to resize some stuff
here and see how that goes all right so
I resize the left side and we can
compare the difference to the right side
it's a fair bit smaller now and you know
I think it's going to be okay
everything's going to be just fine don't
worry so that's what we'll go with
and I resized this tower we can see how
much closer it is now compared to before
like just I counted this this is like
one two three four five six seven eight
nine you know we're going to be like
probably about 10 blocks shorter on both
sides or 20 blocks total which will make
it about a 40 to 50 wide building and
we'll do that 40 to 50 long as well
because it's going to look really weird
if the front is shorter like the front
side if it'll look weird if we have the
front here and the building is wider
than it is long you know so we got to
make it go at least 40 50 blocks this
way to balance out the look of the
building and I put some trapdoors up
here I've got to do some more changes
into the top and yeah the windows the
windows we will do and might make this
come up one more then have glass panes
this stone brick will change to clay
most likely as well let's see let's make
it been
let's do a window like this where we
have just a beam in the middle here
where else we could break it into three
sections instead of two I will do it
like this for now to see how that goes
to do to go around and then we'll have
another break here I guess
the inside of the library itself I'm
going to build mostly out of wood
because from pictures I've seen most
libraries like fancy ones are all wood
inside and they look really nice so like
things like this clay and that we can
easily hide with stairs or or something
and have it and they shape still okay so
what I got to do now let's get a bunch
of cobblestone and dirt to fill in this
hole we have here and then flatten out
this mountain and maybe I'll lay out the
overall shape of the building too just
so we can get idea of what we want it to
look like this mountain this is a bad
mountain it's in our way we got to move
it so I've called in the help of a
demolition expert to help us out and
he's a bit shy guy hey alright so he's
he knows what he's doing here he's gonna
blow it up for us hopefully
I hire only the best nicely done okay
not quite sure how you came to be so so
quickly there but nice to meet you too
that should do for a bit we'll probably
have to clear more but that'll do us
some space to work anyway
so I gotta clear out the fragments
actually one of the nice things about
this building project is my soil supply
is pretty low so I've been able to strip
this mountain clear and replenish it or
whatever we need it for in the future oh
what a mess mm-hmm
yes very good very good what's good we
got this area cleared out now except for
this I got tired of clearing so we'll
leave that for today and we'll just work
on some other stuff so from here to the
other end now is 42 blocks and I marked
from here to this end about 40 42 blocks
is at the gravel here so that's about
the size of our building we're going to
be making which if I remember correctly
is actually about the same size as my
old storage room so it's a decent sized
building and it's gonna be two layers I
believe that's what we're going to go
for so yeah so I when I marked this out
I just made it a straight line but we
will try to add more character to this
wall later we'll give it some some you
know curves or jigs or something and so
it's not straight and
fronts looking good let's work on the
front a bit since we got that going
already let us grab well actually I
think we got everything we need let's
let's go over this okay so we got these
stairs they're going to bring us up to
sort of a platform up here and I've
talked about wanting a balcony area up
at this level here so I think we'll make
the stairs come up like so they will go
if we keep going straight we're going to
come to a 3x3 door that is the main
entrance to the library let's go a
little bit further and then there's also
going to be to 2 more staircases here I
think we'll make go up to that balcony
level there so like three or four more
blocks higher and we could do that let's
try this out we'll go we'll just lay
this out and see where that brings us
yeah it's about that's about right that
and least one more okay that brings up
brings us up to here and then that will
lead up to a half slab probably so it's
free white staircase the big thing I got
to watch for when I do this though is
that I'm not blocked in the window that
we built down there because then it's
totally pointless so we'll do it on this
side we'll do it on that side and then
we'll have a little like fence here
where we can look down at the staircase
here let's actually make sure we don't
block the window by just putting what we
need here so we'll definitely want to
put some stairs here we'll just use
regular ones for now we'll put them at
the top as well I would say libary
instead of library and like for most of
my life I've said library and then one
day when I was looking up the word in a
dictionary I couldn't remember how to
spell it for for whatever reason and
surprise there's another R in there so
that since then I've been trying to
force myself to say library I sometimes
make the mistake still of saying library
you might catch me doing that same with
like deaf February and February there's
an R in February I still say February I
don't know if that's right or not at
least I think there's an R yeah there is
yeah OOP
okay so we'll probably want another
block here
okay so comes close to the window but I
think we'll be able to make it go over
top like we could angle the wall like
this or something that's that's a pretty
good amount of space free yeah all right
so this will come up a hand will make it
go to a 3x3 door let's just put this
here I'm going to copy the same 3x3 door
I used in my village I believe so
it will be like three stone pressure
plates here and then the actual door
itself will be right here and on the
other side stone pressure plates will be
here again but I got to make sure this
all looks good so give me a moment to
refine things here and we'll see where
we're at
now if we go with that layout it's gonna
look something like this I believe I
just kind of did a few more things here
this is this would be the door and then
we'll have stairs to go down into the
library and also an upper area an upper
balcony in the library as well is what I
want to do ah these go up here to the
outside balcony and or patio or whatever
you whatever it's actually going to be
it's not just a balcony and looks pretty
good the only thing I'm really thinking
now though is this is more like the back
of the library like a back exit or
something then it is a front so if you
consider real life buildings you're
never going to have the entrance on the
second floor or even the exit you're not
going to have on the second floor really
so let's that's that's one thing to
consider but this is my draft stuff
doesn't have to make sense so we might
go with that still let me know what you
think
one thing I do know though for the front
of the library you know those three by
three letters I showed the other day I
want to have a sign that says library
spelled out with those letters and we
want that on the front so if this is the
front that's what we're putting up here
sort of a nice little sign okay well
let's let's work on these a little bit
let's grab what do we need got that
let's grab oh yeah we need clay okay
so what we should do with these instead
of having stone brick here we'll copy
the same as we did there with the clay I
don't want to spend too much time like
redoing stuff as a thing because this is
a big project and if we for two finicky
about things it's not going to get done
I hate to say so I should just go with
my gut feeling it for the most parts
unless something looks absolutely
terrible and then we'll redo it but you
know you can only Finnick with things so
much yay
so sleep for now too much roll is not
good but we'll we'll see what it looks
like be like that this let's just try
this out so then we would have to put
slabs in front of that and then in some
places will add stairs like we did here
this doesn't really work mmm kind of
hard to put stairs though isn't it and
mmm I have to go in the middle if
anywhere huh all right by the way if
you're wondering what quartz blocks look
like we'll just try that up too
they're really white almost too white
but that's another idea I think we
should stick with the wool if we do that
another idea I had is maybe we should
drop this all down one block like go
along here with these stairs oops
like so just try this out real quick an
idea is maybe we'll put leaves here and
then the grass will be here Oh zombies
might be a spawner
oh there's all oh wow there's a lot of
mom I got to make a mob system in this
area it's just insane Oh
oh no oh yeah no not gonna happen today
I should stop going forward I should
just stop and wait for a second here to
recover at the same time I want to see
if it's a spawner
ya know spawner okay mmm
all right well I tried the leaves here
and I'm having a hard decision now
should we or shouldn't we is the
question if we do this we can hide
glowstone and that kind of thing behind
it and it'll make it easier to light up
the base here because as it is right now
it's kind of dark but it looks weird
around these edges so if we do I think
we'll have to make the land go up here
or something the other problem is that
adds you know it's another block height
where I have to do something with so
it's more work and I I'm leaning towards
not doing it but what do you guys think
well I think that's going to be all the
work we do on the library today we got a
lot done especially with terraforming
you didn't seem well so that but that
was a lot of a lot of time to get this
where it's at now but I did do one of
these windows here I'll show you that I
think it looks pretty sweet
the only one problem with it is that
block right there
I curved the wool so it goes inward
toward the building and I need that
block there to get the half look on the
wool block but it blocks the clay then
so
kind of a trade-off we could fix it by
lowering the window one block but it
wouldn't look as cool if it's only four
rocks tall so I think we'll just live
with it I just know something the
fishing rods when you spam cast it now
it doesn't actually take durability
anymore like it used to it seems to only
do it when you catch something actually
which is a good change
that's much better so we're at our fire
work area here I think about working on
this a little bit before we were
randomly launching fireworks using fire
tick to do it and we're going to change
it to use tripwire hooks instead if we
power a dispenser and put tripwire hooks
next to it it will randomly update the
dispenser ha got it
and it seems like a better method to use
but also guys I want to apologize if my
uploads have been a little less lately
the month of March has been pretty busy
for me and it's going to be until March
is over so I may have a few less uploads
but I'm trying to stay consistent anyway
um it's hard to keep up sometimes with
the with real life stuff and then you
know I got three series that take up
quite a bit of time but your patience is
much appreciated you know it's nice to
get to stop and just fish once in a
while in Minecraft you know it's not
something you do all the time
really like this area - whoa hey it's
been a while man how you doing nice of
you to drop in for a change
Wow oh we got so much to catch up on ah
this is awesome
okay let's go have some fun all I'm
saying is Baz is like if you're going to
be gone for a while just call like I
worry about you takes two minutes think
about it next time
come on all right so we're clear on the
rules right first one to go boom loses
all right I think it's about the starts
you're going down man you are going down
Lady Luck is on my side oh don't look at
me like that
you should look ahead man
they're coming oh here goes whoa Oh so
far so good
come on oh that one was close felt it
whiz by my head Oh aw don't be a sore
loser man you lost deal with it okay so
I have to come and picked out for today
number one dear ito
there is a new YouTube layout which you
can use I'm not a fan personally of this
design as really glaucoma's the only
element of customized customizability
is the banner at the top and the picture
avatar image the rest is plain white
sand doesn't really stick out as a
channel and looks more like the YouTube
homepage will you be switching to this
to this plan if it is not obligatory I
do have to switch to it unfortunately
just I have a grace period where I don't
have to but eventually YouTube's going
to switch everyone over to it so you
better get used to it change you know
nobody likes the changes on YouTube when
they first come out but I think people
get used to them or at least I do in
time so just you know you'll get used to
it
don't worry second comments put a
librarian villager in there referring to
the library we're building and yes we're
definitely doing that we're going to
have librarians we might have a coffee
shop owner villager of some sorts and
maybe a butcher for cows if we get a cow
farm and a reed farm in there to make
books that kind of thing
got a few other plans for the library
we're going to add some life to it it's
not just going to be a big open room
with bookshelves hopefully hopefully
it's kind of cool
I want a fireplace in it and some other
stuff too but would get to that later so
that's it for today yep okay bye-bye see
you thanks for watching