[Music]
oh
man i am so happy about this you have no
idea
i've wanted a better gold farm for
months now for months and i kept putting
it off putting it off until
last episode we finally did it everybody
we have a
decent gold farm now and we're getting
the gold
so hello everybody and welcome back to
another episode
of the let's play series what have we
done to this gold farm since last night
well you can see we got rid of the chain
that was in the middle there
uh we were having issues with the baby
zombie pigmen falling down into our
piping and messing things up but i took
your guys's suggestion
put a slab there and we haven't had any
issues since so that's great
uh since last episode we have also
installed an item disorder
so we got the zombie flash we got the
gold ingots and
all the chicken nuggies i mean the gold
nuggets now in order to get this item
sorter to work
we couldn't just do the standard thing
we had to get a little bit fancy with it
not
not super fancy but just just a little
bit extra um
for one thing we don't have water
streams in the nether right so we can't
just move
items around with water streams
we actually use slime block launchers to
launch the items up and then we have
another one that launches it sideways
into the ender chest
that aligns it ender chest is slightly
smaller than a block
which is important and then they fall
straight down there
where did they go well
[Music]
let's go check it out so
it lands on some ice well it lands right
over there actually
on the terracotta then it gets pushed on
the ice and because it's aligned in
between
the ice blocks and the hopper it still
gets the slippery effect from the ice
but it can also still go into the hopper
and then i put redstone above it just so
mobs don't spawn on top of the ice there
and it runs over top all our item
filters this is important because
like a lot of times when i talk about
systems i'll say one times hopper speed
two times four times hopper speed
there's a certain limit to how fast
hoppers can work in this game
and when you get to a farm like this
where we need like 14 times hopper speed
the standard method just doesn't work we
can't move items around
using hoppers we have to just launch
them around with slime blocks basically
and then we run them over top the
filters and each one
can accept a certain amount of items so
if we have five item filters for
gold nuggets we can increase the speed
that way
so with our big globs of items here we
filter out the zombie flesh the gold
nuggets the gold ingots the one thing
that doesn't get filtered that makes it
all the way to the end here is the
golden swords those pass over a bunch of
hoppers
uh and funnel down into blast furnaces
that's melted down for
a few extra golden nuggets i think it's
worth doing that you probably get at
least five to ten percent extra gold
from your gold farm
a lot of people like to just toss them
in lava but i think i think it's worth
the
you know smelting them down you can get
a little bit extra and then they go into
the chest on the right side here
so yeah overall i think we're about done
with this farm and i'm very happy with
how it turned out
when i designed it i wanted to make sure
i'd be happy with it long term though
i made the decision to design it where i
could use looting 3 for my sword
we get extra items that way but the
downside is i can't just afk
but like i said i wanted to make sure
i'd be happy long term if we just
replace the hay bales that they land on
with like glass blocks
they'll splat when they hit the ground
we'll get less items that way but we can
make it
payable and we have the option of both
styles of farm
with this so that's really cool i'm
going to use it as a looting farm for
now though
but if i change my mind later we can and
we also get xp
from it and overall just it's really
cool
now when it comes time to collecting
stuff what do we do well we just go over
here we bust the chests open
all the items splat to the ground fill
up our inventory with some gold ingots
we go walk into the gold nuggets
a crafting table just like this will
automatically pick up a bunch more every
time
and make crafting it pretty easy and
then we just gotta put the chest back
when we're done
we're also getting a whole bunch of
zombie flesh from our farm which isn't
really a valuable resource
but in our world you know it's not that
bad because we have
the cheat those i think we have three of
these guys at least
and we can trade infinitely with them
and get rid of all our zombie flashes
spam the space bar and left click on our
mouse
all right well this is what all the
effort in setting up the gold farm has
been for guys we got five and a half
stacks of gold blocks to trade in at the
moment that's a pretty good amount
should get some good resources
uh you know i just had a bit of an idea
here while waiting is like
i can't really tell what's going on why
don't we put some lamps
on our item filters so we get an idea of
like when we get an item we can actually
see it
and it'll add a bit more life to our
system and a little bit more
satisfaction you know it's like oh
that just lit up i just got an item
there oh some quartz is going in
blackstone i like it i think i think
it's a little bit more dynamic
the bartering has finished and from
those five and a half stacks of gold
blocks we got about a double chest the
black stone aha that's one of the main
things we needed
crying obsidian we got just about nine
stacks
i think we had half a stack of obsidian
here so i think we got about five stacks
of that
the big reason why we want resources so
much what we're doing here is we're
trying to fill up our
ender chest storage system we set up
last episode
which means we need to collect like 12
stacks
of every single item in the game pretty
much and fill up all these chests
there's more on the other side as well
double this um
and we needed blackstone for this and uh
i think uh today what we're gonna do
actually
i'll do most of this off camera still
but i thought it might be cool let's
actually dedicate an episode
to resource gathering you know it's
something i kind of skip over a lot
these days
it's a big part of the game though and i
think there's a there's some interesting
stuff to be said about it so
that's our goal for this episode uh
blackstone
we had the regular stuff we did not have
the chiseled so let's get that in there
yeah so for this episode i wanna show
you guys how i'm gonna go about
collecting some of these resources but
also maybe some tips and tricks for you
how you might get stuff a little bit
faster in this game
and also some oddities with resource
gathering or nuances
uh i think a good example of that would
be black stone like you can use this as
a cobble substitute
to a certain extent and the cool thing
about blackstone is you can actually get
it totally automatically you don't need
tnt dupers
or any of those shenanigans you just get
it from the piglet bartering
um but you can't use it as a total
cobblestone substitute like you can't
use it to make
droppers for example the only two things
you can craft beyond the cobble tools
is brewing stands and furnaces
furnaces you need of course for making
blast furnaces and smokers as well
so even though i do have lots of
cobblestone saved up in my world here i
am going to use the blackstone for
making furnaces and stuff
just because when you get to like making
50 stacks of furnaces
that's gonna tap into your resource
supply even if you do have a lot of
cobblestone so
i wanted to pick the automatic method
here something that used to always
happen to me when i would go mining or
when i was digging out a hole
is i would find i didn't bring enough
shulker boxes to bring all the stuff
back with me so if we go check one of my
old
speed mines down here i'm sure there's
tons of resources
which we can collect if we need to which
we do um
especially like diorite and stuff i
don't have a lot of that in my world
so dirt's always good to get but even
things like cobblestone and stone i
would always leave behind
uh because i just didn't have enough
space to bring it back with me so
one trick i kind of caught on to
eventually
because i always carry a bunch of
redstone in my redstone box here i can
take that
right i'm going somewhere here or like
when you're mining you usually get a lot
of redstone
i can then craft things like droppers
and it compresses those seven stacks of
cobblestone down into one
and then it's much easier to bring those
resources back home
the thing i really like about piglet
bartering is it gives you resources that
you can use in a variety of different
ways so in my case with nether quartz
i could craft that into quartz blocks
but i think it's much better just to buy
that from villagers most of my world was
generated before diorite granite and
andesite became a thing so i'm very
limited on that actually i have very
little of that stuff
so i'll probably be using another quartz
we get from the big one bartering to
craft it actually
that might seem wasteful to you guys but
in in my world here
trust me this stuff is pretty rare and
then you can craft
that into andesite or into granite and
that
now i have a way of actually
automatically farming this stuff
another thing we get a lot of though is
gravel and something i think is pretty
interesting
a lot of people struggle to get enough
dirt i find
you can craft dirt now automatically
with gravel
you get from piglet bartering the catch
of course is you don't get dirt you get
the coarse dirt
which is probably why people don't do it
but you can process it similar to
like a concrete factory where you push
it into a tnt
exploder thinger just get the coarse
dirt in your offhand get the hole in the
other one
and make a line like this if you just
hold right click it'll till it and turn
it to regular dirt
and then if you want to get really fancy
with the idea another thing you could do
is combine
the dirt farm with an enderman farm
and make it so you push the dirt in an
area where the endermen walk by maybe
even set up grass and mycelium here
so that you can farm those automatically
as well
when they pick up the dirt and die
down down at your enderman farm they
should drop it then
yeah and then you can get dirt
automatically
that might be a project we do in the
future because i think it'd be a lot of
fun
okay so next up here i'm gonna be doing
some tree farming i need to get some
logs some saplings leaves
um i'm gonna be using fortune three on a
hoe to get the saplings
because again we gotta get like 12
stacks of those even but it's going to
take a bit of time
the way i like to farm like acacia trees
and stuff is make
rows that are five blocks wide even if
you don't have an automatic tree farm
i would highly recommend people use tnt
for farming trees it just saves so much
time
if you're chopping trees you're a sucker
okay so after a quick haircut this is
what we're left with and then i take the
tnt
and go down the middle and uh just light
it
so tnt will blast through up to two
blocks of wood
and it'll take care of any leftover
leaves and stuff
and it's just this saves a lot of time
you gotta be a little careful though but
look at that you know how many
blocks we just chopped with four tnt
over two stacks so we're gonna need 12
stacks of each type of log plus i'm
going to be crafting them into
this version of the log 12 stacks of
each of those
plus we're going to be crafting trap
doors
for each type of log so it's going to
take a lot of wood
excellent so we're making some progress
here we got the acacia we got the oak
done
uh i rated our spruce logs here we have
lots of those in store thankfully so
that was quick and easy dark oak we
snagged from here as well
i've never actually farmed jungle logs
at this tree farm
and i found something out that
apparently you can't do the jungle trees
here because
vines seem to be a block that trees
can't grow through like there's certain
blocks they can like logs leaves
uh dirt but like as much bone meal as i
put on this thing i don't think it'll
ever grow because these
vines are in the way vines are something
worth mentioning
as well it's one of those weird things
in the game did you know the proper tool
for harvesting vines is actually the axe
so you can instant break them with the
axe
but you don't get the silk touch and
even with efficiency 5
shears here you do get the silk touch
but it's super slow there's no way to
speed up the the mining
of the the vines which is really
annoying so you they're such a pain to
collect
um i can't think of any other block in
the game where the proper tool
won't still touch it okay let's just
double check here i got the tree d-vine
so now i'm assuming this will be able to
grow
yeah so it's the vine stopping it
ah yeah
i go up and i go down all right so
lately in the let's play series here
we've been running out of a lot of
things i'm not gonna lie
um usually i do like a couple hours of
resource gathering after every episode
and it just hasn't been enough we've
been doing bigger projects lately
and um some stuff has caught up
with me and it's like oh we're out of
sandstone we're out of flowers we're out
of wood
we're out of all these things all at
once so
today is all about the resource
gathering and i think i've been at it
for at least six hours now mostly just
collecting the wood here
and we got the chests filled up look at
this oh it's so beautiful
so magnificent so tremendous that is
gonna last us a long time
i hope please uh but we've also been
collecting other things like the vines
off the jungle trees we got the leaves
uh we got a bunch of nether plants and
uh
saplings we collected the saplings we're
missing some birch saplings jungle
saplings and we need
some more dark oak as well um
did some redstone stuff as well we're
not done yet though we're gonna keep
going here
so there's actually one resource in this
world that i've never collected before
at least not the proper way you guys
remember this thing
that we had a way of converting yellow
sand into
red sand using a glitch in the game and
i took advantage of that for a while
doesn't work anymore though i'm kind of
wondering
what we actually have here so there's
some red sandstone
oh there is regular sand here too we'll
snag that
uh okay one two and a half
oh it's so close but it's not quite
enough to fill up the ender chest thing
so we might go mine some
just to see what that's like let's see
yeah because we only have like one chalk
or full and we need like a shocker and a
half okay so the thing about that is
we switched our world to amplified a
long time ago
i don't regret that decision i think it
was a good idea
um but it does have some negative side
effects
one of those being orange sand i believe
is quite rare it's uh
it's not so bad there's very little
though it's just like on the very edges
of the
the terrain i'm pretty sure okay there's
a bit of a patch there
there's a bit of a patch there okay
maybe it's not as bad as i remembered i
thought it was
like really bad
yeah we can get little bits here and
there but the thing is because most of
the
terrain is amplified the orange sand
doesn't generate there it has to be at a
lower elevation so it's like just on the
edges of the terrain mostly
the one thing that really kills me about
red sand though is it's only one block
thick why is it not thicker
oh it could get so much more if it was
thicker another thing we don't really
have too much of is these dead bushes so
i want to try grab a couple stacks of
them while we're out here as well
awesome check it out we got the red sand
chest pretty much all filled up here i'm
happy with that
it's not a resource we use a lot of but
uh it's good to have it on hand
in case we need it same with dead bushes
you know probably never use these all up
but i know in the back of my head now
it's like oh we got him okay so we're
back at the mesa again we're gonna mine
up a bunch of clay for the clay chest
so i mentioned there's some negative
effects to having amplified terrain but
there's also some positive effects
like usually in a world you only have a
few layers of clay
in your mesa uh in my world here
like as usual the stone generates around
y60 and down right
but because we go way way up into the
sky
we have not like just like 10 layers of
clay we have
about 100 or so which is kind of nice
you
don't have to go very far to get the
clay the beacon will uh just stay in the
one spot and you can go
and get tons and tons you don't have to
move it around constantly
oh man we're really getting around today
aren't we so we're over at the witch
farm now we're here for two things
we gotta get 12 stacks of clay blocks
for our clay chest
but also we're gonna run around here on
a boat
run around row around i don't know and
uh collect some lily pads
look at these guys they have probably
been there forever
let's leave them alone okay what do you
guys think about the idea of having
i don't know if it would be a tool maybe
an armor piece or an enchantment for
armor but
something that lets you pick up items
from a distance kind of like a magnet in
modded minecraft
you think that'd be overpowered in
vanilla because i'm like noticing a lot
of times when i hit these lily pads it's
like
they're way too far away for me to pick
up and i got to make a second pass
or maybe like when you're farming kelp
in the ocean a lot of times you can't
pick up everything at once it's pretty
annoying
i i kind of would like it actually i
think yeah i think we're ready for
something like that
i think it would probably work best as
an enchantment and the more pieces of
armor with the enchantment
then the stronger the effect like the
further away you can pick stuff
up i think that's the way i would like
to see it done uh but yeah we got it
loaded up everybody and we got the 12
stacks the lily pads ho
that was a fun one kind of wish i had an
afk fish farm at this
at this moment not that they work like
they used to anymore uh
but yeah that's all taken care of now uh
for each of these loaders we also need
two
shocker boxes for the thing so i think i
got it in there already actually
yeah so this this is one of them and now
we got to fill up a second one
so that one stays here and one goes in
our ender chest
the way i do this is i kind of clean out
my inventory
i look at this i press q q q q q q
q all the way along and then they go in
order that i want them in the box here
and then we just transfer over
boop boop and then after we got it all
prepped we just swap it out
get this one over here it's gonna fill
up and this one goes in our ender chest
okay next up here we're gonna need 12
stacks of cactus and i don't show this
thing too often but just outside of the
man cave we have a
a pretty big cactus farm it's not
anything amazing but
over like long periods of use it does
create quite a bit
more than we ever need um so let's go
ahead and snag those
12 stacks of bamboo should be pretty
easy uh
because about got it already
now we did make a fern farm a little
while ago let's see if we have 12 stacks
in here
yes we do a lot of running around but
thankfully we got the ender porter set
up
get those in there
let's talk sand so sand farming in my
world
unfortunately does kind of suck it's
another one of those amplified
negatives because uh when you're farming
sand you kind of want things flat and
this is a flat spot in my world pretty
much
uh so that's uh that's not great now
i think it's been a couple years since
they made the change where tnt
drops all the blocks and i think correct
me if i'm wrong but a lot of you guys
are still
farming sand with shovels
you're a sucker if you are i don't want
to offend
anybody but you're a sucker uh tnt
look at that one tnt that was a lazy tnt
i just put it on the surface it was it
was easy we just about got two stacks a
lot of times i see people say
something like oh etho spins sand to
farm sand
i do but it's only force sand for tnt
it's cheap
right what i do is i run in a line like
this
and then after i'll go again with the
shovel to clean up the
remnants that way i do a thorough job of
clearing the desert out
usually i run i'm not running right now
because i've taken it nice and slow
oh you do have to be careful don't blow
yourself up you know it does
i think the reason a lot of people don't
want to use tnt is because it does
require a little bit more
brain power and a lot of times when
you're resource
gathering you don't want to think right
you just want to chill and relax
but after you do it a few times you do
get used to it it's not too bad
so usually i'll do like 10 to 20 tnt you
don't want to do too many because then
it'll despawn on you
but uh then i do a second pass and clear
the sand down to sandstone so that
you get a nice clean line through your
your desert plus you pick up the sand
that the tnt drops
on the way
good stuff so we filled up seven
shulkers of sand and a bit of sand stone
in there as well
we're probably gonna have to go back for
more because we got a little
we need a lot of sand i've been
neglecting it
we need to craft tnt
and uh we got lots of gunpowder sitting
around this thing has been full i think
it's overflowing
yeah when it overflows it goes in here
and we're just about out of space
so we got to take care of that but we're
also going to need a lot of sand for
making concrete we got to fill up five
double chests of concrete
but let's not forget we also need sand
and sandstone for our ender chest loader
which is totally filled up now
so sand sandstone cut chiseled and
smooth
and then for the final row in these
ender chest loaders i just put whatever
extra we have of the five all right
we're gonna need 12
stacks of purple blocks as well as the
purpur
columns so let's do a harvest
this farm's kind of crazy it like always
just barely breaks even
like we we're not gaining any coarse
flowers but we're not really losing any
either
um it could definitely be improved a lot
though this isn't
an ideal design we kind of put it
together afterwards when uh
they made it where you could shoot the
flowers off with the arrows wait what
that one didn't get chopped
is that a glitch
oh an enderman
unbelievable we had 34 when we started
and we ended it with 34
no change once again the way that farm
works is it has an item sorter to
separate the coarse fruit
seeds and then the actual coarse fruits
whatever they're called this coarse
fruit goes to this building over here
and gets smelted in these furnaces
and then this is the pop stuff that we
make the per per blocks out of
it's gonna take a bit of time though oh
yeah there's another tip i wanted to
tell you guys about
don't buy clay from villagers i realized
this is actually a bad deal let's assume
you have
infinite emeralds and they have no value
to you it's still not worth it because
when you do the trade you can only get
and it's not worth the time to click
here and do that because you can mine 20
clay a second i believe
and it takes longer than a second to do
that so you're just better off going to
a mesa
anyways it's about time we have to wrap
up our episode for today
is a weird one right we didn't do any
building which is kind of against
my rules for the series i try to do a
little bit of building every episode
uh it's a weird uh weird episode though
i kind of wanted to stand out as a
different one
uh we will do just a little bit of
building mode just just because we have
to
just a little bit um around the nexus
here i'm going to add some
andesite this is supposed to be like a
transition
material because it kind of works with
all these blocks it kind of works with
grass kind of works with this kind of
works with that
instead of going straight from the
building to the grass it looks weird
right like it's got a
very strong contrast by putting a border
around this it'll
transition a little bit easier and also
looks like the building will have a bit
more of a foundation
the front of the nexus looks very dark
because it's pretty much just the dark
concrete there
other parts of the building are have
other stuff mixed in with it
so let's try and mix some stuff in with
with the front here as well
we're going to add some slabs over top
this middle section to keep this theme
that we have in other areas like we have
slabs here we have slabs above
the concrete there let's do it in the
middle as well
and i think we're going to add some
light blue clay around this landing zone
as well
maybe we'll we'll build it up like this
and just go around
all the concrete uh-huh so i think i
like that a bit more
got the andesite around the building the
light blue clay uh slabs over the middle
there
and we even added in a staircase and
connected it up to the path here
probably will be making some tweaks to
it in the future but just for now
i think it's a bit of an improvement so
i'm happy with that
let's get to the comment of the day it
says hey etho
the new snapshot that came out changed
to the new cave gin what
the new cave generation let's go with
that
and lower the bedrock level to minus 64.
i think everyone following your let's
play must be wondering
are we gonna be seeing a man cave 2.0
in the future now i've thought about
this
i thought about this so if you guys
didn't hear they're adding 64 blocks
below
the world and 64 blocks to the top of
the world another 128
blocks of play space which is pretty
cool
now i don't think we will ever do
another man cave the same
as what we did over there there would be
no point right if we want we can expand
that
the one we're living in but we might
live underground
but with a different style of base is
that something that would interest you
guys let me know in the comments
and if it is we'll go find a cave in the
next update and we'll
we'll set up there and not make another
man cave exactly we want different block
pellets
different rules and stuff i think the
next space i make i want to make it work
where you zoom around it with riptide
that's like something high on my
priority list of fun you know
so we'll be designing around that most
likely um
but yeah with our current world here
what's what does this change mean for us
well we don't know exactly just yet but
i
suspect the world's not really going to
change
that's generated already which means i'm
going to have my bedrock at
y zero and i think if we break a hole
through the bedrock we can go down
another 64 blocks i think that's the way
it's gonna work
but again i don't know for sure they
might change a generation so the first
time you load up your world it adds a
bunch of stone underneath
we'll see but uh yeah we might be able
to expand down in our
existing man cave as well which would be
cool
anyways that's it for this one guys hope
you enjoyed it even though it was a bit
of a weird episode
uh but we did a lot of resource
gathering i was able to catch up and uh
we invest now for the future right
something like that
uh hope you guys have a great day though
take care
bye