[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode of our let's play
series
i've just been doing a little bit of
maintenance here guys trying to fix the
pop-up sheep farm
because last updates if you didn't see
that uh
most of the sheep died in here there was
a change with pistons
where they will actually suffocate a mob
so when the
when the sheep popped up that was that
was it for them
they all died so now we got to change
out the
the pistons with stained glass
just just go in please there we go um
and then
to do this we can't just place the block
where we want it because the sheep is in
the way
so we have to do a bit of a puzzle here
i think we want this facing down or
facing up
we grab a regular piston face that down
and we pull that
put another one there and then
push the glass block down yep
and then put our lamp back yes
and that is how we do it all right so
for today's episode guys i thought we
would check out a new concept here
uh remember i teased we were gonna look
at a new idea
and you all hated me for it last episode
well today's the day
uh we're gonna be looking into the idea
of using menus and control panels
in minecraft now i know what you're
thinking doesn't sound very interesting
but it is a cool idea
trust me on it it is something we have
kind of done already
in the past year like for example i
think the first menu i have made in
minecraft is this
menu system at the nexus here so this is
an information menu all it does is give
us information
doesn't do anything else so when we
hover over one of these uh
items it gives us the code the number
for it there
so for example if we want to get stone
brick out of the system that's bd
then we hit bd on on our thing here
and the menu gives us this information
so it's a handy thing to have here i use
it all the time
then we just flip the lever and we'll
get the stone brick
in here eventually why is there a button
in there
[Laughter]
i don't even know how that got there oh
uh oh
oh i bet you the codes reversed uh what
is uh what is that
db yeah bd db i put in backwards
anyways let's look at another example of
a menu or a control panel system
we did before here the pixel has a
really cool one
if i do say so myself uh not only is
this like an information menu
it actually is interactive you can make
choices with it so
uh let's say for example we want to look
for sand i've shown this before
several times but we'll do it one more
time um
so we got sand in our menu here to make
our choice we hover
over it with our mouse press q
and that makes the selection so it
shoots the sand out of our inventory
here goes into the hopper and then that
replaces the item filter with a piece of
sand
and then any shulker boxes that have
sand inside get matched up with that
and they show up here is the way this
works
so this is a menu that is actually
interactive that's the key i'm trying to
drive home here so there's different
types of menus
and you can make them do a lot of
different things yeah so last episode i
kind of hinted i would want to use this
idea for a future base
so let me try explain that a little bit
better if i can
like even even in chocolate island days
i had a central control room
there was like six levers in it i could
turn the mob system on and off i could
choose to sort spiders and i think there
was a lever for turning lights on and
off
very simple functionality but i thought
it was the coolest thing
and ever since then i've kind of dreamt
about making a
a grand base with lots of functionality
that you could like turn the lights on
and off
turn the mob system on on on and off and
um you know open doors closed doors do
do all sorts of different things from a
central computer but i've kind of
realized you don't need a computer all
you need is a chest
it's actually really easy to do so let
me let me show you just how easy it is
let's say for example you wanted a
function to play a song
so let's let's call this play song
all right and that did not work
why play song
do i pull him out of here i like never
name things
is this broken uh oh
um guys help no i can't i can't name
things in the anvil for some reason
is it because this is about to break
i don't know okay let's pretend this
says play song right so
we would have an item filter all you
need is item filters
most of us know how to make those um set
this up
so this needs 41 items
[Music]
all right so that goes to 41 items and
then you have like a stack of ice
that's a place song in this chest
that's one function added to this thing
all we got to do is
attach redstone over here to some note
blocks and it'll play a little tune
over here we have a dispenser with
fireworks in so if we add another
function let's say
use pistons this time 41 pistons in here
pretend they say shoot firework that i
named them
and then you have shoot firework
function in our chest here in our
our central control panel so you can
have like up to 54 different functions
in the double chest right
so if we want to play a song all we got
to do now is just throw the ice in
if we want to shoot a firework all we
got to do is
do that oh it's super simple right you
can do a lot of cool stuff with this
uh menu system idea i'll give you guys a
few more applications of this because i
think there are quite a few actually
so for example i might make a minecart
system in our
our world here where it's in the mine
carts
and then you have a chest full of of
choices like let's say we want to go to
the nexus or the man cave or
or guardian farm you know you select
whatever choice you want press
q shoots item out into a hopper
and then that would make the minecart
start moving and switch the junctions
according to whatever choice you make
you know
um and it'll take you right to where you
want to go that would be a really nice
way of doing a rail system i think
instead of having like a bajillion
levers or buttons to
to make your choice all you need is a
chest super fancy
right um or let's say you're making a
brewing system and
all you got to do is oh i want to brew
strength potions or i want to brew
speed potions you know make choices that
way
all right guys so back to this thing
over here our search engine
i built this kind of as a prototype like
i wanted to see what you guys would say
about it and also it was just a really
good learning experience like i learned
a lot of stuff
building this and now that we have an
example of it actually working i can
improve upon it
that's what we want to do because you
guys really like this thing but it
is it does have a problem it's kind of
slow
once you get to about 30 or 40 shocker
boxes
it's going to take quite a few seconds
to actually uh
find an item for you right it's a linear
search
so we got to make that better there's
also another problem of there being
about four or 500
items in minecraft so
yeah we can have six double chests of
items or whatever here
but you got to look through all those
and find the item you're looking for
start your search it would be really
cool if we could do it all from a single
chest
right yeah so i think for the next
version of that what we really want to
do is break the items up into categories
that'll make the search faster and it
will also be easier to uh
to find what we're looking for when when
we're starting the search
instead of having all those double
chests we can maybe get it down to a
single chest here
um what we want to do is build a menu
that we can navigate
basically add an extra level of
complication to our life here
so for example we might have a selection
here for a redstone
category not just the redstone dust
piece but everything in the redstone
category so we'd have like redstone
blocks
maybe lamps in that category um
you know all this kind of stuff here in
our redstone chest repeaters
comparators then we might have like a
clay category
so this would be hard and clay in the 16
different colors and maybe regular clay
would go into that so yeah basically
what we're doing here is we want to have
two levels to our menu system so we
would have our main categories
to choose from first you choose the
categories such as clay
by doing that and then you want all the
items to leave this chest
and then that category selection to come
up so it would be
hard and clay the 16 different colors
regular clay would then come
up in this chest then you make your next
choice of what item you specifically
want to search for
so choose one of the colors for example
then items would leave this chest and it
would go back to the main
choice main category choices i know it
sounds a little complicated
i actually got to set this up for you to
probably understand it better
um so you probably have a hopper here
that you throw the item into
okay so i think this might take care of
the first step of our problem
so let's pretend these are different
categories like hard and clay wool
glass redstone
after we make our choice of what
category we want we then want these
items to leave the chest
okay so to do that right now
these two hoppers are locked under the
chest by the wire here
when we throw an item in this hopper
it's going to make the piston push the
block over
and unlock this so let's say we pick
card and clay as our category
that gets pushed over these items leave
fairly quickly
they go down to uh a storage minecart
down here did they all go in
or did one get left behind no i think
everything went in that's good
okay and then we need to re-lock this
chest
uh which we do by detecting when it's
empty then this
this gets powered over here and pushes
the block back
so now we're ready for new items to come
in here and they won't
they won't get put into the mine cart
below
okay i got a rough working example of
stage two now
this should clarify what i'm trying to
do quite a bit in peace in case you're
not quite getting it
so let's pretend we're picking our main
category here we're going to pick hard
and clay
the items the categories leave the chest
and then our selection comes up
so now these are the hard and clay
category choices so we would then
specifically choose
what item we're looking for and let's
say we do green and then ideally we want
that
main category to come back up so those
items went down to the storage mine cart
uh we need to like bring them back up to
this chest
okay so the next part of this guys is
the most tricky part of it so we're not
gonna do it today we're gonna save it
for another day
because we've been working on this whole
episode let's try to do something else
here too
uh but yeah but basically let's say we
have 15 categories to choose from
in our our chest here then we need 16
storage mine carts one for each category
and then another storage minecart to
hold the categories
right um so after we make a specific
selection we want the
minecart that holds the categories to
come back
empty out its contents into the chest
then when we choose the main category we
need one of the 15
storage minecarts the one we choose we
got to detect which category we choose
and then have that storage minecart come
over here empty out into the chest
and then somehow get its contents back
and put back into place
it's going to be a big thing and we got
to make it fast too so we can't just use
item filters and
probably got to do something super fancy
but we'll we'll work it out another time
okay
so let's head over to our underground
village now guys
and i thought we would try build an
elevator here
because we really need one there's no
elevator nearby i have to
either fly out of here or go a long ways
to get up to the surface again
uh so let's see maybe we'll just put it
over here
oh hey we got a nitwit hey buddy
where did you come from i can't trade
with you
what good are you
[Music]
what oh no i'm thinking of the librarian
that's right nitwits are totally useless
i think of the new cartograph
or cartographer uh guy i thought he was
the green guy for a second
uh-huh no nitwits are totally useless
they don't have a trade
all right hey cool
i think that'll be a good spot for it
over here so
let's get to building we want a two by
two thing going up to the surface so
we'll probably go to the top and just
dig down to do that
the easiest way but uh let's experiment
a little bit with the idea
so i want to do a boat elevator guys
we're going to challenge ourselves try
something new here
and hopefully it works out okay so i
figure
have two pressure plates
like that and then the boats and
hopefully
like if the boats on these uh they're
not going to activate until we go inside
right and hopefully it clicks
yeah we got the click good and then i
want this
to get uh launched up to the surface
hopefully as soon as we go inside
oh this has to be higher up but yes yeah
because the
the boat's kind of fat right all right
so let's raise that up too
so probably just use slime block
launchers to do this we'll put the slime
block launcher over here
and something like this oh we'll have to
do it so it doesn't stick to anything
too
let's grab some note blocks here just to
try this
oh i got him on me i got him on me
okay so these have to be note blocks
i heard they're gonna make it so i think
it was the glazed terracotta blocks are
not gonna be
uh sticky to slime blocks in a future
update here hopefully that's true
because we don't have a lot of choices
for
blocks that don't stick to slime blocks
they were going to do it but i heard
they
forgot forgot to add in before the
snapshot but maybe
maybe next one okay let's do that
put that back and there we go so if we
go into the boat here
oh what's going on oh yeah it does
launch us okay
is it getting stuck on
getting stuck on something here
sometimes
[Music]
what's going on guys like sometimes it
doesn't launch
and sometimes it does every third time
it launches
hmm one two
oh oh is it just because i think slime
blocks are glitched out right okay if i
got the coordinates right this is going
to be the spot over here
hopefully uh if the slime blocks don't
work out we might just do a zipper
elevator
because they might be glitched i'm not
sure if it's gonna work but we'll try it
we'll try it first
okay so i had to put some fence gates
here because the villagers
kept going in the boat and killing
themselves
from the fall damage so uh if we got the
boat in the right place the sun block
seems to work okay
oh i say that it fails the first try
really it was working perfect before
um maybe just got unlucky there
yeah and it launches us pretty high each
time like that's that's the cool thing
about using boats they go a long ways
let's see so it's above the dirt blocks
by maybe one block or two blocks
yeah so if i was to guess we were being
launched to about that height
there so we want the slime block to be
at this height
and then push us up right it's my best
guess
we'll try it out if it doesn't work i'll
adjust it and then we'll count it and
figure out what height we actually need
here
but we're gonna do like a tripwire thing
um so we want this slime block to get
pushed out and then pushed up
right that's our goal so this block over
here
or let's do it out of stone brick so
it's a little clearer i'll probably
change out this whole elevator to clay
afterwards though
or some or maybe even concrete uh
but we want this block to get powered
so i'm going to just try put a trip wire
over
here and one over here so when the boat
passes through the trip wire it
activates this thing
run some string across okay so that
is right there right so if we put
a piece of redstone here this block will
get powered from that
and then we need to run it over to the
pistons here
what's the best way of doing that guys
uh maybe we'll put it over there
let's try this redstone dust up there
we need at least a two tick thing or two
take difference here with the
repeaters let's try that out see if that
works
and no why did that not work
good question oh because uh
right if we do that
the the wire is facing this way not not
into the block
so we need to move this block over
oh yeah let's just do it like that and
put a block here
uh-huh and now um
perfect okay so hopefully that works out
let's sleep real quick
here um we'll break the blocks we'll
take the boat up and see if it gets
launched here
possibly the tripwire is also in the
wrong place could be another issue
but this is how you figure things out
all right let's try it out
oh something happened
oh i think it's pretty close but uh
it might not be getting launched high
enough for it to work
oh that time it worked
this is going to be a really bad
elevator isn't it
hey it worked that time again
things are don't seem super consistent
though
i have to like push forward on the boat
for the pressure plates to activate
[Music]
and then that pushes me over
oh that time we went too high
oh it's a disaster guys
i don't know okay one thing i've done
now guys is i changed the side these
pistons are on like they used to be on
this side
now they're on this side so when they
push us
it doesn't push us off the pressure
plates and it seems to be making this
thing a lot more consistent
although it's still not great i don't
know if i would recommend it
but we'll try it out here this is a good
ex
good learning experience okay so do that
and that's
uh you only need one piston here because
the slime block uh
brings this back you don't need the one
down below here
okay and then this is good hopefully got
the right height here
let's go put another one there good
all good yep seems to be working so
let's go down again
see if we can triple triple jump now
all right boat goes there and
it seems to work best if you're aligned
in a certain spot
but i don't know what that spot is the
sweet spot we gotta find the sweet spot
with it
oh i don't know if that third one's
working
so the problem is sometimes the slime
block just pushes you up like a normal
block and it doesn't actually bounce you
right
that's the issue with slime blocks right
now that seems to be happening a lot
with this
hmm well it works every single time if
we're not in the boat
so it has to do with the client server
lag too
which i thought like if you're riding an
entity that's not an issue
but i guess i got that wrong like i
thought if you're riding a boat or a
minecart then that's no longer a problem
but yeah obviously it's not working too
well
uh so maybe one last ditch effort here
i'm gonna get a horse
and then we'll ride the horse up while
it rides the boat and see if that works
[Laughter]
i don't know how i did that i got off
the horse weird apparently
oh he stopped that was awesome i wonder
if we can do that again
i was like moving while i got off the
horse
or maybe i jumped oh yeah if i jump
oh it's great uh okay so having a little
trouble here
even if we can get the horse into the
boat
uh we won't be able to activate the
pressure plates and also
i can't get the horse into the boat for
some reason
i don't think you can put them in boats
right is that what's going on
what if we remove the saddle
yeah he doesn't want to go in there for
some reason
okay so if we can't use horses let's try
llamas
so they go in boats for sure and
let's see how do we do this guys we
probably only got one shot of this
because this guy's probably gonna die
maybe we'll take away all the pressure
plates first
then get him into position we should be
able to ride him
oh what there he goes should be able to
ride the llama
while he's riding the boat
let's double check yeah looks like we
can good
so then if we put the pressure plates
back
or maybe i'll just use a button to try
this
yeah that's probably a smarter idea
instead of using the pressure plates
so put the button over there hopefully
i'll be able to click it
that didn't work what's going on we're
not getting launch design now
man um
yeah we're not going nearly as high as
before
or are we getting stuck on the piston
how you doing on health buddy oh i can't
see his
oh he's got uh he's two hearts now it's
not too bad uh maybe we gotta
make the pistons take longer to go out
then
if we're not riding the llama then he
goes all the way is he gonna splat when
he hits the ground
no he's fine
this just is not working is it here we
go again
oh it worked it actually worked
is it consistent it might be consistent
okay we might have a winner here guys
yeah i think it's actually consistent
now look at that
so i had to change some timings here
let's go back up here
what did we actually do let's figure
this out i've just been uh
adding one to the timing over and over
until it finally worked here
trial and error so this is at
seven that's from the tripwire
seven delay then it goes to uh this
block that we need to power
one delay later so eight ticks
and then add two ticks extra from this
to the piston yes
all right it works it works
okay big moment guys for llama vader's
everywhere is it going to work now i
changed the second one
all right so if they're both changed
is that good enough is it going to work
first one's good second one's good
let's try that again one
two consistent oh my goodness
i don't believe it that's amazing
except it's not going as high now right
or is it oh i can't get off the llama
let's try that again see if i can hop
off the llama
yeah all right cool
and let's check out the block heights
here guys just in case for some reason
you want to copy this
three four
five six seven eight nine
ten eleven so at the 11th block is where
the first slime block is
okay so then from that one two three
four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve so it's not quite the same
eleven then twelve and i'm guessing the
next one would be twelve two
i tell you i was about to give up on
that whole elevator idea but we did get
it working in the end so i'm happy about
that
uh but i think it's time we wrap up for
today guys so here is the comment i
picked out
the technical question it says why is it
that when i use his world seed
and go to the coordinates where the man
cave is for example it's not the right
biome at all
i guess a new question but still so i
made
this world back in minecraft 1.9
pre-release 3 i think and since then
there has been a biome
update so they added jungles after i
made this world
and all the existing biomes changed
positions
so if you load up the world or the seed
in the current generator
uh you actually get a world that's like
mesa and there's a whole bunch of ocean
like um nearby here too so it's a
completely different world
and which is why this world's so special
anyways thought i would answer that one
hopefully you guys enjoyed today's
episode if you have any
comments or anything please leave it
down below but until next time
thanks for watching have a wonderful day
take care
[Music]
bye