those cows they costed me my life due to
no fault of my own I will add I had to
make new tools it was brutal and now I
look forward to eating them for
generations as I get my revenge that
cows got stuck all right move it move it
- stupid cow what happened to the other
mine carts I had another mine carts Oh
have that one come back
did you just duplicate oh so I almost
just lost one of the cows pushing it
through the lava curtain and if this guy
dies I go all the way back and get
another one let's just see if it dies
how it dies okay
it took damage like instantly somehow
stop stop it stand perfectly still I got
to do this right okay that wasn't good
oh why am i dying oh come on don't die I
think it died he got stuck up here there
was nothing I could do
ah man alright so there we go we got him
here it only took a couple hours that
was one of the biggest patience tests
I've had in a long time
died and lost all my tools and then a
cow died on the way you know man cows
but I will care for them I will love
them I will feed them and I don't want
to hear it from you guys I know what
you're thinking yes I got them
segregated but I am NOT a cow racist I
am NOT I will I will kill and eat them
equally I'm not like that I am organized
that's what it is and you do it to point
that finger back at yourself I know you
do tell me right now tell me right now
your sheep they're not all together no
no you got fences between all the
different colors I know it okay
everybody so I have a project in mind to
start off with today we're going to be
doing some terraforming oh yeah oh we
got more don't you worry if we need it
so there's something I've wanted to do
for violence it's to connect my world
together with water there's a river
there that connects pretty much up to
the man cave and comes to this lake and
then that's it though so I want to
extend that further it also goes out
that way quite a bit if I ever need to
go that way I don't use it very often
though just once in a while because well
boats you know how they are but sounds
like mosaic may actually fix them in the
next patch they're working on them not
it not just a quick fix but like
actually reworking boats a bit it sounds
like so if that happens oh man I'm I
hope it happens so what I'm gonna do
I've I've scouted this out before like
I've surveyed the land up a
head here if we run T&T like from here
we'll make a new river let's just see
usually best not to do it super straight
or anything maybe look bend it a little
bit to left then and then right down
this mountain area and I'm gonna make a
backup before I do this because often
when I do things with tea and tea it's
like no why did I do that and I regret
it later because it doesn't quite turn
out in the right shape but yeah we can
run out to this water and then you're
like oh that's it II so that's that's
what you want to meet up with well if we
then continue through the mountain of
bits we get to another lake alright I
was like what is that that's the Nexus
over there looked like a spaceship
what's going on if we go further then
this is sort of the end now I think if
we connect straight through here we have
another lake and then oh we don't stop
there no we kind of got this cool arch
thing if we go further
dead-end but let's see if we can get up
on top the mountain it's kind of a
mountain in our way here we can blow a
hole right through it and then it
connects oh wait is this ice here no
it's not connects to this lake and this
lake is sort of big like it goes on
quite a ways sort of all over so that
would be cool because I do actually go
out this direction sometimes and it's
really hard to get back with these
mountains here because I got to go over
top them there's no shortcut um so that
would be cool record record yeah I got a
record oh no oh I didn't get record oh
I'm almost dead No
safe it was blocks solid record good
record I liked it
alright so this is ready to go you want
to do the honors mr. creeper no you
still have that problem where you can't
swim in water don't you
yeah okay never mind
I'm still on an old old version of
Minecraft here oh hey oh I'm right in
the line of fire we're good
I may have spaced these too far we'll
see ouch
yeah they're not even detonating that's
fine it's fine
so this one goes all the way up over
here I'm gonna be careful actually
because if I lose my tools again I'm
gonna feel really dumb I blow myself up
all right and then decide to go through
the terrain here these ones I put pretty
close together should make a big boom
all right Oh is there a team underneath
a little bit okay and you better run
helping it listen last but not least we
have the tunnel through the mountain
here again I put these ones pretty close
together yeah good oh that's actually
pretty far okay so I'm trying a
different method for flooding here
usually what I do I'll put a layer of
dirt and then I put the water overtop
and flood flood the dirt and then I
remove it this time I'm just putting ice
all the way through and leaving it
hollow underneath I'm not trying to fill
it solid that will just take longer and
it's not necessary the nice thing about
doing it this way is I can stand on the
ice and like shape it if this is all
water you know it's kind of tricky to do
so yeah so now what I'll do is I'll go
by and I'd have a row of of stone or
something probably dirts and put torches
on both sides and try to melt the ice
and see if that turns out okay
that's a lot of Mom's alright guys I got
the river done here we're gonna go for a
ride and try it out got to make sure I
can take those bends at full speed
actually it's pretty much a straight
away I think um melting the ice didn't
work out as well as I hoped I had a
weird side effect where it created all
these air pockets in the water which I
had to then go fill but it wasn't too
bad either
Oh oh yeah this is pretty easy
we got our first cave oh I got a I got
like a flicker there did you see that
but we seem to be okay still yeah you
see these air pockets because the water
melts and then it doesn't update in
certain spots oh man
things seem a little uh a little leggy
as I'm riding here no I was so close to
actually hit the water was it oh man
here let's do a loop around and then
we'll try to get up to full speed again
and see if I can do that man I really
hope they make it so boats don't break
like there's no reason for it unless you
break it yourself you don't want it to
break great ah there we go we're good
okay and then this is the main lake over
here so it would be nice to add like
vines and stuff hanging down and trees
along the banks floating sheep but what
we'll do that another time because this
has taken quite a while I am ready to do
something non terraforming okay where
does this one go I think I have to dig
out more spots to connect it to other
water places but I'm just kind of want
to check it out as well I think this is
the end here oh wait this might be where
we need to go next
yeah looks like a river that's not fully
formed here so we'd have to cut out
there and maybe then cut across here
just go to the swamp ah know that I am
having such a bad luck streak lately
holy smokes and I didn't even notice him
after I tell afore it's not telling
heard the noise I don't know what I was
looking at he was right in front of me
oh man huh alright I have to try to get
back you know it'd be nice a boat right
about now I'm gonna make a boat I think
that's far enough it's not gonna be
spawned and I still got time yes I can
go back and get my stuff solo is that
where I went down oh right over there
okay oh there's a lot of water there by
the way just to finish our survey yes
there's a lot of water if I want to
connect there ah but we're gonna head
back now alright there we go finally did
it no nobody can say anything about it
anymore okay so we got to decide what to
do with this building I just wanted to
bring that up as well
it's quite the eyesore we also have a
problem with this is the gold farm by
the way this elevator stopped working in
one of the patches kind of it does this
all the time and for some reason I get
stuck in it and it like stops weird
I should almost investigate this this is
a very strange thing it's like sometimes
it goes and then retracts other times I
get stuck in it
it's very odd not exactly sure what's
going on with the redstone
is it every second time it doesn't like
I should get stuck this time right yeah
I got stuck this time okay maybe it's
making uh oh oh man so strange anyway
it's not working quite right anymore so
I need a new elevator design I think but
also this building doesn't look the
greatest of course it's not finished but
maybe we need to do something about it
so yeah do you have ideas let me know
there's a specific theme or or idea we
could go with it sort of has to sit stay
in that spot is the problem and there's
a portal up there that we also need to
access to so yeah we're going to head
over to the library though I just want
to try check out something as well all
right so some of you are probably like
etho why you know work on library what's
going on well it's because we've hit
sort of a tough spot - right - now if
you remember I wanted to wire up these
buttons you see how close together there
and on both rows here these are supposed
to go to some droppers that have the
enchanted books in which we'll probably
want to put in the middle here somewhere
and I gotta connect each of those
buttons to the dropper and nuts have the
wires connect with each other and we
don't have bundled cables or anything so
that is not an easy task but I think
we'll probably do it like like we did at
the Nexus where we have droppers then
hoppers and a chest going into the
droppers these will shoot the the books
into like a nice ice water stream thing
and then those will get launched to us
when we're over here with some slime
block launchers I think is my plan now
but to actually connect these is going
to be very tricky I want to see how I
does this I think we need 23 droppers or
something 23 different types of
chanted books I believe maybe I got that
wrong wait we should check that just to
be sure one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven twelve
thirteen oh now it's twenty five
thirteen plus thirteen twenty six and I
think I had one extra 25 that's nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen oh man
so if we go that way it doesn't leave us
any space to walk by all right so that's
not going to work we might need to do
like like we'll probably have some going
this way then some going this way and I
guess we'll need a couple on the sides
because otherwise it's it's too fat and
we can't walk by it so I might go with
this arrangement here we have seven by
six so 14 plus twelve that's 26 that's
good that's what we need
well we only need 25 but I'm I'll keep
the extra you never know they might add
a new enchantment to the game or
something dumb and that would be pretty
sad if I built all this and they added a
new one
so I got I'm trying to set this up so
that we can manually access these if we
want and like check how many books we
have but I also wanted to work
automatically with these buttons down
here which is going to be tricky let's
see probably the best way of doing it is
to connect these top ones in the middle
here with these first droppers here all
right so I'm gonna I'm gonna remove this
stuff and start trying to lay this out
um a little secret you know I love doing
redstone it's a lot of fun I like trying
to work out the problem and and build
the components and all that stuff I
really don't like this part of redstone
though trying to find how to link
everything together with the wire isn't
always that easy or that fun oh I broke
one of the buttons Darrin I was hoping I
could just
and a cheat with this and run repeaters
like side-by-side but it looks like we
gotta go down one more alright so I
worked on it for a little while here and
I'm happy to say I think I got it all
together pretty much it did take a
little while but it wasn't as difficult
as I thought actually I mostly just had
to alternate the redstone with the
repeaters in wire but yeah this is the
downstairs this over here I'm going to
have to cover up I just left it open so
I can still still walk around over here
but yeah I think it's going to be good
the only thing I haven't put in is the
water screen for carrying the books
around and like the the launcher
elevator or whatever I end up doing with
the the books to get them to me in the
middle here
one thing I may actually do is set up a
item elevator over here that will like
bring the books up and then throw them
at me over here the goal is to get the
books to me when I'm in this spot
because enchanting tables right here so
I want my enchanted books delivered if
possible and yeah okay so we're going to
do a horse update today as well we have
a few to try out here we're trying to
breed high jumping horses highest
jumping horse possible currently the two
of highest jumpers are the ones with the
gold armor here and these are all the
babies all right this guy's no good
not counting the middle of course oh
sorry
um how about you alright
nope no good alright I felt bad about
killing one on camera does that make me
a monster when I do it on camera I
usually like to hide that stuff off
camera alright
nope no good alright but if I don't kill
them they always wander back in the pen
and yeah gets annoying nope not looking
good so on average I'm I have to breathe
like twenty to thirty horses at least to
get a any improvement now which is quite
a bit all this guy's terrible
he's like a block lower than he needs to
be alright last one already yeah we're
on our last one come on I want to see
some improvements no you don't have to
you don't have to fill the jump bar all
the way to the end like this is this is
fine the way I'm doing it um as long as
it's in the orange it's the highest jump
possible alright so well no improvement
this time but we'll keep trying so guys
that's going to do it for today's
episode but I did pick out a comment and
it's a very disturbing one that I had to
bring up says this not a joke like come
on already we know this guy is not right
this is not a joke but granite looks
amazing in the desert no joke it's also
great for the buildings and put the
granite in the pillars and on the tip of
the temple it's super good okay so I
don't appreciate troll comments like
this obviously obviously it's a joke
okay you can say it's not a joke but
it's a joke granite does not look good
in anything ever so don't even go there
okay no more all right
well that's going to do it for today
guys thank you for watching have a
wonderful day bye bye
you