[Music]
hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another
you episode me right round baby right
round no uh yes so guys
oh wait a minute where is it nope not
that button that that's the button we
want
14 w29b i've updated guys to the latest
snapshot
one just came out today and
i think it's it's a keeper i think we're
gonna stick with it this time
the last few have been crashing my world
here
but this one seems pretty good and
and yeah so maybe we'll just talk about
a few things here
so whoa creeper this snapshot
of course we have the water temples
which we're gonna go check out today if
we can find one
uh there's bunnies there's bunnies in
the snapshots
which sound amazing i have no idea where
to get them though
i didn't look into how they spawned yet
like if you gotta go to new chunks or
not
i'm guessing you do though um
and also this snapshot in particular
has introduced a new
oh we're fine yeah we're good
it's introduced multi-threading for
chunk loading which
i'm tr i want to test that out here
while recording when i was not recording
it was perfect
it looks like it's a quite a bit slower
while recording though
darn it see the mountains slowly loading
in
ah come on it was so good when i wasn't
recording i could not see any chunks
loading anywhere
is this always perfect maybe we'll
ride into the the horizon here and see
oh yeah it definitely has trouble darn
oh well
oh i was all excited about it now now
i'm recording it doesn't work so well
and i can't show you what it looks like
when i'm not recording but basically i
don't see chunks loading anywhere but
this is a lot worse
while while recording than the last snap
snapshot i was using
let's see maybe let's go into our
options i turn mipmapping off i don't
like this on unless we have that
aerostropic filtering which for some
reason isn't in the options anymore
let's try turn off vsync
see if that helps hello villagers
lovely day we're having
[Music]
um
still seems kind of slow doesn't it
here let's try turn vbos off i think
that's the multi-threading thing
see if that makes a difference um
about the same isn't it
all right well i think we're going to
live with it get used to it guys
no hopefully just for one or two
episodes we might have a
a few chunk rendering issues hopefully
you guys don't mind
if you do i will downgrade
when i'm not recording it's perfect
though which is
the majority of the time for me uh
hopefully it doesn't affect the video
too much
but anyway the reason i brought you out
here
let's do this one more time turn it back
on i don't think it made much difference
um i got something special to show you
let's see let's go over here
just outside our village are we gonna
find any
there we go yes they are here
the guardians
okay so this is gonna this is gonna be
tough to explain we're doing the water
temple thing today but before we go look
for one i
just want to show you this too i've
never
like encountered these guys in survival
yet so i'm not sure how they attack
exactly
i know they have the lasers but it
didn't really
hurt me
i've tried my best to avoid any spoilers
on these guys but i have seen a little
bit
uh but i've never seen anyone whoa whoa
okay i've never seen anyone take them on
in survival yet
so i don't know exactly how difficult
it's gonna be
but that was three and a half hearts
with my my boots of the traveler on even
how did they attack though because they
were zapping me and nothing was
happening
yeah nothing's happening
oh okay so it's like a charge up and
then zap
and then they finish with their laser
so if you're in their line of sight get
out of it type of thing i guess
huh these guys are so cool this this was
an amazing addition to the game they
look awesome
oh is that me gonna zap me no i got too
far away
don't they look so amazing though i love
it
and they move so fluently too they did a
really good job on
on adding these guys in um
all right so let me explain this these
guys do not spawn
just anywhere normally they only spawn
at the water temples right
well let me we're going to go into
a different world here for just a second
the same world same
seed but with the current generation and
i'll show you what's going on here
pay attention to our position here
negative
263 and 7 15-ish okay
okay so here we are guys does it look
familiar
this is about i think this is where the
mantive is
roughly uh as you can see the world
generation has changed a lot since i
made my world
this is the new course dirt too let's
see wait a sec so i just started a
creative world here
by the way we're just going to spend a
minute here d mode
0. i wanted to see if you can pick this
stuff up
okay what
oh that's one of the issues with the new
snapshot you know i wasn't getting that
my lp world though i wonder why it's
doing it here
all right anyway just ignore that it's
fine it looks like you can pick it up
though
uh let's go to doo doo doo doo
what were the coordinates here tp etho 2
negative 240
64. this is where we saw the guardians
and 714 and you can probably expect what
you would find here
it's going to take a little while to
load oh yeah we're oh wow we've got raid
on it here
oh i'm wait a second
so yeah that's what's here in my lp
world under the current generation
uh there is a water temple right right
there
but since uh those chunks have been
loaded
previously in my lp world
it doesn't actually generate the
structure the water temple structure
there
just uh it'll just try to spawn the mobs
it it sees it as a water temple
area uh but it doesn't overwrite
the land there and the reason for that
is so that doesn't destroy
stuff people have built previously in
their worlds
uh-huh all right let's go back so with
that in mind
i most likely will be making a farm
for these water guardian guys and it'll
probably be right here
because this is the closest one i could
find to our home
i made some leads at the village too
like oh
no no no oh
watch out horsey i don't know if they
attack horses or not
here actually so i made some leads at
the village i wanted to try bring some
animals in
i i haven't investigated much with these
guys hello piggy
wonderful day uh might be your last
let's go let's go let's go do they
attack all passive mobs i wonder
or is it just squid
i have an offering for you guys a peace
offering
oh no piggy go for the piggy
oh man i think it's just squid they just
go after squid
it's not yeah it's not looking good darn
i was hoping we could like make cow
farms and stuff and then have these guys
zap
the the animals as well
they only go they only go after squid
and human it looks like whoa
i also wanted to see if i could uh grab
them with the
the lead horsey be careful
i'm not totally sure they won't kill you
all right here's one here's one no
no no no no ouch ouch
okay i don't think it works i don't
think you can you can put a lead on them
because they are hostile mobs right
i'm gonna see if i can block their
attack
oh oh are they attacking
i need one okay here we go oh
come on guy
and denied oh you can blocked it that's
awesome
oh oh oh oh
whoa okay you're getting out of there
getting the invisible block thing again
for some reason
it like comes and goes it's weird
so now we're on our way we are going to
try find a water temple
and let me tell you my plan for it i i
think i came up with a pretty good idea
here
so we are on our way to oh oh
i'll be right back
so like i was saying we're gonna go find
a water temple
i don't have a lot of ocean
in mind like there's not a lot of places
to check for ocean
i haven't found a lot of it uh but i
i've been told many times in my comments
where i can find a mushroom biome
and as you know those always spawn in
the middle of the ocean
so we are going to go check out that
that
mushroom biome and hopefully there'll be
a water temple nearby
guy are you really gonna kill me i have
to
i found out also this block this weird
block behavior where it's like not
disappearing or
replacing seems to only happen when i'm
recording
because my computer is under stress or
something i don't know
most of the time when i'm playing it
doesn't happen though
all right that is weird stuff
all right so the biome
the mushroom biome is at i believe
negative 312 positive 312 in the nether
which is right around here
oh by the another fortress actually
let's go
probably shouldn't have brought a horse
i regret this this decision now
um we gotta go 200 blocks this way
let's dig in my little hole
let's pretend to dig them a hole down
you go
there we go okay it's fine uh we'll pick
him up on our way home
all right so if i remember right though
this goes to a lava lake that could give
us some trouble
huh we kind of hit the end of the line
here
let's drink a fire resistant potion
and go check this out again we're
looking for 312
312. where is our villager house here
so this is about right on the axe
uh we gotta go about 20 blocks
this way yet though
not really bring any blocks
let's check on these guys i haven't seen
them in a while
hey what you selling these are the old
villagers i guess so they would have the
old school
trade system uh he still has bottle of
enchanting
um here let's do it maybe
here and i will bridge out as far as i
can
this is this is getting trippy
uh-huh got a little bit of a problem
here i forgot to bring the flint and
steel
so stupid i don't want to go back so i'm
going to try to do the wood thing
and if we're lucky it'll work it might
take a little while though
i also checked the villager house there
i noticed there was a chest
and oh
that lava sounds weird
oh it's burning it's burning
that's good there was nothing really in
that chest there's just some ender
pearls
oh come on come on come on oh you're so
close you can do it
i believe in you
[Music]
let's put some above it maybe
put another block there lights
please lights oh it caught fire on the
wrong side
oh no there we go we got it we got it
it's like the dumbest way to make
another portal but it works
all right let's go check it out this
might be amplified
mushroom biome if that's a thing
if it is the right place also oh not
cave
it says mushroom island okay
so check it out everyone this is the
mushroom island i
staircased out of the cave and here we
are
it is amplified too you see that there's
it's a pretty big mountain there
it's not super crazy stuff but it is
definitely taller than normal
and i'm just going around the coast here
i'm trying to spot a water temple that's
that's what we came here for um although
this is cool dude
don't get me wrong look how green the
grass is here it's amazing
why is there grass here this must be oh
this is a different biome
right yeah ocean then you cross the line
and it becomes mushroom island okay so
the
the mushroom island grass is even
greener
it's like starting to transition to the
ocean grass
already um
so keep your eyes open we will possibly
spot one
anytime here here's a good chance right
now a lot more ocean that we haven't
seen
i did bring my good helmet too we'll get
a little bit more armor with this
and we will be able to see underwater
pretty pretty easily too
nope all right i'm going to keep going
around the island hopefully we'll find
one
and if not we will just take a boat and
we'll sail around for a bit
and most likely we'll find one
yep there is one here on the very tip of
the mushroom island i saw it and just
barely
um so let's go look
let's see what we got in store we're not
uh
i think the main thing i'm going here
for is for sponges
um i'm not planning on making our farm
here
we're gonna do that closer to home but
i want to try it some sponges and just
for the adventure i'm curious to see
how bad it is um
i'm hoping i don't die though because i
don't know if i could get back here
all that easy and survive
see oh i see them already this is what
we got on us i got water breathing
night vision regen i'm gonna have these
going all the time i think the regens
i got strength and instant health
in case of emergency and hopefully
things are okay uh let's drink up
already
but i'm going with very little armor so
it should be challenging still i didn't
want to get super pumped
or like super op
oh wow that helps a lot
i think that's the boss zipping around
up there
i don't know if those guys respawn or
not i i'm trying to decide if i should
try to kill him or not
um okay let's go in oh you can see
that's so easy
i thought it was gonna be tough now
are they mad at me already please don't
be mad at me already
let's get some ender pearls too we might
be able to escape
um gonna take the regen
just to get a feel for how bad this is
oh
oh no okay this could be pretty bad
actually
oh and they're chasing me they're
chasing me
the problem is oh
oh that scared me the problem is
if they get mad at me and start chasing
me i can't really get away
i better get some blocks on my bar too
then
uh oh yeah doesn't he give mining
fatigue i do have mining fatigue so i
can't get in
the temple now right no
we gotta stay really close to the walls
so that we can block up if we need to
all right gotta go super stealth mode
[Music]
that that did not sound good whatever
that was
all right i'm pretty sure the entrance
is on this side i
could be wrong
how do you get in this thing oh yeah
this is it right
this looks like an entrance we still
have regen
let's get another one on our bar 40
seconds
not very long i think we'll be fine once
we get inside it's on the outside that
i'm
i'm scared that i'm gonna get surrounded
oh oh
oh oh oh get in get in see if i'm inside
i just block things up and we'll be okay
oh man
this is spooky let's turn the sound up
lots of lamps
yeah it's it's a lot safer inside
oh hey
nice nice oh there's another one
they don't get angry like zombie pigmen
where they call for help do they
because that would be bad
this is a big room i don't like this
room oh is this
uh is there gold inside that thing we
kill them all
they might not spawn inside anymore
why do they hurt me every time i hit
them do they have thorns
okay okay we're still good
regen has ran out i just saw one zip
around the corner there
it's the bosses that i'm scared of
because i heard they're really nasty
i better get that going whoa oh i hit
him i hit him
and i've never been in one of these so
i'm gonna get lost too i hate
mazes so much
sounds like he's close
[Music]
this is it no it keeps going
there's no bosses i thought we would ran
into one already
this place is deceptively large isn't it
what's up with this
weird
there's one right out that way however
you get there
i got lost in that room holy smokes
tells you how good my sense of direction
is
nope blocked
did we go in here
i think we did this dead ends as well so
this is not the way to go
i'm going to block it with some iron so
i know
oh there's lots of them down here now
sneak up on this guy no no
i'm almost out of regen potions
one shot killed him oh yeah they dropped
fish too
oh
i got no idea where to go
i was hoping to find a sponge room
let's get one more on our bar we have oh
we have three left that's not too bad
oh
don't think we were here can we go up
how bad is this mining fatigue like oh
it's pretty bad
you could break blocks if you had maybe
a minute
um
the thing is i'm totally lost now like
if i was if i had to get out of here i
don't think i could
uh he's trying to zap me
i feel like we were in here for sure
good the regen has ran out i'm trying to
conserve them though
where do we go
whoa no
no ouch let's go
let's go this way
oh this room dead ends too ouch
whoa whoa whoa that guy hit me a bunch
of times
okay it's blocked off oh there's two of
them
whoa whoa whoa taking so much damage
that's the entrance nope
um
hmm oh okay here we go sponge room
jackpot
oh my night vision's wearing off that's
why it's blinking
got worried for a second there which
means my aqua
or water breathing is worn off and my
speed or my strength potion
okay let's get a strength
okay we're all charged up again those on
our bar
can we grab these already or do we have
to fight the guy
i think we have to fight them otherwise
we just keep getting mining fatigue
the question is though where do you have
to go
i keep going in circles
oh this is maybe good oh there he is
there he is
got one hit does he have the same attack
i think he does
oh that guy's huge
okay let's be let's be sneaky here
on he's got a buddy in the room too ah
i hate when he does that
i'm so scared to just jump in this room
without having things to block my way
gotta get closer
okay i think we're good oh whoa
okay let's put one more pillar here
we're slowly getting closer
ouch oh man he found me he found me
whoa oh yeah
we got him we got him
he drops the sponge block eh
but there's three of them
i feel like i've been through this whole
place already and i've only seen the one
oh man
although i haven't seen this room i will
admit that
this is a bad room to walk down because
they're just going to snipe me
when i get closer and i can't hide
i better be careful if i was inside a
room and i blocked it off i probably
would get stuck in there because of the
mining fatigue i just realized
so i think that's it to this floor let's
go down
this is a sponge room i'm gonna block
this
every time man it gets me every time
my heart just jumps
oh this is the end guys night vision
wore off water breathing is wearing off
this is interesting does that go down
that might go down no it doesn't that's
kind of weird
all right we gotta get out of here we
have got to get out of here or i am
going to die in here
whoa i think this is the last regen
we have
having trouble finding my way out though
is the problem
things are a lot darker now too without
that night vision
okay let's see
oh no oh i did block it
just barely
my room there's a ton of them up there
oh and this guy's gonna snipe me
i'm drowning the door i found the door
whoa oh i totally missed that i bet you
that's how you get to the other bosses
right at
the entrance here
i see one of them up there okay okay
that's that's where we gotta go if we
wanna kill them later
i just want to get out of here live we
got one sponge block
no why are they chasing me stop chasing
me
he's not gonna leave me alone is he
block rate when it turns yellow that's
the trick
okay we're i think we're free
yeah we'll be fine i think we did it
that place is no joke that is that is
some tricky stuff in there
okay guys so that was a lot of fun i
really enjoyed that
the water temples are pretty cool
they did a good job on them and i'm
loving these new enemies
they're so neat i want to try and knock
one of them onto the land but every time
i try i almost die
come on yes yes
oh that is awesome they have a special
special like uh fish sound when they
when they flop around
oh that's awesome yeah very cool
next episode we are going to most likely
be making a farm for them over here
i got the gold already to make a haste
beacon and
we just gotta mine out a big big section
where the temple would have been if it
spawned here
and starts i don't know how i'm doing it
yet but we will
we'll figure it out next time um
here is the comment for today it says
etho
in 1.8 your whole gold farm would be
useless
in order to obtain the gold you would
actually have to
kill the zombie pigment with your own
sword hand tool etc
this will also affect the rare drops on
any other mobs
and the iron from iron golems
so pretty early in the 1.8 snapshot they
did actually change it so you
you have to kill the zombie pigmen with
a sword and and iron golems with the
sword but then they reverted that change
because
people in the community were kind of
angry about it they they weren't the
nicest about it
um so yeah they undid the change
and you can still get gold from
from zombie pigmen in fact you can
actually get it through the
the iron golems as we saw in the other
farm uh the reason i'm bringing this up
though is because i
checked it out with the snapshot i'm
using now
the 29b
and the zombie pigmen still do not
attack the iron golems but
now magma cubes and zombies like regular
zombies that spawn
are attacking the iron golems and
eventually it's gonna kill them
so we're gonna have to set up a healing
station to
to make that thing work now if we want
to keep using it which i do
because that's where all this gold came
from
it's so convenient so nice and wonderful
but anyway that is going to do it for
today guys i hope you enjoyed our
adventure
and i will see you again in the next one
thanks for watching bye