does this remind you of a dream you've
had before of a nightmare
that you can never forget that haunts
you every time you close your eyes when
you should seek professional help
because this is just minecraft so so so
so hello everybody this is its toe well
well welcome back to another oh I messed
up my intro let me try it again hello
everybody this is Ito and welcome back
to another episode of my let's play
series today we are starting out in the
end because we're safe we're good ok
there's something I want to do here and
also people have actually requested that
I do an episode in the end because it's
been so long and it really has been I
haven't been here in a long long time I
usually use my dual blaze firm instead
of the ender ender which still works
pretty good
okay I let you kill when they call now
awesome out
off
come on
everyone here again hey come on guys
yeah it works pretty good I like when
they fall now it makes like this big
explosion effect from the particles like
that because they fall 40-block so it's
a big fall for them it's like you got
these little bombs falling all over
around us but yeah I don't come here too
often anymore I still use enderpearls a
lot though and one of the things I've
been wanting to build in my world here
is like a way of transporting the ender
pearls from the farm back to the ender
portal here so they're easy to get but
get through because I find I don't use
ender pearls as much as I would like to
because they're kind of a pain to
transport like from here all the way to
my man cave is a long distance really so
today we still have the East Road here I
think I think the way we're going to do
this is open this up right now the
easiest way of doing it I think is to
set up a track underneath here with a
two-block high clearance mm maybe maybe
we can get it so we can load the
minecart up over there with ender pearls
and then when it's full it'll take off
down this track drop them off and then
come back once we reload the the
minecart or something but yeah so we're
going to we're going to try set up some
automated ender pearl delivery system
today if we can and there's also a few
other little things I want to try out
with the end like getting a horse there
how how does that work exactly let's
find out so luckily I have a pathway all
the way from here to the stronghold base
that I almost never use but it's it's
available if I need right over here
hey guys yeah I built this a long time
ago don't really use it but it's it's
there if I ever need to like move
supplies from one base to another easily
so we might use this to get the ender
pearls to the man cave or we might try
to set something up through the nether
because the nether would be a lot closer
but just got to deal with going through
portals and stuff if you go the nether
route this is actually a lot further
than I remembered
oh and Enderman damage look at this now
we got to decide what we're going to
build the rail track for out of and I'll
probably just do stone slabs because
they're nice and simple wow this is far
this is really far Wow I thought I'm
actually a little amazed I don't
remember being this long okay mountain
this mountain biome Oh River and take a
turn and for some reason it's dark here
oh because it's swamp land that grass is
darker and it comes out to over here oh
that thing was fun to make okay so we're
pretty close I think the strongholds we
can get to right here maybe hello oh
that wasn't smart nope yeah why am i
taking damage so fast did they change
that to like that is quick suffocation
damage all right come back so second
chance we got to get you up here
and there's a fall here that will
probably kill him so let's be a little
careful and me kill me too I'm sure
okay jump don't fall don't fall don't
fall don't fall jump let's actually get
a little protective wall going okay good
and then the end portal right down here
let's just take a look yes we're gonna
take this out just needs a two by two oh
he did not do that he killed himself
didn't he seriously he's gone he fell oh
there you are you you little bugger
second chance it took half a heart okay
now I got to do this jump again it's not
too bad not too bad okay and here we go
what is going to happen okay expected
that now when we hop off yep we both
went through and now safely get them up
here okay so I had this idea with the
horse like I can I can run around here
with a pump down my head and just take
these guys out or I can I can stand over
here and and look at them all and have
them come to me but then I gotta wait
for him to come towards me this way I
have to spend time running around but
I'm wondering how quick is it with the
horse if I just go like assassin mode
here how tough is this
not superfast still see I'm trying to
find something that's quicker than
having them come to me with this this
set up where they're all flat on the
ground like this
okay let's try speed it up I brought
some potions and other ideas I could get
a beacon here with speed to on and then
I could run around a lot quicker not
with the horse but just eyes as myself
this isn't too bad don't think it's
faster than having them come to me
though but it's interesting to see
regardless it's just a little too hard
to control well we got 30 levels in no
time just goofing around over here so
let's try and chant the sword I
enchanted one of these earlier today and
I got a little surprise let's see if we
can make it happen again for lucky here
what a piece of junk could you ask for a
worse enchantment Elias is there bane of
arthropods three that would have been
pretty bad to you but yeah earlier today
I enchanted a diamond sword 30 levels
and it got unbreaking three on it so
they must have changed it when they
added the Chapmans for fishing rods I'm
guessing where you can now get
unbreaking 3 from enchanting swords or
run breaking period I would say so
that's pretty cool
okay so we're just laying the the ground
for our track here we're going to use
these wooden slabs I guess they kind of
match the fences in that above not that
it matters too much I put all my stuff
in the chest because I figured I would
die placing these slabs above the void
there but I actually actually didn't
because sometimes when you place these
it will place
like a half slab blower and you'll just
fall through the ground as you're
placing it which is really annoying but
it didn't happen which I was a little
surprised yeah we're going to make this
come all the way up to our n portal here
I was trying something here with the e
throat - I I wanted like a return an
ejection system for the boats it turns
out and these are a pain by the way if
you want a boat to dispense you have to
put it the dispenser one to three blocks
below the actual or two blocks below -
no three blocks one two three below the
actual water you want the boat and so
watch this
do do to do and we get the boats so
press the button and the boat comes up
there any higher and it goes on top of
the half slabs here which is really
weird but I tested it out and on the
return instead of breaking on the cactus
it the boat explodes and into sticks and
planks and doesn't doesn't return
properly so I may have to make some
adjustments but let's see let's go let's
go back to the world here and get some
tracks going I got something to tell you
guys this episode let me know if you
notice the difference but I've changed
my audio settings a little bit I've I
noticed that see we want these I noticed
that all this time I've like I checked
my recording settings my mic settings I
should say and apparently I've been
recording at forty four thousand one
hundred Hertz instead of forty eight
thousand so my but my voice might sound
a little bit clearer this episode let me
know if it's better or worse I've tried
listening to it and it almost sounds
more pingy to me for some reason
but maybe my my speakers are too loud or
something I don't know
let me know if you if you think I sound
better I've also made some other
adjustments in the video might be
smoother and that too I've just I've
been trying to improve things quality
wise and I've been looking into it guys
I've had a pat this current computer for
three years now it's it's a pretty good
computer actually I paid fourteen
hundred bucks for it
three years ago about and it's got an i7
860 in it and I figure what the video
card is actually I got all the specs on
my channel I think but 16 gigs of ram
it's still a pretty good computer I I
think it's pretty good still I don't
have too much trouble with it but it's
been about three years and I use my
computer a lot like a few hours everyday
at least um so I've been looking for a
new one and let me know what you think
of this guys like you you experts out
there I found this computer it's $2,000
an Asus I don't know if that's a good
brand or not let me know and it's down I
74770 KN processor a lot of people don't
realize this but just saying you have an
i7 doesn't doesn't mean you have like
top-of-the-line computer there's
different models like first generation
second generation third and I think
they're up to the fourth now so the
4770k is a part of the fourth generation
there's also different lakes specs to it
like some are more efficient than others
like they consume less power
but do more well then they won't be as
fast as like a gaming processor anyway
but I think it's pretty good processor
it's only been out for a few months it's
got a g4 770 video card in 32 gigs of
ram 3 terabyte hard drive 128 you could
bite solid-state drive with Windows 8 on
and that's about it
blue blu-ray drive so 2,000 bucks let me
know what you guys think of that I might
get it um we definitely improve my
quality because I could sometimes when I
play Minecraft it its legs a little bit
like the frame rate gets choppy and if I
had a better computer it would probably
work better and also I'd be able to
render videos quicker and that kind of
stuff too which would be nice I think
what we're going to do just for this is
I'm where to start we'll keep it a low
profile we'll do power rail tech drills
like this every every few blocks here ah
come on
this is why we don't build in the end
very often I was taking the East Road
back like grabbed a bunch of tracks full
stack of power rails there and all kinds
of stuff and on the way back when I made
it to the end of the ice road uh the
boat fell through the ground and broke
and I am falling come on come on come on
hit something it's something no sure
sure there's that and I just lost a
whole ton of stuff still have some more
now thankfully I had a feeling something
like that was going to happen today
that's why I put my tools and my boots
in that chest I still have those but I
have them on now so I definitely don't
want to die now I did lose an enchanted
diamond axe though and a whole bunch of
rails the type of rails power rails for
the rails and like a stack of woods and
stuff to my stake so bit annoying but I
recovered here and I got most of this
built now so I'll show you what it's
going to do very simple actually not
nothing too fancy here but we have a
storage minecart down below
with iron fences I can walk on these
without falling through no problem
but I can also access the minecart and
fill it up with ender pearls and let's
just see if it makes it all the way back
so yeah I'll be able to get ender pearls
here and then send them off over here we
have a button there goes hopefully it
makes it all the way I decided to do
something like this just it was the
easiest way of doing it oh you know what
I don't think I have any ladders so
we'll just walk on here I guess and
every 20 blocks I have a detective rail
and a power rail hopefully that was
enough for it to make it all the way
hungry already watermelon is really
really lame you see the snow been there
that's from when I fought the Dragons
still I still have snowmen on the island
and they're like an never-ending battle
with the Enderman they'll take a take a
shot at the Enderman Enderman teleports
every time so that before they used to
attack the snowman but they don't
anymore and it made it awesome so we
need to make an unloading station here
too yet oh no I didn't I didn't we're
good let me grab some comparators and
stuff and we will do that so I was
looking through a bunch of chests for
some redstone stuff here and in one of
them I happen to find a single lone
comparator we only need one though so
let's make sure we don't lose it these
guys have actually saved me a few times
like I've accidentally looked at
Enderman and they've been chasing me and
then one of these guys will just
secret-service him and take off and
leave me alone
that's pretty cool
so what we're trying to do here
storage minecart is going to come we
want to unload the ender pearls into
some chest reservoirs here and then
return automatically on its own if if
the Ches the reservoir is full we want
it to sit here and wait until there's
space for it and then once the cart is
fully unloaded may take off again so to
do all that is actually pretty simple
let me show you how to do it case you
don't know we're going to change this
you sound change this over to a bunch of
hoppers and actually let's put the chest
down already so we'll have a few double
Ches well this is actually really messy
setup sadly my end is not very pretty I
haven't I haven't focused too much on
making it look good and it shows maybe
one day we'll build some natural
structures here though and try to make
something cool let's get our power rail
back so stuff stuff will trickle down to
the bottom chest items in these hoppers
going into the chest can also go down to
these hoppers so should work out okay
and then to do that cart thing see hey
whoa
guy get out of my crosshair oh yeah
we're gonna have to lower this more
actually pick these out
this is why I had an axe on me before I
lost it
get that going and compared her here
look how simple this is so we get a
comparator block in front of that oops
invert the signal with a torch and get
some redstone dust up here and then a
block on top of that like so so that
power is the power rail unless there's
an item flowing through here then this
turns on this turns off and the cart
sits there until it's done sending stuff
through the hopper so it's pretty simple
however though let's actually get rid of
this for right now I just want to show
you something really important with this
setup okay just a little experiment here
so if you if you send blocks through
this look at this the comparator is not
turning on because there's it's not
registering any items in the hopper very
strange because it's definitely sending
stuff through there if you were to lock
the hopper below for a split second as
it's still sending stuff
hey all Sun starts working it's flashing
on and off very strange take this stuff
back but again we send stuff through
this isn't turning on we powered for a
while now it stays on all the time very
weird take that out put it back and now
it's not doing it again so this is a
weird thing that happens if you have a
hopper below it sends it right through
and kind of skips this one but if we
just a really simple trick you can do is
just use a chest
and now when we send stuff through this
always works pick it out put it back
this turns on so that's one way of
getting around that little issue and you
should definitely keep that in mind if
you're setting this up okay so let's
let's actually test it out now doo doo
doo okay so you get a storage cards
let's put this let's make this easier on
me
oh yeah and put the power rail back like
so so now adds let's cut that in half
actually so it goes quicker push it over
that turns the power rail off beam seats
off it's unloading right now 13 12 10 mm
5 4 3 2 1 and automatically goes back
sweets so that's all there is to that
well it said time again everybody where
we need to wrap up the episode
unfortunately so here we go this is the
comment I picked for today it says
heyyyyy so what's your favorite movie
just wondering not going to judge not
going to judge you or anything like that
mmm this is a tough one because there's
a lot of good movies really um and my
favorite movie changes quite often too I
find but probably currently well I just
my all-time favorite movie is probably
the Truman Show I really liked that
movie um when I was in school I had to
do like a film study on it for my
English and that really made me
appreciate the movie a lot more because
I had to like look at the different
camera angles and figure out what they
meant like what mood they were trying to
convey and all that kind of stuff
and just really in-depth analyzation of
the movie and yeah that was a really
interesting movie because there's like
all these different camera angles and
that kind of stuff and just blew my mind
when it realized all the work that went
into it um and it had an awesome story
and all that kind of stuff good actor
Jim Carrey you know probably second
favorite movie is the prestige and Oh a
couple other good movies I like I like
the Guardian that's a good one I like my
favorite animated movies probably wall-e
really like that one um let's see
I like Gone in sixty Seconds a lot of
people don't like Nicolas Cage I know
that's but I like that movie um what
else what else what other than alight
amuses Canal woo um what else
Armageddon is good
that's a really cliche The Dark Knight
The Avengers it was good I'm kind of
getting sick uh well I'm not eating sick
action movies I just don't find it I
could ever pick them as a favorite movie
ever I like something that's a little
more intelligent than just like a
Hollywood thriller type thing but like
the procedure for example but anyway
that's just a few of them um Jurassic
Park very cool yeah so thanks for
watching guys hope you enjoyed it I'll
see you next time take care bye bye
you