[Music]
hello
readings salutations and other
delightful welcoming words
hey hey hey
no you're supposed to be a good spider
that's right put your head down
um
still messing around with the silver
fish and
you're gonna behave you're gonna be hate
if you want to be part of the show you
gotta behave
okay uh pattern three i believe was the
winner
and i think it looks really good now
that it's all done
i did replace the glowstone with the
lamps and it looks
a lot better with them as was suggested
uh i like how they're kind of they got
the dark
and the light look mixed in with them
which kind of goes with the floor pretty
pretty well now you're not
in the shot come down here
all right oh oh
oh now look what you did
oh dang don't do that don't do that okay
we tried to include him but he he didn't
want to play nice
uh i also set up this little
um what do you call it like an archery
range thing for the snow golems
basically these guys will be shooting at
the silver fish when i let them out so
that i don't uh
have to hit them myself these guys will
take care of it for me
and it works out really well because the
snowballs don't do any damage to them so
they can hit them all day
no problem and basically
it's just like uh i got half slabs
surrounding them
and above i just did like a little
pattern thing here
the snow block will probably get
replaced with the glass block
and then put a sticky piston above him
and that way i can control
when i want them shooting when i don't
because if the sticky
or if the glass block gets pushed down
into their head i don't think
they'll be able to see anymore without
taking any suffocation so i think that's
the way i'll do it and hopefully that
won't cause any problems with lotting
off or anything
and this wooden stuff is mostly just for
looks but
it's really important that it's a block
and a half high so the silver fish can't
jump and get the snow golems over here
because they only get they can only jump
one block up
so that works out pretty good and
i think i got rid of all the lava around
here so i
had a lot of fires while building this i
think that's taken care of now
this is all cobble where the lava was
and this isn't done yet this wooden
stuff i just
want to get this all settled the problem
is i believe i'm going to have to
lower everything one block
because when this room fills up with
these silverfish blocks
uh it's going to be right in these
guys's face and they won't be able to
see the silverfish
so gotta lower the floor gotta lower
this wooden stuff
and basically start over all that stuff
can stay though
because i originally planned on having
them shoot through like these little
half half block gaps or whatever near
the floor
but they just don't i tried it they
can't really see through them
and even if you can get them to target a
silver fish they
uh almost always hit the walls
there's just not enough space so now i
got them
a nice open area around them so that
they can hit the silver fish
fairly fairly often
and i blocked that off there because i
kept being creepered
and now mobs just pour in there and get
stuck
anyway i i hate to do it but i will
lower the floor now
it's going to take me a little while and
then we will
be back and do something here
all right so i did it i lowered the
floor on everything by one block
uh which took a bit of time but it's
very important
that's done so that these guys can see
their enemies i've got my minions in
place here
and you can see there's a sticky piston
above
which will push the glass block into
their head when i want them to
stop shooting and the reason there's
silverfish missing here is because i uh
practiced to see how they
dealt with it before i haven't seen it
with all them yet
oh i saw a silver fish appear back there
now i've noticed
stucco with each other you see that that
guy got hit
um oh now they're popping
okay
it's really weird how this works i
almost think it works better if i'm
standing next to the silverfish
blocks
[Music]
i'm not sure
i'm not like uh they only break out of
the blocks
if uh within that
i think 10 blocks of the silver fish or
it might be
10 10 blocks of me or 10 blocks of the
snow globes i'm not sure which one it is
[Music]
like when i get close to it they start
popping out
actually they might be too low
okay i'm gonna pause the game and check
what the range is
on these guys
all right so i checked the wiki oh no
that one got up there
that must have been from outside
i checked the wiki and it says they
appear
in that 21 by 11 by 21
space so that's like 10 blocks
horizontally
and either five blocks above or below
them
so it seems like they're chasing me
mostly
snow golems
it's really hard to do anything here
i missed i want to get on top of that
dang it
yes okay
so now these higher ones are breaking if
it's
of the silverfish uh five blocks above
them would be
one two three four
five so that would be the limit now
they're breaking no
above that
maybe we'll just hang out around here
don't let it popped off
and see if these continue breaking could
be they
they break when the silverfish jump
yeah no more really popping off so it
must be of the silverfish
taking damage
all right and i think when the snow
golems shoot them they chase the snow
goal
for a little while and then they start
following me oh
great you see that light just went off
there must have been a silver fish under
[Music]
there destroyed the lever
okay so that might be a problem we'll
have to deal with trying to get the rest
of them to break at that height
okay i'm noticing another problem here
uh when the silverfish gets
shot and they're in the middle of a jump
they can get launched up
above the barrier and start attacking
snow golems
which is a big problem
it's amazing the damage these things do
like just one silver fish will make
such a mess
there's a big hole over here too that
has appeared
in a very short amount of time
and it keeps going by the looks of it oh
there we go
and these guys are tougher to work with
than i thought they would be
i have to redesign this a little bit
let's see
what to do what to do
[Music]
yeah there goes the snow golem
all right well i'm going to kill all
these guys i think we're done with them
snow golems are doing a good job of
where they're at though they're
hitting them pretty consistently
um
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
run wire to all those pistons and then
they will all just
go down when they're powered and go up
when they're unpowered
i'll probably do that pretty quick
ah peace and quiet finally i want to
check out this
this spot over here where i keep hearing
the mobs because
i haven't left this area since i started
working on it really or since i lowered
the floor
and more and more keep funneling there
and i want to see how many
there actually is now
so quite a few
get a record
yes
look at them all there's another creeper
down there
wow
another creeper over there
silverfish damage
look at this
wow
ooh iron all right
uh okay so i'm going to think about what
to do about this uh
silverfish problem this is the line of
wire i gotta run yet
for the pistons all along here oh
looks like a silver fish got up here
um i don't really know how to fix that
though because if they get much higher
they won't be able
to really hit them
and i'll have to lower everything again
that's going to be annoying if i do
changes
okay so i thought about this for a
little bit and i think we can make it
work still
i believe if i'm not down there the
silverfish won't jump
that's what we want to test out here
so we'll see if we can spot
the silverfish jumping
maybe we'll just branch out here
get a better view
um what i'll probably do
is put a layer of glass above above
these
pistons here at that level like at this
level here
and cover this whole room with it
so then i can walk above here and
observe from above
i'm pretty sure they won't be able to
get up to the snowball
unless i'm down there oh oh he's jumping
he's jumping
it's hard to say they lose their
attention really quick when the snow
golems hit them
that guy got ticked off he's going for
him he's going for him
oh
um
it's hard to say so the snow golems
could take care of the bottom
four layers for me and a little bit of
the fifth one even
and then i think i should set up another
room up above here to hit the
the silverfish as well to take care of
the top layer
or top two layers
and these guys will just be like my
assistants
um i just uh
got an idea for something i want to try
here too not really related to this
the other day when i was playing
minecraft i had a
pet wolf and
i never really have messed around with
the pets i don't know they just never
really appealed me to me all that much
oh
and you know what else i do have the
setup now we should check it out
see if they still attack while
being inside the glass but basically
i attacked the mob and the wolf killed
him
and when the wolf killed him xp dropped
which i didn't know that happens i don't
know if it's always been like that since
uh xp was introduced or not but uh
let's get one more down here
you guys gonna hit them okay so they are
shut off now
that the glass is down
um i'm going to log out and log back in
and see if they get messed up at all
because that's something that always
concerns me
okay so that's a good shut off for them
very simple uh
yeah so i'm gonna go try find a wolf to
tame and we're gonna do a few
tests with them as well
okay i've been out hunting for wolves
and i haven't found any yet
but i found a ton of sheep all these
white
all white sheep some over there
some here a whole field of them here
these are all natural i didn't i didn't
create these
it's crazy uh yeah i'm kind of on the
boundary of
more over there my discovered world
i've only found wolves once in my lp
world so far
and i don't remember where it was i
don't think they despawn anymore from
what i can tell
so if i could find that spot again i
could get some otherwise i gotta
probably generate new world here
so i finally stumbled across a wolf pack
here
um oh
that was bad i was wondering if you can
breed them while they're still wild
breed
doesn't look like it
no i don't think so
all right i choose you nope
get back here
one i'm not going to bother naming them
i'm not good at naming things
and i'll probably lose them i give them
my food
so we'll just grab two for now
they don't do good against spiders they
never do
spiders have too big of a
collision box
okay so i'm gonna take these guys back
to my skeleton trap
and we're gonna check a few things
and then uh i'll see you in a bit here
all right here we are at the skeleton
farm with
our wolves and we even have a baby wolf
now with a
giant freak head um
i was thinking you could make an
automatic xp farm with them
but they don't seem to be going after
the skellies
so i'm guessing the skellies actually
have to hit me for them to
to attack the skeletons
or else they have to be shooting i don't
know
let's see how can we do this
i don't want to lose all my wolves um
yeah they're gonna kill each other
though
there's got to be a way of doing this
no they don't attack when they're
shooting either
i was walking through the forest at
night and they were attacking mobs
all over the place
that'll do it
hmm they only attack the ones that hit
me though
okay well yeah this probably won't work
it's just an idea
actually there's one more thing i wanted
to check too uh
get xp from mobs that the wolves kill
i'm wondering if you also get the rare
drops like the bose
from skeletons so i'm gonna stay here
for a little while with the wolves and
see if we can get
a bow drop from the from the wolves
killing the skeletons
oh it does work amazing
yeah so the only real way of doing the
automatic xp
thing is if you let the mobs attack you
first
then the wolves will do their job
which is too bad uh it's possible but
not very practical
all right well we figured out a few new
things today um
this project is going to be pretty cool
it's all done i'm pretty sure
the way we're going to get the
silverfish out of here is uh over there
now
i know i talked about having like a
licking area over there before but i
decided it would probably be best
to put it over there just to keep
everything consistent
uh so we'll have the killing thing over
there and
we will also have a way of transporting
the silverfish
up to the surface probably and out to
other locations
is the plan but
all in due time so i'm going to call an
end for today
thanks for watching everybody and i'll
see you again
some other time bye-bye