hello all you wonderful people and the
rest of you too thanks for joining me
again for another LP episode I am just
collecting some sand blocks pretty much
all outs using using them up quick I've
been trying to fill my potion room with
glass bottles so I don't have to worry
about ever running out and that's eating
up all my sand and the sandstone is
going to the tree farm so constantly
running out this is my new official
block gathering song it's growing on me
it's a really long song actually and
whoop there goes I thought it lets you
join me on the fun part of this anyway
ah it's kind of wondering what I should
do with today's episode and a lot of
people have asked that I actually work
on the Enderman farm some more it seems
to be one of the big things people want
so I think that's what we'll do to start
out at least you're going to start work
on the third ring today don't know if I
can finish it
because it will be very very costly and
I don't have I don't know if I have
enough materials to do it and it's also
going to take a long time because just
the second ring alone took me an hour to
when I did it a few days ago or weeks or
however long ago it was
but anyway I'm going to get my stuff
together and we're going to head out
there yeah ah love click this and I'm
not sure which way I like more this way
or with TNT TNT is slightly more fun I
think and quicker but it's a lot
sloppier and you lose out the get nearly
as much Sam stone using TNT so I think
I'm going to stick to this method and
guess what I finally figured out how
these jukeboxes actually work and
something confusing me for a long time
so normally I keep my music volume down
so you wouldn't think jukeboxes would
play music right well they do they're
actually linked with your sound volume
apparently but if you adjust your volume
after you start it it doesn't affect the
volume of the record now it's way louder
now that I turned it up turn my sound
all the way down still plays now if I
restart it
apparently it's still plating for some
reason okay um I got a few more things
to figure out about these apparently I
don't know why oh I bet you it messes up
if you're off somehow yeah it does
that's weird that's got to be a glitch
playing right now you switch it to off
you can steal the record and it won't to
turn off trysting anyway let's head off
to the Enderman farm I when I finish
collecting this and I'll meet you there
okay so welcome to the ender farm I've
been busy working on the third ring here
it's going well it's taking taking its
time though as I expected and I thought
I would get you guys involved on the
exciting repetitive building involved in
adding a third ring I thought you would
enjoy that actually this is something I
can do in Minecraft that is fairly easy
and I can focus on talking because
normally I can't talk while building but
this is something extremely easy to do
so here's my chance to talk to you guys
name what should we call ender farm I
did ask that a while ago and we got
quite a few good suggestions one I liked
was the Rainmaker because the Enderman
fall down like rain and there were a few
other good ones for some reason I can't
remember them now I should have checked
before bringing that up I guess anyway I
thought I would do like a
question answer type thing here because
I get a lot of questions asked
repeatedly and I I do often reply to
them in the comments but my reply gets
drownded out pretty quick so I'm
guessing very few people actually see it
and I thought I'd answer some of the
questions that get asked a lot so to
start off with will I ever show my face
that's the number one question it seems
on people's minds
ah here's the thing about that I am NOT
against showing my face but the thing is
a lot of people want to see my face but
there's a lot of people that don't want
to see it either it would ruin the
mystery and as it stands right now I
don't really have a good camera or any
camera actually that I could use to show
it so I don't really see any reason to
at the moment if there was a reason like
a good reason for me to show it I
wouldn't have anything against that of
course I'm not trying to hide anything
but at the moment there's no good reason
for me to or no real way for me to so
you probably won't see my face for a
while or a long time or ever at add the
way things are going now so that's that
um another question what do I use to
record I use fraps I record it half size
and then I reduce the size to 854 by 480
before I upload it to YouTube and I
compress it with the exid not
necessarily the best thing or the best
way of doing it which brings me to
another question why don't I upload in
hd-quality 720 or higher it's because I
have slow internet so it would just take
too long I've tried it in the past and
it usually takes me about 15 to 60
in about yeah like 16 hours to upload 20
to 30 minute video at 7:20 which is
really crummy I like to upload longer
videos when I go to sleep so that in the
morning it's sitting there ready to I
upload as unlisted and then when I wake
up in the morning I'll often just switch
it to public after I fill in all the
information I need to but if it takes 16
hours that means a big portion of the
day my Internet's going to be running
extremely slow because I'll be uploading
a video so I'll lose my internet access
during the day which really sucks if you
ever have to do it doesn't completely
lose it but it slows down quite a bit if
you're uploading video so yeah
no no 720p or anything coming anytime
soon I can't get faster internet where I
live it's just I'm a little bit out of
the city so that's just what I have to
deal with there's nothing better mmm
what else should we talk about am I
going to enter the new race for wool
tournament the second one coming up the
reddit one I am NOT I talked to if you
disco and sethbling and Kraft Dynasty
about that and it seems we would like to
like it was fun but it just takes too
much of our time so we all kind of
unanimously agreed not to do with this
round but does sound like a lot of cool
people are entering it which would have
made it extra fun last tournament I
didn't really know anybody who entered
besides my team but now it's like I know
cilantro said well I'm not going to name
names just in case anything changes but
a few of my buddies said they were going
to enter
um what else what else I should have
made a list before I start doing a
question/answer thing it would be easier
if you were here to actually ask me
questions but just going by memory of
ones I've seen often am I gonna stream
anytime soon it's one of those things
I'm just I'm really lazy and haven't
gotten around to setting it up I would
like to do it for slower drawn out video
things that I'd like to do like I
mentioned practicing legendary within
the new patches to do speedruns that's
the type of thing I would do streaming
but I want an upload video of on YouTube
just because I think it would want to
appeal to a whole lot of people and it
would take a lot of time but hopefully
one day if I find the time I can set up
streaming at twitch TV again my twitch
TV is etho TV there is an imposter that
uses the name etho LP and he doesn't
seem to be going away so be wary of that
mean person who is trying to steal my
identity let's see my twitter is etho LP
just like the name he stole so if you
want to follow me on twitter that's
that's what it is I don't often forget
to post tweets and stuff just because I
never use Twitter the only reason I use
it now is because people wanted me to
and I try my best
oh yeah the CTM map I wanted to talk
about that - I'm not afraid stone
dang it I'm still working on it it's
taken a long time I got a lot done on it
today I try to work on as much as I can
but between making videos and stuff I
don't have a whole lot of time for map
making and it's
one of those things I can't put a top
priority but it's going well it's a big
map
lots of trickery to it so I think people
are going to like that I'm working at
making it fun and entertaining and good
for video and so far I think it's good
for that I'm worried I'm not going to be
able to get things bounced very well or
that it might have a bad flow to it but
hopefully I can get it going good
before I release it I haven't like I'm
adding chest the matter as I build it
but I'm not putting anything in them
because I figure I should do that
afterwards to bounce things out I'm
totally on redstone okay that's end of
Q&A for now I don't know if I'll
continue but I gotta go get some
redstone this is a WoW so I'm gonna
probably stop at three rings because
it's it's going to be enough I think I
could get better
Enderman rates if I was to add more but
then they would spread out more and it
would cost a lot to build it so three
rings looks pretty good to me
and like I said the watermelon and the
corners I'll probably have to replace
with green wool or something because
they keep stealing the watermelon all
right I'll see you guys in a bit alright
guys I'm back here and I think we're
going to work on the farm some more I
hope you don't mind today being a bit of
a talky episode the advantage of it
being a talky episode is you'll probably
get it a day sooner than it normally
would take me is do not have enough time
to do a normal episode today it actually
takes me I would estimate about four to
eight hours to make it regular
regular LP episode that's because I tend
to cut out anything I think people find
boring or repetitive or uninteresting
like what I'm doing here I think people
are going to find a little bit boring
but is that well I like to throw in
curveball episodes like this every so
often just things interesting to a hole
and I know some people like to talk you
once but I know a lot of people are
going to find today's episode boring
what was I saying something yeah about
four to eight hours for an LP because I
cut out me caving usually I cut out you
know like sand gathering and all that
stuff resource gathering usually there's
time I spend thinking of ideas and
playing around with them that I I'll
skip out and stuff like that but on with
some more questions here one I get quite
often is there going to be madly it's
okay I didn't look at them then look at
them why don't I use mods I got nothing
against tunnel and there's no guarantee
I will all forever stay here for mods I
do actually use mcedit now for map
making and sometimes for tutorials oops
so definitely don't have anything
against them but hope if I was to use
them regularly in my gameplay I think it
would
she's guys would get lost all day he's
bad
I think it would okay you made this
choice you would wreak vanilla minecraft
for me if I was to use mods you'll never
be the same again
so try to avoid them I don't use a
texture packs because oops I do videos
and I want people to know what blocks on
placing and if you use texture packs
sometimes it's challenging for people to
even tell what you're doing it there's
some really crazy texture packs out
there so definitely want people to know
how I'm building things and stuff I have
been tempted to use the old faithful one
it looks really nice I like it a lot
but I think I'll just stay pure here
texture pack free I've never even tried
one before don't really read it um what
else what happened to dots Dave the
tentacle I was doing that series of the
night got distracted or something I
never intentionally stopped making
videos of it but it just kind of
happened
and I have been thinking about finishing
it up I probably only need to play it
for another hour two hours tops to
finish that series so I probably will
pick it up again sometime soon here
because I have a lot of people
requesting it Harvest Moon though I
intentionally did stop it was getting
repetitive very repetitive and I wasn't
very happy with my commentary during it
so if I'm not happy with one of my
videos I'm not going to release it so I
just stopped that series it's more of a
game again that I should be streaming
instead of posting new videos of I do
really like Harvest Moon
what else tips for starting your channel
make an awesome video post it on the
forums get a lot of attention do it
again that's my advice do not go to
other people's channels spamming come
check out my channel I really do not
recommend that it might work but it's
not something you should be doing it's
like poor etiquette on YouTube and it's
not required in my opinion I never did
anything like that and I have managed to
get a few subscribers not to doing cheap
things like that so yep just my advice
on that stuff um what else mob system in
storage room idea around the backside
here Oh actually I think I'm I didn't
bring any green wool with me I should
have I can extend this out though I
think maybe I will be making a mob
system and storage room sometime soon
probably also be building a lot of farms
around that area once I start that like
cactus farms and all that uh oh well no
no no I didn't look at you it's bad
place being knocked around day
I'm gonna lose if I get knocked off what
do I have on me um yeah storage room and
stuff coming soon probably but probably
within five or ten episodes I'll start
working on the new area I have a lot of
interesting ideas coming up soon so I
think you guys will like some of the
night
next the things I build what else am I
going to make more minecraft server
videos I am I have one ready to go I
just need someone to open his present
and then I can post it but that's just
an occasional series so don't expect it
all the time
and I think that's about it for the Q&A
I hope you enjoyed it too hope it wasn't
too boring I do ramble a lot I can't
help it um to finish up this video I
think we'll do a little bit of
experimenting with enderpearls
oh don't touch me um yeah maybe a few
other things I don't know yeah well I
died that was pretty bad I fell right
from that corner down to here I lost my
chess piece
I lost my shovel and my really awesome
axe the best axe you can get is gone or
almost the best axe you can get still
have my pick though and my awesome
swords
it's a trade-off I lost some redstone
some Pistons some wool and I'm sure some
other things I'll realize later so a
little bit depressing but it happens I
think I will stop working on this for
today because of that and let's go see
what we can do with these things okay
let's have some fun with these ender
pearls let's see what we can do over
here but apparently you can hit mobs
with them I didn't know that that's
freaky you can uh I mean throw them
raided a creeper and get teleported
right to the creeper probably I should
try that Jack on the zombie yeah
definitely works I guess there's no
creepers around anymore but I did find
pig here oops
okay I guess we're not going to try that
that's going to going to ride them and
then throw one but oh well I guess I
could try with a boat or something or my
cart would probably do the same thing
yeah okay so you take damage but you
don't actually move very weird
I'm not really sure what happens if you
throw more than one pearl at a time so
let's try that we're going to throw one
way up first up I then we're going to
throw a second one that'll land first
and see if we teleport twice or which
one
teleports us okay we do teleport toys
that's that's interesting
now I'm wondering if there's like a
certain delay that needs to pass before
you can teleport the second time so I'm
going to throw three in a row really
quick together now there's no delay by
the looks of it I got teleport three
times and I I only lost five hearts
instead of seven-and-a-half all right if
I throw two really quick it should take
five hearts but it only took what was
that two and a half hmm
so if you do a few spam I'm really quick
you won't take damage the second time
because you're still you're hurt delay
is still occurring so it doesn't damage
you the second time next I want to try
see if you can teleport to the top of a
block by throwing a pearl at the bottom
of a block kind of like how you can
place boats on top of a block if you
click on the bottom let's try this out
mmm might need a bigger platform like a
teleport to this side they're only going
to do it one thick
you throw on at a wall I think you just
fall down yeah oh I was stuck in the
wall there that was weird
I should have brought some regen potions
with me or something that time I didn't
stick mhm okay I'm going to try this
hopefully I don't die here now okay I
didn't tell them then teleport me
through the block it's getting dark here
so I'm going to try throw one and sleep
as it's in the air nope interrupted my
sleep although I'm right by the bed so
it just woke me up then teleport me okay
I made it 30 blocks I now we're going to
try it again but first I wanted to do
another thing to see if you can throw it
downward faster then you fall or roughly
to save yourself you know so you can
cool all right this is where I die
maybe ah maybe not
it goes over 30 blocks high that's crazy
um it looked like maybe 33 34 yeah yeah
I would say about 33 34 is the height
let's do the falling one again here I
think it might be a different story if
we wait for our velocity to increase
before we throw it so maybe like halfway
down the fall I also extended this to 35
blocks so we can do the height one again
after we get down so here we go okay so
i teleported onto myself which helped
break the fall that was really weird
okay let's do the height one again so
this is 35 blocks oh great now nope it
was going to happen that's why I set my
spawn here so I rewatched the video from
that falling one the last one where i
teleported onto myself at it looks like
I felt quite a ways after that but
didn't take damage because I was still
under the delay from the enderpearl
damage so I didn't take any additional
fall damage which is interesting the
height one I didn't get a good look so
we're going to have to do it again it
did look like 33 or 34 though yeah I
would say 34 maybe it's a max height
it's really hard to tell without a
second person here okay I'm going to do
the falling one again because that was
fun yeah so throwing the Pearl halfway
through the fall definitely had a
different result than throwing it at the
start let's try near the ground as close
as we can see if the same thing happens
and yeah so if you're going to throw a
pearl make sure you do it right away
give you your best chances of survival
we're going to do one last test here I'm
curious to see if this works or not I
saw someone do it in a video apparently
if you throw an ender pearl before you
enter a portal it will still be
traveling
and you can apparently walk aways away
make a new portal enter the world again
and you will get teleported pretty much
instantly when the Pearl lands but I
would think you would need the world to
be loaded for that to happen so you
probably can't go overly far away for
that the work I could be wrong although
it's kind of perplexing because if it if
the world does unload with the ender
pearl in flight
that means you'll instantly teleports
when you get near the loaded or when you
load the area again right I gotta try it
it just sounds like too much fun so
we're going to make an affordable
generate a new one in the real world and
I just I need to know what happens and
I'm guessing this would work with the n
portals - not that you really would need
it for anything although I don't know
how useful this is either because you
can set your your spot where you come
out using your beds so from the end I
mean okay here we go what's going to
happen
please make any portal
be hard to tell maybe well I did not get
teleported I am in somewhere I do not
recognize okay so I have to I found a
snow biome okay I'm going to make my way
back I will keep recording though just
in case set we teleport when we get
closer I'm curious
yes I guess no teleport I don't know I
might have done it wrong or it just
might not work I'm going to try it one
more time except they're just going to
come out of this portal
oh that time i teleported so it was
still in the air so i guess we we
probably don't need to try it again
but on that note I'm going to say
goodbye for today thanks for watching
guys and I'll see you next time