[Music]
yeah this updates pretty awesome guys I
gotta say so welcome back once again
everybody to another minecraft episode
this is etho having lots of fun with the
slime blocks so as most of you have
probably seen this update has given new
- fun new - functions to new functions -
slime blocks they let's just take a
moment to enjoy this moment yeah do new
functions - slime blocks say now will
stick to each other and adjacent blocks
will stick to slime blocks as well and
the thing I especially like about this
update though is the whole bouncy spring
effect they have when they're moved with
a piston so all entities players boats
minecarts mobs potions ender pearls
arrows TNT everything can get launched
by these things and that allows for so
many possibilities but really they're
just fun they are really fun so I've
been playing around with it doing a few
things with boats look II didn't even
hop between them and midair and I think
you can like jump across them too like
if you had a line of these time didn't
sync with each other you could use them
as like moving platforms just something
I always wanted in this game although I
will have to say from from just playing
around with this for a little bit boats
are pretty glitchy in this update still
like they they have this issue where
they're not where they appear to be
sometimes it's like a visual drawing
glitch maybe or a desync of some sorts
so trying to time jumps between boats I
did it attempt something like that and I
had a lot of trouble just because of
some bugs
and also of course boats are extremely
fragile still but it looks like we're
gonna be able to do some cool things
with boats and and and especially with
other things as well like mine carts and
yeah just a great patch to the game oh
oh I have to be careful as him oh I'll
add all the zombies head and he's stuck
oh there he goes
I love boats on the loose what have you
done my experiment fully jumped yet it's
awesome so uh sometimes gets stuck I'm
not exactly sure why I do it and do a
run jump sometimes I just do a run jump
without yeah there we go
let's destroy it all it's got messed up
already
whew alright guys so we're gonna hop
into one of my creative worlds here I
was uh I was trying to get eats Road
working with his boat hopping effects
like to do jumps with the eighth's road
and I came up with something that seems
to work pretty good so I want to show
that to you and maybe a few other just
random cool things I've seen people on
reddit do with these and and that I was
experimenting with myself so I will see
you in the creative world okay so this
is what I wanted to show you guys this
is my eats road launching system I was
trying out and it does seem to work
pretty good I repeated it many times
here to make sure it would keep going to
that it could do more than one jump in a
row if I wanted and it does it does work
pretty good I have just encountered a
problem though that I didn't realize
before
apparently the glitchyness of boats sort
of depends on my frame rate it seems run
on people's frame rates so when I wasn't
recording this worked very well now that
I am recording my frame rate drops down
to thirty frames per second right that's
what I have it locked at and
it becomes pretty apparent that boats
have a little bit of an issue when when
using this so let me show you all right
so on the second jump already is when it
started happening
the desync whoo I'm sailing away and
down we go and now we finally hit the
ground for real so yeah it does work
what what's happening though is it's
rendering my character in a different
spot somehow there's a desync of where
it actually calculates where you are and
where it shows where you are which I
don't really understand but let's try
write it again Oh
even on the first jump it messed up Wow
yeah so you can hear the Pistons are
still activating up there it is
calculating things properly it's not
drawing things properly and you'll
notice if I get out of the boat here it
puts me in a totally different spot so
yeah to the eyes it's it's trickery but
it actually is figuring things out
properly and it does work properly so
that's good hopefully in a future
version of Minecraft we will have
working boats but yeah so that's pretty
cool I think I'm gonna mess around with
eats Road stuff in the future my let's
play maybe even today I don't know we'll
see how things go I tried a boat
launching thing here see if I still have
boats in yep pretty simple all you
really need is a dispenser with boats in
water above that and then two right next
to the water have the slime block with
the sticky piston below and activate it
one tick after you activate the
dispenser pretty cool though I got I got
burps I'm sorry I just ate not the best
time to record I I think it was on
reddit somebody showed this this is a
new block update detector a new butt
switch very simple very very effective
anytime it updates next to the piston it
will it'll do that so you can have like
a redstone wire up here for example and
every time it activates it will send a
pulse to that I believe or not wait a
minute it's not lighting up I never
actually tested it oh yeah it does work
is this really quick I guess yeah that's
cool I was trying to make something here
to make suspended enderpearls didn't
turn out too well I'll show you the
general idea behind it though G mu zero
get an ender pearl yeah it's just a
little too inconsistent to actually try
it try to get this working properly
throw it up nope and ender pearls they
travel slower through waters less the
eyes doing it this way and I was hoping
I could just keep bouncing it over and
over with this with this slime block
thing I got it to bounce twice but it's
is this too inconsistent you throw it
kind of randomly and the release time is
random and yeah the fence gate is tried
is to try to control when it's actually
released a little bit better but still
it doesn't work too well so that idea
was a flop some people did make devices
though that were able to bounce an ender
pearl when you throw it horizontally and
it goes like a hundred blocks or
whatever instead of like half that which
is cool
there's elevator designs that are coming
out this is when I I worked out but I
saw on the reddit lots of people did
this so I never bothered making a video
on it but it seems to work pretty good
very simple to set up
is it glitched out oh it is good to know
there's some issues still like slime
blocks sometimes get left behind I just
realized I never really showed how this
works so maybe I'll do that I tried
sending an empty boat through it while
recording and that seems to go okay so
we can watch it this way yeah pretty
cool so this this first water block
catches it and allows it it gives it a
little bit of time to to position itself
properly again and then the second water
block whew the second one here it's a
it's a moving stream right so that
allows it to keep its horizontal
momentum otherwise it would just like
slow down each jump and eventually it
will just drop right so that's cool and
since the boat is always trying to float
upwards this carpet prevents it from
from going upright and that keeps it in
the track but when it gets to this
pressure plates it didn't it can flow up
through that it triggers it and then
that also triggers the slime block which
it's positioned over and that sends it
sends it flying basically and this is
one two three four four blocks over one
two three four five six seven up is
where the first water block is in case
you were wondering if you want to do it
yourself and I never showed the anvil
wave either hey let's go check this out
and then we'll head back to the let's
play world yeah so piston waves are a
thing again whoo that's awesome okay
everybody so we are back here and I got
something set up with this should be
pretty fun if it works if I did it right
but to commemorate this patch and all
the cool slime block stuff we can do I
got I got something set up here to show
respect and appreciation
the new patch there's that creeper face
that's not good I need to get rid of
that thing so you guys know I've always
had a real I've always really enjoyed
TNT cannons and pretty much anything
related to TNT and something new has
come out as a result of this patch a new
device that is pretty awesome it's been
posted on the reddit a few times and we
need a button it's got to be an epic
button I really hope I did this right
we'll find out all right here we go bump
bump bump bump bump bump bump bomb
I think I feel like we need some epic
music playing here
epic music TNT oh my god what do we do
it's our TNT missile it's awesome so the
entity missiles are a thing now which is
pretty cool in basic and like flying
machines and all that stuff that's
basically what it is it's a flying
machine with TNT attached and when it
runs into something it explodes that was
a design made by mostly disappointing
this is reddit name so that's pretty
cool there's a few designs out there
let's see I think what I gotta do next
time I do one of these is have like I
had it hidden in here I need like a door
that opens and then it launches out of
it get like a proper missile silo going
on here all right so I've been trying to
decide what we should do for the rest of
episode get back here where are you
going I did mostly get that mob spawner
all set up - the only thing that's
missing
is to ocelots and I went to the jungle
to try to get more ocelots I even cut
down a bunch of trees so that there
would be a bunch of grass exposed and
hopefully they would spawn and no
ocelots so I could probably finish that
today but I think we should focus on
slime blocks today maybe next episode
will we'll check that out again so I had
a fun little idea that I thought I would
do with you guys try to invent something
together haven't done that in a while
for a long time I wanted to make sort of
like a parking garage parking garage
grad do you say garage or garage because
I used to always say garage and then
that then I for some reason I got the
impression that garage is correct and
I've been saying it ever since but I
sound like oh I feel like I'm
pretensions pretentious when I say
garage I don't know anyway I'm rambling
here so I want to make out like a horse
parking garage have you seen I think
it's a Japanese thing it's like a little
little garage thing they parked the car
in it and then they press a button and
it like cycles to a different car it's
like on a conveyor belt and yeah that's
what I want to do with horses and we're
gonna try to using the new slime blocks
so anyway let's let's keep going here
and rambling for quite a bit so horses
they need like a 2x2 area so I figure
let's get 2 by 2 thing of slime blocks
down I guess we'll start it over here
this is just a like a work area we're
not actually putting it here the thing
is the mine carts have been reverted I
guess we gotta get rid of this too and
actually yeah we gotta get rid of all
this huh so they're no longer super fast
the mic
so I'm probably gonna be using horses
again and I want like a horse holding
area set up in the nether like I was
gonna do so we may end up using this if
this turns out okay which I hope it does
cc slime blocks they have this thing
where they stick to everything so for
the most part you almost have to always
use obsidian or furnaces they don't they
don't stick to them which means a lot of
your builds aren't gonna look very good
unfortunately I kind of hope they add
more block sets that don't stick to the
slime blocks like maybe maybe stained
clay doesn't stick to it because it's
got like a smooth surface but maybe wool
does because it's you know it seems like
slime blocks could stick the wool pretty
easy I don't know just kind of split the
box in half of ones that do and don't
stick let's do like a viewing area here
like that and put this front give it a
border now I want the horse to be in
there let's put up some walls although
when that when these go up they're gonna
stick to this clay these play blocks so
we have to use obsidian here too and I
guess the glass has to go that the the
sticky thing is cool but there's a lot
of restrictions to it I'm finding it's
kind of hard to do stuff with it
actually um yeah yeah you you are test
dummy
you go inside whoa nice and bouncy let's
try it can you not jump on this stuff oh
there we go uh-oh I'm trapped with him
cool cool so now let's see how high this
guy gets launched up when we do this to
have Fred stone yep
okay and let's make a button all right
yeah whoo it looked like he went maybe
maybe three blocks above this block here
maybe two how about how do I want to do
this I could either use like water
streams to like cycle them in a loop
sort of thing or maybe maybe let's try
this let's try this do two horses and
like as this one falls down this one
goes up and they switch places let's see
if we can pull that off
so yeah let's go up here let's set up
some I guess we don't need as I was
thinking would put Pistons on this side
and this side I guess we don't really
need that because horses are big we
could just get away with let's put some
sticky pistons in the back here like
this alright and they will move glass
blocks so that when this guy launches up
in the air we want these to extend and
hold them in place so these will need to
be inverted with a redstone torch so
let's do that it's been a while since we
did an episode like this where we just
like goofed around with like technical
things it's fun I like doing this
alright and we'll put redstone up there
so now if we if we power that redstone
wire it should
yeah that's good that's what I want okay
so mmm we'll want these to open up to
the right and left probably this glass
block so he can get out but we also want
this to bounce and that to retract maybe
let me run some wire off-camera for a
sec because this will probably take it a
little bit oh snap I was worried at
first it wasn't doing what I wanted it
to do but I got it worked out now so
let's just take a quick look at the
wiring the cycle button is over here it
runs down like this goes to a repeater I
had it set at 4 and that that makes the
springboard activate and I also have the
wire running down and it goes up this
little staircase thing of half slabs and
it goes up to up to there and that's all
I got to it right now
the problem I was having every time I
press this he gets launched back up
there and as I go this is not gonna work
but if I change the timing all is good
in the world he's still there yeah he's
still there oh let's sleep for a second
before we get the mobs blowing up all
our stuff so yeah this is pretty cool so
you can you see how he's down here I
press the button he goes to the top
layer press it again he goes to the
bottom layer so it keeps cycling between
top and bottom which is what I wanted
and now let's let's see we got to add a
second layer to this so let's start
filling this in I think most this will
be pretty hidden which is good should we
put this there sure why not
I kind of want to see the second horse
though yeah let's try to make that
happen
so the second horse will be here I feel
like I want why is this mmm I feel like
this is in one more than it should be
oh whatever
I'll try this out so let's let's put a
window here build it up like this how
does that look from down here
that's okay
should we do the street tall thing like
we did with that one
get it going like this and then have it
go over top again
sure let's try it then we'll fill this
in oh do we have more yes we do okay and
that is about it oops let's just cover
this for now okay let's try it out
we're gonna launch him up to the second
floor oh he took damage what do you take
damage on is he hitting is it cuz he's
hitting his head on wait a second you
might be hitting his head on this didn't
think that would matter let's just keep
it open for now then yeah there we go so
we could put glass on the top then it's
so stupid I love it so now we need to
set your horse let me go get a second
horse cool so we got our buddy over here
and he's gonna help us see if this works
the wait I think it's gonna work
hopefully it does let's get this guy to
the second floor
awesome let's open this up and we'll put
them inside alright so this is a whoa I
got out on the other side I guess that
confused me for a second
cool now we got a guy on the first floor
and one on the second floor when we
press this yes it does work awesome
that's exactly what I wanted so they
switch switch between it so the extra
step to this that we still need to do is
make a release for it so we could do
something like this and have sticky
pistons that open this up we would want
one on that side one on this side that's
one option we may be able to put like
fence gates here too I built this out of
cyan clay and like gray glass it's more
of a you know a high-tech theme but if
this was made out of wood and all that
fences would look pretty good with this
too so maybe let's try that although
mm-hmm that might not work because oh
yeah and stupid slide locks are gonna
stick to him yeah you see how it leaves
him behind mm-hmm unless they were up
one more
oops
oh man and it's night time that's going
bad all right maybe I'll try to figure
this out off-camera we're running pretty
long time for today so I'm gonna wrap
this up in just the little bits the
fence gates could work at one level up
though yeah yeah the thing is if I have
the Pistons on the side it really
increases the width of the the design
which isn't good fence gates are pretty
simple well I decided to go with the
Pistons after all the fence gates didn't
really work because they're not a full
block and the horses were watching into
them and and suffocating and things were
bad so I switched to the Pistons instead
and got it doing that which is pretty
good they they only had one more block
to the sides both sides the wiring isn't
as compact as I would have liked I can
make it very compact if I just have this
one retracting on the right here but if
I want both of them to retract for for
the looks of it I have to do this with
the wire because I could just have like
redstone dust block redstone torch
underneath this piston that's all I
would need but instead I have it going
to a repeater which branches off this
way to a redstone torch up to that one
and then goes to the left Dodge is the
other wiring I have here goes underneath
that to the redstone torch in up there
so yeah pretty good there's a creeper by
ear that has me a little worried and the
nice thing about doing it this way is I
can seal it up totally flush if I want
ah very cool all right so that's pretty
good so that's had to horse to horse
shuffler if I was to make this bigger I
would probably want like a window there
in a window there so that you could see
three horses and then shuffle between
right and left it would probably be a
six horse shuffler like it would go you
could see the one to the left and the
one to the right and then there would be
three more like at the back
side here but I don't really need six
horses so this is probably good
I could also I'm sure it changes so it's
one block shorter in the back here if I
just have the blocks here and the
torches on top and try to work it out
that way but I'm not too worried so yeah
turned out some I'm happy with that
cool cool right out of here oh you know
I never even thought of it but I'm
really glad I made this three blocks
tall because I would have took
suffocation damage
otherwise I'd even even plan that it
just worked out that way change it with
obsidian to make it look better
aha cool cool I'm pretty sure their
color changed color in this update
it looks like it's orange I'm it was red
let me try diet red and see if it's the
same cuz oh it did change okay so for
some reason their color change color
interesting today's comment is related
to our little buddies here says hey etho
did you know that tamed wolves cannot
teleport if they are tied to a fence
with a lead that would eliminate the
problem you are happening with them
randomly teleporting anyway great video
and I hope this helps I actually did not
know that and we're gonna try it out so
come on guy come on I have a fence post
over here okay I was worried there was
still that glitch where you couldn't
attached if you just had one okay so
he's it he's attached and that was
that's the red color right let's get
this guy up
yeah okay this guy teleported that one
did not that's cool I didn't know that
um so he said that because I I was
worried the wolves my teleport in that
mob system when we get it set up so if
if I am concerned I can take advantage
of this trick so that's pretty cool also
with this horse thing I can remove these
blocks I just realized so a slightly
better view if we do that might be worth
doing but anyway hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode it was a lot of fun
doing all this stuff with the slime
ducks and we will probably be using them
a lot in the future let's get a baby
wolf we'll end it with a baby wolf what
color will the color be or is this head
too big we can't see I can't see the
color I don't know can you not see the
color on baby wolves oh it's orange it's
orange hey you have such a big head
alright yeah so thanks for watching guys
I will see you in the next one have
yourselves a great day bye bye
[Music]