[Music]
hmm
oh man i've been trying to decide if i
should do this really cheesy intro
for this episode and i think we're gonna
go through with it so
brace yourselves just because this is
probably the funnest way
i can show you these tricks i came
across today
so um today's cheesy
infomercial is brought to you in part by
ethocorp
where your future is mine it's a
terrible motto but yet so true
hey kids do you like mine carts
yeah do you like storage
my carts oh my god yeah
i love them too but i can never decide
between the two they're both just so
great
what are we to do don't you wish there
was a product out there that combined
the
smooth and elegant riding capabilities
of a regular minecart
and the grandiose tremendous storage
capabilities of a storage minecart into
one
well don't you worry ethocorp has just
the product
for you introducing
the donkey carts with five easy payments
of one donkey
one mine cart and one chest you can be
riding home your very own donkey cart
today saddle not included
no longer do you need to choose between
going somewhere and being comfortable
anymore with the donkey cart you can do
both
the donkey cart allows you to bring all
sorts of life's conveniences with you
and your travels
including torches ender pearls
arrows and of course cookies
i like to keep my cookies warm and the
dante cart allows you to do just that
and so much more
are you tired of fumbling around with
overly complex
mine current launching systems i know i
sure am
with the ethocorp dante card system it's
so easy
you don't even need buttons or power
rails your docky cart waits patiently
for you just hop on
and point the direction you want to go
the donkey card takes care of the rest
amazing and don't forget to pull a nice
warm cookie out of the back of your
donkey cart
to enjoy your travels even more
now wait a minute you're saying you have
no need for a donkey cart
because you don't have the power rails
required to make a minecart system
not a problem you see the ducky cart
ain't got no time for physics
it's too focused on getting you to the
destination as quickly as possible
to give a care uphill downhill
no hill it can do it all no power rails
required amazing order now
also you can change directions at any
time on a slope
now wait a minute you're still not
convinced your lazy sack of bones are
too lazy to even lay down the tracks for
your minecart system
still not a problem order the donkey
cart
and he will assist you simply hop on
select your tracks point the direction
you want to go
and he will move your lazy butt as you
lay down your tracks
amazing order now you have no excuses
you can even negotiate tight turns with
some experience
and stop by now
you're throwing money at your monitor
yelling take all my money
but wait that's not all order today
and receive a very limited edition mule
cart
at no extra cost
no no you go you go there what are you
doing
come on yeah they are very limited in
supply
as you can see
now that's value added
um
i'm sorry i'm i'm really sorry you had
to watch that
please forgive me please
please donkey's really sorry too he
knows that was weird
he didn't mean anything by it um
anyway no that's so good though
uh so yes welcome everybody to another
episode
there is a crazy thunderstorm going on
right now uh where i live and it's
it's making me nervous because like one
out of three one out of four times
there's a thunderstorm like this my
power goes out for at least two hours
and it might happen again today
and cut my recording short here let's
hope it doesn't
um sometimes it like takes six hours or
even longer for them to get the power
back on too it's really weird
nobody else i know has that kind of
problem there's just something
something really bad about the power
where i live um
so you don't really appreciate
electricity in that until it's gone you
know you just take it for granted
and the power goes out and it's like
well
what do we do now there's nothing for us
to do can't play on the computer can't
play video games
can't watch tv you know
it's like you may as well go to bed um
it's like you can't even do like things
you think you can do once the power goes
out like it's like oh i'm gonna go make
myself a cup of coffee
nope gonna go take a shower nope can't
do it
can't do it so
um usually if it happens during the day
you can go driving
somewhere and go do something it's not a
big deal but yeah anyway
i've been working down here a little bit
i got the stahls
installed and
looks like we're not going to have as
much room as i thought for these
these are these are the stalls by the
way ride your your horse or your donkey
and you can walk out
when you're ready to go again choose the
one you want and ride
right out it's pretty sweet
i think it looks pretty decent too i'm
happy with it so we got four of them
total
second chance is over there we got
zenith in this one
and i decided to go with this very
similar theme to what we have
up in this part of the man cave i know i
said i wasn't going to do any more
arches
and i've done more arches down here i
i really like this part of the cave
though
like i really do and i think it's
because of the arches they add a lot to
it so i
i got two more arches down here
well three more technically because i i
did a double arch here
to wilson um this isn't really done here
though
we got piston lighting we got lights
under the pistons
and i put hay bales for the ground
where the horses are we have leaves in
the ceiling here the river is right
above you can see the water
on the leaves even i was really worried
when i was
building this i was going to update the
river here and if that happens oh man
like if i was to break this block right
here
or if an enderman came by and did
something like that
this water block would update and it
would update all the other ones
down the river it's a real pain to fix
oh that actually doesn't look too good
does it
it's only one deep here that was a
problem and if i place a block here it's
going to update
so i guess we'll just live with it um
yeah so that's that's done that's pretty
cool
um still gonna work on the outside here
a little bit like maybe put
i might put some wheat here that would
probably look pretty good
yeah that doesn't really look that good
does it uh we should probably do
something else
there's just this little bit of space
between the paths like this
three blocks here one block here uh we
should probably
do something with although we could we
could probably make it to stonewall
or something too it would look okay uh
it does look a little wrong if if all
the stone isn't being held up by
something i haven't decided
fully if i should keep my cave like if i
should keep all this stone in my cave or
if i
should change it we'll probably keep it
though because it's supposed to be
supposed to have that underground feel
to it too so a little bit of stone is
good
so in that case maybe we should change
this
because look look at the the slope on
the roof it looks like it needs support
here doesn't it
if there was gravity and all that fun
stuff in the game
which there isn't of course
um today i think we should head over to
my other
base like where the silverfish farm is
and all that i haven't checked
if the baby zombies have affected that
or not
my uh sorting system and all that might
be broken
i'm a little concerned about that
i don't know what what to do with this
if it's all flat it doesn't look good
either
anyway i'll mess with them another time
so yeah i was originally talking about
having eight of these stalls
the thing is just four of four of them
goes up to here
and we're i punched through the wall and
we're up by this mushroom farm which
even though we're taking it down we are
getting really close to
my my lab here as well
and if we put four more in it would go
up to i think like
here so yeah just cutting it a little
bit close
because i also wanted to put an elevator
a horse elevator to get up to the
surface here
so four is probably good um
i don't need that many horses around
i put a chest here i'm not really sure
what we're using that for
but it's there in case we want to put
something we got drafting tables on both
sides and of course
an ender chest which is really important
one of the problems i have with my base
is i never really factor in
like spots to put crafting tables or
ender chests or anything like that
so it can be a little bit annoying i
have to walk a long ways sometimes
to to get to one like we got one here
i didn't originally plan to put one
there that was an afterthought
that's why it's a block switcher too
um there's there's a sneaky little ender
chest
in this waterfall which was also an
afterthought
and if we go over here we have one more
they're actually their space pretty good
with that that third one where i just
put it there
but there's one more ender chest here
which is also hidden again an
afterthought
crafting table there there's a crafting
table here too but i always forget about
it because this thing's kind of weird
it's like the only place i've used brick
for some reason i thought it would look
good
and now that we've done it we gotta live
with it so
yeah anyway let's head on over to the
other base
and check things out over there
oh yeah by the way i don't think i've
mentioned this yet but
the silverfish farm haven't seen me do
anything within a while
i'm pretty sure it's broken
for like a few months now uh like a
little while ago
actually we'll turn it on we'll try to
confirm it today
if it's broken or not did some silver
fish spawning in here
but like a few months ago they were
making a bunch of changes where they
were reducing
the number of things that were affected
by
or that caused block updates so like
sheep beating grass no longer was
causing block updates
and i think they got rid of silverfish
entering blocks
causing block updates so that's how this
farm operated
and if it can't detect it anymore it's
not going to work anymore so
we'll just get a few spawning there and
we'll check it again maybe they changed
it back
but or maybe i just maybe i just didn't
uh
do something right last time i tested it
who knows
okay but anyway what we want to check is
if this is broken
today as well let's head on up there and
switch it
because the baby zombies it probably
isn't broken actually because they
should follow the same
logic as a normal zombie i think they
chase villagers
and i'm pretty sure they're over a block
tall so they shouldn't
really be that much different than a
normal zombie
oh we should maybe go up actually let's
go up
we need to finish this thing too this is
one of my other big projects i haven't
finished
okay we got a baby coming up here we'll
be able to see if he does anything he
shouldn't do
uh for the most part it seems to be
working okay though
you went to the villager here's the baby
yeah you ran to the villager too so
i think it's fine just the same old uh
problems they had before
troopers went there skeletons went there
let's check down here that there's only
supposed to be zombies down here but i'm
sure if you got mixed in that
and the baby he can't get me so that's
good
cool
actually you know what i want to check
out today too uh this thing here is
supposed to be
a record farm or be able to do that
let's just shut this off for right now
switch it off hopefully
hopefully it's just creepers in here
yeah okay so it's just creepers
uh what we're going to do
do that get them down to one hit
watch them burn that's really loud
the idea is i was i planned on making it
so i could stand
here it was dangerous
they can see me through here okay so no
more should be falling down
it should be down to one hit and i'm i
designed it so that the skeletons would
be in the middle
and then creepers on an end so that if i
walked into the line of sight
the skeletons would shoot at the
creepers and and kill them hopefully
this this doesn't all blow up on us yeah
look at that
oh yeah i need new records i am so sick
of the ones i have
i'm not anywhere close to collecting
them all either
oh oh
you better kill him
well that's good he's not exploding at
least i thought that would have been the
end of it
what the heck you like a
million health that guy
cool let's go check that out
wait where's my uh that's over over here
we got stahl we got ward far
yeah 13 13 cats
and maul i don't think i have them all
or stall no i do have stall i don't
think i have ward
far or mall so that was awesome
i should do that a few more times and
get them all
[Music]
all right so this thing is bunching up
here uh
i'm looking at it another thing that
might be broken is this
because this was all the way down and
it's not supposed to be
this uh this detector seems to be broken
somehow
because the idea is when the block gets
to here
it's supposed to send redstone oh you
know what's missing
there's supposed to be a redstone torch
right here
and i just happen to have one dust
that's perfect
okay i think that'll fix it
um let's try this out okay
maybe that's not what i did i don't know
something's wrong with that
for sure let's see if they enter
the box so and cause an update so
when i tested it before i put a repeater
here to update the piston
i think that did something let's do it
one more time just to be sure
actually yeah is this a silverfish block
that is a silver fish block okay that's
good
okay so the block that's there should
definitely be
a smooth stone without a silver fish in
let's walk away
oh okay never mind it's working
i guess the thing that was broken was
this
i'll have to fix this
i don't know i've been watching it for a
while now there's something definitely
wrong here
i fixed that but it's like
i'll update this is the silver fish
yeah that's a silver fish oops
what did i just do update it
okay they can't enter a block when i'm
here at least they weren't able to
before i have to be outside of their
aggro range before they can enter a
block which is i think
it's over eight blocks away for sure
it's like 16 i think
okay that's
that's smooth stone right there there's
no silver fish in that one
or the the one right below there it's
like when i move out of the range
it works the first time right away no
problem
second times good just trying to figure
out
why it's not working okay third time
it's gonna keep working
yeah after three times it just stops
working for some reason
maybe my cobblestone generator is not
keeping up but
i don't know oh it's still going look at
that
still going good good
i'm gonna watch it for a bit longer it
wasn't working before for some reason
ah yeah no worries guys it's running
just fine
i'm so glad we tested it i thought for
sure it was broken and i was gonna have
to
either change this or tear it down or
something
so i'm glad that's working again uh i
think what happened
probably i'm pretty sure they did remove
the ability to detect
a silverfish entering a block for at
least one patch
i remember checking out the wiki and it
had a notation for it
and a few other blocks that it was
removed in so and so patch
and then during that time this
must have broke where it it broke the
redstone torch
and they must have re-added the ability
to detect them
and it's it's all working good now i
think
um i could be wrong though anyway
it's working today that's all it counts
so i got another really cool trick to
show you guys here this
is this is a jaw dropper when i saw this
i was amazed i'm looking for a slime
there was one baby one
here hoping to find a few slimes
actually
did he die no he's still here
don't know
darn it ah man
i hear another one but i don't know
where he is maybe he's behind
oh he's okay okay he's over here um
so normally if you kill slime or you'll
get
let's get them to their baby form here
okay normally when you kill a slime
you get between zero and two slime balls
i believe
so we got zero that time got two that
time
zero two
anyway no more than two usually
now if you kill him with a looting sword
which i just
happen to have all right so we're at 15.
test this out 18 so we got three that
time
21 22
25 so we're getting like three
apparently
this is really cool this was discovered
by accident by a guy
that goes by the name atomic who just
coincidentally also was on the
minecraft fan server um
he found that if you ricochet a gas
fireball
while holding a looting sword that you
would get extra drops
from the gas like extra gas tears or
gunpowder
and simply sarc saw his video and he
found out that it's not just gas if you
happen to be holding a looting sword
when any mob dies assuming
you did some player damage to it like
where it will drop
xp in that you will get the looting
effect without using the durability on
your sword
so if i was to kill the slime with this
potion of harming and switch to my
looting sword
before he dies i would get
extra slime balls so let's try this out
okay get my hot keys ready
which is pretty crazy i wish i'd known i
wish i knew this for
for a long time now because this is
really useful
okay so we're 25 28 look at that
it works doesn't take any durability
from your looting
sword so you could have a ton of mobs
in a tube throw a damaged potion or a
healing potion or something at them
and get extra drops without using
like a ton of durability on your looting
sword
which is pretty cool i would have liked
to known that a long time ago
um so with this if we get a bunch of
creepers in the creeper tube
throw a damage potion at them switch to
a looting sword we get tons of gunpowder
and that would be pretty cool
okay so i'm doing a little test here i
brought my dog back
from that village we restored a long
time ago
i left him there because he kept
teleporting when he wasn't supposed to
before
and it was really annoying me so just
left him there for
quite a few months here and now we need
him we're going to use them
so with this whole looting thing
i kind of thought it would work with the
dog too but it doesn't seem to
so we should get at most
uh well we we should get between zero to
two leather
each towel we kill normally and
one two three steak right that's the
normal
alluding three sword though increases
the number of items you get by three
so it should be
what should it be it should be three
to five leather right
math is hard to five leather or four to
six
steak i believe with a looting three
sword
um doesn't seem like that's happening
though
i've tried a few cows i'm holding the
sword when the cow dies
i'm getting xp from the drop so it's
like a player kill
do you get him i think he got trampled
oh no he's getting he's getting him
yeah again nothing beyond the normal
limits
okay we're at eight and five
eleven so that's three that's still with
the normal limit so
i don't think it's working with the dog
i was thinking you could use it for an
afk farm but
no it doesn't look like it
um i'm gonna try with the damage potion
just to make sure it's actually working
all right so we got our instant damage
potions we're gonna check one and
quickly switch to our looting three
sword before
they die and hopefully we get extra
drops from this
without taking durability from the sword
no kills let's try again
and okay we got a kill
i think it was just one that's perfect
for steak
four steak where's my leather give me my
leather
hmm no leather i'm gonna double check we
didn't kill two cows i think that was
just
one though and we got the looting effect
which is good
i double checked the footage and that
definitely looked like one kill only so
we got the looting effect
which is awesome uh just doesn't seem
like it works with
dog which was unexpected to be honest i
thought it would have
okay i think that was one kill again
let's check this out
eight and five oh yeah that's definitely
working cool
i'm a little surprised no leather drops
that first
time um
okay we got one more again perfect eight
and five
twelve and ten so that was four and five
definitely getting looting effect
with the damage potions not with the dog
though i'm pretty sure
cool all right so you can use it on any
mob i'm pretty sure
yeah so these are the three records i
brought back to our manatee let's check
them out
we got far
it's a decent one i kind of like this
one it's like uh
i would rate it as average it's a little
bit slow but it's
it's very pleasant and nice
um then we have maul
this is like sleepy elevator music i
i'm not a big fan of this one
pretty slow
and then we have ward and
guys ward is among the best of the music
discs
don't judge it by the first few seconds
most people pop it in
and they're like ew they pop it out but
just give it time
it gets good
but anyway here is the comment i picked
out for today
it says hey etho what has been your most
favorite redstone involved project ever
uh from a technical standpoint
wilson down here has been the most
complicated
by far there's a lot of really
weird redstone designs involved with
this build
um there's also a lot of redstone
involved with it
and lot of
like this was sort of my showcase
project for trying out the new redstone
update back in 1.5 and it's still not
complete unfortunately
but there's a lot of analog stuff
involved with this
which isn't there's not a lot of
like tutorials or anything like that on
the analog
aspect of uh of the redstone update and
i had to use a lot of that with this so
it was
that was an interesting challenge i even
had to invent a few things to make it
work the way i wanted
so that's that's always fun uh but i
wouldn't rate it as my
favorite it's close it's very close
maybe if it was finished i would like it
more
but uh it's definitely a close one
i really enjoyed working on the trivia
game back on the other minecraft map
it's cool to get that done and it worked
the way i wanted
and i think the the one i'm going to
choose though
as my favorite is probably
oh that was a weird part of the song
still going though it's still good still
good
my favorite is probably boat dispenser
2.0
which is one of my very first videos and
one of my very first redstone projects
it was very complex
for the time um
yeah to give you an idea of my
redstone knowledge at that time i
i didn't even know you could send like a
redstone signal up
vertically using redstone torches like
like how we do this pretend those are
redstone torches and you
can get it up in a one by one space i
discovered that during that build and i
thought it was the coolest thing
ever because i i don't think a lot of
people at the time knew that either it
was this like
early redstone at that time the build
had
over 700 pieces of redstone in i was
counting
and it was the first time i used logic
gates
and yeah it was it was a fun build
i think i think because of that build
[Music]
the song is so good it's still going
lots of variety to it too
oh yeah um
what was i saying i had an idea of what
i wanted to do
um with that build i i did it
i spent a lot of time with the redstone
turned out exactly how i wanted it to
and i was happy i think if i didn't do
that project
i wouldn't have gotten as well involved
with redstone though
that gave me a lot of experience and it
gave me an idea
of how to use it and and it worked the
way i wanted a lot of people they'll try
redstone in this game
they'll get frustrated with it and then
they'll never want to touch it again
which is it's fine but
you don't know what you're missing um
it's a lot of fun to play with redstone
in this game
anyway that's all for today guys i hope
you enjoyed i hope you have a good one
take care bye