[Music]
hello
everybody this is evo and welcome back
to another episode of
the let's play series so you know we've
been
working on finishing up projects and
today we are going to be tackling
one of the oldest longest running
unfinished projects of the world i think
you guys might know where i'm going with
this one
that's right today we are going to be
doing the old bait and switch we are not
working on the library we are going to
be working on
uh well no it's actually done already
let's check it out here the pyramid
for the longest time we've had we've had
this project and this has been sitting
unfinished you know we see it almost
every episode and uh we had this side of
pretty much done so it wasn't really
bothering me too much but with the
world tour and download coming up soon i
figured we'd better
finish the other three sides on this
thing but as most of you guys know
finished is a word i use kind of loosely
it's finished in a way but we might come
back to it later if i feel more inspired
to add some
more color to it like maybe a line of
orange sandstone around the bottom or
something
or uh lower the detail i'm not sure yet
we'll live with it for a bit and might
change it later this is technically the
entrance to it on this side
the side we never see made some odd
choices while building this thing
and would like to add some kind of
interior to it eventually too
aha so we're just trying something that
was suggested a long time ago to add a
gold beacon on the very top of the
pyramid because we had that like big
flat spot
and i don't really want to build the
sandstone any higher so it would be nice
to put something up there and uh
gold beacon might be a cool idea only
thing is i don't like it from this angle
i feel like it really stands out maybe
we got to mix some sandstone in with it
so it doesn't stand out as much
yeah i don't know about this one
i'm really hoping you guys will just be
like oh etho it looks great it's
wonderful
couldn't couldn't have done it better
myself never have to worry about
building the pyramid ever again etho you
got it you nailed it today
but i don't think that's gonna happen
it's got issues still
um i do think the sandstone helps it
not stand out as much but it's a little
strange still right i don't know i'll
see what you guys say
but anyways let's get to checking out
some other stuff here before we get to
our projects for today
so i fixed the slime thing a couple
episodes ago and
uh something has changed with it for
sure like
at most we used to get two or three
slimes going around this thing
uh but now it's like there's always like
ten or
more and it's out of mine carts i think
if we had more mine carts it would
eventually have like
because i think they don't despawn
anymore or something
yeah he moved in from the underground
village all the way to here that's like
200 blocks that way
somehow he found one of these
workstations and he's he's checking out
the new changes here so
made a bit of an expansion again got rid
of all the torches that were on the
ground we have hidden lighting under
bushes now
and added in a water elevator to get to
the surface from here
because when you're in a cave that's
actually a big issue not being able to
fly somewhere right away you got to find
the eggs at first
we got some of the stone ceiling changed
out here with leaves and hidden lighting
behind
we expanded the grass path here all the
way to the concrete maker pretty much
and we'll have to do a bunch more work
in this area to get it looking nice
but main thing i want to show you over
here is our brand new farm
if you can guess what kind of farm this
is just by looking at it you guys get
major bonus points because i was
thinking about it as like i don't know
if i've ever seen one of these built
before
and i was really struggling with how
should i design it you know
um so if you don't know you can actually
farm ferns in this game like if you grow
a tall fern like this you harvest it you
get two
so you get one bonus right and then you
can just bow meal it to get another one
the other day i realized i don't have
any ferns left in my storage we used
them all up
and a lot of my world was generated
before
ferns were in the game so if i want them
i gotta go pretty far away
to collect them so i thought why don't
we make a fern farm
the way this works is we have our shears
in one hand we might be able to use a
silk dutch hotel i haven't tried that
yet
and then uh burns in the offhand hold
right click
and it does that and every now and again
you gotta press left click
and we get burns so it's pretty simple
goes through durability very fast on
shears though so
probably got a switch or adam breaking
or something to it
but yeah the way this works is first one
nothing happens second one nothing
happens third one it goes to the
observer
that triggers all the bone meal to go on
the three dispensers
and then oh
day time's on
so you'll notice that if i right click
on a tall fern with the regular firm
it replaces it
that's a big problem so that's why we
have this extra one at the end
because that way we don't waste any
ferns because when you
when you do this it destroys it so the
way the game works if you have a fern on
the end here and you try to place
another fern it's not going to replace
that existing one it sees oh it's the
same block
don't need to replace it but the tall
ferns
are considered to be a different block
so that's why it will replace it and
destroy it and then you lose
ferns doing that this is like a cap to
stop things so we can just hold right
click right click the whole time
and then you can see we got tilled
farmland over here which is a little bit
smaller than a block so
we can put hoppers underneath
and can we see things here or do i get
it all closed up it's kind of all closed
up
but yeah there's hoppers running
underneath the tilled farmland and it
delivers it to a barrel
so that that keeps going and then we
also have hoppers under the barrel
to go into a
something there's a dropper facing up
under here as well to keep our inventory
full of ferns i'll try to show you that
too so if i'm up over here and i trigger
the observer
you see some ferns get shot out over
here i think we got two that time
plus as we're standing close to the
ferns here we'll get a few more so if
you look at the number of ferns in our
offhand here we want that to stay pretty
much consistent so we don't run out so
if i'm
using the farm 54 55
53 it goes down a little bit because i
don't have it perfectly tuned
52 52
so it's not too bad yeah you know i
think the pyramid on top of the pyramid
is actually a pretty good thing
it's a good cap to the the top of it
what do you think you though
you think the same as me oh that's never
a good thing uh over at the big etho
here
made another little minor change this
was all stone behind him
i cheaped out on it apparently i saw
that like
and i was like oh why didn't i finish
that in the past but
glowstone used to be pretty hard to
collect so i think i just
cheaped out but on some sharp angles you
could sometimes see the stone
not anymore and then over at our
firework cut here
also added in a new thing there's a
lever to launch the fireworks
now and did a little thing here with the
snowflake as well we got some soul
fire lanterns hanging off of chains
underneath it now
which uh it could be a cool thing i
don't know if you guys like the show and
tell style of episodes we've been doing
lately but this makes it a lot easier
to get work done off camera as we're
trying to finish things here and then
just show it to you
if we were to try to do it all together
it would never happen
like uh like it's been forever right so
i got one
last thing to show you here and then
we're gonna get to it together um
the guardian farmer remember last
episode we did the the middle section
and
you can see i've now gone and done a
trim all around it's
farmed up a whole bunch of warped wood
and shroom lights and also did a trim
along the bottom that goes
all around and i think that looks pretty
cool
very weird though right um but we still
got the big stone
sides to fill in here and i suggested
maybe a kelp firm and i wanted to see
what you guys said last episode
and got some good feedback so one of the
big things suggested is
pixel art have pixel art on the sides
here
uh some some people took it a bit
further and said do pixel art and try
tell some kind of story with it
which i thought was a bit intriguing and
then someone actually suggested a
specific story so that's going to be our
comment of the day here
it says i think one of the sides of the
guardian farm to be filled in would be a
great place for a mural to tell the tale
of our explorer hero ergo and his
capture
and imprisonment of an elder guardian on
a windmill rooftop
i know you like your pixel arts so i
think that's a pretty cool suggestion
you guys remember um
the elder garden we had on the windmill
here he disappeared
and now that story is lost to time
unless we can tell it again somehow
aha so what is our plan here how are we
gonna do this mural is the question
i got an idea in mind here but i guess
let's start off with the story
that we're trying to tell so the way it
happened is i conquered a guardian
temple
and then we transported the elder
guardian through
a nether portal through the nether on a
minecart
to the top of the windmill and that's
how it happened
so i think our plan here is to divide
the mural into three
main sections we're gonna have the
guardian temple that we conquered we're
gonna have the nether
and then we're gonna have the windmill
and we're gonna go left to right
because we read left to right so our
pictures should go
left to right as well all right so let's
get to it here this should be pretty
fun i especially like doing pixel art
where you have to take a bigger object
and compress it down it's like doing
visual compression um and you got to
decide what key features you want to
keep and what's the unimportant
information you can get rid of
so with a water temple we're gonna be
building a tiny one here
and if you look at the front of it i
think the thing that stands out to me is
the three
pillars at the bottom holding it up and
you'll also notice it's built on gravel
like the ocean floor so we got a layer
of gravel here and we're gonna leave
like maybe a five block space
between the two sides and then three
more pillars on this side
this will be the center of our our
temple and that kind of
gets close to another rack i think that
should be good though we'll just bump
this over a bit more
the nether is like the part where we
have the freedom with because there's no
specific structure we got to build here
now guardian temples also have way more
than
just three of these pillars they have
several rows of three like i think at
least five
rows of these three but we can represent
that depth just by adding one more row
probably
uh we're not trying to do a perfect
scaled-down model we're just
trying to compress the information so
this gives the illusion of depth in many
many sets of them right that's probably
good enough
now there's also a bit about overhang we
need to represent
with some stairs here just again we'll
compress it down there's probably like
five or
six arches of these sea lanterns we can
represent just by building like two of
them
so let's just do it like this i think
sea lanterns and then bridge the gap
between them
maybe with a wall whoa so i loaded up
a guardian temple in uh creative and i
noticed i might not be getting all the
details 100
correct i thought it was like several
sets of three for the
the pillars here but no there's actually
none in the center so we might want to
bump
these out and probably got a couple
other things wrong but as long as we get
the general
gist of it corrected i think will be
good i think this is a general shape of
it we got to mix in some dark prismarine
there though
and also we got to add that thing on the
top
that you know when you when you float
over it with a boat and you see that
those sea lanterns you know it's a
guardian temple below you
i don't know what this thing is actually
called but uh you know what i'm talking
about hopefully
this thing over here
all right so i'm thinking we might just
put the
portal over here as well because again
we gotta represent a portal to the
nether somehow and i think this might be
the spot we don't want to build a
full-size portal
we want like a mini one and i guess
we'll just fill in the sides here with
something and then we'll build an actual
portal behind it
let's maybe put some prismarine in the
back here as well just in case we can
see through
we'll light it up and we got our three
by four
portal oh yeah i guess we can see
through here too
let's change that out uh-huh uh-huh
all right so we're back in the creative
world again to check things out so we
just built this
i guess it's prismarine at the top not
not the bricks so i'll change that
um and then if we look at the front of
this thing
we have all this dark prismarine so it
does like a double v thing
and then we got some lines alright so
check it out everybody
i think it's about done here actually
it's a bit derpy but i like it
we got our dark prismarine so instead of
doing like a double v
like the original in like three lines we
just do a single and a double
and it sort of represents the same thing
it's just more compressed
and i don't know if it's just me but i
keep seeing like a crab when i look at
this thing like it's got the big shell
in the back
the beady eyes maybe the claws in the
front there
this is what i've been seeing when i
when i look at it all right we're gonna
move on here
uh check this out oh snappers we got the
windmill done
already i just worked on it off camera
because it was so
finicky and i had i really struggled
trying to record this
so we got the planes with the wheat
field couple hay bales mixed in there we
got a couple
random trees and then the windmill
itself
so i would say this is about two-thirds
the size of the original so it is
compressed down a little bit
but a lot of it looks the same and then
at the very top
had to build an elder guardian and that
was really tricky uh i had a hard time
matching the colors
so i ended up going with just stone
brick for for the main color
we got a beacon with an orange pane in
front
for the eye and then warped trap doors
for his spikes and he's bouncing around
on the top there
all uh all captured and stuff
aha so we got quite a bit done on this
but i realized there's
actually a ton left to do here yeah so
not only do we still have to build
another section which
by the way i think we'll try to build
like another fortress as a structure in
it
make it a bit more interesting but we
also gotta probably build some kind of
frame around the edges
and looking at the sand up there i
really like that with the warped wood
right i think that's gonna be our other
color
maybe smooth sandstone going all around
the edges would look cool
um and then we still got stone here
so we got rid of a lot of the stone but
there's still a lot left
for the backdrop we should replace with
something else and i i was thinking we
should try to make an artificial sky
now light blue wool is like the
traditional sky color people always use
but i don't think we can use it anymore
because the color kind of changed now
right it's a little bit deeper blue
so instead i think what we'll go for is
packed ice i like packed ice a lot more
now i think
let's try a little section here and then
we'll build this like all the way up the
wall
this is like a lighter blue more natural
more sky-like with some whimsical white
cloud fluffiness in it
maybe i think it works a bit better
hmm yeah i don't think you're gonna get
out of that one that's a tough situation
all right we're gonna head over to our
packed ice farming area we gotta get a
bunch of materials
so i set this up a few weeks ago now i
think
basically it's very uh
very unprofessional at the moment i dug
a tunnel through the netherrack here
and then it keeps going for ways
it's a bit of a distance i don't know if
we're ever going to build an official
tunnel here or what
but for now i've just been flying it and
then we take a turn
we got another portal over here and
this my friends is where the packed ice
has been coming from lately
so i've got a couple icebergs knocked
down already
let's take out a few more
cool so we got a bunch of packed ice and
we repaired our tools now let's head
over to the super smelter we gotta smelt
up a bunch of sandstone
make smooth sandstone here
yep yep i'm liking the packed ice there
i think that's looking pretty cool
so as far as the frame goes i think it's
going to go up and then kind of bend
over
and maybe we'll leave the three block
spacing at the top there
all the way down which means we'll have
to fill in that water over there and
then it'll come down on the other side
so let's try to map that out a bit i
think
yeah it's gonna be two blocks thick here
too
and i guess we'll replace over here too
with it
all the way up this is all gonna be
smooth sandstone here
i guess we don't need to i'm doing like
the whole thing here i guess this can
still stay
stone still stays stone that's hard to
say
still stay stoned when we first started
working on this today i was really
debating if it was worth setting up the
haze beacon
and i am so glad we did that because
we're going to be doing a lot of digging
here i think
uh-huh all right so this is the general
shape we're going to go for on the sides
so it's going to curve up
and then go over and i tell you what the
sky's looking a little bit plain there
so maybe let's add something cool here
where it's diagonal yeah right over here
i want to put some gold
and let's do a couple clouds here too
just above the trees should look cool
oh yeah i like that a lot more so we got
our sun and some clouds
oh snappers all right so we got a whole
bunch done
i decided to just build up the frame
right away we removed the water that was
there
and also cleared a whole bunch of land
got that out of the way so we're free to
work on the netherrack section so i went
and i got some etho banners because the
story goes
etho vanquished the the guardian temple
right and kidnapped the
elder guardian so we got to get our
banner down here like we conquered the
place
for a backdrop maybe go for glass
and then we'll put water behind that
potentially
with like fish and stuff might look cool
so we're gonna get rid of the stairs if
we run into them and just start building
the glass up here
oh wow actually just the blue glass on
its own does a pretty good job of
mimicking the ocean doesn't it might not
even need to put water behind maybe just
blue terracotta
and then do like the bridge across
so it'll be stair slab
and then i guess the next one would go
over
here three four
and then connect like that oh i just
love this shulker box so much look how
organized it is
let's grab the nether brick fences we're
going to
maybe build like a mini bigger room here
a mini bigger room that made sense all
right i'm liking that a lot actually so
let's do a cool little detail thing here
too
so this is supposed to be the nether
we're gonna get a bunch of fences around
here at the top
like they kind of have and we're gonna
put
i don't want to put an actual hostile
mob here because it's going to take away
from the mob cap
with the guardian farm so instead we're
going to do an armor stand
and i brought over a wither skull
ah yeah so this is it everybody the
moment
i've been waiting for that we've been
waiting for
uh but me especially because i've been
working on this for
hours oh my goodness the final little
bit of detail we're gonna be adding
today
uh we're gonna go around with some lava
and just fill in the bottom here
and then i think it's gonna be good uh
there'll be a few more details we'll
have to add
another day but overall it'll be pretty
pretty close to done let's light a
couple fires here for a bit of uh
ambiance all right everybody so i think
with that we got it done
so check it out oh man
it's pretty insane actually i like it a
lot though i think it's pretty cool
um let me know what your favorite
section is i think my favorite one is
the windmill one actually
followed by the nether and then this one
this one's a little bit plain i think we
should add the water behind and maybe
some fish
and that'll liven it up or maybe we add
like an island
somehow at the top there i don't know
that might just be a distraction though
uh but yeah check it out so this tries
to follow this story
the idea is we transport the elder
guardian from this portal to
this one up there using a minecart
through the nether so
you can see the minecart goes up to here
and that goes through the nether
fortress
through there and then up at the top and
to the portal
so hopefully that's a that's a good way
of doing it i don't know i didn't really
know how to symbolize it better but
overall i think that's pretty cool
i like it a lot so i don't know if we're
gonna do murals for the other three
walls it took quite a bit of time maybe
we should just do kelp farms but i'll
see what you guys say about it
if you have any other ideas for stories
let me know and we'll
take it from there i guess but anyways i
think that's gonna have to do it for
this episode guys let's do one more
comment of the day it says
etho is there anything that vanilla
minecraft
doesn't have that you think should
already be in the game
question mark there are things that pop
up all the time in my head that probably
should just be in the game like cave
biomes
more varied world generation or the
surface and natural disasters
are what i immediately think of yeah
those are those are cool ideas i like
those
uh for me it's always like redstone
stuff i love whenever they add a new
redstone thing to the game like when
they added shulker boxes and observers i
spent so much time just
goofing around with those having fun so
i'm i'm always big for that um
i think more specifically i would say
why don't we have block breakers and
and placers you know i think the
argument for them for a long time was
they didn't want to
allow us to fully automate things but at
this point in the game i feel like we
fully automate a lot of things already
anyway so
why not have some more fun i recently
saw a new mod that came out i think it's
called super dispensers and i would like
that
for the block placement in in minecraft
i thought it was a cool idea
so instead of just placing the block
what it the super dispensers mod does
is it shoots the block in item form like
this
uh i think you can control how far you
want it to shoot so you can shoot like
10 or 20 blocks away
and then wherever it lands is when it
then turns into
a solid block so that means if you shoot
another one it's going to end up over
here and then over here and over here
and i think that would be a cool way of
doing it
and add a lot of crazy stuff to the game
aha
anyways that's going to do it for today
hope you guys enjoyed the episode thank
you for watching and until the next one
take care have a good day bye