hello everybody this is etho welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series distance yes we have a
problem we have a first-world problem
right now guys I moved a mushroom over
to the Steve spider firm we're building
we got to move this Moo shroom up a dare
somehow so probably somehow with a
piston we're gonna do that put a block
there I don't know if I showed this last
episode but I actually made it so that
this floor raises and lowers by one
block there's a switch over here so oh
wait no that made it go down in it oh
right right
so that makes it so the spiders fall
farther and then they die right away we
actually need to go down one more block
then right there yes okay so now move
the mushroom over to dere good and just
going to work we got to put a button
here or something or I shat made a lever
good and then one by one we should be
able to let's make sure we don't crush
them I had a hard time getting this guy
over here pretty far away from the man
tape let's go one more block good so I
always looking at the comments on last
episode now that we're up here we're
gonna starting spiders too so we got to
move quickly we made a pretty weird mob
system here using the thorns armor and
the mending and Chapman we can actually
auto kill spiders and if we have our
sword selected we get the looting
effects the problem we found out last
time though is once we start taking
starvation damage the healing we get
from the beacon the regeneration is not
enough to gain any health back
even with resistance to so we need some
other way of healing and I was thinking
of doing it like a life support system
where we throw potions healing potions
that ourselves
we would need one like every five
minutes or so or I asked you guys what
we should do and use a lot of you guys
said just eat food just eat food and a
few of you even suggested using a
mushroom which is a great idea although
it's gonna kill me oh and I don't want
to use my pick cuz I might hit the cow
oh okay let's make this a little bit
taller while we're doing this so that
never happens again okay so I'm going to
drop the cow down into there there is
one problem with using food though which
we'll get to in just a second here
actually this is going to be impossible
I need some kind of wall to line them up
against otherwise we'll never fall down
there or she'd okay good so now if we
stand right over here
beautiful oh look at this screenshot
that's amazing should be able that is
hold right click and get unlimited
mushroom stew okay so I just went and
repaired our sword and some of our gear
so we can do a durability test here the
problem with using the food
there's kind of two issues with it so we
found out last episode that if we have
protection for diamond gear all four of
it here with mending on and then we put
a thorns item like thorns three prickly
pants in our offhand then the amount of
XP we get from the spiders repairs all
our all the durability lost on our armor
it's tough to find that balance where it
will be able to repair it without it
ever breaking but we found this works
and then we were going to have the sword
in our other hand so we get the looting
effect if we introduce food into the
equation though then we need to have
that selected as well and hold right
clear
so how do we do all this we can't what I
think we're going to try to do now take
the thorns off we can't just like wear
thorns pants and then the rest of this
gear because we found out in that when
we were doing that Enderman testing I
don't think it's able to repair all four
of these pieces if we have thorns on one
of them because thorns takes three
durability instead of one every time it
loses your ability so I think to bounce
it out we have to get rid of most of our
diamond armor and hopefully the food we
get is enough to keep us alive with the
extra damage we're going to take we can
still put the sword in our offhand that
way we're not using any cheating method
of keeping thorns in our offhand because
it wasn't taking durability when we did
that which was pretty cool but they
might patch that if it is a glitch um so
yeah let's see if this combination works
and basically we would just do this put
something heavy on your mouse on the
right-click key or change your key
bindings there's lots of ways of holding
right click when you're not there and
here comes the spiders the other problem
of this is we can't see the farm working
this is all we're going to ever see when
we use this farm but it's meant to be an
afk farm anyway
okay spiders are dying or getting in the
looting effect from the sword we're able
to eat already
we refilled the stew I'm going to sit
here for a while and see if our armor
durability goes down or if we get close
to death all right guys so I left for
about 10-15 minutes here I went to make
coffee and I just got back let's check
out the damage after afk f king for a
little while loop took the heavy object
off my mouse due to my preferred method
i also added in some hoppers here which
are trapping the experience and my armor
is breaking oh oh
it invalid test I got to do it again I'm
gonna put carpet over these hoppers I
guess whoa
we're down to half a heart guys okay
guys so doing another test here this is
about five to 10 minutes of AF King this
time we're not anywhere close to dying
because I got two pieces of diamond
armor on I got pants and the chest piece
with just one it's very risky even if it
was a diamond chest piece you would have
to eat some better food I think to stay
alive like something with higher
saturation like steak instead of this
mushroom soup garbage that we're eating
but then you need some way of keeping
yourself fed like some dispenser
throwing state at you and you got to
keep that full and it yeah things get
more complicated then
anyways let's check out things take the
heavy object off my mouse so I do have
the carpet over the hoppers now so the
XP isn't getting stuck like it was
before is really important how's our
armor doing the armor is breaking still
yes mmm
big-time breaking is there any XP not
getting picked up a couple specs there
oh this is coming from the spiders right
now there might have been a couple
pieces on the ground but not enough to
to fix this oh yeah there's one thing I
should probably point out too because
this was like the the biggest suggestion
on the last video a lot of you guys are
like oh just use regeneration to that'll
stop you from dying no you can't do that
with beacons regeneration is a secondary
power in the beacon so that means it
only goes up to tier one while all these
other settings have it to your two
option so we can't do region two we need
some other way of keeping us alive so I
have decided guys I'm going to try to do
that potion thing I had in mind
originally so I've entered to build mode
now and I made a pretty cool little
device here I think I'm going to use for
it one thing we're gonna have to do if
we're healing ourselves we don't want to
heal the spiders so pure
ah - I'm going to have my machine here
move me away from any of the spiders and
then throw a healing potion at me and
then bring us back into place it is a
plan and to do that I'm going to use the
piston translocation trick so here's my
little my little device that makes it go
down so pretend the armorstand is us
that makes it go down that makes it go
up pretty simple if you press up again
stays up down press it again stays down
now really not too much to it this is
for regular Pistons this allows you to
stay in the same spots to go up and down
which is pretty cool this is a
monostable circuits sticky piston with a
block above and all these repeaters are
set to one so now I've added some more
on to it basically it just activates
this one first and then seven redstone
ticks later it activates that one and
there's also a dispenser set up now
which gets activated by this repeater so
it does something like this goes down
goes up now what when it goes down you
hear that little tick
that's the dispenser down here this is
what's going to have the potions inside
that'll heal us so this should be fairly
simple let's get rid of this guy and
just try it on ourselves and I made sure
to build this in such a way that we can
put blocks all around here too so this
should work
kick press button down and up
good and let's put in some healing
potions I brought up a couple over with
us all right just to try this out so
what we're going to need after this is
some kind of upper cloth that goes like
every five minutes or so to heal us and
we also need like an auto brewing system
to keep this filled up with healing
potions alright so and then this should
all be good yeah
that you heard that got shot out good so
quite a bit for a silly little farm here
but it'll it'll be neat when it's all
done oh alright guys so this is much
later now but the good news is I think I
got most of the redstone e the
functionality bard is build all done
here we're gonna try it out soon ah then
we got to do the looks of this farm and
then it's complete oh and we got to test
it and find out it doesn't work then
which hopefully doesn't happen but yeah
we got a lot of fancy stuff on here now
we have item filters set up so hopefully
the string will go in there and spider
eyes in here with a bit of storage for
them as well yeah we got our little afk
spot over here where the armor stand
dude is and added a little access store
oops there's a pressure plate there to
access door to get back to the wiring
here if you ever one check it out I've
been doing this more lately where you
make the wiring area look good
it just helps in the future if you have
to modify it or if you ever want to look
at it it's nice to have a way back into
the wiring so we saw how this part work
works the healing station I've hooked up
a hopper timer to it now which is locked
at the moment so it's not running but
depending on how many items we put in
here controls how often we get healed so
it's fully adjustable we'll probably
want to set it to like every five
minutes or so like we said which works
out to about twelve motions every hour
right and since we brew 3 potions per
thing that's like 4 nether wart for
glistening melons for gunpowder and glow
stones not too expensive to run for an
hour
I don't think um did I say that already
in the video I can't even remember so if
I repeated myself um okay and then I
hooked up by an auto brewing system here
this is just my design I have a tutorial
for this if you type in etho brewing in
the youtube search you should find
if you're curious but we have nether
warts
we have gunpowder glowstone and glisten
glistering melon um let's try run this
actually make sure it's still working
yeah so water bottles go in we have go
spring melon next
glowstone gunpowder and it'll finish off
with the nether warts alright and we're
safe to shut it off at any time so
that's good umm so those are going into
this gutter storage here oops and those
go into the dispenser we also have a big
storage for water bottles up here quite
a few double chests we don't have to
refill it very often and over here so
the pickup area that all those hoppers
go to this one which end goes into an
item elevator just a dropper item
elevator if there are items in that that
comparator turns on this repeater turns
on this comparator clock turns on and
sends redstone pulses to all the
droppers on the way up up this staircase
we got here and then we got some hoppers
running across the top there those go
down into the item filters over there
and there and then the items get sorted
into these chests we got three double
chests here four spider eyes and string
and hopefully this all works oh yeah and
this goes up here I forgot to show this
too this goes up to the top of the
spider farm whoa
almost there you know if you're doing a
build you may as well go all out on it
even if it's a simple stupid little
project you'll appreciate it more later
I say so yeah that goes to these lamps
when they turn off it allows the spiders
to spawn there's one spider spawner
right below this torch so two diagonals
from the spawner is I have the lamps and
that seems to stop them
from spawning while I work here which is
good against the inside it is lit up in
there ah the reason for these slabs by
the way in the front here is just to
block out light entirely but we can
still see through them and I think we
can get it going might add the switch
outside there yet but basically if this
is flipped it should run and I don't
have many items in here so it's gonna
trigger pretty frequently yeah so that
go down um yeah here the spiders falling
so that's working and also the brewing
should have engaged yep so everything is
all three things are controlled by this
which is pretty cool Oh
two hearts this is getting scary this is
very scary
I need my healing to activate very soon
got that one and a half hearts oh okay
that only brought us back up to five so
I need to speed that thing up right now
I have it set to I think seven minutes
or so every seven minutes it's gotta be
quite a bit faster probably every four
minutes by the looks of it if I was to
stay here any longer I would die my
armor is doing I don't know the pants
are really low
they went down 40 maybe I'm not
recovering enough then it's really hard
to say okay let's get out of here this
is the other problem I'm noticing they
are really getting stuck
oh okay we did not get a full heal
they're pretty close to a full heal I
gotta speed it up just a little bit more
though full heal okay and this spider
was close to us let's just check his
health he still dies in one hit so he
didn't get healed at all which is good
that's what the the whole point of this
contraptions for um I tried raising the
ground in the back there one block but
yeah like those those guys are within my
line of sight but I guess searching far
away that they're not tracking me and
like I don't know spiders are dumb
that's all I gotta say
are there any stuck up there no good how
do I make them come towards me I really
don't know and our armor is like okay I
think yea the durability is not too low
right now well I think we'll try water
streams now it's the only thing I can
think of to make these guys cooperate if
it works I'm going to set up water
streams like on those walls and probably
on this wall to bring them right to the
middle if they end up over there they
should see us and then come get us
I've also extended this platform one
more block forward and I might change
these out with hoppers this will
increase the amount of experience we get
because I I've noticed the odd time a
little bit will trickle over that should
keep our armor a little bit safer and
I'll show you how I did the water here
too just in case you were curious I
don't want you to think I'm cheating or
something I know some of you already
know how to do this but just in case you
don't you do something like this alright
put our water over here
like so and then I think I got to build
this out too right
possibly okay and then all you got to do
is boop boop boop boop all the way down
to the very end good remove it and we
have Super GT water oh yes all right
guys so good news this is working pretty
good now
I found the timing right for staying at
full house and it's not using to too
many potions which is great auto brewing
is working the sorting system is working
everything's working as far as I can
tell our armor doesn't seem to be
breaking actually now that I expanded
this platform work we're also getting a
bit more XP which is helping out
I think we're collecting all the drops
as well I don't have a hopper where I'm
standing I did put a piston back here
which I might use to push the drops but
most of the drops get picked up by the
hoppers anyway so I don't know if it's
really necessary and the water streams
are working pretty good I don't really
like like how some of these look because
I use signs the hold of the water
yeah I might remove those the one in
front of us is the most important one
the one that we did the Chiti water with
so the very least I'll leave that one
and I kind of give it a little bit of a
look here since we're getting tons of
string I decided to do the build out of
wool it's not a block I usually use and
it looks a little crazy yeah anyways
it we got down four hearts and it did
foliar heal us they're so good I think
we got a winner now all the string and
spider eyes we could ever want awesome
so we did get that working in the end of
things I'm happy about that
unfortunately though that took up like
the whole episode and I usually like to
do several things in an episode but
today I'm really tired now I'd spent
longer than a normal episode on that
unfortunately so it's going to be pretty
much just that one thing I thought we
could try real quick here just to end it
though something a little different I
don't know when you fly with your Alijah
wings I haven't tested yet if you
actually dig slower if you don't you
could potentially speed mine while
flying and like since you take up less
space you might be able to break all the
blocks in front of you before you hit
them which would be pretty crazy so
let's try it out here built like a
little take off the platform
oh okay so it does slow it down darn
good it had a lot of fun with that try
it again
yeah you see how much slower it is ah
okay let's see if I can pull this off
apparently something people have shown
on the reddit is you can dig a hole like
this and then activate your Alijah wings
fly in that hole and like start digging
around see if I can pull it off here oh
I think you need a little bit of a
launch pad actually can't do it on flat
ground right let's go up one block note
still failed come on hmm they made it
look so easy on the rivet Oh
oh maybe I need a block below that could
be it aha oh hey so when you're crouched
down like this you can speed mine oh
that is crazy
break half as many blocks this way um it
might make you feel a little weird
though oh yeah that's awesome so you can
speed mine like this oh and reduced down
to dungeon hello sneaking in here like a
little mouse that's so cool
alright let's check this out
ideally we want to try get some horse
armor here buckets I'll take them I
guess
and saddles not bad Oh in another bucket
oh and I'm dying okay let's get out of
here alright so the comment of the day
says etho you watch whose line is it
anyway I didn't even know that played in
Canada they just started showing
episodes again my whole family watches
him together that's so cool yeah I was a
big fan of whose line is it anyway when
I was younger I think I watched them
when they aired originally um
check this out by the way woohoo um I
didn't get all the jokes though and I
was younger recently I'd start watching
them on YouTube here and oh my goodness
they are so funny
I've watched I watched quite a few hours
lately and I haven't laughed so hard in
a long time
dah dah alright guys hope you enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and I will see you again in the next one
take care bye bye oh and we'll be doing
something else of course so if you're
sick of that farm don't you worry and
also I should probably mention uh I've
seen a few comments like people
complaining there hasn't been an episode
in a month or so I know for sure that
two episodes ago may be the last one as
well couple videos did not show up in
sub boxes properly so you may have
missed one that that didn't show up in
your sub box even though it was posted
if you're really interested in my videos
and this applies to all youtubers you
should probably actually go to their
channel page to watch the videos because
not YouTube does not always show you
every video in your sub box that's that
one of your subscriptions posts so you
might have to check out their channel
every once in a while to buy anyways
thanks for watching guys have a
wonderful day
bye bye
you