[Music]
hey there hi there ho there no I'm not
doing that intro that's terrible
welcome back everybody to another
episode of our let's play series how you
doing today doing great here things are
wonderful magnificent terrific fantastic
better than you I took it too far didn't
I I'm sorry
so what have I been up to here I've been
working on this llama Vader that we
worked on last time didn't quite finish
it then but I think it's about good now
changed all the stone out there to red
clay just so it looks maybe a little bit
nicer and I had this thing here but I
think I'm going to change it so one
thing with this elevator is I wanted a
way to call the llama up here so I'd
like a trapdoor thing so if we want to
ride the elevator down we can basically
up comes a llama you hop on it's a
little bit glitchy but not too bad and
then we're down here and then if we want
to go up it's working pretty good
somebody said this is going to break in
the next patch though and I don't know
if there's a specific reason for that or
it's just because elevators tend to
always break every update I'm not sure
hopefully it doesn't break so I kind of
like this thing okay okay what should we
do here instead of doing the trapdoor
thing we'll do something maybe a little
bit more automatic yeah I think we'll do
it like this guys so we're going to have
a button in the corner here that
activates the redstone shoots an item
out of the dropper falls down the hole
here and that triggers the llama Vader
we could just jump down here too if we
want it's not that far of a fall won't
kill us if we have Pez are falling
there's a little bit fancier all right
except for for that part of it
one thing I did down here too is like
when we hop on the llama we go where the
tripwire is here that that activates the
thing but on the way down we won't don't
want the llama
again otherwise it will just go into an
endless loop of getting launched here so
I put in a t flip-flop so it only
activates once but not the second time
on the way down so let's just look at
the stuff here real quick
oh we activated it so yeah this is where
the item falls down into the hopper that
gets detected and sends a signal over
here
I heard the lump get hurt there I think
he's okay though like I've been watching
itself and he wasn't dying yet the
tripwire starts here activates a piece
of redstone into a monostable circuit
into the T flip-flop and this has to be
set at one goes down the piston that
launches it so yeah kind of a mess but
it's pretty simple actually alright
everybody so for today's episode I think
we're just going to do maybe some random
things around the place maybe some
building projects stuff like that we
recently refined this area here but it
kind of stops like here so I would like
to make this area polished up a bit more
we got the Simon game I don't know if
we'll get to that today that needs to be
finished still and then there's a tunnel
here this is I think what we're going to
focus on let's see let's count it here
one two three four five six seven let's
work with odd numbers always I let God
numbers yes that would go over here this
will be like the divider for the room
and then we're probably going to have a
tunnel of some sort have a little idea
here I wanted a trial we really haven't
done anything with the concrete blocks
or powder yet and I thought it's
something fun we could try I want to try
make like a changing tunnel here that
keeps changing the walls so they don't
always look the same and might be
possible with concrete powder might be
really easy to do actually so yeah this
leads over to the village if we go far
enough here don't want to make this
totally straight though because I've
learned that's a really bad thing to do
you want to break it up otherwise it's
it feels really bad or
so we'll probably go about like halfway
and then they'll be a t-intersection
and then we'll go the rest of the way
that's door ever I think I had to
sacrifice the wiring because I got too
close to to it or something there
anyways so cleared out a little bit of
area here for a see it started on the
idea we're going to have our
intersection room here right and then
this is going to be the tunnel so let's
just play around with this first and see
we got to figure out the function before
the beauty right that's that's always
the key when you're doing a redstone
project try to get it working first and
then make it look nice afterwards so I'm
thinking on the left and the right here
will have a will have walls made out of
concrete powder all right those will be
on top of pistons and we want to be able
to change the pattern probably using a
hopper clock or something every so often
will change it'll move the blocks here
so I think all we got to do really if we
want to keep this really simple is just
push the concrete powder up here and
then at the top of the stack have
Pistons pushing this way and I made some
levers yeah okay let's try this out
we'll do one piston at a time here so
that is over there so this will get
triggered push up this will push
sideways go fall down and then I guess
we need Pistons here if we want to keep
it really small could just have a piston
there to push it sideways again I guess
we're going to have to activate this
piston first and then like two tix later
this one so it'll it'll raise the block
and then sneak one in underneath before
these start falling down right so I
think we're going to go in here to
activate this piston first and two ticks
later one two we will have to run power
up to this piston somehow maybe go
run it along like this it doesn't really
matter how we do it with our test
testing here though so we'll just do
that okay so let's put down a buttons
and just see what happens we probably
need a monostable circuit before this
though
yeah we need a monostable circuit
otherwise it just does that okay let's
get that in here too
I will just try it out with a piston
thing here first okay and redstone dust
there put a button on top of that this
is really messy I know I'm sorry but
we're doing it together this is how I
work okay that didn't quite work that
didn't quite work why would it shove it
off okay let's try a different timing
here what if this is at one I probably
it probably needs to be three that's no
good
one two three no still no good oh okay I
just we're going to have to do it like
this guys I put a sticky piston here
instead it's going to retract and pull
the concrete powder back here but this
piston will still be powered so as soon
as this retracts it updates this piston
causing it to extend with like no delay
between the two and that'll push a
concrete powder out so it's going to do
this basically that's how you do it and
this is set at two we have have to use a
redstone torch I think so here uh-huh
monostable circuit here and I ran a wire
up to this piston just so we can try
like doing a loop here to see if it
works so for example we could have
gravel on one side and concrete powder
on the other would look pretty ugly but
hopefully we'll come up with a
cool-looking pattern but this should be
able to switch between a white concrete
wall in the gravel wall
ah something like that that's idea I
just hopped over to the zombie pigmen
farm guys got to do a tool repair here I
don't carry the bow with me anymore
right for flying so I need a pigment in
the middle here I can just smack but
this is what I've been doing until I get
that here anyways I just throw it ender
pearl up in the middle and I enter pearl
and hit one of these guys and then I
land over here my lazy way of activating
the farm seems to work pretty good
actually
wahoo alright so I've been making some
good progress here guys just about got
this all done got the redstone stuff to
mostly figure it out and it's it looks
really nasty right now I just want to
show it to you before we cover it up
though so like in our test example here
or from before does the same thing
except now we have a big line of pistons
I think I made this 11 blocks long and
you know if this is a cool thing we
might do this more but I'm not sure yet
so it pushes the gravel up and then at
the top there there's some Pistons that
push it sideways and then it falls down
so in total that's three pistons per
column and a piston can push up to
twelve blocks right so I think it pushes
twelve blocks up and then double that on
the other side roughly maybe 23 24
blocks in total here we could add more
blocks if we add more Pistons but then
it gets more complicated so we're going
to keep it simple here and honestly it's
like this doesn't take up much space
because it's only two blocks whine right
you could easily have moving walls guys
everybody should do it it's the future I
tell you no probably not but it it'll be
a fun little thing here I like to try
add something new to each part of the
man tape here so it doesn't become
repetitive you know so yeah let's just
check this out real quick so sticky
pistons get powered by this line here
this is our redstone torch goes over to
here to a toothpick repeater and then
that power is this big line of Pistons
down below here from this let's see
there's really not too much to this yeah
from this this is our monostable circuit
here that just goes and activates us on
both sides so I fall down hole I do that
a lot don't I
uh-huh I think I do that every episode
so just copied it on the other side here
and then there's also the line that goes
up to the Pistons up above so let's go
check those out too just runs up a
staircase thing here and over to this so
it's not super complicated really mm-hmm
so if this is 24 blocks or so right and
we have a wall that's five blocks tall
divide that by five you can have four
completely different walls within our
our block limit there right if it's a
seven block wall seven block tall wall
we're trying to make then you know 23 or
24 divided by seven you could easily fit
three completely different walls within
our blocks here so not quite sure what
we're going to do with it just yet or
how tall our walls going to be um or we
could just shift the wall so it moves
one block at a time but I think we'll
just make it so you and change it into a
completely different wall with the push
of a button or by a hopper timer running
so yeah we'll probably have some sort of
border running along here I made sure we
could keep this all flat if we wanted to
so let's just fill this in with grass
right now I don't know if that's oh it's
going to be in the end of things here
but that'll give us an idea of what the
rooms going to look like in and how tall
we should make the walls and that kind
of stuff just tie how it feels so it's a
pretty wide room I did it that way so
like the walls can actually be seen like
if if the roof is really short and the
walls are like right in our face like
over here won't really be able to see
them to you all right so I think this
will be good and if it's only five
blocks tall one two three four
while five blocks tall is pretty tall
actually let's see so if we kind of
block off that space that's that's a
five block tall look room that's not bad
actually okay so I just framed this in
for right now to give us a better idea
of where are our moving walls going to
be right and this room feels pretty good
to me the way it is I don't think we
should go any taller like five blocks is
quite a bit already don't go to six or
seven I don't think I kind of like this
too like we have a narrow doorway here
so as we walk forward then the pictures
on the left and right here will get
revealed has that reveal feel to it you
know reveal feel up and we can see it
with our peripheral vision right we
don't even have to like turn to the
right or left to see them we'll see them
as we walk by so now comes the tough
part we actually have to do some art
here or or make some walls that look
cool and I might not know what to do
here should we try do a mural as one of
the walls not only do I have to design
one wall I have to design like four and
possibly four more if we don't keep them
the same on the other side I'm not sure
okay let's just copy what we kind of did
in our tree farm no we'll make like
grass and sky and see what that looks
like okay that looks pretty bad yeah
we're not going to do that
the color contrast between the two is
this way too sharp okay I do like the
blue though I think the blue looks
pretty nice maybe we'll just mix in
another blue block with the light blue
here mm-hmm so I might need some
guidance here guys help me out with what
colors I should actually be using for
this room maybe like I don't know if I
should keep this as grass and like this
wood stuff it feels like it doesn't
really go with the concrete powder right
even the different colors will probably
have trouble but just in a simple
pattern here maybe too simple I'm not
sure I guess like if we're walking by
here
we're not gonna be staring at it right
where it's gonna be off on the side so
you don't want too complicated
otherwise it's it's gonna be disturbing
as we walk by maybe I really know what
I'm talking about okay I guess I'll try
this do four simple patterns like this
and see what it's like so I'm gonna do
like a yellowish one maybe a grayish
color one and or a brown and maybe a
purple one and just see what that's like
all right are you ready for this here we
go so I got four different patterns here
and ideally we want to set this up so
this gets pressed like five times in a
row automatically without us doing it
right set that up on a hopper timer that
activates randomly so maybe today's a
blue day when we walk down the tunnel or
maybe it's a gray day just try it a
couple random patterns here this one's
not too bad either
it's okay there is one that I don't
don't really like so I did a yellow an
orange one here kind of a stripy thing I
think this one's pretty good to you I'm
happy with that but then I did a perform
this one maybe you should be changed the
colors are if if we keep this grass
anyways something about these colors
it's just not right uh-huh anyways it's
it's kind of a goopy random idea thought
you guys might like it though and it'll
make our tunnel a little bit more
interesting here AHA anyways so this
goes to over here this is our pixel I
think we'll put in a window where we can
view the redstone wiring and then
they'll probably be the like a big room
over here right so it's not not a total
straight straight area yeah so we'll
have the window on this side they'll be
like at an intersection that goes this
way and then probably not straight
through here we'll go over a few blocks
and then start going straight this way
again towards the village
is the plan I think we'll do something
else here for today's episode and break
things up a bit okay so I just checked
in we don't have a whole lot of time
left this episode but we're going to try
to do a quick project before we finish
it first I want to show you the mushroom
farm though so I have been working on
this I finish building the Sun shield
over top the mushrooms I decided to do
that instead of using just string like
we have the Basel here right so we can
just put string above the mushrooms
without blocking out the light but we're
going to do the Sun shield just because
it's going to make it a lot easier to
put in the water streams here I'm going
to put dispensers on top of this with
water buckets in and we just have to run
a wire down the middle here to activate
them all and then that will flush all
the mushroom drops towards these holes
and they'll get picked up so that's
going to be a nice simple way of doing
that we need more orange sand to finish
this build though so that's what we're
going to do here we're going to make one
of these at once and make arewe machines
and try to semi automate it so this
turns this yellow sand into oranges and
kind of a glitch in the game but I'm
okay with it and I think we're going to
go ahead and do it but not over here
we're going to build it at kind of in
the Sandy City area I think a sense
because sandy city sand you know so
let's head over there I picked out a
spot already you guys might have noticed
I have I have done a little something
here too so I extended this hat a little
bit a while ago and I've started
building like random stairs and stuff in
this mountain here we have these really
cool mountains and they're not really
being being used so what I would like to
do is maybe make a cool-looking bridge
here eventually they'll go through a
tunnel here and then if we want to build
like in a snowy area that's that's
what's going to be over here we'll go up
on top of mountains and and we do some
snow things for ice themed things and
just put some some random things here to
see how they look but yeah I think we're
going to put our red sand maker machine
just over
they're in this little area don't have a
lot of space here but it's also not
going to take up a lot of space I don't
think so this will this will be good and
then we can connect the path to this and
hopefully make it look like a little
shack or something but we'll see so I
decided I want to put the Pistons at eye
level here so it's going to be easier to
place the sand inside this thing and
then we have to have two sticky pistons
here - sand blocks above this I don't
know I think you can just use any sand
block I don't think it matters or any
blocks with gravity and above these
pistons you definitely need to use slabs
you can't use full blocks and on top of
those redstone okay and now I think all
we got to do is have repeaters over
there let's go up so we can actually see
one of these has to be set at two and
one of them at one oh I don't know I
changed that oh and I fall down again
okay we're going to try seek this into
the ground a little bit so doesn't pick
those up as much vertical space either
and then over here we need a monostable
to start it so just the sticky piston
with a block on it okay now to activate
this we're probably going to use an
observer block so every time we place a
sand block it will trigger um so maybe
let's test this first to see how it
works
so think we might put the orange sand
block on that side and yellow on this
side and let's just set this up so we
can trigger it okay do that and then a
repeater or something or duff's would
work even and do we have a button let's
make a button put that on here so will
this make orange or yellow sand let's
find out okay yellow sand turned into
orange spam that's what we want so this
is where we're going to be using it so
I'm just going to put the observer block
like facing us here other way like over
here that will probably point into a
block and then go up to here so
break this again right and maybe put a
repeater here so this isn't connects
trying to build this with you so you can
see how to do it if you want copy it
okay something like that so I think
every time we place this block here now
it'll trigger
whoa that was weird oh I just pushed it
and then this pulled it it's like how
did that move it two blocks that's the
same okay so let's try this yeah that's
what we want so then we're going to want
the sand to fall and break right so this
is going to be our Center and I want a
bunch of storage for all the sand so we
can hopefully afk here for a while and
collect a bunch so probably gonna do one
two actually three double chests
probably fine we'll break the bottom one
here don't need that much storage even
three might be overkill I'm not sure
then we'll have a hopper going into
these so I'm flying do something like
that did you guys see they announced on
the on Twitter that they're adding
parents to the game we're finally
getting Birds it's going to be so cool
that that spawn in the jungle apparently
so really looking forward to that
hopefully it'll be easy to get them to
spawn in and we don't have to travel
super far to get up oh that has to go
down one more block OOP okay we had it
right the first time let's see if we can
reach that bottom chest from up here
though doesn't look like this we can
reach we reach this one maybe we'll just
do two double chests and and call it
good that way this gets a lot simpler
and put this over here good got two
double chests of storage is probably
plenty plenty of sand and now what do we
want to do we want to be able to afk
here alright so our one stack of fan is
going to run out really quick here we
want to be able to feed ourselves more
yellow sand as
we use this so let's put in a dropper
maybe facing that way so they'll shoot
the sand at us and I guess let's get
some trapdoors too because we'll
probably have to stand on those or I
just so you'd use slabs and still be
able to open the chests here right yeah
that'll work too okay good
so inside here we're going to have our
sand to get sand into there or to
activate it first let's see the observer
goes into this block so then all we got
to do is like something like this
even put a block there or actually it
probably needs some sort of delay too so
let's let's try this first redstone dust
into it like that so now if we put down
sand what happens yeah it shoots two of
them we only want it to shoot one so
we're going to use a repeater so it will
hopefully only trigger once that will
probably have to be said it's like three
or four let's try it one it at one first
okay still shot twice
let's switch at two to three there we go
that's what we want qo so that seems to
be pretty good you get once and every
time we place the sand for extra storage
I'm just going to run a dropper into the
side here and then probably put like a
chest above that or two two double
chests here we can put another one like
this if we want all right and then fill
this up a bit for the yellow sand so to
auto-feed into us what else we got to do
here there was a problem like if we try
to hold right click here if we replace
two blocks and then it blocks the view
so if we put a sign or something here if
we build this up and then put a sign
over here then if we hold right click
it'll never replace an extra block
I think that's that's what we're going
to do and kind of frame this in a little
bit and probably cover this up if we
want and I think we're just about done
with this what else could we do to it I
guess we're going to want to add or
something so the mobs don't come kill us
while we're using it to and some way of
getting to our chests here so maybe a
trapdoor will work here and then do
something like that so we just open this
to get our stuff and close it well
anyways guys I think we'll wrap up here
for today and we'll try decorate that
next episode or I'll do it off camera
but here is the comments I picked out it
says hey Ito have you ever thought about
doing a factorial let's play it's
definitely the kind of game you would be
good at and I think it would be really
interesting to watch so I have played
factorial I love the game it's a great
game I don't I don't think I'm very good
at it so like I'm not I'm not V still
level expert or anything like that so I
don't know how how good of a series I
could actually do on it I would struggle
quite a bit kind of like as a more of a
learning series than me telling you how
to play the game really well or anything
like that
a lot of people have asked for a series
on it but yeah I'm not sure not sure
about that I have considered playing
rimworld though that's a game I'm
actually good at and it's very
complicated kind of like factorial also
oxygen not included just came out
recently too so I might do a series on
that like a short one it's a little bit
simpler than rimworld but a similar kind
of game uh-huh
anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode if you have any feedback
or comments leave it down below but
thank you for watching hope you enjoyed
it and until next time take care bye bye
[Music]