ah man it happened again everybody I
knew it was gonna happen but still it
hurts me every single time I got some
real problems here some real first world
minecraft problems you guys ever have
that issue like where Enderman come by
and they steal your sombrero wearing
cactus melons cuz yeah it's it keeps
happening I replace them but then they
just disappear again it's it's really
frustrating honestly so I came over here
guys and I dropped down a piece of nily
oh nice trying to farm up these crimson
fungi right I'm trying to get some
nether resources together and this is
bone milling it here getting the odd one
every now and then and it's been good
and okay but then I start to realize
wait a minute
we have something to do this for us
already we just have to modify it very
ever-so-slightly here punch out two
grass blocks and now look at this
oh it's timing a little bit better there
we go huh look at that oh my goodness so
much better oh we good okay wait a
minute
might have a couple issues with this one
thing I really like about the nether
update is pretty much every single block
they're adding with it can be easily
farmed or instant mined in some way with
the exception of nether right but like
everything else that's kind of weird
that one grew cricked you see that oh
that one did too everything else is
pretty easy yet though those things grow
pretty tall actually this is what we
ended up with we have like 64 fungi
growing here together I think it was
last episode we did some trading with
the big lens and we ended up getting
another right-o off of them I've been
chanted it now with efficiency and we
can instant mine and other work blocks
that grow on these trees which is pretty
cool in instant - shroom lights with it
as well okay so looking at this I'm
pretty sure the nether wart blocks
overwrite the wood if they grow overtop
of it so we ended up with very little
wood here actually probably best not to
grow them together like this then but it
was interesting to try it out yep yep
and as you saw there we can also
instantly mine the crimson and warp
woods and you can use these the craft
wood products like chests and stuff so
that's a new way of collecting wood
quickly because like spruce you can't
instant mind none of the other wood
types just the new ones and next up on
our incredibly easy to farm list we have
the basalt block guys which is a
especially interesting one so basalts
has its own biome basalt delta's you'll
find plenty of the stuff there if you
need it but even if that's not enough
they made a way for you to be able to
generate it so if you put lava and have
it flow over top a soul soil and then
touch some blue ice it'll create a
basalt block in the middle here I messed
around with a few different firms for
this obviously you make afk farms and
stuff with it but I thought this one was
particularly satisfying and interesting
maybe a little less obvious can you use
some note blocks here and can easily
make a bunch of smart pistons to create
a big slab of this stuff I just love
watching this thing so cool yeah so
basalt can be instant mine you only need
a haste one beacon and like diamond
tools or nether right tools but it has
the same hardness as hardened clay
terracotta hardness of 1.25 which funny
enough makes it a block that you can
instant mine with gold picks without a
hey speakin while we can't do this with
nether right you see this we try to
break it with our net the right pick
it's not able to instant mine it but
we've gold again there is actually a way
to farm soul soil as well it's just kind
of weird and convoluted and are not
really efficient if you can go to the
soul sand Valley that's the way to get
this stuff but you can farm it by making
soul campfires using soul sand you can
get soul sand from piglet bartering like
if you're playing a sky block you might
actually want to end up doing this place
these down it turns out you can't
instant mine these though I've been
trying here
those fortune you only break them it so
quickly but it gives you so loyal as a
drop also you can trade with villagers
for campfires please give me charcoal Oh
to pieces when you break them so that's
a way to buy fuel from villagers but
again it's not really worth it but yeah
I think another soul sand value in this
instant - stuff so I went on a bit of a
trip here around the nether doing some
exploring trying to find a good location
to set up our nether base that is our
goal for today also the reason we're
collecting a lot of these resources I
ended up finding a tiny little what was
it called again
assault Delta's yeah which it's not
really a super nice one so I figured
this is the one I'm gonna destroy to get
the black stone which is again another
block an instant mine if you have these
two alright everybody so I'm getting
pretty excited here we're gonna start
building
that crimson keep very soon very very
soon we got our black stone over a full
chakra box of it even rated a couple
than the other fortresses got horse
armor as may be looking for a dual blaze
spawner but I didn't end up finding one
like if I did it would probably
influence where we actually build the
base I still haven't quite figured that
out yet but I do know exactly what
building pellets I want to go for
spoiler alert it's not this I've seen a
lot of people using this building pellet
and I think it looks pretty good
actually but I feel it's better for like
fantasy sort of builds more so with the
brighter brighter blocks
I actually don't to be honest with you I
don't like the nether brick with the
blue too much I've seen a lot of people
combine the two together but I do like
these other six and I would probably use
a different contrasting color if it was
me ohoho snappers so I think we found it
guys we got our location I've been doing
some more browsing around looking
through the nether and I have found a
spot it's at minus 1,000 minus 3,500
here so it's a little ways from 0 0 but
it's not crazy I think that's a doable
trip still as far as building scheme the
block pellet I wanted to use the black
stone it's a new cool block right and
then I thought hey crimson forest is my
favorite of the biomes let's go for red
so we're probably gonna use the crimson
wood maybe some other red blocks to mix
in with it and then I started thinking
what else would go with these two it's
like ok oranges yellows and light gray I
think that's like a traditional Chinese
color scheme I could be wrong about that
though but I see like fancy Chinese
buildings like in moving the movies and
stuff I think of these colors for some
reason so that is what inspired it and
now as far as location goes I wanted a
area with like two big land masses like
big landmass here at big landmass here
and I'm lava moat in the middle and I
wanted to build a big bridge to like a
castle let's go take a look around look
at this we are in this pretty amazing
nether fortress actually and it looks
pretty cool but then it joins up with a
what do you call it a bastion or
something one of the new structures in
the game let's take a little peek inside
and I recognise the layout of this one
it is the one with the make my slime
spawner inside and like the giant room
so I got to thinking this is pretty cool
probably very dangerous in here by the
way oh I thought I heard someone load up
the crossbow yeah yeah so the fortress
goes right into this thing actually and
I was thinking maybe let's move inside
and like take this place over or
renovate it or do something similar of
that nature so I was looking around
outside of the the bastion here oh I
should eat before I jump down that was
dangerous I got caught up on that bridge
bad news
oh there's no lava and freaked me out
really bad I think this is where we want
to do it if we yeah I think I think this
is the side over here so I was looking
around outside yeah here it is there's a
big big lava area here and then we got
more of the crimson forest over over
here so what I'm thinking we're gonna
start here with our build I'm gonna
build a big massive bridge from here to
there and then we'll build like a
cool-looking castle facade in front of
that thing and then that bastion is
gonna be the interior of our base okay
so let's get to it here guys so the
first thing I did is I just set up a
temporary hut while we fill this up with
chests and like the stonecutter and
different different things
so when I fill my inventory book jungle
somewhere to drop it off then I built
like a temporary bridge to so I can try
figure out how I wanted to line up with
the bastion here like what height level
the bridge should be you fit through
there really you're not not after that I
think this is a center unfortunately
it's like an even number so I'll
probably have to either lopsided to this
side or over here this is about 45
blocks long from from that Island to the
bastion now I need to figure out roughly
what I'm calling the wall here so this
is like a walkway area inside what's
behind here we got a staircase and then
it looks like the wall is like two
blocks here actually so I'm gonna try go
off of odd numbers as much as I can so
let's uh say it's three blocks wide and
then like this is a big cube this
building here so if we want to give it
any shape or definition we're gonna need
to come out quite a few blocks away from
that so I'm thinking at least seven
probably more two three four five six
seven all right I don't know what I'm
doing exactly I'm gonna say let's go
this far away from the face of the thing
though so roughly where we're standing
at this torch here is gonna be the start
of our crimson keep right where we're
standing is gonna be the door like the
entrance into it and then the bridge is
gonna go right up that door so let's
work on the bridge here my fire
resistance has worn out so I got a check
if I got any more of my shelter boxes
away I think I want this as a center so
what we're gonna do get rid of that one
the pattern we're going for first stuff
here is two crimson wood and then a
shroom light in the middle and that's
gonna extend all the way down here I
want plenty of light with this build if
you guys don't know it I really hates
dark nether builds drives me crazy so
it's gonna be gloomy right it's gonna be
gloomy but I want it to be a little bit
bright
here's the tough part now we have so
many options with the Blackstone it's
like we got to decide which one we're
actually gonna go for I think for our
bridge the polished Blackstone makes the
most sense like I think the bricks are
better for walls when I do the borders
of a bridge I usually have to go a slab
below like the base of it so I think
we're gonna go down a slab and then up
one will be able to see a little bit of
crimson wood through the side here full
blocks above those now you might have
noticed with our bridge here the shroom
light and the crimson wood don't exactly
blend together the best so we're gonna
try mill them out a bit by putting glass
over top and then we're gonna have red
glass over the crimson wood and then I
want to start mixing in some acacia as
well yeah so I think that's good that
adds a bit of 3d depth to the bridge and
also a little bit of variation with the
colors the trim lights aren't quite as
shocking either with a bit of glass over
top and now we're gonna line the border
here so we don't fall off with some of
these bricks uh yeah yeah so I'm liking
the look of this I do feel like the
bridge needs to be a bit longer though
so we'll probably extend it further onto
land here or even terraform a bit and
have more lava below here but the look
is okay I'm really trying to push myself
with this build to get better at bigger
structures it's something I kind of suck
at to be honest so I'm having a huge
bridge like really trying to add space
to the build I usually I like to go
small and compact with the entrance I'm
gonna go up I think seven blocks here
for the door
another thing I'm pushing myself to do
with this build is to use a lot of walls
walls are a lot better now than they
used to be and kind of use them as
vertical slabs with this update like if
you if you do this it actually looks
really good now you don't have that
space between them anymore
so to get your building to the next
level
that's what you're gonna have to start
doing and I need to practice so I'm
gonna use them for detailing for adding
interesting shapes and steps of the
build this way like we don't have a big
piece of orange now we just definitely a
thin line there alright so check it out
guys we're using the black stone here to
beef up our door make it look a bit more
impressive a little bit more
structurally sound I snuck in some red
clay over here so thin sliver of it you
can barely notice blends in pretty close
to the acacia and I'm starting to use
basalt as well I think we're gonna go
for the polished basalt I liked it a
little bit more and now I'm kind of
getting to the point where I just need
to start detailing this thing and it's
going to be hard to record that a lot of
trial and error but I was thinking try
to mix some of this stuff in over here
alright
I brought some that's kind of cool
I brought some acacia fences to use as
like the thingy that comes down from the
door the actual door I don't know what
you call it it starts with @p you know
what I'm talking about right yeah yeah
and now I also want to detail the bridge
a bit more so I think every fifth block
one to here let's count on the glass
this is your one two three four five
we're gonna add a piece of basalt here
and then like a slab over top of that
that's our piece of basalt I got a slab
a stayer chiseled and now this is gonna
go straight down into the ground into
the lava there a couple walls here which
are nice because they don't connect to
the slabs it's a little kind of cool and
then some stairs and I'm gonna try
detail underneath the bridge even which
is gonna be tough here so I think we're
gonna run some slabs all along the
shroom lights will leave the crimson
wood exposed that like how it looks will
run a beam across
and what some stairs maybe I kind of
start arching up to support this uh-huh
I'll figure something out
I messed with it a bit here and we
actually went for a pretty detailed arch
thing here so I like the shape of this I
think that's a good arch and then we
replaced a lot of the slabs with stairs
and just did some funny patterns with
them I got a couple chiseled blocks in
here and I've been using the nether wart
as my scaffolding because it's easy to
collect you can grow it easy to line up
afterwards oh you jerk I'm working here
man I'm working here these are the
dangerous guys the ones with the gold
sores they do so much damage so quickly
and if they're enchanted you're just
like dead instantly
yeah we can't reach it and it looks like
it's floating on the lava if we don't go
just a little bit further down so we
have actually have to go one more block
lower oh whoa yeah okay that looks
pretty cool I like it if you open doors
by oh it's pretty pretty freaky
I still haven't died if I died I
wouldn't be so sad though it's quite the
walk to get back here I was looking at
the time on this episode and man the
where has it gone guys I got so much
more stuff I want to do with this yet
I'll probably be building a lot of it
off-camera but yeah check it out we've
added more details to the bridge more
details to the the gate there the
entrance so these are campfires on top
of the basalt here I kind of like that
it adds in the yellow the orange and a
little bit of life to the build having
the animation is nice I do kind of wish
I made the bridge wider now that I've
done this though does these things stick
out unless I get rid of them or
something I don't know get rid of these
it's not bad either is it I think that's
okay maybe maybe you guys have a
suggestion see what you say in the
comments oh I might leave them there for
now umm added some some of these Chinese
lantern things on the front here
I kind of like that I don't have any
string on me those I can't stop them
from growing and now oh yeah the best
part here we're gonna add some danglies
okay let's go up here is that new thing
I've learned to do guys it's gonna be
amazing
so we add some acacia it look like rope
and we add another or how do I want to
do this maybe we go down again Oh
ooh in this place and end it with one of
those yeah that's pretty cool I like
those now do you guys remember a couple
episodes ago you were working on that
bee farm in the end and you remember how
I don't finish my projects well it's
it's really haunting me this time
because I could not find any honey I
thought I had like a stack of it at
least at the base somewhere but I
couldn't find it so I'm using gold
blocks as a placeholder for right now
but that's where I want to put the honey
up over there I needs a little bit more
brownish orange ish so it will blend in
a lot better that really stands out but
that's that's kind of what we're going
for and I think we're about done with
the door here like the entrance add some
jagged ease up at the top there and the
next thing I think we should do with
this is boof and boof add two towers
next to the entrance here to the beef up
the build a bit more the problem is
because we're not building this on land
like I originally planned is this gonna
be like lava below here so we either
need to make the towers go down into the
lava or I need to do some terraforming
here and make it look like there's
actually some land like at the edge here
which might be the best thing to do
because I would like to get the nyam the
red now Liam in with this build as well
oh man okay well that was a lot of
building guys but check it out the
crimson Jeep is pretty much all not done
but we got a nice faceplate to it at
least but honestly it's not bad like if
you look at the width of the towers
there they and just about at the width
of the bastion that sticks out about
five blocks further there so if we just
add a little bit more bulk it we can
kind of surround the whole thing and
we'll probably want to build some more
towers up above there as well or more
structure in time but I think the next
thing we're gonna be doing with this is
start working on the interior and then
later we might come back to the front
here and add more to it but yeah look at
our look at our towers these things are
nuts so much detail on them oh it's a
sword you know
well you saw it at least oh no I got
teamed up on that there very end now I
know what you guys are thinking etho why
didn't you just make the new save point
thing the respawn anchor because like I
found this spot there and I managed to
build all of that without heading back
home but like as soon as I was gonna
head back home I'm gonna make one of
these for sure
and get honey and all that kind of stuff
but now we gotta head back there oh I
only got three armor oh no I forgot to
grab pants then and I answer important
I'd be pretty close to here oh that's
the fortress that's it we found it
oh and there's the build Wow okay that
worked out really well actually I don't
think we lost anything or nothing
important that I can tell so that was
pretty lucky because we used walls guys
Oh such a good decision they're a little
bit taller you know it's harder for the
items to fall overboard so let's figure
out how this respawn anger works we're
gonna set up in our our little Hut here
put it down I think we put glowstone in
very good very good so now if we die
with that respawn anchor will respawn in
our little Hut there and we brought some
backup here with us and we got backup
food and stuff so it shouldn't be as big
of a deal if we do die here now so yeah
these are our towers again by the way so
they're pretty detailed they actually go
like seven blocks thick or so maybe even
more than that they're pretty pretty
crazy uh-huh and then I'm thinking we're
gonna have a bit of a walkway to get
into the builds or into the bastion here
and then later like with this empty
space we can put some rooms is that not
closed up okay yeah maybe
let's let's go check this out real quick
as well ah fire resistance let's drink
one of them I brought it told them with
me
so I'm not taking as many chances now I
think of all the structures or all the
dungeons in the game this is probably
one of the dangerous if not be dangerous
one now little guys don't attack you
little piggies though they like to
attack you if you hit them they run away
if you let them so that is the magma
cube spawner which is kind of cool it's
like right under the entrance we're
gonna go down here
I think there's some good stuff in the
middle there we're gonna go get that if
we can I mean I got the fire resistant I
should be so scared I'm gonna leave the
gold and everything in its place
oh we got pants make me keeps you hurt a
lot though there's just one chest it's
just the one yeah cool cool
ah but there's more throughout the whole
basket in here how do we get back up oh
there's kind of some stairs here I
didn't know that stairs and then there's
a little side stairs here but the layers
and by the way I haven't thought a whole
lot about how I'm gonna renovate this
place like what colors were gonna use or
anything like that or how we're gonna do
it so if you guys have any suggestions
on what we should do with this build I
would love to hear him but I was kind of
just thinking now maybe since we have
also have the nether fortress maybe we
use this area the fortress for our arms
like we set them up along the corridor
here and we might want to renovate the
fortress as well change out the blocks
maybe from nether brick something else
and try to make it look nice could be
cool as well I think there's a blaze
spawner in there too but I didn't find
any dual blaze burners unfortunately go
up here this is the top of our home oh
oh wait is there another one can have to
do this there might be a lab a room over
here let's make sure I keep you in here
it is gonna spawn these guys constantly
in this this base will either have to
find some way of dealing with them or
will have to learn to live with them or
like wear gold armor or something oh
this is gonna go anywhere actually it's
kind of an estranged and dead end
there's a giant lava lake near here so
if we want to set up any farms like
crimson
crimson forest farms this is a good
place to do it nearby here as well oh
there's another chest another two chests
whoa
now I think if I take that they're gonna
get mad at me right maybe oh we got some
string I actually needed string for the
vines there that's a great find
got some spectral arrows oh and some
chains oh another double chest more for
the black stone we got some crying
obsidian obsidian no record though so I
thought there was only one blaze fire
but there's one over there and they
might be close enough but I don't think
they are no they're definitely not ah
it's too bad the other ones over here
well anyways guys we made the trip back
home again here and I think we got a
wrap-up episode I did have a redstone
project I wanted to do today but there's
just not enough time now so don't have
to wait for another one the comment of
the day says how you here go how do you
keep motivation playing Minecraft I want
to be back in the game and enjoy it like
in the old days put together a vanilla
plus mod pack and play it on an
amplified world but I don't know I don't
seem to get into it how do you motivate
yourself to keep playing especially for
such a long time now that is a great
question there's a lot of things that
could be said about this and where to
begin I think probably the biggest thing
is if you're playing single-player
single-player gets boring I hate to say
it it's different for me because I'm
doing YouTube so I'm not just playing by
myself here Oh
anything I do in my world here gets seen
by hundreds of thousands of people
actually which is crazy and then they
give me feedback on it they judge me on
it you know if it's good they give me
good feedback if it's bad they give me
bad feedback sometimes it's just neutral
or whatever anyways that kind of pushes
me to try harder right because I want to
give a good good impression with my
videos so I tend to do bigger projects
as well
which is another big thing try to do new
stuff in the game that's a big thing
because again I want people to see
something they haven't seen before in
another video like if you're just
copying someone's builds or farms or
whatever or something you've done in the
past and you're just rebuilding it again
you're gonna get bored you gotta you
gotta push yourself to try new stuff out
I think another huge huge motivator for
me is a new content as well so you might
notice I'll usually have a vanilla
series going and a modded series or two
and usually the modded series are quite
different from each other right like
Terra Firma craft is nothing like
pixelmon or like enigmatika - those are
totally different types of minecraft
experience and then Mojang keep putting
out new patches I actually feel kind of
overwhelmed with all the stuff that they
keep adding to the game and in fact I
got some big projects I've been wanting
to do in my world here I just keep
pushing them off because I can't get
through the new content can't make farms
quick enough to deal with all this stuff
at it like today I had to build a nether
base cuz another update right now I'm
gonna spend a few episodes on that I'm
sure um yeah
new content helps a lot too anyways
hopefully you guys enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching hope you
enjoyed it I said that already take care
have a good day bye bye
[Music]