hey everybody this is etho I was doing
some caving today that would start out
the episode picking on a spawner zombie
spawner I'm pretty sure I haven't seen
if it's a dungeon yet but it definitely
sounds like careful I don't this is the
same one I found before it might be me
it sounds like that there's two or
something there's so many zombies or
else I've just been sitting here so hey
let me eat you got knocked back on my
sword level one probably the worst skill
oh they're like I'm well approaching
this the worst possible way too by the
way
you never want to go up from below I'm
just doing it for the fun of it and
he'll has everybody doing mm-hmm I can't
hear you but hopefully you're fine
I'm doing quite well why is he gonna
follow me oh what's going on here buy me
out there's yeah this looks like the
same one I did before a few episodes
back if you missed it my game got
corrupted so now I'm reading all these
caves again I'm gonna break my sword
aren't I yeah same one except last time
I got this one I came from up here and
they were all stuck in the hole and this
time I'm stuck in the hole so it's
opposite alright well that was pretty
easy still let's head back to my base
and welcome back to the man cave are you
guys still liking the cave stuff are you
getting bored of it
should I try go exploring sometime or
build something outside let me know what
you think personally I'm still loving
the cave thing but that's just me maybe
we should
do a little bit of variety yet I still
need to go to the nether sometime I need
to find a snow biome need to find a
mushroom biome and I would like to check
out the mountains around here so if you
guys want some exploring we could do
that but anyway check it out since last
episode I have finished
well mostly finished polishing up the
enchanting room and I'm happy with how
it looks
thought it turned out pretty pretty nice
that lab lighting on the sides here our
levers are here this is what looks like
inside and there's a light above here
which kind of highlights the enchanting
table nicely mm-hmm and so with this we
basically have five different levels
with our levers here if all the
bookshelves are up they'll be to here
always got to and then every every lever
you have down as another seven for
maximum of 30 which is needed to get
level 50 enchanting but as you can see I
still don't have all the bookshelves in
here because reads grow so slowly or so
it seems
and maybe we'll take a look up here
quickly wiring is pretty simple on this
thing it just uses a lot of pistons
though I think it was like close to at
28 pistons I believe it's the exact
number anyway that's enchanting room
it's pretty cool okay um I'm gonna play
around with doing some water stuff here
I'm going to fill this in with water and
maybe try connect and eats Road to it or
something yeah so we'll just make a pool
here first to play around with it
I'm going to pull this off and I'm going
to place down some glowing pumpkins to
try keep the grass alive I don't know if
I'm not sure if I want to keep it alive
yet or not but if I choose I want to
then it'll still be alive after we do
this so got that we're going to fill it
in with water
OOP still not used to water stacking on
top of each on top of itself it's a
little weird okay good okay so we have a
pool of water now I want to work on
elevation changes so if I have full like
that I don't know if I can get up there
with a boat you see how difficult it is
so let's make a boat hopefully I have
some planks on me I never checked I do
good so it'll be a mix of still water in
places and eats roads so I'll have a
still water over here and let's see if
we can make it up here if it's difficult
or not
it is very difficult darn it so yeah
this is the one thing I'm a little
concerned about we can make it work
using fence gates but it might look
really ugly
it could also use signs um mm okay well
I'll get some fence gates and try it out
see how it looks and I don't know guys
it doesn't look that great in my opinion
signs would probably look better but
still not great does work really well
though exactly like I wanted it to it's
very easy to go up and down still water
that way but I don't know I think I'm
going to try to avoid elevation changes
if I do still water just because it
doesn't look that great
mmm-hmm okay so I lowered this area down
one block so now they're even so we'll
fill this with water and I'm planning
now to have a drop here free drop down
to a pool below down there I think would
be pretty cool and put these signs here
to hold the water back um I noticed
something too and it's really bugging me
now but this this is a center basically
and that's off-center by one block and
it's just bugging me now hmm no I don't
know if I really like the style of
elevator I think I'm going to stick to
using the solid block styles the four by
four the nice thing about this is it's
three by three so it's smaller but I
don't I don't like how it looks as much
and these floating signs are weird
I don't might rip that out and redo it
okay what was I going to do I had a plan
yeah we got to do the water down here
we'll stick some pumpkins in again I
guess these are mostly just to give
light through the water to three now if
it matters much we'll fill this in
like so
and it's done okay so one issue I'm
having is the pumpkin lighting the light
doesn't seem to spread very evenly when
it's underwater so I might remove them
they kind of kind of stand out too much
I didn't notice it as much up here low
but oh well I'll try to instead light
around any still water I place oh and I
got to be careful to find a nice balance
here I don't want to get too overboard
with the Stillwater stuff otherwise this
whole place will be water just it'll
take some tweaking to get it looking
just the way I want it to but anyway
let's try out the drop here I think
it'll work nicely very cool
okay so we'll have to have a way back up
and eats Road somewhere you can tell I
keep changing my mind about things
because I'm I don't it's different once
you actually do it in it
now I'm thinking have different ways of
doing this
I took a little bit of a break from the
water stuff to mess around with some
minecart stuff here I'm starting to
figure things out the way I want it to
work a little tough to explain what I
want to do I like to keep it as simple
as possible so maybe I'll show you
so basically the way I like my card
systems is you hop in a minecart and you
go alright from point A to point B is
what I would like the thing is if you do
that then the minecart is no longer on
this end it's at this end right so say I
will just walk back here guess what
there's no minecart here so that's a
problem so you need to have two my carts
on the track one at each end the easiest
way to do that is to have two tracks but
I'm trying to make it so there's only
one track to save on rails but that
means we need to do something fancy and
the idea is you would have another one
of these things at this end as well and
so if a minecart comes from this way
this minecart needs to get out of the
way and get sent back right so that's
what this contraption does here this
then pushes it to over here this one
goes up around here and it also aligns
it so it's half on the pressure plate so
when you hop in you boost it and you
also hit the pressure plates is the way
that I'm trying to do this
yeah so I think this is the way I'll do
the minecart track stuff this is good
for only for short travel distances
because if you try to send the minecart
back and it goes to an unloaded chunk I
believe you will have some problems so
this is more like say I want to go from
our creeper face to the cow farm you
know it's maybe a hundred blocks set
something like this up pretty easy this
does take a little bit of space you'll
have to have one of these on each end
but it's not terrible and a lot of a lot
of this stuff can be hidden nicely like
these levers I just have on the surface
but
you could put torches under these power
rails to power them it's wired to be
hidden I did make a little bit of a
mistake here though by the way I did not
come up with this pressure plate idea I
saw a video a long time ago I can't
remember who came up with it first but
it wasn't me
so let's just say that right now but
basically the idea is the cart comes up
and goes into it aligns itself to one of
these iron iron fences or glass panes I
think you could use regular fences to
I'm not sure maybe not and the cart
drops down so it's on the pressure plate
and also on the rail and when when you
hop in the cart you activate the button
which powers a rail and you get sent off
and now it's my thing here there's two
junctions one takes you this or one goes
like this for coming back
this detector here switches this so that
you go straight if you're coming from
this direction
maybe we'll we'll check it out here see
it switches straight so Mayan carts go
straight and then it goes up here it's
this detector and then activates a
piston to get the card out of the way so
that it can fall down safely and then
the cart that gets pushed out of the way
comes back here and gets sent through so
some of my longtime viewers probably
know this already but I don't do a whole
lot of stuff with mine carts usually
especially my LPS and that's basically
because I'm not very good at it to be
honest it's not really my specialty
um but today we're doing it just for fun
yeah I usually make mistakes in that too
when people have to correct me and
today's no exception I realized a few
mistakes I've made here
so one of these I'm sure there's plenty
of mistakes I made but one of these
I need a docking station I forgot to put
a docking station in here because
otherwise it's just going to send me
right back because I'm in the minecarts
when it lands on the pressure plate so
yeah that's one change that needs to be
made so I'll probably have it go up here
the detector rail which will send power
to this rail here which will send a
minecart back and then there'll be a
stop here or something for me to get out
of the Maya cart and I'll probably use
AM 77s nice switch idea for exiting the
minecart and when I hit the me switch
this my cart that's stationary here will
get pushed forward and get set on the
pressure plate like it needs to be so
the other thing I've realized is I don't
need this separate track here and I
don't need this piston it's all overkill
since we need a docking station the cart
will be out of the way so the other cart
that's here can get sent back no problem
doesn't need to go off to the side here
and even with my other setup there I
didn't need it either now that I think
about it yeah very very good so maybe
I'll set up a new prototype to show the
changes that I need to make to this I
messed around with it a bit I think I
think I got it now the way I want it
this is what it does you would go from
one end then this is like where you
would get off and then it goes back up
and gets into position like that
okay and you can have a nice clean
licking end over here for getting on it
you don't hit your head or anything
which is nice oops yeah so we'll send
this back and then I'll demonstrate with
two cards on the track so we need that
to get out of the way so that the this
cart can take its place and that cart
would get sent back to this end and this
end would have a copy of one of these
added as well go like this you would get
off you could either use a me switch
here or just put a pressure plate
somewhere that you'll walk on it or
something
oops should've been standing on it try
it again it's not really clean setup at
the moment but yeah the wire would go to
this which would make the cart move and
it also goes to this one which would get
the other card out of the way and that's
all there is to it so if you ever want
to take a carts all you have to do is
right click and there will always be a
cart here and on the other end as well
so that's kind of my minecart plan for
the cave
you could make this a little bit smaller
yet of course this is just a prototype
and let me know what you guys think I
don't know what I'm going to do about
the boat stuff I don't want it to get
too messy I'll have to think about it
let me know what you think about all
that water too don't want to get too
overboard with it
anyway guys I think I'm in an episode
here today sore it's a little shorter
than normal just been busy this weekend
and have a whole lot of time to record
today
so it's either either this or nothing
for another day so farm looks almost
identical now doesn't it you would never
know it was gone except this part I did
a little different maybe I'll talk
quickly about something some people seem
to think that I'm uploading legendary
episodes instead of LP episodes that's
not the case
basically all the legend a lot about
legendary episodes are pre-recorded I
have them all ready for uploading and I
upload them if I don't have any LP
episodes made so it's you're not getting
legendary instead of and now P you're
getting legendary instead of nothing
when I upload them I'm still missing a
Chester so that's the deal with that
having a lot of fun playing the hostile
series so I'm going to continue with
that I've also been working on map by
was planning on making did a lot the
other day on it it look it's looking
really good good traps it's just turning
out really good so far but there's it's
gonna take a while I only have a few
rooms built in it so far and they're
huge and look awesome but I don't know
there's just so much work to it
hopefully it turns out cool but I'm
rambling so I will say goodbye until
next time hopefully I'll be able to
record more soon and then we'll get more
LP episodes thanks for watching take
care guys