yeah well not too happy about this this
is what I saw when I logged in so if you
don't know here let me get my boots on
at least yeah it's not quite the same
but yeah if you don't know I've had the
Alex character model for a long time
since Alex was introduced a few months
ago Mojang maiden a second character
model with thinner arms so there are
three pixels wide instead of four like
Steve has and Alex e'er has a different
default skin too which is I believe a
girl right or a guy with long hair
anyway and when they introduced Alex
they randomly gave people that's that
character model and I was one of the
lucky people and for a while I couldn't
change it I think I tend now but I can't
figure out how to so yay I think I have
to like when I go to the site it says
I'm Steve where has Steve selected by
default so I think I have to re-up load
my skin maybe and select Steve I don't I
don't quite understand it but yeah if
skin servers ever go down or if my
internet is down like it is currently I
become Alex so I'll have to try figure
this out okay so let's jump into the
future a few hours together my
Internet's back up I got my normal skin
on I did do the upload or irie uploaded
my skin while Steve was selected and a
couple of hours have passed and yes my
arms are still three pixels wide so I'm
still Alex I don't know what to do
there's no it's very strange there's no
like confirmed changes button on the
form so yeah for ever and Alex I guess
oh man well let's forget about that
let's get into our episode here I have
worked on this Simon Says well it's
actually I've been informed it's called
Simon not Simon Says
I had a Simon game when I was younger
and everybody always called it
Simon Says so that's just what I assumed
it was but apparently it's called Simon
the memory game and been trying to solve
the next problem we're having here so we
have this memory right here it'll be
like 30 to 40 droppers when we're done
when you start out the game the sequence
starts at one right you just got to
remember one thing then it builds up to
2 3 4 or 5 all the way up to however
many is the end of the game right the
thing is when we're at the very starts
when it's at 1 2 3 4 or whatever the
chain is very short and there's a lot of
blank spots like a lot of these droppers
will be empty and when we want to like
starts the sequence over we have to move
those items through all those empty
droppers and since we have to do this
thing where we delay all the droppers
like 3 or 4 seconds to delay them all
you do the math on that 30 times 3
seconds for example it's gonna take a
minute and a half to do one sequence or
to run through one sequence at the very
start of the game that's a problem it
technically will work but I'm gonna call
that a fail so I have to had to come up
with a new method and I experimented
with it and creative it was going good
for a while but I hit another wall
unfortunately but we'll just check that
out real quick and then we'll probably
do something else so let's jump into
creative so this is my new IDE whoa I
don't know if you heard that but my
elbow just bumped my glass of water and
it it was it was spitting it almost fell
dumped all over my desk
mmm-hmm I should move my record key yeah
so this is what I came up with everybody
I decided to use hoppers instead of
droppers the advantage they have is
items can flow freely through them the
disadvantage is I have to very precisely
lock them otherwise items are gonna
bunch up or skip spots or stuff like
that so this is the other thing though
that's really cool about this I came up
with this idea here so if we for example
had red clay in here it would flow to
the front here as soon as soon as it
enters here this detects it and then
locks the whole thing alright so that
stops items from flowing and then I have
like a release gate here when I push the
button it allows one item to move up a
spot it's time very precisely and if
it's the end of the chain like like that
was because it's a very first one it
will go all the way around and then when
it gets back to the front again it stops
automatically so it's really really cool
I thought I was on to something if we do
red red blue yellow Alice or green into
as an experiment we press this red jumps
ahead one spots
and that should be Oh see it should have
been red red but it jumped it skipped a
spot so we have issues with this design
yeah so basically the problem with this
is just the way items move through the
hoppers like we have we have it all
locking and releasing the items at the
exact same time you would think the
items would move through here equally
right that's not the way it works so if
we for example have red green blue the
game might actually decide to move the
green first because it has to pick one
of them to start with even though
they're all moving in the exact same
frame in the game logically it has to
pick one and it might decide to move the
green first and then it goes into the
second spot and then the red will maybe
move but now we have this empty spot and
the next time we move the blue which
will be here when it moves it's going to
go into that front spot this green one's
gonna get stuck there forever or until
something else messes up so we need to
precisely time these hoppers that so
they activate in the right order so I
came up with this and it also has a
problem
so like non-stop rain in this world I
tell you so it's red red blue green
yellow yeah you got it precisely times
every time we press this and moves ahead
one spot so red got me red red red red
blue red red blue yellow and I forget
already yeah
now yellow is at the end should be green
yellow
we have five items in here I pressed
this four times so red red blue green
last one is yellow when it's at the end
of the chain or the end of the sequence
it'll reset to the start and skip all
those empty spots so just take some
moments way less than a minute and a
half though it's like five to ten
seconds and then it's it should be red
red blue green yellow again but for some
reason in this spot it decides to bunch
them up even though it's basically
exactly the same here as the rest of the
thing as far as I can tell there's no
errors in timing see 4 3 2 1 4 3 2 1 4 3
2 1 yeah so it's for some reason the
game decides right here to mess it up I
don't know exactly what's going on and
I'm tired of thinking about it for today
so we will just forget about this for
right now this is the idea I want to
play around with today though I think
this is gonna be fun so this is an idea
for a sheep farm we're gonna go try
build this at the amplified base
something like this the idea is sheep
can actually eat grass when they're in
the mine carts and on a track so we we
can keep these guys on a track and have
them go around on a loop and when they
get to a spot to shoot them up like this
and cheer them alright everybody so here
we are at the amplified bass and I
looked around for a while trying to find
a good spot for it I think I might put
it up over here it has a very small
footprint like we could just we just
need like a 3x3 hole basically and then
we can hide the rest of it underground
like where the sheep actually stay so we
might put it here the only downside of
building here is how do we get the sheep
into the farm when we're way up in the
mountain that's gonna be the toughest
part of this whole thing unless we build
it down lower but I didn't really see
any
spots that stood out to me so I think
we'll put it here so my plan is we'll
probably pick a new spot darn it's the
tract is there haha yeah we we gotta
find a new spot okay well I've been
running around this place for like 15
minutes trying to find a spot it
actually I don't know it's really tough
to find a spot around here because it's
all open there's not a lot of walls or
corners around but I picked this spot
over here I think it'll work
it doesn't look very good right now
because the area's undeveloped but we'll
try we'll try and make it work so we got
a 3x3 hole and then what we'll do is
we'll like build the actual sheep farm
down here this is where they'll stay and
minecart track will take them to to this
spot and then we will have a oh where my
pistons oh well have a slime block
launcher thing I must have put them in
the chest up here and this actually
probably isn't gonna be very difficult
if I'm not mistaken we might not need to
control it at all like we could just
have mine carts all over the place
bouncing around and they should make
their way to the launcher you know I
think I might have planned this wrong I
might need to go up one more block we
should figure this out for sure actually
so let me know I need a minecart
at least I think I do maybe not let's
just see how high this launch is that's
that doesn't seem right wait a second
huh that seems very short I'm gonna get
a minecart just to be sure let's see
let's get back up here I did bring mine
carts this is very you know it would be
nice here is some ladders
never underestimate ladders they are
amazing
alright now let's grab one of these I
just want to make sure the sheep get
launched high enough before we build
this whole thing otherwise it's gonna be
a big problem so I want the minecart to
go above the surface here at least oh
yeah I think that was perfect actually
so we actually need to build up one
block I think okay here let's take a
moment to figure out how this is gonna
work so I made sort of a loop here we're
gonna have about 10 to 20 sheep down
here I figure and basically they'll go
into minecarts up to the launcher
they'll get launched up and then we
don't want to just send them back
because then they'll be in the front of
the line we want them to to like get out
of the way right because we'll shear
them and they need time for the the wool
to regrow and we want the next sheep to
come up that has wool so we'll probably
want like a piston to push the minecarts
out of the way onto the second track
over here
well not set in the track but you know
what I mean push them out of the way get
out of the way sheep you have no wool we
don't want you anymore
type of thing all right and we'll need a
detector rail to figure out when to
launch the sheep no I hate when this
happens
stuck oh there we go
okay so we'll probably run the wire just
underneath here for right now this is
just temporary
don't don't give me a hard time you know
I do this thing where I I put my what
redstone wiring on stone brick and if I
don't do it now people like Esau you
broke your rule go fix it and even if
it's tip
rewiring sometimes I get that and it's
like you know I choose to do this you
can't tell me what to do with my
redstone wiring okay so that launched it
up oh but then it didn't you know it
might need more delay let's try that
again
if we gave it more time oh that time it
was good actually because we want it to
false perfectly straight down again if
possible okay maybe we wonder if we
bumped it the first time or why didn't
it work okay that's perfect
that's perfect so if there's a sheep in
there this piston why should push them I
think because can we test that if I'm in
here man this is where they really need
help ta because no that did not want to
move me that's gonna be a problem isn't
it I'll have to think about this alright
so this is going to be a bit tricky we
can move the mic hurt if it's down there
the problem is if we put a piston there
we have another another issue the slime
block doesn't go down it sticks to that
piston so that's not gonna work we got a
you got to move it up at least one like
I wanted the thing is we're gonna have
to time this so that as the minecart is
falling down it'll push it in midair I
think which is not going to be fun or
maybe it'll be easy I don't know we'll
see so let's let's just try get some
delay going on this circuit see we got a
run let's try about a second delay see
if that works
oops yeah and we'll run that just to did
I just break that with my shovel
that's stoned am I seeing things
I thought for sure that's what just
happened okay oh we need way longer
delay we need like three or four seconds
okay this is pretty cool actually I
thought we would have to be extremely
precise with the timing on this move but
what happens is the minecart seems to
bounce on the slime block quite a bit so
it's like in-between two blocks and we
can yeah have a lot of flexibility here
actually not that it matters much I just
thought was interesting oh that's too
short if we do that we want as quick as
possible of still yeah so that's about
right and we'll want to push it onto a
downward slope track if possible so now
this this man I really wish these slime
blocks are so sticky they stick to
everything like if I have a track here
it's gonna get stuck on that now all
right
yeah okay so I decided to go down we got
a slope track there it should bring them
up here and then we want it to go back
into the loop so let's run this over to
here and oh we need another one of these
okay so now we got to do this BAM
minecart test if we have a bunch of mine
carts going here what happens when they
start bumping into each other because
with just one it's perfectly fine okay
so let's get a few more going I'm kind
of hoping they'll look just like bounced
around and everything would be okay that
is not the case so we will have to set
up some sort of gate to block them I
don't think this is gonna work but we'll
try it this is very simple I just threw
a piston down here when they go over the
detector rail this will go up and it
should stop anymore from going through
for at least a second or two that work
oh that's what happened here oh is this
sticking to something oh I should have
put that block there yes ah ah you know
I was trying to fill in all the the
holes and make it look nice and then
breaks everything let's try again so
yeah this is activating way too soon
and it's messing up the minecart let's
try it again here I moved it one block
away from the detector rail search and
it mess up the minecarts good good very
good okay good
now let's spam my carts and see if we
have issues
so they will get stuck on that I'm kind
of hoping if we get a bunch of mine
carts bouncing around
they will bump it free they don't seem
to be moving it though oh there we go
Oh mmm cuz keep in mind there's gonna be
20 Mike Hertz bouncing around oh this is
getting nasty I might need to put a lot
more control in this whole thing
I was hoping like we could be pretty
pretty loose with it and it would work
but they're bunching up and they're
stacking on top of each other and
although if there was a sheep in that
minecart that wouldn't have happened
there but because this minecart would
have bumped into it and bounced back all
right we got a few things to work out
here I am unfortunately out of time to
record for today though so I'm going to
wrap up this episode if you have ideas
let me know but we might need to do this
a bit more fancy a little bit more
well-thought-out by the looks of it
maybe even pick up the the sheep with
mine carts and drop them off in places
I'm not sure or make a holding pen for
each sheep and then and then pick them
up nicely and move them one at a time or
with precise timing I'm not sure because
I guess it doesn't really make sense to
have them moving around here all the
time either it would get annoying
listening to the mine carts all the time
whoa I almost never see that happen and
it just happened when I start recording
here that is awesome
like I'll walk by and I'll see the
flaming arrows but to actually see them
shoot out of the eyes is very rare yes
so here we go guys I picked out two
comments for today says the first one
says etho it would probably just be
easier to predetermine the entire
sequence before each game this is in
regards to the Simon
the memory you liked have one dropper
with one of each color below a hopper
and activate them all for tea or however
many turns you wants when I Oh Oh
where's this name
no its name's not on here it's no other
page I'm sorry is this is Patrick that
said this I don't know why your name
didn't show up I'm sure I'm sure I put
it in yes let's blame something besides
my own faults yeah it's copy paste
doesn't work in this for some reason I
don't know I I was sure I put it in no
this is a great idea Thank You Patrick I
my jaw dropped when I read this it's
like oh yeah why didn't I think of that
so this is probably what I'll end up
doing I think it's great thank you for
that that's like instead of like
figuring out after every sequence a new
random thing just figured out all
beforehand and that way you don't have
to worry about it later which i think is
a great idea second comment EXO door
hundreds nearing bump up ah yes oh man
I can't believe we're almost at 400
episodes here that is a big number 400
episodes usually I like to do something
special every hundred episodes as well
so typically it's like a world tour or
something but we just did one of those
recently if I'm not mistaken so we need
ideas for episode 400 and I would prefer
it if you told me what to do it's I
don't like figuring out what to do every
every hundred episodes you guys tell me
this time
okay I'm gonna look at the comments if
you have ideas there's anything crazy or
special you want me to do for episode
400 let me know otherwise I'll have to
try think of something because I can't
just like world tours are easy I like
doing world tours but if we just did one
it doesn't feel quite right and since we
always do them maybe they're not special
anymore I don't know but yeah that's
gonna do it for today guys thank you for
watching I hope you
joyed and i'll see you in the next
episode take care bye bye