[Music]
hello everyone this is etho ah did you
miss me did you come on it's okay you
can admit it just say it say it say it
say it now come on say you miss me do it
now oh no no it's okay really it's only
been a week since my last LP and I've
been up blowing other videos too but
that's like the longest drought my LP
has ever had a whole week it's like the
foundations of Minecraft have been
rocked the last few weeks with all these
new patches but we're good to go again
here I think we're gonna we're going to
start fresh we're in a new world I was
waiting for the official beta 1.9 to
come out before I made a new world but
we got the pre-release number two today
and it'll probably be a week or so maybe
longer
who knows before we get the official one
and I'm tired waiting this this looks
good now - they haven't changed anything
with the terrain in this patch and
hopefully it'll be more stable in the
future and even if we do have trouble
we'll just go to a new area and start
over or something the main reason why I
restarted from our last world was
because we got two hard hits within
three episodes number one that terrain
generation change so that we would have
lines where the new generation takes
place that's tolerable it just looks
ugly but the other main thing was we got
these like greyish dark green swamp
biomes now and the main reason I chose
that location last time was because I
like the bright green grass and trees
and everything and that got killed
okay no more and now in the game there
really is no green grass which is very
very strange because that's the main
color of grass in my area like where I
live it's green
we don't have grass like this and only
place you'll really find green grass is
these like messed up areas where the
swamp biome borders are and there's a
few areas where it's kind of teal ish or
whatever but not really any bright green
grass like there used to be but yeah
this is my world this is the seed look
at it look at it it's gone okay you can
check that out if you want but I would
recommend not checking out so that
exploring is a little more fun when we
do it here this is the actual spawn area
right here and I went through about 20
seeds today looking for a new world and
this one look great to me because number
one we have I got stop numbering things
for one thing we have the mountain
biomes there we have swamp here desert
there and we have forest there so right
off the bat we have four biomes which is
cool and of course mountains my new
favorites and right in front of us
there's this big ravine which is cool I
believe I saw I tracked down yeah right
there so we have a stronghold nearby
this should be good looks like a good
world did I say strong once I meant to
ban in Minecraft I actually haven't even
seen a stronghold yet like I've never
found one myself I've seen other people
find them in videos and that but I never
found one myself yet I'm looking forward
to doing a bit of exploring yeah so
we're gonna go Oh pumpkins over there
and we got one of those kick-ass trees
up there cool world very cool I want to
head to the forest though it's the
greenest grass so that's where I always
go this is yeah I guess this is a color
of it
um yeah pre-release came out today
number two we got breeding and all that
a few other changes we got hardcore mode
I tried that today I had no mobs
spawning so it's glitched a little bit
I'm guessing whatever you had your game
set up before hardcore mode is what what
the game lacks should be set on but it's
a fun feature when it gets working
properly we'll be able to like one one
death in your game over world it's
deleted it's a pretty pretty fun idea so
in this new world I have kind of a new
plan I think it's going to be fun idea
let me know what you guys think of it
I'm going to start my first base
underground we're going to live
underground not exclusively or anything
but just to get started yeah like like
this looks perfect yeah this is this is
exactly what I was looking for a nice
wide opening so we're going to live
underground and the plan is to make our
underground world epic and have like
mechanical stuff fit underground and to
move grass underground make farms that
kind of stuff you know I think it'll be
fun because Underground's in cave
systems kind of like a biome in itself
and in my opinion it's the best changes
in the new patches is the cave systems
there are a lot more interesting now so
I would love to live underground for for
at least the beginning of this
check this out we got iron already and
that's other thing I need resources so
it may as well build underground because
that's where we'll find them right and
we'll run into enemies and it'll be
exciting and stuff like that let's get
on to poops oh it is on bright ok the
other thing is I don't know if it's just
me but like ever since I've been playing
my draft like I could build a tree farm
above ground somewhere and it would be
cool but then I would take the exact
same tree farm and build it underground
and somehow although all of a sudden it
would just be like 10 times cooler just
because it's underground for some reason
so that's another reason I want to build
underground stuff just seems cooler
somehow even though it might be the same
thing now we got more caves here oh we
get coal cool but it might just be me
but for some reason I think it's going
to be a lot of fun to build underground
alright so we got a bunch of coal now we
got a fair bit of iron and it looks like
this cave system goes deep and is pretty
expansive I don't know how well you can
see on YouTube right now but yeah this
is going to work out just fine I like
the spot please tell me it's not dark is
the yang dark oh it's getting dark no we
don't have any food yet oh boy we don't
even have tools yet that's the hard
thing about doing LP and that because
when I started this the Sun was already
pretty high in the sky after I looked
around and everything so we lost a big
part of the day oops we should get some
food though where I'm not going to last
long
a tools in our axe
another thing about building in cave
systems is I'll probably build with the
cave system instead of you know my
normal style if I'm in a flat area I
tend to build really symmetrical because
it's more efficient usually but it
doesn't look as good generally oh boy
yeah it's night we have no food to mark
the spot sweets okay let's get some
trees I'm surprised I haven't seen a
single animal yet and a little bit
worried with the new breeding we'll be
able to build animal farms underground -
like there's no no reason we can't have
animals underground first creeper take
them down before you tell spaz where I
am aha oh nice cheese around mountains
back there - pretty nice world all the
mountains now though they're really
amazing that's alright we needed some
soil what I did one time actually when I
was having trouble with my game I like
downgraded back to one point seven point
three and I played the world that
generated and one point eight with the
mountains and all that and wow it looks
amazing when you downgrade when you have
the brakeman grass and everything it
just looks so much better the mountains
and all that if you add two trees to
them it would be an incredible look even
more incredible than it is already
because the mountains are a little plain
you know there's
not much to them there's barely any
trees there's no flowers hardly and the
grass is blue it looks so good when it's
bright green did I ever mention I like
breaking grass mmm where are you oh he's
right above hey oh there's two
hey I need a bow tell your buddy oh you
got it critical hit on me oh ah oh yeah
we got eyeballs nut I think I read you
can eat them there's a bunch of new
items in the game now a lot of them
don't do anything though he can't eat
them oh oh oh good it's not a long
poison he'll heal I didn't know it
poisoned you I guess it makes kite no it
doesn't make sense does it not at all
why would eating spider poison well hmm
I just
spiders are poisonous but not all
spiders not these ones the ones
underground are the tiny ones
the tiny little buggers let's make a
furnace cool a little base camp here
yeah
all right maybe I'll chop down some
trees and stuff off-camera while the
night went really quick that's already
day so yeah maybe we'll just mess around
up here you're a bit of wood now
books for a little bit see what's around
us and I'm really I really want to find
some animals for food and I want to make
sure that they're actually spawning
today oh okay
hey you just made me feel a lot better
you know that thank you
yeah I was worried they weren't spawning
sometimes when you started in the world
in the skiing it's like like I named
this the same as my last one and
sometimes when you do that the previous
world doesn't fully get deleted and
stuff will get messed up in your new
world so I'm always worried about that
oh so we have mountains there and
they're cool what was I doing
Oh floating get some floating stuff run
aah
oh cool we got pumpkins that's another
four ouch that's another new change as
well you can make pumpkin seeds from
pumpkins
kyoool
very nice very nice
and we have the new while the old camera
back we get f5 you got the smooth camera
actually seems a lot smoother now I
don't know if I like that oh ah and we
have this one too but I'm distracted now
check out that dungeon wait wait we
gotta do one thing got to do we gotta
try this
wait what's coming to me burn up eat
creeper aha
I want to try yeah it does work that's
awesome
I love it oh it's so hard to control
them do any of you have motion sickness
look away I can't believe it works on on
this OH
okay enough of that hahaha get some pigs
all right we got to check out this
dungeon OOP it's a little bit laggy for
some reason when you go on the slow
camera we whoops no we don't want to do
that we want to do this and we should
eat something
Rahmi there's always a good choice good
hitter egg yeah we found the dungeon
already that's that's always a good sign
creeper over there
Oh spider - sweet really hard to get -
it's up high I got robbed there's no
chest why why no chest why I'm sad now
oh well we'll find more just amazing
these chickens are freaking me out I
took you get creepers now let's go get
some pumpkins
chicken chicken is like my favorite meat
because it's really easy to make new
chickens with eggs I don't worry about
them not reappearing okay let's try it
out yeah we get pumpkin seeds
lots of pumpkin seeds that'll work out
good because you make jack-o'-lantern
jack-o'-lanterns out of these with
torches and that's perfect if you're
doing anything underwater otherwise you
got to use glowstone in that is a pain
in the butt to collect sweet okay maybe
we'll go check out the desert if we can
find it make sure it's to our liking
yep
so I realized something today I've been
playing this game for over a year now I
think I got it back in late August last
year originally when I started playing
it I started playing it because I heard
a lot of people talking about it for one
thing and so I tried it out I went to
and placed the creative mode through the
through the my browser and that it was
it was cool you know I like looking
around what people built in all that but
then I started building a few things in
my own that I made like one of the first
things I made was a giant Scott Pilgrim
pixel art thing as probably 80 blocks
tall or so with its head cut off because
I didn't know about the limit to the sky
limit and I knew griefing was a big
problem but like within I went to eat
and when I came back it someone had
already grieved it within 15 minutes of
me finishing it and I repaired it like
five or ten minutes later someone else
grieved it and I repaired it another
5-10 minutes briefed again and is like
yeah this game is cool and everything
but I can't stand like why would I ever
want to build something if everything I
built is going to get wrecked so this
game didn't appeal to me too much at
first but then I found out that there is
this embedded or not embedded what was
it called in in instead now I got a
check one sec in devmode INF de vie I
found out there was that mode so I did
more research on it found out it was
replaced with survival mode which is
what we have
today still and that really appealed to
me because I learned that you could play
single-player I wouldn't have to worry
about people wrecking my stuff all the
time and not only that there's like
health system bad guys you can make
weapons and stuff the crafting really
appealed to me that's when I really
became interest in the game but I wasn't
sure at that point if I was going to
bother buying it like the only way you
could play it is if you bought it well
that grass looks weird over there let's
kind of decide if I should bother buying
it you know or if it's one of those
games where I would get bored of it
within a day so I went like I was
familiar with LP series at that time
I've watched protonjon and ezra blade
those are my two favorite at the time
very good
LPS so I thought I'd check my era
YouTube personnel P's about minecraft
and see what was it looking for grass
believe that that's so ugly cocoa brown
weird I'm getting hungry
let's try to figure out if I should buy
the game so I checked YouTube for some
LPS now a lot of you guys got into this
game watching seananners not me nope I
wish I wish I found seananners over back
at spawn cool uh I found some LP by a
guy he had like 100 views or something
and it was the worst LP I've ever seen
for this game like even to date it was
terrible the guy spent the whole time
hiding in a little hole he dug in the in
a hillside and I was trying to figure
out like what the scheme is about he
talked a little bit about the crafting
and then he like slowly poked his head
out the door and something shot at him
and I was like what was that what was
that and he's just freaking out like he
want to go outside he refused to go
outside and he just spent the whole
episode mining and then he came to a
cave system as like oh this looks real I
was like that looks really interesting
but he's like oh no I don't want to go
down there and he closed off and then he
ended the episode so he did absolutely
nothing the whole episode and it's like
that's when I decided to get the game
because I realized the only way I would
ever figure out what this team's about
is if I bought it myself and played it
and I didn't like it or I would get
bored of it and it turns out I didn't
get bored of it because I'm still
playing it today
so that's the story about how I got into
this game I gotta find my base I went
this way nobody's ever asked me how I
start playing so I thought I'd share it
just in case anyone cared and it's been
over a year now this game is over two
years old believe it or not I was
looking at some of the changes to the
game on the wiki it's come a long ways
pretty cool where's my freaking base
camp I don't want to be lost I hate it
when I get lost and I can't make a map
and I'm out of food
ah okay I'm going to be wandering for a
while I'll be back in a second
oh here it is cool perfect timing is
this getting dark cook up our chicken
and maybe we will get started here on
our new home
cool okay I'll be back in a second
all right we're back just upgrade to
iron tools partially and we should go
check out what's in our cave here yeah
so I want to bring the grass down here
so we should work on that too we don't
have a whole lot of soil at the moment
where yet okay doesn't really bother me
getting hit because it just recovers
wait where's my soil get down here it'll
take time but that's fine still see what
we got yeah there's a sharp drop-off
here
just good that means we'll get down to
bedrock quick I'm gonna bug me looks
like it goes down here too maybe we'll
check out the sharp drop-off first say
hello to mr. creeper oh you know he had
a buddy over hey Sam
we better shut that off on unless the
ocean ride the wave
or is that skilled in Oh surprise my new
home here guys
oh this is perfect nice and open
that's what I wanted you are being
evicted this is mild cool yes the will
run grass down here we'll make it look
pretty that's an important thing I don't
know if you guys can see yet but it
looks really cool because the cave
systems now they just keep going and
going so it's not like we're going to
hit it dead end at least I hope not
nice and open here though this will be
my main area we're fairly close to
scoops light it up we're yet see above
must be hmm I don't see him
he must be above Morty's over here I
like branches off a few different places
Oh
abandoned mineshaft awesome oh dang is
that what I think it is now not yet
the spider though is making me worried
yeah this would be nice so let me know
what you guys think about the
underground idea I think it'll be fun
might be a little hard to envision it at
the moment but I think when I work on it
a bit you'll get a better idea what I'm
intending and so will I will see if it
works I do have a few oh there is
no you said it I do have a few big
projects planned for this world but I'll
need resources first
yeah we need bones like big big projects
majorly resource intensive I'll talk
about more later I think we're getting
close end of this episode though and I
think one thing I'll try to like not at
first but later I'll try to not use
torches in this underground base will
try to use lava for lighting and maybe
pumpkins and that just to give it a
different feel more yeah more indirect
lighting will make it look better I
think be like the 404 challenge but it's
not the forward route for a challenge
just like you know we are allowed to go
to the surface and we will be cool so
yeah I'm going to try get the grass down
here we'll plant the tree - I don't have
a tree we'll do it next time I'll call
it an end for today thank you for
watching I hope you enjoy the new world
I expect it will be a very good series I
hope