[Music]
hello everybody this is Ito welcome back
guys to another episode I am practicing
my tightrope walking I'm over a hundred
meters in the air above concrete one
wrong step one bad somersault and I am
out of here so we're in the nether above
the gold farm I'm getting a bunch of
zombie pigman to spawn and we're gonna
go kill them this is kind of fancy and
I'm just imagining staring off into the
sunset but the sense that has been
destroyed and he's like looking into the
future of some terrible planets with no
Sun or something never mind
okay so I've been up here for about
20-25 minutes and we've kind of already
established I can't be up here for
longer than 10 to 15 minutes because
you're actually let's try throw an ender
pearl let's see what happens if it lags
because last time we were up here for
like 10 minutes we had 500 Sambi Pigman
in the gold farm and I was getting 5
frames per second while recording so
that's about the limit of what we can
handle but I am stress testing because I
am on my new computer oh yeah my new
computer I'm finally using it this is
the first episode of Minecraft I'm
recording with it so I might sound a
little different things might look a
little different I don't know how this
is gonna turn out to be honest because
new computer new settings new hardware
new everything might throw a few things
out of whack but one thing I can tell
you this computer has got some power it
is silky smooth
let's see how much leg we'd get with
this mini Pigman I'm really curious if
you can handle I haven't found anything
that dropped the blow 30 frames per
second yet okay it did it we are at 20
frames per second
oh except when I look down it got a
whole lot worse let's jump down oh it
was fight until I looked out looking
down at all the Pigman was where I went
wrong here let's turn the sound down Oh
sky is you see that it was lagging the
moon was jumping still not too bad a
framerate though I can still do stuff
with how many do we got oh oh man
1100 zombie pigmen give or take that is
a new record right there probably
shouldn't do that many ever again though
oh yeah man that is so many mobs as soon
as I looked away it's fine like look at
this frame right now we're up to about
[Laughter]
oh-oh-oh
just got really led you Jen did it drop
a bunch of XP I want to do a bunch of
stress tests to see how the new computer
handles compared to the old one
all right we are going to kill them this
might be a big leg bomb let's find out
up to eight frames per second here did
we lose a bunch oh we didn't lose like a
hundred or so all right here we go
I threw it give it a second oh maybe it
wasn't in my inventory let's get another
one oh there it goes oh yeah I pushed
the limits a little too far that's not
good that's not good all right so 2025
minutes
it looks still a little too long it
turns out oh man okay I got to get my
stuff back now now we're actually pretty
close oh all right I might need to stop
recording for a sec be right back
oh man I wish a recorded that hey here's
a random idea let's go visit emerald
village everybody Wow let's see houses
are still here very nice
oh there's XP on the ground and a whole
bunch of stuff uh so I I couldn't record
that it was pretty bad yes
there was 2,000 entities with all the XP
orbs so I went to pick them all up and
and just deal with this situation
I recovered most of my dear except for
my feather falling boots and maybe a few
other things I haven't noticed yet but I
enderpearls back to where the man cave
is yeah let's just make sure we get this
all before we use some stuff because
it's been a few minutes already oh wait
what was that
is that a squid I heard something fall I
thought I picked this up already so I
got all like all the XP I had like 50
levels on me got most my stuff back
except for the boots and they're all
back to the man cave and I fall through
the ender pearl hits one of those sides
just randomly by chance and the one
moment I don't have my feather falling
on splat all 50 levels gone so yeah
that's that's why we're down here okay
so we learnt don't do 25 minutes let's
try 15 minutes because I do actually
need some gold and XP and I'm gonna have
to enchant some new boots now it looks
like so back to the gold farm so I had a
bunch of these books on me too when I
died there that has gonna use to make a
tree those chop it today before before I
lost my boots and all that one of the
things I lost though was the unbreaking
3 book it looks like which is pretty
pretty sad those are hard to come by and
they're really really useful so we're
gonna come check if we have any in our
stash here at the Enderman farm
respiration I'm pretty sure I must have
a few here at least feather falling
they're falling come on at least one yes
there's one just one c5 Wow all the
enchanting I did here there's only one
unless I used it up already just one
okay okay guys so I was up there 15
minutes we're gonna go in for round 2
should be able to handle it this time
I'm pretty sure man take some diamonds
with me to make an axe oh did that make
one already okay I didn't know I made
one of these already well it looks like
I started one I don't have this
sharpness on it huh all right well that
simplifies things a bit I must have done
that a long time ago I would have
remembered maybe even before I made the
one on line crack alright that did the
gold farm I gotta say guys we might need
to make some additions here today cuz I
did not like how that one guy Kamikaze
does and killed us there's usually one
guy that while there's a few up there
isn't there because I got the the ground
next to the portal but there's usually
one or two guys up at the top there and
sometimes they will jump down and attack
me which is why I died there get lost
man get out of here
nobody likes you alright this is much
more manageable though
so what do we got we got oh wait we're
at 800 here
this is about the limit I would say
let's not go over this 800 it's pretty
tolerable if I'm looking away I did 30
frames per second if I look at them it's
more like 8 just too bad as long as I'm
still function all those chickens in
there alright this time
I don't think of die go die alright here
we go here we go how many got left now
we're still losing a bunch I wonder I
might have to change this to some reason
we're still losing a bunch when we
suffocate them with one we should it be
awesome oh and they didn't all die what
is going on take care of the rest of the
guys here so yeah new computer it is a
i7 4770k processor it is NVIDIA GeForce
GTX 770 graphics card and the 3 terabyte
hard drive in this thing 32 gigs of ram
it's pretty sweet I gotta say
but I've had the computer for about a
month and I just got around to setting
up for recording I've been using as a
secondary computer like I have a dual
monitor setup and I have one computer on
one and the other on that the other
monitor and see what do we want to do
here and let's make a bunch of sharpness
books but haven't made this jump to
record until just now because I was
having a big problem as much as I like
this computer it does have one really
big really annoying problem that I was
just
fearing terribly before it arrived
whenever I get a new computer I'm always
worried is it gonna be loud how loud is
a fan gonna be first time I started up
it was just fine I loved it
next time I started it up I don't know
what I changed like I I just I probably
downloaded a bunch of drivers and stuff
and changed a bunch of things but the
next time I started it up soon as
Windows started the fan started just
going in
you know it's just running at full speed
on the graphics card for some reason see
what am I doing here sharpness 5 you
gotta hurry here that stuff's gonna do
spawn well now that we got this let's
make a new pair of good boots for me so
we can get protection 3 you get that the
protection for oh I need more XP yeah so
for some reason the fan just started
running like crazy 100% all the time
making so much racket like it was loud
enough where I couldn't really record
with the computer which is why I haven't
been recording with it
ok we kind of got a hurry here before
our stuff T spawn so I just went ahead
and make made these boots and and spent
some of this up but yeah a lot of people
have been saying I can't believe etho
hasn't been using his computer he's
headed for a month and he's not using it
if it was me I would be using it right
away and it's like yeah I i admits part
of its been because i've been putting it
off but honestly I've spent at least 30
hours setting this thing up already so I
set up as a secondary computer so I
could like download programs and set
them up while a I continue to use my
main one just kind of oh that's it's
good just kind of had on the side and
every now and then I just poke in and
download a new program so now you got to
download all the programs it's not like
you just load things off CD and you have
it all there ready ready to go you know
you gotta you gotta download everything
now which it takes a long time on my
connection because most programs or
games are over a dig to which is just
like oh boy so that took a while but
half of the time setting it up like
those 30 hours half of that has probably
been trying to figure out this fan speed
issue I've downloaded like 10 different
programs - yeah these are good by the
way these are really good
to monitor and change the fan speed so
the the the GPU that the core
temperature of the graphics card
is like room temperature it's like 30
degrees Celsius all the time the fan is
keeping it plenty cool running at full
speed
it doesn't need to run at full speed oh
man look at all this gold very good
let's go to the man cave and I'll show
you some cool things that we can do now
that we have this super awesome computer
so from what I've heard there's it might
be something called what's it called
what's it called GPU boost 2.0 which
comes with the lot of the 700 series
Nvidia cards that if the the fan is
running under 1300 rpm when windows
starts it will it thinks that it's in
danger of overheating because the fans
not running quick enough so it kicks in
and takes control and sets it to maximum
speed and over overrides all settings
you set for it so that might be what's
happening from what I've looked into it
but not too many people seem to be
having the same problem as me
yeah check this out I don't lag anymore
when I go in the storage room how cool
is this remember that a giant like spike
I'd always get when I would walk over
these fresher plates or when I'd switch
this crafting table used to always have
giant legs bike nuts anymore so awesome
let's go to the lab and see if we can
run that without lagging because that
was like the worst thing in my world
actually
so yeah the solution I have found so far
it's not really a solution it's more of
a band-aid fix which lets me use the
computer now without the fan getting
forced into 100% speed is I gotta unplug
the computer switch the power off hit
the power button after it's unplugged
and that turns the light on even though
it has no power and then I push it one
more time to turn the light off and that
light drains the battery or something I
don't know
clears the memory I'm not exactly sure
what that does but when I started up the
next time the fan doesn't go into super
100% moated it it's controlled
automatically like it should be
depending on how hot the CPU gets the
fan speeds up if it needs to which is
the way it should work but it goes into
crisis mode or something and I've spent
like 15 hours trying to figure this out
and from what I understand there's no
way to get rid of this GPU boost 2.0
it's built into the graphics card unless
I do like a BIOS flash and risk wrecking
my graphics card and it also voids the
warranty on it so yeah not too happy
about that
but I'm gonna try a few other things
maybe I can find another solution look
at this man no leg no leg I love it like
this was unrunnable before while
recording and there's I'm getting no
jitters at all from it so that is this
is a crazy wish I got some jitters here
just a little bit but there's a lot of
redstone going on down below there when
that thing is ready the main thing
actually that made me decide hey you
know what I really gotta get my new
computer going well as last episode when
I was recording over here by the tree
farm I don't know if you guys noticed
but that whole episode was like 20
frames per second for some reason I
think it was my computer's like Kat was
having trouble with item frames so
because of all these item frames on the
map I was just getting terrible frame
rates over in this area even when I
wasn't recording like 20 frames per
second around here now
everything is super smooth and wonderful
but I decided you know what it's done I
got to get my new computer running cuz
that was very frustrating I spent like
four hours here at 20 frames per second
and that is just like gave me a headache
it was so bad
this is a little example of what I did
with the roof by the way kind of cool I
haven't finished it yet um hopefully
soon I will get to that and yeah so I
can use it it's only a problem when I
boot it if it boots up properly I have
no trouble at all
so I know how to boot it up properly now
is this kind of annoying I can't just
hit the power button to start it but I'm
gonna try a few other things and
hopefully figure out a better solution
to my fan speed problem I'm just gonna
do something else here so you get the
ethos
stompers we got why did I call them ito
stomper
I'm not stomping myself oh well do you
late get the truth or choppa and yeah oh
I didn't combine the looting books I
wanted to make a cow tipper sword that's
what I wanted to do here let's see let's
get these looting books together you can
do like a sharpness three looting three
unbreaking 3 sword although I don't have
any unbreaking books left yes that you
can actually repair which is awesome
sharpness 3 yeah if I get another
unbreaking 3 wood book I can do that oh
yeah and just to clarify I'm probably
gonna get a lot of like tips on how to
solve this problem and if you do know
what's wrong I do welcome it but I said
I tried like 10 different programs to
change the fan speed with all my sheep
where all my sheep why are they all down
I think tell him to go down Oh ghost
mode all right then I'm in a reblog
there we go that's better so yeah I
installed like 10 different software
programs to change my fan speed I did
MSI I tried speed fan I tried Nvidia
drivers you can get Nvidia drivers that
allow you to access a performance tab in
your your like control panel for the
graphics card so that allows you to
overclock the GPU and change a fan speed
through that and set up all these cool
little features and I tried Nvidia
inspector and just a bunch of other
little programs none of them work though
not even that the Nvidia stuff something
with the higher priority was overriding
the fan speed to 100% so that is not the
solution to my problem yeah so it's been
very frustrating but at least I didn't
use it now so I'm happy about that and
let's see what else
so minecraft specifically let's talk
about that the man cave my old computer
I would get about 40 50 frames per
second in here when I wasn't recording I
locked my framerate by the way that's
why you always see where is it in f3 30
frame fps up here it always says 30fps
cuz I locked my frame right at 30 when
I'm recording it just makes video
editing a lot easier but when I'm not
recording in the man cave here I did
like I can get up to like 220 frames per
second now which is just awesome
I can also now I can go up to 16 chunks
if I want when I'm in the man TV that's
not really necessary because we can't
see that far anyway I've also turned on
anis tropic filtering I wasn't using
this before because my
Peter was struggling as it was without
this on by the way if you don't know
what this does here's a good example
that actually you see the the lines in
the stone brick as you look off into the
distance everything kind of smudges
together all the lines much together and
if this looks like a blur but if you
turn on anise tropic I'm probably saying
that wrong anise tropic filtering it
renders the stuff in the distance a lot
better now we have these nice crisp
lines even as we look far off into the
distance it it still keeps that that
look so it's much better and tried
flying around in an amplified world for
bits at sixteen chunks like with this at
sixteen chunks and I was able to get
like 120 frames per second while flying
around in an amplified world which is
really promising especially now that we
have areas in an amplified world's yeah
but unfortunately guys I think I'm gonna
have to call this the end of the episode
I do apologize if you don't like the
talkie episodes this is really out of
the ordinary I try not to just do taught
the episodes like this but I wanted to
let you know what was going on with my
computer and I haven't had a computer
last two or three days so I'm really
playing catch-up now with all my series
I'm gonna try to record another episode
in a day or two though to make up for
today's quick one but hope you enjoyed
it nevertheless anyway so here is the
comment that picked out for today it
says hey etho I was just wondering if
you considered playing any parkour Maps
or Maps like the code or diversity small
maps like that keep up the good video
small maps like that keep up the good
video they're common there or is he
saying small maps like that keep the
video good I don't know anyway I have
considered doing like random maps like
maybe adventure maps and that kind of
stuff I've never actually tried an
adventure map
Minecraft's um but I don't know I don't
like parkour maps like at all I can
handle it for a few minutes but I
wouldn't wanted to spend a few hours
doing parkour in this game
it would just be frustrating I have
consider starting a new series where I
do where I play on the play minecraft
server try to get some more PvP games
going but that would just be an every so
often sort of thing if I do that but
yeah anyway so that's gonna be it guys
loving the new computer it should
improve the quality of things soon I I
am noticing let me know if you notice
anything different like if anything
seems out of whack it might be a mad my
imagination but I kind of it feels like
there's a little bit of a haze with
everything like everything's a little
grey which I might be able to tweak in
my settings but it's not too bad like
the colors might be a little washed out
I'm not sure but if you notice anything
that that seems off from what we're used
to let me know if you know for sure how
to fix my fan speed issue I I would like
to know if that's even though I can kind
of work around it now at least but yep I
have a good day guys I hope you enjoyed
and I will see you again next time bye
bye
you