[Music]
hello everyone this is etho
and since last episode i've just been
doing a few
little tweaks and changes around the
place trying to get things
looking a little better the way i wanted
to
like for example
i said i was going to replace the stairs
with our slime escalator here with the
half slabs to try and make it look
better
turns out they get stuck in certain
places if i do that
oh here comes a big guy
right over here i was having big slimes
get trapped
when i had half slabs there
kind of like that medium slime did there
but he he managed to keep going
had me worried for a sec um
so it seems to work okay now again
and i've also i've done it
the wall is gone we have it
wide open now you can see the tree farm
very nicely from here now
i like it um
we will probably put something there yet
though
yeah so it was kind of suggested maybe i
should put a glass wall
over here with some texture to it
uh one other thing people have been
suggesting is that i
stick up an information board somewhere
in my world for
everybody that downloads the world to
check it out
you know information board with
locations to things like the stronghold
or
thief spider spawners or whatever that
kind of information so i
might try rig that up over here
a glass wall with an information board
somehow
that's what i was thinking and
this whole area of the cave is dedicated
to my viewers mainly that's why we have
the tree farm here
i will be putting the trivia game here
sometime soon
i've cleared out a whole bunch of area
again
for a new row of trees
a lot of a lot of blocks to take out
this is probably as wide as i'm going to
do the tree farm though
if if it needs to be bigger i'll
probably extend it that way
but this is probably as wide as it's
going to get because we have
40 trees per row here so 40 80
120 160
200 trees once i get that new area
finished
that's a good number
pretty good number i haven't figured out
what i'm gonna do for the ceiling here i
was
thinking maybe having skylights
to get some natural light in here too
maybe i'll probably
hook up some stairs here to get down
and probably on the other side as well i
might do that today
oh yeah i want to say thanks to
everybody that mentioned in the comments
you can put trapdoors on glowstone again
i had no idea that was re-added so
got the waffle look going on here with
our cow face
it's uh helps to blend the colors a lot
better i like it
i'll probably use those a lot more
around my world too
it's a it's a nice look
i was thinking probably won't put it on
the sides
and uh the bottom there
don't think i will i don't know maybe uh
we should try work out the staircase
here
so i would like uh
this walkway to go up to here at least
and then it can start going down so i i
think i'm going to make the staircase go
down
and then halfway down it's going to
split to the left and to the right
and then same for the other side we'll
try copy it
and see how that turns out so
get rid of these mushrooms i don't know
why i keep planting these things
i'll put one down randomly and then it's
splits into a million
like uh i don't know i keep doing it too
for some reason
okay so
actually let's make this wood here
we'll start the transition never dig
straight down
um
so
up
so we got the stairs laid out here i
think they're pretty good
the way they are um put grass up here
i'll have to rig up some lighting so i
can get rid of this torch
and then at the corner here i rounded it
out a little bit
and big guy over there you size uh
playing around with different
uh borders and stuff around here
different things i did kind of like the
fences
but i wasn't totally sold on it yet
and i did try out trapdoors on the
inside of the frame
i think it looks better so i'll keep it
like that gives it kind of a
more 3d look with the trapdoors sticking
out
um another thing i was thinking for this
frame
is maybe something like this although i
think it might have problems too
instead of having wood here
you go down two blocks
on the inside here
i would have a light source such as
pumpkins
for
for a glowing uh bush type effect
actually yeah that's right
this would come up and then instead of
the wood on outside here it would be in
one block over here
like that and that would help to get
light on this side from the pumpkins
and it would be a rail so i wouldn't
walk off but
the only problem with that idea is it
doesn't look quite as good on this side
i don't think
yeah that looks pretty crummy
otherwise i would definitely do it that
way
so yeah i have to think about that for a
little bit yet
so we do need some type of rail for our
stairs yet and i'm not exactly sure what
type of block to use
i might try some wood
maybe fences i don't know i think a
general rule
and this might just be my personal
opinion but i think in general
is the stairs need to stand out more
than the rail itself
so for example i shouldn't use
sandstone as a rail for this because
then the sandstone rail
would stand out more than the wooden
stairs in my opinion
um
i might do
something like that
and then have fences perhaps
um yeah i'm not good at aesthetics
aesthetics try it out see how this goes
that's not bad actually i don't mind
that
i have to go up higher maybe
oh that's all the blocks i had lame um
let's try out the dark wood too
dark wood um
i do love this dark wood
what do you guys think
it makes the stairs really stand out
that's for sure
okay i'll i'll try rig something up here
there we go that's not bad i like that
i think the the dark wood was just a
little bit too high of contrast
especially when it was next to sandstone
but let me know what you think
i may change it after all
and then this will kind of just merge in
here
excuse me i'm catching a cold here
um yeah i like that so
one thing i'm wondering about now though
is with the fences should i connect them
together
at the top if i do the fences like this
too
it would blend nicely if i put a fence
around this top
as well so that's a that's a plus
but should i do this and connect them
together
can't really do it on this one
not sure
again let me know what you think for now
i'm going to keep it the way it was
before
okay one last little detail here on the
inside of the staircase i have added
this little
station with chests and a crafting table
then we have glowing pumpkins behind
leaves for
light and i'm pretty happy with that too
so i think we'll end the staircase stuff
here today so i'll be
copying this assuming everybody likes it
i'll be copying that and putting it
another one over here
that will connect to the path there and
let you get down
as well is the plan and then in the
middle like i said i might do
an information board possibly
glass something or another over here
okay so one thing i noticed as well
this ufo thing one of my favorite
features of it is not
uh working right now the water's not
dripping down like it used to
and i don't know why i don't
know why i'll have i'm gonna
i'll probably do it off camera but i'm
gonna try fix that back up again
maybe after i'm done recording today
because this is where it got left off uh
after my world was corrupted
and i had to load the backup this is as
far as it was
so i need to put leaves all along here
where these blocks i'm removing are make
leaves two blocks high
here you didn't see that
two blocks high there and then i think i
had half slabs on this
ring of leaves the water needs to come
up and flow out
and then i put water channels
on top of these leaves which take the
cows to
i'll probably make them drop down here
or something next to these mobs
yeah i'll do that some other time though
um
i think we're going to do a little bit
of exploring here so i'm going to
drop off my better stuff here
stuff i don't want to lose i got
something to show you today
i probably won't die
a lot of people for one thing have been
asking where the nether portal is so
i'll show you
i know these caves pretty good because i
spent a lot of time in my world
but it is extremely confusing the first
time you see it so
you gotta go down here follow the grass
road
hello
and get to this area
then if you keep going over here
you have the nether portal um
over
down here along there is the old slime
farm which i still haven't
uh paved with half slabs to disable it
if i disable it i'll get better rates
upstairs so
something i should do soon
anyway slime farm over here
the thing i want to show you though
as uh as i plan to expand here i'm
looking for new areas to go to
and there is a nice area in the cave
over
this way that i like hopefully i won't
get lost
i think i go straight here even i get
lost in these oh
yeah i think i took the wrong way
it's a dungeon here with the spawner
destroyed when i tried out silk touch on
it that one time um
okay yeah i'm lost already
was it this way
it was this way
from the portal if i
if i get lost here i'm just going to cut
it and then take you there
yes it's looking right so it takes you
to this
area here which is nice and open
it would be a pretty good place to build
some stuff
and then if you keep going further it
gets even better
get another really open area here
with uh pretty spacious caves and
everything
so this would be another good place to
build something
kinda it's pretty open over here
and then further there's still more
stuff
so i want to finish up that one area but
as i'm doing that i might start building
here as well
and this is ravine
which is pretty cool but further
i didn't make it are you kidding me oh
that was embarrassing
such an easy jump too okay further
we have yet another ravine up here
there's actually a lot of mobs around
uh and this place doesn't really lit up
too well
it's the right one that might be in the
wrong spot
it goes up to the surface down
here i hope this is the right place
i remember there's water though no i'm
at the wrong one i think it was a
one we were just at
um sorry
no it couldn't have been okay give me a
second i'm gonna cut it here
yeah so it was the darker further ravine
up there is a sir
the hole to the surface we saw it's
confusing because there's actually
a third ravine that i forgot about right
next to it
over here
okay and this is where i'm thinking of
building my
mob system and
storage room we'll probably go here too
got a nice big ravine
and you might remember this area this is
where i went to
parkouring over the abandoned mine shaft
garbage up there
and i had that really close near-death
experience
with the creepers and skeletons
the reason i particularly like this
place
besides it being nice and open and
having all those
good areas nearby to work with um if you
go up here
just found this other day
there's a cave spider spawner here too
and not only that there is another one
over here so there's two cave spider
spawners and they are
get out here they're right next to each
other in line
which is fantastic only one two
three four five like five or six blocks
apart
which is pretty good so
be a nice place to make uh a mob system
because not only could we have the
creepers and skeletons and all that but
we could also have
cave spiders for extra xp and
item drops excuse me
so that's what i'm thinking
just wanted to show you around and let
you know
the plans i have but i will try to
work on that other area as well and
finishing it up
excuse me losing my voice today
and the tree farm area is going to be
kept for the viewers mainly so that's
probably where i'll put fun things like
games
trivia game any other games i come up
with
information board that kind of stuff
will go around the tree farm
and this is where that hole comes up to
the surface here
it's kind of around the desert area um
the village is right there and about
three to four hundred blocks that way
is the stronghold so
it's a nice in-between area as well for
that stuff
i'll probably end the episode here today
though because i having a hard time
talking all of a sudden
this is not helping my voice at all and
uh
we the redstoners played team
brute the other day and race for wall i
will be uploading a footage of that
after this episode um
so if you're looking forward to that
match it will be up soon
not gonna tell you who won or what
happened i'll let you watch
although i'm sure you've probably seen
other videos of it already
anyway um
it's probably gonna be the last race for
wool i do in a while
although i may put up a highlights video
of some of my favorite moments
throughout the
the matches and the practice matches we
did
but anyway that's it for today thanks
for watching
i'll see you again next time
oh yeah