[Music]
keep the wind polar bears in the Canada
land you know what guys we're gonna
start off today's episode with an
important topic this is a conversation I
think we need to have it's kind of kind
of being ignored right now the polar
bears you know we love these guys
they're cute fluffy funny little fellas
right we love them but they have a
problem they have a big problem you ask
anybody out there what does a polar bear
do polar bear does nothing they just
kind of they kind of stand around they
don't really do anything but can you
blame them honestly like if you look
around if you look around here what do
you see huh or what don't you see you
don't see any seals no seals around here
there's no plump juicy walruses waiting
to be eaten nah most disturbing of all I
don't even see a Tim Horton's or
Starbucks within eyeshot Slyke this is
this is a horrible scene the polar bears
are starving they have nothing to eat
there's nothing here
no wonder they're not moving around
right but that's not even the worst of
their problems the biggest problem
literally and metaphorically or whatever
they are not the top of the food chain
anymore ah what little food they do
manage to scrape together gets stolen
there there is a massive beast out there
massive scary smelly fearsome and it's
eaten all the food what little food
these guys do manage to to scrape
together this massive beast just steals
it right from them what are we to do
about this what is the solution well I
have come up with a pretty good idea I
think it's actually pretty simple
basically your mama is so fat that
whenever she goes camping the Bears need
to hide
their food problem solved
uh-huh but anyways guys let's get to it
tears so we're gonna start off
underwater again today last episode we
worked on this mob system got that
working pretty good and we did the
underwater enchanting area here get us
started today I thought we would add the
on/off switch to this mob system I saw
one of the biggest comments or questions
last episode is like where are these
guys actually coming from they like they
come out of the ground here but where is
that so we're gonna head down there to
the spawning area and we got to set up a
bunch of lights that we can turn on and
off to enable spawning or disable it you
know so yeah here we go this is where
they're coming from we got a bunch of
spawning space here they fall in the
water streams and then they get carried
to a bubble stream in the middle we just
got a skeleton just went up there other
guy went up there so I think the plan
here oh yeah and by the way the carpet
here is to prevent spiders from spawning
the way we got it laid out I got to eat
something I'm gonna die down here but
basically I made a whole bunch of
redstone lamps and I'm gonna go here and
try to figure out the ideal spacing for
this so like what we have to have a
light level of eight or higher to stop
mobs from spawning down here so at this
block here it needs to be light level 8
9 10 11 12 13
14 and then I guess the lamp would have
to go here 15 at the lamp right so
that'll prevent mobs from spawning on
these two platforms and basically I'm
gonna go through the whole area here try
to pick out figure out the ideal
position for all the lamps and then
we're gonna run some redstone wire above
that we can turn on and off oh I guess
this is gonna be way harder to do than I
thought the lighting engines pretty
broken in this version I guess so if we
look at the light it's like right around
here where my mouse cursor is client
light says light level 11 where I'm
standing we walk over here and it goes
all the way down to zero so it's like
taking a shortcut when figuring out a
lighting needed so it goes down and then
it sees this block here it's like oh I
can't light anything that direction so
it's making like a a line right here
which is kind of weird because then when
we start turning on other lights like
you see there's a jump here it goes from
11 to 7 we shut this one off 6 to 7 then
I can shut this off oh no that worked
there is a way where it'll get stuck
though yeah so all the lights are off
here right now but it's still lit up
until it gets updated until it gets
updated right oh yeah we're gonna have
some trouble with this why is why the
lights still on usually that fixed
itself whenever I place a block down but
now it's like permanently stuck on
there's no lights on here right is it
just thinks it's lit up right now
there's gonna be hard to make an on/off
switch for this
what's the block I guess we got to find
the block maybe where it's at the
lightest and 1112 probably if we update
here yeah that fixed it weird very weird
all right it's very good so we can turn
all the lights on and off now just with
the flip of a lever we got them all
connected together
there's about 20 of them in total and I
am still having that issue or sometimes
the light will get stuck on but I think
it's actually like kind of like the boat
issue where it's sometimes the client
and server don't line up with what they
they want I think that's happening with
the lighting and I found that like if I
reload that chunks it actually fixes it
so not too too worried if it does happen
it seems like it's not gonna get stuck
on so we're gonna cover over all these
wires now one more branch to do here we
don't have to worry about mob spawning
you know wiring you know and then we
just have to run a wire from the surface
like from our mob system control down to
Center parts aha so we got that all done
it's pretty cool and now you can see
we're getting the Drowned zombies
spawning around us again kind of all
over the place so it's not super useful
but it's kind of a cool thing we can do
if we want them to spawn heyyou we want
to firm try dance or whatever we have
that option now but most the time we'll
probably leave the regular mobs on so we
just right-click that and then they'll
start spawning again but yeah guys we're
gonna we're gonna take a moment now just
a little talkie-talkie here I want to
try explain this idea I have for a new
storage system it's kind of crazy it's
kind of like Nexus level stuff here
maybe not quite so ambitious but it's
it's gonna be ambitious for sure and
pretty complicated so I'm gonna try get
that the key details laid out for you so
that hopefully you'll understand what
we're going what we're trying to do with
this underwater base we're building
because that's where we're gonna install
it we're trying to make like a modular
storage system so that means it can be
built in smaller pieces not like you
think about the Nexus we had to build
the whole thing before it would be
functional this we'll be able to build
in small pieces at a time and as we add
more pieces on to the storage system
it's gonna get better and better
basically and it's no fixed size so it
doesn't have to follow a certain shape
like the Nexus we were limited to 250
six items max
we weren't able to increase the storage
space at all if we wanted to it was very
fixed while this one will be able to do
whatever we want we can even change the
shape of the storage and stuff it should
be pretty cool with a couple other goals
we're gonna have with it
Auto item sorting like most storage
systems have using item filters we're
gonna have item requesting like the
Nexus has but the Nexus that uses codes
like a binary code system we're gonna
we're gonna keep it a little bit more
simple with this one we're just gonna
have to give it an item and then they'll
give us 64 of that item back and we can
do that several times right if we want
more than a stack of items the downside
is we're gonna have to have that item on
us to request it but I got some plans to
deal with that as well um let's see what
its gonna have a smelting system built
in here's a big one this is like this is
like what makes it kind of crazy it's
gonna be accessible from the entire base
so anywhere we want in the base to
request an item or or to put items into
storage we'll be able to do it we don't
have to like go up to the storage room
to get items we can just be anywhere in
our base and we'll be able to smelt
items or get items or put items into
storage that's gonna be one of the big
challenges and it's gonna connect to all
our farms so like if if we got a cactus
farm hooked up to the system we'll be
able to request cactus from anywhere in
our base basically his idea or to put
cactus into a storage at the cactus farm
yeah so I built a model here to try
explain this idea hopefully with this
storage system we're gonna have a four
pipeline plan for pipelines so basically
for water streams like this one of them
is gonna be for the inputs Auto sorting
so like we give it items passes by
hoppers item filters and if they go into
the the hoppers and they go into storage
basically automatically figures out
where stuff needs to go we're gonna have
a request line so that is where we give
it the one item gonna pass by some item
filters again if it gets picked up by
one of them then it's gonna give us 64
of that item
delivered to us through the livery line
that's where we get items from and then
there's also going to be an auto
smelting line where we can throw items
in it'll go to a furnace array and then
it'll deliver the smelted items to us
through the delivery line so over here
is a model of how the delivery line is
gonna work
so the key concept is it's gonna operate
on a closed loop so the items will just
keep going around and around and then
this loop is gonna be running underneath
our base over a large area and we're
gonna be able to connect up to this loop
at different areas of our base through
these ports so basically if we remove
this block here then those items are
free to fall down and they would get
delivered to us at this location right
now we're gonna be able to connect we're
gonna be connecting lots of ports up to
this loop so if we're if we go to a
different area and we try to get items
from here guess what those items are
gonna go to that first port that's still
open so the key to operating this is we
have to close all the ports first from
the area where we're trying to connect
up to so we'll do something like this
where
like if we press this button it's gonna
get stuck into an infinite redstone loop
we don't want that so what we do is
we'll have to retract the block
momentarily then press this that'll
reset all the ports so that they're
closed and then this goes back into
place and then we trigger this and that
ensures it goes to where we want so one
of the main rules to the system is we're
only gonna have one port open at a time
also we're not really trying to store
like every single item like Auto sort
every single item it's more like if we
build a cactus farm I want to be able to
hook that up to our storage system and
then we'll be able to store and request
cactus from anywhere in our base and as
we add more and more farms up to this
thing we'll be able to get more and more
stuff and like if it's an item we can't
farm like sand for example we can hook
up a storage silo to the system and then
requests and from that silo and store it
in the silo also we're not really trying
to store items in mass it's more like I
want to have a bunch of smaller storage
rooms with a variety of items that hook
up to these ports and as they run low on
items we can just request more from the
system and like if we build a cactus
farm the cactus is gonna be stored at
the cactus farm not into storage rooms
it's more like we we take them from that
cactus farm as we need it but the bulk
of the storage will be in the farms
[Music]
so at the end of last episode I spent
some time farming wither skulls we got
15 of them now to cash in five five more
begins here and I was playing around
with idea maybe blowing up a wither I
thought that would be fun but I couldn't
get it to work there's a like I thought
if I put enough TNT together it would
kill them all in one shot but like even
after one TNT blows up in that frame the
damage thicken vulnerability kicks in so
you can only do so much damage in so
much time so it didn't work I think this
trick does work Oh actually I'm supposed
to have him that high never done this
before that's loud
yeah so he'll kind of get stuck there
it'll automatically die that way as well
from attacking itself
not as cool but we got to get these
peakins right so I'm gonna farm up a few
withers here damn first wither down
he's a cake let's do one more here and
we'll try get some winter roses with the
last one I think okay so I think the way
this works though if the wither kills a
mob either a hostile mob or a passive
one or whatever
I think they drop a withered rose and
then you got to grab it before it gets
blown up because it can get blown up as
well so I think we can use snow golems
right I'm hoping hopefully they don't
die in the swamp I think they like in
some biomes they die I don't think the
swamp is one of them no yeah they're
fine so we're gonna fill up a cage here
of snow golems and then spawn the wither
in the middle and I think that should do
the trick I think he'll blow out the
ground and then all the wither roses
will fall on us right I'm hoping what's
the best way to fill this up let's let's
maybe make a wall here uh-huh
I mean I like spawning 64 of them this
so we have some way the Roses to play
around it's because I still haven't got
any of those yet
all right we pretty much oh yeah we did
use them all okay cool cool so yeah I
think 60 for snow golems in there now
we're gonna spawn our wither and right
above and we're gonna get out of here um
this will work though right I hope this
is probably a bad idea but anyways we'll
see what happens here I'm gonna go down
below oh they're fighting him you hear
all the snow snowballs yeah I killed
them all oh no he didn't oh no we did
get a few year though or one now we got
25 okay that's something there's more
here uh-huh uh-huh very good 46 so not
all of them died where is this guy
always still floating down okay let's
get away from him for a moment I mean
getting like super good gear or anything
here hoping I'm gonna take him down got
our trusty try Vince for strength let's
go for regen and maybe do some flybys oh
that didn't didn't do much
is this too much damaged not really so
much okay yeah I should have brought a
bow I can't get this guy like at all
just out of range
no balls do nothing all right I'm gonna
leave him here actually I'll come back
some other day awesome alright so we got
46 with the roses I haven't played
around with these things at all yet so I
just wanted to check out a couple things
here so you can plant them and you know
use them for decorative things they look
kind of cool they got particle effects a
little smoke if you walk into them or if
mobs do they get withered well that
lasts for a very short time though so
that must not be wither to wither one
effect okay the wither gives you wither
to effect so it's stronger can you plant
these in flowerpots oh you can and do
you get no you don't
uh-huh okay I read you can also plant
them on netherrack and soul sand which
is kind of different yeah yeah checks
out okay cool cool
is there any way you can walk in between
these without getting probably not right
how close do you have to get to it but
I'm still in this block pretty much I
guess let's go f3b
check out our hip box yeah so it's got a
pretty big hip box I was just thinking
this could actually be useful like if
you have an animal pen a lot of people
just put a bunch of animals in a fenced
area oh it kills
oh I thought were just weaken them
actually kills them oh it does kill okay
never mind I thought it got them down to
one hit for some reason oh so it
actually kills things I just kills me -
probably right weather is different from
poison poison doesn't kill wither does
ha okay never mind then you know he
might actually escape this guy has been
in the man cave forever he was like
never able to get out of the sheep farm
then he finally made it to round here I
got the top of the stairs and now he's
actually found his way to the exit
almost he's so close might be the day he
actually leaves look at this oh man big
day for I wanted to see what the actual
height on this thing is okay get
withered there get where there there oh
[Music]
no you're gonna go guy this is your big
day everyone's watching must be a full
block a full block okay interesting
interesting so at this level here and
he's gone he made it Wow proud of you
guy alright everybody well unfortunately
I think it's about time we wrap up our
video for today and we're gonna do it
the way we always do with the comment of
the day I picked out this comet because
this is something I've actually seen
come up every so often in the comments
and I've even seen people arguing about
the Sun right and and stuff so I thought
I would clarify this it doesn't happen
often but I have seen it before I
thought it was kind of funny it says hey
etho I just heard somewhere that you
were the one who invented or at least
coined the term bud switch blocked
update detector switch I just wanted to
hear from the horse's mouth if this is
true yes I am the horse's mouth here so
basically what happened is I thought I
invented the bud switch when I posted
the video a long time ago
and if you look on the wiki page what
ended up happening is like a few months
later they found more videos
demonstrating bud switches on YouTube
like that came out I think the earliest
one was like two or three weeks before
my video so technically some other
people have shown bud switches before me
and I didn't see those videos though
when I posted mine so I thought I
invented it but I independently invented
it later in their videos though they
never really explained the bud switch I
just showed it with some redstone right
but in my video I actually showed like
what triggers a bud switch like beds and
all that kind of stuff and like my bud
switch isn't the traditional one that we
use today like with the diagnol powering
of a piston and I went up something
updates next surfaced and it causes it
to extend my original one was actually a
boat switch like this I tried recreating
it here and you would update the water
that would flow to the boat and the boat
would lift up off of a pressure plates
that that mechanic doesn't work anymore
because boats sink in water now but
pretend that gets lifted up pressure
plate goes up that causes the Pistons to
extend and cut off the water and then
the boat would sink back down onto the
pressure plate you retract the top
piston first then the bottom one so that
the water doesn't flow back and then
it's ready to get updated again so it
resets the bud switch so that's how mine
originally worked and then like a day or
two after I posted mine I remember
sethbling showed the way of doing it
with a piston and I think maybe a couple
other people and pretty much away it
gained popularity quickly was like my
channel is a decent size at that point
and growing I think Seth blings channel
is pretty pretty big at that point as
well like we're probably maybe fifty
thousand subs or whatever I was the
guest and then a few days after I posted
the bud switch video CaptainSparklez saw
it and he also posted about the bud
switch and gave me credit for it in a
shout-out which was pretty cool
he had a big minecraft channel at that
point so that's how it kind of spread to
the my
Krabbe community and a lot of people
learned about it and stuff like that so
yeah that's kind of the history of it
anyways I hope you enjoyed today's
episode guys thank you for watching I'm
starting to lose my voice for some
reason so we're gonna end it here and
until next time thanks for watching have
a wonderful day take care bye bye
[Music]