[Music]
we spend a lot of time in our world
in this spot right over here this is our
favorite spot
and uh for good reason it's right next
to our storage room oh
it's a fine storage room we use this
thing all the time you know it's got a
little bit of everything in so we just
pick up a couple stacks of whatever we
need and we're on our way
well after this episode i'm hoping that
might change a little bit because we got
a couple plans for the nexus today
i know we're done with the nexus but
we're never done with the nexus
if you think about what the nexus is
what are its pros
well it's a massive storage room it's
got a lot of storage space
that's something the man cave storage
room doesn't really have i've been kind
of getting around it by keeping stuff
stored in shulker boxes uh which works
but uses up a lot of shulker boxes right
uh the other thing this does great is
it's got an auto sorting system and
retrieval system but what it really
lacks what the nexus fails at is being
able to come in here
pick up items quickly and then get out
so i was thinking about it and we
actually have the perfect thing
to cover that weakness now we're going
to be installing the
ender chest storage system
in these wings on each side of the nexus
you know we didn't really know what to
do with these rooms
we have an unfinished roof in here and i
thought it would be perfect because they
need to go
like in the roof so that's what we're
going to be doing and they allow us to
pick up a little bit of everything
not just quickly but automatically
so we're gonna be placing a shocker box
loading station where each of these
netherrack are that's where the shocker
box is gonna be
and we place five hoppers facing into
the shulker box
of course each hopper holds five
different items so five times five
that's 25 different items
we can potentially automatically refill
into a shulker box and
they hold 27 different items so
it's just about perfect right there's
two items that
we use least often we're not going to be
able to automatically refill
but otherwise we can cover like every
item in the game
probably with 16 of these stations so
eight on this side eight on the other
side
and above each hopper we're going to
place a double chest to automatically
refill the hopper
and so we can have like quite a bit of
stock here actually
and there we go it's pretty much all set
up so the the tricky part of this is not
setting up the
storage system it's filling it that's
what's gonna take the most time here
now i'll probably be doing most of this
off camera but just to give you an idea
of what's involved in stocking that
thing
initially it's great when it's all done
it's gonna be
so amazing but to initially stock it
does take quite a bit of time we gotta
get like
12 stacks of each item in each category
so one category
another stuff we gotta get like 12
stacks of each of these things
so either we collect it from what we
have on hand or we gotta farm it
i'm sure we got some of those things but
we're gonna have to farm some of them as
well
what's in here actually let's check our
bulk storage i think this is all
pumpkins
oh actually yeah that's one of the
things we need
oh okay so we can easily get 12 stacks
of those no problem
let's check out what we got in here so
we have netherrack
uh let's see that's 12 stacks there good
good
this is a lot of moving stuff around too
uh looks like we got some of these not
quite
enough though and what's that snow
don't need to know we need the black
stone though 12 stacks of these
i think a lot of the nether stuff we
have in our piglin trading system so we
should check that out too
all right so we ran around a bit here
and we got some things to drop
off so now we got to pick one of these
stations
for the nether stuff so let's let's just
say this one here
and then i like to kind of group it into
things of five if i can as well
so if we look at this easily quartz can
go into a group of five the five
different types of quartz
five different types of black stone
should go into their own hopper
and then we just uh drop them in here
like that and now we have somewhere to
actually unload the black stone we
collected
this is the crack stuff and then i'll
just make a line like this
and then fill her up
and as much as i would love to get this
all finished today there's just no way
that's gonna happen there's so much to
do here
uh but we almost got the nether stuff
thing filled
this is also kind of good because it's
gonna show us weaknesses in our current
world like what items aren't we really
able to get
so i did go to the piglet trading system
and it was empty like
i've i've taken all the stuff out of
there previously i guess
so we don't have crying obsidian we
don't have blackstone at the moment
and quartz we gotta set up villager
trading for that
this is our total like quartz supply
right now so
it's pretty pathetic aha so even though
that's not fully loaded at the moment we
can still use it it's just kind of nice
to get 12 stacks of everything
to begin with it saves a lot of work so
if we want to top off our nether stuff
box we just go under here
and throw it in and now it's going to
automatically fill up with stuff
the other thing we're going to be doing
with the nexus though if we look
in what's what's being stored in there
honestly there's a lot of stuff we don't
need to store
here's a perfect example uh maybe when
uh the bundles come out i don't know but
like
leads rabbit hide yeah we probably don't
need to actually store that
there's probably zero in the system um
so
food as well probably we're gonna remove
that from the list and then we're gonna
add
some of the things we're missing in here
like we put this all together i think
back in 1.9 or something and there's so
many new blocks in the game
like pretty much everything in here
isn't being stored in the nexus so i
gotta go through the menu and like redo
all the item filters and stuff we have
so this will actually be more useful
okay well this is gonna be a bit tricky
i've been working it out here though and
i think we got a list
figured out this is the stuff i would
like to add to the nexus the things that
are missing
and it's uh it's uh oh we don't have
enough space
and we don't even have glazed terracotta
and concrete on that
um that would add another 48 items so
we're gonna have to make some sacrifices
here because we only have room for 256
different items now for some of these
like redstone for example
i've added in redstone blocks so rather
than just storing redstone dust we're
going to switch over to
redstone blocks because it's more
compact and same with a lot of other
things like
iron gold lapis coal emeralds
bone blocks you know rather than just
having i think we only have
an individual thing here we're going to
store it compressed because that makes
more sense
oh snappers all right well we've been at
this for a few hours now
and uh just doing the spring cleaning
you know things are starting to get
organized
it's like when you go to a restaurant
and they hand you the menu and and you
go to grab it and it's like oh there's
something sticky on here
some jam or something worse maybe even
oh it's so gross
why don't they watch the menus get new
menus well the nexus finally has a new
menu guys look at this
so uh got rid of all the useless stuff
well it's not useless but it's like
seldom used so we got rid of all the
stairs slabs fences
that uh we weren't really using before
by all the highly processed stuff we
don't need we got rid of planks
um just storing the logs instead and
like
detector rails activator rails we don't
need those stored
um so i tried to get the the more
useless stuff out of here
and put the the better stuff in now we
got like a plant chest over here
anyways let's get to some other stuff
now so this zombie has been here forever
we're gonna finally release some he's
gonna be our patient zero
in our villager breeding thing we set up
in the nether recently we gotta get
their trade prices down
hey he's here good good good follow me
i got some friends for you to meet all
right here he comes here comes
run run run so these villagers up here
we're not
i wasn't really intending on making this
a trading system but it'll function as a
lazy one for now until we actually set
up a good one
oh there's a carpet there
does this work this is a bad idea
this is so scary all right let's throw a
weakness
all right very good very good so we
ended up infecting and curing the
villagers three times
and their trade prices are they're not
as low as they can go but they're pretty
good
like we can get books for an emerald now
and stuff so
that's what we're gonna be doing once
they get a good trade like mending i'll
probably start trading with them
to unlock their other trades i want to
get the glass trade unlocked with
a few guys we can actually buy glass
instead of
smelting it oh we got fire aspect that's
not bad
that worked out pretty good uh we'll
also probably get
a couple mason guys over here so let's
switch out
a few of these and maybe a few farmers
so we're gonna get rid of some of the
librarians get masons instead
one thing i've kind of noticed with
villagers is everybody seems to have
their own favorite guy
like i know a lot of people like to set
up an iron farm and then they just trade
iron to the
the weaponsmiths or whatever uh i like
the
masons personally i think they're my
favorite
because they always have like a stone
trade and then there's usually like a
diorite or granite or
andesite trade so not only do they buy a
lot of useless things off of you but
then they sell you really good stuff too
which makes them like the the complete
package and buy bricks off of them
glazed terracotta regular terracotta
quartz is which is what we need here so
we'll be buying some of that
and they also sell like the
oh i don't want to talk to you uh they
sell like the polished andesite granite
and diorite too
so yeah i really like i like the masons
by far my favorite
noise all right everybody well you might
recall a few episodes ago we worked on
a wither skeleton farm and i don't think
we got
all the way done with it but it's like
all done now it's all all finished up
and it's working pretty good
got most of our nether slabbed out now
and uh
yeah we just head down here we got an
auto sorting system for it and stuff
here as well
walk up to them smack them with the
sword and we get tons of bones tons of
gold
so we're gonna be starting a new project
today right next to this thing
we are going to be building a gold farm
whoa now before you guys freak out at me
and you're like etho
another gold farm what is that number
four number five
uh the truth is we really do need a a
gold farm though like this goon farm
is mostly just an iron farm we get a
trickle of gold from it but it hasn't
been
enough we can afk at it but i usually
don't like the apk in my world
so in general we're kind of running out
of gold
uh like even today to the to do that
villager thing we used like a stack of
uh
gold blocks and now we're out again
and i it's been like weeks of collecting
that so
the problem is all the gold farms we've
got we have operational
are above the bedrock ceiling and the
higher you place a mob farm in your
world the worse your rates are because
if it's trying to place
a mob like spawn a mob up at the
platform there it checks all the air
space below
that and tries to place mobs there as
well and most of the time it's going to
fail so you very rarely actually get
a mob spawning there but if you build a
farm under the ceiling it's a little bit
more tricky
you gotta like spawn proof your nether
if you do that
um you'll get better rates though the
ultimate is to remove the bedrock
ceiling and build it way down at the
bottom of the world
but that is like very tricky and i don't
have the energy for that today
so the plan is to build it right next to
our wither skeleton farm here like
right over here is going to be the
killing chamber hopefully
and then we can kind of use both of them
at the same time
maybe but we'll see we'll add like on
off switches to both of them as well
all right well i guess let's get into
building this thing so i did bring some
supplies over we got some glass from
those villagers so i didn't have to
farm sand or anything that was nice and
i
got a bunch of magma blocks back when we
were filling the nexus up there
so i think we have pretty much
everything we need
now we want to build this gold farm as
close to the wither skeleton farm as
possible
so it's convenient but we also don't
want it to interfere with each other so
the way their skeleton spawning pad
is at the dirt there we're gonna go four
blocks
from that and uh we're gonna build the
killing chamber first it's gonna be a
bit confusing until we
uh actually get the whole thing done
probably
but i think this is going to be our ring
we're going to try drop the pig lens
into a three by three area
and then over here will be three pistons
to collect the drops together
into the middle we're going to try to
get it all into a one by one area
then we'll have a piston on the side
here
and a piston over here and
then let's get three more on this side
and i think that will push all the drops
to the center then
so yeah we're gonna build a bunch of
spawning platforms up above here
for the piglens to drop down and we'll
drop them into the three by three area
onto hay bales hey bales reduce fall
damage
so they will hopefully not die from the
drop we're gonna want to kill them with
looting
is the idea behind this whole farm we're
not going to make an afk farm
uh we want to use the looting sword so
they actually drop the gold ingots and
we'll be able to get gold
very quickly from this i just went ahead
and placed a bunch of blocks here so we
could do the redstone quickly together
idea is we're gonna try trigger these
three pistons and those three pistons
first together and then we'll trigger
these two side ones afterwards
um so the drops will get collected over
here and here and then push to the
center
um so to do that we want a little bit
extra delay on the side pistons we'll go
for three ticks
these ones will be a one tick and same
deal over here
three ticks and then we run redstone all
combined together here
down here oop run underneath over to
here to the other side
and i'm trapped uh oh that wasn't in the
plan
oh i almost fell in the lava there run
it around and then again three more
pistons to the back here so now in the
the redstone gets triggered all the
pistons will go together
oh i missed the piece there okay all
good and then uh over
down here uh what we're gonna do is i
think
two ticks we'll have a sticky piston
over here and the drops are going to be
falling here right so we're going to
drop them onto an
ender chest because ender chests don't
get moved by uh
slime blocks or honey blocks um
here we go all right so our items are
gonna fall on the the ender chest and
then we're gonna push them with honey
so after the honey block pushes the
items off the ender chest here we're
gonna have another sticky piston with a
slime block
i think down here is where we want it
and that'll push them
down an ice path or something into our
item filters all right well if the
piston noises weren't bad enough before
we're going to be adding a few more here
so i built a hopper clock right next to
this thing and we're gonna connect it up
we got eight items inside there and
we'll have a redstone torch on the side
you see that pulses every time it
triggers
i i guess every second time yeah and
then uh we'll go to observer
and now these should start firing there
we go
and now any items on the three by three
area here should get combined together
and drop down the center
onto our ender chest and then they'll
get moved by the honey block on the next
cycle
if it actually worked oh no
what's wrong why are you no pushing oh i
left a glass block underneath yeah you
got to make sure nothing's sticking to
it i'll probably have to put the glazed
terracotta next to it oh you
saw it get the shot into the lava there
though so that'll be
for the future we'll we'll set that up
uh whoa
for now let's just work on the platforms
next
uh oh yeah and also
i think we're gonna have a column of
glass down the center like built all the
way up
glass in the center glass on the sides
in the very
center we got to make sure baby piglets
don't fall down there
so we're gonna try sneaking and rod
and items should be able to fit between
that still but the baby big ones won't
and it also gives a little bit of extra
lighting oh wait a second one other
thing i forgot about we also have to be
able to kill them right so we're gonna
leave a one by one hole here
uh and then we're gonna carpet over this
try hide our redstone if we can uh and
then we'll just like go in
like this and swing our sword at the the
pigment in here okay so next up here
we're gonna be building this glass tube
24 blocks up because mobs can't spawn
within 24 blocks of your player
cool cool so we got our tube built and
now we're gonna fill the space between
the top of our tube and the ceiling
with magma block platforms for spawning
in the zombie pigmen
so i decided let's go to the top of this
first
all the way up to the ceiling and this
is the pattern i'm going to go for it
doesn't really matter too much the shape
and whatever you do but i like this
pattern because we can put
dispensers above these holes and drop
lava down to light up the platform
enough where
zombie pigmen won't be able to spawn and
then you can have an on off switch for
it
oh snap okay so there's one thing we
don't have that we got to get here still
uh turtle eggs we need turtle eggs for
the zombie pigmen to chase
they're pretty easy to get it i'm not
mistaken so you you beat them to sea
grass
they scoot around on the beach for a
little bit
there we go yes okay we got some turtle
eggs and then you can just feed them
again i think
like right away and steal these ones
it's a great system
you know what this is actually a pretty
big project
it's one of those ones it's like oh i
just got to build a bunch of platforms
how hard could that be
right well i ended up mining a bunch of
space around the platform and the
ceiling there five blocks out all around
and then uh even though it's a simple
repeating pattern
it's just a lot of blocks to place when
it comes down to it
so we just got this center thing to
finish up and then it's done
so i think we got about 20 platforms in
total though i think we're going to
start the trapdoors
here and then we just hop on and stack
up to the top oh we're at the top okay
here's the fun part now
i love doing this oh this is so
satisfying i don't know why
good stuff so we got the trapdoors all
the way up the center now
on all four sides these trick the zombie
pigmen into
walking off the edge here and they also
protect the eggs
um making sure nobody can get to them
so the other thing we gotta do now is
just put the eggs in so we're at the top
of the ceiling
you can skip every other platform so
we're gonna go go down one
and you wanna place them at the
head level so i'm gonna put a glass
block here and then
one egg over here and now the the
platform above this platform
i think they all can see that egg then
we can go down
oh yeah by the way if you if you're
walking on magma blocks you can use a
fire resistant potion
old shift or frost walker to stop taking
damage
so we're gonna skip this platform or go
go down another one
i can carefully light your wings help
out a lot here and then we're gonna do
another one over here head level again
and then they should see that pretty
pretty quickly yeah there they go
bunch of fools oh snappers all right we
got it pretty much all done here we just
got to do the
uh sorting system in that for it's the
collection system
but everything else is working we did
add uh
an on off switch for the wither skeleton
farm so it's off right now
we just have lava pouring down and
lighting up the layers there
this is a bit of a mess at the moment
but uh it's working pretty good
so we just stand here smack them with
the sword and they fall down at a pretty
good rate
they're all pretty much a one hit kill
with our sword
and as far as i can tell none of them
are getting stuck on the platform up
there which is
which is awesome now we have one little
problem to work out
it turns out the baby
pigmen can still fit through that middle
middle uh end rod right i switched out
with a chain because i kept actually
hitting it
um yeah we're getting good rates
so i'm pretty happy with that we can
stand here and get xp
no problem but the thing is the the
little guys are getting through
and well
yeah i don't know what to do about them
i think it might because all the piston
heads are extended at the same time
maybe if we
alternate them a little bit we won't
have this the issue
like we set these repeaters all the way
to eight or something
and maybe it'll stop squeezing through
currently my best idea um let's kill
these guys
it is like non-stop picking up all the
swords
and uh the idea is we're gonna launch
the items up here and then launch them
to the right
and then they'll go through some item
filters we can't just send this stuff
into a hopper because we're collecting
it way
way way too quickly like probably five
or six times hopper speed at least
and we're gonna want to set up some
smelters for the swords it's definitely
worth smelting those down for the gold
i can't hit these guys there we go
they're all gone now let's see if any
more show up there after we kill a few
two we're finally gonna have gold though
i'm so excited about this i've been
wanting i've wanted a good gold farm for
a very long time now and we finally have
one
we gotta do a little bit more work to it
yeah another guy got through again
uh-huh but i'm thinking that's enough of
that project for me today
i've been over there for many hours now
uh
but yeah i'm really happy with how that
went if you have ideas on what we should
do to finish it off
let me know in the comments and i'll try
to get the item sorter
set up between episodes and and polished
up
now before we finish things here today
there's a couple things i want to
check out and show you guys so since the
world tour episode
i got a couple spoilers in the comments
on where some spawners are hidden
in the world so apparently there was a
double spawner
double skeleton spawner underneath the
windmill like directly under it
where's the other one i did find the
other one oh it's over here i
i guess they're kind of spaced out apart
from each other uh-huh uh-huh so that's
kind of cool if we ever want to
get like a bone farm going on but you
guys have also mentioned there's not a
double spawner not a triple spawner
not a quad spawner but five spawners
all in one location somewhere around our
pumpkin farm here so we're gonna try
find those
and we won't do anything with them today
but maybe
sometime in the future it'd be a fun
little project i want to show you guys
though the x-ray trick in case you guys
don't know about it
because i love using this thing uh this
is great like when you're playing
single player and you're like you don't
have a cam account and you're trying to
light up all the caves for a mob system
or something that's not fun to do
without
uh like seeing into the world so this is
a great way of doing it
you can just like check things out you
can see all the mobs kind of
lit up as well see if you if they're
spawning places you don't want them to
i'm not really seeing any spawners
though
oh that's much better okay so there's
one over there for sure
sometimes the caves don't get rendered
though so this isn't the best at looking
into caves
really uh oh there's one over there too
oh and i see a cave spider spawner there
i'm
assuming uh a few of them must be cave
spider spawners right to get five
together
no
well that's not good that's not good at
all
i don't know where that was
oh is this it this is it
okay whoo
oh no no no i slipped
i tried to hit shift oh
that was bad i deserve to die there on
that one for sure
yeah this area there is something going
on in this area
as soon as i came back here it's like
non-stop oh here's one spawner
oh and it gave spider spawner okay
that's at least a double
what we got here skeletons nice you know
even though i've been playing this game
forever i still really enjoy caving
caving has never lost his charm for me
i'm kind of sad i don't have a reason to
do it anymore
you know because you just trade for
villagers for everything now
or iron farm everything i don't know i i
miss the caving
i think this might be it actually so
we're at 500-ish
at this zombie spawner we got a saddle
i'll take it
um we go down the stairs here this took
me a while to find them all
so this is 5 14 5 18.
they have to be within 32 blocks of each
other otherwise they're too far apart
and then 521 down here so that's
definitely within range right
21 blocks and the other ones over here
so that's five spawners so three of them
are cave spiders one's a skelly
and one's a zombie cool cool well we
found it so the pumpkin farm's over here
and it was actually a bit further
away than i expected it is all the way
over here
this is the zombie spawner
oh yeah and i should probably talk about
my nemesis here as well
so last episode you might remember we
were trying to install a switch to farm
dark oak trees at our tree farm
and we it blew up at the end of the
episode and i rage quit
i did get it rebuilt i made a major
mistake though
i forgot to put a some sort of lighting
in the tunnel and
you know it was fine but then i came
back later and the tree farm blew up
again
because apparently a mob spawned down
there and walked on the pressure plate
and like blew up the tree farm a second
time
i rebuilt it twice and it's all good now
well i think that's where we're gonna
have to wrap up this episode for today
everybody
i was thinking about it we didn't really
do anything like new and exciting
we built a gold farm but like number
five come on
but in terms of like making useful
progress in our world
this was probably the episode where we
did the most like we got the
nexus updated we got the ender chest
system we built a gold
farm and now we can use our piglen
bartering and we did the villager stuff
it's like
yeah bartering villagers
storage like the three main things you
want
in your life when you're playing
minecraft we did them all today so that
was kind of cool
anyways the comment of the day says etho
do you have any background whatsoever in
architecture i think your years of
building in minecraft has kind of
naturally trained you to think about
more of the basics of architecture this
is pretty cool if you don't have a
background because
that means through pure experimentation
and experience building
you've generated pretty distinct
aesthetic and rule set for your builds
you do
this is something that i always found
very fascinating about minecraft you can
figure out like everybody seems to
develop their own unique style
i i know it never spilled when i see it
never spilled
or when i'm flying around the
hermitcraft server and i don't know who
built something just looking at the
build i can usually figure it out now
like yeah everybody seems to develop
their own patterns and stuff
and i'm no exception to that uh i don't
have background in architecture though
no no no
i generally don't like to follow the
standard like foundation walls roof
you know i i build more abstract in
minecraft i find
occasionally i'll try build a house like
this one or in here but it's pretty rare
that i do something like that speaking
of bartering
we got some gold to trade today i'm
gonna do that right now
but that's probably gonna be the end of
this episode everybody thank you for
watching i appreciate it
and of course i love reading your guys's
comments i read probably at least 90
of them so i appreciate any feedback you
leave on the episodes as well
anyways i hope you have yourselves a
wonderful day
take care bye bye