well hello everybody this is etho and
welcome back to another LP episode woo
yes so the rumors of my death have been
exaggerated I am alive and well no no
nope still in hundred 15 levels I
shouldn't have done that
he died since the worst intro ever I got
him I got him
oh baby okay yeah so I'm alive and well
and I did not just die which I was kind
of expecting through there um I went
away this weekend and I haven't posted a
video in two days and I deeply deeply
apologize
for realsies I'm so sorry guys I I meant
to leave it a Twitter message or
something but I forgot yeah
little this episode's gonna be pretty
informal by the way usually I come up
with a plan and all that stuff and today
I just got back I'm tired I don't have a
lot of time to record so we'll see what
happens here but I'm gonna have to come
up with some ideas for today mm-hmm oh I
know I know we could go take a walk
let's go take a walk
okay well that's a little bit lame we we
got to come up with some better ideas we
could let's go take a look around what
else is there to do let's go take a walk
by the beach well that was better
definitely better I enjoyed the sand but
it's it's still not quite there you know
what I mean let's go for a run by the
beach no horseback ride horseback ride
by the beach with fireworks yeah and we
will ride backwards oh yeah nailed it
perfect so I think the only thing I've
done since last episode is I finished up
our room here so let's go checked it out
you might remember last time this we
worked on the sorting system for this
that's all good and then I I finished up
the room here kinda I don't know if
we're gonna keep it exactly like this it
feels almost a bit plain but it is a
small room so maybe we don't need too
much with it and I still have to get rid
of these on you guys I don't have to but
maybe I should some people suggested I
put some dispensers with arrows in to
shoot at them with that's going here
yeah sorting system is working pretty
good though zombie stuff gunpowder
getting lots of gunpowder with
excellents arrows and
Bonz um yeah I got a brick lining for
this room I decided to go with a spruce
floor goes pretty nicely with brick I
would say a couple waterfalls
I used mushroom blocks I've never used
mushroom blocks for a build ever and I
kind of liked them actually oh that's
not true I did use mushroom blocks now
that I think of it on the minecraft
server in my nether tunnel that's right
yeah
got those then we got stone slab ceiling
I think it must have turn night them
because their drops have stopped but the
room might be a bit plain we need like
pixel art for the back or something I
don't know but it's good for now pretty
happy with that you can only reach three
and a half blocks oh that's why I wanted
slabs for the floor here if this was a
full block I would not be able to open
the chests here I'll show you go up one
more block can access it it's kind of
annoying so that's good and I've put
fences under these trapdoors so that I
would never fall down and also so I
don't sink down half a block when I walk
over it you know there's no transition
which is nice and that's all I got to
show so we have to fill 15 minutes or so
for this episode so let me think of some
more ideas we will harvest all the
nether warts all of it I say all of it
hahahahaha
oh but we will not stop there we will
harvest the mushrooms that is not the
end of our harvest we will harvest the
pumpkins and the melons and we will
spare no one
alright everybody so I came up with a
plan here we are going to do some
exploring today I've come a very long
way Zout here in the nether were 350 and
negative 1250 uh-huh
that's like 10,000
blocks in the overworld oops ah the
reason we came out here is because
somebody gave me a tip a while ago and I
have a spite ice biome here this is
actually the closest one to my place
apparently so we will go check it out
and see if it's a troll or not
hopefully not though because we actually
need Speight dice not spy dice Pat dice
for slime stuff we're doing because he
employs pressure plates on it and it
still behaves like ice which is kind of
special so let's see what we get
due to - oh we get rain that's not good
and we get flowers and darkness flowers
and darkness 8,000 what what
oh that's not good you see the numbers
right I'm not no no no no what I might
never get back home now what is going on
22400 negative 80,000 did my portals
just glitch out I think I've been
trolled but not by the person by the
game here I have never seen anything
like that happen let's see if we can go
back I kind of don't we Chen oh no nope
we can never go back oh we are 10,000
blocks out in the nether now
I don't even know what to say to that
what okay then
how could that have happened
i we looked at the coordinates before I
went through right ah okay I have to
think about what to do now I'm guessing
I just have to kill myself oh I brought
an inner chest that is good news that is
very good news
oh but the levels No
Oh No this is the worst thing that could
have happened to us is this how it ends
I wanted to see how I can go without
dying and I think it just ended
let me think though I need to figure
this out
okay then well I looked over the video
just to make sure my eyes did not
deceive me and yeah that was that was
some straight-up bogus right there
that's what that was
I I admit defeat
the game has won I will die I I thought
about watching back in making it
adventure an adventure out of it but you
know what it's it's not worth it my
world size would become huge because
we're so far out and yeah so
all right I'm going to head back to the
nether I'm going to I'm going to go
through that portal again and I want to
see what happens or if that was a one
time craziness okay so I made it back
here and we are going to go through
again just to see if it happens again
and to clarify we are at about 350
negative 1250 which is very far on its
own that's like a it's like a five
minute walk to get here but instead of
like teleporting eight blocks per one
block in the nether we teleport like 80
blocks per one block I'm pretty sure so
let's see if it happens again yeah same
spot that is so weird well that's some
crazy transportation right there I ever
need to get out super far super quick
that'll do the trick I I don't know what
to do
maybe I will try rebuild the portal one
block offset or something of where it
was and see if it happens again I guess
I gotta die again man
and it's still raining they can't get
any worse that I'm so tired ah gonna
sleep now
alright
things are looking brighter
yeah I have a good feeling about this
day all right I'm going to point this
out do I don't know if this is related
to it or not but for some reason the
world doesn't load here I had the same
problem last time I came by and we used
the portal we're pretty close to it
right now yeah and I never see this
happening single-player personally so
kind of strange all right so we are
going to move this and see if that fixes
it because I actually do want to go here
if this is the spite dice biome
this might be the greatest troll ever
they found a way to break the game or
something I don't know Bravo if so
because this this might be worse than
the triple blaze spawner that never
existed that you guys made me go look
for you found a way to kill me kind of I
guess we'll just move it over one block
or maybe tell you about I'm going to
like really move it over it will put it
over here now and we will see what
happens I'm going to remove the backing
to just the case for some reason that
affected it I want no similarities 350
man so weird so very weird
okay everybody well I hate to do this
but I figured this would be better than
no episode but it's gonna be a short one
a very short one today I have to go to
sleep this late I just got back from a
trip like I said so we're gonna go right
to the comments already says Ito
whatever happened to terraria I never
see those kind of videos out anymore
I do enjoy your LP maybe even more than
terraria but still what made you stop so
if you guys don't know I used to do
terraria videos with Zee stow we stopped
because it's sort of a linear game and
we reached the end of the content I'm
actually surprised I get this question a
lot which is why I'm bringing it up
because in that last episode we recorded
we said why we were going to stop and we
basically ran out of content and we
might resume again when more is released
such as the 1.3 patch I believe is
coming out soon which might be a big
patch and we might continue then
so until then there is no terraria
because we've played it a lot there's
over 50 episodes of the series which is
quite a bit actually ah was it 50 I
might have that number wrong wait a sec
don't quote me on that
I don't quote me on that anyway again
sorry guys I'm going to be back to my
normal schedule starting tomorrow but
hopefully this one holds you over until
then I haven't not here though i if you
have ideas on that portal thing let me
know too
it might be a very weird snapshot
related thing or might be well known I
have no idea I've never seen anything
like that before though um that's it for
me thanks for watching have yourselves a
great day and I hope you're enjoying
your summer bye bye
you