hey everybody how's it going I wanted to
start off today's episode by showing off
this absolutely incredible ravine and
cave system I found I found a bunch of
stuff to finally found some diamonds
happy about that
red stone it's pretty cool there is a
creeper here waiting to jump down seems
to be okay up there though
yeah I think they're mean kind of
branches off okay well maybe we won't go
down there yeah it's pretty awesome
though goes up to the ocean I saw some
squid floating around up there too
can't see him now and over here it's a
glob of flowing big lava pool so spawner
over there
kamikaze creepers it's awesome
Yeah right there is where the spawner is
but just what else I just found some
more diamond this is my fortune 3 pick
one
oh wow that's what I like to see you
seem to get more redstone now when you
use fortune on it
one two three four five six one two
three four five six seven or maybe I was
just unlucky before I don't know because
I could only get five or six before
using it to one might be lava here I
should check that's okay - one two can
get up to four I believe with Fortune
three which is pretty awesome
yeah I'm just loaded I should probably
think about hitting back soon but I want
to check out that spawner first sounds
like there's water in there there
definitely is
you're very close to bedrock here that's
kind of hoping that it would go down to
the voyage or something like that it's
not quite that closely just lights oh
okay
came in from on top and that should do
it
check out the chest Oh - cocoa beans not
bad
all right well I think I'm gonna head
back home now because I do not want to
lose this stuff this is actually pretty
cool you know how there's water above
the spawner here you know it's above
come on go faster there's a pool water
with lava and there's even a lily pad
lapis pretty cool this is a very very
neat place so I'm swimming my way out of
here and there's more on the back it's
abandoned mineshaft
and I got a buddy here hanging out with
me goes up to the ocean and we end up
where hey cool floating islands awesome
I think that's the glowing tree isn't it
maybe not we're near spawn now whatever
I'll find my way back somehow well we
made it back safe and sound
got plenty of diamond now and I'm about
to do one of my absolute favorite things
in this game making a whole stack of
iron blocks this is the greatest feeling
ever
awesome alright everybody we're back in
the nether now as you can probably tell
pretty easily
we're going to get started on the blaze
farm finally we got a lot figured out
last episode but now we're going to
actually build it and the basic plan
behind this is we want all the blaze to
collect at a central point and then
we're going to hook up a crusher like
docum did with this chief spider thing
and that'll get them to low health and
then we'll be able to punch them or
something - to do the final blow on them
is the plan so I'm going to get started
building here and use stone bricks and
glass and I did definitely did not bring
enough blocks with me but we'll we'll
see what we can do here so I'm gonna
highlight the frame around it and when
this is all done I'll be removing this
netherrack all around this area here but
just for now I'm going to leave it in
okay go and maybe I'll go in one more
block yet and then I'm going to use
glass just so we can see what's going on
inside this is going to be the central
centerpiece of our nether base that's
what we're going to be looking at yeah
definitely never enough blocks okay oh I
went too thick year so nice these things
break quicker now
okay so two blocks thick and then I'm
going to put glass on top on the sides
and hopefully that looks pretty decently
afterward okay and the so we're going to
move the blaze around using pistons and
I have played around with this before in
the past and creative mode which is a
really good thing actually because it
would be so difficult trying to tweak
this thing playing in a legit world and
trying to figure it out so I'm glad I
have the experience so then this will
come down we have to leave that one
block airspace above there so that see
I'm going to leave this one air block
space so that they'll be able to spawn
at this level here and put the frame
down usually when I build stuff in my LP
world I do it
for the first time in the lp world I
don't pre build it and then rebuild it
in my LP because that would take a lot
of the fun out of it for me but this is
an exception I haven't fully built it in
creative mode but I I have played around
with ideas so I have it pretty well in
mind how I want to do it it's kind of
going to be like a giant ice cream cone
okay so maybe I'll do a little more
off-camera here and then we'll get back
to it all right so I did a supply run
brought some goodies over here made a
bunch of pistons - got more glass I've
been working on it I'm pretty sure I
don't know I think I'm going to have to
make the border one thick and replace
some of these stone bricks with glass in
the end just to make it look better I'm
not sure we won't be able to tell until
we remove all this nether brick around
it oops
and then we'll be able to see from the
distance how how good or how bad it
looks but we'll worry about that later
so yeah I've been extending this glass
down like this and we're about to start
the ice for the cone part of it and I'll
probably link to people in the
description of this video because
they've done a lot of work on blaze
firms I did a search and that they seem
to be two of the big guys working on it
and one of the guys actually made a cone
style as well which is going to be very
similar to what I'm building here so and
check them out okay so the very lowest
the blaze will spawn is at this level
here so I'm going to start bringing out
the cone here
so they'll be able to spot on top these
blocks I'm placing right now and just
leaving a little door here so I can get
out okay then it will go down and the
block will have a two block drop so that
the blaze will not be able to get back
up up here if it's confusing now don't
worry I'll make more sense once it's all
finished this is a little hard to
visualize at the moment okay now go down
one more layer here and so that is this
collecting them all to the very center
going to be careful around this drop so
it'll come in one more block like this
okay once the blaze fall down to this
level here I believe I know they'll
still be in range they have to fall down
one more yet sorry I'm not explaining
things very well right now
okay so what I'll do next is we'll have
pressure plates and Pistons repeaters
etc I'm going to skip putting pistons on
this first level here just because I
don't think they're really necessary the
blaze will probably fall down on their
own but it wouldn't hurt to add them
either I'm just I'm just being cheap and
then we'll have pressure plates here on
all four sides one there and let's see I
just behind here is where no not there
over here where the pistons will go okay
so basically we'll have repeaters next
to these pressure plates they will go to
the block and then the sticky pistons
will go on top of that oops and then
we'll have more stone bricks in front of
them okay so if a blaze is up here and
he wanders down lands on a pressure
plate the block will push him down one
more and then when he falls down one
more same thing will happen until they
all end up in a 2x2 area okay
so I think I'm just going to go ahead
and finish this up and then you'll be
able to see it a bit better and I might
add one more piston in the corners okay
so the second level here is just about
done at so it doesn't matter where the
blaze land on the second level they'll
activate one of these pressure plates
and that will cause the piston push them
down one more level to the center and
then they'll be I think a three block
drop and the land on more pressure
plates and then that will push them to a
2x2 area so in front of every piston is
a block and I just I'm just leaving a
doorway there for now and then there's a
repeater for each one as well so that's
all there is to it for these corner ones
I hope this works they should get pushed
into into this pressure plate here that
that will push them off it's important
to use these sticky pistons instead of a
like with a block on them instead of
just a regular piston because sometimes
the regular pistons glitch out with mobs
and it won't push them so the the mob
will still be on the pressure plate with
the piston inside of them and they will
never move away from that area so
they'll get stuck but if there's a block
and that happens they'll suffocate so
that's important so just don't use
regular pistons so what I'm saying okay
so that's one level done and when this
is all done I'll remove the cobblestone
as safely as I can I'm going to start
working on the next level down here okay
so the third level is finished now
there's 12 pressure plates Pistons
repeaters on it this level here has 20
if we were to do them on this top level
there would be another 28 which is
pretty expensive 28 pistons 28 repeaters
that's why I'm skipping it it as long as
there's not six blades up here at a time
it shouldn't matter much because they'll
wander off and then they'll get sent
down here and they'll be far enough away
from the spawner that they won't affect
the spawning rates we'll see how it
works once it's all done here and it's
red pigment dye okay so there is one
issue here though I'm having these
pressure plates are affecting the
Pistons below as well as the ones above
isn't it no way it's not a huge issue
because as soon as we get pushed off of
them it will retract within a second
anyway but yeah a little bit will stand
on a block for a second or half a second
there before it gets retracted should be
okay it's just due to that piston glitch
or whatever that makes the piston bud
switch is possible like even if I remove
this repeater stays extended but if I go
off it retracts but now if I walk on it
it doesn't extend unless a block updates
near the piston okay so that is that we
will set up our crusher down here a
little viewing area and so I got to
connect the fortress to down here
somehow so I'll be doing a little bit of
tunneling so instead of our base being
oops instead of our base being up at
this level here we're going to be down
down there will be our main level for
right now I have a path down to the
crusher area here this is where it will
happen the drop is four blocks down so
one two three four and I don't know
exactly how I'm going to wire this yet
and we probably won't be able to do that
this episode but I'll tell you what I
want what I want to happen with this
wiring I'm going to have I think Pistons
here no not there you can have Pistons
at the back there and in over here
facing the right way
be careful there's gas out there okay so
these will have blocks on them and then
below that we'll have another group of
pistons in the same position maybe maybe
I'm not sure yet oh he just felt saw me
like that okay so that that's how the
Pistons might be and then this will be
closed off too and they'll be glass in
front here so the blaze can escape and
then I think I'll have two buttons oops
when I press the first one all these
blocks will close in that will cause a
suffocating to happen the button will
have to be hooked up to a pulse extender
so that the pulse takes eight or nine
seconds or whatever it is to suffocate
the mob's just to the point where
they're they have like half a heart
health left ideally without killing them
then after that time passes
this bottom these bottom four Pistons
need to retract again but these top ones
will stay closed so it'll look like this
basically and then I'll be able to punch
the blaze and then when I hit the final
the second button here these tapas tins
will open again and let the blaze down
and that's just so they don't get mixed
together where some are suffocate and
then some aren't I need a shutoff for
the thing and ideally I want these back
two Pistons to extend first and then the
two side ones and that will bring the
blaze up to these front two blocks where
they'll get crushed in that way their
drops will be within range where I can
pick them up
easily instead of like landing in the
back here where I can't reach them
that's kind of the plan I might mess
around with this a bit yet I don't know
we'll see yeah it's kind of expecting
this but the Pistons won't work how I
have them positioned here I tried it out
so that extends the top one extends the
bottom one but the problem is you won't
be able to retract this bottom one
because the top ones being powered due
to that piston glitch so that won't work
because this is the one we need to
retract so that they won't suffocate to
the point of dying and the top one is
what keeps them from coming down but I
should be able to fix that just by
offsetting the Pistons from each other
so they can't be directly on top or
below each other so I could maybe put
the top two over here instead of at the
back wall and then instead of having one
here I could maybe put it over here and
see how that works out yeah so this
seems to work okay so if I power the top
one it extends bottom one can extend and
I'm able to retract the bottom one which
is what I need
so they're independent now they're not
affecting each other and I can either
put the power into this block or this
one this block or this one it's
invisible block right here uh-huh
and then other front Pistons will be
here I'm thinking I will use glass for
this for these top ones just so that
we'll be able to see the mobs above so
to look like that'll extend and get two
more levers here so I should be able to
power these ones on the side here you
won't be able to see the wiring that way
she'll be okay and yeah I think that'll
work yeah all right so maybe what I'll
do is I'll just put some temporary
blocks here for now and we'll I'll
remove the cobble and we can see this in
action
because I don't really have time to do
all this wiring today I came in through
the ceiling here I'm going to just
remove them like this and get out of
here as quick as I can because these
guys are going to spawn in like crazy
now
yes is pretty dangerous I would
recommend putting your good stuff away
in chess before you attempt this is it's
pretty scary
make sure your full health all the time
or full full food they are able to fly
up that you so if you think they're
going to fall down from it to the bottom
there think again
ah dang that's that
the situation gets bad you can always
just block yourself in for a while to
recover and then try again or you know
the best thing probably is just to do it
from outside all around the sides
instead of actually going inside the
thing okay I think I got it all they're
tracking me now though I think it's
because I attacked them hopefully or
maybe they can see through Pistons here
I don't know I'll have to watch it for
walls try to figure out what's going on
yeah it's working pretty good they seem
to do their thing there there's a few
issues with it though you know how the
pressure plates were we're activating
the ones below the piston is below well
I'm having that problem here these these
crusher and holding Pistons are getting
activated whoa take down a new problem
what the heck that is not a good thing
okay I'm right here yeah
gonna have to tweak it a bit after all
like I said I didn't build the whole
thing in creative mode and I'll have to
put some blocks above the spawner there
because if they spawn there like on top
of it they won't ever move probably so
yeah should be able to get it working
but we'll I'll do that some other time
I'll say goodbye for today thank you for
watching and see you again next time