ah yeah yeah give me candy
I want that day mm-hmm
looks like we got ourselves a friend but
you know what dude you should really go
for Jeff Jeff is a lot more tasty than
this guy
this guy he's he's been here a long time
he's getting old losing his flavor Jeff
you see Jeff over there oh man he's just
he's just waiting for you should go get
Jeff I'm wondering I think I have that
outfit still here oh there it is I'm
gonna give this guy some clothes and see
if he'll stay around for a while because
he'll just stay locked in that spot if
you'll put these on I think not all
these gonna put him on no is he
oh they disappeared I think oh I picked
them up
obviously that would do it yeah but you
get him to yeah he might not want him
might might not be his type come on pick
him up no it's not his type he's not
into fashion this guy too bad
Jeff over there Jeff is the guy you want
Oh
oh not me Jeff what's he do now he's
finding a different route he's coming
for you that'd be crazy if he could find
his way like through down here jump into
this room no no he trapped himself okay
so hello everyone how are we doing today
ah I've been I'm doing okay I'm doing
great excellent to you in fact and I
just been kind of wandering around my
world you're trying to decide what I
want to do today for this episode and I
got a few random plans that we might do
but I think maybe maybe to start off
with work on Wilson for a bit because we
stupid last episode working on him um
what I kind of want to do is start
working on what we got to put in a clock
a master clock for keeping track of the
age I want to start maybe setting up
some of these interactive features with
them so one idea was to have a way of
feeding him feeding our pets through
hoppers so the way that would work and I
got a lot of this stuff don't I I'm
going to put these in here too the way
this would work is we would kind of have
just like a slot where we could throw
food probably something like this so
when he's hungry
we can we can feed them just by throwing
a food item into the hopper and then the
hoppers going to work out what type of
food item it is and affect the stats
that way like certain foods might
recover more hunger some some might add
other boosts like the happiness or or
something else in
stats but at the expense of maybe
something else like maybe it adds a lot
more weight to our pet or something like
that
I'm not exactly sure it will probably be
fairly complicated so I don't think I'm
going to do too many different types of
food what do we want we want something
to feed our pets so we'll have a slot
for that and maybe next to it will have
another slots I think at once oh you
know what we'll do because I also want
to add the ability for our pet to get
sick if his health is low he has an
increased chance of getting sick
randomly um what we should do I guess
with our hunger slot here we'll add the
option of giving him medicine like
instant health potions and that will
take him out of being six states um how
would that work but if we give him one
when he's not sick it's gonna negatively
affect him yeah something like that so
we can do that in this slot itself we
need indicator lights for when he's sick
and when he's sleeping so we might put
that down here we also need a way of
interacting with him like by playing
with him not sure how to do that yet
let's see was this workout - oh you know
what I'm gonna do actually I'm going to
make this water I'm going to extend this
one block wider because the way it is
right now if I did this it would be an
even number and I want an odd number
because this is six blocks across if we
add one more block it will become oh no
no wait a minute
maybe that won't work yeah yeah we'll do
it that way yeah I'm going to add one
more block to the width on both sides of
this thing I've been trying to think how
I want to do the attention stat on
Wilson like how are we going to refill
that meter do do we want to actually set
up little games to play with them and if
so how crazy are we going to get with
those because I can get really crazy
with the mini games but then I'm not
going to have the space form or do we
just want to press a button and it will
take care of his attention or I'm not
sure but one one thing I do want to do
if we if we don't just do the button
thing one thing I probably will include
is a jukebox mechanic so it he might
want us to play a song for him when he's
in need of attention so play a song and
already feel his attention a little bits
and you can interact with redstone with
jukeboxes which is awesome I fixed this
other day during the livestream I did
just a quick little practice one
that's a new Big O all you know it's
really cool guys
sounds really loud to me this snapshot
you can run upstairs that is such a good
change oh man I love that so much you
don't lose your sprint anymore a lot of
my staircases I designed like these ones
just so I wouldn't lose my sprint
running them up running up them so now I
can if I do stairs in the future I can I
don't have to worry about that as much
just good but yeah anyway so I got that
extra bordered on both sides so it's
going to be an odd number base now we
could do something like this where we
have four slots I don't know how that's
going to work I thought about that
giving him a potion to cure sickness and
that would be cool except you can't
actually stack potions so there wouldn't
be an easy way of detecting them so I'm
my updated rethink that I'm not sure I
started setting up the master clock up
here the wiring it's getting crazy
already and we just sort of begun I'm
scared to see what happens with this
like that is that's a lot of wiring
things are going to get crazy ah yeah
for the ages that we want this to be a
really slow doesn't change very much
stat so I'm going to use stacks of 64
items we're going to fill it all the way
up with cobblestone and we have our
locking mechanic up here I set up the
hopper timer here this is our master
master timer for the whole system so we
can control the speed
everything works from this how many
items we put in here so it'll be easy to
configure or even change in the future
I'll probably have to move this so but I
just want to do a simple little test
here maybe we'll just put in let's put
in eight items dope wrong one there we
go put in eight items I'm going to just
temporarily hook this up to the age
statin we'll see how it works give us an
idea of how long we want that pulse to
be just not switching
oh no it's switch okay ah yeah I'll just
do maybe I'll do this like that but yeah
I'll definitely have to move this later
dad just run wire is it not going to
make the torch switch oh it pulsed very
very quickly there no item got through
no item might be too fast for most of
these variable things I don't want the
timing to be very long like probably
somewhere between 1 1 and 10 ticks for
all the variables if we make it really
long it's going to take up a lot of
space so it's not really ideal we got to
do this
I wonder if we'll go through now oh it
didn't switch at all now
okay I'm going to switch at now let's
get this to three and down we go
darn it's so hard building this oh
there's just no space no space and go do
parkour all the time okay it should be
no line items through oh you know what
it is I bet you this is set the wrong
let's change this picture that's what it
is
so now Oh No still inlet one through
they've been changing the timings and
stuff on everything so maybe hoppers are
more specific now I like takes three and
a half ticks or at least it did to send
an item through but occasionally if you
did a time shorter than that it would
randomly let one through every now and
then but maybe it's very specific now
since this is less than three-and-a-half
say three maybe it's not going to let
any through ever so we'll try four well
this torch might be locking it could
that be it why isn't it working
I'm confused
okay well yeah it should be this way
yeah okay there we go so now it's
letting one item through every time it
seems like it's more specific now that's
good I'll be easier to control things so
if it's a three it's not going to let an
item through is it now if it's at four
should do it every time yeah okay cool
so that's the shortest delay we can have
for the variables for ticks
all right I've just been kind of
watching this for a little bit here I
went FD for 15 minutes with this set at
3:00 just to make sure no items were
randomly passing through over time and
good news they're not so yeah hoppers
are very very much more stable now than
they used to be I'm using oh six eighty
now so somewhere along the line they
they made them more stable which is good
and I'll be able to fine-tune control
everything that means and this here is
going to be our lowest common
denominator basically in this whole set
up the age variable is going to move the
slowest out of everything just one item
per
update from our main clock here while
the other things like the hunger and
whatever we might want one two three
four
you know items passing through per
update but no less than one so nothing
nothing is going to be less than this
one and it's just a big balancing act to
get them to change at a rate we want
them to based off of this one so yeah
that's about it we're going to go do
something else so we've spent quite a
bit of time on this today more than I
expected
oh man he's going to kill me I do need
to add a main reset to this as well so
like if I if I pull a lever this is
going to drain down to zero this is
going to go up to five this will go up
to five this will go to three or and
stop that will go up to five that will
go up to five and it will be like a new
pet in case it dies or something we need
a way of resetting it so that will be
fun we're going to head over to my
stronghold base alright guys here we are
at the stronghold base and it's been
quite a while since we were last year
I've been neglecting it's not gonna lie
it's kind of giving me like if
something's not going good in this team
I like to step back and think about it
for a bit and I've decided now I
definitely want to do some major
replanting with this because not that
this is necessarily bad what I was doing
here but everything kind of feels dated
to me with this build and I would build
it differently but I was to redo it so
rather than continuing it and then be
unhappy we should just take a couple
steps back and replant some stuff I
think like the storage room for example
I did I did really like this storage
system at the time but now we have
trapped chests
and there's automatic sorting methods
and that kind of thing we could
definitely have a lot more fun if we
were to do something like that here I've
mentioned this before but I'm getting
sick of the symmetrical building style
I've been doing a lot of like like
there's my main problem with it is it
doesn't look different from other angles
like if I was to look here and then if I
was go to if I was to go to the other
side here it would be pretty much the
same thing I'm looking at like there's
no there's no character to it so we
should change that up not that some
symmetry is bad I do like some symmetry
in what I'm building but not this
perfect four quadrant circular thing we
got going here we need to change that
the mob system is actually good I think
we'll still use it but we might build a
second one and use this one if we want
to keep the mobs alive and use a second
one if we just want the item drops so it
will auto kill them and it will be a
higher efficiency one and you know
there's other stuff too like we were
putting ice underneath here and we don't
need to do this like we have beacons now
this is just like this gives you a speed
boost if you jump on it on the half
slabs um you know it's better just to
use a beacon now than to do something
like this
so just stuff like that I want to get
into fixing this place up and
restructuring it so I'm going to tear
all this ice out for sure and we won't
get into it this episode I'm going to
think about it a bit more but yeah just
want to let you know the plan
awesome so I got all the ice ripped out
from under the floor there was old man
there was a lot of it's like it's a big
surface area so I got that all out just
the first step towards renovating I
don't know exactly how much I'm changing
it but probably quite a bit we might
even just completely redo the whole
thing
and maybe change the style as well I
really want to make something with
quartz so maybe we'll do I know quartz
another brick look really good together
so we might do that or we might do
quartz and sandstone and maybe a darker
block mixed in or I don't know exactly
what what we're going to do yet we won't
get too far into it but if you know a
good color combo for quartz blocks let
me know and we might go with that but
anyway moving on let's head back to the
other base and maybe do a little project
there Oh incoming squid I can see it
he's gonna fall he's gonna fall come on
he's a fighter he is definitely a
fighter oh there he goes
uh-huh oh what's going on my performance
just started stinking like crazy though
I'm only getting 20 frames at the moment
um trying to think about what it is the
clock on that on Wilson is not running I
checked that and I cut down these trees
maybe it's freaking out trying to make
them grow again I don't know my game is
not going or it's not running too well
if I go over this way see him frame
rates going up slightly we're 23 I
noticed it was really good if I got
close to Wilson for some reason
26 if I climb up this ladder gets up to
30 no problem if I'm down low it drops
its really I don't what's going on 25 29
Oh huh smooth lighting is on I'm going
to turn it off yes you know now you know
what I'm just gonna I'm going down great
I'll be right back all right we're back
- oh for a snapshot Oh for a and it's
working a lot better
ah it's weird it was like I know it
wasn't as good with those six because
there's some performance issues they got
a workout but it was working fine for
the first part of this episode now it's
kind of teetered out for some reason but
yeah you know what I want to work on is
this so we've had this water here a very
long time the plans for it kind of got
changed a little bit
we have bunch of wiring behind your now
so that Skyview we're going to do a
water elevator before the original plan
with this water was we were going to
fill this tunnel up with water and it
was going to be like a boat access
routes go to other parts of the cave
there is a lot of wiring this way so it
would be tough to do that to make it go
to this part of the cave but it might be
possible what now I'm lost now I am lost
okay here we are underneath the stairs
but since that water has been there for
so long I can't upstairs anymore now
since that water is there for so long I
don't feel right it's getting rid of it
so what I want to do is try make that
work and maybe we'll have like a boat
access only area part of the base that
could be cool so maybe we'll try to get
the rest to spread over here and then
we'll start terraforming this a bit
we got Pistons up here so we want to if
we do have water down here we want to
cut down a little bit give it a little
more Headroom and we'll just see how
this goes and maybe we'll make it branch
off mmm where would we want it to branch
off maybe to branch off to the right
somehow um there's also all this space
here where I could put a bedroom or
something because I still haven't built
one of those I know there's that little
area at the top of the stairs there
where people keep telling me to put a
bedroom or a place for my bed but I
might want to do something fancy with
that I'm not entirely sure yet Saul
wants an area where I can do some wiring
which would be over here oh okay I know
what that is that is my other storage
area there's nothing wrong with those no
blocks guys by the way it's just leaving
the world and coming back it does that
it's just an issue with no box Keane
updated let's go down at least one more
probably at least two more actually I
want the water to be at this level here
so water rate where I'm placing this
block I want that to be the surface and
make it come up to the stairs here I
think that would look cool if there was
water to the left of the stairs when you
come down here
so yeah i'll terraform this a bit
off-camera and see where we get with it
okay so up here I also want a little bit
of grass over here not too much not too
much is something like that there'll be
a we need a boat dispenser could put one
over there maybe under the water
yeah then we get to this parts I guess
because we have the enchanting room up
there remember there's some Pistons I
got that covered now we'll actually want
the water at this level so that we can
have a three high clearance here because
if it's too high it's going to be really
crap feeling so we'll have the water at
this level actually we could keep going
here we might want to keep going and
make it go down eventually I want to
start working underneath all this stuff
like we have a heavily a downstairs area
we've never really reached yet so at
some point we might want to expand our
cave downwards and this water route
could be a good way of accessing it in
fact the original plan was to have a
pool water here and we might still do
that if we did that we could have like a
water elevator that shot up here from
the lower levels
hmm so basically what I'm doing here is
I'm trying to make layout little grassy
area next to the river so we're all this
soil is that I'm placing oh what's up
here what is this oh this is behind the
enchanting room okay a little bit of a
cave there still yes for for grass and
reeds and that kind of thing maybe
flowers if I can get a tree or two in
that would look really cool too
then all this this area here is where
the water is going to be so much gravel
down here in my way it's terrible so I
guess we can try this out see how it
goes wait a second
it's going to be a lot easier to modify
it without the water and so I'm trying
to get it going to get that going we're
trying to get things figured out before
I do this part but we'll see how this
looks I'm going to make the water too
thick so if we break all these should
fill up pretty good I love ice blocks
man they're so cool all right get a
couple more in here OOP OOP and I'm just
placing all over the place
sweet just a couple more and that's
that's the bottom layer now we want it
to go up one more whoo smash be tough to
do yeah we'll do this I love like they
changed it now where you can create
source blocks on top of water blocks so
much much easier to fill water area like
this I'm going to make it come over to
the other edge see if we do a diagonal
here it's the easiest way of doing it
that now it should join right oh yeah
beautiful that is so cool
all right we got an empty spot here and
that was easy
that's that is so cool okay that's our
general water area
we'll definitely want some lights I'll
probably make this come out some more
yet as well see now this is the
challenging part trying to make a water
track to get up and down here in the
boats so don't really want flowing water
like we could do this but it would be
flowing
tell you what I'm going to close this
off for now
I'll try lay out the icebox in a way
that'll work and here is where we're at
I'll take you through it
I built a framework for my water here
that's what these ice blocks are about
and we're going to fill this in from the
bottom up and then we're going to melt
all the ice blocks still got to do a lot
of shaping too like I'm I'm going to try
put a tree here I believe there will
probably be a fork off in this water
somewhere as well I haven't decided
where yeah so what we got to do take our
ice see where's the bottom layer bottom
layer bottom layer bottom layer here
this is our bottom layer we're gonna
flood this they're actually really
challenging to work work out the water
mechanics till all this hopefully it
turns out okay so that bottom is solid
then we go up another one and do the
same thing and the ice blocks are
holding the water in place for each
layer all right see is that right they
come out further and we need one there
okay so that's another layer I'm going
to get to the top here and then I'm
going to melt them all this one's
actually really big layer the thing is I
can't put the ice blocks next to each
other like they have to be diagonally
like that otherwise when they melt
they're going to update each other and
it's all just gonna fall to pieces
which might be a big problem with this
I'm not sure like if an Enderman ever
came down here and place the block next
to the water and updated it oh I would
be upset I tell ya but we'll see how it
goes all right and the reason I want
this extra pushin area behind the ice is
so when we drive the boat up we don't
just ran right into the the cliff
hopefully it'll be a smooth smooth the
transition to come up here because it'll
be all this water cushion yeah this is
what it's like all filled up and now
oops
basically we just need to melt all these
ice blocks and it should be all done I
believe so we're going to put torches
next to the ice and try melt them as
quick as possible and I'll come back to
you once it's all done and hopefully it
doesn't get updated and see they're
starting to transform I will just have a
flow though all right that's right I
forgot about that hopefully it's not too
big of a deal all right guys here is our
water stream it looks pretty cool
actually I like it with the with the
flow aspect to it it looks neat but it
doesn't make that constant flowing water
sound which is also nice I don't know if
I'm going to be able to ride a boat up
it though because of this I forgot if
there's water below it that it'll do
that or near it
um the other thing is we should make
another water stream a waterfall come to
here so it looks like this pond is being
filled up from somewhere because as it
is right now it looks a little strange
not going to lie but let's try it out I
got a boats going down should be fairly
straightforward oh oh I'm going to raise
the ceiling a little bit too yet
where I 1000 the slime noises make them
stop okay here's the challenge show can
we get back up oh not even nope
darn it can't be done ah it's too bad I
thought that was going to work
it looks cool at least but ah too bad
that's what I was really going for I
guess we'll have to do an elevator if we
want to get back up but it just
instantly turns the boat around
and it's the boats rude glitchy at the
moment it's not letting me move what's
the deal with that well that was weird
hmm
but I'll keep working on that try make
it look nice down here oh now we ain't
getting up to you're too bad alright and
we'll add a little more grass the sides
and everything it should look pretty
good we just have time for one comment
today because the episode is getting a
little long here but Jacob says you
should add music to your montages that
makes them more interesting and besides
I and many others I'm sure would like to
know what kind of music you like I do
add music every once in a while to my
montages and pens uh uh how how the
montages work out I guess those quick
cut ones are really easy to put together
so that's why I do those usually because
they're really really fast to edit
compared to a music one the other thing
is though I can't just pick any music I
want like he says I would like to know
what kind of music you like it's not
like I just pick a song you hear on the
radio or a song you have on CD or
something like that
No
no there is copyright issues galore that
I got to worry about I have to use
specifically licensed songs Creative
Commons and then even out of those not
all of them I can use so I actually have
a very very very small library of songs
I'm comfortable with using in my videos
so that's why I don't use music too
often at the moment anyway so yeah
that's answer to that question thank you
everyone for your questions and your
feedback I do enjoy it and I thank you
all for watching as always I hope you
have a good day see you later