hey how's it going everyone this is the
ethos lab how are you guys doing today
I'm doing quite well myself personally
thank you for for asking and for caring
that is of course if you did care if you
didn't obviously your mother never loved
you because you're some sort of monster
um but yeah so hopefully you guys get
your cookies in your and your ice cream
and your chips and your Yahoo's and yo
hoes and and relish and cantaloupe and
pickles with horseradish whatever weird
snacks you're into oh it's still burning
I thought it was fixed I thought it was
fixed cuz it's been a long time here
without a burning and I updated to the
see darn it
ah well I better put this out shouldn't
I otherwise I might spread to over here
yet okay I thought that was fixed I
guess not but yeah we are we are rockin
another episode here let's do some
enchanting you can see I'm level 73
because oh wait I just harvested those
never mind you guys gonna harvest the
vines level 73 because I was gathering
up XP while using the gold farm I I did
three runs with it and decide just to
keep it all OOP um so that when I start
recording we could do a big enchantment
here so we should be able to do like 15
things using the new enchanting system
so this should be pretty fun and I'm
going to try to do some value shopping
here get exactly what I want and see how
successful we are so I think top
priority is going to be looting if we
can ever get it sink in looting 3 may be
looting 2 is good too though let's see
what our book option is power 3 no
definitely not
these are probably all going to be
efficiency
Oh punch nope um excuse me
I hope you didn't hear that and breaking
okay we're doing the sword doing a sword
learning - is fine just looting - darn
it okay let's try again
mmm I'm breaking three oh yeah yeah yeah
yeah we want that excellent okay and
breaking three is also a top priority
one oh that's not the sword let's just
get a bunch of tools because we're
probably going to do a few things here
now there we go that's the sword I used
to have labels here I should get them
back all right let's try again
and sharpen this three nope let's go for
the book feather falling for that's
pretty good if we see infinity in the
bow I think we should take that or
fortune three with the pick would be
good too um yeah okay I think we're
going to go what was it feather falling
let's do this all right
oh yes Wow wait a minute feather
following efficiency for fire aspects
for the sword fire protection is for
armor this is like a different item for
each thing
so really it's only like one or two
enchantments you can get fire protection
and feather falling together everything
else is separate that was kind of weird
protection 3 no sharpness 4 it's not
really great infinity nope can we get
fortune efficiency for a let's just go
ahead and do that oh we did get fortune
awesome all right so we're doing pretty
good on the value here
we still got 61 levels holy smokes let's
hurry this is going to take too long on
a fire aspect
no no I'm freaking three yeah all right
what was the pick yeah let's do that
Oh baby that's a good one I like that
sharpness three No
hi there phone oh we've done this
already last time we got four enchants
let's try it again
nope failed dr3 no a sword
come on yes yes we got looting three
awesome and just not just leaving three
well you can't win them all
that's good though I can put other stuff
on it no let's try did I hire the book
thorns no I don't like thorns very much
personally because it makes your stuff
wear out quicker what am I missing here
I need more pics there we go
that was probably a really weird noise I
apologize I do that sometimes uh okay we
tried that
what would out what did I want here
let's go ahead and do it that's decent I
think if it's not something I want just
go ahead and do a pic and probably be
happy with it
oh man okay let's go ahead and do a
shovel kind of a dud pic again just
efficiency for darn power for no frame
one ah yes see this hopefully we get
sharpness oh yeah
sharpen is for unbreaking 3 that's not
too bad mmm man enchanting this took a
lot longer and I thought it would tell
you what I think I'm just going to go
ahead and do books for the rest of it
this value shopping takes too long on
camera oh yeah I totally do one at one
at a time jet blast protection I'll take
it that's actually not terrible if I
ever want to play with TNT like cannons
or something that's always a good thing
to have around and I don't think I had
any blast protection books actually I
could use them all up and getting a lot
of feather falling oh and that is it
okay we did it we made it all the way
cool so I think what I want to do guys
I'm gonna I'm gonna pick that up by the
way I just got and load a few things in
my storage room I think let's head over
to the nether I want to show you a
project I've been working on for quite
some time I'd give you an update on on
where it's at so I will see you guys
there in just a second yeah so to
introduce you guys to the idea of what
I've been doing here if we look in this
chest you can see I got a few stacks of
nether quartz here and
we've got some blocks up there I think
here's even some more where is it odd
box
oh I guess there's oh yeah there's three
blocks in there Wow so so much nether
quartz it's amazing but yeah as you guys
know I'm not too fond on like going on
nether quartz gathering adventures so
they're just you don't get quite enough
for the amount of time you put into it I
feel and it's not super enjoyable if you
do it for long periods of time it gets
kinda grindy of half an hour an hour's
fine every now and then but but I don't
like doing it in aid of any large amount
and of all the things to collect in this
game nether quartz is one of my least
favorites um I had a creeper blow up
here by the way it came through the
portal instant boom glowed all four
portals on me - that was fun um so if we
go down this tunnel quite a ways like
three four hundred blocks and then take
a left and go another three four hundred
blocks we come out to over here and this
is a nether fortress we found a long
time ago I don't know if you remember it
but I think when they added oh look out
when they added chests the fortresses we
did some exploring around the nether to
try find a new one and we found this
fortress which was pretty amazing
because there's so much lab around it if
I ever wanted to set up a wither
skeleton firm this was the ideal place
of course there was a lot of like
islands and land outside of the fortress
that had to be cleared still and that is
where the quartz has come from like look
at all these skeletons we got here
already grazie
it's working so good already and I still
have a fair bit to do to it
come on give me some more those wither
skeleton heads they're so rare it's
crazy how many of these you have to kill
there's another guy over here yeah lots
of laughs around here I ran right into
him as you can see though I still have
some land I need to clear like there's a
big chunk there I would like to get rid
of there's lots of like overhangs like
up there there's a pretty thin piece of
an overhang that could be cleared out
pretty easily so what I do this is the
multitasking when I need nether quartz I
like to come here
and as I'm prepping this area for wither
skeletons I like it oops I didn't need
to break that as I'm clearing the land
out I come across all kinds and other
courts buried in it and and I can do two
things at once basically I can click I
can prep this area for wither skeletons
as I clear out the land and I can get
the nether quartz which is in my opinion
a lot more enjoyable than doing nether
quartz hunting so that's what I've been
doing and it's been working out pretty
good
but this area is turning into quite the
wither skeleton spawning area so let's
see awed by the way this this fortress
used to have like netherrack all over
the top of it it's all gone now because
I've cleared it out you can see like how
high the nether rack is there that used
to be land all the way up up to there I
believe and there was there's pretty
much netherrack over top all these
walkways but there's not anymore it's
all opening can easily see wither
skeletons whenever they spawn oh that
looked like it we got it but we didn't
darn but there's a lot of things we can
do here yet like we can prep these
walkways get rid of this piece up like
one high things that'll help us get a
few more um let's see ooh much stuff on
me I want to start knocking down these
walls inside like we have all these
rooms that are sort of not getting used
by me at the moment because they're just
so hard to see there's wither skeletons
on the inside here but if we start like
taking down the walls it'll become a
nice big flat area where they can spawn
I think we should go ahead and do that
Oh
yeah just kind of wanted to show you
this project because I haven't really
talked about it and I've been working on
it whoa well I thought he's going to get
me what I want to do here though one of
the reasons I brought you guys is
because I wanted to set up a portal too
and just see what's what's around here
so let's go ahead and do that I still I
still need to find like podzol I need I
lost my acacia sapling we got one in our
adventure but I don't know where I put
them so we need to find a tation
saplings I'm just kind of wondering what
we're going to find because this is new
area new terrain and also it would be
good for us to get some of the door
rights and stuff instead of using our
nether courts to make it so Oh
okay I think we might be in an ocean we
spawned underground let's go check this
out but yeah look this is good this is
what I wanted nice place to get this
stuff instead of having to make it
because this is all new terrain ooh get
in the middle a because it's generating
I guess that's to be expected
Wow a lot of leg okay okay let's check
the f3 is it an ocean please don't be an
ocean ice Plains ice Plains here I'm
gonna go up to the surface and we'll
check it out a hole man
hopefully the leg stops to you oh I just
saw some blocks falling we've got some
natural granite that's awesome oh yeah
much better than using nether quartz
yeah so this is what we got going on on
the surface it is pretty crazy around
here I thought since it was like this
was his cold taiga but the area we came
out at was ice Plains I thought it was
going to be like why 64 pretty flat kind
of like the swamps and amplified terrain
no ice Plains is pretty wild still oh I
left the torture trail so ed what you
lost
yeah this is ice Plains and we got huge
mountains I looked around just a little
bit Oh getting a lot of light because
lava and stuff water is doing weird
things updating like crazy right now
it's a new area but I thought I thought
there might be some of that packed ice
the ice spikes around here I don't see
any though I haven't looked too much
because I don't want to get lost but
this is good this is an area where I can
get the door rights or what's called
diorite diorite and andesite and the
granite might bring a beacon out here
for mining it hey Stu beacon
get really quick but yeah let's let's
head on back I might do a little work on
the fortress but I also want to get over
to the village today to the underground
village all right so I got the walls
down for the most part and it seems to
be helping quite a bit makes it really
easy to see if there's any wither
skeletons in here now oh these Jason me
you better watch your back boy better
watch your back up do it I got one I
think I just got another one got two
wither skeletons skulls which is good
that brings my total up to eight at the
moment so gonna have lots of beacon soon
I think that's one of the reasons I made
the gold farm is for beacons and now I
find one I like stand here for example
here let's get some light down just
temporarily when I stand like around
here a lot of the guys from the second
layer will come down these stairs even
hey they can like paths fine to me now
so that's cool so getting rid of the
walls seems to be helping quite a bit so
the one more thing well I'm going to be
doing a lot of things here still but one
big thing I got to do there's there's
these intersections like this these are
the really good ones these will spawn
withers within the 19 by 19 area
centered over here and you hat can get
up to like four layers so what is that
tattoo later time 19 times 19 times for
fourteen hundred and forty four spawning
spaces for wither skeletons at each of
these intersections which is pretty
crazy so we have one of them over there
there's one over on at this end they're
kind of spaced out too which is also
good because
when I run to one end of this fortress
skeletons will like all the Pigman and
stuff that have spawned over here will
despawn because I get far away and then
we can kill the withers over there and
then when we come back though all the
Pigman that spawned over on that side of
the fortress will be spawn and we get a
bunch of wither skeletons on this side
so it's ideally you want to be like
running back and forth in a fortress so
you don't want to just be in one spot so
this is going to be good when it's all
done so we got one here I'm not quite
sure how this looked before I made these
initial changes but I think this might
be one like a long time ago I smooth
some of this out so I'm not exactly sure
what intersection this was but I think
this was one there might be one over
there too
these these with the overhang are a
little different they don't get the 19
by 19 yeah so many wither skeletons I
just wish there wasn't all these blazes
they're so annoying
OOP they've got the torch they don't
spawn if there's light so unfortunately
the nether is really dark for YouTube
though and there was one more
these guys working so good oh look yeah
you can see the withers in there now so
many withers whether it's skeletons
there's one more over here so that's
like five of these intersections where I
can get over a thousand spawning spaces
if I if I want to take advantage of them
then you got all this area inside yeah
this is going to be a really good firm
when I get it all done but I think let's
go on over to the village I want to do
some stuff at the village today okay so
we don't have a lot of time to spend on
this today but I think we can get
started so this is the underground
village and as you know there's new
trading in the new snapshots like
there's new villager subtypes and I want
to try get some of the new villagers
going problem is this village has
reached maximum population we can't get
more villagers I don't think until we
get rid of some of them so I have come
up with a plan on how we might do that
let me look at your face gang I am so
sorry for you okay so he's got the big
nose three hi I brought some of this so
here's a plan what we're gonna do um oh
my goodness so loud so annoying turn it
all down um see so it was eight wide I
think we can make it work here one two
three four five six seven let's do let's
make you go out one more here all right
so I'm gonna appoint a villager chief
over the village and I'm setting up him
up right here he's gonna decide oh how
we're good
you're going to make noise though so I'm
going to kill you when the villager
chief starts crying that means it's time
to exile a village a villager from the
village like one of the junky ones that
don't have good trades we're going to
get rid of them I think rather than
killing them I'm just going to send them
to the surface like up up there they're
going to be removed from the village by
their peers and the villager chief and
if they survive up there good for them
they can manage among the hostile land
but if not the and the zombies get them
so be it what can we do but as we get
rid of some of the guys from the village
here we should be able to get new baby
villagers and that will be good um let
me look at your face again again I am so
sorry so sorry
now there's going to be another class of
villagers though these guys are special
the ones that rule over the other ones
that transcend transcend yet transcend
the other villagers they will also get
exported from the village and they will
go to a cryogenics lab that we're going
to build it in the nether
so we'll push the good villagers like
the ones with the really good trades
we'll push into the nether through a
portal and we will store them in
cryogenic ice yeah that's the plan and
they should stay alive that way for sure
okay so let's do maybe we'll do indented
eyes like so and hopefully I did that
right go this way wait wait yeah like
that
these are the Chiti emerald blocks by
the way that's why I'm using them for
building and see that goes like that
hopefully this looks pretty good let's
see what I think I got it pretty close
oh yeah that's pretty good
I brought some of this for the mouth too
here let's go around I wanted to put
like a headband on him to like my ninja
headband I wanted to put it on his
forehead but I don't know if we'll have
enough space he looks like he's just
barely fitting in um yeah let's do this
kind of make that indented - I guess we
can do that that's probably good all
right now we'll go up one more block
since we have the space might remove
some of the ceiling here and so that you
can have a higher forehead like the
villagers have nope I missed let's get
closer
all right probably can't see it anyway
all right i--i villager chief right
there so I want to make it so he cries
do I have any dispensers here not seeing
any this is bad news okay well should
have brought some what I think we'll do
with that maybe let's let's indent the
emerald eyes one more block and pretend
we have a dispenser right where I put
that block facing upwards with a water
bucket inside and that will run out the
front when we when we pulse it
let's bring this up like that that's
probably good I think that'll work the
dispenser down there
hopefully the eye doesn't look too
messed up with it invented like that I
think that's okay oh you know what we
can do it better we can get one more
block over here yeah in and out okay so
we just got to get dispensers and water
budgets and I should take away more of
the ceiling I'll be right back
oh ho you know what we almost missed a
really important detail with our
villager chief can't be a villager chief
without a very proud unibrow in the
villager world's the unibrow is like a
lion's mane that's how they show their
pride that how healthy they are how how
strong of an individual they are the
stronger the unibrow is stronger the
individual very distinguished okay so I
hooked up the tear ducts so haven't
thought this through
totally like all the details but either
we're going to trigger this ourselves
somehow like
we'll we'll check if we need to export a
villager and they'll be like a random
chance he'll start crying if it's a yes
or we might figure out some way of him
doing it automatically on his own I'm
not sure I haven't thought it out I
think when he does start crying we
should have sent some note blocks
playing and also it will open up like an
elevator to the surface for the villager
and similarly when we transcend the
villager to the cryogenic lab that we're
going to build um we're going to have a
portal open up somewhere and we'll
probably also send iron golems to the
lab and sort of collect them there that
way new ones can spawn in our village
but yeah I'm thinking too far into the
future with something I haven't to work
out the important details of just yet
but if you have ideas please let me know
but we have a villager chief and I will
try to think of how to make them cry
properly alright anyway we're going to
end the episode here I do have a comment
picked out for today which says a eso
what happened to the supercharged
creeper that was in my potion lab Jeff
our buddy Jeff a lot of people are
asking about Jeff one episode I showed
or I talked about how he despawned I
don't know how it happened one dot one
day I just checked and he was gone so I
think I logged in in peaceful mode
without realizing it because I sometimes
like when I'm in creative worlds I
usually go into peaceful mode there that
might have happened but I don't know
exactly what happened to him
thankfully it's perfect opportunity to
tell you this in the new snapshot there
is a new feature where you can or is it
you can lock worlds for one thing but
also difficulty is no longer global like
in if you're in the main menu
you my man should we go to the main menu
let's go to the main menu this is so out
of the ordinary when you go to the main
menu there's no longer an option for
difficulty here because it's saved in
each world independently so in my let's
play world I will always start in hard
mode now even if I go to a creative
world in peaceful so that is a great
feature no more accidents like that
there's the option to lock it
permanently to certain difficulty I'm
not sure I kind of like the idea of
doing that because it's like a way of
showing hey I keep it in hard mode even
when I'm not recording and I'm truly
jits all the way but there's also the
downside like what if I'm at my gold
farm for an hour accidentally and
there's a bajillion zombie pigmen I
can't just switch to peaceful to clear
them anymore and save my world from
crashing or whatever so I think I might
leave it unlocked just for that rare
opportunity where I do need to switch
the peaceful um anyway so that is our
episode for today guys I hope you
enjoyed it and I will see you again next
time so take care have a good day bye
bye