[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and we are back at the Nexus Year
right now you know I got to thinking
we've been working so hard trying to
finish up our old projects trying to get
things done in the world for the world
tour coming up soon why don't we spend
the whole episode working on the Nexus
does that sound like a plan is that good
idea just kidding we're not doing that
hey gets them every time
uh-huh so the thing about it is we
actually can't work on the Nexus anymore
because it is finished
oh yes so those of you that have watched
the series for a long time you know how
long this project has dragged on and we
got it functional a long time ago but
the interior the exterior of it wasn't
as important and I just let it drag on
and on and on and I decided with the
world tour coming up soon I want this
finish this was the main thing I want to
get done and so let's go check it out
here let's go see the finishing touches
that were made to the the Nexus build
here first off this window used to only
be about a block or two tall now we
built the frame up and it connects to
the second layer here and also the glass
goes up and kind of domes over here so
now they actually get to the second
layer you have to take these up bubble
faders or you could just fly into here
but now that the windows finished this
is what it looks like from in here we
added some slabs going across here to
kind of frame in the look as well now a
big thing is the ceiling in here was all
stoned before now we actually have a
prisoner een and quartz pattern some sea
lanterns mixed in to keep it nice and
bright and this looks pretty crazy to me
this design of the Nexus is a little
strange but it's different you know it's
kind of kind of neat just because it's
different
uh-huh now the ends here used to be
stone as well now we have some great
concrete we got a weird design over here
with the prismarine and we actually have
tunnels to connect the two sides
together with a viewing window over here
to look over
at the redstone oh oh man look at all
that redstone kind of wish I built that
on some colorful blocks instead of the
stone bricks but you know it was a long
time ago and that was the way I always
did the redstone back then so we come
out on the other side here and again the
ceiling is finished and all that kind of
good stuff this windows finished there
is a tunnel down on the lower level as
well that we can walk across to to get
to the other side the water streams had
to be moved to build these tunnels they
were kind of in the way before some
things also got added or changed to the
exterior of the Nexus one of the big
ones that got added was these stone
slabs around the whole area here we also
got them on the lower section now as
well it used to transitions straight
from the light blue here to the dark
gray and now we kind of have an
in-between material and I think that
looks a lot better especially when
you're coming in from a distance you can
really notice that we have like a white
highlight around the whole thing now
which i think looks cool we had a big
problem over here there was a dropper
elevator in the way of this window like
right over here oh is where it was built
I tore that out finish this window up
and now we have a bubble Vader instead
installed over here that goes across and
connects up over there and starts Auto
sorting the items this connects down
over here we had to build all this over
here and I think this was here before we
just connected to this stream somewhere
around here and this water stream next
to it is something that just got added
in there was a big problem with this
where we didn't really have a good place
for non sortable items to go like if
anything wasn't in the menu or if
anything didn't have space like if the
chests were full it really didn't have
anywhere to go I just kind of dumped it
off in a double chest in the middle of
nowhere now it actually goes to a proper
place it follows us down up a bubble
elevator that we just added in here
which leads to the main room right over
here and we can check any items that
don't get sorted properly they go into
this double chest and we can easily see
what's going on before is like oh I
don't know if there's still space for
that no idea I throw stuff in here to be
sorted is like
we have room for enderpearls it's
anybody's guess now like if they end up
in here it's like okay we're out of
space in the chest it's full right also
this used to be a dropper and I decided
to replace this with the shocker box for
when we request items they end up in
here and droppers only have nine
inventory spaces and this has 27 which
is much better
aha so I think that's most of it but of
course when I say the Nexus is finished
some conditions may apply so we got the
building finished it's all done but the
landscaping outside of it is another big
issue right that's for a future etho to
worry about though but yeah we got all
this stone brick still showing here I
think we're gonna build the mountain
over top of this and hide that away and
then just leave this gray concrete area
showing but anyways I think our plan for
this episode is we'll probably do some
fixer-upper projects around the world
here but and also we'll probably head
back to the Crimson keep again today
still got lots of plans for that place
so let's head over to our nether work
firm first this place is a little scary
as you can tell it's not properly lit up
I did add some emergency lanterns here
but we still need more that still has
lighting issues which we're gonna try to
fix because when we first built this
magma blocks had this weird ability
where like if you put a light next to
them they would acquire that light power
even after you removed it but now they
just have a solid light level of three
lighting a five over here so that's
pretty dark we'll stick a shroom light
behind and then glass in the front maybe
so that should light up this whole
bottom section now but I'm seeing
there's a couple dark spots in these
corners if we check it out it says it's
a block level of six so I think we'll
put a light over here I feel like we got
so many lights spammed in here and
there's still so many dark spots so I
discovered between the two lanterns
there's actually a dark spot light level
is seven over here and the only way I
can think of getting rid of that is
either to lower these by one which I
don't think will look very good
all right yeah that looks horrible so I
think what we're going to do is Gary the
lanterns and maybe I'd some shroom
lights down like this and then put us
there on top the light will shine
through it's orange so it'll kind of
match the orange here okay so I think we
pretty much got it all lit up now we
even got rid of some of the lanterns but
we did have to make a few compromises
here like I have to put this in I
wouldn't have liked to keep that
netherwart blocks but we have a dark
spot here I had to deal with that also
some sneaky lighting over here yeah that
makes a huge difference doesn't it I
think I like it more though I do we
replace the yellow glass here with green
again like we used to have as well I
think what happened this path box came
out and whenever something new comes out
in this game I'm always like okay that's
the new best thing we got to use it
right so I I got rid of all the grass
here and I don't think that was the
right call
so yeah we we went back to it we're
gonna put gray terracotta on these ends
I think just so it looks a little bit
more finished instead of having stone
it's a thunderstorm we got to get a
brown music hurry go get these guys out
of here okay build a staircase up we'll
get a red one it'll be easy nothing's
gonna go wrong here they like to follow
me you you're the one you're the one
you're the guy not you another guy he's
gonna knock me off okay it was either
hammer me okay you better you better
follow me quickly it's not a nice
neighborhood not a nice neighborhood
okay maybe let's just let's just get him
over here we got our Trident we get we
do the shooting thingy oh and there's no
thunder anymore yeah so in this nether
update they've added a new type of cow
in the game the ever elusive brown
mushroom which you get by striking a red
mushroom with lightning so you got a guy
wait for a lightning storm which are
kind of rare especially if you sleep in
your world and then if you have
channeling on your Trident you can
get a lightning strike to hit him right
but I missed my chance there I was a
little too slow but we're ready if it
ever thunders again we got the guys on
the surface now at least okay so this is
going pretty good I
I replaced the stone on the ends there
with the Terra Cotta also I kind of
finished up this exit although I got to
work on the lighting and maybe add some
more nether work into it but it goes up
to our swamp area out here awesome
alright everybody well I think we got to
the nether word farm all finished up
here actually it was actually a bit of
building but I'm pretty happy with it
now so did a bit more work on this exits
at it some red nether brick up around
here more shroom lights more creepers we
used to only have two of these magma
things that went over and now I've added
a third one here that kind of goes half
over just to fill up the space a bit
more and it goes up to our very
dangerous swamp up here that was a close
one I actually didn't see that guy okay
and then over here where we actually
harvest the nether word it was all stone
before and now we got a bit of a nether
work red nether brick pattern right and
it's all lit up as well we got the
shroom lights again we only had two of
these magma things before and now I've
added some half ones that go up just to
fill in the space over here as well and
let's see if I broke any redstone while
doing this so it says press to harvest
dues oh I did actually break the
redstone burn it's supposed to come out
on all these but only this one worked
okay and we can shorten the time on that
water because now stuff travels a lot
faster to you okay I think we found it
here actually it looks like a redstone
repeater must've got broken okay and I
think every place do it with dust
instead that goes hopefully that that
did it I didn't hear any water buckets
but we might have been too far away
let's go check it out so now all that
nether work should have been harvested
yeah okay they did very good very good
one of the very first projects we worked
on in this world and to this day is
still one of my favorites is the pop-up
sheep farm the cool thing about this
build is that use so many different game
mechanics and combine them all together
to make the farm work the problem with
that is it breaks every single updated
field it's broken again guys I'm not
sure why let's investigate together here
I see the sheep are stuck in the glass
and the piston extended okay so the
piston extended but the Sheep didn't go
up for some reason that is weird let's
see if we can manually get this gotta go
okay so that lowered it oh any wander
free oh no
why how he shouldn't have been able to
right cuz he would have been down here
and still been stuck in that glass block
yeah so we put a piston here get the
block and then that's a little strange
we got a sheep back here and he popped
up like you supposed to and then the
ideas we would shear um this makes him
go down let's see if he wanders free
again it looks like he's gonna stay
somehow I think the Sheep gained the
ability to walk through blocks I don't
know why but once I put him back here
they seem to be fine again look at this
guy you see this oh come on
okay where some reason the lead does not
work on this one yeah so I don't think
the farms actually broken I think maybe
when I updated to one of the snapshots
they just glitched through the block so
now and then they were able to get free
and broke the farm but now that they're
back in place I think it'll be okay
we'll test it here just to be sure by
the way I am still on the twenty w17 a
snapshot that's why it's raining
underground here the snapshot has a few
bugs in it I also can't bonemeal two by
two trees which is really annoying but
I'm a little scared to update I'm still
waiting for the full release I think is
when we'll do
and then I'll have to fix a bunch of
redstone probably because they made some
changes with that but anyways let's
let's see what happens here that's that
piston things still kind of broken we
don't really need it but
okay they went down that water clearing
thing still doesn't work properly I
don't think we can fix that because the
mechanics changed but they wander free
here they gonna stay in place looks like
they're staying in place cool yeah so I
think now we're gonna get back to doing
some new stuff here with another updates
at our bastion a renovation project
hopefully you guys enjoyed the picture
up stuff too though because we got a lot
of that to do still I know that stuff is
like it takes so much time to do and I
kind of think it's not as interesting as
like start a new project so that's kind
of why I don't you do it normally but it
would be good if we just get it done oh
yeah anyways let's get to this here so
we're gonna build a bit more to this
bridge this is like the entrance to the
bill Dover here and then I'm expecting
there might be some rooms to the left
and right of us eventually so we're
building sort of like a stronghold
castle sort of thing here but to be
honest with you I don't have a lot of
knowledge with how castles in that are
laid out so I don't know how we're
supposed to do the entrance here what
I'm planning on doing like what I'm
doing here is we're just gonna extend
the bridge again with this little
section but this area is actually going
to be enclosed so we're gonna we're
creating like a transition area here
where we're outside on the bridge to
inside on something similar to a bridge
and then the next room over is gonna be
actual inside of the bastion here if
that makes sense and then I think on the
left and right of this will probably
have some statues just lining the walls
I think would look cool
so as far as I can tell bastions don't
actually have a proper entrance anywhere
so it's up to us to make our own and
this is where I decided to do it because
we got this this bridge that goes across
here and I like that but we do have a
bit of a decision to make here like do
we make a tiny entrance into there or do
we do a big one I think we're gonna go
for a big one because it doesn't make
sense to me to have this big door and
then like confine it down to a small
door and then have it open up again here
I think we'll just keep it about the
same size hey you so I think we're gonna
be ripping out from here to the other
side of this and then we'll build a door
much like that one over there so this is
gonna go up about seven blocks as well
very cool so we got ourselves a double
door now and I think that adds a bit
more depth to this entrance for sure so
we got those two lines there you can see
opens up pretty good here I think we're
gonna want to get rid of this nether
brick it's sort of in the way right yeah
eventually probably so I think what
we're gonna do next let's do the bridge
thing so I made a little step down here
just so everything's not on the same
level
right and then I think we're gonna go
netherrack all the way down here again
we have a decision to make the bridge is
actually only two blocks wide in the
bastion so do we keep it two blocks wide
or do we go to three I think we have to
go three it will drive me crazy
otherwise to go from an odd number here
to an even here comes another one I
can't believe like I saw in the patch
notes they're gonna do enchanted year
two big ones now they hit so hard
already it's gonna make it really tough
I guess it was a bug that they weren't
getting it before oh dear
well change these stairs at the end from
to wipe to three wide as well and likely
figured out last episode we're gonna be
mostly making the floors out of this red
now Liam
because I think it looks pretty cool I'm
thinking we'll probably want some
Blackstone borders on this as well but
we'll try add some more details to it
similar to that big bridge we did out
there I want to add some basalt in with
this thing so maybe every three blocks
pace will go up with the basalts I
should little hard to see where that is
and then we'll have a slab I want to use
these nice ones though extra will leave
the nether axe showing on the outside
kind of like we did on the big bridge
there and then I'm thinking acacia
trapdoors as like railing keep you from
falling off sort of thing it might be
cool I feel like I want to get another
color in here like orange and at case
your trap doors is the way of doing that
and then slabs over top of these okay so
here's our side profile that mini bridge
and I think it's okay I do find that
acacia stands out a lot those who we
might need to change it but this is also
the worst angle for seeing it because
usually you'll see it like this right
and that's not too bad yeah we'll have
to think about that one I think is what
it looks like from up here which i think
is cool I want to add some red nether
brick down the middle these stairs I
think for a bit more color a bit more
texture and stuff good things yeah let's
do one on this little stair thing - cool
so I noticed that this seems to be two
blocks thick here so maybe this is
double check let's go up here look yeah
you see how the the ground is kind of up
there so maybe what we'll do is is shave
off a block down here so that it's at
least three blocks tall person to walk
under and it'll feel better compared to
a two block grant space you know so
where we can where it makes sense we're
trying to match the original Bastion
design I feel like this is one of those
cases that doesn't make a lot of sense
to me like there's a staircase here
that goes up and then whoo it just kind
of falls off it's a little strange right
I almost think I want to cover over this
to block gap here I know it's not it's
not like then the original design I
think will just make the floor a little
fatter here and then have a staircase to
go down over here and I think that'll be
pretty cool
let's also replace probably two blocks
of this black stone with the netherrack
let's check out our magma cube firm we
built last episode I'm curious how many
drops that's alright 30 and a stack okay
not a lot I haven't been here for too
long yet this is starting to feel good
to me though it's starting to feel like
a like I something so we got the Gabbin
Allium all over here we're just
basically laying the groundwork for the
our structure here and then hopefully we
can figure out some details to add like
in the walls and stuff and that'll make
the build start looking really good
hopefully um let's oh yeah I wanted to
do something here so we popped out bees
when we put the door in let's put them
back now do you like that would come all
the way down and then it's probably
another one on this side it actually
doesn't line up because this is a side
that we changed from an even number to
an odd so we're gonna have to move
everything like one block over probably
yeah we'll do something like that um I
think I want to add like a balcony here
maybe this becomes stairs you're gonna
shoot me down no no
yeah and then let's do trapdoors here
good stuff so we got our pillars in here
we might change that out with the basalt
later or these walls or a combination of
the two and now we have our balconies
with the railing up there I think is
cool now we have to kind of make some
imagination guesses here like what these
things are this feels like a little
lookout area to me like we got a bunch
of these openings all along the path so
maybe we try do something with with
these we'll make them pop out an extra
block just so they have a bit more depth
than will look better I'm gonna put a
polished slab here and then assault on
top and then maybe another polished one
over that and then this is gonna be more
railing but you don't fall down you
don't want to fall down that would be
bad and then probably entirely I'm up to
here and how does that look it's okay
alright we're gonna make these stairs
actually on top awesome so we're
starting to figure some things out over
here which is great we're at the point
though are we gonna start wrapping up
for today because I put a lot of camera
work into this one it's been taken I
took a bit of time to do this episode uh
but yeah let's let's just check this out
so I added a door frame over here I
think what we'll do because we don't
want to change too much of this main
room like we're not gonna be putting any
firms or anything in here or any cool
builds those are gonna go branching off
of this room so we'll probably build
like out this way there's actually a lot
of space back here yeah so we'll make
connections to this main room and then
put our functional stuff back there what
I would like to do over here is probably
make like a gold trading hall with the
big lens instead of just having one big
one the trade the golden gets with I
would like to have like eight of them
you put the gold in a chest and it
distributes it's all like eight
different guys so it's quick
and then have like an auto sorting
systems that pick up the stuff they
trade you would be cool that's my plan
for there we'll probably do that in the
next episode for this episode though we
are gonna end things with the comment of
the day which says I just want to
comment again on the increased quality
lately
do you now use a strip during some of
the talked over parts keep up the great
work
ah ha well thank you very much um I'll
have a lot of people asking me that now
now as I'm still doing the same style
usually I'll just have like a mental
outline in my head of what I want to say
and then I'll try say it right and I can
still improv things in between that and
whatever I want to do right what I've
done lately is I've watched some of my
videos critically and I've tried to look
for ways of improving one of the main
things I noticed is in my videos I tend
to repeat things a lot so I'll say
something and I'll say it again in a
different way and that's good in the
sense that it can clarify something but
it also just drags out the video and
doesn't add any new information so I'm
trying to avoid doing that also I tend
to use a lot of generalized words and
I'm hoping to use more specific words in
the future like I'll say that thing and
I won't say what that thing actually is
you know but bad habit so I'm trying to
be more specific in the videos now that
convey more information and also I'm
just cutting a lot more of the stuff we
don't need in the episodes so it seems
to be faster paced even though it's
pretty much the same way of recording
just in for an editing uh-huh thank you
for the question though and thank you
guys for watching this episode oh yeah
and if you didn't notice I did actually
add a face on to our super smelter here
so I covered up all the red still and
stuff which is good and we've done a lot
of other things around the world that
maybe you'll notice eventually anyways
thank you guys for watching this episode
and until the next one take care have a
good day I might
you
[Music]