all right everybody welcome back this is
etho time for another let's play episode
so first of all to begin with I died
died in the end Enderman pushed me off
into the void so I lost my good picks I
lost my shovels my axe my sword my armor
everything basically but I went on in
chanting frenzy after that because I had
no good tools so this is my new stuff
actually I had that from before but I
made that this this and I had that there
before too on the on the plus side at
least my axe and all that was pretty
close to breaking the shovel my boots so
it wasn't a huge loss but at the same
time it really sucked to begin with
today I wanted to work on this room here
the silverfish
storage room where we store them as
blocks in here from our silverfish
factory over here which is currently
disabled from the lights so what we got
to do with this project we got Pistons
pushing a line of the silverfish blocks
here then that gets moved down with this
piston here this is a smart piston a
downward one we have to make it go
downward because I don't think you can
actually make an upward smart piston I
could be wrong it's something I played
around with before though and I could
never figure out a way of doing it so
got to make it go down
this will make it stack into a column a
bunch of blocks and then when it gets to
the very bottom we need like when a
block hits this part here we need all
these Pistons to extend
and push out this way and then when it
gets to when that wall gets 12 blocks
long we need another detector over here
and then have a whole big wall of
pistons a 12 by 6 high wall of Pistons
push the blocks this way to make a big
12 by I believe 13 by 6 set of
silverfish blocks in the end that's the
final thing so it basically goes from
one dimensional a line here to 2 to 2
dimensional the column which creates a
wall and then finally three dimensional
we kind of get a cube at the end of all
this not a cube but you know a
3-dimensional shape after all that so I
got a dig down quite a ways here and try
and make this look a little less chaotic
so I just I'll get to work with my new
tools and see how it goes
all right so we got most of that space
cleared out now that we're going to need
it's a big room really is basically I
want it so we can walk underneath the
silverfish box yet if if the room is
full you know so we'll need two blocks
for that and then we'll have six blocks
high of the silverfish blocks and this
here will just be floor of whatever
block we choose still don't know what
what type of blocks we're going to do or
how we're going to decorate it or
anything like that but the next step to
this is going to be making the piston
wall over here so I believe it will go
one block away from that and like that
twelve blocks long and six blocks high I
think that's right yeah all right so
that's the next step to this it's going
to take a lot of pistons and if you guys
have noticed my videos have been a
little bit irregular lately it's because
I'm just about in my busy season of work
and pretty soon I won't have a whole lot
of time left to play Minecraft I
actually start working ten to twelve
hour days soon starting in May so I
don't know how that's going to go hello
want to fight no I don't know how that's
going to affect things I'm going to have
a much harder time getting videos out
obviously four five six seven eight nine
ten eleven twelve so that's that's as
far as we want to go but I'll do my best
I believe you we will start uploading
the next huge series soon and that
should run throughout May so they'll be
for sure a video every second day for
that and hopefully people are happy with
that and then I'll try to let's play
episodes as I can but the thing is I
don't want to do an episode if I'm not
in the mood and I've always always felt
that way like if I don't feel like
playing I'm not going to play because it
won't be fun for me and it will show in
the video too so we'll see how it goes
but I know last year this was back like
around the episodes I think 70 or so was
last May I managed to do okay but there
the episodes got a lot more talky and a
lot less buildi so that might happen
again might do caving and whatnot who
knows who knows I'll try to keep it
entertaining though as much as I can and
I'll probably not be able to play other
series like the Ultra Hardcore until
June once June comes around I'm free
again like even more time than I have
now
so things should get much much better
than just May is a real killer on me
both physically and mentally
okay so how did you get there there's so
much silver fish damage around here
because I must've missed killing a few
of them and they just kept breaking more
and more blocks every time I killed them
um I will finish this up and then we
will start doing the wiring for it
should be fairly simple I imagine OOP so
I'll be back in a little bit
all right welcome back to the cave I
just had to make a pit stop here to pick
up some glowstone for the wiring and
some better food because these melons
I'm sick of them this window here is new
this is going to be for the furnace room
I don't know what I'm going to do with
the furnace room all I know is I wanted
a window a three by three window there
for some reason is like window popped in
my head and I wanted it so I've made
that happen so this is where the furnace
room will be eventually in the space
here and I just wanted to see what it
would look like from the side too that's
why I have that dug out when I do
eventually build the room and it's a
pretty decent view I would say so
haven't forgotten about this part we
will continue to work on this even
though we're building way over there now
too and I also dug through here to see
how it would connect with that upper
parts just get a feel for the distance
and the height change and whatnot so
we'll probably connect with over here
eventually put in the staircase or
something over here and should be pretty
good all right and also the jukebox
station here
got a few good suggestions on how to do
it and I might follow them the only
problem is a lot of people didn't take
into consideration this wall over here
so with the videos people sent me like
this might be wood over here and that
looks really bad if you got one one
block of wood from this side so I will
mess around with it though probably and
make it look a little bit better but I'm
gonna grab the glowstone grab some food
and we will head back okay so I believe
I have this all working now got all the
Redstone wiring done and all pistons in
place so let's just go through it real
quick
basically that piston up there is a
smart piston um so if a block goes in
front of it it will automatically push
it down and every time that happens it
keeps pushing them down until they get
to the bottom piston here which is also
a smart piston but in control it
controls this whole column so when it
gets here it all extends and six blocks
get pushed this way and then that leaves
space for new ones to come down and
slotting no get there get there come on
there okay so the way this works is we
have a lever here powering the redstone
wire and when it gets cut when a block
gets placed here it switches it off and
that triggers this it goes around here
to redstone torch and that goes up to
there's wire there and then wire on top
of all this glowstone which sends power
to all the Pistons and there's also one
block here which prevents this wire from
connecting to that
they're so yeah this goes off for a
split second which switches a torch
makes a piston extend and then the block
is no longer cutting the wire so it
retracts and that's basically what
happens over here - we have another
smart piston in this corner this one
here except we were using a redstone
torch for this one sends power up here
this is what happens when the block goes
there all of those extend and get pushed
that way um yeah there's a redstone
torch right there so this wire goes to
that torch which power is that repeater
and then it goes to that block which has
wire on it which powers that repeater
and then we use glowstone to get this
powered up here - to this final repeater
up here and then the easiest way that I
found of powering a wall of Pistons like
this is to use redstone torches each of
these will power two Pistons so you just
run a line a redstone wire and the line
of of torches got three layers of those
for the six layers of Pistons and it
seems to work pretty good I do get a
little bit of lag from this so usually
my FPS drops down to twenty-five when
I'm recording when I do that which isn't
isn't too bad um beyond this we will
have another detector on this side here
and it will detect when this room is
full and hopefully shut off the
silverfish factory so that it doesn't
cause problems and also send us like an
indicator like no blocks or something to
the storage room telling me to
come harvest the silver fish or whatever
that the rooms full we have to deal with
them
and Oh ay where did you come from
place really isn't safe now that the
silver fish I've done so much damage
everywhere we will have to encase this
area with blocks they can't get into and
also we'll have to pick a block for this
room here that they can't enter either
so that we can contain them the plan is
to have like a window over here that we
look into the room that will keep the
silverfish from getting us and we will
probably be able to break the silverfish
blocks from here and then attack them
somehow and I also would like to have
the snow golems along the walls here so
that they will hit the silverfish and
cause them to break like when we start
the chain reaction so that we don't have
to hit them ourselves we can get the
snow golems to do it for us we'll just
have to make an opening so that the snow
golems can shoot out of but the
silverfish can't get to the snow golems
so if we have like a block here and then
a half slab above here like do I have
anything on me no mmm I'll just make a
crafting bench and show you what I mean
if we have the snow golems behind
something like this like if they're over
here we can do that and they should be
able to shoot out of that hole but the
silverfish won't be able to get in there
because it can't fit and a half of block
space as we've seen before so and that's
that's the height that skeletons and
snow golems shoot at so that will most
likely work
I predict I don't know what
build the room out of the what block
should we use I was thinking maybe of
using stone brick and the mossy and the
crack stuff so it resembles the
stronghold because that's what was here
before but if I use stone brick I'll
have to do double half slabs so they
can't enter the box to keep the look um
yeah beyond that for today I don't know
what we're doing so I'm going to take a
break and think about it and I'll be
back in a little bit here all right you
know what I want to do I want to play
around with the floor different designs
and figure out what people like
including myself so instead of doing the
stone brick thing I'm gonna try use
wooden planks first or maybe maybe only
I don't know first let's try a simple
checker pattern I've marked the center
of the room with this obsidian or at
least I think I did and we'll just see
how this looks if I do use wood I'll
have to make sure I get rid of all the
lava so it doesn't catch fire there's a
lot of it around hidden underground with
three guards two Ultra Hardcore oh I did
this wrong Ultra Hardcore season four B
that was another pretty cool ending I
think people really like that with the
wolf fight and all that that was I was
cool again we had a lot of fun with that
season just amazed it ended like that
that was so close again
couldn't have turned out any better I
don't think or more suspenseful anyway
yeah I should have made an iron sword oh
boy but you know
that's just the way it goes there's
always going to be something you shoulda
did like I and you know it's just we
needed to do - we needed to do one more
heart damage basically and iron sword
would have done it but at the same time
you know hitting him again would have
done it - or you know me not shooting
doc probably would it would have helped
a lot - or overall is pretty happy with
how I did in that fight but I think the
mistakes I noticed were obviously not
making the iron sword I shot doc and
it's funny me and gewd we both pulled
out our bows when we were one block
apart like at the same time basically I
don't know why that was another mistake
that one was pretty funny though and
fighting the Wolves you know I don't
think we should have done that I think
we should just went straight for good
and vintage beef because wolves they got
ten hearts and if you got 14 wolves
that's like fighting 14 players you know
because they have the same hearts as as
a player so I think if I ever in that
situation again I would just go straight
for the player and not even bother with
the wolves but you know you don't really
have time to think in the heat of the
battle how's this looking so we'll call
this pattern number one kind of like it
um we will try a few more so I'll be
right back in a sec we will call this
one pattern number two and if you don't
if you don't want it with the wood
blocks just say what other type of
blocks you would like it with otherwise
I will assume you like the wood blocks
the white and blue and the dark ones or
however I arrange it
and after I show you all these patterns
tell me which one you prefer the most
and how you would modify it if you would
okay this one's much like pattern number
two but we'll call it pattern number
three anyway and in these one-by-one
holes we could maybe put glowstone light
up the room I think that'd be pretty
cool
instead of having torches
I'll tell me which one you prefer the
most and that's the one we will probably
use in the comments but I will call it
an end for today I still haven't done my
taxes and it is a 23rd now I believe so
little bit scared I got to get to it
hopefully I can send them in tomorrow
but I have to I got the might half done
I gotta finish em tonight so that's it
for today thanks for watching and I will
see you again next time whenever that is
probably soon
you