[Music]
whoa
whoa whoa where do you think you're
going stop
you better not wreck my intro
you stay put no no don't go that way no
no no no
okay yeah yeah go over there you're fine
over there
aha what is this look at this this is
amazing
where'd he go yeah you stay there
just a cauldron just a cauldron you say
i don't think so why this is the blast
master 9000 of course
look at it you can't even see the bottom
it just keeps going for
infinity it's amazing
yeah okay let's hope this works i uh
i can't really test it because if i test
it it uh
i'll have to move it and yeah so let's
just hope it works i wasn't able to
to test it but here we go
ah the poor sheep
oh it's fun so yeah we're in the
snapshot here we're in a creative world
we're just having fun
i love it
[Music]
ah you did have so much fun with the
command blocks now
that's actually really loud
i still haven't figured out what
settings i should should use ever since
they gave us more options here
uh but yeah so in the like
there's been all these awesome map or
command block features coming out
over the last few months the thing is
most of them you can't really use you
have to use
like all these mc edit filters and stuff
and it's just a real pain to do anything
but now you can pretty much do
everything you want in the game using
just command blocks which is awesome
it makes it so much easier and uh
i think i'm going to be playing with
command blocks a lot more not not in my
single player but
we're just goofing off here yeah let's
try just
change the fuse time okay those are
invisible
bats by the way with tnt writing on
their backs
uh oh let's go game mode zero
[Music]
oh i just want to apologize to anybody
that's
wearing headphones right now like i am
[Music]
ah
i threw an ender pearl but i i
jumped too soon darn it
well that was embarrassing let's do it
again
ah that's how you save face i did it
right that time
awesome um okay we're not just derping
around here
i've actually got some stuff to show you
and i'm
i stayed on top that ladder for about
two minutes or so so that should have
spawned a bunch of zombie pigmen
down in our gold farm and i will be able
to show you
what's what's wrong with the gold farm
currently and also what i've done to it
um so let's head back into the nether
but
below the nether ceiling so we can
investigate things
i'm still getting used to the new
shaders and stuff and the
mapping minecraft looks a lot different
with it
and here comes the rain oh joy
yeah but i can do this
yeah i think i think about 50 or less is
good for that
i'm still trying to work out all my
volume levels since this update
uh because that all changed
and okay so we're going to go back in
and
so i've been i've been working on the
gold farm a lot
uh since last episode just off camera
kind of repetitive
boring stuff here but there's a big part
of it done
now which i'm about to show you
let's go up and also since we spawned a
bunch of zombie pigmen
we're going to be able to see why it's
not yielding so much gold
at the moment there is quite a bit of
gold around like
uh pigment are falling and and uh
dying on the ground here you can see i
lowered all the nether racks so that the
and far fall enough
did i say far fall enough fall far
enough
um to die so we got a few drops in the
little amount of time we were up there
but if we go up this is the thing i've
been working on by the way this
giant square you're seeing
uh but first before these guys
actually there's not as many here as i
thought there would be
but basically the problem with the gold
farm at the moment is i got all these
spawning spaces close to it where
they're still
gathering instead of spawning in
my trap here they're spawning on the
outside
and i have to make it so that absolutely
none of them spawn on the outside here
for it to work the way i want because
ouch because currently if one of them
spawns on the outside then i gotta wait
like
over 30 seconds usually for them to
despawn
and you can see there's a lot of guys in
here which tells me i still have some
spawning spaces
i have to deal with
but this is the thing i've been building
this cage all around it
to protect it from gas we want to
protect our pistons and our
string and our our redstone you can see
there's a piston missing there
because the gas shot it um i should have
built this a long time ago though
hey guy
and i didn't want just like a a plain
plain old like
solid stone brick wall or solid iron
bars or something i wanted
uh to put a pattern into it if i could
so this is what i came up with it's like
this is the center over here and then it
does this zigzag
sort of thing i think it's pretty cool i
like it
very big though it i i had to dismantle
that beacon up on top of the ceiling
there to
get enough iron to finish this and i
think i still missed a few spots
somewhere too
um but yeah then all the zombie pigmen
they fall down these little holes here
and we gotta set up some collection
system below to pick up the gold
uh they drop and that is about where
we're at with the gold farm
currently so it's coming along
we will get it done um
i've been clearing a lot of land though
i kind of want to mess around with
beds in the nether just to see if i can
somehow clear land quicker
with that than i can with my pick
because
do i dare risk throwing ender pearl oh i
almost hit one
i almost did because currently like it
goes quick
but it uses up my tools very quickly um
i could use tnt but it's kind of
wasteful i kind of want to try just use
beds
yeah let's try let's have some fun here
i don't know if this is going to work
too well i think i've tried
in the past uh clearing another rack
with beds but
it was like too slow
or something i don't know i am going to
stash some stuff here
i went for some wool and i got a regen
potion here i think if i could stay
healed
and if i made enough beds and kept them
in my inventory
it should work pretty quickly
i would think i'm i'm worried i'm gonna
blow up here i'm not sure if i can even
even take the hit
um yeah we'll make a bunch of beds
i think you can recover them
and i definitely want to keep my armor
on because otherwise i'll for sure die
and i went and i got a blast protection
for helmet
and i have blast protection pants um
level four on both of them so i should
be pretty much maxed out on blast
protection with that
so this is like my best chance of
surviving a
bed unless i set up my beacon with
resistance on too that would be ideal
oh please live don't lose all my stuff
okay those guys didn't get mad i think
the bed was gone though
um the worst thing about is it makes a
little fire
yeah fire resistance is a must if we use
regen as we do it though
and i got a string farm so getting wool
for beds
isn't a terrible idea i definitely need
a fire resist though
holy smokes
does seem to clear a lot of space and i
can do it quick
yeah yeah this might actually be a good
good way of doing it okay we're gonna
try it again this time i'm really
pushing for efficiency i want to see if
i can clear
a big portion of this chunk in a little
amount of time so
all that guy's going to make this
annoying i don't have any arrows i left
them in the chest
uh so we're doing fire resistance this
time and
even regen i got tons of beds made
ready to go so we should just be able to
hammer this out real quick
oh sometimes the bed does drop i saw it
dropped that time
that's good that's good if we can
recover it
yeah maybe the main problem with this i
kind of get stuck in a crater
as i go it's fine if you're digging
straight
down oh
i was not paying attention
oh man
ah okay we're not clearing that way
ah it did seem like i was going kind of
quick
though i didn't realize i was that close
to death i wasn't even watching
because i was only losing like a heart
heart and a half last time
okay i watched the video back it looks
like i wasn't taking consistent damage
every time sometimes it's like nothing
sometimes
like i lost over five hearts i think
that one time
and that is why i died so quick
um i'm guessing nothing survived
in that hole there
looking pretty empty
darn it uh what did i have i had diamond
full diamond armor on i had a silk touch
pick
uh my bow was about to break
i think my shovel was in pretty good
shape did nothing survive like really
or was i oh it's over here okay
i figured at least something should
survive like come on
oh good we got the the helmets
how much that was a brand new helmet
wasn't it
it's like a quarter broken already
oh look at this we got oh if i could get
my boots back
we're done with the nether today by the
way i'm done
derping around with this we're gonna do
something else
well lots of beds survived oh sword
ender pearls oh i still have my cold
like it's been over two weeks and i
still having trouble
talking and coughing and stuff
looks like that's it so we got our sword
that's a that was a good one
our axe lost our our shoes though
and our picks
we're still in the nether here but we're
going to get out really soon uh i just
want to do
a little enchanting so we stopped by the
dual blaze farm
for old time's sake i haven't been here
in a long time actually
and i want to enchant a bunch of fishing
rods and then we're going to check out
the new fishing
mechanics this episode i brought a
looting 3 sword
so there is a good
over 350 blaze here so this is going to
be pretty crazy actually
activate the crusher still getting like
10 15 frames per second which is a lot
better than it used to be
and i have my memory up to two two gigs
with the launcher so it's the blaze farm
works a lot better than it used to which
is awesome
so i'm going to throw this and switch to
the looting sword hopefully quick enough
get all kinds of blazer odds um
let's get out of here
so we're going to put 30 levels into
each of the fishing rods
i also want to repair my boots
if we can although i might do that
off camera okay so first one i want to
get the
the what is it called ah not there too
there's some some enchantment that uh
allows you to find better stuff and it's
not leer leer makes it so you
catch fish quicker but the one that gets
you better stuff is like
i forget what what's called
uh hopefully we get it here though
come on come on come on no
darn it try again
um these boots are actually
really old and they cost like 34 levels
to repair now so i should probably
name them
i'm not giving up till i get this i
think it's sea of enchantment or
something
unbreaking three there three that's a
good rod
but it's not quite what i was looking
for
come on come on come on
all right
all right we're almost out of experience
okay and last chance
luck of the sea that's what it's called
and we got lure three
so you can get them both on one rod
i wonder how much it would cost to rip
to put them together
too expensive too expensive ah
darn it what if we just do do i have any
unbreaking books here
i kind of would like to have a rod with
all three on if it's possible
nope i do have one back at my main base
so
the man cave let's see how many blaze
rods we got from this
well i'm gonna be um
smelting lots of stuff it looks like
that's a lot of blazer rods one two
three four five six seven eight
nine ten over ten stacks
wow
okay so we're going to do one more big
batch of blazes here
we got like 340 in there at the moment
we're gonna do an experiment too people
always tell me to name
my tools and stuff so that when i repair
them it's cheaper which is something i
almost
never do i'm kind of curious
i've never really experimented with it
either though
so i could be wasting tons of levels who
knows
uh i kind of don't think i am though
we'll see here um so these boots i think
i've repaired them close to 10 times now
i believe they only costed about 18
levels the first time i repaired them
don't quote me on that though let's just
say early or low
low 20s now to repair them
costs 34.
so even if we do it this way yeah it
costs more if we do it that way so that
this is the way to do it this is uh this
is like
always the way to do it if you're
repairing a
diamond pick just make an unenchanted
diamond pitch and use that to repair it
instead of using the diamonds
directly i find usually works best
but yeah it costs like 34 levels now to
do it so we're going to try name it
how much is that going to cost 37 okay
let's get 37 levels off these fools
uh activate the crusher
there's a lot in there
probably shouldn't be walking around
with 35 diamonds on me
all right losing a few it's fine it's
fine
i didn't lose that many and once again
we're going to try to
extra blaze rods by switching to the
looting sword
hopefully i did it quick enough and here
comes the xp
i love this blaze farm it's so cool i
think if i was to do it now though i
would try to set up like a minecart
system instead of the
conveyor belt down there because you can
automate everything with hoppers
and like cactus to destroy the mine
carts and
and move blazes that way instead
would i say 37
i should do it
a lot of xp just to name it
just to name it that doesn't even repair
it what i'm wondering is how much it's
gonna cost to repair it after we've
named it
uh we'll call these the vintage beefs
i don't know how to spell vintage beef
i think that's it right vintage beefs
now let's go beefers
okay so now to repair it
it's down to 27 so it's seven levels
cheaper but every time i repair it from
here it's gonna increase
so i think if you're gonna repair stuff
don't
name it right away only rename it if
you've repaired it like
five times or more i'm guessing is the
trick
then it starts to become cheaper again
wait i forgot what it was 27
it was 27.
yeah okay cool oh and there goes the
anvil
hmm
yeah so i tell you what guys fishing is
still pretty boring in this game
i've been at it for over 20 minutes now
i just wanted to see what i could get
i'm using the
the super lira 3 luck of the c3
fishing rod here uh turns out i didn't
have an unbreaking three book round i
wanted to see if i could put it on there
and how much it would cost um
but i just i can't do that and i
enchanted two more of these
oh or maybe three more did i miss that i
really did
darn it um and it looks like you can get
all three enchantments on it this one
though
only got luck of the c2 and lear lyr2 so
it's not
quite perfect but it's pretty close
this one though i should be getting good
stuff and quickly but it's
yeah i'm about done here
a lot of people have told me i should
really have built this
above ground so that i would catch more
fish
i've gotten that those comments so many
times already
and i believe i could be wrong but i'm
pretty sure it doesn't matter if you
fish
above ground or or underground like i am
now
uh unless this is an important thing
unless it's
raining oh here comes a fish
got him uh if it's raining then you have
a better chance of catching fish if
if you're above ground and i think it's
by
like 1.66 times
more likely to catch a fish or something
but even with lier 3 on this thing
spin around spin back
oh i pulled it too soon he was just
about to get it
anyway so about 20
25 minutes of fishing this is all we got
from this fishing rod 18 raw fish
five puffer fish eight raw salmon and
that is it
so definitely gonna be doing automatic
fishing i think
because that was pretty pretty slow
going
didn't get any clown fish with this
fishing rod but i did get one before
with
with this one um
so anyway uh these are what i was mainly
going for these puffer fishes hoping i
get maybe some treasures too
and i want to try eat one
oh i'm not hungry let's get hungry
puffer fish are
very dangerous you have to have a
special
well-trained uh
chef not is it a chef i think that has a
special name but
somebody that trains for years and years
cutting these fish
to get rid of all the toxins because if
they cut them wrong
they will kill people
and i'm not getting hungry there we go
so
in the game the same is true from what
i've read it's my first time trying one
wow poison four for a minute
nausea that is awesome
if only you could make a splash potion
that did that to people
that would be awesome um
oh you know what i would like to go to
the lab
if only this guy wasn't here is he still
here
pretty sure he's in there somewhere
oh
i don't see jeff
he's in there okay
oh that wall looked messed up
for a second um i need a brewing stand
i probably still have some around here
gotta be careful not to jump
as much as i'm tempted to i like to jump
down my stairs always
oh this could be fatal is there any
brewing stands
yes cool oh
he almost got me
yeah let's do that okay
and i will snag some of these
so there's a new type of potion in the
game apparently
that you can brew with these puffer fish
let's try that out it's going it's going
good um you can probably extend it
i'm guessing i haven't made one of these
yet
puffer fish makes underwater breathing
potion
potion of water breathing okay for three
minutes
um i'm gonna try glowstone first
actually
if it can't use it it won't yeah okay so
there's no
tier two level for it but it can be
extended it looks like
that's good it's good and all those do
i think you can breathe underwater
without suffocating at all
but we'll try it out
all right cool so we'll grab one of
these
let's go yes we got plenty of water
around we don't have to go far
make our great escape uh let's just
let's just jump in the water here
okay
and we filled it with water
water breathing for eight minutes
yeah so i'm not i'm not drowning at all
the air bubbles aren't going down at all
is it like in terraria the gills potion
where you suffocate when you're in the
air
where it reverses doesn't seem to
that's pretty cool you still
can't move quick underwater with it
though
uh which would have been nice and i
doubt you can
yeah you don't you can't dig stuff quick
with it either you still need aqua
affinity
to do that
with the new rendering code of the
snapshot something that really caught my
eye is these leaves here look how easy
it is to see through them now
and to see the stone and the dirt behind
them before was pretty much
solid green and even if i change
if i turn off mit mapping
don't think that does anything that's
only for distance stuff so it's like
i don't know just the the way it's
rendered has changed
oh yeah let's not mess with that i
really like this one
the bump mapping one uh okay so comments
for today
uh etho what games are you excited for
for this fall
slash winter uh i believe
terraria the update is coming out i
think on october
1st and there's a very good chance i'm
going to be playing that
i might even be posting it on youtube
which is
something i've been looking forward to
and also a big game i've been wanting to
play for
like i've had my eye on it for i think
at least
two years now is starbound um
it seems like that's coming out soon or
at least that's the impression i got
that's coming out soon i don't think
they've set a
date but i could be wrong and i'll
probably be playing that too
uh when it does i've been i've been
really looking forward to that
uh but yeah so that's it for today guys
today's a little bit of a
derp around episode next time we'll get
to building
oh man i can never find the right one
again
is that it no next one
there we go okay so yeah thanks for
watching guys
have a great day and i'll see you again
next time bye
[Music]
you