hey how's it going everybody
uh this is etho and welcome back to
another episode
i'm very happy guys i'm excited to show
it to you i got the ender ender 2.0
all complete here you can see the
enderman falling down
oh yeah this thing is crazy
goes all the way up to about 128
two sides man
you can see the tnt in the middle there
and
i just finished it today i haven't used
it very much i think i just
did a couple test enchantments with it
but today i'd really like to do some
enchanting
and just show it working and also let's
let's go up there and check it out too
um and also oh
did i i hate how it gives you the false
like
a lot of times it'll make the noise but
you didn't actually anger them
so it's like i cried the boy that cried
wolf type deal where you
you just assume you didn't look at them
almost
and sometimes they actually get mad and
chase you
and you don't expect it
but yeah let's go check this baby out
what was i saying i'm in 1.7.1 now so
the stained glass did change
um and this walkway i think it still
looks pretty good even with the change
it's more
transparent now and the texture looks a
lot smoother
the colors don't pop out as much but i
think it still looks pretty good
so that's cool and i've added in a too
high walkway here
as we get closer to where the endermen
are so they
they can teleport up to 32 blocks any
direction from themselves so
if we don't give them a valid spot to
teleport
32 blocks from that building like they
won't be able to teleport to this
walkway because it's only too high
and then on top up here there's water so
they can't teleport to that either so
they can't get away
onto my walkway here
but yeah all in all this project is
crazy it took me over 12 hours i think
just to build it not counting designing
and stuff
and i still have a few guys that come
out of here if i let them sit for too
long
not a big deal the tnt will blow them up
even if they're in this middle area
but uh let's go up top first
i don't know how many layers it is i
didn't count yet so we should count that
too
let's see so we got the rings here to
keep them from falling out then this is
where the spawning pads start right over
there
got the vines to reset their fall damage
i'm wondering i guess we'll just pillar
up i'll remove this later
and i'll try ender pearl to the top so
we have to go all the way
but yeah this thing it seems like it's
working great
um it usually takes them only
like 10 to 15 seconds to fill up down
below
oh man we got a long ways to go um
maybe i'll get the y up here so we're at
y
how about when we hit 100 we'll try
enter pearl up to the top
i'll come back up here with ladders and
remove this well i ran out of dirt
oh yeah we can make this no problem
let's do over there hopefully i don't
land inside oh
there we go so up to why
125 is where our feet are
and my eyes are at why 126 ish
or 27 the very top
here's what it looks like looking down i
put half slabs on the very top so
everything's topped off but at the
everything's capped off
at the top here so nothing will spawn at
the very top
and uh i think the way we're going to
count this is we'll go in at ourselves
so here we go
and hopefully i don't die from this
one two three four five
six 7 8 9 10
11 12 13 14 15
16 17 18 19 layers
oh boy
this is scary uh i should be able to get
out on one of these rings let's try not
to look at them
oh yeah that worked all right give me a
sec i'm going to remove this dirt
all right everybody so let's uh let's
fire this baby up let's do some
enchanting i'm excited
break it in and i'm trying to learn how
to use it still
um i've been really careful not to look
at these guys when they're in these uh
cages because i'm not exactly sure what
they'll do but i accidentally looked at
one here and he's freaking out
so i want to see just as my first
learning experience
i like to learn the hard way uh if i can
look at them and be okay
i think i'm okay look how they're all
bunching up though
let's get the other side
yeah you mad bro
so i have did they change that because
you could only anger like 15 at once
before and now i have like 80 on me
there was a limit before how many you
could have angry at you
oh oh i got too close there
i think this is one of the mad guys i
think he teleported out
yeah he did okay
but overall it's pretty safe even if i
look at them
oh although i can't get down now
let's do that okay
uh this first batch i'm a little anxious
to get rid of
so let's let's get it going here this is
the bow i've been using
i got two uses on it
oh man so long suckers
oh that's much better much quieter
and then you just stand in the middle
all the xp orbs float towards you
i'm worried about my sounds here there's
a lot of stuff going on i think this is
the xp
orb noise maybe
still learning the sounds it still
sounds the same
i think what else would it be though
i'm not sure anyway so
today let's do let's do a bunch of book
enchantments first of all i guess
um i want to get
like i have these pretty good boots but
i would like to get protection
for feather falling for unbreaking three
on some boots if i can
don't stand underneath that is dangerous
if you're not underneath though it
doesn't really do any damage to you
and i find two shots is about all it
takes to
get it up to 30 levels
and uh we should probably time it too i
want to see how long it takes them to
fill up i said 10 or 15 seconds
before but i think it might be like 15
to 30 actually
it's done now um
unfortunately with this i find a lot of
the times i run
just shy of 30. it's always like 29 and
a half
oh there we go i added this thing into
here i'll explain this in a second
um let's let's get the books going
though
made a bunch of books brought them over
here
first book it's my four woo hoo
party uh
uh those xp works actually there those
are the ones from there
they glitch out like that though so this
thing here i've added this in
as sort of a way of holding the xp orbs
as a reserve
so you get the bulk of them over here
and they're actually in there but they
do that little teleport out motion so it
looks like you can get them here
but they're actually not there they're
over there so now if i'm ever shy of
30 levels i can just walk under there
and i'll get what i need
tt doesn't seem to blow them up when it
goes off
so that's cool but i gotta collect them
within five minutes otherwise they'll
despawn too
so uh we'll just leave a few over there
it tastes river shorts
oh yeah this is so cool man it's
i didn't do a lot of enchanting before i
think i'm going to do tons though i'm
going to
use efficiency 5 tools
and all that good stuff from now on i
think because this is just so easy
like why would i not
and it's fun to use um
oh yeah oh i got too many on me
uh quick quick quick no
camera angles get a book in there quick
we're wasting levels
all right leer two
not bad we get them all out sometimes i
find
xp orbs get stuck in the corners a
little bit
might be too far for them to move
usually they do make it but it just
takes a while sometimes
all right let's count how long it takes
to refill one
two three four
five 6 7
8 9 10
11 12 13
14 15 16
17 18 about 20 seconds or so i might
have been counting a little slow i can't
tell
and once they stop falling that's when
you know it's full
and so i'm shorts 24 uh
we might be able to get it from this
maybe not
and then if i walk away like they stop
coming to me the xp orbs
but i can get it through through the
trap door if i walk up to it
nope didn't have enough in reserve okay
i think there's a few more flying around
up there
oh did i run out of tnt
i just missed okay um
oh i've never seen that happen i just
can teleport down here
pretty cool though all right
one other thing i really like about this
is uh
your inventory doesn't fill up with
ender pearls because they're up there so
you don't have to keep tossing them out
when you're doing your enchanting
which is really cool
but uh yeah i think i'm going to do some
enchanting off camera here and see
let's see what we get from it
no no
no oh
no man you know how i said i tested this
thing like a hundred times and it never
once exploded
oh i found some combination of
tnt jump randomness and
fall height that apparently
man you
gotta be kidding me
i don't even want the xp anymore i want
this fix
oh you oh i'm drowning i thought i was
getting attacked
man you gotta be kidding me seriously
i don't even know how many times i've
made this thing pop like especially
while designing it
no dude
sad thing is i don't even think i have
the quartz needed to fix it i used it
all and i
may have moved well let's get this
quartz off the ground
man this is going to be a pain to fix
ah
okay so i'm gonna have to put more water
i just had the one block there if i
did a three by three water it would
never explode for sure
i just looked better without it but
sometimes you got to sacrifice a
aesthetics for functionality especially
when
it blows up on you like this holy smokes
quartz has really low blast resistance
too which really stinks
because a lot of it probably got popped
there
all right so let's build the ender ender
2.0 once again
ah oh yeah okay so this was all
this is quartz here that's the chisels
got some chiseled
all right and then glass
i should probably fill in the half slabs
first i'm going to walk off
and be really sad
the nice thing about making stuff is you
usually remember
exactly how you did it or at least i do
if i build something i can remember
every block
from memory pretty much
so that's good at least i don't have to
check my design and keep switching
between
creative worlds and stuff man
i was on a roll too i was getting a good
enchanting groove there and
boom half slabs all the half slabs fell
down into the void
we gotta get this water taken care of
did i have a water bucket i did
okay i'm just gonna pick this up so it
stops annoying us for right now
now i don't want to look at them i think
i did look at him
yeah he's mad where's this water from
that's from that
there
all right let me let me clean this up
and we'll get back to it
man i tested it so many times i just
i can't believe it that was a shocker
i'm surprised i didn't even die i was
like
you saw it i was like just hovering on
the edge of a block
just about fell off but man
i don't know i think i think it's all
been fixed i don't see any other blocks
missing there was a lot of damage up
here too
all the window panes are back all the
court stairs and stuff up here is back
yep got really lucky now that i
i've been thinking about it because just
the one tnt exploded that i lit but if
the tnt had been lower in this
tube like down here the whole thing
would have went
all the way up and would have destroyed
like everything everything below the
spawning pads pretty much would have
been destroyed
especially this white quartz area
so look on the right side i guess
um so i got a three by three thing of
water here
i cannot imagine this will make it
explode
it should be safe i'm i could be wrong
though
i'm always surprised by things like that
and it's being held into place
by these three signs per side
it should be safe i'm pretty sure
i don't see how it could explode now
um so anyway i'm gonna get back into
enchanting here
try to get my groove back after it was
disturbed
we're all good first test since the
rebuild
looks good i think we're okay got rid of
the
xp reserve here too because i got i just
got used to
uh getting ready to put my book in
um it's just easier when you're prepared
like i know as soon as this hits 30 i
can enchant it so
come on come on come on i don't know if
it's going to make it
nope all right so anyway
be back in a bit
i don't understand
how it could blow up
really like i don't i don't get that
there was
a three by three thing of water this
time
unless it's the ladder below that's not
working properly
but it's not falling through like it's
not landing down here with the glowstone
it's blowing up
in the water
and it's under water so if something if
tnt blows up
underwater it doesn't blow up blocks
so why is it not
ah i don't get it
what could it be
like i mean this is water this is where
it's landing right here
did i no man it
should it's not falling that far either
it's not like it's exploding before it
hits the water
it just doesn't make sense to me
i'll have to i guess i gotta get back to
the drawing board this is
uh some some flaw with this design
and it seems to be happening a lot more
often than i would even expect
compared to how many times i've tested
this before um
hmm all right well
that's it for the ender ender for today
i do not have enough quartz to fix it
again
so i'm not sure how i could fix it if
that water didn't
do it
except using something besides a ladder
might
be the issue
so let's go let's head back to the man
cave and i'll clean up this mess some
other day
oh what does that mean for the world
download though i wanted to release the
world download today
uh now that i got this all done but
i might delay it one more episode i'm
not sure i'll think about it
okay so i had an idea maybe we can
troubleshoot this problem together
i'm in a creative world now this is
where i built the original prototype for
it and it looks
it looks pretty much the same there's a
few
subtle differences like different
spawning pads and stuff in this one
compared to when i actually built it in
my lp world
uh but let's let's trigger the tnt and
just
see if we can spot exactly
what it's doing it's fine
oh i'm gonna have xp in my face
the whole time no
ah fly up it's good
see it looks like it was kind of off the
corner you would think tnt
explodes in the center of it itself
though wouldn't you
i always thought it did maybe it
explodes in the very
corner it's good
oh i think we're out
i don't know this is very weird i'm not
shooting two
that's not the problem either it's not
like oop
was that it somehow an
arrow fire arrow got stuck behind
that was weird
oh where'd it go
huh these arrows are doing weird things
i'm shooting it and it's not uh
oh now i'm glitching to the ground what
is going on
there we go maybe it's an issue with
arrows
yeah so it got stuck in there
could the tnt maybe be exploding the
fire
fire arrow up one more and two tnt
are falling from that
that could be it
although even that i would be surprised
if it blew it up
okay so how about this just
let's assume that's what is going on
here i'm gonna light
two of these and see if it blows itself
up
let's assume a fire arrow is getting
launched up somehow
i bet you that's what it is i think
i think that might be it so there the
fire arrows are getting stuck in the
tube
and then the tnt blows it up to the next
piece and two are getting
dropped i bet
aha how do i fix that i don't know
i'll think about it i guess i pretty
sure that's the problem though
all right so i was thinking about some
more obviously the tnt is not
launching the fire arrows
in the tube because it doesn't explode
in the tube
so what's probably happening is when i
shoot the flame bow
you kidding me what was that
i want to do that again
is it not sticking into i don't even
know what's going on anymore
i think there's some bugs with arrows or
something going on
that is so weird it's like it's not
sticking sometimes
you're i'm shooting it too hard it's
bouncing out
um so i think what's happening is when i
shoot up sometimes
like arrows i believe can move up to
four blocks per second
and i think it's somehow
triggering two tnt per shot
but i didn't get a good view of it
either time and i wasn't recording
either time
so it's really hard to say exactly what
happened
yeah look at that that is so weird
um that was like a that was a strong
shot too huh
anyway so why are we at the stronghold i
just wanted to point something out
uh there's been a change in
one of the recent snapshots where now
witches spawn
naturally as i'm sure a lot of you heard
so my mop farm here is getting them
they have more oh it's it's nighttime
we're not going to see
too good of rates until daytime so let's
go sleep
they have more health than the other
mobs though so i didn't really plan
around that with this mob farm
so sometimes they fall and they don't
die but
most of the time when they fall they do
it's just the lower level
the lower spawning levels in my giant
tower there
that they sometimes
don't fall far enough
we might be able to i think was that one
no that was a zombie
that makes a weird noise they're hitting
the wooden planks as they fall
come on mobs i think what happens at
nighttime a bunch of slime spawn outside
too
so right when you switch it today it's
not very good till they despawn
but i did get a few drops i got seven
sticks
for spider ice three sugar and an
instant health potion from
the witches already just being here for
a little while i
don't think i'm gonna get much redstone
and glowstone out of it though to be
honest
i was really excited i thought maybe
because i'm always desperate for
redstone i thought maybe this is
what was gonna do at this change but now
it's pretty slow
although it'll it'll help um
i almost never show it let's go outside
uh
if there's any new viewers out here and
wondering where the mobs are coming from
we are in a swamp biome here this is
stronghold that i've kind of converted
into a base
and above here is a giant spawning tower
i built
all the mobs fall down a single one by
one hole
all the way down here
and it gets pretty decent rates
considering there's no pistons involved
it's a pretty good mob farm
oh yeah
that's my jam okay we're back here
it's a really good song i like this one
the most
i always say cat was my favorite but
ward
it's awesome i don't
yeah that's actually really loud though
i even turned it down
oh does it not work
oh yeah it must be glitchy okay anyway
uh so i've been doing some stuff around
here this now goes all the way through
and i put a staircase
uh down i talked about wanting to
putting
wanting to putting wanting an elevator
here that goes up to the surface
that i can take the horses up to and
checked it out right above here is the
river
from uh which river
this river up here um so i wasn't able
to go straight up there so i decided
just to make a staircase that goes down
and instead i put the piston elevator
over here
i think this is a good spot for it
it's not done yet though needs some
polishing work but it is functional at
this point
uh so let's try it out we'll get a horse
here
and i got a second chance
there he's in the end now he's like man
there's a spot missing
uh this is cool too i i noticed this
today if i go in here
this is my uh little holding cells
now when i get off the the horses or the
donkeys it actually puts me outside
which is
really cool
kind of unexpected and nice because
before
it would drop me off inside here and i'd
have to walk out so it's just a little
bit nicer
a little more convenient but let's uh
let's take this guy i guess
and check out the elevator here it's
just uh
this is the jeb piston design thing
um basically this sticky piston pushes
this piston out
and then that gets powered from behind
there
and pushes up and they alternate every
redstone tick
that's pretty cool uh i don't have a way
of jumping down yet so i have to take
the long route
and i'm still working out how to make it
work for a player it does work for
players
too but it's you gotta get your position
just
right some people they like to put
fences on both sides but then i wouldn't
be able to get
the horse through
so i just kind of have to guess where
the middle is
alright so let's go back down
here i'll try ride it so if the best way
seems to be to stand in the middle
all right so i had to jump at the end
there i don't think i can just walk out
with the way i have it set up if i
change these to half slabs
or added a piston that pushes me forward
should work out just fine
that's not too bad though oh yeah i was
just
trying to walk forward that time didn't
work out too well
yeah that's actually not too bad i you
guys having more trouble before
if you hit that middle though it seems
to work
yeah okay okay that's more promising
i was having more trouble before um
that's good let's just take a look back
here i don't know how much you can see
yeah it's pretty sorry guys it's pretty
much
blocked up but i'm planning on adding
one of these in the end as well to get
up to
the portal to leave from my ender ender
2.0 once i get that working
so i'll build another one probably and
i'll record that
if you guys want to see it
yeah that's that's pretty nice
not too bad i like it
it takes me out oh that didn't work
yeah my position wasn't even that great
that time it still worked so that's cool
um so it takes me out here there's
nothing really
here so i'll need to dress up the
outside over here too
okay so that's gonna be about it for
today everyone but we are going to end
it on a high note with enchantment
oh and that's a good one i like that so
the plan is
i'm gonna go get some quartz i'm gonna
fix up the ender ender
2.0 and i'm gonna remove the whole
shooting the tnt with the flame bow
aspect of it because i don't know if the
arrows are just acting funny and
maybe they'll get fixed in the future i
don't know
but i'm going to use a flint and steel
to light the tnt and just do one at a
time
instead of having a whole chamber of
them and that should work no problem
pretty sure but i've been wrong twice
today so
yeah don't take my word for it and then
when i get that fixed up next episode
sorry to do this but i'm going to
release a world download
then because i want that project
finished before i
actually release the world download so
another delay
my apologies but
again the world downloaders is something
i do because
i want to make people happy not because
i need to so
don't demand it because it's it's
something i'm
i'm doing as a bonus sort of thing um
okay so well you can demand it i don't
care
doesn't mean you're going to get it i
actually like to see when people ask for
it because it reminds me but that's the
time to release it again
so don't like hate on people that ask
for it either so anyway here we go
here's the comments for today uh this
one gave me a chuckle so i included it
i was talking about the statistics last
time about people that like blue
and he says sixty percent of males like
blue forty percent of females like blue
therefore one hundred percent of people
like blue
did i do it right uh
yeah uh next one hey etho just wondering
how tall
you are keep up the amazing videos love
from england
ah so this is something i've never said
in video before a little personal
question
um but i am i used to say i was
three but i measured uh one day and i
think i'm actually six
two i that kind of caught me by surprise
it was wasn't as tall as i
was telling people i think i'm six two
but i could be wrong too
um it's actually really interesting a
lot of the guys
on the minecraft server are really tall
like there's a lot of
a lot of us that are over six feet which
is
unusual at least where i live um
i've noticed in the u.s there's more
taller people than in canada
when i go visit there but even still
uh there's very few people over six feet
and to have like i think at least
well i don't know how many there's i
don't know the exact number but it seems
like about half
almost are six feet or taller
in particular paws and dot dam are like
really tall
i think dot m six foot five
or something i can't remember now off
the top of my head
anyway interesting
interesting coincidence so that there's
so many tall people in one place
but that's gonna do it so i'll fix up
the intermittent farm and get the world
download next episode most likely for
sure even if there's a problem i'll
probably release it anyway should be
fine though
and i will see you guys again next time
thanks for watching as always
and i hope you enjoyed bye