[Music]
Hey
how's it going everybody this is etho
and we are back again to the guys with
another episode of the let's play series
hopefully you guys are having yourselves
a wonderful day today and I got I got a
strange episode for you today I don't
know how this is gonna go I'm a little
bit nervous about this one but there's
been some big changes guys as you
probably already could tell like what
what are these strange sounds coming
from etho is he depressed
why is he caving he never goes to well
I'll try to answer some of those
questions for you today I'm gonna give
you some background behind-the-scenes
information on our recording setup today
and it's gonna be a bit more of a talky
episode instead of like doing minecraft
stuff we might do that if we have time
later but I just want to give you an
update on some stuff here so that's why
we're caving it's a lot easier to talk
while we're keeping than if I'm building
so I guess the first big thing I wanted
to mention this is a little bit personal
I I hate to say it but over the last
couple years oldi throw here has been
the victim of some very light-hearted
bullying yeah it's true every time I
would press f3 inevitably in the
comments somebody was making fun of my
computer you know and it really really
didn't get to me because I know it was
all light-hearted and fun but not
anymore guys nah look at this we've got
a new computer brand new computer it's
finally happened I had that old one for
over four and a half years at this point
and I decided to splurge and get a new
one I've been wanting a new one for
quite a while now but honestly that old
one wasn't too bad even even still like
the only I think the only two things
that ever gave me trouble with it was
when I was trying to record arc survival
and no man's sky even at the lowest
settings like I could barely get 30fps
with those
other than that like I never really had
a problem with that but you know it
doesn't hurt to get something new and
better so we got a new computer we have
a we went from a 770 which was released
in 2013 that graphics card which we now
have a 2060 which is over twice as
powerful of a graphics card which is
pretty amazing I tried our survival on
it we can run at the maximum settings at
over 60 fps now which is crazy so that's
pretty exciting we also have a better
processor now we went from a I think i7
4770k to a i7 9700 at 3 gigahertz here
that's a little bit faster and we also
have 16 gigs of ram we have a 2 terabyte
hard drive and a 256 gig solid-state
drive with our Windows 10 loaded up on
it never use Windows 10 before I I got
mixed feelings about it so far a lot of
stuff running around in the background
I'm trying to figure out how to shut it
all off but once you do that like most
windows are fine when you shut all shut
all that background garbage off but yeah
so that's the first big thing here new
computer super excited oh and the best
part about it it's quiet like I can
barely tell it's running our other
computer was like a constant
I even when I was idling um I ended up
putting a pillow over top of that thing
to dampen the sound and that actually
worked pretty good because before that
it was getting picked up in the
recordings but the pillow trick kind of
dealt with it although it restricted the
airflow a bit as well but it never
overheated so it was fine so now that we
got a new computer I got to thinking
like do we really want to just load up
all the old stuff or do we want to try
make some improvements here as well
because I kind of wanted to upgrade to
60fps video for a while I can't really
do it on that old one but now it
shouldn't be a problem right only
problem is like since the beginning I've
recorded with fraps which is a pretty
good recording program except the only
issue is like it's totally uncompressed
all the video so if you go from 30fps to
60fps recording with that thing your
file size is double like no matter what
there's no compression on it so we're
talking like I can't get this guy yeah
we'll get him wait a sec wait a sec he's
like running away - this guy is really
moving oh no way
did he actually she got away I don't
believe it okay that's fine one in a
million
um what was I saying yeah so I'm
recording now with GeForce experience so
we switched from fraps which actually
compresses things I also that was
probably him I also have OBS as a backup
I might use that instead if I'm finding
problems with this but I think this is
working okay actually I did run into one
kind of issue though this new GeForce
recorder I'm using only saves the files
as empty fours
which guess what fraps always save them
as a be eyes and virtualdub the editor i
use does not accept mp4s
when editing videos unless maybe there's
a plugin for it you could get or I'll
have to pre convert them to AV eyes but
I decide on the third option just to try
find a new video editor finally
virtualdub is pretty much only good for
simple things like piecing together
Clips a video I can't really do any
fancy editing unfortunately with it but
our videos have been pretty simple up to
this point so it's kind of worked up
until now I've always wanted a better
editor that maybe I'm gonna do some more
fancy stuff with I just had trouble
finding one I liked until recently just
by coincidence I finally found one that
seems pretty cool I'm trying out the
Vinci resolve 15 to edit together this
episode we'll see how it turns out
hopefully it's good though and we can
keep using it so that's that's big that
means in the future here as I get more
proficient with this editor we can maybe
do some cool little transitions in the
episode or speed up video or you know
mix and match things we got we got
options now instead of just clipping the
video together like for example when I'm
shaving here maybe I start talking about
the the creeper face and the man cave
and you guys are kind of like what's he
talking about it I can't see that I can
like show a clip of the creeper face at
the man cave and you'll you'll know what
I'm talking about or we can go over to
Wilson meanwhile I'm just caving here
and you you can see what I'm talking
about and one more big final change to
tell you guys about since the beginning
of my youtube channel here I have always
used the exact same microphone I've had
two pairs of the logitech g3 thirties
it's just a cheapo $50 headset but the
microphone on it is amazing right I
sound different in the early videos
though because like my voice was
probably different my speaking style and
also my settings did change over time
because I used to whisper in the videos
and but then I figured out how to change
it properly but anyways always had the
same exact headset right I plug it into
the new computer and it doesn't sound as
good for some reason I'm guessing
because the sound card is different
maybe it just doesn't like them or maybe
there's some settings I can't find but
they're just not as good as like in the
previous videos they sound a bit more
tin can II and and stuff like that so
that was a bit of a downer
I decided though to try out this 8020 35
XLR microphone I've had laying around on
the old computer when I tried it out it
sounded horrible like way off from what
it should be I plugged it into the new
computer here and it sounds a lot better
maybe not as good as a logitech g3 30s
I'm not sure yet I'm kind of releasing
this video to get your guys's opinion on
it how do I sound compared to the old
videos I think my voice is a bit more
full like from what I can tell I might
need to make some adjustments like I can
can use an equalizer to fine tune things
a little bit but this is just my voice
raw on the microphone now so you guys
like it do you think it's better you
might not like it just because it's a
change and you're used to it one way but
try to think like is it actually better
or not and you just don't like it cuz
it's different I guess
yeah I don't know anyways I'm gonna
hopefully keep using this microphone
from now on because those old g3 30s
they don't sound as good on this new
computer and also they're trashed like
they are gone I've talked about this
before like the frame broke on them a
long time ago the padding is all falling
off of the headset so I think we went
down there already so it's like super
uncomfortable to wear them the mute
button doesn't work and because the
frame has been broken for so long even
the wiring
is starting to fray like crazy like
they're gonna eventually totally snap in
half and the electronic part of its
gonna be broken so they're almost
reduced down to just being a microphone
at this point so I really need to change
so hopefully you guys like this new
microphone it should be better like it's
technically a way better microphone I
just had trouble with the settings on it
for some reason before uh-huh but
anyways guys that's pretty much all I
wanted to tell you I figured I should
say something instead of just like
leaving you scratching your head in it
wondering like what's going on why does
evil sound different why is everything
different now for good reasons so to
summarize all the changes here we got a
new computer it's super fast super
amazing I love it which we're gonna use
to try upload at 60 frames per second
from now on to go along with that we
needed to get new recording software so
we're using GeForce experience and we
needed new editing software to make that
work so we got the DaVinci Resolve 15
for trying out seems really cool though
and we're even using a new microphone
not a new one it's one I've had for a
long time by just couldn't get it to
sound good before no matter how much I
played with the settings and equalizer
and stuff it just sounded horrible but
now it seems decent I think it's gonna
be okay
and that's that's about it oh yeah one
more thing my scroll wheel on my mouse
was broken so I got a new mouse that's
like the last final change so quite a
bit quite a big amount of changes there
that's pretty much everything you could
change as a youtuber so it's gonna take
a while to adjust to it but hopefully it
will be okay but I hate to say it I have
years and years of built-up frustration
with not being able to edit my videos
seeing all these youtubers do amazing
things and I'm just clipping stuff
together I have to take it out right now
I saw in this editor it has the greatest
transition
let's start this off with a star wipe to
the mancave followed up with the
Magnificent star wipe to the library ooh
that was classy that one that felt good
now we're gonna follow it up with a
tremendous star wipe to the windmill
whoo whoo that was a good one that felt
really good
I've been wanting to do that for so long
but wait you think we're done we're not
done no no no we still got an incredible
star wipe to the nether hub and you know
what one of our longest-running projects
I think deserves a long star wipe to the
Nexus but you know why do we even need
to go anywhere we can just star wipe and
star wipe and start wiping star wipe oh
this is great I think we should we
should finish it off though I could go
on for days here but really let's let's
end it with one really graceful heart
wipe to Ethos lab here oh snap okay that
was good I think with that guys I should
be under control for a while
all right everybody well we're gonna try
to keep today's episode pretty simple
just in case we end up strapping the
whole thing to some unforeseen technical
problem I've actually had to scrap a lot
of it already because I I keep running
into small little issues but yeah one
more simple thing we could do here to
fill out a few more minutes is just to
check out this this fortress thing so
I've been wanting to make a farm out of
it like a raid farm
I think this only spawns the bowmen and
the bannermen right none of the axe
wielding guys have indicators
the damage was enchanted yeah so check
this out let's go over here uh-huh
speaking of technical issues I just had
to scrap a few more minutes of a footage
because I'm getting that static sound I
just left a little little taste of it in
for you guys so you you know what I'm
talking about
but my microphone will just randomly
start making static and like chirping
sounds and I haven't figured out why it
might be something running in the
background on my computer but any of you
are technical geniuses audio geniuses
let me know if you know what's causing
that cuz I need to fix it it's a big
problem right now what I said though
hopefully you can hear it this time is
this this tower is actually great it's
amazing for making a farm here because
normally you need to clear out like a 90
diameter cue ball around this thing
which means we're moving a lot of land
because it usually spawns on flat land
right in the plains but it's on top of a
mountain here so all around is cleared
out already there's nothing around this
thing except this mountain here which
I'd have to clear out a little bit
because they do spawn over here and in
like 20 blocks below this but again like
most of it's cleared out around just a
little bit of the mountain will have to
go away and we can we can have ourselves
a pretty awesome raid farm here so
that's hopefully what we'll do next
episode but unfortunately with that guys
I think we should just keep this one on
the short side hopefully I'll get things
running smoother next episode especially
if you guys give me feedback on what you
think of the voice and if you know the
answers to any technical problems I'd
appreciate it but let's do the comment
of the day it says hey etho I know when
I play a lot of Minecraft my dreams
start to take place inside the Minecraft
world I would assume that this must
happen to you from time to time as well
if so what is the craziest most awesome
Minecraft dream you have ever had oh you
would think because I play this game a
lot right I
play a lot of games actually I never
really have had video game dreams like
ever um I actually don't dream very
often it's very rare I usually am a
super deep sleeper like I dream
obviously but I don't remember them
right the few times that I do remember
my dreams
for some reason aren't that great I have
a lot of like almost nightmarish dreams
I don't know why I don't get scared in
the dream but a lot of times I wake up
friends like man that was a it was a
messed up dream why did I dream that
notably like one that keeps reoccurring
as I I keep dying from tornadoes in my
dreams I don't know why but that has
happens in at least 20 or 30 dreams it's
it's like a major reoccurring dream for
me so I actually don't mind dreaming or
not dreaming it's it's kind of cool
uh-huh anyways hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
sorry it's so short
until next time take care have a good
day bye bye