well hello everyone this is ether hari
Wow
okay did not see him hello hello creeper
so glad for you to make an appearance
that's not she kind of weird that he
came down came down from here alright
usually if there's that creeper in the
basic comes down from from there anyway
so uh how are you guys doing today I am
I am not feeling so good myself to be
honest I I don't think I can record
today guys my voice I'm dying basically
is what I'm getting yet but no my voice
has been biting me the last couple days
I think I might be catching something
it's not quite terrible yet but I've had
to record my intro several times here
just because I have very little voice
control today it's it's all over the
place I'm squeaking and I'm and I'm
grumbling and and making motor car
noises it's crazy so hopefully I can get
an episode out today regardless for you
guys it is flu season so if you guys
aren't feeling good you're there there I
did it again I was like yeah if you guys
aren't feeling good today or the O and
ice I'm terrible just feeling so bad and
it's it's affecting my brain in my
speech but if you guys are not feeling
well do not I repeat do not go shopping
do not go to school do not go to work do
not go visit friends keep it to
yourselves I'm telling you don't don't
share your germs
you got to prevent the spread stay home
watch youtube videos all day and if your
parents or your teachers or your boss
give you trouble just just let them know
that ethos said it's okay okay alright
so
the thing I'm really excited to show you
guys today though as you know with 1.8
snapshots there has been a skin update
and I have updated my skin for the first
time in like three years I've never
changed it once not even for a day not
even for a little updates to fix a pixel
or anything it's always been the same
until now so are you ready to see ISO
2.0 oh yeah so sleek so smooth I have
I've got like a spring/summer thing
going on here I'm preparing for the
warmer weather so I got a nice haircut
hair is nice and smooth and short and of
course I got my summer mask on as you
know in the summer it can get quite hot
and when you're breathing in a mask it
gets warm as well and quite moist and
you can develop rashes around your your
lips if you're not careful so I have a
little sleeker summer version of my mask
right now and it is pretty good I'm
liking it loving the new changes so oh
yeah ethos skin 2.0 now but here is my
real skin I had to do this thing with
the mask because it looked really weird
if I did the full mask like some of the
pixels were kind of showing on the outer
layer still so the trade-off is I look
really stupid without the mask on like
my my headgear let's put it back on our
hat I guess it's called
there we go good as good as usual yeah
you could see like weird weird pixels if
I did the full thing before though I
think it's okay like this so so I got a
new new hat
I got excuse me let's do sleeves I think
I changed the sleeves oh yeah I did some
stuff with the sleeves I don't know if
you can see it here I got to get
something off my bar um but my my
my wrists sweatbands or whatever they
now are kind of 3d they they kind of pop
out a little bit which is cool it looks
like they're around the arm instead of
like built into the arm although I can't
like can't make the whole arm skin color
because when I go into this perspective
it gets rid of the wristband on my eye
arm here I think we're out of snowballs
I think that's what that's trying to
tell me let's go away from that I don't
know slimes are worse so yeah I got some
3d wristbands now I think they're kind
of cool I think one again
what else did I change I got I did some
stuff with the legs as you can see I now
have like kind of 3d sandals which is
really cool I think that's my favorite
change it actually looks like they're
their shoes like I got something on my
feet instead of it being built into the
foot which is cool so I'm liking the new
skin changes and we had the emblem on my
shoulders you can see you're kind of 3d
now they kind of pop off I might make a
few other changes I'm not quite sure I
wasn't really sure what to do with my
vest like I tried a few other things
like I tried putting a bandage around my
right leg like Kakashi normally has
didn't quite like how that looked I
tried putting a belt around his waist
didn't quite like that either so I just
ended up doing something kind of fun and
stupid this is my jacket you ready for
it oh yeah double etho all the way
across the sky so yeah I got I got an e
so on on my front if I turn that on most
the time I will not have that on and I
got one on my back too pretty cool and
if you look as the arms are swinging I
even have the mask going around all
around the body which is cool so it's
like I'm wearing an ethos ace E
it so there's that I'm I think it will
look really funny I can't see it from my
camera angle but I think if I have my
head back like this and I'm running
forward it's gonna look like I have a
very short body or my head's missing
because they'll see the head but they
won't see the other one that's tilted
back I can't say for sure what it looks
like I haven't seen it anyway so that's
the new skin pretty happy with it there
is of course many fancy versions of
Kakashi with shading and all that I
don't really like that I like this is
what I'm used to this is what I want to
keep even though it's a little plain I
like it it's Who I am because I've had
this skin for like three years so just a
few little tweaks to it nothing major uh
today guys we're up to fifteen with our
skull so I think we should go kill them
the problem is we've got to do it quick
otherwise it's going to take the whole
episode so we kind of have to fight all
five at a time and I can barely handle
one at a time so I think we either are
going to fight it in a cave or we're
going to fight them above ground and
I'll set up like healing stations and oh
you know what I could do I get to have a
notch Apple yeah let's go ahead and do
that
not Chappell perfect I still will
probably die even with a notch Apple
because yeah withers are pretty tough
since a nerf protection on armor but
we'll give it a shot
all right so we'll do this notch Apple
and I'm going to have to fix up my armor
here too I got them a blast protection
book I couldn't find another protection
but around but that should do okay and I
should probably repair my helmets
everything is so cheap analysis with
these changes within chanting and
repairing pretty cool I even made a new
sword that has looting on looting three
sharpness five unbreaking 3 and I'm
hoping I'll be able to repair it I think
I should be able to because it's got
repairs have gotten very cheap in this
game it's at 4 right now but as this bar
goes down it's gonna cost more so I
think we're fine alright so I'm going to
prepare a little fighting arena make
some preparations and we will hopefully
do a quick 5 wither fight here the most
I've ever done it once oh man this is
gonna be good everyone right this is
gonna be good nothing's gonna go wrong
what could possibly go wrong it's just 5
withers oh boy yeah I guess this is it
let's see what happens my plan here I'm
going to eat this as like a food source
I think notch Apple has regen I hope I
know it has resistance that's the main
thing I'm I wanted it for
I think place the heads eat the apple
get more potions on the bar I'm hoping
they fight each other if they fight each
other I might have a chance here I might
run in with my sword and try to do as
much damage as I can to because the bow
takes forever and I'm using a pretty
crummy one here so
yeah here we go oh man
oh no no Apple eat the Apple get more
potions run away what it what are they
doing really gonna do are they fighting
each another
wait don't get too close
they're like doing nothing I kind of
expected a little more to be honest
okay well I'm wasting my Apple here so I
think most of them are over there oh I
think they might see me let's go for it
for the sword whoa that was a jump that
was a jump if I've ever seen one who
does much sword damaging hopefully they
start hitting each other oh and I'm
trapped in a hole now that was that was
good oh they are they're clustering up
good yeah I can only take so much damage
at a time right right
although oh man what am i doing should I
just run
I think they'll hurt each other but they
might blow up the stars too is the
problem oh come on
oh I'm almost dead
I just can't take the hits oh let me go
let me go ender pearl please and thank
you okay I threw it let's get out of
here and recover quickly quickly they're
coming I think my region wore off I
think that's why I'm taking so much
damage although if I eat this you know
what this is a bad idea
I think that'll wear off my region it
brought lots of potions where did they
go their health is going down just don't
really want them to ah okay we're going
in for sortie I guess
hello can I join the party whoo Oh what
have I done
I'm never gonna be able to kill these
guys nope not looking good well this guy
he's getting uh oh he got a pony okay
come on come on come on oh the Stars I
don't think I'm getting the Stars though
I don't think I have room is a problem
picking up too much of these junk blocks
gonna recover a bit a lot in fact oh we
got another one I see the star okay I
got two on me I got two on me you know
if I can get three out of this I would
be more than happy to be honest are you
the last guy
or is there one more Elsword motor
already awesome no you were sword mode
gonna recover and sword mode come on guy
oh yes wait no there's another one there
is another one
what's my region that look at the stats
we need more regen okay we got three
stars there might be one on the ground
if I'm lucky but it probably blew up and
I saw another wither health bar
somewhere where did that guy go though
that made it ah ha oh look there's
another star yes did a wither get away
was that what that was or are they all
dead because I saw the bar might have
got too far away from him oh I hope he
didn't go this direction okay you know
what I'm going to pause for a second and
review what happened there because I
didn't see how many died and there might
be another star on the ground so if
there is I want to check the footage to
see if I can get it back so I'll be
right back okay so I checked the footage
I think I killed them all they're pretty
sure on and it looks like they all died
in this death bit I didn't see exactly
where all the stars dropped so let's
just look around if it is here we should
be able to find it I think if we just
look but I'm guessing it blew up because
there was just way too much weight to
may wither bullets like going on there
for it to survive day it's not there
kind of expecting it in the main death
pits up over there this terrain has
gotten so scarred I thought I think I
fought every wither here in my world so
far alright I should stop wasting my
time over here
don't think it is and go where I think
it is over here not here okay it would
be on full on things okay that's fine
it would be down here I think let's
check all these cracks oh yes yes got
all five so I know that I know
Dinnerbone made it so they don't blow up
like after a wither fight I wonder if
that applies for like sometime or
permanently because I'm surprised that
they get destroyed we got all five
withers or all five nether stars out of
that which is just crazy because there
was so many explosions going on I think
they are invulnerable for a little bit
after the fight but even still I'm
surprised they all survived there that
was pretty cool so we did it
all five withers we're going to be able
to get five beacons one of them is going
to go in my nether fortress so that I
can farm more withers quicker that's
that's like kind of an ironic thing
spend all this time farming withers so
that I confirm withers yeah that's the
way it works though because I want to
speed beacon at my nether fortress and I
need a hey speech in at at the Mesa
biome we found where the clay is I need
I need he's speaking at and probably a
speed beacon for mining just regular
mining so yeah I'm gonna pretty much use
all these beacons up like right away as
soon as I get the gold to make the the
beacon of course but yeah that was
pretty fun I'm surprised how well that
turned out to be honest and the fact
that we got all five stars so I am I'm
pretty happy
I hate to do it everyone I really hate
to do it but I think we should call this
the end of the episode it's a little
shorter than what we're used to but my
throat has gotten a lot worse bothering
me a lot more since I started recording
here from all the talking it's not too
good for it I can tell
so hopefully find out some more ideas
most likely if it's going to be
something that bugs me all week or if it
or if I'm lucky I might be better
tomorrow
we'll see I don't have any other
symptoms so it's just my throat bugging
me so hopefully it doesn't progress into
something worse but as a youtuber that's
that's like the worst thing you know
give me give me the sniffles well
sniffles are kind of bad to give me an
upset stomach a headache you know
non-stop runs to the bathroom iein deal
with that just don't take away my voice
I need my voice kind of sucks oh well so
or you know what we could do we could we
could continue on like I used to in the
past
I'm a slow typer this isn't working you
know this isn't gonna work
nope way too slow okay so here's a
comment I picked out for today etho
which videos do you like making the best
and what do you think what we like to
watch my favorite is Minecraft and keep
up the great work and don't ever stop
making videos because they're awesome
haha what do you think what we like to
watch what do you think we like to watch
while the views kind of tell me what you
like to watch the things you you view
the most is what you like to watch so
it's pretty close actually between
Minecraft and my single player I think
my single player might be a little bit
more popular still but I put about equal
effort into both series except for today
sorry about today
uh your favorite is mine crack that's
good me personally you know it varies
for me like what I like to do sometimes
I got something going in my
single-player world that's what I want
to be doing
sometimes multiplayer minecraft peels to
me more if I'm I'm doing something
interesting over there I kind of go
through phases as I'm sure you guys find
different things I do more interesting
than other things so kind of goes both
ways I guess anyway
that's going to be it guys remember stay
at home watch YouTube don't go to school
don't go to work don't go shopping get
better if you're sick and I guess I'll
have to do the same oh yeah check this
out I saw the etho is enchanted if I
take off the chest piece but if I take
off the pants it goes away it's kind of
cool
same with the shoes anyway I'm stalling
I have a good day everyone
bye bye
you