did you you just kill the the villagers
no I did oh no oh yeah so welcome back
to everybody this is ESO we are back in
our vanilla minecraft world here I put a
slime block there let's see what that
does that does not work at all ah
all darn for some reason they're taking
fall damage in this thing now
oops even though they shouldn't because
they're they're not really falling far
actually they've now they only fell like
two blocks right cuz they only got up to
like that block there um tell you what
let's try put this one block higher I
might need to just put some water up
there or something let's see what that
does
I can't keep I can't keep damaging these
guys I got to heal them up or something
oh and let's let's block this before I
let this guy free okay I think that that
kind of worked right you like bounced
several times there look cool alright
let's do that then put slime blocks
there and there and that should probably
fix it alright all good looks so weird
now they bounce so many times alright
well it works good enough I'm gonna do
it through these ones too
alright guys let me tell you what's
happened here since we finished up last
episode all our beats have died here
pretty much I think I think some slimes
came along and just crushed their their
beat juices out of them poor poor little
beats um
I used to love beats guys have I ever
told you this I used to love them would
eat them all the time and so many of
them too and then one day I ate like all
the beats all the beats I possibly could
and when I went to the bathroom it was
purple and ever since then I've chosen
not to eat beats it it was very dramatic
for my like five six year old self I
couldn't handle it anymore um yeah so
I've also hooked up these piston doors
it's three by three doors I can build
these in like three minutes now llantas
do the redstone so fast I've built so
many of them I know exactly where I need
to put everything now and I've worked on
the Simon game since last episode so we
we started this we kind of got the GUI
interface set up forward the controls
some of the game logic we did last time
but the big thing we had to do the
memory for the game and that was going
to be the most difficult part of it but
thankfully I got it worked out here and
it was actually a lot easier than I
expected um so let me let me run you
through the basic idea here what what
trouble we had originally so I wanted to
have like red blue green yellow clay put
it in droppers right and then when you
press a button it would go to the next
one right and we can make a memory chain
that way
well it turns out if you just use
droppers like this press the button
again you would expect it to be over
here right wrong is it over here no here
no no no it's all the way over here shot
through like one two three four or five
six seven seven of them with that single
button press so you can't really
reliably change droppers together like
this to like move the item from one to
the next to the next because of the way
redstone works in this game since it
activates all these in the same instance
in the programming it has to pick one to
update first so if it updates like this
one first then this one then this one
all in that same instant it shoots it
through the whole chain so the solution
to this problem was actually suggested
by you guys in the comments just put a
hopper between into the droppers and it
works wonderfully it's amazing it's
beautiful
basically hoppers they have a point for
second delay with them at least last
time I checked where it takes like for
the dropper to shoot an item into it it
takes point for seconds for it then to
automatically move it into the next one
so that it creates a delay forces a
delay so that items can't just shoot
like from there all the way through all
these because each each dropper has that
delay to them right so that makes this a
lot a lot easier to do and I've just
been playing around with it a little
bit's imagine it's a worm or a snake
okay going around in a circle in a loop
this is the head of the snake right we
got we got a green there blue this one
here is a yellow then red and then we
got some air spaces here this is just
empty space room for this snake to grow
because every time we do a cycle we want
to add one on to the tail so basically a
random one here next umm and then over
and over here it passes through for item
detectors alright and this can tell what
block color passes through either red
blue yellow or green and then it
activates these pistons accordingly and
sets the memory to that color alright
still following me I hope you're not
sleeping I tried to do most of soft
camera because I know not not a lot of
people are fans of redstone let me take
you through it though so first step was
green right there you see the green one
got activated okay and now that green
one passed through the items detector
here it goes down
and then into this dropper here so
that's that's how it gets the next side
press it again should be blue they're
activated blue greens up there blues in
oh blues over there uh-huh
press it again for yellow yellow and
then finally red but the other thing
okay so we got red in here this
comparator is on it's detecting there's
an item in there still this one's empty
though and we don't really want empty
spaces so we need to advance from from
the empty one back to green which is
over here right now so there's a clock
that runs when this becomes empty that
just updates us to send it up to the
front then confused let me do it just to
show you okay now this clock is running
and this piston extends to shut it off
and now greens they're green blue yellow
red keeps the order automatically
advances it it's very cool whoo so I've
spent some more hours on this got some
more features at it this project is
crazy guys what have we got ourselves
into this time I gotta take a break from
it today though I've smashed my head
into this wall a few times here umm it's
gotten it's gotten pretty good though
it's it's very difficult to work out
some of this the details to it but yeah
I'll just show you where we're at with
it right now so as of right now we
cannot build the chain on it
that's not implemented yet so I just
have it hard-coded a sequence here
yellow red green blue so right now we're
on yellow and it's also in cheap mode
right now so when I when I get yellow it
shows me what the correct answer is next
I didn't easily get rid of that later so
red is next if we step on green our lose
condition checker there turns on
um it doesn't actually end the game
though right now is it but yeah so let's
select red that's the correct answer so
then it's green step on green this part
of it goes pretty quick I'm happy with
that like it it picks the next answer
fairly fast it's nice and evenly timed
so blue is the end of our sequence here
so now what happens is it shows us the
sequence again and it's supposed to add
one on to it but it doesn't do that
currently so goes through it yellow red
green blue this part is not fast enough
I'm not happy with this I can make it
twice as quick and I think I'm going to
have to try to do that which would be
about perfect you know alright so it
showed us the sequence again yellow red
green blue and now it's set it back to
yellow it's ready to go
you can enter the sequence again ah um
so it's getting there it's getting there
we got a bit left to do on it though let
me show you how crazy it is down here
now some blue was last on the list let's
run in here see all the things changing
all the crazy chaotic redstone doing
things I don't even know what's gonna
happen next
also the blocks are like randomly
rotating every time Pistons move which
is freaky something to do with the
latest updates uh-huh
so yeah basically that's what happens
and is done okay oh this was fun to work
out oh and by the way once we get out of
the testing stage with this I'm going to
add more memory onto it more more
droppers and hoppers currently we only
have like a combo of nine I'll probably
bring that up to about thirty or forty I
built it in such a way that we can
as much memory as we want which is cool
and also no blocks will be adding no
blocks don't you worry but one thing at
a time alright everybody so maybe next
up here let's just take a moment to
relax a little bit take a walk together
check out some things on or in the
comments on last episode I got a lot of
positive feedback on this swamp I tell
you a lot more than I expected so that
made me really happy you also seem to
really like these end rods so I'm gonna
put them back I don't know if it's
because I like star take him down nobody
really said that they thought it looked
better without them so I'm gonna put
them back and just see maybe all the
naysayers will come out now like those n
rods are the stupidest thing I've ever
seen I don't know anyways um yeah swamp
got good reviews this is the place to be
place to live you want to see something
crazy I've updated to the latest
snapshot right I like I was a few
versions back I was like in the 44s now
in the 47s 47 see here they've changed
iron golems right they they made them so
they're more useful they don't get
knocked back by skeletons and I'm
noticing maybe something else has
happened because I have craters all over
the place now over here oh snap I got to
do something about these iron golems but
let's try out the the no knock-back
thing see if it applies to players - no
I can hit him back okay so maybe it's
almost skill - I kind of expected I
wouldn't be able to do this he's taking
a beating also I've wanted to try out
something here you guys are always
telling me to use this feature is it in
video
yeah the attack indicator oh there's a
few options your hotbar
let's try crosshair
I don't notice anything did that do
something boss hair oh I see it now I
see it okay so man those guys that punch
half a hearts
um yeah I saw it right below the
crosshair there there's a little sword
that appears and it charges up as you
can attack again what's the other one
hot bar and I'm scared to hit this guy
now oh I see it's on the right of the
torch right at the hot bar oh it's cool
so once it's once that icon disappears
you're fully charged is very cool very
cool they've also added in subtitles for
sound you can hear footsteps like water
portals attaching iron golem dies pretty
cool
we got the sword attack sounds like all
the all the weapons make a woo sound now
I like it a lot but I think they should
tone down the volume a little bit check
this out there's a new brewing sound to
I look so good I think I like it with
the the sword at the bottom of the hot
bar they're the most I can see it with
my peripheral vision pretty well when
it's at the cross like the cross bar I
have a really hard time seeing that for
some reason they it's obvious if it's
against black background but if it's
like I don't like if it's a quartz or
anything bright the sky probably I don't
think I would ever see it alright guys
so next up here let's do a little bit of
building it's always fun to do that
together every now and then I saw this
it's like I wonder if there's a record
in here oh there is good
Oh where'd it go it's gone oh I have it
oh and it's cats that's a good one get
some music some tunes tune skis while we
build it's actually pretty loud isn't it
oh yeah right how's that too loud I'm
starting to regret this this decision
okay um so yeah we just want to like a
little shack you're nothing too crazy
let's let's plan this out and we might
even like go over into the water and
build like a little deck or so that
overlooks the water let's let's kind of
measure this out though basically the
plan is I'm going to put a button here a
button in here to activate the fireworks
eventually all right one two three four
five six seven always with odd numbers
that's the way to go just make a little
layouts
maybe we'll plan to come over here and
bend it around good that'll be the other
corner something like that just a really
tiny building is all I want here all
right let's clean this up and this is
the axis down here to the fire work
redstone which we're going to connect it
to
probably not today but eventually cuz
we're just building a house that's all I
want to do alright let's let's bring
this out let's do it like this bring up
the fence build this up throw fences
everywhere yeah like that that's good
and then the entrance to the building we
will put right over how kind of like a
soul all right what's that out down a
door lead the gravel to its
like so is that good
sure all right and I want this up as
well then we're gonna do like a little
overhang
let's do stairs on the side and yeah
just these posts can go up then connect
to it like so I actually like I used to
hate building a lot I enjoy it more and
more the more I do it's the more fun I
have with it all right
I still find it very difficult though I
will say that I don't know how some
people can like come up with ideas so so
quickly you'll notice I tend to do a lot
of the same thing I love the natural
like just wood and and grass and flowers
sort of look a lot so I do that a lot
let's do this as well yeah I like that
all right so we go inside
do we have birch wood no we don't should
we change it to a different type of wood
I usually use birch for the floor but
I'm gonna be crazy today we're going to
do spruce why not
the walls are gonna be Oaks so I don't
want to use oak for the floor hmm
always good to take a step back and just
look at it see if you like it or not
I find it with this one maybe we should
change it a little bit because we got
this giant overhang in the front that
sticks out right and then we made this
stick out as well maybe we should maybe
tweak this a little bit let's move this
like that yeah and then it'll be a
little bit bigger inside too I think all
right the art of this post here okay and
let's do something with stairs kind of
give it more detail
we'll use stairs instead of just
straight-up planks you know let's rip
this out
do it over here as well to do like us so
all right and we could even just use
like fence windows or something like
that fill this up it'll connect then on
this side this is the longest side here
right so maybe you just add some more
detail to it we'll bring it out one more
block yeah I like that idea
and like that all right
all right if you guys didn't know this
my least favorite part of building is
making the rooms and look how beautiful
and flatness is yeah I kinda know how to
make better-looking roofs but they end
up being like twice the size of the
building and I just I can't I can't
devote that much attention to them I
don't love them that much you know I
just want something to cover it I don't
want to like you almost penned more time
making the roof than the house Lauer's
on the man the greatest invention ever
aha so it looks like beacons give you 16
seconds of a buff now before I'm pretty
sure it was only a torso right or am i
imagining that I'm sure it was eight
that's kind of cool now you can get
pretty far away before it runs out so
here's our our house as it is right now
a little shack put some bushes on the
outside here um curve some stairs for
some detail and a little window there
more bushes and vines on this side I put
in some hay bales just for another color
get some yellow in there and inside not
furnished too lazy to do it today um we
do something here let's put down a
brewing stand
okay that looks terrible oh but now it
takes up the whole like we don't have a
lot of space I can't do that that's a
crime against space let's do do a little
table like that we need to fit a bed in
here or something - over here we have
the little deck I wanted with a covering
over top kind of cool kind of cozy and I
brought I brought this - I'm just going
to put it down I only had one bookshelf
can you believe it just one what am I
supposed to do with one that's not
enough can you put these in here no you
still chant I didn't think so
ah yes very nice I can't find my pink
tulips either pink tulips are the best
if you guys didn't know they look very
good and we're going to try grow a tree
here - let's do this trying to go for a
tall tree that is not a tall tree and
it's the dot again darn it
okay well I think I'm happy with this
now guys we got a tall tree to grow here
I I put some vines on it we'll see what
those do hopefully they they don't get
too crazy and I also changed out the oak
logs with dark oak some of them the ones
you see mostly I think that's kind of
cool because in the area we have dark
oak trees and I wanted to keep that look
you know put down a couple flowers and I
also put in a little garden here which I
like just a little extra thing to give
some some color and whatnot fill up the
space oh and I I did a couple more
changes in here but I'll do a little bit
more later
anyways I think that's good let's get on
to the comment of the day we're going to
wrap it up here and here it is it says
hey etho it looks like you could do a
dance dance revelution game out of this
setup as well so we worked on the Simon
game last episode and that
that's what this comments talking abouts
you know it's funny I actually thought
about doing that and I decided to do the
Simon game instead and maybe down the
line velu will do something like that I
was planning on doing like a note
randomizer and then we would have to try
copy the note at the right time and that
kind of stuff but I don't know we'll see
maybe a future project
anyways I hope you guys enjoyed today's
episodes thank you for watching and I'll
see you in the next one take care bye
bye