[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho
and today is a very special episode this
is the 200th episode
of our let's play series and it's been
it's been a fun journey that's for sure
um
so since it's a special episode i wanted
to do something special for you guys
i was going to do a world tour of
this current world and maybe even the
older worlds we've had
but you know what there's just not
enough
time there's not enough time we might do
that sometime in the future
sometime soon if people want to see it
but today
we just didn't have enough time um
for what we have planned so i did ask
what people wanted to see for the
special
and surprisingly it's what i had planned
well a lot of people said what i had
planned uh the common request was to see
my face and i am going to show it to you
my freaking awesome clip episode
also known as montage of previous
episodes
uh is what we got planned for today i
the thing is it's really hard
i'm switching views it's too hard to
walk around like that
the thing is the plan was
to go through all 200 episodes and make
a montage of all of them
but there just wasn't enough time just
the first hundred
picking through the highlights i had
over like 36
37 minutes so i just did the first
season of the old world
the chocolate island world and
maybe in a future special we'll do a
montage of this current world but
if you haven't seen the older episodes
or even if you have i'm sure you will
enjoy this
so get your snacks together
and enjoy the show oh yeah
i guess only way to really show you
the episode the montage the face
is if you go inside my mind
here we go
hello everyone my name is etho
he sees me he sees me what
hello
how's it going this whoa
awesome aw
of course what is he doing
move
oh man
now i'm just messing with you i'm not
going to harvest this clay
i am going to leave this clay here and
you're going to see it
every episode and it's going to torment
you next player would get off
it open
and around and around she goes
yes i'm pretty lost
ah
[Music]
woohoo
so this water wall is kind of
interesting
for one thing it kills creepers if they
try to walk through it
[Music]
whoa
saw that coming
oh he wasn't even flashing
this is our second mob system
close that one oh crap
i hate to be cheap but
oh no no
i was on peaceful
oh two
one blast off
[Music]
then what you do is you place two stairs
here
and it creates the flow again
and so the mobs just keep going through
and they get pushed up the stairs and
it's like there's no space
thanks for watching
hopefully it won't be a big issue with
the guys fighting with each other
and that's the end of our episode thanks
for watching
[Music]
oh it didn't work
died feb
9 11.
they immediately get the fire
immediately gets put out
so they don't take fire damage
so this is a possible new mode of
transportation
using minecarts so i enter the my carts
nothing happens if i press down
we take off and we can travel
on land that has no
tracks on
don't don't don't don't please don't
[Music]
oh
oh you got it
and i hit this tree now
here comes the boat
and i just jumped across an impossible
jump
it's impossible evo your arrogance
will be your downfall my friend your
pride is is
now eating away like a worm on your
sanity
it's impossible you can't build a mob
sorter
if you guys don't already know how to
make one of these repeaters it's
pretty simple
wait yeah i forgot for a sec how to do
it
and i think that yeah that's how you
make a repeater
very interesting little things
you place a torch and then remove it
and i think that's one o'clock maybe
it's a two o'clock
q he asked me if i could think of any
way
to make a door stay open for
uh two seconds or longer when you press
a button
because normally if you press a button
on a door
a lot of times you'll try to go walk
through it and it's closed by the time
you get there already
that's really annoying so yeah this is
what i
came up with
works pretty good well first let's
launch this
oh my goodness it hit the boat are you
kidding me
oh i hope i didn't blow everything up
oh okay
yeah not my proudest moment ever
it works
but these fences are because whoa
oh no ah
it is called chocolate island boats like
that items can fall down
the pipe into the stream and when the
boats like this
they cannot
seems to work pretty good
they get pushed to this corner here and
they take damage
oh yeah
[Music]
okay here we go daytime launch
first time high speed
still random all right let's go download
oh
i knew i was gonna do that too
you can separate chickens using gravity
and water
and separate pigs using a one block high
opening with a diagonal water stream
oh it's madness
holy smokes
ah
we probably are a little bit whoa
that's not good that's not good oh my
goodness
oh look there's a brown sheep that's the
first one i've seen
hey everyone this is e to the t to your
mom
and as well i like watching uh damn 77
of course
he's builds awesome stuff and
uh he's got a great accent knows how to
make things look good
and he knows how to build complicated
stuff too
so it was a real challenge to get them
to make it all the way around
uh not an easy thing to do they work
pretty good
one million views guys i didn't think
this would ever happen
let's watch all the animals die
uh that's cool
but you know what i think i think
everybody misses you
a lot right now and wishes you haven't
hadn't left us
you know the world's just not the same
without you you've inspired so many
people and touched so many lives
and i don't think things will ever be
the same without you
what the heck oh you sneaky
oh
so you can go ahead and start growing
your next crop
and if you want details on how this
works uh please watch
the tutorial i just recently released
geronimo
[Music]
well i guess what's this track see what
happens
[Music]
oh
i shoot it back up
[Music]
nope seemed fine
cool in a snowy biome
i hear someone creeping yes
no you're not allowed in here no sorry
whoa there we go
so here's to the first launch guys
[Music]
right on that's what i wanted to see
i'll just show you this
i was working on making like a buffer
kind of like a pez dispenser except
spread out horizontally
so the water in this hot and cool thing
does nothing now
unfortunately so the only way to put
these flames out is to actually destroy
the minecarts and replace them
and no wolves are going through that
i've seen so far so
you can make it buddy no you don't want
to go that way
i believe in you
and that's what i like
so
window
oh why didn't i think of that before
oh it makes the place so much bigger
it's like the world
is inside my house now
no
let's try it again
oh
oh that's weird oh you know unless
maybe you need to throw like a bunch of
them on the ground first
and then light it up fire and then it
probably makes blue fire
no he didn't tell me how to
use them properly i just kind of
assumed
no
and what the heck
oh unless it's to make
like blue fireworks
that could be
no man what that is so weird
it must have been a false tip then
but yeah this is uh this is
above the farms spent a little time
trying to make it look a little better
got a cool little bridge here
um and this is what it looks like from a
distance at night
it's kind of cool thank you everybody
enjoy the show
oh
well that didn't happen last time get
get down here
oh boy oh no
oh you little cheapo man he always does
this he always
ah he can't beat me in a fair fight and
he knows that he always has to do this
ninja crap on me and surprise attack me
so i'm gonna sneak around real quiet and
try
climb up
because he's stuck up there he can't run
oh crap yes tnt no
no that's it spez i'm going home man if
you don't want to fight fair
oh man that just happened
no
you know when you're ready to fight like
men when you grow a pair
of arms i have installed my first
minecraft mod yes
now i know i know many of you are upset
right now
but uh hear me out you know before you
judge me
before you create an we hate etho fan
club
and burn me alive just tear me out
listen what i have to say about this mod
it's incredible
uh this is the g all nether mod
created by ibel from the minecraft forms
this is like the best feature of this g
all nether mod
when you walk through the portal
it's instant
how cool is that
[Music]
i really like that feature and now this
other feature
just boggles my mind i don't know how
it will coated this but you can see
the nether through the portal you can
see the fire in there i hope you can see
it
and not only that you can like hear the
fire through the portal somehow
so i'll be able to fix these only
problem is it reverses the doors
or it reverses the signal
yeah i like these things though they're
very cool favorite part of the patch
by far kind of a bummer these don't work
anymore because i
spent a long time on them
way faster than walking
[Music]
it's just a giant minecart
spiral tower thing
second attempt here
ignore these first few notes
and here we go
[Music]
so
okay just want to say thank you to
everybody
very awesome thank you for showing me
your support
and for watching my videos liking them
telling your friends about
them it's really really cool i'm amazed
so many people
watch my videos and
yeah so we've come a long way guys
no no no no
it's baz we're not doing this this
episode
we're not
spaz look i don't want to fight you
anymore because
you're a big loser and a chicken
you are a chicken because whoa
calm down spaz calm calm down man
fine you know what i have an idea of how
we can
show who's the bigger chicken so meet me
at the track
stop running for me stop running
what are you doing let's just go to the
track
okay we're gonna go to the track
okay i'll meet you there just follow me
it's it's that way okay
okay well i'm just gonna go and then
you're following okay let's go i think i
have a boat around here
i'll meet you there here we go
this is it spaz you're gonna lose
you don't stand a chance and there's no
way i'm backing down
do
this is crazy
[Music]
and i'm out of food here so i can't mess
up
[Music]
am i oh man that's crazy
this is the coolest dungeon i've ever
found
i don't know what was that no
no
the latest addition let's go for a ride
you just right click on the boat
trap door opens solid water source
blocks in here
all the way to the surface
step on a pressure plate trigger the
trapdoor it falls down
and resets
so when i was playing around with
pistons today i came across something
very cool
this is going to be very fundamental
to a lot of things i do i'm sure uh what
you do is you dig one hole
and get your get your piston above
like that place a redstone wire below
and
a lever next to it
turn it on and guess what you have here
this is a block sensor
piston
so when the tree grows guess what
happens
automatically moves all the logs all the
way around
nice
oh crap he's gonna kill me set this off
yeah i don't like the new tnt very much
oh
it water gates come
all the slimes get pushed to that
corner there
what's wrong are you feeling confined
restricted
powerless okay calm down buddy
calm down hmm well it seems like i made
a huge
gonna have to redo all these walls
so these will just keep going around and
around
until they disappear or the water
freezes
[Music]
wow wasn't that awesome guys that was
very cool
i have an intro now finally took a while
but i got one
uh big thank you to elle the hedgehog
who made that for me
so i'll see you on the other side oh
you gotta be kidding me
how did a creeper get in here the point
of this
you go in it and you die
of course can't get
why would you do that well this is what
i'm using to get from
my starter base to my new ice base
because this is where i slept so this is
where my spawn point is
enjoy
epic you still remember who this is
right
eso efo etho
yeah uncle leo i mean etho this is etho
so this should work out pretty good and
this is the fifth
mob system i'm gonna be building it's
also a hostile mob one
uh the main difference though this is
aimed at high efficiency
and as you can see
moves the items all is good
assuming of course my water streams down
here
down here aren't frozen this should work
good
they won't freeze once the floor is on
let's try this out
that's pretty cool water
will probably be on all the time only
turn it off when you
want to restock it and it's bright
enough that mobs won't spawn
so directly
what the heck how did i fall no
no got these switches here that one's
for the lighting
switch is pretty quick it's good
um this one's for spider options i think
i showed that already
um you are now going to believe this
this is crazy
[Music]
oh such a crazy patch
look at them all it's crazy
switch it
okay we're gonna go down below
all right so the reason why i made the
spawning pads
bigger is because of this experiment i
did here
but it looks like all the pigs got
separated amazingly
all the chickens are getting separated
to our emp units with
i didn't do all the tubes because i
didn't have enough glass at the time
oh yeah they straight fell so they died
all wool in there all pork in there
and bunch of chickens in here blast off
we got our sand cannon
and our water switch
there's the torch it's going to the
pressure plate
it worked that time that's
it's cool of uh hard to deal with them
when they're all out
if you share them you get more wool it's
another nice thing
instead of only getting one you get
between two and four
but yeah that's the ideas
should be a fun build
i'm not worried about
it not working with my lp series the
patch
from what i understand things like
villages and that won't appear in my
game
the new biomes won't appear in my game
unless i explore
further
every time a new mob spawns there's a
slim chance it will be a slime
and you're just increasing the number of
times that dice roll
occurs so you will get more slimes if
you're killing other mobs quickly
the lava turns all four on or off
these ones control the water
cool
do
i absolutely love the dashing i'm so
glad you can do it all the time
i was worried you wouldn't be able to
passive mob spawning has changed
significantly but as is right now
my mob systems are all broken enderman
will take pieces away until water starts
flowing down
and it totally gets messed up goodbye
worlds
we loved you we enjoyed you had many
good times here
but don't be sad people even though
we're saying
goodbye to it today we
had good times here and those good times
aren't leaving us we learn many things
here and we will continue
to remember those
very good i hope you guys enjoyed that
as much as i
as i did that was a lot of fun to make
did you clap at the end of it did you
of course he did that was that was
really cool i'm happy with the way that
turned out
uh there's a lot of work putting it
together of course but uh
had a lot of fun doing it you know as
the guy recording this
i usually don't go back and watch my
episodes
so a lot of the stuff i went through i
haven't
really seen myself like i know what
happens in the episodes but
to watch him again as like a viewer
instead of the guy recording it's
it's a different perspective so really
cool to go through all that again
and relive some of the memories i
forgot about some of that stuff happened
years
like a year ago or more so forgot a lot
of things
um
oh yeah so basically for those of you
that aren't sure how that works out
uh everything you saw there was from
episode 101 and before that's when we
ended that world
we ended it because of the 1.8 patch it
messed up
just about everything in the world
including the main project i was working
on it got
the brunt of the problems
[Music]
so i decided to start a new world since
everything was
a mess and i do not regret the decision
i've really enjoyed
working in this world so everything from
i think episode 104 to now
has been in this world i think that's
the way it was
and i plan to continue this world for
as long as possible i don't think i'll
ever have to change it
because mojang or moyang
have improved um
the way the game handles older patches
so that is good
and what else was i gonna say
i was able to
i think by watching that i was able to
think of ways i could improve the series
as well what is this guy doing here
where he must from up there maybe
you know where is he going i've never
had trouble with creepers in my base
until just recently i get tons of mobs
now for some reason
yeah he was weak um
but yeah you know i think the episodes
are pretty good as they are now but
i'm always looking for ways to improve
them and uh watching that old stuff
i was i did a lot of fun and goofy stuff
back then i think we need to
incorporate more of that into the let's
play as it is
now um but yeah that was good
all right guys so we are going to wrap
up our episode for the day our
very special episode i hope you enjoyed
it
and of course a big thank you to
everybody who
continues to support this series
i very much appreciate it so thank you
everybody
we have a lot of fun together don't we
um
oh yeah one more thing the 1.3
pre pre-release blah has come out
the other day and i plan on using that
for the next episode
the 1.3 patch official one will be out
soon as well
but i think the pre-release is stable
enough to use so
that's the plan for next episode we're
going to check out the
1.3 features in our world here and i'm
very excited for that i've been waiting
oh so long as you guys have been
as well so it's going to be fun looking
forward to it
and i will see you guys again next time
thank you for watching
all this time