[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys to another episode
why won't you move come on guy
uh you know that little baby villager i
couldn't find last episode i think this
is i think this is it he grew up he
became the world's greatest fisherman
all on his own fortunately i'm not too
interested in those trades so
honestly i don't really care if he
doesn't want to come back to the village
but
he has a way now i gave him away
uh so i've i've spent a little time at
our village
since last episode and we got a bunch of
baby villagers in that time
about oh we got another one too
awesome uh i think we got maybe
four or five new guys
uh maybe maybe that's a stretch maybe
three or so but we did get a cleric
that i was hoping to get and i locked
him up right away
he had sort of a bad childhood in this
cage
he grew up into the glass block and he's
been here ever since
um but he's been safe this way
so let us i think let's do a little bit
of trading with these new guys and just
see what we get
uh he does want 36 which i think
might be a little expensive or like
a little more than some of the guys it's
really annoying when it's over 32
because you can only do one trade per
uh per stack
you have to keep clicking okay that's
done so we got seven out of that
so then the second trade that he started
with unlocked is the gold
which we can get gold pretty easy from
our gold farm but i don't really want to
trade that
all that much
oh yeah he's got the stars oh and that
unlocked two new ones so we got emeralds
for redstone four redstone
okay and lapis you can get lapis now
that's kind of interesting you weren't
able to before
i'm really wondering if they like some
of the trades that were possible before
aren't
anymore with these new guys um
and i think this is going to be the
final trade it looks like we got two
glowstone
for the final trade um
here let's do this one again
as much as we can here
this guy's going to be awesome to have
around the gold farm though because i
get so much of this rotten flesh that i
i've pretty much just been throwing over
the side of
the gold farm because i had like two
double chests full of it already
in no time
all right so i guess we'll do a
glowstone trade see if that unlocks
anything new
but by doing this it'll refresh the
rotten flesh trade i think
even though we didn't quite use it up
over there all right
i think that's the last trade
that's cool nice way of getting
glowstone
um who else do we have around here i saw
the armors were offering a few things
see that's an old cleric
could do a leather worker i'm kind of
curious just to see what we get
even though it's a terrible terrible
deal
thorns one protection two okay that
might be the end of the line for you my
friend
uh armor
yeah i wanted to try this one i just
want to see what he unlocks
hopefully gets us something good okay we
got two new ones
iron for emeralds no uh that's not
happening
13 for iron chest piece that's pretty
bad
that guy's stuck
that might be it that's all the emeralds
i have actually so we probably can't do
much more trading here
uh but i did a little bit of uh
changing around here i added in this
little thing try it out
and it's pretty cool the villagers will
actually
like they tend to go around over this
way and then when they come back they'll
go down this ladder which looks pretty
cool
and it got me thinking it would be
really neat if we could somehow trick
them to
like fall 10 blocks somewhere onto
slime block trampoline somehow
i'm not really sure where to put it
if we do that oh we got a baby
baby a librarian awesome we might
actually get a decent trade out of this
guy
because the other one really wasn't good
with the being of arthropods five
uh maybe maybe give me a minute here i
want to see that guy grow up
and i might try to set up this
trampoline thing
aha so he finally grew up guys this is
the trades he has he's got the paper
trade
35 same as other one exact same actually
uh and he's got a book trade it
is flame one darn it
that was flame two that would be good
but i do want to see what he gets next
so we're gonna do some trading with him
regardless try to build up our emerald
supply again
do this as much as we can
and that that looks like the end okay
so we got seven we need i need five more
to get to the next stage so i got
also some oops i also got some oh
what's going on here we gonna get
another one
no it doesn't look like it
okay so we got
some more zombie flesh and we can get
i think enough to do it now yeah
very good let's head on back
so i think librarians are the ones you
can get the name tags from so i
really really would like that trade
here goes flame one
it looked like they unlocked a new one
okay we got
books oh that guy sounds like he's
pretty close
where's that zombie it must be
behind the wall
oh good it didn't end there i was like
man i don't really want to buy a compass
okay so that did do nine books for an
emerald 12
12 emeralds for a compass thankfully
that's not the last one we got four
for a bookshelf that's pretty bad as
well written books
two for one clock
wow that unlocked a lot of trades there
11 for a clock
and then one for glass let's see if we
can get past
that if there's one more trade past that
uh
who can we
there's this guy okay this is the other
librarian
we will get a couple more emeralds from
him
all right let's head on back oh oh he
took the ladder and we missed it
darn it i got in his way okay let's do
it
hopefully hopefully there's a little
more
to this guy yet if we get the name tags
that would be awesome
oh awesome we got another enchanted book
for six so this is probably something
pretty
pretty bad a fortune one
you'd have to combine four of those
two two yeah
i think you need four of them to make a
fortune three
sounds about right check this out
that's what it looks like when they go
down the ladder it looks so cool i love
it
uh i think they just had another baby up
here
ah we got another little uh armorer guy
or weaponsmith whatever it is
uh i had to be careful though i like
they need this block in front otherwise
they
they'll just run off this and take fall
damage even though it's three blocks
some for some reason they were taking
fall damage
on this drop which is pretty weird um
okay so i did some more trading we're up
to 27 emeralds
that we can waste wasting fun here
uh to see what they unlock uh just
trading like
the paper trade and the rotten flesh
trade it seems to unlock
new trades uh because i didn't do this
fortune one trade and we got one past it
now
which is pretty cool uh
where's the other librarian where'd he
go
is that him there he is okay
so this guy i saw he's he's unlocked a
few new ones too just by doing the paper
trades
so let's let's see what we got passed
here
and hope i'm really hoping to get some
good book trades too
like for enchanted books i would love to
get efficiency
or something like that okay so only
three glass that's not nearly
as good as you you were offering five
oh okay here we go punch one darn
that's not that great i not have enough
for this oh i do okay let's do this one
i don't really want to but i just want
to see what comes
past it because i think he's getting
close to giving us a name tag
because we've done a lot of trading with
this guy there it is we got it
awesome so name tag for 21 emeralds
that's not
too bad uh they are pretty expensive but
it's it's a rare kind of cool item so i
think it should be pretty pricey
uh-huh so that's awesome we got our our
name tag guy over here
and yeah
i tried the trampoline thing a little
bit it's
here maybe we'll do this i don't know if
it's going to work
it's not going to look good if if it
does work as a problem
because we would have to have something
like this uh let's just try to take out
that fence over here
and then we gotta try to make them walk
off and then they'll bounce
which would look really cool if we can
make it happen uh
so we get a trap door to trick them into
walking off
but the thing is we then need like
something for them to try to walk to
over there because they're not gonna try
walk down here they'll
they'll take the stairs always unless we
try
to get them to walk to something over
here which
would require we have like a platform in
the sky
if we built it here i can't really find
a good place to put is the problem
but if we did something like this they
might choose to walk
off there
we'll see i'm going to watch it for a
bit and just see if they'll if they'll
try to walk to there and then fall down
oh here he goes here goes
okay so it does work it definitely works
um
it's uh it's not the best spot for it
though i think we need to find a better
place so that
we can hide the platform a little better
um
there is this big drop over here so if
we expand the village a little more
we can get them to fall like from up
there down to there
that would probably look a lot cooler
because this is a pretty small drop
but keep that in mind when we expand
this village further
anyway oh i think
uh i think let's go do something else
we've been here for quite a while
already today
so i'll see you at something else
whatever it is i'll figure it out
okay so i team up with an idea of
something i want to work on today
uh but first we need to collect a few
things such as
red wool i need a lot of red wool i got
a bin already
um i do have that other sheep farm the
rainbow one which i do use but when i
need a lot of one type of wool color i
usually come here because it's
a lot quicker because the other one you
just get a little bit of everything
this one you get a lot of one thing so
this is this is the place to be uh then
after we get our red wool here we're
gonna get some
bookshelves from the strongholds base
here and as you can probably guess
already we're gonna be using these to
work on the
library aha so we're gonna try to get
some stuff done here we're gonna work on
it and i'm not just saying it i'm not
just teasing you guys we're gonna
work on the interior today i hope and
lately with the changes to enchanting in
the game i've been getting a lot of
enchanted books
and i needed a place to stash them
it's gotten to that point so that was
the point of the library one of the
points
a place to put our books so i think
i think we need to get this building
rolling i've been avoiding this build
a little bit even though it's like one
of the most requested things i work on
for some reason
you guys really want to see the library
done i don't know
why you like it so much uh
the thing is when i started this build i
didn't have a plan for it really i just
worked on the front until
i liked it and i still do like it but if
i was to build this
again today i would probably do it a lot
differently
but we're gonna go we're gonna roll with
it and just see what happens i still
don't have
much of a plan but hopefully
it turns out nice and if it doesn't it
doesn't we will see
so okay
kind of my rough plan here i want
somewhat of a second story to the
building
oh that's a spider it's like what was
that
um how tall is this if this is ground
level this is one
two three four five blocks
i wonder if that's good i'm thinking
like we'll do
paths like this from underneath
like i want like uh
paths running along the top here with
railing that you can look over
down to the second or to the bottom
floor here um
so i want this to be spruce on the sides
with a fence above
red carpet just for some color and then
probably
i don't really want to see the red from
below here though so i'll probably put
some slabs
under that and probably another
like stairs or something here
i don't know some more detail oh it's
getting dark out
let's go sleep for a second um
yes the library hopefully it turns out
uh this project man
i'm scared of it okay here we go let's
go back
and honestly i have no plan here really
what oh piston didn't retract
okay so if if we do that it'll look like
this kind of from up here is this going
to be okay is that too much red maybe
[Music]
might be a little too much red we could
also use the dark wood
instead of the spruce that might be
better
let's see let's try this out
i think i like that more i don't know
about you guys i wish there was darker
fences in the game too
um yay
do the dark wood so i think
let's see it the building seems like
it's going to be wider than it is long
i kind of want like a centerpiece thing
up here like
maybe a tree with a skylight above and
then the pathway will go around it
um yeah
and then i think i want like bookshelves
all along the walls
with a railing that you can look down to
maybe maybe give me a moment here
to work on this figure out a look i like
with it
all right everyone so i oh
i was standing on leaves uh that are
despawning
i ran out of wood very quickly here i
had to get some trees going
uh so we got spruce wood for these posts
and we have spruce wood slabs underneath
uh dark oak wood stairs there and then
the fences
and i think that'll do i think that's
okay
i don't know if i want to keep doing
this like every three blocks it might be
too many posts if maybe we should space
them out some more
but uh i'm thinking
how are you gonna do the lower area here
a little bit oh you know what i put all
my stuff away let's go get it real quick
really quick here uh we're going to get
some
some more of that red wool i like the
red wall but i
i don't want to overuse it too i got to
be careful about that
now we're going to get some bookshelves
let's grab
some of these some of these
and see maybe some more books
fences that's what i want
yeah what am i forgetting
i don't want to have to come back i
think i think i got everything i need
okay let's go
so down below here this is what it looks
like up here by the way so i want to
want these posts going up and there'll
be some fancy roof
or ceiling work hopefully like some
arches and stuff
um we'll have lighting lighting on these
posts as well
to keep the walkway lit then down here
the lower level i was thinking it would
be cool if we did like
had like bookcase coves sort of
so let's pretend the walkway
will not pretend let's actually make the
walkway here
something like this down below
get the red
red i might not put the tree or the
center piece in here like i talked about
i think i
instead we should have like something
kind of central over here because it
wraps around like this and i don't want
the building to be
too big like if we put something really
big over here
the building has to come all the way
over to here but if we just
do it over there we can kind of put the
back wall around here
which will make it a lot smaller and
have like another centerpiece thing on
this side too
all right let's go back here uh so i was
using the dark oak right
i think so dark oak to line the walkway
like so and then in here
this is probably where i'm going to hide
some chests to store the books by the
way
anywhere i have these bookshelves
make these go up oh man
my mouse battery keeps dying i don't
know why it's i don't know if it's dying
or if the connection is bad but i'm
having a lot of trouble with it
um it might be my new computer not
recognizing it as well
okay because i do use wireless a
wireless mouse i don't like wireless
keyboards too much they
they just aren't responsive enough i
find but i really like wireless mice
okay so i think this will look okay
something like that walk in probably
change the floor out with some kind of
wood here too maybe
i don't know if i want to make it dark
we might try a lighter color of wood for
the floor
um i don't want to have the carpet going
everywhere either like the red carpet so
i don't think we'll put that in here
um yeah
so do that and should we put
more books like over here there's that
too many books
oops
it is a library so we need lots of books
around
could be cool i guess
all right um what else should i do here
maybe maybe give me a moment to do a few
things and and get rolling on something
else here
uh yeah look at that i think it's coming
together pretty good here i'm liking it
so far
um so i did some more stuff with this we
got
downward stairs and then upward stairs
meeting together
and then i just put a line of spruce
wood here give your eyes something to
focus on i guess
and kind of worked on this i'm not
too too settled on this floor yet but
it's something i tried this is the dark
oak wood
and then the spruce wood i like how
they're different colors now the
the logs instead of all being the same
got a light up here which i think will
be okay
and sign at the front so we could
put whatever we want on that so if we
wanted to put the protection books in
here for example
oh no is it getting late i wanted to
show the upstairs before it got light
okay it's a little bit light outside but
i i have these uh glowstone lights up
here
kind of like i did on the bridge on in
uh
minecraft by ethel corp i really like
that for some reason
this trapdoor thing with the spruce wood
uh but it lights it up pretty good up
here mobs won't spawn
and while being up here i kind of
noticed this
sort of lines up with the this window
over here so
i might make the path start going this
way
and maybe put the fence like have the
fence end over here instead
of going further because if this goes
out
here let's go let's go check this out
that's three
posts one two three post
one two okay so it doesn't quite meet up
perfectly
um have it come here then we'll go
here with the red wool and that
should we cut all the way across i think
we should yeah
cut all the way across
and then we're gonna have a whole line
of books up
along this wall i think with uh the
rails
uh should look pretty cool
and then maybe we'll make it meet back
over here make it do like a
full circle full square around
and then the center piece
yeah that would that could be good might
need to make it the path go
that way a little bit and then come
together yeah
uh can you visualize what i'm talking
about because i
i feel like i i left you in the dust
there i'm sorry
i start talking about things in my head
and i can't quite convey the image to
you sometimes
so i did a few more things here uh i
changed out the wool
floor and put carpet instead this way i
can hide the lighting
underneath here i got that in a few
places i think every
third or fourth block currently might
add more
uh i don't i don't really want to use
torches if i can
get away with not using them and that's
a that's a good way to hide lighting
under carpet
this i added one more of these coves and
it might be a little too much if we add
a third one over there instead i think
what we'll do
we'll take this section move that over
to here
this will be bookcases then cove here
bookcase cove bookcase so there'll only
be two codes total
instead of three like i have going
like if we this is the middle right here
so if we did that it would
go over there too um
that'll make that a little simpler and i
tried making this go
this way and it's just not enough space
like
this is from this path to there is too
close together
you wouldn't really be able to see much
up there because you pretty much have to
look straight up and then
the angle is just wrong so instead of
making it come
out this way we will just have the path
end at the wall there i think
let's go back up
yeah so let's let's get rid of this and
then we'll have book
bookcases over here on the side i
changed out the
the oak wood with this window to the
dark wood
it looks pretty nice and
it's coming along it's a big project
but we will soon have a place to store
our books so it makes it all worth it
oh man
that's the great thing about minecraft
though you know you you spend all this
time
on a building that does almost nothing
and it's just a cool little thing to
have around
all right
take this out
yeah i think this will work out better
because you have a pretty nice view
of of this walkway from down there
and then it'll be more open feeling too
over here instead of all
claustrophobic and paths all over the
place
it'll be a little bit less this way
all right and i'm not sure what to do
about the wall on the inside just yet
here let's go look at that may also add
a staircase to go down there
like from here down to here oops
skeleton
yeah like that's a pretty good view from
from over here to look up at that
uh i almost wish i made this all one
block lower but i think i think it'll be
okay
it gives it more of an epic feel when
it's taller like this
yeah anyway i think that's about it for
the library today
it's nice to actually get something done
on it um
maybe we'll go go do the commenting now
here we go everyone i picked out a
comment for our episode today and it
says
etho if you could make one working thing
from your first lp world
what would it be keep on making great
videos
well i'll try there's no promises there
but i'll do my best
uh this is a good question i like this
one actually
i think you know i
i really like water ladders but i don't
think i had those in my lp world i think
those
were removed before i started that world
i had them in the one before it
well the two worlds before it um
you know what i kind of miss well boat
elevators i think
boat elevators did work in my old lp
world i missed those
like the the super fast ones
um and
passive mob farms you remember how you
could have like
passive mob spawning pads and all that
kind of stuff they'd spawn on grass and
then you'd funnel them down
i remember i just finished my passive
mob
spawning pads and sorting system right
before the adventure update came out
and that broke everything uh
i was so sad uh but you know it worked
out all
pretty good and i'm pretty happy with
the way breeding and that works in the
game and how
farm animals worked in the game now but
passive mob farms are pretty cool too so
i think that's what i'm gonna go with
yeah yeah i think that's a good one
all right guys i hope you enjoyed
today's episode i'm gonna try to get
into
uploading more frequently i've been sort
of taking it easy lately and i gotta get
more discipline so hopefully
i can get more episodes out to you and
maybe some other series soon
and hopefully see you again soon
if that all works out uh i i'm pretty
free this week so i think i should be
able to record more
alright so until next time hope you
enjoyed today's episode and i will see
you
again then yeah
bye
[Music]
you