hey hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode of our let's play series guys to
start off with today I got another
redstone riddle for you you remember
that one we did a couple episodes ago a
lot of you seem to like that well I got
another tricky thing for you to figure
out we're going to do this one quickly
though I'm going to give you the answer
right away instead of waiting an episode
so a lot of you probably know there is
such a thing as locking repeaters in the
game so now if I try to give power to
this repeater it doesn't accept it
because it's locked up if you have the
repeater on the side it locks its rights
and if we unlock it allows the power to
go through then we can lock it if we
remove the redstone signal it stays
powered because it's locked on power if
we remove it it loses it and so on and
so forth okay so here's the question for
you guys how well do you know your
redstone without checking if we power
this redstone dust is it going to lock
the repeater do you know also the other
thing we're going to check is if we use
a comparator does that lock the power do
you know what are your answers I'll give
you a couple seconds to think about it
okay here we go
and so this should be locked right now
right it's not okay so redstone dust
does not lock it what about the
comparator this one's a little bit more
tricky ah didn't logits or did it haha
so comparatives actually do lock a
repeater but it doesn't draw the graphic
like it doesn't show that it's locks
even though it should that might be a
bug I don't know but yeah you can
actually lock a repeater with a
comparator so a to begin with here today
guys we're going to work on the Nexus a
little bit we're going to do a few
things on it you guys have been
wondering Etha
why are you not using the nexxus you
spent so long building this thing and
now you never you never use it well item
elevators broke great and I haven't
gotten around to fixing those on the
Nexus yet I don't know what design to
use even I was just goofing around with
it here it's kind of tricky to make the
item elevators now I got to say I tried
doing a search on YouTube see if I could
copy someones design but everybody is
showing the old method still I even the
recent tutorials so I don't know this
might be something that works so at
today's a very weird episode for me by
the way uh you might also feel weird
right now I don't know if you've noticed
I sound different today I'm using a new
microphone for the first time in like
five years of doing YouTube so it's a
bit of an adventure for me today
different audio setup ah yeah basically
I've used the Logitech G 330 headset
forever here I've had two pairs and well
they've both broken broken in half the
padding on the speakers is falling off
the mute button doesn't work the the
glue is leaking out of the the seams and
oh they're just a nightmare but I've
continued using them because I can't
find a microphone that sounds anywhere
near as good as them for some reason
it's a cheap like 50 $80 headset is a
sad thing and like these expensive
headsets and expensive Microsoft tried
have and haven't come close to comparing
I don't think this is going to work
yeah it's bunching up okay I bet hmm
maybe we get rid of this piston at the
start here instead like every time it
goes over the pressure plate let's make
a clock that runs that that makes this
happen and every time it goes over the
pressure plate it refreshes that clock
maybe because if we stop the items it's
gonna cause trouble I think oh and there
goes the redstone yes I don't know if
this sounds as good I downloaded an
equaliser I've been setting it up for a
few hours here I got an equaliser but I
wasn't really able to change things much
yet so I might be able to improve the
sound to me it doesn't sound like my
voice is as full compared to what we had
before but maybe maybe I can I can get
it sounding better but I'll see what you
guys say about it maybe it's just my
opinion and you guys are hearing
something else that sounds better to you
but I can't continue using those old
headsets even though they sound better
microphone still works perfect on them
but the headsets because the frame is
broken all the weight is on my ears and
since I wear them day in and day out
it's gotten to the point where my ears
feel bruised all the time because all
the weights on the ears for hours and it
really hurts to wear them I can't stand
it anymore I have to get a replacement
here so I figured out how to get my 80
20:35 worked and finally I was having
trouble with it not producing enough
volume but I guess I had the wrong
cables or plugged into the wrong spot
anyways I'm going to try work off-camera
a little bit on this elevator and see
then figure it out alright so well let's
try this out now I got like a little
prototype set up just like a hopper
timer and that's pretty much all there
is to it ah I don't know how stable it
is though is the problem so we're going
to put 50 for dirt in here yeah ideally
we want 54 in that hopper up there when
this is done so let's get this going and
that doesn't work wait a second and
break in replace nope
there we go okay oh no nope nope nope no
good we have one piece that shot out
already oh that's a lot of mobs that is
a lot of mobs I was wondering where all
that noise is coming from ha I guess
there's a water pool over here don't you
blow up I was a mile away
oh come on so here's the deal I've been
fiddling around with this item elevator
right I get it to the point where it
seems reliable and working and then it
just stops working when I start
recording or like I had a bunch of mobs
here in this jave and then it wasn't
working properly because like this I
think the skeleton AI is laggy in the
newer versions of Minecraft and if
there's any skeletons nearby the
redstone just slows down quite a bit and
starts behaving a little bit weird and
that was making the elevator not work
properly ah so I think what we're gonna
do we're just going to do a dropper item
elevator because I want something 100
percent reliable and I think this will
last the longest like if they update the
game I don't think this will ever break
I hope it should be because it's like
the official way of doing item elevators
kind of in a way there isn't there's no
actually official way but I think this
is the most long long term method we
have available so basically all we're
going to do is a big chain of droppers
facing upwards here we have two item
elevators to replace at the Nexus 4
things that need to go a greater
distance like vertically I might try to
that other method but for a short
distance like this I don't mind using
droppers yes all I had to do here is put
a bunch of redstone torches on the
outside of the droppers and as they
alternates the items go up up the the
chain here pretty simple at the bottom
though we need to detect if there's any
items entering the droppers and then
cause this to run on a clock sort of
thing but we don't know where the bottom
of the chain is right now
I just remembered we're gonna move this
item stream lower let me show you what I
did here earlier by the way I installed
four buttons here these are item call
buttons so instead of just using this
lever we can now like press this one to
get like half a stack this one's for one
stack two stacks or three stacks of
items that way we don't have to like
time oh I want I want items I think
that's about 32 items worth and then
unfledged áown here each one of these is
pretty easy to configure depending on
how many items are inside is how many
items it's gonna request so if there's
48 I have no idea it's about 4 4 items
per one item in the hopper here so 32
items is 126 items so just about 2
stacks it's not perfect here I'll show
you show you this working - so requests
1 stack this light turns on as it's
running and if we go to the back here Oh
see that flashing over there
every time that flash is it it gets one
item out of the Nexus so pretty cool we
were going to move the dropper lower
down here though because it was really
loud and annoying like it was at this
level before and now we have all this
stuff all this redstone here - so we
don't actually have space to shoot the
items into that that water stream we got
over there so we're going to use hoppers
to go a little bit lower down
what is this for oh this is to get the
items up here yeah this is the other
item elevator we have to replace oh we
we actually requesting something there
we got some spruce saplings apparently
okay so this is a little bit messy but
it should do the trick
so if there's items in here yeah you
notice that a little slow down in the
redstone that means is there's like a
scale to nearby or something it's pretty
nasty must be nighttime yeah yeah it's
nighttime
called it's alright can we can we hear
that now it's completely silent when
we're here that's what we want we go a
little bit this way though we can hear
it that noise was really bugging me
though because like whenever we would
drop off items that you would hear that
clicking sound but now now since it's
farther away I just did like a huge
hopper chain here to get that distance
so now this is going to be the new item
stream instead of up here so you see how
all the mobs are like stuttering along
like this it's got to be the latest AI
changes right I want to sleep to get rid
of all the mobs but I don't know if I
can safely here let's try now I think as
soon as they start burning up then
everything's gonna speed up again oh
please let me sleep I hear a spider
coming there's a zombie slowly getting
closer they're getting closer no yes I
slept oh that was the longest sleep ever
okay so I think we got this item stream
working again and the item elevator and
all that stuff so let's try it out now
will drop off 64 stone into the Nexus
that's gonna flow down all these hoppers
and go down this chain get your goes
so as soon as they enter this dropper
auto-detects it makes this clock run
they get shot out I'm picking up the
items so they go down the stream into
this hopper puts them into this big
dropper elevator thing item elevator we
did so this is filling up oh yeah I'm
missing a repeater here still check this
out by the way somebody told me you can
pick block in survival so if you middle
click on a repeater because I had in my
inventory it selected it's automatically
just so cool like I knew you could do it
and creative but I never knew you could
do it in survival or or when they they
made that possible so I've been using it
all the time now okay so now this should
start making items shoot outs and go up
the elevator and once this is empty
it'll stop let's go check this out I
think I got to put a glass block up here
yet - I forgot all right yeah here going
items are going into the Nexus good
yeah we need a glass block here because
sometimes they might shoot over the edge
otherwise I'll put one here just for
safety okay so they're getting aligned
properly I believe yeah it looks good so
I think that's working and now it's it's
quiet over there too which is cool okay
very good so I just installed this other
elevator as well this is the one that
actually delivers the items to us from
the Nexus so so how do the esses pick up
on this microphone I I'm wondering right
now that was probably that maybe it
wasn't too high pitched hopefully not
alright so let's see I did this one a
little bit different than the other one
this one we need to be very fast and we
want to make sure no items get left
behind inside these droppers so I think
it's going to be okay let's
throw in half a stack of dirt so it goes
into the topper here and when there's
items in this dropper it makes this
comparator turn on and then this clock
runs activates this comparator clock
which ticks very quickly like one one
tick on one tick off goes up the
staircase here to all the droppers and
let's just double check nothing got left
in these wrappers so we don't want any
let items left behind if we request an
item we want them all to arrive and to
arrive very quickly yeah that looks good
I don't see any there so all the items
end up in this dropper over here yeah we
got 32 good so I think everything is
pretty much where it needs to be right
now let's let's actually give this a try
make sure the Nexus still works here as
it is let's let's see if there's any
gravel in there so we want an f7
that is if for some reason this is
reversed I believe I thought we fixed
that and now it's like wrong again I
don't know why I spent a long time
switching these displays and now they're
they're incorrect all right let's try
get half a stack of it I think that's
actually 30 items we're looking to get
inside this dropper if there is 30
gravel in the Nexus I believe there
should be let's drop off some junk here
while we wait is there a thing for
buttons we'll find out all right
22 23 29 we're one short
I believe did it get left behind
somewhere
or it could just be that the timings not
what I thought it was supposed to be
maybe it is only twenty nine items yeah
I don't see it anywhere there okay the
other question I have are is our items
getting stuck in this hopper for a long
time see the beauty of those other item
elevators is they're quick as well this
one you got to handle the items kind of
one by one which is pretty slow let's
try to do that again but let's go down
here and just monitor what happens to to
this dropper here so we should get some
more gravel hopefully coming down the
stream here and here it comes
is it getting backed up pretty bad a
little bit yeah that kind of sucks see
the old item elevators those would all
get delivered instantly pretty much
which is a nice benefit of them but I
guess I just will try this out for a
while and if it's a problem I might
change it if it's only going to be a
problem if we're like getting over a
stack of items really otherwise it's
only like a couple seconds we have to
wait extra alright guys so let's do a
little bit of building today as well
change things up here so this part of
the man cave has looked pretty bad for a
long long time like all this area here
it's pretty nice go down here I'm happy
with this area I would call is done even
but like over here that hasn't gotten
the same tender loving care as we've
given other areas so maybe let's clean
it up a little bit to begin with let's
just do a border we're going to mirror
what we have on the other side I get the
slime farm there so just change this all
out now we could put like a glass window
thing if we want to keep it exactly the
same so this should all be glass so one
issue is I think we have the slime
minecart
behind here yeah so this is supposed to
carry big slimes underneath the tree
farm area but we've we've tried fixing
this many times and it keeps breaking
maybe we'll try one more time and hope
for the best I think mine card stuff has
gotten a little bit better since I last
attempted to fix that yeah let's make
this all a window or plan to anyway if
we manage to fix it and we'll just do
what we did on the other side kind of
like us oh and I would really like to
move this track like one more block this
way though so that we could like have a
wall here well let's plan to do that we
might have to change some things around
then over here nothing too crazy I guess
we did use stone here so maybe we should
use stone here as well just to try clean
it up a little bit we can add some more
details after we do this do you want to
go all the way did you do all right
that's the flower farm back there yeah
let's get some more this is how I used
to build guys just like big walls all
one type of block um yeah we could add
some more details to it though I feel
like we should okay so here's the setup
with the slime thing basically he's
jumping on a pressure plate right now
which is supposed to release a minecart
that picks them up in the corner but
nothing is happening let's take a look
what's what's going on here why isn't it
working
ah let's try how's this work exactly I
think this would release a minecart
something like that so went into the
corner and didn't pick up a slime at all
maybe we will attempt to do that a
couple more times here just to see if
it's possible and
or it kind of looks like it's not
doesn't seem like you can pick up the
slime through the corner anymore okay so
I was just looking at this I think we
could get it to work again but like this
PEZ dispenser I'm pretty sure doesn't
work anymore
most of this redstone is unnecessary we
could really clean things up here and
simplify it because all of this was
basically to make a whatchamacallit
dispenser full of minecarts like it's
such a simple thing now it's insane all
right and then do something like that so
if we put some pressure plates some
stone pressure plates over here and here
when the big slime falls down he should
activate the dispenser chute out of
minecarts and we need a full block I
believe for him to actually fit through
this gap otherwise like if we do the
cheesy method of this I think that'll
work for the minecart but I don't think
it'll actually allow a mob to fit
through oh it's not letting the cart go
through either okay yeah so I think we
need to open this up all right and is
the minecart bouncing off this wall no
it's not we might want to put a solid
block here too just so it'll move okay
and let's see let's go down here so this
will go to where we can get rid of like
everything here where's our target I
guess I should figure out because
there's that drop area yeah right here
is where it used to drop and where is
this track over here okay so we could we
want to put like the track over here
maybe that would look pretty good if
we're trying to make it as a display
thing
break these blocks good there's a button
there I don't know what that's for it's
gone destroy it all I say okay so if we
have a wall here the slime should hit
the wall and fall straight down and
start going that way is the the hope oh
oh oh we're missing it go go go go it
didn't work
oh that did work okay why didn't work
the first time okay I just saw him go
down yeah he's going he's going he's
doing the thing alright so that works
that part of it now the only thing I'm
not sure about when it these spawns what
happens to the minecarts see when we did
this track originally we just like space
the booster rails every so often I think
we might want to change out this track
oh he shrunk somehow on the way oh no we
got two of them going okay that makes
more sense yeah we didn't we didn't do
the solid booster rails we might want to
change it so that the the carts never
stop aha but there's like a cart empty
cart detector here which probably
doesn't work anymore and then they go
back up here and nothing
we need like I tacked this cart breaker
over there and I've set up some hoppers
to put them back in that dispenser let's
let's try this out do we have any empty
carts no we don't
can we get any empty carts let's try
steal one from one of these guys alright
here comes a guy we are going to try rob
them all right give me your cart thank
you oh hey
ah let's drop these they're actually not
able to get me when I'm next to them
like this oh here comes another one
oh you went up there well well
hey now yeah there's the detector rail
over there okay let's go back a little
bit and just see where the cart goes oh
I can't push it I really want to push it
you still have to break it and this okay
get up to speed get up to speed it's
going to turn
oh it did turn okay that's good so if
it's if it's got a mob in it just keeps
going because they they travel faster so
that looks like it's still working we
just need some way of breaking the
minecart and putting it back into the
hopper here but anyways guys I think
I'll take care of that another time
because it is time to wrap up the
episode for today so here's a comment I
picked out it says etho do you plan on
implementing the end rods I've seen
designs like end rod staircases and
other fancy things just wondering
because they seem like a cool addition
ah I think those ender or end rod
staircases don't work anymore last I
tried
I have tried using end rods a little bit
but I don't know like I'm starting to
not like these anymore and they don't
they don't really suit like a nature
themed area like we have down in the man
cave here um from my experience with
them so far but in more like clean clean
builds they would look good that
redstone leg like anything with the
hardened clay and stuff I think it would
look good with end rods this is this is
more a hidden lighting area mm-hmm
anyways hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode again let me know what you think
about the microphone if I need to make
some adjustments if you
know what equalizer settings I need to
change I would love you so much because
I have no idea I just have to goof
around with it try figure it out anyways
thanks for watching guys hope you
enjoyed it take care bye bye