oh boy okay here we go guys accidentally
triggered a raid on our underground
village here I'm not sure how this is
gonna play out I think they're safe Oh
[Music]
nighttime song I think they're safe
under here though all right I was just
doing some work in the world then I
forgot I had the potion effect or
whatever it is for a tree in the raid so
let's see if you're okay maybe we'll
check over here I think they're gonna
spawn above ground how did you get on
the other side did you climb up here and
jump over these villagers are getting
too smart guys yeah I guess let's check
above-ground I'm guessing that's where
they are
Oh creepers those spiders well I don't
see the Raiders so they must be
underground somewhere still can't see
him
Darren I thought that's gonna work ok
maybe we got to move around a little bit
and try find them it's like one of these
underwater pools with like bunch of
creepers in oh I heard a lot we're okay
oh there was just enough like of a
platform here to spawn mobs in and over
time I just filled up haha
all right we found them guys it took
quite a while I like I looked through
the caves for so long and it's like you
know they must spot on the surface right
even though it's an underground village
I think they still spot on the surface
so I checked the surface again and they
were like hiding in the corner here most
of them so they can't get to the village
which is like over here ish yeah right
over here is the village like underneath
and like they have no interest in me
which is also pretty interesting maybe
until I hit them then they might change
your mind
now it looks like they they're just so
focused on trying to get to the village
that they don't care about me this is my
favorite thing about updates though is
just trying to figure out the new game
mechanics so we have the next wave of
guys here they're kind of hanging around
up right above the village the center of
the village I'm kind of curious if we
send them through another portal does
that count is like removing them from
the wave like will the next place start
then or do we actually have to kill them
so we're gonna let them just like wander
through on their own that caused a lot
of leg do you see that oh just the first
one okay so there's looking for a place
to place the portal I guess but then
after that they should kind of just like
figure out how to get to the nether on
their own there it looks like the Raider
count is dropping it's only one left
I think we started a new raid wave here
yeah so that seems to work actually once
all the leaders went through the nether
portal the next wave started and in that
next wave we got a Ravager who is a
friendly because he can't find the
village so he's not trying to attack us
oh he's not friendly he's neutral right
so we're kind of like buddies you know
we respect each other we're not gonna
hurt each other um I was kind of curious
I don't think you can attach leads to
them because they are actually hostile
alright yeah
can we what happens if we equip our
shields and he's like not trying to
attack us will he still do the stun
thing I think he actually has to attack
for that to happen not just like walking
into him okay I think I can't ride them
unfortunately that would have been cool
let's see I want to try to get them in a
minecart too
just out of curiosity I think that to be
fun people just do a little loop alright
buddy oh yeah no problem there no
problem okay let's maybe just some of
these leaves I want to see if you can if
you'll still break the leaves when he's
in the minecart or if that's possible
that's above like that oh yeah you still
get some look at that
push uh-huh so you're gonna have some
fun with this guy ah well I guess we'll
go through the portal now we'll check
out the ones we sent through see if
they're still friendly to us or if
they've become hostile now that the the
villages I was sight
why do they hit me pretty hard there
oh yeah they are angry little guys okay
so yeah if they don't see the village
they will come after you for sure Oh aha
you can't walk on my heels oh you shot
each other
oh okay if he's on a rail he'll come
after you be cool guys we're cool
we're actually cool again what happened
there I mean I thought we were friends
and guys just turned on me like really
quickly all of them at once oh did we
lose anything to that cactus see shovel
we got shovel yeah I think we're fine
let's chill this chapters I don't trust
it you got regen for me thank you okay
let's let's take these guys out okay
cool that's another wave done I did
notice some guys up by the pyramid
they're kind of chilling outs let's go
see what's happening down here now so we
got five waves going on hmm it's a
little bit glitchy this might may be a
bit of an issue
oh no no no no oh I fell in the lava I
knew one day one day I would do that
Oh traveling merchants oh he's come
however did oh he's fine he's okay don't
worry guys oh this is just crazy yeah so
there's multiple waves going on at the
exact same time here we have Ilic errs
everywhere I saw some fell down the hole
over here so you're not limited to just
one wave so if you want to firm these
guys for emeralds or something you can
probably do it pretty quickly actually
if you have like several weights going
on at the same time I don't know I'm
gonna get rid of all these guys like
they do actually attack me every so
often plating this invoker's after me
yeah sending his little minions on me so
kind I just want to let loose a TNT in
the middle there about the boom kind of
missed the water actually had sex yeah
we got most of them at least that time
was fine
yes oh that doesn't even heal you what
what's the point it doesn't heal you
when you die oh all right so we have
some guys make it down to the village
actually and most most of our villagers
died not all of them there's still at
least like eight down here but it was a
pretty hard blow
oh yeah and just to clarify the illah
Jers didn't actually spawn underground
they fell down those holes and survived
the fall and then they proceeded to kill
like most of the villagers haha anyways
this is what I was working on before I
got distracted it's like an endless wave
of ill udders by the way like it's still
going on I just left like every time I
go check out the village another wave
starts it's like okay what do I do I
kill off the wave I get the bad omen
effect then I check out the village
again and it starts a new wave and I
don't know it's just like an endless
loop so yeah anyway so we're still in
the testing and setup setup stage for
this tree farm we're about to possibly
blow it up if I did something wrong here
we'll find out so I figured we would we
should start recording this oh I missed
one repeater here too okay let's go back
up I guess we'll just fly up but yeah
this this tree farm is going to be
pretty nice for us I think I'm gonna be
using it a lot because you can get
stacks and stacks of wood in seconds
with it which is really cool so what
we're doing we're gonna run redstone all
the way up from down below here you see
we got it
and the porches running up from
underground the way this works after we
row the trees go back up we have to
shear out the core of the leaves here so
we drop down here these out and as we
get down here once we fall through the
water we're gonna hit up pressure plates
which will automatically push us so that
we return to the surface but we also go
over another pressure plate which is
gonna activate the TNT to fall down here
there's a second part you play we just
hit so now it's sending a redstone
signal up there automatically triggers
yeah that's what I was afraid of I think
we just blew of our cheap herb
oh my goodness so the timing is wrong on
some of that I guess yeah okay oh not
just some a tree farm a lot of the tree
farm got blown up there uh-huh fun fun
well we got it all fixed up here again
it actually only took like five minutes
so it wasn't too bad so what happened
there is we're using these piston arms
to hold the TNT and then they retract
and let the TNT fall down after a
certain amount of time the perfect
amount of time right and what happened
is because we only sent the piston arms
here like a quick pulse it extended
again while the ones above we're still
retracting and they the TNT landed on
this lower one and like blew up to the
tree farm basically so what we did to
fix that is down below here I added in
just the hopper clock here so that the
Pistons will stay retracted until the
whole cycle finishes basically so it's
got a long delay on it yeah so we fall
down here we land on this pressure plate
which activates the piston pusher there
but it is this one here activates all
the Redstone so this is a signal that
goes up that big torch tower like the
torches are right above this block here
okay
on the other side here we also have
another branch off which were using for
something else basically after we hit
that pressure plates that other branch
off causes these to push up after a
certain amount I'm completely there they
go
so that I'll push this up here and
they'll give us a free space to plant
the next thing of trees all right so
we're gonna try to get in here everybody
it might blow up one more time we'll see
we'll see we got it now so again we fall
down here the leaves will land on that
pressure plate which will activate the
whole thing alright so this redstone
just all switched went up to the top and
now the TNT should be falling down
looking good looking good
did it blow up the clay up there now I
think we're good actually so that's all
fine and then we have all these hoppers
down here as our collection system so
they all kind of branch off to this
chest here and you see it's tilling up
with the spruce wood that fell down a
lot of the spruce woods gonna land up in
the middle here which is fine if we're
doing like multiple harvests cuz when we
plant the next set of trees and they
grow it's gonna push that those items
off into the hoppers I think we'll see
here ok we'll go for the next girl yeah
that's right it was like did it branch
off here no that wood that was there
already I got confused for a second so
you see they're like saplings and stuff
got pushed it off and then we go up for
the next round and we should be able to
grow like all the different types of
trees this way too like we if we put the
saplings in all the spaces I see we've
got some of the wood there I didn't
notice actually did this push at the
right time
let's look down here okay so we can even
shorten the Glee on that if you want
awesome alright so I'm pretty happy with
this tree farm as it is actually but
there is room for improvement obviously
it looks pretty nasty so we could we
could spice up this area a little bit
more would be nice I'm gonna put some
carpet over these hoppers probably to
hide them I just want you guys to be
able to see like what's going on you
know another idea that was suggested is
to set up a mattock bonemeal dispenser
for the growing the trees which is
something I did play around with a
little bit but decide not to do it for
two main reasons number one if we set up
like dispensers pointing towards these
trees it's gonna block some of the
collection hoppers like they'll take up
their space right so more and more stuff
will lands where we don't want it to oh
we lost the clay block somewhere not a
big deal it's it's fine guys it's fine
there is a thing called the Northwest
rule though with trees so if we're
facing north this way or west this way
and there is a block next to the tree on
either of those directions so either oh
let scrubs smooth stone maybe so if we
have a block north or west of the tree
this tree will never be able to grow no
matter how much bonemeal you give it it
just won't grow get rid of this one
still won't grow because we got a block
on the north side but if we get rid of
this one then it'll grow like within
five full meals probably yeah so just
the way this configuration is with our
trees it would have been impossible to
set up the dispensers where they
wouldn't be in the northwest region for
at least a few of the trees right so
that was another issue so I decided just
to skip it another thing we'll probably
want to do with this though is add a
filtering and storage system to it so
like instead of putting everything in
one chest we'll will separate the sticks
into their own logs saplings leaves all
into their own spot right so it'll be
nice and organized that way and we'll
probably want to do that for all six
types of trees because I think we can
grow all six here but I'm gonna spear
with that now so we'll do jungle bleep
trees next year I think if we do other
trees so we might not get enough
saplings back so it might not be
sustainable but if we have like extras
at any point we could do this to quickly
grow them maybe but we'll see we'll see
how this goes so those should grow fine
yeah so one thing to keep in mind when
we're removing this core out of its
jungle trees you might get some branches
that that shoot off here but also looks
like we're gonna have some vines right I
don't think those will mess up the tea
and tea though right all right let's
check it out here wonderful people in
vines and we got to be able to get like
16 jungle saplings back otherwise it's
not sustainable so we got 14 jungle
saplings back we needed 16 so it's not
too bad it was pretty close and
obviously there's more leaves more
jungle leaves there we could get more
from but we'd have to climb up and
manually harvest them or wait for more
to de-spawn you know which we probably
won't do in regular use so we're gonna
come up deficits I think a lot of the
times also interesting about the jungle
trees we we have three logs here that's
normally never get left behind I think
the vines actually did interfere a
little bit I have the TNT exploded where
a vine was it's gonna dampen the
explosion a little bit and it didn't
have enough power to take out those
three logs I think is what happened so
that's kind of interesting as well
another tricky one will be the dark oak
I think these are destructive sometimes
unless they change that we'll see how
this goes though oh that's weird like
the jungle trees overwrote the spruce
wood but the dark oak didn't replace the
jungle wood well that time it did wonder
why I didn't with those and there's like
a hollow spot here
[Music]
okay one final thing we'll do here you
guys are probably getting a little bit
bored of this remark by now because
we've been here for so long I'm having
the time of my life with it though I
think this is awesome but yeah one idea
here why don't we just put a water
column in the middle right I believe
this is water counts as one of the
blocks that prevents trees from growing
so again that Northwest rule if we have
a spruce tree here for example this is
gonna be north of it that's water so it
won't be able to grow and likewise the
tree over here it'll be west of it so
that's that's a no-go either these two
trees here should be able to grow just
fine though with that column of water
there but we'll try it out because I
could be wrong about this and if I'm
wrong we can improve this farm even more
so let's try grow them it's not looking
good cuz yeah if we if we could stop the
leaves from growing in the middle that
would be great right
alright everybody well we are off
exploring here once again we're looking
for some of the new stuff that came out
in this updates mostly bamboo forests I
want to find a bamboo forest you
wouldn't mind seeing a panda or two and
like foofy died right we got to find a
new floofy those iron bars well that's
gonna be the blacksmith down there right
uh-huh
buy right into this village a desert
village I thought I'd show you guys kind
of cool up in the hills here these crazy
and new desert homes and heads in the
ceiling and all kinds of other crazy
stuff that's pretty nice actually got
like the main area here with the bell
and we even got some iron golems I saw
Kitty I believe one of those stray
kitties but I think you ran off the
cliff
so he's Gani he bailed
what's what's this oh there's another
home there oh that's the blacksmith
isn't it no it's not oh it's the
stonecutter
that's actually a building I don't think
I've seen before all right let's go
check out that blacksmith's we'll see if
there's any goodies there i raided a
desert temple and got like three sets a
golden horse armor which is really cool
that is something I actually don't have
a lot of yeah so we got a library over
there all right yeah lots of good stuff
in this village uh-huh Oh with a lectern
- that's cool
it's a nice man I love how they changed
the village houses there's so much
better now but anyways I'm off exploring
here I'm not really looking to settle
down although this would be a cool place
I gotta find me a jungle or something
does a sprawl off to the other side of
the hill here nice I think we saw most
the village yeah okay off we go oh oh
okay let's let's check out this
coordinates here yeah so I've been
looking for donkeys for so long in my
world like I we had to originally and
one of them died and I've never been
able to breed more since then so I'm
gonna be coming back for these guys for
sure that's a great find like every time
I go to my planes I always keep my eyes
out for them I've never been able to
find another another pair of them
there's some bones over here - this is
pretty cool - I like this oh snap you
know it goes like desert savanna desert
savanna desert savanna where are the
jungles guys I thought they were
supposed to spawn next to the desert
sands vent savannas as well I've
traveled thousands of blocks now I just
can't find a jungle anywhere uh-huh yeah
look at this place this is kind of weird
it's a savanna mountain village so
there's like snow everywhere even though
it's it's savanna pretty cool we're like
way at the top of the world here - I'm
hearing all kinds of mobs over here ah
that's why uh-huh we should you should
keep the eye on the spot I'll take the
horse armor of course named eggs are
always nice and Oh more horse armor
this is horse armor day what don't we
want we're gonna leave behind the arrows
for sure
okay so where's our location we'll check
that in case we ever want to come back
here I did notice like a lot of the
houses are on the way down from the
mountain as well still no luck with the
jungle by the way I've been looking and
I just can't find one I found a
megataiga I found like the polar ice
fields and like every other biome except
for jungle and Mesa Oh
oh yeah there's like a farm over there
random farm
everything down below here another farm
and any houses down here I think that's
about it I thought there was some like
part way up the mountain here too isn't
there
oh yeah there's a there's a few over
here this is a town center yeah this is
where the Bell is got a bunch of kiddies
some of these new straight cats oh snap
all right guys we finally got ourselves
our jungle here it's been hours like
legit hours looking for a jungle our
world was over a dig before I'm scared
to look what it is now because I'm sure
it's huge and we finally got one but I
actually kind of had the cheat to find
this thing I loaded up admidst there's a
new version for 114 I downloaded that's
pre-release which if you don't know it's
a third-party program for Minecraft that
lets you see the biomes in your world
based on your seed so I just looked at
that and found like a closed jungle
where at minus 3000 on the zed yeah it
turns out jungles are actually extremely
rare in my world here though like almost
as rare as mushroom islands so kind of
kind of decided after a few hours of
looking and I wasn't finding one that
maybe I should just kind of look at
admits cuz my world was getting huge and
yeah so this is this is one of the very
few and we almost didn't get it you can
see that is like some chunk boundaries
here so like half of the jungle got cut
off from earlier exploration and an
earlier version of Minecraft where this
wasn't jungle and now it is so we got
like half a jungle here one of the one
of the very few and we even found the
needle in the haystack here the one and
only bamboo shoot' apparently yeah we
got that that's what we came here
looking for now that we got that we can
plant some near near our base thankfully
I found a parrot here to it I was pretty
excited about it I can't get him to go
through another portal for
some reason I don't know why I'm gonna
leave you behind buddy you know I'd like
to bring you home
maybe I gotta go through first
a horrible spot let's look up in the air
let's go back maybe now we can come
through I'm not sure why I wasn't able
to get him before spot good all right
come on guy come on I got cookies they
don't like cookies anymore do they
I don't know you feed them now seeds why
won't you go through Hey all right we're
buddies down right you're gonna hop on
my shoulder yes
okay now will you come through the
portal with me please I just read it
barely do you feed him cookies now it
just kills them
well nobody's not with us well check it
out we managed to find two more parrots
actually these two white guys here and
I've just been flying them back manually
I don't know I can't get them through
the nether for some reason thankfully is
only like 3,000 blocks and they teleport
but you have to land like every hundred
bucks or so you travel otherwise it'll
get left behind all right and we're just
about back home
all right everybody well I think we're
gonna wrap up our episode here for today
but but we do have some some kind of
good news bad news the elder Guardian on
top the windmill he's gone I don't know
what happened to him but I think it was
after we updated he disappeared oh that
was a bad throw dragon oh I threw that
one too soon oh man oh I did it again I
went way over we'll get it
I'm a pro ender pearl thrower I'll get
enough yeah he was in a minecart on the
on top here I think that was in the
middle and now it's like he got moved
over and maybe he suffocated or
something but yeah it's gone so kind of
good news bad news it was cool having
him here but he was also kind of
annoying because I couldn't build in the
area in nearby him cuz he would he would
debuff us you know so I don't know we're
not gonna replace him for sure but yeah
let's get to the comment of the day for
today it says hey etho what's your
storage situation like with regards to
how large your video files end up being
of course also do you have an archive of
every video you've ever created if so
how much space does that use kind of an
interesting question there so back in
the day I used to only upload I think in
480 or maybe it was even 360 and those
files are small most those episodes were
like 50 minutes or less too because that
was the old YouTube limits for like the
first hundred episodes of the LP series
or whatever so those are all like under
a gig like a lot of those are four
hundred to eight hundred Meg's but
nowadays most of my videos are
four gigs in size I used to have them
I just want to harvest here too I used
to have them all on a hard drive I was
trying to save every single file I
created like every every video there we
go oh yeah but I had a hard drive crash
a few years ago I had a three terabyte
Seagate's
which apparently is a very bad model
like just that specific one I have a 4
terabyte Seagate now and it's been
perfectly fine but yeah with that hard
drive that crash they gave me a warning
when I booted up my computer that day
and I didn't understand the warning so I
looked it up and it's like oh that means
your hard drives gonna crash so I was
like oh so I just like panic started
backing up everything on the hard drive
everything important you know I copied
my intros that I use them from my videos
all my video codec and filters and
whatever copied that over I had a bunch
of programming projects on that hard
drive from like back from when I was 8
years old
like I made a Frogger game and just just
lots of random stuff and I didn't want
to lose those and then I was just about
to start copying my episodes over like I
had every single episode saved from my
youtube and right when I started when I
looked in the folder it was empty
and then I tried looking another folder
and all the folders disappeared so I was
like just in that moment the hard drive
crashed and I got like most important
stuff but I lost all the episodes
basically so yeah it's just what's left
on YouTube now so if my channel
disappears I can tree up load them or
anything not that I would probably ever
want to because that would take forever
right yeah but anyway since that crash I
have I have kept my episodes again just
because you know I have the space it's
not a big deal but as far as the
question goes how much total space would
that use I just checked my social
beyblade and I have uploaded like 2200
videos now and if you low lowbal it
let's say they're two gigs each
average that's only four terabytes right
did I'm not that right I think so so
it's not that that big actually
like you could store it on to hard
drives easy uh-huh
that's compressed of course obviously
but anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
appreciate the comments as always and
until next time take care have a
wonderful day bye bye
[Music]