ah hello everybody this is Ethel and we
are doing just fine today look at that
guess what we are making some TNT ah ha
I love love my TNT and I finally have a
decent supply in my let's play world I'm
so excited I actually believe it or not
it makes me want to play more such a
stupid thing but some reason T&T really
makes me happy two stacks oh yeah
that's even after we used a ton on that
tunnel last time oh-kay sweet so yeah
the mob system is working very very good
again I've been lighting up more tunnels
its keeps getting better and better
um still room for improvement of course
averaging about thirty mobs up in it now
ideally one about eighty but what can
you do but yeah today is going to be
very exciting for me at least I am going
to be I think it's time I think I'm
going to install the latest snapshot and
check it out I've been very excited to
do it so whoo hold on I'm going to
installed it hold on to your horses hats
whatever yeah I'm gonna install it and
check it out to make a backup before I
do of course and we'll have some fun
with that I'm sure won't we yes we will
woah Wow here we go top left Minecraft
snapshot week 36 A's what we're going to
be using from now on and we or I am very
curious as to what
all entails the very first thing I want
to check out the thing that's been
plaguing me for so long
the tarred billowing man did they fix it
I have no idea
haven't used the snapshots yet today is
the first day dang it
ah the one thing I really really wanted
it's not fixed unbelievable ah that is
too bad I really hope they fix that
before the next official release
actually I hope they fix that today fix
that today okay what should we do next
there is so much to do I'm going to be
messing with this for a long time I
think I don't think I have any leather
here otherwise I'd make the item frames
that's another big thing I'm interested
in but you know what since we are here
let's just go over to the Enderman farm
and check that out oh yeah and you can
see remember I said an portals load
almost instantly now check it out that
is so fast compared to what it used to
be but nether portals are still slow so
we are at the end or ender now and one
thing I'm noticing also our level isn't
displayed right now so when we went
through the portal it got it disappeared
so when we get an XP we're going to go
up to like level 22 it will refresh the
rumor I've heard is that they might be
changing it so the amount of XP you get
from mobs is proportional to how much
damage you deliver and since I'm only
doing half a heart to these guys I might
get very little XP so we shelled check
that out let's see a quickly level
seems like it's same as it was before
that's good news for me
so I was worried this thing's gonna get
nerfed and it is I don't know if this is
quicker than the blaze farm or not the
blaze farm I think is more convenient
fortunately I think that is nerfed kind
of sex but we'll try that out today too
yeah so far this looks oh this looks
pretty good
I'm going to try out the farm a little
bit longer yet just to make sure we
might do one more pitch after this nice
very good yes I did another 30 levels
and there's no sign of slowdown so it's
just as good as it was before another
one Wow Oh what do I need all these pics
for well I'd go through them really fast
it seems always breaking them II well we
had three good ones we can't expect any
more than that really
next up just really quickly I want to
check out the blaze farm because just
and that's not working anymore like I
want it to so we'll just go see what the
dealio is with the XP decreasing with
mob spawn mobs spawn by mob spawners
yeah there she is lots of work went into
it it might be for nothing now well
we'll see nice number two okay
and we get ooh beautiful just wonderful
exactly what I wanted you all right well
I've been at the blaze firm for a while
here and I've killed roughly 600 of them
and I haven't seen any drop in XP yet so
I'm guessing that change never got in
this snapshot or I don't know what the
deal is I thought that was in the game
already but I haven't seen any
indication of it cause it's so hard to
get a looting sword no hmm you know what
I was pretty excited I thought the
wither skeleton and the the new wither
boss is going to be in the snapshot but
I don't see any those guys around here
maybe it's only in creative I thought it
was in vanilla though Oh check it out
it's enchanted Oh can I take them on I
don't know if I can why I could take him
on I don't know if I can take the rest
of the guys on there's a lot around here
all right we got to try it oh man
be kind wait I'm gonna get so killed
yep oh yeah go go go Wow
thought I had more help dang right in
the fire oh that's gonna be hard to get
back um all right I'll see you guys in a
bit yeah I really was not prepared for
that these guys you can't hit them
anymore not with melee or melee look at
them all just guarding my stuff I can't
hit them
oh this is where I died not today
got it oh and I don't think we lost
anything too big there which one of them
had the enchanted sword I don't see it
anymore okay so I did a little bit of
reading about it and it sounds like
these nether or wither skeletons only
spawn in fortresses and I hung around
two of the fortresses I found already
and I didn't see any so maybe we have to
generate a new fortress to get them so
that's what I'm doing I'm going up
exploring a little bit to try find a new
one somewhere I've never been before
although I don't see much glow stone
here I don't know what the deal is with
that I'm sure I haven't been here yet Oh
I'm excited to see them I don't know if
they shoot arrows or what the deal is I
haven't looked up too much information
about the latest snapshot but so far no
sign of a nether fortress well going
that one way I came to a lava lake I can
get by so I've come to this fortress
here it's huge
I've never been to it but it might have
been pre-generated completely I'm not
sure but I'm going to have a look around
there and see if we see any otherwise
any fire resistant potions and stuff to
go any further in the nether found a
blaze spawner sign of wither skeletons
yet I didn't see anything there either
so I'm going further if I can and I know
this is new stuff the lab is still
fallen but looks like we got we got
another lava lake so mmm don't know how
far we can get that thing's pretty epic
I like the lavas flowing all over it's
kind of round
and I think we're onto something here
the kuffara way we are to almost a
thousand blocks away from home don't see
the fortress this is the only thing I
found I just happened to stumble across
it the lab is still coming down no I
can't see it anywhere over there so
let's see if we can get into it from
here
it's totally underground or something
this one is definitely brand new brand
spankin new though netherwart has not
grown who's that
you see the nether brick light pulsing
that's weird
hmm so far not a single mob in sight
what is the deal they might not be in
the game yet I don't know I wouldn't
think they'd be this rare hmm nothing
there I'll keep looking I don't know all
right what is that what is that that's
just skeleton dang it mmm oh yeah I can
turn my particles up hi I thought I saw
one from a distance but then like
despawn so I'm going to have to just
keep looking
they seem pretty rare though Oh found
some three of them oh I thought I lost
all my hearts okay they don't have much
strength freaking blaze behind me man
naturally spawn please yeah they're slow
too
they're huge like they're really tall
yeah they probably do spawn at my other
fortresses I just had to really wait
around a long time because I I ran all
over this thing before I finally saw
that so they're pretty rare
okay I'm done in the nether today I
looked for a long time and I hardly
found any of them
I think only like five or so and I
walked thousands and thousands of blocks
but yeah this is the nether hub I have
done all four of these things and I got
them wired up and ready to go pretty
much so excited to get that going I just
thought I'd show it to you guys and I'm
doing sandstone for the walls got it
going all the way around I wanted to see
what it would look like and it I think
it's going to be pretty good when it's
all done so what else shall we do today
I think I'm going to work I'm going to
try out the item frames next see what
those are all about here we go I pretty
sure the recipe is much like a picture
frame I remember right I think I saw
someone make one before and but except
though instead of wool I think it's
leather in the middle yeah item frame
they're called okay so how do they work
let's see put one here there one by one
that's so cool now when you do it they
can get it back or not oh you can rotate
it okay that's weird
if you break it to get it back I think I
did 37 now 36 oh that's cool
that is very cool yeah I'm going to use
those in my storage room for sure for
sure for sure that is a really neat way
to show what's in a chest very visible
even from side angles yeah that's nice
the kulfi could have like different
colors for the background too so you
could group objects together like tools
could be one color and oh well that is
really neat um I was oh yeah I want to
try the clock make sure that actually
works
I wouldn't go for on with maps but I
don't have any at my place here but if
I'm starting to sound tired because I am
I should go to bed pretty quick here I'm
recording wait recording way later than
I should be and my I'm losing my words
yeah that is really neat I'm going to
put a few of those around my place too
this is really I can't really tell what
time it is when I'm down here which is
one of the cool things about this tape
like you can be raining it can be
nighttime I don't have to worry doesn't
affect me when I'm in here all the time
is daytime to me now in this cave is one
of the reasons why I like living
underground in this game because when I
recorded before like in my old LP oh
that was a nightmare especially before
we had beds I would have to always just
way
get out the night so I could record when
there's actually some light in the game
and I just sometimes I just sit around
for 10 minutes okay what else what else
what else
I know village or trading has changed oh
yeah I want to try some some leather
armor I saw that today in map I was
testing and it looked really cool
especially then chanted stuff what no
just big X's no no more you've done
enough
wonder it's weird that it would do that
for the last one so you really not want
any more paper it's good stuff now he's
done with paper man I think you have to
trade do I have any emeralds around here
I think you have to trade or do other
trades with them before he'll give you a
new one okay let's just go run and get
one real quick think if we buy some
glass from him we'll be able to treat
some new some new things with them
oh that glitch is done you see that
piston so the stair warping and other
stuff is still a problem it looks like
maybe if that got fixed to like
sometimes half slabs will become stairs
and flipped weird and yeah alright buddy
if I'd give you some emeralds will you
give me some back we will buy one of
these
hmm I also heard they have a different
particle effect I didn't really see that
no still no deal what do you want from
me well that's where the particles are
from the inner chest
I think he's set in his ways I don't
think he's going to trade with me
anymore
hmm I'll try it a few more times
I thought if I traded with them enough
times I he would renew the paper trade
with me but instead after five times he
decided he didn't want to trade glass
and this one never opened up so now it's
two trades I can't do running out of
options here I mean getting new ones um
I don't know I have to make a way of
breeding them so we get new guys that we
can just kill that after we've used them
um yeah let's try out the leather armor
that looks that looks a lot better you
see the new icon I think it looks
different totally I think they redid it
actually so let's put some of this stuff
on it's a lot dollar than normal color
almost a bit more brown - it was more
red before ok and if we dye it
what color should we diet first of all
let's try a green shirt that is awesome
yeah I like it that is pretty cool um
what else should we do so we definitely
can't dye that now just leather stuff we
can do wait what did I do
don't do that I'm losing my mind here
purple purple pants we could be the Hulk
oh my goodness I can be the Hulk oh it's
totally unintentional that I just pulled
that off
amazing
so then you can diet another color yet
right and keep going yeah
black was black look like
yeah that's going to be really cool
happy about that feature and just takes
advantage of existing stuff and just
adds new purposes to like Diane and
leather and yeah it's just a great
feature to the game I would say let's
try orange now that is fashionable cool
all right um I think I'm about done for
today I know there's a lot of other
changes like guys I read today that
animals take different things chickens
breed with seeds now and pigs with
carrots I think or something and that
you get those in jungles but I would
have to generate a new one from what
I've read so they might do that sometime
not today though I'm gonna go to bed and
what was it going to do oh yeah I want
to try out the TNT apparently can set it
off with fire arrows now so sadly I've
never gotten a flame bow before so we're
going to do it just with a lava pillar I
hope it's a lot harder to do it this way
though most of the time it won't catch
fire particles are on right yeah
you have to like lob it real slow
is it not touching fire at all
oh there we go finally shot how many
times got it that is cool man
I like that you can like yeah you can
remote detonate T&T from so far away
with that addition I like that and let's
read the comments I've picked up for
today guys number one you need to show
off your parkour skills etho I don't
have any parkour skills really I think
the only time I actually did anything
considered parkour is game is when I did
vexes rage quit holidays and needless to
say I haven't wanted to do any sense so
yeah next one
Etha I've been wanting to see your
statistics lately will you show them to
us or make a rule that you show your
statistics every 50 or so episodes
thanks for taking your time reading this
lots of love from Bulgaria
yeah I'm constantly switching my jar
file and I don't properly backup my
minecraft when I do that I know how to I
just don't do it but here we go I don't
know how accurate this is gonna be yeah
ooh I use lots of those again I don't
know how accurate this is 40
I know I've used or I've made more than
that
general box items lots of sticks and at
18,400
I don't know seems a little bit low to
me 788 hmm yeah well that's what they
are again I don't know how accurate they
are but enjoy hey guys
take care see you later