[Music]
hello hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome to another episode of the
let's play series
we made it through the world tour guys
last episode was the world tour
it was almost two hours long
and i had to record it over several days
because man my voice could not hold out
through the whole thing
and it was a 55 gig upload to youtube
that was the biggest file
i've ever uploaded in my life took like
a full day to do it
but we made it through guys and i was
looking at the comments on that man you
guys uh
you really went to town on that episode
five over 5000 comments
uh mostly left like really nice uh
supportive comments
kind of uh thanking me for the series
and also just like how
it affected you in your life and stuff
so it was cool to read through that and
i
i appreciate it uh but now we gotta move
forward right what are we doing now
well we gotta head over to the village
first stop because some of you
gave me a couple tips i didn't know
about my world
um a while ago
we lost some villagers and i saw even
chito disappeared he was in the glass
cage over here
apparently they are somehow getting
underneath the village
i think around here i can hear some
zombie villagers
um they must be teleporting through the
ground somehow because there's no way
yeah for them to get over here
oh it's a fisherman okay oh there's a
bunch of guys here
oh man uh oh i think that might be
my golden carrot selling guy
oh dude okay what do we do here let's uh
okay come over here for a second we
gotta convert these guys back
get our villagers back i don't know how
they're getting down here like there
should be no way
for that to happen but somehow i mean
reality
says something different here oh it is
cheeto
yeah look at that cheat those down here
too amazing
here we go okay
i guess as many as we can here okay we
got three of them oh oh uh i meant to do
that
i kind of feel like their damage
increased after i hit them with the
weakness potion
i could be wrong
okay
got him with the boat okay uh i got none
of my armor
got a little too close okay
i think as long as i stay here oh he's
fine okay
got our stuff back let's head over to
these two
i mean as long as they see me they won't
attack the villager in the boat
like the the other guy that doesn't
convert right away
there we go awesome so we got those four
villagers converted and back into our
village again
there might be more i'll have to check
out the caves a bit further
but we do have our farmer back again the
interesting thing about this is he's
from
a long time ago right so his trades are
kind of broken
let's see if we can still trade
infinitely with them
without him having to restock looks like
we still can but his trades didn't get
cheaper after he got cured
a lot of people asked how you do that
with the trading by the way you just hit
spacebar to
refill anyways let's get to working on
some stuff here
so the plan for today is to expand out
to a new area
which means we gotta build a thousand
blocks of nether tunnel which means we
need basalt
which means we gotta build a basalt
generator
so we're building up a salt generator
above our goon farm where we can
uh either actively mine it or afk mine
it
gonna work something like this i'm still
in the middle of building it right now
we gotta make sure we spawn proof
everything we're putting glass over top
um so iron golems or mobs won't spawn on
top of anything
and it's a very strange idea
basically it if the salt gets mined
under any of these note blocks it'll
activate the pistons
and we're gonna be checkering the note
blocks
and then have three pistons on one side
and two on the other and they'll
intertwine
the basalts all into one big piece here
that we can hopefully mine
um and the way we got to do this is
let's see we're on this piston next we
got to get
uh i think we got to start this side
actually so
it'll be glass here note block
and then we want the observer going this
way to that piston
so then we just do something like this
all the way down now in order to
generate basalt you need to run
lava towards blue ice with soul soil
below and then that updates the note
block
above which pushes the piston so
there's a lot of stuff going on there
and i didn't pre-build this in creative
so it might be total garbage we'll find
out
they're all activating right yeah i hope
so
okay see what happens here
i think it's okay
i don't know if it's gonna regenerate
fast enough oh we're only getting three
layers deep
supposed to be all five and yeah
probably the best way of using it is
just to uh
kind of afk in the middle here and we'll
get all five rows at once
maybe even in between the hoppers would
be best
somewhere around here and then all the
hoppers collect the drops together and
the chest down
below and it's just another thing we can
do while we're waiting for iron golems
and
and gold to generate aha yep yep so
today is the day everybody oh i've been
looking forward to this
i mentioned a few episodes ago i had a
massive
project planned for after the world tour
so yeah that time is now guys
it is time to find out more about the
ultimate
unfinished project oh what could it be
it's got to be a new storage room right
etho loves making his storage rooms
that's true but no it's not that might
be a
massive transportation system or maybe
even a magnificent
new base with all the redstone gizmos
you could imagine
well i i had some fun reading the
guesses on what it might be
it's none of those things it's actually
something very weird the best way i can
explain it is we've kind of
moved past the survival point in our
world and now we're in the information
age of our
our world so we're trying to create a
giant facility that's sort of like a
testing facility a research center but
also as a museum
a place to gather and display all the
minecraft knowledge
that we have acquired over the years of
playing this game and present it within
our world in one location
we're trying to create the minecraft
wiki within the game
and we'll get into more detail on what
that means exactly in just a second here
but first i just wanted to show you
where that tunnel we just built leads to
to a jungle of course we're going to be
starting our project
where the grass is the greenest you know
me we got to start off in a jungle
i actually spent many hours looking at
different locations and i figured this
one would be the best
for what we got planned with this
project um
the idea is we're gonna use this as our
central hub
location and ultimately the goal with
the project will be to expand out
hundreds if not thousands of blocks into
other biomes in order for it to be
complete it has to actually
so uh we should get further and further
away from this jungle as we work on this
more and more basically
um but i figured this would be a nice
starting
location now the cool thing about this
area we got picked out is there's many
different biomes
right next to this jungle like rare ones
that you wouldn't normally find
uh together as well so we got like
snowy biomes nearby here next to the
jungle we got coral reefs we got
the giant tiger all sorts of different
things even some
very rare biomes like modified jungle is
here
and we're going to need those eventually
not right away but eventually if the
plan works out
our mission statement for this facility
is basically if any piece of information
exists about this game whether it be an
idea
a game mechanic or a thing like this
leaf block or the portal behind us or
something
if the information exists we want to try
collect it together
and put it in our facility and then
arrange it present it in a way that is
hopefully useful
that hopefully looks good and
also very important is i want it to be
interactive as well
yeah so i'm thinking there's going to be
five main categories of information
we'll want to store in our facility here
game mechanics mobs redstone building
techniques
and world generation and then each of
these main categories is going to have
subcategories
tied to it so let's take game mechanics
as an example
uh there's probably dozens and dozens of
game mechanics we would want to
represent in our facility here
i just put down 10 of them to give you
an idea what i mean
so let's take damage as an example
number five here
so the real world application of this is
we would build a room
in our facility to display
information on how damage works in the
game
now there's many different ways you can
take damage in this game cactus
fall damage fire you know getting shot
by arrows
we would need to have all those
forms of damage housed in the facility
with what's possible in survival of
course
obviously we can't get an enderdragon in
our facility
i don't think at least unless you guys
know away
but as as far as it's possible we're
going to want to try to do this stuff
and not only do we want like a lectern
with information oh cactuses cause
damage
fire causes damage how much damage oh
this many hearts right we don't want to
just have the information
stored we want to be able to interact
with it we need to be able to test and
show
cactuses cause damage we need to be able
to design experiments where we can hop
on cactuses and see how much damage they
cause
so there's gonna be a lot of stuff to
factor in here
a lot of things to think about um and
that's just the first one mobs
we talked about making a zoo a long time
ago and that's
we're gonna combine that into this
project we're going to have a room for
every single type of mob in the game and
rather than like on a wiki page where
you just have a picture of a mob we're
going to have the actual mob
in the game here on display and then
all the information tied to that mob
hopefully within a room
every every category gets its own room
basically
so our facility is made up of two main
things the rooms
those are our wiki entries basically the
data
and then there's gonna be um like
hallways and corridors to tie our rooms
together to organize them
maybe transportation systems through the
facility elevators
i'm gonna need like a storage room and
like smelting area
um so there's two main things the rooms
and then the facility
and the lore behind it basically this is
a very talky episode i hope you guys
don't mind
i just want to make some stuff clear
here before we get into it
um now some of these are pretty closely
linked to each other as well like mining
is kind of linked with tools
certain tools speed up your mining speed
right
so rather than having like url links um
like you would have on a wiki page we'll
probably have like a tunnel from
our mining room to our tool room and
link them together that way
in the facility if that makes sense
and then we've talked about making a
redstone museum before i'd like to have
all the different redstone components um
on display somewhere building technique
i'm not quite sure what we're gonna do
with that but i would like to
maybe go over some things like this and
have a room for each of these things
world generation i would like to
make a room for each of the biomes in
the game
um like what blocks generate in those
biomes
and also like any structures like
rather than just having a picture of a
water temple like you would have on the
wiki page we want to
find a water temple in our world
excavate it and have it on display in a
room
so that's why we need to like spread out
and cover lots of area
with this project that's the grand idea
with the project
how far we get with it is another
question though because obviously
we're talking about a ton of work here i
i would say minimum
100 episodes could easily be spent on
this probably a lot more
um so a lot of it's gonna depend on what
you guys think about the project if you
like it or if you think i should scrap
it
um if you like it the good news is we'll
never run out of content to do
um and the thing about this project like
if you think about the nexus it's like
it kind of gets repetitive over time
um the redstone systems get all big and
convoluted to where we can barely
understand them
and with this project i think most of
it's going to be pretty straightforward
we can look at it and get an idea of
what's going on so i like that
it's not really going to be repetitive
because every thing is a different thing
right
and also it doesn't need to be finished
for us to enjoy it like the more
we work on it the cooler and better it's
going to be
hmm it's looking like it's around here
somewhere it's going underground here so
let's go check out the stronghold
um that's another key reason we picked
this location
i'm going to dig straight down because i
got a fire resistant potion
now i don't want to damage the
stronghold because we might be using
this as our display
for the project right um let's go
through a stone brick
i broke both oops okay got an
achievement yeah i've never been to a
stronghold before i'm sure
okay we're inside i'm not going to place
any torches in here i don't want to
adjust anything with it we just want to
find the
portal and link it to the surface if we
can
don't want to loot anything everything's
got to stay the same
at the very least we want to use the
silverfish in here for our silverfish
display
but yeah we this is gonna be a very
expensive project as well so we need to
keep working on making farms in our
worlds building up infrastructure so
that we can actually afford
uh doing this brand project right so
we'll be spending probably 20 to 50
percent of our time
working on this and the rest of our time
doing uh
the normal stuff we do in our let's play
okay
oh is that gonna break no it doesn't
wait why isn't that break it's not on a
block
can doors float getting very close okay
i'm gonna check the fire resistance
hopefully there's no creeper in this
room i found the location though it
should be
right in the middle here yeah no creeper
okay we're safe
uh let's get out of the lava
and i am just gonna block the
door it's easy to remove later right
now i will light up the portal though
we're not going to preserve that because
i need to use this to get back
to like the man cave and stuff quickly
so yeah we're going to do that because
we are 11 000
blocks on the x coordinates and 9 000 on
the z it's a pretty
long distance so now we can just hop in
here
and then fly up to our
end portal over here and we should get
taken back to
the man cave area yeah then we can just
take the nether if we need to go back
anyways my main goal with this episode
was just to introduce the idea to you
guys
but we'll probably get started on one of
the rooms to better
show you how it's going to work so maybe
we'll try to do the mining mechanic
game mechanic and we're on a fairly big
piece of land right now i think we're
going to need a big room for this one
we're going to dig down to about y
180 and then start hollowing out
this mountain um
the reason we're going down low is
because we're going to eventually move
an elder guardian here for
the mining fatigue effect we need that
for this room
and he's gonna be up at the top of the
world there so that we're
we can pull a switch to receive it when
we want uh
in this room now as far as how we're
doing the building
with this i think we'll want to try to
keep a lot of it underground
just to save time if i have to build
exteriors like this is never going to
get done
at the very most we'll probably have
facades like maybe we'll have something
showing on the outside of the hill here
uh but we don't want to spend too much
time building exteriors if we can help
it it's going to be more like
the man cave style and yeah let's just
clear out a bunch of land and see
how much space we have all right very
cool so we cleared out a little bit of
space here to get us started and
we got a fair bit of space to make a
mining room here
if we need more we can always extend
platforms off the side here it's fine or
we can go down vertically too
it should be okay now looking around
here i think
i think what we're going to want to do
is make the entrance
to this room over here because looking
out here it looks like uh we got a good
view for one thing
and we could maybe make a tunnel and
that goes from this room to
over here and make another room in this
big mountain area now to be honest i
don't exactly
know what i'm doing here i'm really
hoping you guys will help me out a lot
with this project like i need ideas for
um decorative things for building things
help me with how we're presenting the
information help me with organizing it
like i don't know if we should make this
the mining room or if it should be more
like the block
breaking room or maybe digging rooms a
better name for it
because mining kind of implies we're
going to have information on how ores
generate in the world and stuff and i
was thinking maybe
let's just focus on like breaking blocks
right
so for example mining speed
speed mining would be a big thing i
would want in this room
and one of the things that affects that
is like if you're
airborne you break blocks slower
compared to if you're
on the ground now we would want maybe a
presentation to show
what happens if you're on a ladder like
floating like this
looks like it slows us down so i think
that slows down our mining speed by five
times
but uh we'll have to figure all that
stuff out
um another thing that slows down mining
speed is water
so we would probably want somewhere
where we can stand in water and try
mining
then we would want some way of combining
them together uh
if you're riding a mine cart you mine
slower we'll want to set up some beacons
in here i know
like one with haste one one with haste
two and then we can switch between them
or turn them both off
um we'll want that elder guardian in
here
and i think we should make oh yeah
we'll probably wanna have some way of
detecting how far we can mine too like
our range
i think it's 4.5 blocks from us but
we'll want to
not just say we can mine 4.5 blocks away
from us we want to prove
with an experiment right so that'll be
one thing we put in here
i'm thinking we want like a main machine
to
measure mining speed so like we'll
again we don't want just the book saying
oh we can mine this block this fast
we want to prove we can mine that block
that fast
so one way we might do that is
set up a little mechanism here where
ah let's see it'll probably be something
like
this we'll have like a hole and then
we'll set up like five blocks of
whatever material that we're testing out
i guess we'll get moved back
all right and like when we mine this
first block here it'll start the timer
and then when we get to this one it'll
stop it and then we'll want an
accurate timer to show how much time
that takes if we're instant mining
it happens pretty quickly yeah let's
actually go ahead and do this i think
this would be a great first project it's
fairly simple
just a general mining machine speed
tester
um so let's have it so we'll have the
ladder here so you can be airborne and
get that penalty
and then we'll have a dispenser with
water bucket in
and that way we can combine them
together as well and still be able to
reach all five blocks when we're
standing here i like that
we'll probably want some way of
returning the stuff we mined to us
so maybe we'll have another dispenser
with a water bucket here that when the
timer stops
it ejects the water and delivers our
items back
this would have to be a trap door
probably because otherwise items will be
too far away from us and then
we'll probably just want to encase this
with obsidian or crying obsidian so we
don't accidentally break
the casing around this thing aha so
we're not gonna worry too much about the
building style
just for today but it's definitely
something we're gonna need to think
about
i kind of like the idea of using
blackstone and basalt in
these rooms um but i know this is ugly
what we're looking at right now so
i'm gonna have to play around with the
block pellet a little bit i like uh
maybe using
light blue and and orange with our build
though
because like lamps are orange
a lot of the lighting options in this
game are light blue or orange like sea
lanterns
or blue the fire types are
blue and orange and lanterns blue and
orange so i think it would simplify a
lot of things if we could use those two
colors
um let's see here so we're going to be
installing a timer
to keep track of the mining speeds and
you guys might recall a long long time
ago in a
land far far away minecraft season four
we came up with the horse timer now it's
not the exact same timer we used a long
time ago i revised it with modern
redstone so it's a little bit more
compact and nicer and
and all kinds of stuff right i think
it's quieter as well
now the basic idea behind it is we have
10 repeaters all set at one tick
so each one represents a tenth of a
second
and it just goes around in a loop over
and over and over
until we want to stop the time then we
send a signal to this
wire and that locks the repeaters at
wherever they're at
um so yeah we send a signal to this line
to start it and then a solid pulse to
this one to stop it
so we got this for this line over here
hooked up to
our observer so whenever we
mine this block it'll start up
and start going around in a loop like
that then when it gets to the end
we should add a seconds timer as well
this is tenths of seconds
when it gets to the end it'll add one
second above here
and that way we can keep track of up to
10 seconds
time accurate within a tenth of a second
but we'll probably won't get that far
with it today but whenever we want to
freeze it
we just send a pulse that's all it falls
to that and i can see it's on the one
two three four
five six point six seconds
but yeah we should probably think about
wrapping things up here for today we'll
work more on this later
assuming you guys actually like this
project idea
i don't know i was very worried about
hyping this up earlier
like i wanted to because i think it's an
amazing idea but
it's also a weird idea so some of you
might not like it i don't know i didn't
want to raise
expectations and then you guys would be
like oh that's this is kind of a dumb
idea etho
i don't know what you're thinking uh one
thing i just realized as well we should
have
maybe like around here
next to our mining machine we're going
to want a stash of all the different
tools in the game
with all the different efficiency levels
as well
so we'll need wooden picks efficiency
one through five
stone picks one through five we'll need
shovels one through five
and we'll have to get another right
tools for that as well
you can you can see how things can start
getting expensive with this project
right
before we finish up here there is one
more project i wanted to show you guys
real quick
just a simple one uh you might recall
we've been
slowly working in this area here we
built the concrete maker recently
and we've had the skeleton spotter next
to it i decided to make a farm out of it
so that while we're
making concrete we're also getting bones
and
and arrows automatically as well so
there's a light switch here we can
turn it off and then they'll start
spawning they fall down
and die from fall damage and we'll just
go in here to show you the design
kind of went a little crazy with it
there's hoppers underneath the slabs
here that pick up the drops and then
send it up a water elevator to the top
there
so it's it's kind of cool anyways let's
get to the comment of the day it says
hey etho
i've been watching your videos for a few
years now
and with the exception of a few series
hermitcraft
rad enigmatica 2 etc most things you do
on your channel are solitary and about
half of the
multiplayer series you have either ended
early or slowly stopped being made
i'm not complaining as i like both types
of content equally but do you have a
reason
for focusing on solo content
yeah so thank you for that i thought
this was a great question to answer
because i don't think a lot of people
realize some of the behind the scenes
stuff that happens
the main reason for doing stuff solo is
i have way more control
over what happens right if i'm doing
something with a group or with
with more people um i have to
record it certain times for one thing
it's harder to arrange recording with
people
because like if you're doing a big
recording with three or more people
like team canada all three of those
people need to be in the same place at
the same time and be able to record for
the same
amount in time and not be sick at the
same time and
all sorts of things right it gets kind
of complicated
especially when you factor in time zones
then there's also the issue
that if anybody in the series wants to
stop at any point it kind of stops it
for
everybody they're recording with or like
in the case of something like
hermitcraft if they want to reset the
map and you don't want to
well you don't have any control over
that or
you know you can't even just play the
game you got to also get servers
you got to pay for servers and manage
them then
you don't have access to the map you're
playing on anymore usually
if you don't own the server and there's
just so many things
um a big one though for me is you can't
edit stuff really
if you're recording with a group it's
like everything that gets recorded
is fair game um if your goal is to take
like two hours and
cut it down to 20 minutes that doesn't
generally happen you
pretty much just post everything right
so it's a lot it's a lot better for like
lazy content
like where you're just showing
everything uh but not so good for
the content i like to do where i like to
edit it down
um then like there's just so many things
like if uh
somebody in the group is doing the exact
same thing as you and you both post the
same videos on youtube and your
viewership overlaps
they watch the other guy first they're
not gonna watch your video then so you
lose
viewership that's that's another bad
thing
so there's there's a lot of stuff that
basically
solo videos are much easier and
generally
more profitable to make and you have a
lot more control
hope that answers the question hope you
guys enjoyed this episode if you got
feedback please let me know in the
comments i'm
i got a lot of things to think about
with this hopefully you'll help me out
with it
but that's gonna do it for today's
episode guys thanks for watching hope
you enjoyed it
take care bye bye