hello hello greetings how are we all
doing today I'm doing quite well myself
let's see what should we do start off
with today well first of all I'll show
you I'll show you the changes I made up
here finish this part off and so some I
have a problem with lighting in the cave
as you know one of the challenges is to
not use any torches when this is all all
finished right so we want to hide the
lighting as best as possible and you
know I've sort of been experimenting
with different ways of doing that such
as these type of lights I tried doing
this I don't like this so stands out way
too much I put one over there too before
I had glowstone here but yeah I don't
like that too much
went through some of my messages the
other day and somebody left me a really
good suggestion so well let's let's head
over here it's it can be pretty tough
trying to hide the lighting like again I
don't exactly like that
having glowstone in the middle like that
but and this like I said I didn't like
this either I have pressure plates with
the pump in there the suggestion I got
though which is brilliant it's actually
kind of what I did in my sheep farm you
know how I hit the pistons in the in the
roof in it or in the ceiling and it
matches the wooden plank texture well
somebody suggested I should just do
something like this
isn't that cool I would think that's a
great idea so you still get the lighting
because light passes through Pistons
wrong way wrong way you can use pumpkins
and it doesn't matter so it's a real
cheap cheap lighting that way like you
don't use glowstone although the Pistons
are a bit expensive but yeah I think
that's I'm gonna use this a lot I think
and it helps to break up the walkway to
s which is nice I don't like like
everything plate doesn't have to all be
planks it looks good if you got the
white mixed in and yeah
just a really good idea so I'll switch
all these and so we'll see how it looks
yeah I would say that's a pretty
clear-cut improvement or at least in my
opinion that looks a lot better
where are all these lights I don't
understand why it's not dark here Oh
what secret lighting yeah it looks good
this tunnel I still have nuts really
made any progress with so we're still
huffing it to the stronghold need more
TNT and I need to spend time at the
strong hole to get gunpowder from the
mob system so guess where we're going
today oh yeah by the way I tried a few
more there were torches here before now
there's none I think I do like it but I
find I need to balance it out like over
here block light the lowest drops to 8
at my head so the grass is at 9 but
there they look a little bit random I
don't know I might have to mess around
with how I position them I tried a few
over here too one in the corner
- over there actually in this spot right
here I realize this the other day it's
actually oh wait no seven thought mobs
could spawn here maybe we can't it's
seven at my head but at the ground it
would be eight pretty sure yeah and I
think that's safe looks a bit dark in
the middle and you know how I said I was
going to put lights at the top the
problem is like in the ceiling here
problem is light level fifteen there
fourteen thirteen twelve eleven ten by
the time it makes the grass that's
already a ten so you're not going to get
much light from the ceiling on the
ground because it's so high up and even
less if you do it here um put three over
here that looks pretty good but yeah
we're going to go to the stronghold
today I've the other day we pretty much
completed the sheep farm all we can do
until 1.3 anyway I'm just wondering why
this sheep is out okay I can't remember
how I left that last time one thing we
haven't finished yet though that we've
spent a lot of time on is the silverfish
farms so let's go work on that today and
hopefully put an end to that long
never-ending project all right here we
are we're at the stronghold this is
where silverfish farm is and also our
regular mob system this is for the
future storage room is going to go so
our dog likes to hang out and randomly
teleport to us I did a bunch of caving
around here the other day and seems to
be working a little bit quicker the mob
system
all I'm going to make that a focus try
to do more and more caving around here
so that we can get it peaked out maximum
maximum efficiency so there's only a few
loose ends left with this thing let's
grab some glass one thing we need to do
is seal it and I did work at that
because remember last time when we were
here we had that disaster the silverfish
got out and they made a mess of
everything they owe and they they killed
me many times a while it's a disaster
look at look at what they did and almost
caught it on fire all went wrong so we
need to seal it so that never happens
again it's like a radioactive power
plant that can have a leak at any time
we need to make sure it's it's safe as
far as I know I got it almost all sealed
there was one spot over here we'll just
plug up with this I think I was still
deciding what to do what we'll do we'll
do glass for now anyway I also did this
wiring I don't know if I ever showed
this but I cleaned up cleaned up over
here quite a bit looks a lot better this
is for the snowman controls to turn them
on and off which is not fully done yet
this is not sealed either it's a good
thing we went around check in here
just put glass for now thing is I'm
trying to make it look good but at the
same time there's a limit to how much
you can do with that so the only big
leak left I believe is behind the
snowman so what we'll do we'll put put
dark planks behind them and see how that
looks and leave that there until we
decide on something else
I was also trying to figure out what to
put behind these little open half slab
areas I put white wool there but I don't
like that well we should figure
something out for that too and the idea
is the silverfish fall down they all
funnel to the spot will have a killing
chamber we're going to have to change
this so we'll have maybe two dispensers
on this side these will be for poison
potions so when they're all in here we
push a button they get poisoned down to
one or two half a hearts then we throw
us damage potion at them and we get all
XP or or we'll also have a front display
so we can see them and we'll have a door
maybe over here you know what I'm going
to make this come out one more block at
least get a little space away from this
this room
oops we'll have a door here that will
terraeum this way and then up to the
surface because we want a way of getting
them out of here too so we'll have the
option of either killing them there or
transporting them out too to the top of
the world I just harvested a bunch of
the pine wood here in this forest
waiting for the leaves to the spawn
there's a nice one right next to the
stronghold over there so we got our wood
for behind the snowmen let's head on
down there and
to see how it looks all right let's see
how this looks I also thought about
using Blackwell something that you don't
really focus on darker colors are better
it I would say and also the marble color
in this this room is mostly the white
color so having a little extra dark will
help bounce out the look the wiring is
right above there okay this is
difference not needed okay let's see
let's take a look out how it's going
such a mess down here
hmm yeah I don't know it almost seems a
little plain to me well I'll do the
whole thing if we want to change it
later we can it's easy too if you got
ideas let me know black will might be
better but it's I'm not sure I've kind
of hit the point where I just want this
thing up and working you know get it
functioning and if we want to perfect it
later we can but let's just get it going
you know so I've actually had that
silverfish farm show off for of at least
a month now maybe two months and I could
be getting XP from it and doing other
things if it was up and running but I've
just been dragging my feet about it
there's we got a few projects like that
the plays farm the dual blades firms
still not up and running where am I
going and I would like to make some
refinements to the Enderman farm
yeah you know what's looking weird is
these dark dark patches and from the
stairs there maybe I should just replace
those with full planks that's what's
making it look weird now I'll try that
let's see how that looks mm-hmm so that
seems to have done the trick it looks a
lot more fluent now a lot more normal
stairs they we're having that lighting
glitch where they appear darker than
they should which is a glitch I I take
advantage of the times like in the mini
storage room I use that for an aesthetic
look but at other times like this it's
not so welcome to you know it kind of
grabs your eyes the darkness so got rid
of that and in these corners they look a
little weird too so let's get rid of
this and this and this and this and try
full blocks
hmm yeah I don't know
let's try get a couple of these what
happens if we change this make it square
we'd have to get rid of this too I don't
know mmm is it challenge
oh let's what about this way now that
one was like that that's okay I'll play
with it let's do it like this this looks
pretty good
I put the stair back there and I did
this corner like that next let's try
figure out what we're going to put in
this little window area with our weird
stair placements I was thinking we'll
try like do the dark wood in this corner
and this piece here and then do the
light wood light wood dark wood dark
wood light wood light wood dark wood and
see how that looks okay dark and then
lights
get over here - OH
dark light let's see how that looks so
far it also just do black wool I don't
know don't know too many choices that's
I like building things with function
because there's always a right and a
wrong choice
but when you do go for things with a
look it's open to anybody's
interpretation yeah I like that
we'll do that there we go that is done
this middle kind of messed it messed up
the pattern a bit so we have dark there
but it works out okay
ah this room should be sealed now I
think we got all the weight that doesn't
look sealed oh that can't be sealed
that's where the that's where the
silverfish blocks come from yeah it
should be good now this is the only way
they're going to get out through here
you're going to fall into the killing
chamber which we want to move one block
let's move these right here
with the dispensers down so they should
naturally fall into this little holding
area and if they don't they can also
track me through the wall like
silverfish can see through walls up to
about eight blocks or so I don't know
the exact number that drop them down
I have glass I kind of want to use iron
bars but Oh ding familiar problem is
back I'm going to I'm going to move this
lava a weight a little bit of ways a
little ways away from here
so we don't have any problems that's
much better
now we have some room to work here to
move to breathe let's get back to it the
point of having two dispensers here is
just so we don't have to refill them as
often and it's going to take a while to
clean up all the mess around here but I
I do intend to not today obviously but
sometime so do something like that I
will do the bottom they'll do the top I
have poison potions in these alright and
then we're going to put just one piston
here is all we all we really need and do
that and let's just put a lever down so
we can control it so that'll be our gate
for sending them to the surface of
course they we want to escort them to
the surface we don't want to just send
them on their own otherwise we'll
probably D spawn on their way we have to
be within the 32 block range that rule
still applies even
silverfish and let's say go into a block
then it doesn't matter but okay
I'll be tweaking this fissure afterwards
too just want to get the shape and
everything figured out and maybe we'll
do a test run today to order okay that's
our holding area open it and close it
and then what I want to do is want to
lead them into a three-wide tunnel at
least because there's going to be a lot
of silverfish and they're going to be
tracking me so to keep them all group
together to keep them following me we
need to give them us enough space to
move around so let's make it three wide
instead of like just one wide you know
otherwise they will bottleneck and jam
and mmm all out of those yeah and what
we'll do is we'll just lead them this
way without moving them up for a ways
just so that they don't interfere with
the storage room in the future because
it if they're like we got to make them
go up to the surface and if we do that
too close to the storage room they will
the two projects will get in the way of
each other right on okay oh I gotta go
to bed here so we'll continue this part
of it next time I would like to do a
killing a killing test today though if
we can there's a few silverfish left in
that room
how should we do this I know what I'll
do I'll just take that out put that in
I'm going to get some armor on - oh man
this freaks me out doing this it didn't
go so well last time this is these are
all the silverfish left from last
disaster so let's get rid of them all
no matter shooting oh that one guys is
up let's get them out okay as long as
they're not jumping they don't damage
you is that other stuntman shooting you
with that okay and it's probably a good
two or three hundred left they're easily
lilia mom man oh no more coming out okay
I guess that's the cutoff point their
plan for this I plan for it come on come
on money out Oh out
how how did they get out come on gotta
be kidding
whistles - there's still a few running
around there if you're mad at the
Stoneman 100 should we try to get that
rest up - it looks like some silver fish
were left over down there that got out
and now we have lapis flowing again did
I tell you and we will put this no not
this gets dangerous still need to figure
out a way of doing this top part a
little bit better dang it
there goes all the silver fish hmm
yeah I'm not sure what to do this isn't
working out too well they can't get up
here right oh you know what those two
that were there they probably were
outside and they came from like over
here was loud was flowing now let's
cover it up just in case don't want any
trouble
let's try out the poison very good
and then 77 okay
team is really legend got them all
awesome alright so next time we'll
finish most of this up I'm pretty sure
and should be pretty cool when it's all
done I'll have to think about ways of
getting the top three layers of
silverfish down because way it is right
now isn't working too well but it
shouldn't be that difficult to figure
out a couple XP orbs got stuck are they
coming from mm there's a lot of XP orbs
like that's stuck there
weird okay well anyway that's it for
today guys thanks for watching I'll see
you again next time