oh yeah we got some big plans for
today's episode guys big massive chunky
plans in the works here are you guys
ready for this this is gonna be amazing
so I figured first off you ready for
this we're gonna we're gonna do some
building and then after we're done the
building we're going to what we're going
to honestly haven't thought that far
ahead but we're gonna do some building
there's gonna be some building this
episode and we're gonna get some blocks
ready here for it and it's gonna be a
lot of big building um actually I'm not
really ready for this episode let's set
let's talk to you give them a couple
minutes here all right very good very
good so we got our black concrete
converted over you guys remember
remember this little gizmo we we tell it
what we want it goes up and it gets it
for us and then we then we take it out
of here fill up our inventory
alternatively I could have just put in a
chest while I was doing it but no this
is this is way better yes wait a minute
no no that's not the right color you got
the wrong color do it all over again
uh-huh so a little lesson for those of
you that don't build with concrete too
often if you look a great concrete here
you know it looks pretty dark and if you
didn't check the name of it you might
even assume it's the black concrete but
no it
get a lot darker than this this is just
great but like if you ever mix them up
you shouldn't feel bad cuz that could
happen to anybody honestly okay well I
think we are finally ready now guys we
are gonna get to the building and we're
gonna be placing thousands of blocks
today we're gonna we're gonna go pretty
big on the building so I wanted to get a
lot of it ready here before we started
we got some sand back up here in case we
need more glass or concrete down the
line here we got light blue terracotta
we got
a whole bunch of great glass some Boom
Blox prismarine stuff here and oh we
don't talk about that yeah look at this
gray concrete lots of great concrete on
hand so we can we can really get into it
here and we're gonna be working on the
Nexus today my goal is to get this front
part of it done or at least like pretty
much done right um the idea is we're
supposed to have some rooms over here
we've talked about this many times
before
it's gonna be a bit of a weird building
though is my problem like it's not like
a house like I'm not building a house
here right it's like a weird shape and
everything so this should be interesting
it might look a little strange at the
end of things but we'll see how it goes
here yeah so I realized I kind of like
this great concrete a little bit more
than the cyan clay we were using
originally for this build so we're gonna
change that all outs our goal is to kind
of make a weird futuristic feel with
this build all right that's our style
we're going for a little bit of a
problem though because we have like a
almost a natural color scheme over there
and then we have another color scheme
over there so this area might look a
little weird it's gonna be hard to blend
them together having these three
completely different builds side-by-side
I maybe didn't plan that out the best
but we'll see what we can do with it
yeah I'm definitely liking the gray
concrete over the cyan clay so we'll
stick with that let's let's do this
entrance area so I don't think we're
gonna actually put a door on this thing
because again it's not like a normal
building right it's kind of a weird
building um and when we go to use it a
lot of times I'm I want to just fly in
grab something and fly it out right I
don't want to go through a big corridor
of doors to get to the buttons here you
know so I think we'll just keep it like
this this is a good angle to view it
from I feel so we'll have like a landing
area here but we're gonna get rid of
this play for sure this we will probably
change to the gray as well keep it
consistent and then we'll probably just
put the prismarine like in the middle
here
I hate when I do that I middle-click
sometimes and it doesn't select the
block and I like Scrolls instead and I
go to like the ender pearl I do that's
so often I don't know why okay let's go
around the sea lantern
I'll give it a weird shape yeah that
looks a little strange doesn't it so I
think we either got to change it to bone
blocks or we have to make more of the
outside of this building that's darker
color cuz it just looks like it stands
out on its own right now
which wouldn't be a bad thing actually
cuz we only got two colors really in our
our outside here just the white and the
blue if we mix some black in with that
it could look cool not black it's great
don't don't mix those up okay um over
here and we probably will bring this
over let's see oh I wonder if my middle
click is kind of open right now I just I
just got this mouse though it shouldn't
be so I'll probably do prisoner in here
as well all along the ground right we
somehow have to add some staircases like
to go down and to go up here and the
problem is we kind of want in the middle
for both and that's not possible we also
have a wire that comes across here that
we have to deal with somehow and we also
need to figure out what goes on this
side of the wall I think I might just
mirror it actually so if we copy the
same distance like this at the same
width one two three one two three yeah
okay so maybe we make this come all the
way across and the nice thing about like
working with this concrete it's a pretty
plain block which means we don't have to
add a lot of detail to the build wait I
like that for bigger builds like this
because otherwise it would take me
forever to finish then maybe you let's
just do what we did here and have glass
or we could put foam blocks might look
cool here too
let's use some of this grass to build up
the train around here as well I'm a
little worried I wasn't worried about
that but I should have been no I was
gonna say I'm a little worried this
might be a little on the plain side but
we'll see and I that's why you gotta
sleep guys always sleep sleep away the
nights I wanted to see the lighting
though and it seemed kind of dark around
here so we'll probably stick some seed
lanterns in with the prismarine but yeah
I do like this window so I framed I put
a frame around it I think that's cool I
love seeing the wiring I think that
wiring looks pretty cool it's one of the
few times I actually use like multiple
colors for the different lines so we got
all these different colors a terra cotta
in there which looks kind of crazy and
chaotic right maybe every three blocks
and good stuff so that should keep our
floor nice and bright now that we've got
all these sea lanterns mixed in I'm
gonna try and make it a bit more
interesting not just by like making this
come out do the same on this side
obviously and then we'll probably try
add some prismarine bricks mixed in with
this other stuff and and create some
patterns so maybe let's do like a star
shape here there's a lotta loads and
then put this in yes so there's a bit
more bright variety to it right and then
for these let's also put some some
breaks around the lights oh yeah that
helps it out quite a bit alright I'm
mostly worried about this floor being
kind of boring cuz it's like a big wide
area all all the same colour you know
hopefully hopefully that's good so we're
gonna glass over it
all right so check it out it's starting
to come together here we mirrored the
window to the other side did the border
around it we got our crazy floor with
some random patterns starting to feel
like something right I think we got to
get rid of the hill there though
we got no view or I also got to change a
window with foam blocks I'm still
considering that but we'd have to do a
lot of terraforming here which might be
worth doing I do kind of like the window
though cuz you can see the wiring from
outside that way and and like some of
the building right I think the next
thing we're gonna do is try to work on
connecting this part of the build to
that part now so we we changed that out
several times now I'm gonna do it one
last time we're gonna get rid of the
dark prism arena and we're gonna put the
gray end I think that's that's gonna be
the final look
uh-huh yeah that's like our fourth or
fifth time changing that oh it's perfect
now right guys you all love it right
it's not just me
yeah I feel like I'm gonna come back in
a month and be like what was I thinking
you know all right so we're gonna put
some we're gonna put a staircase here it
would it's the bottom layer looks like
it's gonna end up around here which is
actually perfect look at this don't have
to change any lights or anything all
lines up good so fill that in the rest
of the way uh-huh uh-huh now we gotta
like do some wire dodging here so we got
wires there but I think we can place
some of this over here without wrecking
them right so can we do the same on the
other side here yeah we gotta be really
careful working around the wires here
because I can easily mess it up yeah
yeah we'll do it classic ethos staircase
here I got to maybe get a little bit
better at building staircases I feel
like I always do the exact same thing
where I just make them three wide and
then I do a border around the sides is
that what other people do too like is
there any other way of doing it
it works for me but it's also not very
creative because I always do the same
thing again the middle mouse button what
I think it selects it and then it
Scrolls I think that's what's happening
to me okay so that feels really good
right I just got to fill in a little
section here what's wrong with this boat
let's run with this boat stop it we're
good we're good
okay so I thought it might be nice for a
bit of variety this episode for took a
break from the building there and just
worked on a quick project that this
great firm we set up a while ago so this
thing's pretty cool they spawn down
below they go up some water elevators
all to a central point they fall down
here and then we can we can kill them
for some XP we get that raid buff so
when we enter our village it triggers a
raid and we got a villager over there
making a lot of noise but these guys
also drop crossbows sometimes enchanted
and they drop banners both of which we
can use to smelt stuff in furnaces so I
wanted to maybe set up a thing down
below here for auto smelting could be a
cool little project and also I want to
be able to like pick through the
crossbows we get and see if there's any
good enchanted ones that we might want
to use so yeah well we'll set some
hoppers below the slabs they'll pick up
the crossbows that drop then we'll
funnel all of those into a double chest
here run into the side so they should
all gather to one point and then let's
just run it maybe into two furnaces you
can see how that works out oh yeah like
that and then point the hoppers into the
side and we want to
yeah let's know that's a hard placement
you know like jump and shift at the same
time yeah we want some hoppers pointing
down so that's where we can place our
stuff we want to smelts into this double
chest that should open yeah okay so any
crossbows in here should go into the
fuel slot yeah okay good and anything we
want to smell it should go the top slot
yeah okay good good so then we want to
take those items out of there and put
them into a chest that we can pick up oh
I guess we got a probably place that
first put in the front here put these
underneath the furnaces anything that
smelt should go into here now and then I
kind of wanted to set up some lava
somewhere actually so that we could just
destroy any crossbows that aren't
enchanted like when we're picking
through them oh yeah we can we can click
the double chests here like these
hoppers aren't really in the way so we
can access everything from here but I
think it maybe we changed that and have
these sticking out on the side like this
yeah
so that'll that'll give it a little bit
more storage for the crossbows but also
we can put some lava like over here and
then as we're looking through the chest
of the crossbows we can just press Q to
throw them into the lab a sort of thing
so let's set that up
probably like that right and then
actually let's grab some trapdoors here
yeah so we'll put the trapdoors here
then we can put lava in there all right
both sides and then kind of build this
up a little bit like that yeah so check
this out after we kill a few of these
guys right we go down below here we
should have a bunch of crossbows and
like any that aren't enchanted we can
just press Q now they'll go into a lava
and just get destroyed like if we're not
smelting stuff and we're trying to get a
bunch of enchanted ones that'll EDD
Allah allow us to pick through them
pretty quickly that's cool just add a
couple more blocks here and yeah I think
it's pretty good just like that it's
nothing too crazy right simple project
but should allow us to get some good
crossbows when we want them I decorated
it a little bit you know nothing crazy
and I added some ladders so we can
actually get up to these guys but good
because before I had to use ender pearls
or a rocket every time just kind of
annoying actually it's a XP pretty quick
with this thing - it's not bad uh-huh
but anyways we are back out of here guys
let's get back to the building so I did
fill in the little spots here just put a
spotlight in and some blue clay I think
that looks pretty cool I thought I'd try
to do a story time with etho though as
we do a bit more building here if I can
I saw on the last episode once again
something that comes up quite often
actually people are like you know I
don't know you might want to go to the
doctor get yourself checked out I think
you might be a programmer just just the
way you're doing that redstone no no you
might might want to get looked at so I
thought I'd give you guys a quick little
rough history of my programming
experience because yes I I do know a
little bit about programming I am NOT a
professional programmer by any means I
never got schooling on it's totally
self-taught
but I started learning programming when
I was eight years old that's right I
knew guys at that age when I grow up I'm
gonna make video games for a living that
was my dream job I had it all figured
out
but life can be cruel guys at can only
play video games for a living I don't
gonna make them oh man whoa is me right
uh-huh
so I got into programming so that I
could you know pursue that dream you
know
I got Visual Basic 3 is my first
programming language which maybe not the
best one to start with because it wasn't
the greatest of languages but you know
it's okay and I got like a bunch of
books they used to sell these books like
they were a thousand pages usually or
1500 pages and they would give you a
couple examples on um programming's like
some test projects for you to make to
teach you how to do it you know like
hello world and they would get more and
more complicated so I would read through
those and and sort of learn a couple
things and then I think about I think I
bought about like ten of those books or
so so they some of them were more
advanced than others and slowly I was
learning more and more right by the time
I was nine years old I made my first
game it was a Frogger clone with pretty
much all the features like totally
implemented like the vehicles at
collision I drew all the pixel art
myself I would show you a screenshot of
it if I could run it but it's like I'm
an old computer of mine so I can't
really show you but yeah it was that
pretty good for Agra Cologne you know it
wasn't bad it would get more difficult
as he progressed through the levels and
all that kind of stuff and then I was
gonna go I think at that point I decided
you know I gotta get something better so
I upgraded to Visual Basic 6 spent like
all my money buying that it was like a
hundred bucks or something crazy I just
worked on a couple more details here I
think that's good now we're gonna go up
there and start building some stuff too
but yeah I think the next big project
like the next game I tried to make was a
Tetris clone and that did not go so well
again I was nine years old at the time
and I did not understand the concept of
a race and it's not like I could go ask
somebody for help either right
like I couldn't just go to stack
overflow whenever I had a question I had
to figure it out myself I didn't have
the Internet and I just couldn't
couldn't really make the Tetris because
I didn't understand arrays and they're
pretty important when you're doing
something like that so I gave up on that
and I think I just did a bunch of like
test projects for a while to try get
better experienced with programming
because it's like when you're learning
programming programming you usually
don't want to make like some big giant
projects you want to go a bunch of
little projects and just build up your
experience and understanding of how
things how to do things you know so I
just did a bunch of test projects for a
long time and I think it was like when I
was 13 years old I got my first online
game I played which was worms Armageddon
and worms world party and then when I
got those games it kind of ticked off my
programming experience a little bit more
because those games had a lot of like
custom files in them like you could make
your own teams in the game you could
make what were called schemes that was
it's like the game settings and stuff so
I challenged myself to try make some
editors for that game like scheme
editors team editors map editors which
meant I had to learn how to read and
write files in programming I had to
figure out how a hex editor works cuz I
had to reverse-engineer the file formats
I had the Internet
at that point that's when I got the
internet when I was 13 so I could
actually look online for help and stuff
at that point made a huge difference oh
my goodness so basically you would like
you'd load up the game you would change
one setting in the in the schemes or the
teams or whatever then you would load it
up in the hex editor and see what
changed like what byte changed in the
file and then you would know okay this
byte here this controls like the worms
Hal
this one is how much turn time you have
stuff like that right so you have to
document the whole file figure out what
does what and then you have to make an
interface for editing that yeah so for
most of the projects I did I never
really tried to like release them
publicly they were just like test
projects the game experience but I did
challenge myself a few times to make
like public releases for the the
programs I was making like try to refine
them make a nice interface and I get rid
of all the bugs and stuff for it I
thought that would be good good to learn
as well right so here's a picture of one
of the editors I released publicly like
one of the first ones I did and got
quite a bit of use actually so that was
good and I think later after I kind of
got tired of making editors I started
looking into like how to do online
programming like how to make servers and
stuff so I figured out how did you pack
it sniffing I did it first with that
worms game I was playing I I would like
watch well the incoming and outgoing
traffic of the game right and then oh I
can't see the glass it's invisible okay
there we go
so that game was based on like a
high-bred IRC client so I figured out
how IRC clients worked and I was trying
to make my own server for the game right
so I could host it myself instead of
using the official one so I eventually
was able to do that then later I think I
moved on to other games I think the next
one I did was a MMO game Survival
project some of you might have heard of
that and that's when I got into hacking
I hate to say it wasn't always always a
good guy on the internet although I
never I made sure what I did it not to
interfere with anyone else's enjoyment
of the game like I never messed up the
economy in the game but still probably
shouldn't never
done that but yeah that was also some
learning experience like I was playing
the game for a long time and it was
super grindy right super grindy
eventually got tired of grinding out
like the money in the game right people
in that game would not let you play with
them if you don't have good enough items
either so that really frustrated me like
they would just kick you out of the room
so I was like you know I'm tired of
grinding all this stuff why don't I just
try make a program to play for me so I
ended up doing that and it worked and
the game had what was called n protects
which was like to stop memory editors
from working because that's how most
people used to hack the game and then
nobody was able to do it once they
installed that but I made a hack that's
worked by like intercepting the the
packets in and out of the game again my
experience with the making the worm
servers and stuff kind of came into hand
there um yeah
anyways eventually you know I got tired
of doing that I I did get in contact
with the developers and told them how to
fix the exploit I was using and stuff
too so I tried to be good about it but
again not the thing to be doing right I
did work on this side a little bit too
by the way
uh-huh yeah so after that I did play a
few other online games but I made the
rule for myself not to hack them anymore
even though I was really tempted a few
times so I didn't do a whole lot of
programming after that just odd random
project I kind of realized at that point
like ice little older that maybe making
games wasn't gonna be the most staple of
careers either so I was mostly just
programming for fun at that point it was
funny though like people from the old
game I used to play that I hacked to it
like contact me and the new games I was
playing and is like alrighty so are you
gonna you're gonna hook me up with those
hacks when you make them I was like no
I'm not gonna do that anymore as I go
are you sure
like yeah but yeah I think what I did I
did make one program for another online
game though it wasn't a hack it was an
analytical program where I don't know if
any of you've heard of starport GE but
that's like a colony management sort of
game um and there's a bit of space
fighting and stuff in that too big part
of it is called any management though
and there's like eight or ten different
settings for the colonies like how much
food you would produce morale-boosting
mining weapon production security
pollution clearing stuff like that right
and the colonies were very finicky in
that game if you set anything a little
bit too high would exponentially like
grow out of control and kill itself if
you set it too low then your colony
would be really easy to steal so people
would just steal it from you right so I
managed to figure out the formula the
game used like the math formula for all
the different settings and then I wrote
a program that would tell me like the
perfect settings to like maximize the
population of the colony without it
having any trouble right and like in
that game what we're doing here maybe
put this over here in that game there
would be like these groups of people
with like five or ten people and their
culture in their group right and they
were just barely managing their empires
and meanwhile I was like on my own with
the bigger empires in like these five or
ten people and they were like how are
you doing this what's going on so then I
would tell them and then they would be
like oh really
well on this other server if you want to
join our group for a bit and like bounce
out our colonies for you we'll pay you
like actual like the the money in the
game that people would pay real money
for they would like trade that to me to
bounce out there their empires forum
that was kind of kind of interesting
so I did that and I played that game for
about a year or two then I think it was
like when the xbox360 came out that's
when Microsoft released the XNA
framework which any of you are familiar
with like unity or something like that
it's a it's a framework for making games
and they it was actually possible to
sell them on the Xbox Marketplace as
well so that's when I really started to
think started thinking like hey maybe I
actually can make games for a living so
I started prototyping a bunch of games
than that that was when I moved on to
c-sharp as a programming language the
main problem I had was that those I had
a lot of trouble like focusing on idea I
would I would prototype one game idea
I'd work on it for a bit and then I'd
get a new idea and I'd move on to that
and I did that a bunch of times I
couldn't finish a project oh my goodness
when has that ever happened right and
funny enough like one of my prototypes
was a twin stick shooter with like a
Zelda style to it like where you would
switch screens and you get a new wave of
enemies like at that time a lot of the
twin stick shooters would just
constantly send new enemies at you all
right I had the idea like man it would
be a lot better if you just like switch
screens and there'd be a whole bunch of
new enemies there and then you'd have
like an exploration aspect of the game
too right um almost a little bit like
binding of issac which came out two or
three years after I had that idea so
maybe if I just focused on it I could
have actually had a successful game you
know but I didn't think it was that good
of an idea at the time another game I
made that was very similar to Mario
maker as well I was like the last one I
was working on before I start youtube
and then when I started youtube I didn't
really do any programming because I
didn't have any time so that's sort of
where my programming ended uh-huh but
anyway story time with ethos over guys
you can wake up now
oh you got to finish up this episode I
might have rambled a little too long
there it's it's actually getting pretty
long so I did the rest of this off
camera just to speed it up and got
pretty much all of it done had a couple
snags here I'll show you
but let's
let's get into this over here first stop
so it feels pretty good to me again it
kind of stands out cuz it doesn't match
the theme of everything else around here
I still need to put some kind of roof
over this probably you I'll probably
just put glass above this though either
flat glass or like dome shaped glass I'm
thinking I added a window up there for
the second-story we got to add a way of
getting up to the second story and again
we can't put a staircase in really
there's not enough space so what I
decided to do I just frame this in with
some glass and stuff we got a tube here
we're gonna have a water elevator we're
gonna hold the water in place with the
pressure plate in a trapdoor here should
work
I hope I'm gonna be very sad we do not
want to wash away your redstone so dig
this out a trapdoor will hold it right
where am I wrong about that let's go
over here
yeah it's holding it okay good yeah so I
don't think us up to the second floor
here and then we'll add another one on
this side oh and you know what that
doesn't look that bad either having the
bubble streams there it's kind of a cool
effect we got glass on this side so we
can see the the water from here too so
that's cool I like that so easy to get
to the second floor here it's a little
bit awkward because again we do have
that wire running across here but I
tried to hide it as it was I could
actually let's just add this over top to
you yeah we can look down over here
through the window and the roof in this
is not complete so I didn't bother
trying to connect the top of this to it
yet that's another another step of this
I need to do now we have a way down over
here so the big trouble with this build
that I ran into is on the other side
pretty much tried to mirror it exactly
but I ran into a couple things we have
an item elevator here we can rip this
out and replace it with a bubble stream
so that's not a huge deal
this is our line where anything that
doesn't get sorted it's shot out here
and there was like an ice cream that
went through this whole thing that I
ripped out so this needs to end
somewhere else and what else did we run
into Oh up over there there's like a
gizmo that got in the way of my build so
I'll have to move that and right over
here there's wiring where I want to put
the elevator I don't know if I can get
rid of that we can do it on this side at
the very least which is good we'll add
one in here as well cool cool and again
this side needs a roof as well we made
some good progress on this pretty happy
with that
so I might also try to like put a glass
dome over the wiring here this is all
open right now
so yeah there's there's a little bit
left to do with this but we did pretty
good ooh I forgot we also have all this
stuff to deal with too we probably
should cover that up it doesn't look the
best but this is what the side of the
building looks like I don't think I
showed it actually but yeah let's get to
the comment of the day guys everybody's
worried about Coppa it says hey etho are
you worried about the copper laws that
will soon be enacted by YouTube I am
sure worried sap sad face so a little
quick introduction to this for everybody
that's not familiar Coppa basically is
is meant to protect children some people
on YouTube or posting videos targeted at
children and then they were putting like
adult content and I believe and kids
were watching that so I believe they
enacted a law in the u.s. to make that
illegal up to a forty two thousand
dollar fine I think per video even so if
you have a couple thousand videos is
like yours truly here obviously I'm a
little bit concerned because if every
single video of mine got hit with that I
would definitely be bankrupt but for
many reasons I don't think I will be
affected by this at all so for one thing
that's a US law and Canadian my videos
were made before this was enacted the
big thing though is I have set all my
videos to not targeted at children
therefore everybody 13 years or older
and if they were for some reason to
interpret my videos as for children like
I think most of them are pretty clean
like for example even when that had
apocalypse happened I know a lot of you
were concerned for me about that and I
appreciate it but not as single one of
my videos got hit in that which is
surprising because almost every other
youtuber had trouble but yeah I got away
scot-free
so think I'm okay I think I'm okay the
people that are gonna really suffer from
this is anyone that had as a child
targeted channel like anyone that was
doing like toy openings or reading
stories to kids or whatever they were
doing their videos are like not gonna
get advertised anymore on YouTube and
they're gonna basically have to quit
doing YouTube for money if like they'll
need a new job basically so yeah but for
myself I should be fine not too too
worried about it but anyways that's
gonna do it for today guys hope you
enjoyed the episode thank you for
watching hope you have yourselves a
wonderful day take care bye bye
[Music]