[Music]
greetings everybody thank you for
joining me again
this is etho and i got a lot of great
feedback
last time about the whole snowflake
project people seem to really be
enjoying it
it's not often i do artistic things in
this
in this game but it's nice every once in
a while to try
try something different and i'm glad
people
enjoyed last episode uh
looking at some of the feedback in the
comment suggestion is that i should
put snow where the leaves are and then
fill in like a circle with all the
all the transparent space with ice so
like that would be ice that would be ice
that would be ice that would be ice and
all the leaf stuff would be snow
i think that'll look really good and
then they'll give me a full platform up
there to walk around and look at
and look at the terrain so to start out
with i have some snow harvested
and we'll start laying that down i'll do
that off camera
and again we'll have to wait to 1.3 to
do the ice parts to fill in the cracks
but it sounds like 1.3 is just around
the corner like any day
maybe even by the time this episode goes
up who knows
so shouldn't have to wait too long to do
that
and also uh we might do some
some stuff around the landscape like
add some more glowing trees and maybe
plant some stuff in the mountains
a great idea i got for the desert i
didn't really know what to do with it
some people suggested i should build
some pyramids
which could be cool to have a few of
those uh
you know i've never built a pyramid in
minecraft before that's
which is it's kind of crazy because
that's like the second thing people
build
in the game first they build their
wooden house and the next thing they
build is like a pyramid
it seems like that's i remember seeing
so many videos about
people building the tallest pyramid in
the game
um possible like the full 128 and
and now there's probably videos of the
256 and
because it's such a simple thing to
build
um so we might do pyramids but a great
idea i got is to make an oasis in the
desert
and that could be cool that could be a
lot of fun
anyway i'm gonna do the snowflake i'll
get back to you in a little bit
yeah here's a good perspective of the
glowing tree numbers uh
we got quite a few here but
uh like all that back there that would
be cool if that was all glowing trees
and
and that stuff there so i'll work on
that a little bit today too but i'm just
going to go underneath
the leaf stuff here i guess i should go
maybe i'll go that far down
making myself some scaffolding
to walk on and i'm just going to go
underneath all this
and put that put snow underneath
and that should be fairly easy because
we got the shape all laid out
that was the tough part
and there it is all done so i had to put
a few torches down
to lower mob spawns it needs a few more
yet
and i don't know let me know what you
think of this
whoa whoa whoa
those are some good shoes wow oh it's
because i got protection on as well
maybe wow i can't believe i survived
that
oh it's my first time seeing it at night
with the lights
it's pretty cool now i'm
trying to record and
if i do the ice thing uh i won't put ice
in
i'll probably leave it pointed on the
edges instead of doing the circle like i
said
so i won't put ice there but i'll i'll
put it in the
in between stuff get out of here man
an interesting facts you know when i
started this world i said i wasn't going
to switch off of hard i still
have kept my word on that i always play
on hard mode
at times it can be annoying but most of
the time it's it's pretty fun
um with a few
like accidental peaceful modes like if i
just log in sometimes i forget to switch
it but usually it's always on hard
um let's go from a distance
get away from that skeleton
and go a little bit further
and then we will start decorating our
world some more
that's pretty cool it's not as eerie
looking as the leaves
and if we put more lighting there it'll
look better too
i like that a lot more at night time
though for sure you could barely see the
leaves at all
against the dark sky
although i didn't have any lights and
okay so glowing tree time
yeah this area here is very nice very
very nice
there's mountains over there too i think
when 1.3 comes out we're going to do
some more exploring
generate a few new chunks look for a new
village
and things like that
with the glowing trees i'm gonna do it
like this same way as before
to keep it consistent
go down one on all of them
thankfully i have ender pearls this time
so today well yesterday
i did something i haven't done in a very
long time
probably four months or so
i shut off my computer for about a day
half a day um
and of course when i started up guess
what i hear that
noise and
i had the same problem with my last
computer
uh the graphics card fan the bearings on
it went and it just made this terrible
terrible racket i had to keep oiling it
like every
every month it would go bad at least
and it was just so annoying and this
computer seems to be doing it too
but thankfully it stopped after a few
minutes of grinding
but i don't know if there's any any
trick to stopping that besides boiling
it
or getting a new graphics card or fan or
what
but two computers in a row it's very
annoying
but i'm glad it stopped and
yeah this place is really nice usually i
leave my computer on all the time it's
just so much more convenient
because you know i'm i'm there
then i'm gone i'm there and then i'm
gone i don't
i don't make a point of being at my
computer for six hours or something and
then
and then shutting it off and not using
it for the rest of the day it's just
like
every so often i'll be using it and then
i'll be gone
type thing
so it doesn't make much sense to to shut
it off and then overnight
is usually when i always do my uploading
oh you see that shots that was nice so
it rarely gets a rest then there's
rendering
um the computer has been doing pretty
good actually
all right so we're going to lose a few
leaves
it'll help it'll give them a little more
shape
a little bit more unique each tree
and oh no anyway i'm gonna keep going
here i might do a little montage
hey
spider come back come back spider
no don't leave me
oh okay so i did 64 trees
i would have done more but i'm a little
pressed for time today unfortunately
actually this whole weekend i don't have
much time so i'm just recording a quick
episode today
but uh i think past that waters all the
new ones and a lot of them are out of
range you can't see them
but that looks pretty good
ouch let's go
right to the top and check it out
okay
yeah that that makes it a lot nicer just
adds so much uh
variety to the land when you have the
different lighting
the different light fadings i should say
okay so i did not do that spot we'll
save that for another day
um let's go to the nether
did i bring i did bring it good just
wanted to put some of this obsidian down
on the other side
and make our begin making our nether hub
portal we're going to do the same no
we're going to do the same dealio
over here a lot of people keep telling
me to switch
my throw key because i have it set to q
sometimes i throw stuff accidentally
um i've considered it but you know what
sometimes i want to throw stuff
and it's really handy to have it there
at those times
so generally i prefer having it
easily accessible even though that
sometimes means
i throw my good stuff away but usually i
can just pick that right up again anyway
but like like sometimes if i'm
playing race for wall or for example and
i i swig wiggle potion real quick
i want to get rid of the item slot i'll
just press q and toss it
so it frees up the spot but
if you have that key far away it can be
a challenge
to press it
okay now let's see should we do the
trees
or should we well one thing i definitely
wanted to
do today is hook up the other portal to
the other base so what i'm gonna have to
do is go there get the coordinates
then go to the nether and make a portal
for it so we'll we'll do that next
okay can we make this jump
what do you think if we don't
we might survive anyway nope can't make
it
uh oh
i threw a i threw a pearl i don't think
it teleported me
all right guys here we are i do have
another portal here already
something i just put out of the way
we're going to try connect to it
and maybe in the future move it
but i built this one on this side like i
didn't build it in the nether
and it takes me to my main nether portal
which then takes me somewhere else if i
go through it again so
i think to connect to this one i need to
build the portal actually in the nether
and divide my coordinates here by eight
so we're
about negative 472.
where is that spider y
23 and zed
8 18. would you have to divide
y by eight i wonder that would be at the
bottom of the world right
no you must not have to divide y just x
and z
okay so
let's get somewhere safe i'll do the
math
and we'll figure out where we have to
put it
okay it works out that the portal should
go here negative
59 x and 102 zed
but i checked the wiki to see what it
had to say about it
and apparently i always thought that the
nether portals got linked in this game
but they don't
it's all based on their position
i guess it checks it every time and
there is a 257 by 257
by 128 box that gets
checked centered around the player for a
portal
and whatever portal is closest to that
is the one
that gets chosen
yeah i always forget to bring a bow
um so that works out
to being an eight block leeway
in the nether i have because
every block in that nether counts is
eight in the overworld
he's so annoying so
i can put it over
where were we 59 102
i could move up to eight blocks this way
or this way or this way the y doesn't
matter
so if i put it here it should work from
what i understand anyway
not something i'll have a lot of
experience with don't make nether
portals all that often
unfortunately if i do this though i'd
kind of lose my shortcut i've been using
okay so this should take me to
my other base
try it out see if everything is right
here
we may move it once we do the hub
perfect okay that that's it very simple
and now in the future i'll understand
how they work and i can use them
a lot better um
and maybe one last thing we'll do before
we end this episode i'm sorry it's a
short one
i figured it was better to have a a
quick one than than none for
many days you know well not many days
but for a few days
i wanted to check out over here we used
to
this is where the original blaze farm
was and i know we had a bunch of stuff
around i'm wondering
if we left anything good behind
it's been a long long time since i've
been here
i'm sure i've left i know i had at least
a double chest here
of stuff yeah there it is
oh maybe i looted it already oh no
we got some stuff nothing
i'll take the gas tears this is the
original blaze farm
for all you newcomers you might not have
seen this
and is there any chests below here
i don't think so okay
yeah i'm pretty sure this still works
too oh yeah and we had another ward farm
here i
totally forgot about that just a small
one this is when we were doing those
tests
okay well that's it for today guys i'll
try to get back to schedule by monday
i'll be free again
and in between i might try to do a
minecraft episode or something
but thanks for watching today and i'll
see you again next time
you