[Music]
hello
everybody welcome let's try this one
more time
i recorded this intro already but i had
my mic muted
i hate when i do that all right so
i think i got this mostly all done now
this uh
slime go around type thing
uh you got one trapped here you can test
this
i've been having trouble with the slime
sending two carts
when they get picked up i don't know why
it's doing it uh
i tweaked this a little bit hopefully it
doesn't happen again
i tried riding it myself and only one
cart was sent like it should
but maybe something weird is happening
with the slimes i don't know about
so let's uh let's give it a
whoop dang undo undo
there we go here we go
okay i think that was only one charts
yes it was only one chart
that was very weird why i don't
understand why it wasn't working before
so before i had the
reset hooked up to this detector rail
and now i just added another one over
here
and i'm using that instead
but i don't understand why
that one would have been the problem
it's almost like this no i'm not even
gonna
i'm not even gonna jump to conclusions
because i know i'm going to be wrong
about it but anyway it seems to work now
this has gotten slightly more
complicated now
but it should be all fully automatic now
where is our slime i got this opened up
because i had a few
cards get stuck while testing this there
he comes
this is my new lazy junction here you
see that switches and then switches back
that is to pick up empty mine carts they
go over this
over this detector rail here
and that powers this redstone
goes to
there's a redstone torch back there by
the way um
that goes to this junction
and since the carts go faster if there's
a slime in it they
speed by before it switches back but if
it's empty
they go to the right there and up our
little uh
collector units but this is
oh no it's not full because we have
slime on the track i thought
i thought the pez was full here so it
holds six
we got one on the track though so we
better get rid of that or we will have
issues
um hold six i don't think we'll ever get
more than six big slimes
with this thing and
there's also a safety mechanism i have
hooked up so
let's just trigger an empty cart
they go down here goes over and now that
went to the left there
so there's another lazy empty cart
detector here
where it will uh
switch it if the cart is going slow
right there
but uh wait i need a cart i need a cart
but yeah it seems to be working fully
automatic now i'm
happy this was a
project i've been wanting to complete
for a long time and i
think we finally can close everything up
and say it's done
all right what was i gonna do i need a
cart for something
oh yeah i was gonna demonstrate so
that that switch is there if i'm in the
cart
or slime is it did not work for some
reason
let's try that again it does work
trust me
all right let's just power this off so
we can get in
properly there we go
so this is what the slime see when
they're riding
the carts goes all the way around the
tree farm
um and i think
if they despawn the carts will keep
going if i log out
log in i think they stay in the carts
because i think it's only if the carts
aren't moving that mobs will hop out of
them
if i'm remember correctly
oh yeah so that's the course
and that is the project i think it's
done it's going to do a couple cosmetic
things here yet
with this netherrack it doesn't i don't
think it'll look quite right
with this uh stone here
it's not symmetrical i'm gonna try
change that a little bit and put
a line of netherrack here on both sides
and see if that looks better
and then we'll go do something else
hmm
i would have to put one there too i
think and that would
no that's not gonna work
no i'm going to switch it back to the
stone
all right we got another big slime there
coming up we can test this one more time
but i think it is working just the way
it's supposed to
let's see because i had that big slime
on the track
and one two three four five
oh maybe it's not working
there should be six cards we're missing
one
it might when the slime despawned the
cart might have got stuck
on the track
i've never seen it from this side before
let's see if he gets stuck
anywhere
i just want to know it's working so i
can
comfortably cover everything up
otherwise i might have to remove the
ground again
and he's still going
i don't know if he hit anything
all right so it seems to be okay let's
check how many carts are there one more
time
if there's still five we might have a
problem
because there should be four if he's on
the track
okay good four it is
there he goes
oh is there two one
hmm all right well i'm confused again
i'll i'll just have to watch it for a
while i suppose
before we know it's safe to cover up
but let's go do something else i think
we're gonna go back to the silverfish
farm and work on that a little bit today
aha you know what this guy here he
decides to teleport to me even though i
had him sitting
and that is why i usually don't keep
wolves in this game they act really
weird and do things they shouldn't do
isn't that's right and his head
there we go i thought his head was
broken for a sec
uh this is a silverfish farm
and this has been full for a few days
now and i've been very tempted to
kill all the silverfish but i want to do
it on camera the first time
so we're going to try to set up some
sort of killing system
just see how it works first of all uh
to get rid of the top two layers we need
to hit some silver fish up high here
though so i'm gonna try just have a
little pit like this
actually that's not gonna work is it
we'll have to line it at least half a
block up
so they can't jump out because if you
break that
oh damn i'm stuck
if you were to break one of these they
could jump on another one and jump on
glass and get out but if we have the
half slabs they won't
be able to get out i don't think and
we'll just see how that goes and then
for down below
i think the snow golems will take care
of a lot of the work for us
um
what i'm thinking we'll do actually is
have
like a two wide opening here so let's
find the center of the room
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
one two three four five six seven
and there that's the center
so we will have them fall in a pit
of some sort
and maybe i'll just put glass here see
how it looks
for right now anyway
so we can observe the silver fish from
outside oh
oh i can't believe i'm going to do this
don't look guys i'm using a pick on soil
i'm sorry but
i do not have another one around another
shovel that
is
all right um
yeah i feel like good not using a shovel
this is weird
just kidding just kidding uh
we'll have a two drop hole i brought
some dispensers with me
we're gonna put poison in those
oh oh the humanity
actually yeah we just need to drop
two block drop and i did not think about
that
we'll have to make it come out one more
block i guess
do it here
don't want any stone exposed and we'll
probably put our dispensers oh
right there that was close
dude i thought i had this place safe
huh well yeah so uh
i got minecraft on xbox 360 the other
day and
played it a little bit i didn't have a
whole lot of time to play but
it was it was pretty cool uh pause even
came
on into my world and played with me
little bits one of the first things i
did of course is i made a boat
and that handled really well i was happy
with how that felt
in the game uh the controls were a lot
like
the script i made which i kind of
suspected
oh
so kind of proud of myself that i picked
good controls
originally with the this
the script i made to use your xbox
controller
to play minecraft on the pc
if you don't know what i'm talking about
uh as much the same
and okay we'll put one poison potion in
this is just a quick little test quick
little setup
uh we we found a dungeon
and it was a pig spawner oddly enough
and we even went to the nether
the nether in the 360 version this this
is one of the sad things about
the 360 version the world is not
infinite it's uh
infinite is that the right way to sing
it finn it
ah so it's a fixed sized world
and in the nether there's a bedrock wall
that prevents you from going
too far in the regular world there
is just an invisible border if you try
to walk into it it stops you
which is really sad because that's one
of the best things about minecraft the
worlds are infinite
of course if kurt j
matt did a far lands or bust on the 360
version he would be done
in probably a day one episode
because the worlds are fairly small i
think they're
a thousand by a thousand if i remember
right
which is okay uh i had a lot of fun it
was very nostalgic to play
1.6 version
and what are we going to do here
well we're not going to do anything too
fancy we're just setting this up as an
experiment see how it works
and we will tweak it later i'll leave
this open because i'm going to throw a
damaged potion in from
above
and yeah i i probably won't play the 360
version very much so but it
it is cool to to try it out anyway
and it's got some good features to it um
i think we're gonna go here i think
we're gonna do it
let's see how this works so
get some silverfish going
and all chaos breaks loose
oh i knew they were gonna come they came
from over there
and i can't reach darn okay so we
already have problems
the other option is to somehow get a
snowman up at this top layers
to deal with these guys
things if the silverfish only get hit
from below
there won't be the top two layers won't
get destroyed
this is gonna get really laggy pretty
sure
that looks really cool
what is going on
it's like the blocks aren't breaking
below them
where they coming from
this might actually work because they're
all staying up here i thought they would
have fallen by now
oh that would have sucked
they're all gonna fall at once
you know how many that is you hear the
snow golems below hitting them
although that actually escaping anywhere
is
a big concern
i think the top layer got shaved off
and nothing below i think we're breaking
them faster than the snow golems
i can't hit anymore
one yeah just about the full
top two layers is gone which is what we
want
ah if only i could hit them a few more
times
that's really really interesting looking
all right i'm gonna go down below
although i can't go in that room i got
it closed off now
oh oh no
there's a leak dance
they're falling through the pistons
aren't they
i just almost walked in how are they
getting
they are all over the place those snow
golems are taking too long
and they're not jumping even they're
just
okay uh here's here's an idea
i need another
poison potion where do i have one
i wonder if uh
because poison keeps doing damage to
them if every time they take damage from
it
if another more silver fish will spawn
i hit myself i don't seem poisoned at
all
ah
what the heck i'm gonna die
this is good we're learning things this
is not a total bust
don't die don't die don't die don't die
i think we're all right
but yeah there's definitely a leak
somewhere
[Music]
now they're not breaking out of the
block so i don't think it's causing
doesn't count as a hit i don't think
the damage potions do though
all right let's go see what happened
down here
oh yeah we got problems we got problems
oh no no
[Music]
oh this is bad this is really bad
i just made a hole right in the room
somehow
i can't get out of here
oh boy yeah we got work to do with this
thing
i think they're all out of the room
well there's quite a few in there
actually
this is the problem this isn't sealed
over here so they all just poured down
aha
all right well for next time
i will probably be able to get this
working better
i'm going to kill all this the
stragglers and
and clean up the mess here
yeah this just keeps getting more and
more strange i ender pearled into this
room
and these snow golems aren't doing
anything
for some reason and some of them have
their glass blocked down so i'm guessing
the silverfish got into the wiring and
messed everything up but i don't know
why these guys
decide to quit their job or something i
don't know
uh i'm gonna make the rest of these fall
down just by
oh now they start shooting
huh well for a second anyway
yeah so it seems to spawn the silver
fish
out of the blocks horizontally first and
then
it goes up one layer when there's no
more on the bottom layer
type thing and same with
from top down
bottom up top down
they're not really attacking me when i'm
in the room
but yeah we'll definitely set up
something a lot more professional than
this
this is just a funsy and to experiment
with them
now we have quite a few new things just
from this
has a lot of silver fish and there's a
bunch in that
room holding area a bunch died
a bunch got free
[Music]
oh no wow
i think i'm gonna go into that room
pretty soon here
whoa it came pouring down
i've never seen this many silverfish
games getting really laggy
i don't know if you can handle a full
room of them
for 12 frames per second
and there's still a lot left up there so
[Music]
it's not looking good
wow okay i'll have to stop it there i
think
it looks like there's two layers left
even
oh no we all lava pouring everywhere
what's going on out there
[Music]
let me out oh
okay i gotta recover
dang man oh dead
[Music]
yeah oh my stuff it's probably gonna get
launched in the lava somehow
dang these guys they're just
bad news burning lava
that was a fail there i didn't want that
to happen
all my all my levers got destroyed again
for the lights oh man
it's all my stuff look at this
wow
what a mess
and they're probably everywhere outside
here
well anyway that was fun at the very
least
there's lava everywhere though it's a
big problem
i bet you the room's gonna catch on fire
too okay i gotta
i gotta kill these guys and deal with
the lava
before things catch on fire
if i can get out of here
whew crisis inverted that was uh that
was pretty scary actually there was lava
all over the place
but i think this is the only real damage
here one block missing
and i got a lot of repairs to do on this
room now and everything around
because it's just a mess like i'm just
gonna
get rid of all these blocks make it
hollow underneath and
rebuild it out of something other than
stone so it never happens again
i'm gonna have to seal up all the leaks
before we attempt this again
and set up a better killing chamber
what happened is since i built this out
of wood i think it caught on fire
and that's how they leaked out of
there and
well that's how that got destroyed
anyway
uh but them leaking out before they got
in the stone over there
broke the blocks and then lava started
spilling everywhere
but no harm done i got my items back
mostly i
think the only thing i noticed missing
is my stake
but i did get this back which is what i
was really worried about most my other
tools are just about worn out
and yeah it's good learning experience
very important for figuring this out and
learning the hard way that's what i'm
all about so
i think i will call it an end for today
i was going to say one more thing about
the xbox
version of the game there was one thing
that
i really didn't like about it and paws
didn't like about it
i hope they fix it it's the lighting in
it they
seem to have had to use a different
lighting engine
and it is a lot darker like you place
down a torch
and it's still gray and i know like in
1.6 it was using a different lighting
lighting system than what we're using
now but even still like compared to how
it used to be it's not
quite right because i think it's on a
different platform they had to do it
differently
and it needs to be a lot lot brighter
but other than that it's it's pretty
cool worth checking out
especially if you missed old minecraft i
think there was pistons in 1.6 if i
remember right so
there's there's a bit of stuff you can
do and it it's a lot harder to
uh if you make a world on hard anyway
it's very tough to stay alive
all right well i'm gonna go thanks for
watching
take care bye bye