[Music]
hey hello welcome back everybody to
another episode of the let's play series
and yes we are starting off
the same place we were last episode
still working on the shocker box farm
it's getting close though i think uh so
at the very end the last one we kind of
saw it working
and
it worked kind of but it was a very slow
so i decided to add more layers onto the
shulker box farm here instead of just
having one we're gonna go with four
and i'm in the middle of building those
up right now we also talked about the
idea of having a potion system to heal
the shulker
and i worked on that it was a disaster
well actually it's it's kind of weird
it's a huge success and also a colossal
failure at the same time what do i mean
by that well we're gonna have to go
check it out all right everybody let's
go check out the battle be no just
kidding
so uh this is my world list and i'm just
showing you this so you're not confused
basically over the years what i i've
done is i've created copies of my let's
play world and i use those as creative
worlds until they get cluttered or
outdated
and then
this is our real world over here this is
uh my current creative world
so here is where i've been messing
around with designing different auto
brewers for that shocker box farm
because we need something to heal up the
shockers so it doesn't die on us and
it's got to be a pretty fast auto brewer
like more than one brewing stand is
needed probably like four or five uh to
keep up with the rate we were gonna need
to heal that shulker so i've just been
messing around and i came up with
something pretty interesting over here
which i thought we were gonna use
spoiler it doesn't work
it does but it doesn't uh and we're
gonna see why but otherwise i would just
show you in our let's play world how
this works we're not gonna be building
this
uh but yeah basically it's an auto
brewer
that doesn't use any redstone really
it's uh it uses minecarts and water
streams to do all the complex stuff
which is i think pretty cool now the way
this works is in this updates
rails can go underwater but they can
also hold water back which allows us to
do some pretty new and interesting stuff
with the mine carts so as it goes by
here picks up the water bottles
goes up a bubble column
over top here and normally when it goes
over a hopper like on a rail
it'll only drop off one item but if it
goes over slowly like with the water
stream then it can drop off all three
and then we use water streams to time
the length it takes for the brew to
happen and mine carts move slower over
soul sand as well
so i i got a couple extra seconds that
way
and as soon as the brew finishes the
minecart passes underneath the brew
stand picks up the potions
and then it's a chaining system so then
it breaks it over here the awkward
potions
and it's gonna add melons to make an
instant healing
again it's going around the loop i found
a pattern here that's pretty compact
so i could squeeze a bunch of brewing
stands together
and again it's gonna go right underneath
that broom stand pick up the potions and
all in all
it works just fine actually with one or
two minecarts anyways so the real
problem comes in when we add more than
that the whole idea with the system was
to make a fast brewer
so i was trying to get it to work with
like four or five going around the loop
just space them properly build it all
within one chunk
everything should be fine right
well what ends up happening is kind of
weird
it's a little bit of a lesser known game
mechanic basically the more hopper
minecarts you have like in a single area
i think it it calculates it by a chunk
then uh
oh yeah of course it's working fine now
that i'm trying to show people
uh what will happen is it'll start like
not picking up the potions that might
only pick up two instead of all three it
might only god this one's messed up see
this there's only got one potion in here
or it might only drop off to over here
instead of all three like it's supposed
to
um and the reason is because mine curt
hopper mine carts share the amount of
items they can pick up between each
other so the more hopper minecarts in a
chunk
the less each one can do and when it
comes to high precision things like this
that means every once in a while it's
going to skip dropping off a potion or
picking one up and the whole thing
gets out of sync and the end result of
that is not only does it slow down
brewing and waste brewing ingredients
but also the final results sometimes you
end up with awkward potions in here
we're trying to brew instant twos
sometimes they will be missing the
glowstone or whatever and you'll just
get regular instant health or some won't
have the gunpowder aha yeah so the long
story shorts i wasted like two or three
hours building that
i was kind of sad it didn't work but i
thought it was pretty cool so i wanted
to show it off anyway uh but i did learn
a couple things from that so like i
always assumed the hopper sharing like i
knew about it as i was building that and
i thought it would be fine because i
assumed
it was only true when the hopper
minecarts were actually moving items
around but even if they're empty it
seems they will
share
the amount of items they can move with
each other which is news to me i didn't
know about that which is what broke it
so that's good to know and the lesson
also if you're trying to use them for
doing anything with precision
probably not a good idea if you're just
picking up a bunch of items like in a
mob farm it's fine but anytime you need
to precisely move items around
probably not a good idea to have more
than one minecart
doing the job well it looks like we
might have a bit of a reoccurring theme
today so this is quite a bit later
and i got the four layers built on this
farm right and i've been testing it out
and
well
disaster
oh man so my assumption was if we add
more layers to this
this guy
would have more places to duplicate to
and it would be less likely his
duplication will fail and when he
duplicates he gets healed up to full as
well which means it's more likely more
duplications will happen
less likely he'll want to teleport out
of there
and it the farm should get exponentially
better the more space
he has to teleport to the problem is it
seems like four layers isn't enough
space it still fails quite a bit
like it takes three or four shots
on average maybe for him to actually
duplicate to one of those places and it
only takes him like two shots
to get down to half health and then want
to teleport out of there and now we've
given him so much more space to teleport
to
that uh he's out of there
like right away he doesn't stick around
he's gone
uh so
that's an issue
and i've tried spam spamming him with
healing potions and it just can't keep
up he damages himself so quickly that no
it's not going to work and if we try to
add like a
replacement system where when the shulk
box disappears that we put a new one in
there it's just going to take too long i
think for the farm to run
at a decent rate even because every time
we replace this guy
if he teleports out of there the
snowglobe's gotta require target we
gotta detect when he leaves and get a
new one to
get carted over or whatever and this is
not gonna be very good
so
you guys might not like me for this but
i'm going to be building a new shocker
box farm
the other option is we tear down all
this stuff and add like 8 or 12 layers
to the thing and then it might work but
the problem is there's also the chance
it might fail again and we're back to
square one uh which i don't want to take
the risk on also there was some issues
where the snowglobe might randomly die i
never figured out why that was and i did
see
the minecarts break on me from the
choker box collection system so there's
like a lot of little problems with that
farm too
um and while i was building it i came up
with a new idea that i'm way more
excited about and i've
after that one failed i decided to test
it out the new idea and it works way
better now the main downside to building
a new shulker box farm is we have to get
brand new materials for it uh but
thankfully it's mostly just glass and
sandstone we're gonna be building out of
i grabbed some rails so we can cart a
shocker over to our main island area
i found one
just uh 2 000 blocks away there's a
leftover one in one of my fortresses
so i think it's worth just bringing it
back here actually
and we got to get started
off the main island here we're going to
go way down to the bottom of the world
and then we're gonna build way up to the
top of the world it's gonna be a huge
giant skinny farm is the plan
and
i think this is the best way of uh
starting out right i don't know
usually i just use a water bucket and
then like propel down
and build off of the island down and
just try to keep an eye i don't go past
zero
i've done it before but thankfully we
got the rockets now before you use that
like bow boost your way if you fell into
the void
that was uh that was scary
all right careful five four three
two
one we do one more
wait we can do two more
oh i can do another one
yes got it okay so that's the very
bottom of the world
awesome i'm gonna build off away from
our island now and it doesn't really
matter too much where we put this i just
want to be far enough away that the
dragon has like zero chance of ever
running into it uh-huh yeah okay so i
think the plan here is i'm gonna blitz
through building most of this farm it's
actually fairly simple except for the
bottom and the top of the farm this is
the bottom here so i'm going to show you
that before i cover over everything
and uh
you guys are probably sick of me
building shulker farms though
so i don't want to spend too much time
on this
but at the same time i really need
shocker shells like i need them i need
them guys they're such a big game
changer
uh i can't live without them now so
yeah let's get this actually working
now
the whole point of all this down here is
to bounce between the magma
block and the soul sand there's going to
be a bubble column in the center of the
farm that's either going to be
pushing us up with the soul sand or
pulling us down with magma
and the soul sand pushes you up faster
than the magma pulls you down so you
don't want the soul sound here as long
so we have two different timings for one
for the magma one for the soul sand and
the soul sand will be shorter
this is a sticky piston here
and this is a sticky piston here that's
regular that's regular and the other
thing to keep in mind whenever you're
building a shulker farm is shockers are
jerks they like to teleport everywhere
you don't want them to so i gotta make
sure every single surface is covered
here so that they can't teleport into my
redstone and mess up the rates of my
farms
okay on to the next layer here we're
gonna go a block and a half up on the
second glass block and then four blocks
out all around this thing and we end up
with something like this so again one
two three four
and the whole point of this layer is
we're gonna have a water cascading
system in this farm and this layer is
gonna catch that water and make sure it
doesn't pour down and wash away our
redstone we're gonna have a rim all
around the edge to catch the water i'm
gonna add a bunch of sea lanterns down
here as well just to light up the base
here make it look nice
and at this level is also where our item
collection system goes so all the
shocker shells are gonna end up in this
chest
and we gotta get set up some hoppers to
catch the shells as they fall down
and we kind of just do a ziggy ziggy's
id pattern like this awesome all right
so that's the bottom of the farm done
that's the trickiest part now we move on
to the body of the farm which is gonna
take the most time it's the biggest part
but thankfully it's an easy pattern so
basically this is it right here
and we have panes on the four four edges
and we just gotta build the glass up
basically it's pretty simple then in the
very center we also have four panes
like this
now the idea here is we're going to be
standing in the middle of farm and the
shulkers
will be here here here here here here
here here here here okay so there's 12
spots all around us they can occupy
and the reason for these pains is they
allow the shunkers to still see us they
don't block their vision of us
but they block the bullets so the
bullets will try to shoot
through the middle at us and we'll kind
of all funnel towards the middle
and
a shocker cannot
attach to the surface here because the
pain is in the way if they try to do
that so they can't open up this way they
have to
attach to this surface if they're over
here
and they open up towards the middle
which is where all the bullets are going
to funnel funnel down and there's gonna
be a high probability
that they'll get shot by the bullets
that way
that's the whole thing with this farm
it's kind of like a nuclear reactor
we gotta increase the probability of a
chain reaction going off and make sure
there's enough probability for them to
duplicate and not just fizzle out the
reaction
um
and what i found when i was testing this
is originally i had water on the outside
of this farm to stop them from
teleporting out here
but with just the 12 spots on each layer
on the inside of the reactor
it is not enough for the reaction to
continue
uh they actually need more
places they can duplicate to otherwise
the duplication doesn't happen often
enough and now basically i get to shut
my brain off and i get to build and go
put on a youtube video what's old doc up
to on the hermitcraft server this is the
time i catch up on my videos guys when
i'm doing stuff like this
uh also you know a lot of times when i'm
doing things like this i might need to
add lighting every once in a while just
to make it look a bit nicer and i don't
really like to count
so what i'll do is uh oh i went too far
actually
there's a trick to shut off your brain
and still like get the right placements
i just do every 10 blocks i'm at 30 now
put one over here
i just got to remember to check every
once in a while
but i don't have to count like oh one
block up two blocks up three blocks up i
just know by looking at the y
coordinates all right everybody check it
out we got our built up here all the way
to the top of the world pretty much
we're at 2 45 right now
and i did not need to go this tall with
it like even at half the size it works
just fine but i think it gets slightly
more efficient the taller it is and also
slightly less likely the reaction will
fizzle out so i went the full deal here
because each layer is only 20 blocks to
build so it actually goes pretty quick
also
anyways we're at the top now comes the
next next complicated part i'm going to
start putting down some slabs here again
so they don't attach underneath these
okay so the only thing we really got to
do with this top layer is add a water
flooding system for the outside of our
reactor for all the shulkers that
teleport outside
this will launch them back inside
but we got to keep the outside clean so
that they'll have that extra space to
duplicate too and again we're going to
do upside down slabs here to hold the
water in place so it doesn't spread all
over the place because what happens with
water
if it spreads and like joins together
with each other then
it takes much longer for it to disappear
and i think it also causes a lot more
lag on the game so you kind of just want
single columns of water flowing down the
side here and not really merging
together and constantly updating on the
way down so we got 16 dispensers here
and we gotta power each and every one of
them with redstone and i think the most
easy and efficient way of doing that is
just have a redstone dust
like that all around
and this if we put a block here
it'll power three of them
from that redstone dust if we put one
here it'll power that one but we don't
want to put another one here because
then it will get double powered it'll
get powered from that dust here and that
one there um so instead i'm gonna put a
glass block here each side we only need
to power four of them
and same deal glass block there glass
block there glass block there just keep
that pattern going
uh-huh okay so we gotta attach these
four redstone dust together but we can't
just attach them in the middle here
because that's where our water column is
gonna go so instead i'm gonna put some
observers facing down towards the
redstone
and i guess blocks here
underneath
so that'll power through the block the
redstone dust and then we can attach
them together just like this
oh but we're not done with it yet no no
no
we still need to regularly activate the
dispensers with some kind of clock we
also need to fire them twice once to
shoot the water out wants to pick it
back up
and
it's gonna get a little bit complicated
here so my plan is to
the water column's gonna be right here
right
whenever that switches between the soul
sand and the magma block it's gonna
update and this will detect it so it's
gonna steal the clock from all the way
at the bottom of the world there
and take that clock
and bring it up here okay
does that make sense yes it does of
course it does okay then what we do
is
take that signal
we're going to send it this way and this
part is pretty hard to explain but
basically there is a lot of finicky
timings involved with when we want the
wave of water to be released and also
like how the dispensers get activated
they're pretty picky and the observers
complicate that even more and uh
i i don't need to explain it all i hope
just uh
yeah this is what we're gonna do here so
i think i want a repeater here
and then we go this way and then we
gotta lengthen the signal again
for reasons
that are hard to explain
i think we want a block here and a block
here
and a repeater here at two this one's at
four i believe
there so the signal got sent here and
then again it gets extended by another
two ticks with this
now all we gotta do is get the water
column in and kind of just finish
putting this up and making sure
everything's spawn proof that kind of
stuff so i oh i want to sneak one in
over here i'm gonna build this up
and then maybe we'll put some slabs at
the top layer here
cool we got a water bucket and all the
dispensers and now we're free to cover
over all of this so that no shockers
will will teleport here just put a slab
over top everything
oh snappers okay so i think this is
actually the last thing we need to do
and we gotta go get a shoulder uh but
we're about done with this so we're
gonna add a water source here
this is gonna flow down all the way to
the bottom
and we gotta turn these all into water
sources actually so
oh that was a bad throw
oh i shouldn't do that
good thing i got my elytra wings
oh i had a bit of a
scare there for a second how you guys
doing
things are pretty good with me
that's right
just uh it's killing time here
is it coming down yet here we go
oh you can see the water on the outside
too coming down awesome that's working
and then it gets caught over there
doesn't flow over the edge or anything
and disappears
okay so what we're gonna do we're gonna
plant the kelp i brought a bunch of bone
meal here and we're just gonna grow that
up
all the way to the top and that's gonna
turn it all into water source blocks and
then we break it
oh my ender pro finally landed
okay so now we're testing out the
timings on those hopper clocks we
installed the bottom we want this to
take us just about to the very bottom
but we don't want to actually hit that
magma block
like we just did oh it was close though
it was really close
okay the magma one had 65 in let's take
that to 63
and the soul sand careful not to fall
uh we'll just take two out of there as
well oh give me one more
joint okay there we go
okay
hi there
i don't like you and you don't like me
but we're gonna be spending some time
together you see
and i would really appreciate some
cooperation
this should grab them yeah okay good
okay everybody so this is the part of
the project i've really been dreading we
gotta get a shocker all the way back to
our main end island which is two
thousand blocks that way now i've been
trying to decide if i should do a flying
machine or rails and i think i'm gonna
go with rails
just because it'll probably take longer
but it'll for sure be safer
okay
um
and that safer sounds better to me and
if for some reason he dies
we'll still have the rail here and if we
go a thousand blocks that way there's
another fortress loaded up with chalkers
we can grab another one
oh that does not work oh snappers all
right we got her done it goes all the
way to our new farm we just gotta move
this guy now uh i think it took about 40
minutes or so a little bit of time but
it wasn't too bad
what am i doing here i have no idea how
i left them now it's been a while
all right i think we got to get rails oh
it connected yeah okay
[Music]
i don't want him to see me
i'm very shy
you know
will this work
there he goes
okay here we go everybody we're coming
up to the farm so i left an activator
rail at the very end of the track and
i'm hoping he just ejects and sticks to
the glass there
he did
is he on the inside or the outside i
think he's on the inside if he's on the
outside the water should wash him inside
anyway
yeah he's on the inside okay that's
perfect that is perfect
we got our first guy in there he's our
seed
hey buddy thank you for cooperating you
were good
uh so now i'm gonna remove some of this
just so he doesn't teleport back to this
oh man okay so i'm pretty nervous about
this a lot is riding on this little guy
i think the odds are in our favor of it
working
but if he doesn't duplicate and kills
himself i'm going to be very sad i'm not
going to take a chance i'm going to heal
him just manually as we go by here
if i can
anyways
the idea is he's going to open up as we
get close to him here he's going to
shoot
and hopefully shoot himself
all right and give him one of those
the regen
yeah he got i saw the sparkles
and
at the start of this farm it's not
really going to do much because like we
got to pass by them and every time
there's a chance he might duplicate
but there's supposed to be like hundreds
of guys in here so most of the time as
we're riding this we're just wasting
time um as we're first starting out the
farm but once it's going once uh
the reaction is going
it'll be awesome there's a bullet biome
there let's see if this will get them
and oh it closed
and
i think you duplicated
oh i couldn't quite see i think you
might have there oh yeah there is two oh
sweet
i'm gonna give them a heal anyways oh i
missed
yeah that guy got hit he might had have
duplicated i didn't see
oh that's good
all right so i think we got three or
four guys in there now so it's probably
safe we probably don't need to heal them
anymore
oh they're duplicating okay good good
there's like four or five now every time
i pass by here it's gonna
create more some of them are gonna start
dying now though i think as well
uh basically they die just by shooting
each other cool cool all right so i
stepped out of the farm for a second
just to show you how it's looking from
the outside and i don't think i've shown
the water thing too well just yet but
basically it starts from the top and
flows all the way down
and any shulkers it passes on the way
they are forced to teleport that helps
to scatter them
and it also helps to get them back
inside so that they can take part of the
reaction uh if they're needed if they're
not needed then they'll just die and get
the shells from them right um so the one
thing is it takes a very long time for
them to scatter to the two extreme ends
we still we only put one in the middle
and it's starting to get dense in the
middle like there's a lot of guys here
now but it's taking a long time for them
to spread
eventually the whole tubal gets filled
up though i think
um but this is about as dense as they
get before they start killing themselves
now to be honest with you i have no idea
what the rates are on this farm i
haven't really figured that out yet but
we got 24 so far just in kickstarting it
for a few minutes i'm guessing it's
probably gonna be a few stacks an hour
though um but we'll have to wait and see
i'm gonna be uh doing something here
just kind of this experiment
uh so from here
i'm gonna count one two three four five
six seven eight
and then here we're gonna set up some
trap doors three of them i think
this is gonna go all the way up to the
sky
now the reason for this is a little hard
to explain but basically they're going
to be like this right
these are this this is the only surface
this front part that the chalkers can
teleport to they can't teleport to the
sides of the trapdoors or the back of it
just this front part and it's outside of
the range
of the shulkers to teleport to when they
are inside the reactor but when they're
on the outside here they can either
teleport inside the reactor or onto the
trap doors there and those are gonna act
as sort of like a backup emergency in
case something goes wrong
but also they might work as an overdrive
system where we can flood the trap doors
and they'll send like hundreds of
shulkers inside yeah i gotta say shocker
farms are actually pretty complicated
there's a lot of like
careful maneuvering you need to do with
them they're very prone to problems
uh but the idea with this the
duplications only happen inside the
reactor there
and every shocker within eight blocks of
a duplication happening
lowers the chance by 20
so
when it's densely packed like that
duplications happen rarely it's not good
so what we're trying to do with this
inside the reactor when a duplication
happens
the full health guy stays inside the
reactor and the guy that got hit
teleports on the outside
of the reactor or he might teleport
inside as well
if he's on the outside ideally we want
to get rid of him
because he's low health
he's unlikely to duplicate again
so we're trying to send them to these
trap door outer rings
and because it's a double hop he hops
once from inside to the outside ring and
then from the outside ring to the trap
door
it's far enough away on these trap doors
that it has no interference on the
duplication rates inside the reactor
so we're going to store as many as we
want on these trapdoors
and then since they're all kind of low
health guys
once we get a bunch of them
we can just send a water
uh fall down it'll wash them all off
onto the outside of the ring
and then that waterfall will wash them
onto the inside most likely
so
then we're gonna have a massacre
is the basic idea with all the low
health guys
is how i foresee it working i haven't
tried it yet but that's my plan
anyways i don't think we're gonna see
anything like that happening today
though i gotta run the farm for quite a
while before something like that happens
but we did get all the trap doors in and
i think i'm gonna go inside there and
just run it for a while and just make
sure they're actually teleporting onto
the trap doors and then we'll probably
have to wrap up for today and before we
wrap up here maybe i'll mention a few
more details about how this farm works
so if you're wondering why we're not
getting shot
it's because
like there's nothing blocking the boats
from hitting us but we're just moving so
fast through this that they can't really
catch up to us
which so they just kind of follow the
sides here which works out pretty
awesome uh also
it works better on the downward than the
upward the upward works a little bit
like they'll still hit each other a few
times but we go by a little too quickly
that way
but we have to get back up to the top
somehow so i figured let's just do it
inside the farm
and you'll notice like the bullets kind
of hang around for quite a while
so they can kind of like build up and
then like shock on these guys and create
a bunch of duplications at once
sometimes
which is cool the other thing you'll
notice is we're losing food because
we're traveling so far here where i
think it counts as swimming maybe and
swimming takes up hunger
so eventually we'll run out of food if
we can this and then we're in trouble
right well we can also set up a regen
beacon and that counteracts the food
loss penalty so we can be starving and
not lose health that way oh snappers
okay so we ran up and down like five
times or so and it looks like two guys
oh we got three now
sticking to this thing so it is working
that's pretty cool
and again we're not really
uh covering the full length of the tube
just yet
but
i don't know if i should just manually
move a couple guys around so that they
they reach both ends or i should just
ride it out and let's see if it'll
happen
uh
but yeah it's working
it's working and at the very top here
you can see i set up some dispensers
with water buckets in and they can flood
uh the whole thing whenever we want to
but yeah unfortunately guys it is that
time again where we wrap up our episode
with the comment of the day which says
hey etho
do you ever spend time in your single
player world just for fun to relax
now this is a great question so i got a
bit of a story about this
now a few years ago
i kind of got into the habit of joy my
world's press record joy my world press
record
get an idea in creative press record
you know like just like
pump out the episodes right
uh and i found i was starting to not
really enjoy the game as much and i kind
of got burnt out a bit and you know what
it was
oh this guy ain't good
wait is this riptide you know let's
let's just walk away from him we don't
need to fight
only bad things can happen
um what i found out is that i gotta just
spend time playing in my world you know
i like to just grind resources off
camera and like put on a video or
something as i'm doing it is really
chill and relaxing and usually that's
when i get all my ideas actually is this
when i'm not really
forcing
like episode zone out and stuff
just like have fun relax play the game
and i found the more i do that the less
i feel burnt out playing the game which
is important
when you play for years and years and
years in the same world
very crucial also setting your own time
schedule when you want to actually play
instead of feeling forced to
like uh i kind of felt before i used to
like always try to record an episode
every day or every second day or every
third day and now it's kind of gotten to
like every week and
honestly i'm loving it
i love like the slow pace i know you
guys hate it you absolutely hate it but
it feels so good for me
uh and then like at times i feel like
especially inspired to play and i'll
play more then right but i don't want to
force it
great question thanks for thanks for
asking it thanks for watching guys hope
you enjoyed it take care have a great
day
bye