[Music]
in the last episode of ezel plays
minecraft our protagonist etho that's me
had the grand old idea that he was gonna
build a game called a mastermind in a
game called minecraft oh snap
will he succeed will he fail find out as
we watch this episode of ether plays
minecraft and we will see our
protagonist etho slowly succumb to a
gradual but inevitable demise as he
realizes he has bitten off more than he
can chew
as he realizes that even though he knows
the secret to getting better at anything
is to think you can do it but not be so
sure just push yourself a little bit
further than you think you can go and
then maybe you will learn something as
you go along but he hasn't planned out
this project at all he's just going
along he he doesn't even know what his
next sentence is gonna be and he's just
talking here he's just talking and he
won't stop guys he won't stop uh-huh
anyways sorry about that guys here's the
deal though if you've made as many
videos as I have you kind of run into a
problem you you can only do the intro
like two ways basically either you do
the exact same thing every episode and
it gets repetitive and boring hey guys
this is Eko welcome back hope you're
doing well today or or you have the
option of doing like a really crazy
intro and then it'll probably be more
interesting alright but people will
question your mental stability which is
kind of the downside of that there's no
no in between though there's no normal
intro anymore you've done them all after
like 15 videos so you got to do you got
to pick one or the other
uh-huh anyways so we're trying to
recreate the mastermind in Minecraft if
you haven't seen the last episode you'll
probably want to watch it otherwise
nothing will make sense here but we had
a big problem here we got a lot of
problem solving to do with making this
game which is kind of fun but
it's also difficult and challenging
rights we ran into the problem of how
are we gonna display the black and the
white pegs in her mastermind game here
so this was one idea this is just a
mock-up I did where we could like drop
down concrete powder or sand or
something to represent the the pegs
we've we've gotten in the game problem
with doing that is it's very difficult
to reset we can move them using pistons
but it's very difficult to resets also
you can't move concrete powder in what
like bubble screams I forgot cuz it will
it'll harden so you have to use sand and
it's not gonna look great all right
white and orange sand looks kind of kind
of nasty here with the what we got going
on so it's a good thing I asked you guys
for four ideas though for brainstorming
because you've pulled off very well some
some stuff that was suggested was like
piston tapes or using a big glowstone
wall to represent the pegs distant apes
have mobility problem glowstone wall has
a like how are you gonna wire that up
and store all the information problem
one really good suggestion I saw though
that we're gonna do here
it's a glow stone wall idea but we're
gonna break it up a bit somebody pointed
out see finger and show this what we can
do is like insert items into a hopper
here and that'll make the glowstone
light up here and then when we when we
need to move it instead of like pushing
it with pistons like we were gonna do
there we will just unpowered repower
this quickly and you see it'll move
forward one space then we can insert the
next bit here and move it along and that
way we have moveable data right that's
easy to control by instead of like doing
a big wall of glowstone like for tall
here I'll stack together we're gonna
leave a one block space between each of
them because it's gonna be so much
easier to do that and that is gonna look
a little something like this so check it
out
guys I think overall this looks quite a
bit better than the orange end and
yellow sanded right aesthetically I
think it's nicer when we make a game or
a redstone project we want to really
consider how it's gonna look before we
do the redstone wiring like the complex
part how much information can we see
when we're looking at the game right we
can almost see everything we can see the
full play field no problem and then our
white and black pegs are gonna be
displayed on the side here so if we have
one white peg this lamp will be on if we
have two this will be on two this will
be on for three this will be on for four
black pegs will be on this side one two
three four in mastermind it's actually
very rare that you get like three or
four pegs of any color so these top two
grows almost will never be used so we
can see like everything then if you if
you consider that even if we look at
this we can see the third row pretty
good it would be better if we could
squish it all together but that's just
gonna be too hard I could do it if I
really wanted but the games gonna get
way way bigger more complex I think
there's a way of doing that now with
observers like company clumping
glowstone walls together and getting it
to work so this is the way the redstone
is it's actually very compact I like it
basically we go up here run run our
hoppers sideways this is nice because
the hoppers store the information we can
move it we can reset it it meets all the
criteria we're looking for with our
redstone design here so that's that's
great we'll lock it with the red stone
above comparators we'll go in side like
this they won't interfere with each
other because we left that space so all
in all I think we're pretty good here so
like every single block is used hopper
there comparator we need that block
there we need the redstone there so it's
a pretty compact way of doing it so now
we need to add some mechanisms for
controlling our four rows so that they
work together in unison because we
always want to lock and unlock all four
rows of hoppers at the exact
same time as each other so redstone only
travels 15 blocks right so we got to do
something like this I think that'll
power that row and then if we put a
redstone dust on there it'll power the
second row and then we'll do that again
at this level oops this place yeah we'll
put another repeater here and we just
got to link these two repeaters together
and they'll control all four of these oh
yeah so things are happening here guys
it's coming together I'm liking it we
got our two repeaters linked together so
the redstone torch goes up up a
staircase to that one which means when
we flip the lever here we can lock or
unlock all 48 hoppers at once with the
exact same timing as each other as we
choose as we so please which is awesome
so the whole unit is controlled from a
single power source which is great we
also want to do that for the items oh we
need a system for deciding okay did I
put the item in the bottom row that one
that one that one depending on how many
pulses we send the a dropper so we have
a dropper up here if we have like one
black peg we want to send this one pulse
2 4 2 3 4 3 4 4 4 and then have it
decide automatically okay which which
row does it go into so I've added in a
column of hoppers here as a bit of a
buffer so things that can get into
position before they're shown up on the
glowstone so that there's no like delay
issues or anything like that so if we
want to send it to the bottom row of
glowstone we want the items end up here
for the second row here third row up
there right the way we control that you
see I've branched off from our our lock
lines here there's a repeater that keeps
this locked or that wait that's not
necessary for the bottom it oh yeah it
is it is otherwise it'll flow into but
what that is click I heard a click
what was that we're probably not
important yeah anyway so when we send
this draw
for a pulse it'll shoot an item in and
then this hopper pulls it down this one
pulls it down it keeps getting pulled
down right to the bottom here and you
see this comparator turned on I took it
out let's try it again that redstone
down there turns on which power is this
hopper over here so this hopper is
locked it won't pull out of this hopper
anymore so the net that means the next
one's gonna end up in here and it just
does a like a staircase up next one is
in here right and again it it locks in
the next one so it's gonna end up in
here it locks the next one so that one
stays in here so if there's four pegs
that fills up from the bottom to the top
that way and then when we unlock the
hoppers they are free to flow to our
glowstone display here right now they're
just in a buffer and storage if we did
like a quick pulse like that'll it'll
flow one space right so that's good that
we can make it go down Lane here and
then at the end of the game when we win
or lose we can just clear the display by
keeping this unpowered for a while and
it'll just float up down to the end it
gets the ends we collect all the items
together with another column of hoppers
and going a chest here for right now if
we want we can recycle them and send
them back to the start there and then
it'll be a perfect closed system or we
can just keep a big big stash of them in
a chest or something that's fine too
oh man I think I can do a Morgan Freeman
voice I just realized this I am so
excited the only problem is I'm not
admitting very much air so it doesn't
have a lot of power very deep there dark
voice timber so I just wanted to address
I did see the comments on last episode
about our white page issue apparently
the way I was gonna do the ice stream
logic game logic here is gonna have some
problems with the white pegs the black
pegs
them is fine that will work fine we just
have to like connect those pressure
plates up to that dropper on one of the
sides and it's pretty much good to go
but the white pegs gotta figure out how
to do that differently so just letting
you know I saw it I'll hopefully figure
it out we're not gonna do that this
episode we're just gonna look at one
other thing today and then we'll move on
to some other stuff here the way we're
gonna generate the random code to our
game also had an issue we were gonna use
for droppers with six random colors in
they would drop down on the ice here we
had an issue where they were sliding a
lot of you suggested I use cobwebs put
those in front of the droppers and
that'll that'll stop all horizontal
momentum and it'll fall straight down
they'll have a bit of delay but it'll
work but we're not gonna do that we're
gonna do a completely different system
here because another issue is we only
had five minutes to finish a game and it
seems like that might actually be a
pretty big problem so the going
recommendation by a lot of you guys and
even doc hemmed messaged me about it is
to use shulker boxes all right so that's
what we're gonna do
I should let's go over here first so we
can see something so the plan is we also
wanted a way to see the code at the end
of the game if we win or lose we don't
want it to be hidden underground their
rule where we'll never see it right we
want to know why we won or lost the game
so we're gonna have like a shudder
system at the end there and I got
nothing to throw against oh I still got
it though look at that
Oh on and I fell down anyway so there's
gonna be control here to flip that up at
the end of the game if we win or lose
and then that's gonna reveal the code in
front of us and we're gonna use
dispensers to play shocker boxes
randomly each dispenser will have six
different colors of shocker boxes in so
we need 24 total which we don't have by
the way this is a survival world's you
think I got 24 just laying around no
we're gonna have to go get those
which is gonna be tricky so these
dispensers they'll have the shelter
boxes in then this line of wire here is
gonna be used to place them now the
shelter boxes are going to have concrete
powder inside as well and that's gonna
flow down to our ice stream system there
every time we enter an answer we're
gonna refresh it so we will be able to
make a game we go longer than five
minutes so we'll take one item out of
the Shocker box and we got to send it
down to a dropper probably shoot it out
and I'll land on the ice down there so
to do that we're gonna unpowered this
this hopper here if we do that they flow
into there we want them to flow downward
though so we have like a switching
system here it can either float down or
to the right into this dropper this is
where we want the shulker box to go
because after this after we break it we
can use pistons to break the shell core
box so we want that to go in here oh and
it where'd it go oh did it go to the one
beside it I was really worried that was
gonna happen
Wow and all my testing I couldn't get
that to happen and it happened now oh
this might have a flaw then really that
time it went there okay you're gonna
have to test that a bit more I guess
that would be pretty critical because we
want to be able to reset this like we
need the Shanker box to go back into the
dispenser it came from that goes into
another one then we won't be able to
generate a random code it's gonna be
like if one of these dispensers has two
yellow ones in it's only gonna it'll be
impossible have to have like a yellow
yellow yellow yellow code cuz only one's
gonna come out okay I have an idea here
rather than squishing the shulker boxes
with the the piston heads we're gonna
use sticky pistons and maybe trapdoors
will work we'll flip them over
like this and that's gonna come down it
and pop the shawl cur boxes I'm hoping
the trap doors are gonna act as a
barrier to prevent them from hopping
over to the block beside them because it
creates like a wall here I don't know if
that's gonna work I'm gonna test sell a
little bit here okay purple green purple
yo so first first tries a success I'm
gonna do it a few times here just to be
sure see if we have any problems cuz I
make that mistake a lot when I'm
building something I'll test it once one
or two or three times but then it it
fails later it's like oh man
I designed the whole thing around this
and now it doesn't work because of some
random chance I didn't detect before so
you gotta like really really try this
stuff out this is a very random thing it
could be like a one in a hundred who
knows I'm not gonna test it a hundred
times but probably 10 is good enough
right uh-huh
so I tried that at least 10 times and it
didn't fail so I think that's gonna work
I think I'll be good
I just realized we're kind of getting
along in the episode already so let's
change things up let's get some
variations and adventure in our life
here we're gonna go to the end today
after all and go hunting for shelters so
that we can get our 24 shelter boxes for
that plus I wouldn't mind having a few
more as using the farm here the the reed
farm to get some paper for some maps
right and I think since I last showed
this in a video it's changed a little
bit so for one thing lily pads aren't
flat anymore like when you're walking
around in here it's bumpy kind of go up
and down constantly it's a bit bit weird
bit annoying but also like in one point
13.1 they added this effect where if you
break something all connected blocks to
it play a breaking sound now so when
you're breaking sugar cane it's way
louder it's kind of crazy
all right so I think we're all prepared
here and ready to go ready to face
danger and fall in the void and all that
fun stuff this is I got on me right now
and I just got a chest here let's
actually grab one more stack because I
can't remember how much paper it
requires so last time we did this was
quite a while ago it was back when we
still had to do Bo boosting like where
you shoot yourself with an arrow to get
launched in the air we had a lighter
wings but and the map feature just came
out where you can map the end so this is
the map we made and you see all the
purple spots are are the N CDs or
whatever this time I'm going to try
bring banners with me we'll name them
we'll give them the coordinates of where
it is because I'm just looking at this
map here I have no idea which direction
to go to be honest I think I think I
laid it out so that up on the map is
forward but I'm not sure so anyways this
might be a lot easier now that we have
the fireworks just fly around though so
I'm just gonna fly 2,000 blocks this way
yeah doing this with the the fireworks
is a lot easier like before you had very
little control by doing the bow boosting
and not only that but you were shooting
yourself so it's very easy to lose track
of your health and just shoot yourself
to death which is what I did a few times
so I think we've gone far enough for a
mm oh I went a little too far I think
2,900 so I always kind of forget how
maps work I think we can that then zoom
out alright somehow do we need a
crafting table to do it I think so I
think we got to do a ring around the map
now several times as well probably be
what did I say probably uh-huh okay so I
assumed that very good let's do that as
many times as we can here and do the
full wraparound okay and that's it okay
so let's oh I do see that I think it
consumed it one more time when I took it
out of there I'm gonna have to watch
that back I think it did though
oh we got one we got one oh it's a big
one too with a boat look at that
oh yeah there's banners at end cities
aren't there I didn't need to bring
banners all right well let's let's try
this out anyways I'm gonna use up the
green ones I brought so 1960 30 to 20
1960 30 to 20 only one okay so 1960 30
to 20 let's do a comma we're gonna be
fancy like that or should we even do
brackets guys we're gonna do brackets oh
snap
30 30 to 20 gotta do it before I forget
okay that'll go get our coordinates and
then we place it and now can we see them
on the map oh I need an item frame
whoops well we can't check it out I left
them at the at the start there okay
anyways let's go check this out so
Dawkins recommended something here to be
which I'm a little bit iffy about I feel
like this is a bad idea like it's gonna
kill me but he said to use invisibility
potion so I'm gonna try no you got to
take off your armor though and like make
yourself vulnerable and all that fun
stuff but apparently they kinda oh I
probably need an empty hand too right
I brought too much stuff and I left all
my shelter boxes at the at the game
we're making sure there's no entrance
what's going on here yeah wait a minute
wait a minute don't they oh it's a
little bit underground that's what's
happening oh I've never seen that before
alright this where's the entrance here
it is okay cuz there's usually two in
the front right and they're gone okay so
if I have my sword equipped they can
definitely see me all right we got two
we got two that's all we need now we can
make a soccer ball
okay good so now we actually have some
inventory space that's that's kind of
key when you're going to loot something
right you want to be able to store some
stuff so we got no no weapon equipped
and no armor god I'd be careful not to
fall let's see if any of them will shoot
at us like we got a guy right over there
he seems to be chilling out yeah he's
leaving us alone how close do we have to
get before is it two blocks I always
forget how invisibility works I think
I've only ever like used it once
usefully what well building the Guardian
for him but they would still attack you
like if you were within a certain range
of them he seems to be actually leaving
me alone entirely right which is pretty
cool but as soon as I select a weapon
he'll shoot at me right no oh oh okay
that's actually really good then once I
hit him then somehow he magically sees
me will he shoot again and not just him
they're all shooting which is weird it's
like it alerts the pack or something
okay okay I don't know I feel a little
bit vulnerable doing this I just gonna
put my armor just the idea though okay
we got one yeah because the susi start
attacking him it's like all the benefits
go away then and then that's when you
actually want your armor on what do we
got
cursive binding ooh Oh a mending pick
look at that what happened to my trident
there it is
wait so if you wait a minute wait a
minute so if you throw a trident when
it's in your offhand it doesn't come
back in your offhand this might be a
really bad idea but for the sake of
testing what happens if you have no
inventory spots then a terrible idea
what does it do then it just kind of
floats to you it's floating around me it
really wants to come back but he can't I
kicked it out of the house it wants to
come home but I'm not gonna let it oh
man that's weird you could probably do
some cool stuff with that okay I'm gonna
keep that in mind as soon as that comes
back uh-huh
okay cool so I'm using the the Trident
but I'm like keeping this sword in my
off hand so you're the looting effects
that way I got I got a ranged attack you
know it's a little bit nicer and then if
I'm at close quarters I'm going to
switch it easy seems to be working
pretty good
oh oh you teleported now didn't work
okay
Oh No Oh
almost like almost dead
that's all it is one tower he's shot
without even opening up there he's
cheating
he's shooting without opening all right
very good so he cleared out that whole
section guys and it doesn't look like
the banners showed up so when we hover
over them nothing happens so that's
that's a bit unfortunate I guess they
might only work with the small maps and
or I did it wrong or something happened
there but anyways we found four
fortresses in total mostly all at the
bottom right there in total we got 42
shelter shells we made one one box
already Wow which is about enough for
our project I'll probably go on another
run soon though just get a few extra
these are all the goodies we found some
ok stuff found to Elisha wings yeah I
don't want the other one they're from
the the two boats or whatever and all in
all pretty good run no that's that's not
the one I broke a pic today by the way
is so bad like I went for mining with
some redstone right and you know you
look at the durability it's fine it's
fine you get distracted then poof it's
gone so I think with that guys we're
gonna wrap up for this episode and the
comment I picked out it says etho you
should do a video where you fix broken
stuff in your world why can't you do
that we do do that's like whenever we
need do do need to whenever we need to
do it honestly though I think there's a
misconception with a lot of you guys
like a lot of this stuff in our world is
actually working there's very few broken
things the things that are broken I'll
just give you an example
we have broken things like the spider XP
farm here but those are things that are
broken in a way that they can't be fixed
so I'm not ever going to fix them
they're the reason I don't tear them
down though is because they're a
reminder of like an old part of our
series you know but they bring up
niceness teletrac feelings for me when I
see them if I don't want to tear them
down but I can't fix them like I fix
whatever I can but there's certain
things we just can't fix but overall
most stuff in our world works that is
fixable there's maybe one or two things
I need to fix yet but that's maybe I'm
underselling it maybe there's more but
there's there's not many uh-huh anyways
thank you guys for watching today's
episode and until the next one take care
have a wonderful day
bye bye
[Music]