[Music]
hey hey
how's it going everyone welcome back
this is etho
and we we are doing a little adventuring
here i was doing a little adventuring
look at where we are i i have found
podzol
i finally found some puzzle i was
exploring those
those ice planes we found the other day
uh out by our nether fortress
portal thing i was hoping to find the
spiked
ice planes i think that's what they're
called
i've never seen those before and i was
really hoping to find some
and i still haven't didn't find it but i
did find
a mega tiger way out here it's at 3 100
6100 so that is pretty cool
i was wondering what this was going to
look like and it's actually a lot
different than i expected
because uh the tiger
the mega tiger biomes considered like a
colder
uh biome when you see it normally though
you see podzol everywhere
but since it's an amplified terrain uh
and very mountainous uh there's a lot of
snow
everywhere because uh it's considered a
cold climate
and so a lot of the podzol like if you
look out over at that cliff
most of that is possible probably it's
just
uh it's covered in snow there's no
layers everywhere and the
and it has the snow grass like if you
look at the side here
if we break this it turns into bodily so
it's kind of hidden
very interesting um
was not expecting to find this so i'm
not really prepared to take something
back i nope
no shovels no silk touch shovels this
isn't so touch i don't think you can
pick it up normally
no it just breaks the dirt darn
finally found it and i can't get any of
it oh that stinks
um but i got the coordinates this place
we should be able to set up a portal
but no luck with the ice or
what are they called spiked ice planes i
think that's what they're called yeah
didn't find that and i'm pretty sure i
looked through
through most of that ice plane area so
i'll have to look another another area i
guess but this is a
good find i really want to find some
ponzil so
i think i will you know what i'm
probably just going to kill myself to
get back
because yeah it's a long walk
yeah so i don't usually do this but it's
like a 20 to 30 minute walk back i
i would say so we're we're just gonna
put uh
our stuff in an ender chest here and
jump off a cliff i just
uh it's really hard deciding though what
to what to keep and what not to keep
i think i think this is good i would
really like to save this wood somehow
though
i did find acacia saplings too while
exploring so i got those again
i want to keep those steak
it's not really any junk items here is a
problem
guess we could get rid of the diamonds
all right so let's
here we go
boom so many ender pearls everywhere
and that takes us right back awesome
yeah this is way quicker that way
oh leave me alone leave me alone
i think we're good yeah we're good
okay i'll see you guys in just a second
oh
coming through
okay everyone so here we are at our
stronghold base with our crazy mob
system that does all kinds of
crazy things um i really wanted to
start working on the next level the next
stage to this thing
today but i've been here for about an
hour now
trying to work out some of the problems
we were having with it and
they've gotten a little better but uh
we're still having a lot of problems
the main issue is mobs are getting
backed up in the system they're getting
backed up in the water streams and stuck
and
and yeah i've tried putting a bunch of
regulators up there
to sort of deal with the problems
but ah it's just
just a mess let's go over here
um wait what's what's her oops not skin
i always click on skin now because
that's where the music used to be
let's turn this down a bit
all right so this is the mob sorter over
there
i think a big thing we gotta change with
that is get rid of the trap door and use
a piston
instead that will retract a block
to make the skeletons fall because i
think they're having trouble jumping up
that
that block there that skeleton is not
supposed to be
so that's one problem um
[Music]
over here especially once there's a lot
of mobs in the stream
that's when when we have problems it
starts sending two or three
mobs through at once uh
because you see how many are over there
it'll like try to let a few it through
but then like 10 or 20 to shoot through
instantly once this piston retracts here
um yeah so
the plan the plan guys we're gonna get
rid of all these water streams
and we're gonna use mine carts instead
it's gonna be
really cool mechanical system
i think but i'll have to
have to tear all this down and start
fresh so
give me a moment to do that i think i
know
how we're gonna build it
so it should be okay i hate i hate
tearing this thing down i've made a
backup just in case
it was a huge mistake but
there's just too many problems to work
through it i think it needs to be done
properly
so i will see you guys in a second
okay so some of this it looks like we'll
save uh from the beginning mobs they
fall down
that hole most of the time i have them
falling down this tube all the way onto
that hopper
they die and i collect the loot from
that so i think we can keep all that
then i have this water control system
here
if we flip the lever determines if they
fall down there or if they go to the
left
and i think we can keep this as well
this will be the only water stream in
the whole thing the rest will be
minecarts
uh so this is
this piston that one and that one
i think we all keep don't need this or
that
so let's start demolition
man
wait i got it off right yeah last thing
i need is a bunch of creepers coming
through here even though
we're doing demolition i don't want a
big mess
um oh that was scary
oh hey it's trying to kill me it knows
it knows i'm i'm trying to destroy it
taking on a life of his own
i hate destroying it because i put so
much time into this already
but i think the new thing is going to be
a lot better
and i would rather it works properly
then
then try to or just keeping this piece
of junk around you know
not that it was terrible but yeah it's
it just had too many problems
all right so this this trap door there
by the way is what we were using before
to try to just let one mob through at a
time
uh with the new method we're gonna be
using minecarts and that's gonna be
so much better because sometimes more
than one mob
is getting through here and that was
messing up the sorting
a lot all right
oh yeah look at that guys fresh starts
very cool
i'm excited uh so we got our villager
dude over here until we decide
where we need to put them and we got our
noisy kitty over here
just hanging out waiting for us to get
their new home ready
so let's get it going
it's going to be a little tough working
working up high here
without any real scaffolding so the very
first thing i think we need to add
is like a reservoir for the mobs to
collect into
like a one by one tube so water stream
is going to come
at this block height let's get a tube
going on around
this dirt block so over here here and
here and we will put a sign there to
hold the water back
so it doesn't fall down this is where
the water ends over here
mine carts from here on out oh yeah and
i kept i still got this thing in place
this is the
thing that makes the creeper bombs i
might redo that with
minecarts too because i noticed they
were kind of getting stuck in the water
streams as well
having a little trouble
all right oh you know what oh i'm doing
this wrong
i brought special glass this time and we
were going to use cyan
oh i wonder if it's too late to change
it
yeah let's let's go ahead and change it
and do wait
oh i'm messing this up just wasting
glass
left and right here wonderful
all right i find this this color of the
glass is the most transparent like that
i can see through the easiest
out of all the the colors especially
over
clear because clear has all the white in
it which is really annoying
okay we got the sign back very good
let's get that over
here okay change that piece
i'll probably change this to about two
later uh we gotta make them
fall see
they're at that height i think they
gotta go down at least two blocks
it's a little confusing trying to figure
out what is what
uh like with all the glass around it's
kind of
kind of hard to see where the blocks are
all right two
yeah so the ground i think we'll be
there this gives us a little bit of
working room too because we can't go
above the snow layer there
so if bringing it down is kind of nice
and let's get like a
platform going here i suppose
okay so the mobs will fall down they'll
all gather up in this
in this one by one tube over here
should work out okay and then
we are going to get some rails going
they'll go right into the tube there
and so a mine cart will
will pick up the mobs one by one for
sure
like we'll send a minecart in it'll grab
a mob pull it out
and that way i will definitely
definitely not have any more trouble
with mobs bunching up where i don't want
them to
i think we're gonna do like a minecarts
uh system here that kinda goes like yeah
i think like
that so then we bring up the power rails
like that and then we gotta get
let's make this go over a little more
okay we're gonna get some sand down and
a cactus so the mine cart is gonna go
right into the cactus
and break above a hopper the hopper will
pull it in
and it will take it to this dispenser
and then we can send a mine cart out
here and it'll roll this way
when this is all powered that's pretty
good
let's get that going here
and hmm what should we do next
i think
i think we need to push them as well the
mob so we should get a
piston let's get
let's use a sticky piston for this
all right when they arrive here minecart
breaks they get ejected from the
minecart the mobs will be standing right
here
and then i'm gonna use a solid block for
this
this piston will push them over one
block and they'll fall down another one
by
one tube over here that's the way we'll
do it
okay now let me let me encase this all
with glass and
get this powered and that kind of stuff
okay we got a little bit more glass
going on here but i realized something
important we should do so i wanted to
show you uh one thing
for sure i overlooked this but if you
put a minecart there
it doesn't move because we got a glass
block behind there so let's
change that out with the solid block
so now
there it is oops here let's try this out
again
just to make sure from what i understand
with this setup
it'll never get destroyed in the cactus
the hopper always grabs it
very good okay and also we need to
detect
if there's a mob in the tube so i
think we need to get a tripwire going
here
do it like this and if there's a mob in
the tube then send
minecarts to go pick them up kind of
thing
so we will do tripwire there and there
and i guess let's get some more glass
going
zom the baby zombies might pose a bit of
a
ch challenge or trouble to us but we
will see
because they will be able to run out of
here anytime they want
i have to leave it or i think i need to
leave it open like this with
with the one block so the mine turret
can get in there
hopefully they don't cause too much
trouble i think if there's a lot of mobs
in there actually they won't be able to
run out i think the other mobs will hold
the babies in place keep them keep them
in line and i've also added something
down here this is really important this
block here
is gonna act like the trap door on the
sorting system we had before so there's
gonna we're gonna hook a piston up to it
that's gonna
pull it back and and drop skeletons down
and
if uh yeah let's go down
okay so piston will come and push the
mobs over to here they'll fall down
and then if we get rid of this yeah we
can
skeletons will fall down here if this
block gets pulled back by the piston
zombies and creepers will go either to
the left here
or to here
maybe we should get the zombies going
this way because we got the villager
there already that's pretty convenient
all right everyone so i just went ahead
and did a little bit of redstone here
i don't know if it's going to work or
what settings we need or anything like
that
we'll hopefully figure it out but it
goes to
minecart dispenser to this piston up
here and that special block
down there i also have it all connected
to
so basically if there is a mob in in the
tube
they'll activate the tripwire that will
turn this torch off
if this torch is off it allows this
clock to run
which goes from here around and back
and every time it does a cycle it goes
to the dispenser let's one mine cart out
which goes picks up a mob goes over to
the cactus
and then ideally we want it set up so
that when a mob arrives there this
piston extends and pushes them off
so then i have another branch off here
going to that piston
and this is a monostable you can see i
got a sticky piston there
um okay
and then i also have the piston
underneath going
uh which will control if a skeleton
should fall and give enough time for a
creeper
and a zombie to figure out their path
finding hopefully so that's going to
take a while to
tweak i believe it's kind of a tricky
thing to work out
but this i think we can run it
i put a lever up here just to see
all right so that's i think that's too
fast
yeah way too fast okay so we're gonna
add to the clock
uh-huh that's probably still too quick
we'll add a little bit more
okay you see when that goes and comes
back
this piston pushes before the minecart
arrives so we need to add some delay
here
that's pretty close maybe we'll just do
this full
for now
okay we won't really know if it works
until we get some mobs in here
unfortunately seems kind of loud too
doesn't it
um what's this thing doing down here
okay so after they get pushed down
we want okay after this
this piston goes we want that extended
it's kind of hard to see both at the
same time
okay so that one pushes and this is
extended
i think we need a little bit of delay on
that one down there too
and it's gonna take a lot of tweaking i
think
i put a bunch of repeaters down here
here maybe we'll just do all that at
full and see what it does
okay pretty crazy
let's let's turn this off for now none
of the minecarts are getting destroyed
that's good we still have two in there
so the cactus isn't killing them
can we go down yes we can awesome
all right uh just for now i'm gonna put
this here so
zombies we will make go this way so
we'll have two blocks for trap doors
and then another block and i guess the
villager will go kinda around there
we'll have to move them a little bit it
looks like
ah no trapdoors start it
there we go did i i think i have some
more around here too we'll probably need
a few
so we'll need two for the creepers as
well
oh do you think i can make this throw
i don't even know what to aim at let's
try over here
nope nope
that was pretty bad
oh no oh
you guys don't know this but a lot of
times when i'm working here i'll ender
pearl up like that
and i'll i'll go through the snow layer
into the mob system where all the mobs
are and i've had it blow
up on me a few times actually and when
that happens
when this snow breaks just a whole pool
of water and mobs flows down destroys
all the redstone below
it is bad news bad news i have to be
very careful about that
uh all right that
so mobs they see these trapdoors as full
blocks they'll actually try to walk on
them and they'll run off of this
which is pretty cool good way to exploit
their
their ai we'll do that again
a solid block here okay
this will be for the creepers
uh we'll probably need a platform over
here
otherwise the creepers won't want a path
find over this direction
don't know how big to make it either
we'll do that for now okay get that out
and i guess we can start hooking up some
tubes
it's actually not that tough now that i
now that i'm doing it it's going pretty
good
should have done this a long time ago oh
i missed all right let's go back up
let's go over there so i think with
these i want to try to get the mobs into
a one by one tube again so i think
see they're gonna be running this way
so we'll make the one one by one tube
over here
hopefully
might need to get rid of a block there
yeah
so they'll still fall down two blocks i
think that'll work
yeah you gotta believe
believe in yourself and okay
i'm going to do the exact same with the
zombies
let's get there
i'm running out of glass first stack
all right so let's just put like a
block at the bottom here for now we'll
see see if we can get them to sort
properly
and then if this works then we will set
up some kind of reserve for holding them
i guess this is kind of a reserve for
them um
we got to set up some other minecart
thing down here though to move them
further into the system later
okay and the skeletons they will fall
where this block is supposed to be up
over here
uh like right there is where the piston
extends it to so we will bring this
actually let's put that back
okay and they will fall down here i have
a hard time
this is getting really hard to see the
blocks all this all this transparency is
getting
uh a little confusing
all right
cool okay i'm gonna do a little bit of
refinement here then i think we're ready
to do an
actual test with real mobs real live
mobs that can explode and all that fun
stuff
oh boy that kind of looks weird doesn't
it with all the grey glass
i wonder if that was a mistake
hopefully hopefully it's very
transparent and we can see
the mobs in it real easy uh it looks
weird though
from down here at least uh so
it's ready to go to do for our test but
first
i noticed like we got some
some chicken jockeys in here there's at
least two and one of them is a villager
one you see that guy
so i'm wondering if we can get them to
the end try to get them through the end
portal
um here i'm gonna get this ready so
hopefully if we break this they'll be
able to get out
yeah oh hey hey hey guys
in fact i actually have a shortcut to it
right here let's see if they'll follow
us down
yep okay oh oh oh
don't knock me in no oh don't follow me
down here
don't follow me down here darn it i
messed it up
oh oh oh um
wait a minute where's where'd the other
guy go hopefully they both didn't come
down
i was so close there but he knocked me
off
he was just a little too quick for me
oh he is up here still oh
come on guy come on
oops
come on come on oh no no
go down go down
i don't think he's that dumb you know
what i need is a trap door
just a sec i bet a trapdoor would fool
him
he sees it as a hole so he's not going
to go down there
but if we trap door
oh wait nobody's on a chicken he can't
transport through
huh uh that's too bad you know what that
zoo idea of mine
like he's one of the guys i wanted to
collect for it i don't know if that's
actually possible
if uh if i can't send him through maybe
we'll leave him down there see how long
he lasts
all right anyway we can forget about the
other guy down there too i guess
okay we're gonna go for it here i just
want to show you the system before we
start
and so i have video evidence in case it
blows up i might be able to rebuild it
the same way uh so the villager guy i
only had him
had to move him down one block it's like
the exact same spot
which is pretty amazing got our titty in
there
right next to him so uh the mobs are all
going to fall down
right right in that block area there
villagers they'll run towards not
villagers zombies they'll run
towards the villager creepers they'll
run away from the cat so they'll go
that way fall down there zombies fall
down there
and skeletons they should sit around on
that block
and after a certain amount of time
they'll just fall down so
yep that's our sorting system
now it's not going to be 100 i don't
think there are
well there might be but from what i've
seen most sorting systems aren't 100
percent
there's some some
there's always some chance a skeleton's
gonna go where you don't want them to go
is the problem all right so
we can hop on over here
and figure out how bad a mistake we've
made
okay so the water stream we turned the
water stream on it's going over there
did not want to see which first
because which is uh oh
okay well that's not so
it's good stuck
oh okay so it sends out another minecart
at least
yeah witches should go where the
skeletons go
oh creeper fell down the skeleton one
that's not good
we need more mobs i think it might be
night time
oh here comes a skeleton
yeah so if there's no mobs i think if
there's a lot of mobs in that reserve
they'll bounce around to the mine cart
that's weird um
you should be moving why isn't that
minecart moving
interesting
oh man this is weird i think we have
some time issues
oh this is open yikes okay creepers can
uh creepers have a nice passage there
let's go look at the the sorting thing
see what's going on
um not looking so good to be honest
right okay
so i have some tweaking to make maybe
oops oh i thought that guy fell down
um yeah i'm going to tweak some timings
there and see if i can get it working
better and
we'll see it one more time at least i'm
gonna have to call the episode an end
very soon though because
it is getting that time
[Music]
okay man what are you looking at zombie
no he's doing his dance now do you know
what the problem is with this thing
because i sure i am
baffled to some extent i think i might
know what it is
look you see how the zombie he's looking
off over here
he's not looking at the villager
he's looking over like that way for some
reason and what that's doing
instead of the minecart going into the
cactus like it's supposed to
see see how the creeper is looking this
way the creeper is telling the minecart
not to go up this hill he's he's making
it go
down over and over again
see it's so weird
let's see just let's just watch it for a
sec see if we can spot it happening
again
like that was weird why isn't the
minecart breaking
it's hitting a cactus
you see you see what that skeleton's
doing he's looking this way
and instead of running into the cactus
he's telling the minecart to go down
once once he gets to the top of the
slope there
so this is a problem i think i've dealt
with before
i made a mistake here where i only
dropped them two blocks from the water
stream
i think you gotta drop them either three
or four otherwise
it messes up their pathfinding it's like
they want to go
this way towards the water stream again
that's why they're all looking this way
and why they're avoiding the cactus
and doing strange things i believe i
hope
so that means i have to build all of
this one block lower maybe two
oh that's not good minecart fell out
somehow
see the creeper he's looking this way
that's why the car the cart isn't
bouncing
too
anyway i'll look into it more later i
i'm pretty sure i have to build this all
one or two blocks lower though
which is pretty annoying
did you steal my minecart
he's got my minecart
yeah and so they're i think like all
their pathfinding is messed up
because they have that one target in
mind so they're
like almost ignoring the villager and
the cat here
it's very very weird anyway
it's a start but it needs tweaking too
it looks like
um i actually tried building this in
creative just now and
it worked up in the sky
uh so it's it's something to do with in
my world here it's not a problem with
the
setup really
well it kind of is i guess i don't know
anyway project for another day i guess
oh no he's gonna eat me i better
i better back up very slowly and get him
stuck on the fence and
and run away anyway so i'm gonna move
all that stuff down a block or two i
think that will fix it the the issue is
in a nutshell they are pathfinding to
something they're not supposed to which
is messing everything up because the
whole system is based on
uh their pathfinding working so
once i can get rid of whatever they're
looking at
they should do what i want them to do
i'm pretty sure
but another day i'll work on it later i
guess
but let's read our comments for the day
i just picked up one really quick one
here it says etho
can you solve a rubik's cube
oh you know i used to be able to
uh it's pretty quick at it too i could
do it like in a minute or two
which is decent i would say uh
don't remember how to anymore
you know on tv and movies if you guys
don't know how to solve a rubik's
cube they always like associate it with
these really smart people that can
then solve it and then they do it in
like a second and everybody's amazed
it's not really about intelligence
solving a rubik's cube it's about
following patterns algorithms
if you rotate it a certain way
and follow a bunch of steps there's like
eight different steps to it
eventually everything lines up and you
don't even really have to think about it
you just have to do it
and if depending on how it's mixed up
you might be able to skip steps and
sometimes the steps line up quicker than
other times
depending on how it's mixed up so
yeah that's how you solve a rubik's cube
you can look it up it's actually kind of
fun once you know how to do it
to do it but i can't remember how
anyway so that's going to bring our
episode to a
close i hope you guys enjoyed it i hope
you have yourselves a great day and i
will see you again
next time take care bye bye guys
you