[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and you know what
i used to always start my episodes here
looking at the creeper face
i went to do it today and it's like oh
yeah we have stairs there now we have
the bridge
it looks different i wasn't i wasn't
expecting that
anyway today we're going to be doing
something
very cool uh we're going to be building
a new sheep farm design i came up with
the other night
i'm calling it my pop-up sheep farm
i've already built this in creative mode
not the full scale project but
i know the pattern that i need to repeat
so it should go pretty quickly we're
gonna build it over here
we need to make
about 11 wide
um probably about five or seven
tall area cleaned out here and about 60
blocks
back so quite a bit of space is needed
and it's going to house 32 sheep
usually if i make something in creative
mode i'll
just make a tutorial about it but this
is something i want in my
lp world and uh since
it's such a complicated build i figure i
should probably
try to explain it and blab on about it i
guess you could say
otherwise it'll probably go over
people's heads and they won't really
appreciate the intricate details
involved
or understand them i really like this
project because there's so many
game mechanics it works around it's uh
you'll see so i'm gonna get tnt and blow
up that area
i also looked around a little bit
beforehand to find other spots because
like i've said before i kind of want
everything i build to go with the flow
of the natural land
the most promising area i found was over
here
because it you know it's kind of wide
and it goes far back like that
the problem is the ravine floor is way
down there
and i would have to build it floating in
the air which would be difficult
and i don't know this just isn't a very
good position for it so
i'm going to mine away the blocks and
have it
match up with the floor the grass
grass floor up there
and i will begin
all right so i got this all prepped now
we're ready for some last
mining this will speed things up quite a
bit
and help save my preserve my picks
i've wanted to make a sheep farm in this
world for a long time i do have one like
just a pen style one really those are
probably the most efficient
style this one we're going to build
isn't very efficient it's more for fun
and for the cool factor but uh
i wanted to make one that's you know
that has pistons in that has detect
detection abilities in it maybe auto
collection system
didn't really know how to go about it
and then
the other day i was working on something
else and just stumbled into this
pop-up idea for the sheep farm and i
worked on it for
oh probably four hours or so until i
finally got it to the point where it
felt
uh perfected i had a lot of trouble
getting the redstone small enough in
this but i'm really happy with the final
result and i think you guys are gonna
really enjoy this project it's already
starting off good we get some tnt action
in here
will it stall so far so good
oh it's stalled i should i shouldn't
have said anything
on the last one
[Applause]
cool let's go to the other side
sure gets dark in here oh what's this
aha i ran across a
water lake in here so if you noticed all
that cobble on the side that was
because i filled it in
over over here somewhere
okay very good i'm going to pick this
stuff up i'll have to
clean out clean it up a little bit get
rid of this middle wall that got left
over
each of those tnt takes out about a five
by five by five
as i showed in previous episodes not
long ago
this is this is where the water lake was
all right clean up time and i'm
wondering oh there's tracks
oh this is unexplored even wow
i was like is that a slime what is that
that's a grass block
hmm i might have to check this out
what did i fall
check this out some other day i think it
fell there that was weird
mm-hmm very good very good so that is
the rough dimensions of this thing
the left wall is going to be over here
the right wall will be over here okay
and the floor i'll probably make it
level with
this floor here and remember i said i
might make a path come up here from
from below
that will come up to this level so then
a few blocks over we'll have the front
to the sheep farm
and this will be the floor level
here so at this height
and then what we're going to need is two
blocks underneath where we can walk
around
underneath the floor for the wiring and
whatnot
so i'm gonna have to shave off one block
all the way down there and give my pick
some use and also
the shape of this thing is kind of like
a dome
i can't remember exactly how high it is
but i think i'll probably have to
take off shave off one or two layers off
the top of this yet
so here i go
and we are back so i actually had to
shave off two layers off the floor and i
replaced
one of the ones i took off with this new
floor with the soil and the stone bricks
i have begun using one of my many
efficiency 4 picks because my other one
broke
from all the work and you can see this
is where
where the floor is going to be we have
our two block high clearance now
that we need
and this soil here is for grass
maybe we'll just punch a few holes every
so often
we'll put some some of this grass down
um and this is just so
we can
the grass blocks that the the sheep eat
we need the grass to grow back somehow
so that's what this is for
and this will be all underneath the the
floor of the sheep farm
out of sight and
yeah so with this with this design i
think what i'll do is
give you the long drawn out details
um rambling
darn it's version of the sheep farm in
my lp here and i'll probably do like a
quick
tutorial of it afterwards
of uh just how to how to build it
basically not
the whole explanation of how it works
like i plan to do an lp
here okay
so now i will show you the shape of the
building this
is let's see what are we gonna do
like i said i've i've got this pretty
much all planned out usually i don't uh
plan out my stuff for my lp in creative
mode beforehand but just with this
project i have
and if i do make something creative mode
i usually will
just make a tutorial for it like i said
okay we're going to have half slabs in
the middle
like this and
like that right
yeah okay then
i'm gonna grab wood i think i'm gonna
make this out of stone bricks for the
floor and wooden or wooden planks for
the walls
we might have yeah one more
one more row of the stone bricks and
then the wall will go
like that and
um
[Music]
just thinking here
yeah like that okay then we grab our
stairs
they will go up like that
this has to go higher yet i
think i did full blocks before
and i have no idea how this looks on the
large scale i just
with my with the one i did it was only
for
two sheep so i'm curious to see how this
is gonna
all look and work when it's all done
yeah this is pretty much a pattern
we'll do it three wide just to give you
a feel for it
to begin with the other side's the exact
same
i have to be careful there's a lot of
mobs around
grass is growing
and just putting those there temporarily
yeah that is the pattern so imagine that
all the way down that's what i have to
do
and i will probably skip you
or skip showing that on camera because
it's going to take a while
but uh i got all the materials ready so
and the space cleared out should go
fairly quick
there we go the building is done did not
take me very long
it's a pretty pretty easy to repeat
pattern
all the way down and we'll need to put a
back wall on it yet
and a front although the front i might
keep
relatively open just so we can see it
from
further back like if we're
for over here i would like to be able to
see into the sheep farm to see how
they're doing
but we'll we'll put the back in the
front on towards the end of this project
and each of these holes here is for a
sheep
there's 32 sheep total so we'll have
sheep on the right and on the left
and the pattern goes sheep one
two blocks sheep one two three blocks
sheep one two sheep one two three
so it goes two three two three two three
all the way down
mirrored on that side the sheep are
grouped by
twos so it's a group of two there group
of two there
group of two there that's how the
pattern is and i marked it out a little
clearer below
so you can it'll make wiring easier if
we
can clearly see where the sheep go
and now what we need to do as well is uh
right below each of these holes
punch a hole for the sheep to go into
one two three
you can see they're matching up so i'll
do that all the way down both sides
then we'll be back
and there we go we got our holes so with
this sheep farm
the majority of the time the sheep are
going to be underground here at this
level
we don't want to see them we want them
out of sight out of mind
the only time we want to see them is
when we want to see them type
thing and these holes are just so
when we pop them up they don't take
suffocation damage
when we when we jam their head through
the ceiling you know
uh this is also how we're going to load
them into ears through these holes
so the next part of this pop-up idea is
the piston underneath which is
crucial it goes like this right below
each of these holes
and on top of these is a soil block the
sheep
will stand right on top of this soil
block and since they're a block and a
half tall
they won't be able to wander off of
which is very important and we're going
to do that all the way down
oops so each sheep gets a 3 by 3
area to itself and two are right next to
each other
and there's a gap between each group of
two
okay so i'll do that all the way down
and then we will be back
all right that is looking very good very
good indeed
so with the pop-up thing i'll just show
you one thing about that
this is where stuff gets interesting um
so we got the piston right below here uh
the sheep stand on top of the grass
block this is what they eat to regrow
their wool too
it's the only block available to them to
eat
um when it's popped up like that though
we'll be able to see the sheep from this
level here
but it's only a one block high
thing here they can easily jump out of
that so another very important part of
this
is to have a block above that
so they can't get out but we we don't do
that until they're loaded in
so we'll wait on that can use pretty
much any block for that
i can even use glass or glowstone or
anything really
oops
okay another really important part of
this is the way
grass grows um maybe let's go outside
here
let's pretend
do we have enough space probably let's
pretend
this piece of cobble is the soil block
we want grass to grow to
um and these soil blocks here all have
grass on them
these can all spread to that soil block
in this pattern here or from all these
blocks
a big uh you get the point a three by
three
six high area is where grass will spread
from
the more grass blocks you have
the quicker it's likely to spread to the
soil block
of course there are issues with that you
can't just
have a big clump of grass blocks like
that you need
one block air space above each one
otherwise the grass will just quickly
die
for example but with our setup here
this is what we're doing we have the
soil block here
and we have grass one block below so
that'll work
if we had grass where these stone bricks
are they would be able to spread
to the soil block below as well but we
don't want that to happen here
because we're going to be hooking a bud
switch up to
these grass blocks and
we're using it to detect when the sheep
have regrown their wool
so if where's my lever
this is extended and a sheep eats it
sheep can eat grass even if they have
their wool so
if the sheep is up like that and he eats
the grass and it's a soil block if we
if we have the grass like this it cannot
spread to the soil block it's out of
range
because it can only spread one block up
is its limit
if we had grass above though it would be
able to spread to it
which we don't want because it'll mess
up all our
our sensing abilities here
that's also why this farm is going to be
inefficient because we don't have very
many grass blocks around so it'll take a
long time
for grass to spread to the soil
so sheep have very little opportunity to
eat grass
because they're only they're limited to
the one block and it regrows slowly
but this is mostly just for fun
i'm going to put some extra lighting
down here my
my mouse is breaking it's ah i just got
this mouse too
same thing that happened my last one if
i single click it sometimes double
clicks
it's really annoying
i want to get rid of these torches down
here
all right i hope you guys are ready
we're gonna do the redstone now and look
into
the logic behind this this is the
part of this that gave me the most
trouble took the longest to figure out
in my first attempt the redstone was
about uh
six long by four wide so we would have
had this spacey
sheep like five blocks apart from each
other
my second attempt the redstone i think
was
three wide by five long and in the final
one it is two wide by five long
so i managed to compact it quite a bit
the goal of the sheep farm was to
have the sheep automatically pop up
right when they regrow their wool
that's the only time i want to see them
i don't want them to pop up
if they have no wool on so
i'm guessing you know how a bud switch
works but if not we'll go over that
because it's very important to this
that's what we're using to
to detect if they have their wool or not
so if you power a piston diagonally like
this
and then it actually powers the piston
but it doesn't update until you put a
block next to it
and that triggers it doesn't matter how
many times you do it now it's going to
stay extended the only time you can
cause it to retract is if it's unpowered
and you cause another update
okay so
i'm gonna have trouble with this
probably i might have to check out my
creative world
but this is a piston we're going to use
to detect the grass growing
there's going to be two stages to this
and this is what makes it difficult
because
let's say the sheep has no wool right
now he's on top of this block
and it's a soil block
if we made it pop up when grass grew
the sheep would be up there but he would
not have any walls so there's actually
two stages to this
we need to detect the
the grass growing and then detect the
sheep eating the grass
and then it becomes soil again and the
sheep pops up
so to do that we actually need a double
bud switch
that it does not self reset
so this is what i came up with um oop
i'm gonna try to polish this up as we go
to
um this is our first bud switch here
this will detect
the grass growing we have to power it
diagonally
so i put that there and then
this is very complicated i think it was
here
i had a torch block here block
there
torch powers this block goes to the
redstone redstone powers
the block here which will cause an
update
yes
and it does not itself or it's uh
does not reset when we unpower it so
that's not good either
so then beyond that we're going to use
this piston here as our second bud
switch so it's going to do
two things for us it's going to it's
going to be a bud switch
to detect when the sheep eats the grass
and it's also gonna when the sheep eats
the grass it's gonna cause the update to
the piston and piston is gonna
pop pop the sheep up so it's a pretty
fancy
little piston over there
when that extends it will send power to
this
wire
and then we power this piston diagonally
using this block here
so the redstone goes to that block it's
powering it diagonally
now if there's an update next to it
it'll pop up
and it still does not self self-reset so
or it does not
i'm mixing up my phrases here it's
it's not doing that until there's an
update
next to it which we have to add yet
otherwise
we will not be able to control this
thing after one use
so it does that does that
even if we turn this torch off the
sheep's gonna stay
up there
yeah so the double bud switch here is
very important to this design
it's not it's not two separate bud
switches
they're working together this wire only
becomes powered
when this first one goes off
i trap myself see now it's powered and
now it's powering
the second one diagonally otherwise when
the grass block
rose originally if they were two
separate bud switches they would both
get triggered at the same time because
that one's next to it
and the piston below is right next to
the block two
oopsies
that's not right
is it emitting light now what the heck
that was weird anyway
glitches in the game the next one here
is going to be the exact same except
it's mirrored
so
weird mirrored mirrored torch goes here
and then instead of being over on this
side
the piston would go on this side
and do the exact same thing
and wire would be on this side
like that
so yeah it took me a while to figure
this out
and there's more to it yet so don't
think this is just it
otherwise i could make this wiring a
little bit smaller yet
okay test it out yes
that's working
good
all right and then just mirror it on
this side and then repeat the pattern
all the way down for every four sheep
that's all you gotta do
we're gonna jump ahead a little bit here
and go to there's gonna be an auto
wool collection system with this too and
to do that we're gonna get rid of these
two blocks
in between the sheep
on all of these not that one
raining again
i don't know what it is about the
minecraft server but it rains on there
all the time
okay well we do that for all of them now
let's just hop down
and then
there's going to be grates
not that way i'm going to use upside
down stairs like this
to make a little bit of a crack for
items to fall down
oh it's actually we should probably do
that before we do any more wiring
otherwise
it will be in our way
and we'll do a few on this side and then
i'll show you how it works
okay so we're going to use water to push
items into the grating
this is what it looks like
in between the two sheep
now the thing is if you use a water
collection system
we got to put water
where is it we need one here
one here we'll probably make it come
from the ceiling
above we'll have a piston that retracts
to drop water down
at our command
and the other one would be
here i guess so every every that
frequency
will have a water drop and
i'll show you
if we had these holes here the water
would just pour down them it wouldn't
carry the items to these grates
so in the end of all this we need blocks
in all these otherwise
the water will just flow down there
we'll cover them temporarily
over here i just want to show you the
water pattern
got two buckets with me
one will go there and
like that it's gotten extremely dark in
here
one thing i did not plan with my design
is where i'm putting the lighting
so we'll have to figure that out yet
because we can't have torches on the
ground like that
the water will wash it away
excuse me okay so
if we
wait a minute is that right
something's wrong here something is
wrong
the water's in the wrong spot maybe
must be this one
goes here right yeah there we go that's
better
i had in the wrong spot so you see the
water emerges together
right at these grates here which is
important
if we have a block thrown like that
pretend that's wool
it'll always find its way to that
and it covers the whole room here
okay let's go down and see where they
landed
then we'll probably rig some lighting in
here
so all collect down there and then we'll
have water stream here
which will get all the wool into a main
water stream and it'll all
probably flow towards the front of this
farm
the lighting
if we put a light here
the light level 15 if we put a lamp
there be light level 15
down one is 14 13 12 at this block
height
here 12 11
ten nine eight and that's the farthest
point
so it'll that'll work because
mobs spawn at light levels below eight
so that's just
barely enough so i'll put lamps every
all these places where there's three
blocks i'll put in the middle
on both sides
uh
oh man i can tell already this is going
to be a long episode
oh it's all right though it's okay we'll
make time
somehow i might not get it all done
though but we'll
we'll get the bulk of it done i don't
want a whole bunch of loose ends where
people will be asking questions
like crazy um
that's lighting we got our grates in we
got the holes dug
we got these dug for the water to pour
down
a little access way here just powering
the glowstone with
levers i got most of this stuff in
i had to get rid of the torches here
just for now until we get the sheep in
otherwise these might extend for some
reason while i'm
trying to get the sheep in and that is
the next thing we gotta go get some
sheep
get them down here we'll need 32 for
this thing
and i'll have to make like a sheep farm
here to fill my sheep farm
yeah so i'm going to do like a little
pen for them or something
and i'll have to get one per hole
all right so i'm going to take the sheep
out of this sheep farm
here this is what i
oh dang oh
this is uh where i got the black wolf
for the ender ender
i don't think they can fit
there we go come on guys i don't want to
take all of them but we'll try to get
a bunch just to speed this up
and if a few get free
it's okay i'll come back and try
round up and event get lost
and i am heading over to my base i got a
hole punched ready
to drop these guys down
oh this is gonna be hard
okay we're here i'm gonna drop them down
this hole
i don't think i lost any that were
following me from the beginning
get on down
they won't walk down on their own but if
other sheep bump them they'll fall
or if i bump them
and good okay so we got a few anyway
take that out so they don't drown and
there we go breed a few
and i'll probably have to
take a bit of a break here to give them
time to grow and breathe and whatever
okay so i'm gonna try to clean up the
rest of the sheep there that i might
have left behind
okay these guys seem to be dying so
we're gonna get them out of here
or at least one died
aha you are the winner
come over here so we gotta do it one by
one
that's it that's it
yes okay
this is a lot easier in creative mode i
just use spawn eggs
anyway that's what i'm going to be doing
for a while here and then i'll i'll get
back to you
oh man that was painful oh
that took that took a long time
i made i made a few trips from that
main sheep farm bred i bred a bunch
there brought them over
bred a few down here but this
this was too small to really breed a lot
down here
but i got them in one by one
they're all standing there doing their
thing
yeah so next step of this
finally got them in place uh
i mentioned before with the water
it has has to go over top these holes it
can't flow down them
otherwise the automatic wool collection
will not work in this
so you could put a sign like on that
block there right there
and the water would flow over just fine
but the problem is i'm going to
illustrate this
you know what i need i need shears
make a quick trip to the storage room
shortcut
that's why i want well i guess i could
take i could have take
i could have taken that path over there
but i always forget about it because
it's not fully built
nope i bet you there's someone's chest
yes
okay so let's make this guy pop up
we have a block above so he his path
finding won't let him
wander away um
i'm gonna put that torch back so it can
work
we will force an update ourselves
or he'll help us that works too
okay so if we
this is what it'll look like because the
top part of them sticks out because
they're a block and a half tall
and they're one block down uh if we
shear him
there's a good chance the wool will fall
down that hole
it didn't happen that time but quite
often
it would happen
which we don't want so we have to put a
full block there we can't use a sign or
a hatch or
ladder or anything like that has to be a
full block
update
so this is what we're gonna do uh we're
gonna
get i'm gonna use a piston for this you
can use glass you could use glowstone
any block that won't suffocate the mobs
you can use
and replace two please tell me we can
nope
i just fill these now i wish i didn't
um what we'll do
this is a tough part
i'm gonna put a block next to that just
for now
no that's not gonna work uh how do we do
this
i wish you could put levers underneath
blocks
um we need this piston to be moved down
maybe i can get one more
just about no places it sideways
i guess i'll have to go on top and just
do it that way it's kind of a pain
get that down um
put one filler block in
oh man this is gonna be such a pain
i forgot to retract it
and one more
just like that so that is a piston is a
block that won't suffocate them
so if they get pushed up into it they'll
be just fine
for that put this back
then we will have a lamp here to hold
them
down so they won't climb out so now
let's do it again get the idea of the
effect here
i'll have to come up with a faster way
of doing this though of course updates
there's another one it's not suffocating
that's what this sheep farm is going to
look like when they pop up you'll just
be able to see them like that
you can't get out if you shear them
the wool won't fall down into the piston
it'll always come
on the top i've tested it many times
and also important to note is the wool
will always land within
a three by three area
or one block away from the piston in all
directions
all right so i gotta do that with all
these i gotta get it
gotta get the piston there and the lamp
here
so doing this actually isn't too bad it
goes quick if you do the whole line like
this
and then just go up on top
i got my levers all down and you just
you can pretty much just walk across
pretty quick get them all
go down put another block or or whatever
you got to do
and that's it so i take that out take
the piston out
and uh so we got the block here to keep
the sheet from jumping out we got the
piston there so the water can flow over
top
and soak in the items and
this doesn't get in the way of the water
stream it's off the ground
very good the next thing we're going to
do here i got some wool prepared
and take it i don't like how when you
shift click it goes to the
the bottom right
should go in order oh
get her wool i don't want to mix up my
order this is
the way i want it
okay and since there's
room for 32 sheep there are 32 sheep i
should say
we're gonna have two of each color if we
want to change it later we can
it's not not a problem and we'll use
the wool above the the lamps here to
indicate
what sheep is there because we won't be
able to see them if they're underground
alright so they're grouped by twos that
works out perfect
got them down but after looking at it i
think i want it reversed
so i want this and
that way so i have to reverse the order
of them all because these ones are more
colorful
they'll look better if the colorful ones
are in front
yeah i prefer this order much more
looks good nice and colorful at the
front uh
so you probably guessed it but these
lamps are gonna be our indicator lights
that turn on when the sheep grow their
wall and we're gonna
wire that up now we're not done with the
redstone yet
this is what we do i'm gonna add an
extra block here
so remember the torch is underneath
powers this goes to here
i can't remember i think it's a repeater
yeah repeater redstone dust
can't have those two connect put a block
here
if we had the repeater here it would
send power to this block and then down
to that wire
which we do not want so this this wire
here is important
and then we're gonna have to do more
digging i
went through another efficiency for pick
but don't worry
i got plenty of them plenty of them
not gonna run out um
so go to this block then we'll put
redstone torch there
block above uh we may as well take out
another
layer here
we'll just follow it up
okay and then we put another one here
that's two
and then
this goes up to the top of the ceiling
or the roof as it's also called
wire goes here there right on top the
wool block
and now if that's powered it will light
up the lamp below
so you gotta do that with all of them
it's gonna be fun
um we can actually test this out now the
other thing this does is it causes the
update which will
make it all retract when you reset it
by the way my shovel's gone too
sheet pops up let's go check them out
so we'll have to dye them all too the
colors that we've
picked so he'll be yellow and you can
see the lamp is on
because he's popped up like that um
[Music]
let's just try this out so if we were to
send a pulse to this torch
now it actually retracts all of it
all the bud switches and everything so
that's
what we want we gotta do it for all of
them now
and then i'll be back we gotta we gotta
end this episode pretty soon though it's
gonna be like an hour long one
well it seems like it's die time so
let's get our dies
that i had prepared
you can hear the sheep from here i don't
know if that's from the guys in the pits
or if
we're always going to hear them
all right you ready you ready for this
oh yeah it looks cool
[Music]
so we will dye them their colors um
given enough time if these guys ever get
out of whack
like the sensors they will auto correct
themselves
because the sheep keep eating and it'll
just keep triggering the bud switches
until they get to the final
stage which is with their head popped up
like this that's the end of the cycle
so
the only way uh to reset it is to
unpower that torch let's
let's head down quickly
we got to send a pulse to this and that
will reset it so they go back down
and then soil blocks gets grass block
she beats grass block pops back up until
we reset it again
that's the cycle
[Music]
anyway i'll dye them and uh
got maybe one or two more things we'll
do today real quick and call in an end
yeah i forgot to show you guys the top
here i've been mining it out a bit
and i got the wires going to all the
wool
to all the lamps um
what we'll have to do is hook up our
water
thing here we might wait till 1.3 so we
can
shoot water out of dispensers because
that seems like the simplest way of
doing it
oh yeah check them out man that looks
cool
we are missing the two hardest to get
colors
of course we'll get cocoa beans soon
so i don't mind using them i got three
left anyway
skittles okay
um next thing we're going to do here
let's hook up the reset we'll need
buttons for that and we'll have a manual
reset to this and we'll also have an
automatic
reset using the water system which we'll
add later
the manual reset buttons will be over
here so if this guy's popped up
we shear him he's gotten a wall we
collect the wool and then we hit
the reset button to get him back down
that's the way the manual one works
doing this
and then we gotta hook up the wiring for
this
right so these buttons are for the
manual reset there's one per
sheep we have that option but there's
also
the option for an automatic reset and
that
that gets triggered by water falling
down
and pushing the wool we share from the
sheep into these grates and then
before the wool falls into a water canal
it's gonna do this we're gonna have
fences here
in between these two things so now we
can't walk through
that's why we do it last so wiring is a
little bit easier
um put pressure plates on that
the wool will hit the wooden pressure
plates and then fall below
here so the water canals will probably
be
here and go out this way
and then run all along here to the front
but we'll wait till we get ice for the
water canals
coming out in 1.3 as well
um but these the automatic reset and the
manual reset connect at the same line
so we'll put the repeater up there
see it's triggered um
[Music]
two blocks here
redstone dust there another repeater
going that way and we need the repeater
because
this torch goes to this block so if we
didn't have the repeater there a dust
would get powered
by this probably and mess things up
that goes to another block
we'll need some dirt
that goes to redstone dust now
the what you'll call it we'll cheat a
little bit here
it's right behind here so
to use that we're gonna put a block here
and again we have
trouble of our wires getting mixed up
here so we have to use
a repeater again i believe
maybe i'll double check this i don't
know if we do
yeah because that torch goes to that
block so if that was a dust that could
get powered
unintentionally uh we'll put a block
there
so this repeater powers it from above
for a manual reset and the automatic
reset
powers it from below so they both go to
that dust right there
and it turns out we have hit
what is this the storage room wiring
which might be a problem i hope not
but the goal was to then
yeah it's a problem dang it
uh i might have to do a little
improvising to make this work now
but it shouldn't i know i have a way out
of here
it was very
anyway i'll find it i'll find it i know
there is one
man that sucks so with these first four
it looks like our first three anyway
i'll probably have to make some
adjustments with the wiring it'll
probably be
a bit more sloppy but i'll show you
on the right side here instead i got it
set up to where we were
so that's that's the dust there we have
to get that dust
to this torch so what i
think we'll do
take away more wall i actually went
through
pretty much all my picks on today's
project
and do a spiral staircase down
to
[Music]
at least here um
where's the torch i think it's
it's on this side so we got we want it
to go to the inside
but i think
yeah this is what we'll do
we have to be careful because
we do have to set up water canals yet
and they will probably have to go down
one block otherwise the water will flow
into that wire and we need
this part here
so water will probably go here we can't
have
like wire here either for example we'll
have to make sure there's a wall there
so this will go down
like this maybe we'll do a torch
let's see where this goes i think this
will go to the torch
and hopefully we gotta be careful not to
interfere with anything else so
i hate to mess up the grass
yeah that should work we went a little
bit too far
we'll put a torch here
then we will put i always have to do
or make my wire path something else just
so i know
in case it gets washed away or something
is that right we might have to invert it
yet i don't know
no it's powered sweet
okay so we'll clean this up
and i think that's good
don't think that interfered with
anything
go up top and we'll try it out uh let's
force some updates first
this one first
and this one okay our sheep is up there
let's see if the reset works
uh maybe we'll shear him even don't have
shears
the orange ones look yellow call me
crazy
but they really do tell me this works
oh that's so beautiful
and the pistons got reset yep
so now uh when that grass block grows
the first piston triggers the first bud
that preps the second one
when the second one goes off uh the
sheep goes up
pop-up sheep farm that's the idea
so that's as much as we're doing today
this episode's probably an hour already
i'm sorry i wanted to show it all
working in
and everything but we'll continue on
next episode
most likely there's a few other
things i would like to do with this
but i'll try to get the wiring done
afterwards here and next episode we'll
we'll take a better look at everything
and then afterwards
sometime i'll try to make a tutorial for
this that
shows you how to build it in only a few
minutes instead of
a whole hour or whatever and there's
also a bunch of simpler ways
you can set this up too the whole pop-up
thing is
is my favorite part of it um you don't
have to have detection and lights and
and everything there's much much simpler
ways of doing a cool farm with this idea
but this this is the coolest way in my
opinion
all right i hope you enjoyed the episode
i spent a lot of time on it
and i'll see you again next time
you