hello everybody this is etho welcome
back guys to another episode I have
become best friends with these guys they
have taken me as one of their own they
love me they won't let me go oh I should
not have jumped in this hole with them
cuz I don't know how to get out look at
all those polygons okay I'm gonna try
light the ground on fire it's not gonna
work okay let's try it in der pearl out
of here Oh that'll work that'll work Oh
ate the portal Oh No come on there we go
yeah so I'm still goofing around with
these guys trying different things I
just set up a way for them to get into
the nether whether or not I'm keeping
the setup I'm not sure yet there's
there's so many ways you can mess around
with these guys though and have fun with
them I set up like a piston thing that
pushes blocks to the middle and when
that happens then the water extends and
they flow towards the portal but you can
shut this off as well right it's not
perfectly set up why can I not click
what on earth
it won't let me click it all right I'm
killing it that's what you get I don't
really have the water set up properly so
I I have to do that anyway so I've I've
experimented with dropping them through
lava and stuff how did he get out huh
oh and he's gone okay yeah so try
dropping them through lava mostly just
for the visual looks it's pretty cool
when they're all jumping around in here
on fire he's back hey guy known for a
stroll oh the water disappeared okay now
they start bouncing I I made it so two
of the slime blocks down there or
there's two slime blocks and then
there's two non slime blocks so
sometimes they bounce sometimes they
splat and it kills them for sure you
still have the nice bouncy effect or we
can send them to the nether and then
like store hundreds of them and now kill
them all with T&D or something and get
XP and all kinds of good stuff or this
guy he doesn't I feel like something's
messed up he's not trying to attack me
oh okay he is a mind um or I don't know
why but I really want to make like a
hamster city type thing for these guys
like have tubes all over the place and
junctions and have them going all crazy
I don't know I changed this around just
a slight bit there's a glass running
down the middle now and this prevents
them from hopping across from one side
to the next and they get through this
thing a lot quicker that way most the
time sometimes they have trouble still
uh anyway oops
oh I don't want to be down here
anyway it's going pretty good okay so I
think we are going to try set up killing
chamber for them in the nether here
that's the nether hub right over there
and strongholds to the right here so
it's not very far off our path that we
use all the time
TNT might be a myth myth a bit a bit
messy now that I think of it because if
you blow it up by a portal the portals
going to get blown up and you'd have to
teach them city and probably and yeah so
maybe we'll just try poison potions and
damage potions yep listen that sound you
hear that that is crazy you might have
heard a motorbike go by two loud
motorbike alright let's try this oh I
think so mom how come
all right let's fell in one is it not
hitting them all some of them aren't
taking damage alright they stopped
taking damage okay that time it did it
okay alright cool yeah it'll probably
work okay surprisingly the biggest drop
of these guys is actually fish pretty
much you had so much fish from them what
do you do with it though you can't even
trade it with the the fisherman
villagers they they don't need it that's
what they try to or no what was their
trade they I think they take raw fish
and an emerald and they cook it for you
or something stupid so you can't trade
it with fisherman villagers I'm pretty
sure so I don't know what to do with it
all I just I could eat it but I don't
know anyway I just thought of something
one of my villagers I'm pretty sure used
to buy cooked fish
pretty sure I checked them here but he's
not saying it he's not saying it anymore
like the old villager trades the farmer
ones would buy cooked fish I don't think
you can get that trade anymore though so
you would have to have one of the old
ones in your world in order to take
advantage of this which I'm pretty sure
I did have let's just get like 19 I
think that was a maximum just to be sure
do 2 to 2 got lots of iron again 2 by
the way just great over 2 stacks of
blocks should keep us going for a while
because I did some caving under the
Guardian farm um yeah okay that's good
let's take this and and go check
something here I'm not sure if this is
going to happen my villager traits have
gotten messed up as I've been using
these snapshots so I don't know what
will happen here this guy I'm pretty
sure I remember like fishing for hours
to get the fish and then I traded them
cooked fish to unlock some new trades
but I don't see it in this list anymore
there is this and I think this is what
it was I think this was the cook fish
trade right here but it's blank now yeah
it's not letting me do it darn it I'm
almost certain this was the fish one
that turned blank for some reason we
could try unlock more but I don't know
if I have any chicken let's go check our
storage room really quick here there's
also all the guys at the village here
but I haven't traded much with them so I
would doubt I have unlocked the cooked
fish one
see got fish in here you see chicken oh
I do have chicken look at that
alright well we might be able to do
something here although I'm pretty sure
it only unlocks new trades it's not
going to unlocked any of the old trades
villagers had even though it's an old
villager we'll see I realized something
- we're never going to finish project
Pokemon here anymore the time has passed
on it so we might have to put some fake
guys in here to fill the spots because
now there's more than five or six
villagers and also I can't get any of
like blacksmiths and priests like we
used to anymore
Oh
oh no that's the new one darn it I got
excited there for a second you trade
them raw fish and an emerald and he
cooks it for you he's basically a bad
furnace oh man that's too bad that she
unlocked a lot of trade sowed in it got
some new ones
Oh fishing rod unbreaking one four eight
wow so generous he does buy string
though that's a good one selling arrows
yet sell heroes selling bread yeah all
right I want to pick these up let's see
let's get rid of or stack these is there
any other trades pork chops you know I
don't have pork chops and this guy had
this is the old librarian written book
glass has been traded paper has been
traded because just about the shutdown
mmm all right I'm going to check that
other village really quick just to be
certain now I checked it out here
there's three farmer villagers in this
village like three of the old guys none
of them have it unfortunately the only
other thing I can think
there's a village out where I got the
horses I might go check out just really
quick out of curiosity yeah
this farm is actually getting used now
that they replant my wheat here which is
awesome so I didn't and harvest the
wheat and then they come by and they
plant the seeds for me and oh it's great
guy get to work get to work we need any
crops that's one of the guys I just
traded with here if they ran out of
seeds I can throw them stacks the seeds
too and they think areum just cool ok
here we go this might be the village I'm
thinking of let's go check it out see if
anybody's alive still they haven't had
visitors and and so long oh I hear one
definitely heard one yeah it looks like
I blocked off the doors that looks like
a farmer hey guy you want to buy some
fish oh it says fisherman oh man you've
been you've been to a fied no this is
there's no way this is a words oh don't
go out guys don't go out okay that's bad
I'm pretty sure this is not a new
village farmer are these old school
trades I don't think they are huh huh
wait is that two different ones or was
that the same day two different ones
okay this must be a new village end
because these are not old villagers
check out this guy although I'm almost
certain they were before does it make
sense that they wouldn't be because this
is like before I change to amplify
terrain right
pretty sure and they're all all new guys
okay well we tried oh man okay so the
village we were just that was like
somewhere over there and I was looking
around the plains because I need donkeys
right so I was just curious if I left
any behind look across the water here
and I see there's more Plains and it's
like well maybe I left some donkeys over
there so I go across no this is all new
terrain I've never been here this is
within its look at the coordinates we're
less than a thousand blocks away from
spawn and there's bunnies here there's
bunnies oh man what a find I love these
guys so much there's lots of them
there's bunnies all over the place
they're doing their dance and the
scenery here is pretty amazing I don't
know if it's going to render too well my
computer is struggling to keep up in
this area I don't know if it's because
it's creating new terrain or what but
let's just go over here so I looked out
here this looks pretty awesome you see
that up there though that's what I want
to go look at there's a village on the
hill and the houses are at different
levels I've never seen anything like
that before I don't think and look at
this oh this is so cool oh man I'm
tempted to try it this might be a bad
idea
amplified terrain with extended view
it's doing it it's doing it gotta love
the new snapshot it's taking its time
though because I'm recording here oh I
guess that was about it actually like I
said there's only so much you can see Oh
actually wait wait there's more loading
back there but this is a pretty cool
mountain area now let's see if we can
figure out how to get to this village we
go down here Oh horses moving slow
oh yeah it's struggling to keep up this
is what it does now it like goes into
slow mode alright I'm going to stop
recording figured it'd be easier if we
left the horse behind but yeah look at
this we got houses at different levels
there's just like a random house over
here some paths that's pretty cool this
is probably a farm of some sort going
all the way up oh there's a guy in there
too oh man village in the hills I love
it pretty cool
full-sized village yeah you guys got a
pretty nice place here I like it I like
your style
these mountain homes beautiful scenery
we're up that till why a hundred and ten
here it's crazy
oh okay so I was on my way back and I
ran into our ice farm here so it's about
a thousand blocks that way that new area
and it looks like our ice farm doesn't
work anymore no I'm not sure why this is
taiga but it's not making ice I've been
here a while it's not happening it's
just not happening so we might need to
make a new one in the future
and that's our stronghold base up there
alright guys so we are back here and
I've been I think I was afk for 10 to 15
minutes here just letting them build up
they're getting ported over to the
nether um I've killed lots of these guys
but I haven't really collected their
drops like I never setup a hopper or
anything I just enjoyed watching them
die that make me bad is that my bad
person no I'm a good person
yeah so now I actually need their drops
because I want to build with some of
their blocks that they get
or that they make so I just let's head
over the nether and just see what has
happened there
how many of accumulated before it gets
too crazy all right I'm gonna have to
ender pearl as soon as we do it it's not
set up too nicely at the moment okay
yeah
Oh am i in the hole please tell me I'm
down the hole oh sorry guys sorry one
sec ah turns out I had a hole in the
glass somewhere and they have all been
escaping this whole time there's
randomly throughout the whole place here
and it's just a nightmare like yeah oh
I'm trapped
oh no I can't stop moving here so tell
me gonna keep going um man I guess I
gotta walk away from here and go despawn
I guess is what what I have to do and
seal up the hold and try again they
worked out much much better this time
they're actually trapped which is good
we have a 300 in there so maybe 350 that
sound that scream it's it's so bad when
there's a lot of them all these guys are
still here okay they didn't all despawn
most of them did anyway so whoa that's
intense
those particles let's try with the
particles off much better the poison of
ocean particles doing it
alright anyway the reason we are trying
to fuel up a batch of these is so I can
get some blocks I'm playing around with
walked with these new blocks I wanted to
see what they would look good with so I
brought over a bunch of different types
that I thought would be
interesting to try here okay they need
to be quiet let's do it I think they're
ready to turn burgles on again all right
here we go
just a final scream to end it all that
worked pretty good it killed them all oh
why are more coming Oh
did something go through the portal and
I loaded it on the other side maybe
that's interesting
got some levels anyway so I'm trying to
block sear that work with it I love
absolutely love nether brick with this
dark color stuff I think these two my
top choice right now get lost man come
on yeah these guys are my favorite mob
they are so cool I love everything about
them they look awesome I like the sounds
they make they move like crazy
they're just so good um what else
this diorite stuff is another really
good one I really liked it with the
lighter color prismarine blocks like
this stuff do you mix them in oh yeah
very nice let's see and they also the
dye writes really close to the lamp
color as well the sea lantern here so
these two are these three blocks
together go really good together
there's also lapis thought lapis would
be nice to try it's it's pretty good as
like a focus block like something really
bright that stands out I like it
another focus block that people
sometimes use is emerald and that also
looks pretty good it's very a little
closer in color
let's see just regular stone I think
is pretty decent to different types of
stone just that great color is good
although I don't think I would use it I
would prefer diorite over it now and
then wanted to try n stone because these
are like opposite colors or negative
colors from each other so yeah I think
those look good too the other two I
don't think I would use it though
because apparently most people hate em
stone it as I learnt from the the runic
build there um acacia wood I thought
would look good it's not bad I it's okay
it's not I don't know if I'd actually
use it though it's pretty good blue clay
not bad um this is a smooth block though
this these have texture so I think these
look better with blocks that have
texture like nether brick for example um
what else did I try I think that's about
it actually so I'm going to try to
design a room here with these definitely
using nether bridge and diorite I think
and either
emerald or lapis in places maybe alright
I got the room done guys let's go check
it out let me know what you think of it
I didn't have a lot of space it's a
small room but it was just enough that I
could experiment with the new blocks and
see how they work together and I'm
actually pretty happy with how it turned
out I do think these blocks go good
together it might just be me but
especially the nether brick and and this
greenish cyan color stuff is really good
dye right is also really nice I like to
have like a light color block a dark
color block and then a colorful color
block like a base color in my bills
usually usually I just picked three main
blocks and that's it three main colors
and mix-and-match them so
yeah and this room does what I needed to
do kill the mobs here and I got a chest
here for the collection stuff I think
I'm going to have a chest here for
damage potions and I also snuck an
enderchest here there's a drafting
tables underneath here for some reason I
need them and I just need to hook
something up to turn it turn on and off
the portal back there and that's it and
should be pretty easy to do I'll just
add some more buttons up here for on and
off on the portal I think will be easy
to hide the wiring yeah anyway let me
know you guys think of this I was
considering maybe using this for the
amplified terrain bass there's these
types of blocks but I'm not sure they
would look good with grass and and
natural stuff I think we need to go more
nature-themed with that but we will see
here is the comment that picked up for
today as well does hey etho what is the
most fun thing about making YouTube
videos and what is the most boring thing
the most fun thing for me and I'm pretty
sure most youtubers or at least when
they started is the comments I love
reading the comments especially if I've
done something in a video that I'm I'm
interested like if I don't know how
people are gonna react to it it's always
fun for me to check it out if it's a
good way I expect them to react if it's
a bad way it's like oh no I don't want
to put this video out but that usually
doesn't happen yeah I think a lot of
people get into YouTube originally like
if they're doing it for a hobby the
reason they get into it is because they
they like getting the feedback from
people that's that's what does it for
them and and yeah so when you leave a
comment don't act like I'm not going to
read it some people talk like talk about
me in the comments like I don't exist I
see those so don't be afraid to dress
your comments to me I do see them um not
that you can't talk with each other in
the comments as well anyway least
favorite thing with Minecraft there is a
lot of in between stuff that happens
that I don't show in the videos because
well frankly you wouldn't enjoy watching
them probably sometimes I gotta wait for
things to happen sometimes I do a bunch
of grinding work like last couple
episodes I've been digging that hole
that's not all that fun although I do
like watch videos and stuff in the
background when I do that kind of stuff
so I made it fun for myself it's not too
bad that's another reason I don't like
recording that because if I record it I
can't watch
stuff in the background and yeah anyway
so that's going to do it guys I hope you
enjoyed our episode oh let me do one
thing one thing has been driving me
crazy here and I got a deal with it
today before I forget again I keep
needing to do this every episode let's
take these the mushroom blocks now are
split there's the brown ones and there's
the red ones I don't know if you can
still get the original what they were
before here let me show you what I mean
in my my room here I haven't tried I
haven't tried cutting a mushroom with so
Dutch I should try that actually not
sure if you can get these anymore I hope
you can because these look really good
too I like that block but the thing we
need to do delayed ending to this for no
real reason
I just gotta fix this mushroom it's
driving me crazy
it's not gonna be a perfect fix but
it'll do
stupid creeper blew it up a long time
ago and I have to see that all the time
but you see the bottom it's it's
different right
so yeah and the inside not that it
matters too much anyway got that fixed
very good so thanks for watching guys
I'll see you in the next one have
yourselves a good day
bye-bye