hello everyone this is
etho and welcome back guys to our let's
play series so minecraft 1.10 is
officially released guys I've updated
pretty cool apparently it was a hundred
days since 1.9 came out so it seemed
really fast right like 1.9 came out and
then BAM one point ten but you know a
hundred days that's over three months
that seems like a decent amount of time
actually if we got a update like four
times a year that would be great I think
so I've just been checking out things
making sure the deme isn't broken
one thing that was biting me was my
storage room here but now that I'm
recording it's super smooth but when I'm
not recording I get like this big
stutter from it kind of weird I also
just noticed I looked in in the ender
chest here you hear that that is crazy
there's a new sound for it's a couple
new sound files got in the least and I
also read there was one for enchanting
which I haven't tried yet let's try this
out
it's kind of got that sound it when it
closes - I like that
all right so I got 48 levels here I was
afk at that spider firmly built I'd
tried it out for a couple hours and I
didn't die in it so it seems to be good
my armor didn't break let's see let's go
for books I guess just didn't try this I
haven't heard the sound yet so I'm
excited here we go punch one that was a
terrible enchantment for 30 levels but
I'll take it
okay okay it's not quite what I expected
is it just the one oh no it varies a
little bit maybe that's the pitch
changing that's cool I like it see that
one that was a higher pitch I think
right oh yeah well that was pretty cool
I do really like all the new sound
effects they've added like in 1.9 and
now 1.10 they've added a couple more it
really makes the game more enjoyable I
find especially let's give a shout out
for the water but it
like that's the greatest thing I could
do that all day today guys let's get to
it here I don't really know what I
wanted to do today's one of those days I
need somebody tell me what to do I would
do a straw poll if I could if I could
get you guys its feedback but nope so
we're gonna leave it up leave it up to
random chance here I have a few ideas
let's say if we get the stone we're
gonna do building if we get a gold ingot
we're either going to build a new zombie
Pigman farm or but first we'll look into
what's wrong with the old one if I can't
figure it out then we'll build a new one
and the ender pearl will build a new
Enderman farm why build a new Enderman
farm because in 1.9 the ender ender 2.0
has slowed down significantly and now
that I got mending on everything it
actually takes me like 10-15 minutes to
repair it all at that farm and it's like
my best XP farm at the moment so might
want to make something a little bit
better so here we go
Enderman farm alright guys so I just
hopped into a creative world here real
quick so we could test out a game
mechanic we're most likely gonna be
building an endermite Enderman farm
because those are really fast and easy
to build and they work insanely well but
I want to take advantage of the splash
effect to get with the sword now now I
want to see that the actual area of
effect it looks like maybe three wide to
back right like the guys on the gray
blocks on the sides they're not getting
attacked I need to know how big of an
area to funnel them into basically yeah
it looks yeah and it looks like the ones
in the back room aren't getting hit
either
ok let's try it again I Shrunk the area
I think we're going for it's three by
two oh no no no not all of them are
being hit those guys on the sides unless
you're dead center it looks like and
just for fun we have a couple hundred
Enderman in a 1x1 area look what happens
I feel like we need to harness this
effect because this is so cool okay guys
so I think we got it figure it out we're
going to aim for a three by one area
we're going to try funnel them all into
I think that'll work out okay
and if not we might make some
adjustments bi over in our end and now
the original ender ender we built is off
that way way down there and ender ender
2.0 is off that way so 3.0 is going to
be oh no he was waiting for it
you knew give me what I was gonna do oh
what a jerk okay yeah off this way off
this way so something that we might do a
little bit unique with this firm is
we're not gonna actually have a a path
or a tunnel to get off to it we're gonna
actually make it so we fly to it it's
gonna be off in the middle of the void
with nothing connecting it which may be
a good or a bad idea we'll find out
later but yeah you can see I got here no
problem it's pretty easy since we're
going to have to fly back to the island
though we do want an up in the air a
little bit I'm at y8e right now this is
where we're gonna actually spawn the
Enderman then we got to drop them 43
blocks to get them to half a heart right
so that'll take it down to why 37 and
then to get back to the island you know
I'm gonna have to jump off towards the
void and activate our wings and shoot
myself with the arrow before I fall into
the void so need a little bit of
vertical space to do that so
37 blocks should be good enough I think
yeah so the first thing I'm gonna do is
just build the platform this will go
pretty quickly I think
it's not really much to this oh yeah I
should probably mention I'm building the
platform here out of stone right now I
will change it out to something else I
was thinking a lime lime clay
maybe with bone we're gonna go for green
and white green and whites and then the
green glass I think looked pretty good
somehow make that work because in the in
the end here things are dark right and I
think brighter colors are better so the
bone blocks are gonna be the main main
part of this I think pure white - can't
get much brighter than that okay let's
see here maybe we will actually run
pitch let's actually get the ender byte
in here already oh I just still feel him
down there I was walking forward I did
it again
let's get the ender right in here and
we'll just do a test here because I
don't know actually how far the Enderman
will get aggro on them so let's see what
do we want I got actually I think I've
got everything on me I prepared yes
let's let's change it so we'll call this
the middle this is where we want the
Enderman to be and your mites and I'll
just blame clay here so we can remember
okay and the way I'm gonna trap them I'm
gonna put down some power rails oh I
didn't bring a minecarts I have tons of
iron on me good this is the trouble
about building something like far away
it's like if you forget anything it's
the worst that's why I always keep like
iron and stuff in my ender chest here
cuz I often forget things otherwise okay
so we got a minecart bouncing back and
forth now we got to get the endermite
spawned in and I think you got to be
careful when you do this if the
platform's only one thick you can
sometimes glitch through it or at least
I've done that in the past oh that was
second try right that's pretty good it's
there 3.0
yeah we named them good so normally they
do spawn after two minutes I think but
if you name them then they last forever
okay we got them too and we will do what
let's shut that off actually no let's
just stop him from moving yeah oh wait
no he's gonna track me that's the thing
that confuses me a lot now mobs can
still like move around in a minecart
even if it's not to be powered babies
are very hard to control them sometimes
how do we own a block like right there
like right there
but we also need them on the track the
middle one
if you would align to the other side
that would be great oh hey just stay
there stay there
yes all right we got him now we got to
be very careful he doesn't die because
if an ender
men actually touches him he's gone don
skis he's done for so uh how do we do
this maybe I think we can actually use
trapdoors if I'm not mistaken I'm gonna
make a couple trapdoors let's do let's
do three and we will plan to drop the
Enderman down no not there we would want
to do it there right yeah yeah let's try
this out okay it's not gonna be like
super finished right off the bat here is
that a good idea wait maybe maybe I
should lower those I'm gonna lower those
so instead of being at the top of the
block let's put them here so they should
see the endermite they'll run towards
them they'll hit their face on these
trapdoors and then fall down right let's
hope yeah something like that and then
to actually make them want to go to the
Enderman or the ender mites I keep
mixing the two up man put down some of
these we need a couple more use some of
this ugly jungle wood up finally been
taking up a space in my chest forever
I don't think I've ever once built
anything with jungle wood yet all right
there we go I thought there's anything
wrong with it it just looks likely okay
that should work right I'll just put
this here for right now
and take away the torches over here make
it completely dark and let's just see
how far away they'll track them did I
mess up anyway they might actually
teleport to this side of the platform
this is all kind of temporary that will
actually block this so they don't kill
them that's sealed up good now okay
let's back off
and just see what happens who they go
pretty fast don't they as soon as they
spawn that is really cool okay there's
one way in the back there oh he he he
saw him okay
so we can make this platform bigger for
sure and it's done no this is the old
internment farm the first one we built I
just wanted to come check it out cuz I I
know it was broken because of the
pressure plates but we were having them
spawning up here and it looks like it's
the Pistons they're spawning on the
pistons now kind of interesting okay
let's go back oh I'm lost
it's this way right yeah I also was
trying to get the Enderman to be spawn
over here so it seems they can track in
termites from a very far distance like
crazy far crazy crazy far let's go let's
go back here a little bit's something I
want to try out too let's put a water
bucket here and see what they do like do
they run through it oh they do not maybe
they would teleports maybe if we put put
it further back they would teleport no
okay this is really interesting so this
guy he's mad at the ender mites but he
can't figure out how to get past this
water remove it is he gonna go then oh
that's pretty crazy so yeah we can't get
them to teleport to the endermite faster
that would speed up the mod mob firm if
we could oh man I think we finally did
it guys I better have a trouble this
platform is getting huge been trying to
figure out how far they'll actually
track an and termites it looks like it's
about 64 blocks away and then they they
can't see them which is crazy crazy
distance like no way we would want to
make a circle that big cuz then it would
take them a very long time to walk to
the end of my right oh yeah you see you
walked a little bit forward and then you
saw
so he passed the the border
interesting yeah so probably want to
keep the circle around 20 to 30 blocks
so that they don't have to walk this far
because that takes a lot of time and if
we're not getting enough Enderman
spawning then we're gonna probably want
to look into layering the Enderman farm
here like go up vertically instead of
going out horizontally just so that they
can fall down here a lot faster you know
cool so we got a little bit of a
platform built here and I'm just doing
some testing I'm taking a very low-tech
approach to this farm if you're
wondering how I'm deciding like what
shape the platform is and how big I'm
gonna make it basically trial and error
here you see like there's a couple
Enderman there they cannot see the
endermite so they're not going to attack
them so I'm gonna have to shave off a
couple blocks there or else changing the
way I have that set up so that they can
actually see them
the other thing I'm checking old man
that's a big dead zone what happened
there the other thing I'm checking here
is the entity count the number up here
the max spawn spawn Kenter what am I
saying the maximum mob count is about
what was it 79 or something sometimes it
goes a little bit over that if it's a
packed spawn but yeah we want our number
to to go up to that pretty much to reach
you know a decent size of a mob firm
here right now it's only going up to
maybe 10 20 30 you know so I got to make
the platform quite a bit bigger here the
green block at the end there is 32
blocks away from the endermite I might
go out to 40 maybe even 48 and then it
looks like I might start stacking
vertically but we will see I can't
really build on the other side unless I
build some kind of like distant combiner
thing to make the Enderman from this
side join up with the ones on that side
you know which would make this a little
bit more complicated anyways I'm gonna
keep working on
Oh snappers so guys this is a little bit
later now oh no I missed really let's
try it again
a little bit later now I've been placing
a lot of blocks and this thing is pretty
close to done now oh it's so cool too I
just love watching this I've been
staring at it for like 10 15 minutes at
least just watching all the little black
specks fall down the hole here it's very
satisfying somehow yeah it's working
great though I'm really happy with it
I found a configuration that's not what
I meant to do or did I look at any of
them I can't look at them because then
they teleport to the tower here that's
why I got the stained glass to block the
view what was I saying
yeah I found a nice configuration for
like the trapdoors and and the way I did
the the whole endermite area they don't
seem to ever get stuck or fall off the
edge which is great that's really cool
even with like so many of them falling
falling down here and if you look at our
f3 thing here at the entity count here
again it's not quite at that like eighty
mark that I wanted so it could even be a
little bit bigger I think and it would
be a bit more efficient or faster XP
farm but honestly it's probably good you
really don't need to make them this big
kind of wet overkill on this already but
you know maybe maybe I make it a little
bit bigger I could do some some extra
layers too if I want but I don't know
let's actually start setting up the
killing area I think before we even
think of that I would also like to add
some kind of design into the floor but I
that again that as well would be a huge
addition so I don't know like some kind
of pixel art or something would be cool
don't look at any of them but yeah when
you're down here look how big this looks
it's crazy
it's an 81 diameter circle centered on
the endermite here and the minecarts and
you'll notice I changed this around too
I got rid of all the columns that were
blocked
their view and instead of having like
blocks here I just got trapdoors next to
the ender meit's six regular trapdoors
here and then I think there's seven iron
ones here there's no way of them
actually getting the ender might as far
as they can tell and they're all doing
going down a three by one area I think
but I'll have to I will have to maybe do
some experiments on that maybe it's not
I can't place a block what happens if we
do this and let's do loop because it
might actually be it's three by two I'm
not sure if I'm cheating a little bit on
that it seems okay let's try oh it's not
gonna let me put one there is it now
stupid in termite is in the way he's
bigger than one block for some reason
like that I can't place any blocks next
to the minecart like right here
well let me plays anything um
pistons yes let's do Pistons and just
temporarily put this here don't have any
way to activate yeah you could make a
lever right yes all right and yes I do
have a lot of bone blocks thank you for
asking even after doing all this I still
have lots because I never throw anything
away in my world here and turns out
bones actually have a u s-- now which is
great alright let's do that dang it I
lost the piston that makes me sad okay
now what's happening are they jamming up
at all that's definitely a 3x1 they're
falling down now seems okay right I
think we're good I'm also tempted to try
like a one by one and just see what
happens out of curiosity is that a big
mistake though I wonder Lee let's find
out let's put this here and then
how we did it is that gonna jam up oh
yeah you see they're kind of getting
stuck they kind of got a weight freed
for each other to fall down but it's not
bad really right although I am down here
so not as many are spawning
I should go up here and let's just try
that out because that would simplify it
even more if I can get them to one by
one yeah you know it's not that bad
actually we might do this
it does jam up though a little bit and
sometimes like they do fall off the side
but maybe if I tweak it a little bit I
could I could make it work so you won
just off the side there if they fall off
is that a big problem
probably not especially if we can make
it where they fall into the void
wouldn't be an issue yeah I think well
well I should do that
cool so now we're gonna start doing the
killing chamber area whoa I looked at a
bunch I looked at a bunch I'm going to
run and jump off the edge without my bow
cuz I'm crazy
don't you know all right there's a new
game I like to play on my base here you
gotta jump off the bush here it's really
hard to do jump off the bush there and
you gotta get through the door here we
go nope oh one more try one more try for
the camera I've only done it a few times
oh oh here we go here we go
yeah third time's the charm
alright I actually ran out of bones in
my storage room surprise surprise but we
should have no
there's a few here and then there is
several chestful over here still oh yeah
I forgot you can actually convert Boom
Blox back into bonemeal oh well we're
here now let's actually use the bones
otherwise I got to recraft the bone box
anyway head yes what am i doing that's
not what I'm doing that's what I'm doing
green yeah so this one by ones working
out pretty good I would say I think
we're gonna roll with it the only thing
is we got to shut this off while we work
down there cuz otherwise anything we
build they're just gonna be like all
over us it's like a shower of Enderman
down there flying all over the place so
yeah I think the way I'm gonna shut this
off is just do like a piston thing here
it's gonna be hard to place the blocks
like actually in the middle there
because they're constantly walking there
so I'm gonna do this lever slowly push
over a wall of glass we just got to
block their line of sight to the
Enderman endermite it's like that fifth
time I've done that today at least right
okay let's do this and now I think we
can go down right I hope oh snap bow
quickly kind of regret removing all that
dirt now we just about we're at void
level there but we should be fine yeah
we're fine
Oh
smooth landing okay so I made sure to
bring a water bucket with us here so we
could do this we're down here we got to
go down to I think why 37 I said all
right Michael a few blocks below that
just to be sure though and okay let's
not do it too quickly
it's about ran off of there again yeah
this is how we're gonna get down though
and 42 let's make sure I'm not catching
up to the water looks good
yeah boats about over here
and it looks like they're falling down
right here right so I'm gonna build
stained glass all the way up like this
and hopefully all the Enderman stay at
the bottom here this should be far
enough down that they die as soon as
they hit the ground here and then I'll
just raise the blocks until it doesn't
kill them so despite my best efforts I
have dripped up they are not dying
they're supposed to be dying like I just
like flew through the glass didn't II
okay
I don't you saw that that was kind of
weird it's terrifying uh man did I
really get this frog what are we get or
why thirty-eight I wanted to go down at
least two more blocks how did I do that
wrong okay well let's let's get a few
bucks down yeah I'll just do that that
should be far enough okay so to get rid
of these guys oh I hate working over the
void man this is like the most one of
the hardest episodes to record yeah this
is get rid of these fools whoa that was
cool it was really cool uh get the glass
a little bit lower
I guess what do we want to do here I
don't even know what I'm doing here yeah
let's go down here get rid of all this
garbage because it's not at the right
height I'm worried I'm gonna look at
what he says and he's gonna punch me off
of here actually before we do that
okay what are we doing what are we doing
let's put a block right here and that
should kill them if I can these they
keep pushing me out of the way though
and I can't place it
oh there we go oh okay so that is
beautiful oh my goodness is this crazy I
really got a place a block here but I
can't it's not gonna let me
okay let's carry to the block again
we'll try go one higher no that was to
higher yeah let's just build a little
platform so if they do hit me here it
doesn't shoot me off into the void
I'll kill these ones I know they are
landing right now right yeah so this is
a one-hit kill if I use my sword yes
that's what we wanted that's what we
wanted awesome cool so let me build a
bit of a platform here so I feel a bit
safer okay cool so I just built a tiny
little platform here nothing crazy yet
got to get a chanting station and bill
and your chests all that kind of stuff
over here but just for now let's have
some fun with this and actually check
out the rates and that kind of stuff so
we have gets a 72 out of 75 one of those
is a minecart one of them is endermite
one of them is me maybe that would be
the three missing or there might be one
stuck up there yes I can't tell it's so
crazy
so as this game that goes on it just
gets easier and easier to build farms
totally nuts like that first ender ender
ender I built you see all the Pistons
and stuff I had to do for that in this
one since I it's just like oh just put
down a bunch of blocks and it works
better than anything ever uh-huh so how
long was that I figured what like as I
was building this it would take no
longer than 15 seconds
oh my goodness look at that ah maybe
there's about 15 or 20 maybe 20
I'll have to check the recording here Oh
actually did I run out of XP before
finish wait a second beginning X piece
the goodness be Austin's all drop yes I
can definitely like you can only pick up
XP so fast so with Enderman this is the
fastest you can get it alright guys so I
just did a little bit more cleanup here
I got rid of all the stone and garbage
we had on the back back of it over here
it's made a little bit of a platform
there I haven't noticed them ever
teleporting past the barrier there if
they do the endermite is still protected
but I think because they're agro they
never teleport like even when we did
that water test before they wouldn't
teleport past the water or through it or
anything like that so I don't think it's
a problem I do have some torches back
there and some of that light bleeds over
to here but I don't really care to be
honest we have so much spawning space
anyway well I do kind of care but you
know I'd rather it look a little light a
little nicer around the inner mite area
then worry about the spawn rights here
so the lighting is 6 yeah not a big
sacrifice anyways I will show you I
don't think I'm gonna do this I might I
don't think I'm gonna do it though
currently we are getting all the
Enderman down in about 17 seconds I
checked the recording and it was
consistent 17 seconds every time there
which is cool if I want to add more
space though this was the idea I had
like more responding area without making
it go horizontally there is a problem
that happens because Enderman are 3
blocks tall right
and you can't the stack another platform
above here because if if the Enderman
sees the endermite here is in walk
forward BAM
fall damage right but something or a
trick I had in mind is you can use a
slab then like that
you take fall damage if you fall for
blocks you don't take fall damage if you
fall three and a half blocks so this
should work in theory right so the
Enderman will see the ender mites in the
past wait a second no way in the past
you didn't take fall damage if you fell
three and a half blocks why do you do it
now or does it only work the other way
okay so I had no plan for stacking them
vertically it seems okay nevermind I'm
pretty sure in the past that was the
thing but I just it isn't anymore okay
well what about trapdoors right we could
probably use trapdoors yes okay so yeah
if you want to stack them vertically
this is a trick you can use all you got
to do is make sure they still have line
of sight to the endermite wherever
they're standing on the platform but you
could add like additional Rings
vertically probably several layers high
even yeah I think that would work maybe
I'll do a little bit of a platform here
just to get some spawning and we'll see
if we can catch it on camera see if
they'll walk off of there without taking
damage oh here we go
what just happened so they that was
weird
that's very weird they teleported after
they fell they took fall damage right
I'm not imagining that I'm going to add
another layer in front of it I guess
because they might have walked too fast
tape okay the one guy he walked up the
side because it's not centered but the
one guy that walked forward he
definitely he was definitely fine that
time so I think I think it could work
Sunderman farm has one little problem I
have to show some restraint with it over
1,000 entities oh man
yeah I gotta be a little careful with it
if I kill them too quickly I can
probably crash my game eventually yeah
anyways I'm gonna add a I'm gonna
improve this area a little bit - it
needs a roof so they don't teleport out
of the chamber there so you got one guy
over here you shouldn't be there also if
you guys have ideas for like pixel art
or whatever for that let me know I might
just do like some abstract green clay
mixed in could look cool as well or I
might just leave it as it is it's not
really a big thing honestly well anyways
guys I hope you enjoyed that project as
much as I enjoyed building it so that
was it that was a lot of fun actually I
really like making mob farms in this
game it's one of my favorite things to
do so that was really cool
here is the comet I picked out for today
says that last part with eating and
falling into the water transition was
really cool so at the end the last
episode I was flying around right eating
course fruits I think a lot of you guys
thought I actually cut the video when
actually it's a trick you can do a
really cool tricky and do with course
fruit let's get up way in the air here
so we're at Y 3:30 right now if we eat a
tourist routes BAM
right to the ground if you do it above
water though then it I think it just
helped would see downwards and another
cool one that I like to play around with
is see if I and do it here well that's
terrible with ender pearls if you do it
just right you can you achieve a pretty
cool effect here try it one more time
let's get up in there
learn to fly
I'm failing the takeoffs today I can't
build up any speed but yeah if you throw
an ender pearl you got to do it in an
open area but if you have you over here
will work you teleport to the ground but
you still fly here maybe maybe I'll cut
for a second I'll try build up some
speed and and do it really good here
okay that's not what I was trying to do
but that was cool too I've been trouble
doing this to work I gotta admit but
basically you face-planted to the ground
but before you hit it you quickly look
up and then you keep flying there's no
reason I keep like sticking to the
ground no I don't know why
there we go I did it kind of I don't
know the idea is a faceplant towards the
ground before you hit it throw ender
pearl look up and then you fly up again
so you kind of makes it look like you do
a like a v-shape on the ground and would
look really cool if anyone was watching
you which nobody is clip you guys but
you can't see me from the perspective of
another person I'm full of arrows thank
you for watching guys hope you enjoyed
today's episode take care
bye bye