hello everyone this is etho welcome back
guys today I learnt le not
alien-abduction
villager affection is hard work these
guys have been fighting me non-stop
they've been teleporting to the wrong
portals I think I lost one of the guys I
was trying to save which one is this oh
this is the infinity guy well who is the
third one that disappeared
he's got infinity and forty three okay
no don't you run don't you run away from
me so I'm going to start storing these
guys that have really good enchantment
trades at the library and if we later
get ones that have the same enchantment
for cheaper we will trade them out with
with the cheaper price guy but it is a
lot of work getting them here and I just
have a temporary setup right now I'm
just going to stick them in these glass
blocks for now yes there you go your new
home forever
sucks to be you I got one more guy to
get over here I guess I didn't realize
this guy had two good trades then
infinity book for five emeralds is
pretty cheap in my opinion it's fortune
one is expensive but it's a good book
but I'm sure later we'll get a villager
that has the same enchanted book for a
lot cheaper I'm gonna let's see I need a
fence or something mmm anyway I want a
fence so that he doesn't get killed here
I got to remember how to make a fence
every time now because it's changed
actually I could use a fence gate kinda
night that might be cool alright fence
gate we will put that in front and I'll
probably change out this glass for wood
later but for now this is good oh no I
can't click on them
oops all right we got the other guy here
so the ultimate goal with this is to get
pretty much one of every type of book
trade at the cheapest price possible
ideally this guy he has that's garbage
looting three I don't know what his
final one is either yet but looting
three is definitely a good book to have
it's not cheap so we'll probably get a
better guy later but I just want to
start collecting these guys so we we
Fisher have them
oh no oh no no no no how did you get in
oh I think I left the whoops I left the
way in because one of the villagers got
out earlier uh yes so guys I have been
in this village for quite a while and
the population has expanded a lot as you
can see I've been feeding them I know
you're not supposed to feed the wildlife
but I've been feeding them bread and
it's it's causing them to overtake the
land unfortunately and they do weird
things like this sometimes it just looks
a little wrong a bunch of nice people
though you know what they sold me these
pants and they are mighty fine pants
aren't they look at these very nice not
too tight there is some chocolate on the
knees but I like them they're pretty
good
hey no pushing bunch of crazy Wildings
so while I was here I decided to do
something I made a book called villager
trading and I referenced the the
Minecraft wiki page to do this it has
all the stats there and I've basically
wrote out all the different trades you
can get so that I don't have to like
switch between minecraft and so that you
guys can see it here too so we have what
they're buying what they're selling the
item the number of that item and then
the price and emeralds at the dollar
sign there and we got it for pretty much
all of them here I think I did all of
them actually get the librarian so with
a librarian looking on the site it says
that for level 1 enchantments it costs
five to nineteen emeralds to is eight to
thirty to three is eleven to forty five
that looting three book that that
villager was selling was forty three
emerald so it's really close to the high
end on this chart right because it's a
level three inch
meant that at cheapest you can get
looting 3 for 11 that means and like you
can get efficiency 5 for 17 emeralds so
this is nice to have 2 because I didn't
really know that before so um got that
we got yeah we got all the trades here
you know the butcher I just realized
something he sells cook
he sells cook he sells pork cooked pork
five to seven for one emerald I kind of
like that I might start eating pork I
know a long time ago I say that I would
eat golden carrots from now on but it's
just too much work I don't get that much
gold really to do that if I do this I
don't even need to kill cows anymore I
just buy them off the the villagers why
not um but with all this trading I've
been doing here and all these new guys
some of these guys aren't really keepers
like he's got feather falling to fortune
to expensive cost and it's just the
garbage villager basically protection to
like the most expensive paper amounts or
amount he wants for an emerald this guy
he's not a keeper at all so I had this
problem last time that when the village
had all these villagers I didn't know
what to do with them
this time I have finally built a room to
store them and I just set this up it's
not polished in any way but basically
I'm going to try to get maybe three or
four of these rejects of society into
this room and then we'll have some fun
okay so we found five guys here no fries
to help us test this out these are the
failures of our society
he has good like redstone is perfect
lapis is perfect worst glowstone trade
worst enchanting trade and almost
perfect flesh trade but he's no good
we're trying to get the best of the best
here and
and those are going to go to project
Pokemon these guys they're going to play
a game with me I'm gonna take off my
armor so it's a fair game
I have no advantage are you ready for
the first annual villager battle arena
type of thing uh whatever it's called
look at here we go
all right pause the the roof is not tall
enough all right you have a handicap for
the for the first round I guess darn it
this 3x3 door is not gonna work the
babies keep running through it stay out
this is adults only all right
so round two around one whatever it is
take your bets who's gonna win there's
the 40 and 37 dial make sure I teach
them separate you cannot vote for me
though all right
who's it gonna be who's it going to be
here we go now they're still hitting the
walls started oh I think they all got
hit okay next guy that gets hit is out
for sure
oh no not counting me um oh he got hit I
think he's a dead man oh I might die
actually Oh
I should actually try to dodge them Oh
down to three butcher wins although I'm
still in this all right so this is me
but me and him who's it gonna be
stop fighting by the door oh no oh oh
you got it you got it okay
he's out I think oh now he lived he
lived
I didn't regen I think I woulda lost
already
let's save me Oh No I've definitely been
hit the most fun of anybody though how
he's out that's it game over whoo that's
that's pretty chaotic how did we do on
the arrows uh it's not quite a bit left
actually cool that was fun
oh yeah check it out guys I was just
about to leave the village and I saw
this guy did some trading with him so
he's got depth Strider one all right
that's into fancy
I love dip Strider but it's gotta be
level three bane of arthropods five Oh
never gonna use that kind of a mid-range
price on it but here's here's the big
thing right here unbreaking 3 for 11
emeralds and if we check our book level
3 stuff 11 is the cheapest you can get
so he's a cheaper no don't run away no I
want to imprison you come with me well I
got that guy into his prison cell where
he's gonna sell me cheap books for the
rest of eternity oh yeah so we're gonna
move on to something else here now
looking at the comments on last episode
a lot of you guys seem to like the
windmill which is cool
thanks to your bang
what was that did I imagine that anyway
um wait - did someone get inside
actually oh you did get converted how on
earth did you get him oh I bet you got
him through the glass
no you jerk
that was our farmer villager darn it
darn I'm not happy about that now I
gotta move another one over here oh man
so the zombie must have gotten through
this glass cuz it's thin enough for
something yeah I'm just gonna kill not
worth trying to convert him because
there's only like a 1 in 8 chance of
getting a farmer again anyway
ok I'm gonna sleep here ok yeah not
happy about that but what can you do
alright so like I was saying a lot of
you guys seem to like the windmill which
is awesome that means we will probably
use this style at the amplified terrain
base even biggie here likes it right
piggy pointer I'll kill you oh yeah of
course you do
he loves the windmill the two things I
got though the most is it's too short
and it's too chunky too fat which I I
agree it definitely is um I kind of made
it like a windmill at slash house for
some reason I don't know why I think I
was thinking of a like a lighthouse and
how there's lighthouse keepers and maybe
there's windmill keepers but I don't
think there actually is right I think
that's something I made up in my head
anyway that's that's the style we'll
probably use the amplified terrain but
it's not what we're going to be using at
our next project here I scouted out a
location and I think over here is pretty
sweet this is where we are going to
build the Nexus so yeah
so I know I said I wouldn't start this
until we got all the the supplies ready
but I think we can at least lay the
groundwork this is not like a something
I can do in a single episode anyway so
we'll just like do some of the
groundwork framing and that kind of
stuff get started on it anyway and that
way I don't build the whole thing and
then find out at the end of the episode
you guys don't like it or something so I
can sort of play around with the looks a
little bit and then get your feedback
before I finish the whole thing
so Plains biome is pretty nice because
it's nice and flat here so here's make
setting this up easy I think I'm going
to build it partially in the hill and
partially out of it and if we want it to
look more in the hill later we can just
cover it with dirt or something
afterwards and like build a mountain
around it building a mountain on our
building around the building sounds like
a big job but compared to how much work
this projects gonna be over all that's
gonna be a really small thing to do if
we do end up doing that um
TNT woo let's see how messy this is
Oh Oh
okay good so far
whoo
Oh how far down this go a little deeper
than I wanted
looks like cleared up most of it that
whoa I wasn't too careful with how I
placed the TNT there I just sort of
spammed it and I wasn't sure if it would
be too clean looks okay though yeah I
think this cleared out a pretty good
area so I'm going to clean the rest of
this up I have a haste to begin on top
of the mountain right now so I can - out
pretty quick the TNT was more just for
fun although it does clear out a pretty
good area - when you use a lot of it
alright I wanted to show you guys the
sunset here because it's just so
beautiful isn't it you got the windmill
over there some weird cave over top and
down goes the Sun so I'm just chipping
away here this is a scary part for me
this is when the thoughts go in my head
like did I did I start this wrong is
this was this a bad idea to TNT the
mountain should I have built it a little
lower a little higher a different spot I
don't know and I always get worried
could with such a big project like this
any little mistake can have huge
consequences later and this is not a
fully planned out project either like
don't don't think I've got this all
figured out I have the redstone
mechanics figured out but the actual
looks and shape of the place I have not
planned yet so we're going to be doing
probably a little bit of problem-solving
together as we build this but not much
today we're just laying the framework in
the yeah getting things set up here so
that we can start building it basically
I think this is as far in as I will go
with my planning I figured that would be
40 blocks long for the main room there's
gonna be three rooms to this there's
going to be the main room with the
chests that store stuff there's going to
be a control room in front of that and
then I think an overflow storage room is
the way I'm planning on doing this in
the main room
I'm going to give every single item the
same amount of storage then for things
like cobble and sand and and that kind
of stuff that will probably go to the
overflow room and then we'll have to
figure something special Oh special to
do with that yeah with this build I am
focusing more on function than looks so
I'm just going to say that right off the
bat here JC works expecting something
looking incredibly amazing I just want
this thing to work and if it looks looks
good all the better but I just want it
to work so we're trying to just get it
get it together here anyway I was
backing a little bit oh boy the doubts
are setting in guys I'm starting to have
second thoughts about how I'm doing this
now now that I see it now that I'm
thinking about it a little more so let's
run through this okay so first off the
storage room with the chests I expect is
going to be at least 40 blocks long so
that's from this Storch to the back wall
probably 45 to 50 though really and then
we'll have the control room in front of
it so that would be like from here to I
don't know how big it's gonna be but
maybe like here let's say I feel like
maybe we should go further that way so
it's more built into the mountain but
also I'm starting to think it would be
cool if we went down some stairs from
the control room
into the storage room like if we went
down maybe five to seven blocks of
stairs and like this is one two three so
we wouldn't want to go at least four
blocks down which makes me think I took
out too much of the ceiling here it's
like it should be maybe that high which
isn't a problem really because I can
just like put some dirt over over top in
front of it and it'll look like it's
it's shorter hmm yeah so there's going
to be basically two tunnels to this
thing I think is the way I'm going
do it so there'll be one there one there
they'll probably connect at the back so
you can like go around do a horseshoe
type of thing and then from the control
room the stairs will probably split two
ways so like a fork that goes either to
the right or the left yeah tell you what
I'm going to show you the faceplate to
the Redstone I don't want to show you as
to much like how it's gonna work just
yet I want to build up a bit of a shock
and awe factor to it because when you
see it you're gonna be like oh he plans
to do that are you serious and a lot of
this will make more sense later but I
just want to show you maybe how will do
the faceplate to the storage units
alright guys so my plan is to build it
out of quartz
maybe hardened clay maybe some glass
maybe some coal blocks if we can work it
all out I'm not sure you'll have to let
me know if you like that idea my my
thinking behind it is it's like a
high-tech redstone a futuristic crazy
you know type of building maybe it
should be like quartz and clean type of
building instead of like medieval or
something like that that's why I chose
quartz I have a pretty decent supply of
it built up right now so hopefully I
have enough to make it happen it's kind
of gonna go like this so basically row
of chess and then hoppers above those
and then more chess no I didn't bring
enough chess start it above like this
this will be a double chest oh I do have
enough what was I thinking there I don't
know
I'm crazy alright I can't jump and then
maybe this will go up one more one more
and then stairs running across like so
creeper
no there's still a few dark spots on I'm
trying to be careful and then mmm so
that's pretty plain as it is so maybe we
will try add some 3d depth to it so I
like bringing this out one more or
something I don't know exactly like so
and then some half slabs on the ground
here I don't know how I'm going to work
the clay in yet though like any ideas
guys any ideas maybe could we do this
maybe I'll have it in the ground in
places I don't know exactly what I'm
going to do I haven't planned planned
this out too much just yet
but then if I want to do item frames
that's will they'll go and I'll most
likely have signs saying what each item
is all right so that's the basic just do
it the basic gist of it I'm mumbling
here I don't like this I don't know how
to use the clay it's going to be all
quartz nothing but quartz pure white as
far as I can see yeah so the idea is I
would then mirror it on the opposite
side I don't know how wide I'm making
this either yet but I'm guessing I want
at least at least that probably even
more maybe maybe this far and then we'll
like have another one mirrored on this
side oops type of thing I'm also
planning on maybe stacking another unit
on a second layer though and that will
probably end at that height there so
it's going to be a big room which makes
me think this is too narrow so like if
it's really tall you don't want it super
narrow or you feel claustrophobic so it
might need to be even wider and then
there'll be about 15 blocks like three
six nine twelve fifteen and then same
thing over here and then it'll be
mirrored over
years so this will be the second tunnel
I need all this space for the redstone
it's there's a lot of redstone I can
simplify it a lot if I add a gap that's
two blocks wide like if this isn't just
a single wide thing between I didn't
really explain this but basically
there'd be another section over here and
it would just continue on forever
basically
and then you know like this and yeah the
exact same thing copied over here if we
have a lot of these that's going to look
pretty plain too so maybe every few
sections mate maybe every two or so I
would have to add another layer of depth
to it just to break it up a bit but I'm
not sure I don't want to spread it out
too much because it's really important
everything is kind of closed and compact
together because items have to travel
down a nice stream and if it's too long
they're going to de-spawn before they
get to the end of it so I can't be too
fancy with the details mmm did I say
everything I wanted I think so I'm I'm
probably boring you by now sorry for
that I just wanted to let you know the
plants if you have ideas let me know at
least two blocks wider here at least
maybe four even we could have something
fancy in the middle if this is really
wide then I know what I forgot to tell
you so there's going to be 256 different
items in the storage room so each one of
these columns is one item two three four
so each of these sections is four items
since it's mirrored that's that's eight
items and since there's two tunnels
that's 16 and if we stack it vertically
that's 32 so 32 times something 16 is it
I know it's going to be 8 right I'm
using my calculator now 8 yes so there's
going to be 8 of these sections why it's
so 1
two three four five six seven eight is
how I'm laying it out yeah all right
let's go do something else okay guys so
we don't have a lot of time left this
episode I thought it might be cool to
show you what's going on at our wither
skeleton farm though I don't like
recording in the nether usually because
it's so dark I tried a night vision
potion I don't know if this makes it
better it's so bright isn't it might
make it worse actually I'm not sure but
yeah let me give you a little tour
what's been happening here so I I work
on this every now and then whenever I
feel like it's it's one of my long-term
projects and I'll put up put in a few
hours here and there
I had diamond armor on this episode
because I worked on it before I started
recording and I forgot to take it off um
I'm outside of beacon range
all right I'll deal with you and then
I'll look over the edge but yeah I check
it out I've done tons and tons of half
slapping around the place that's all
half slabs all up the walls um I think I
did some up there there's still a lot I
need to do if I well if I want to like
it's good as it is I've added in all
these half slabs between the walkways
I've also done something recently where
I took down all the railings along the
walkways and this is to get more one
second
distracted yeah kill them all well yeah
this is it's gonna be hard to talk with
these guys after me all the time if you
got railings like this and like a mob
tries to spawn here since there's no air
spaces around it like right next to it
it's going to be a lot lower chance
you'll get wither skeletons you want as
much air space around a potential
spawning space for wither skeleton
because the game checks
like 20 blocks all around I think it is
unless that's changed which is a huge
area right but the ones that really
matter are the ones closest to it like
two or three blocks from it it's very
important there's air spaces two or
three blocks from each spawning space so
I got rid of all the railings I've put
in this like raised railing all along
the sides here everything is nice and
flat these half slabs are below the
walkway so that they don't take up air
spaces like if they were here that
wouldn't be good
so you want it one lower and did some
modifications around here so that I can
see it a little easier if there's wither
skeletons like inside the fortress these
intersections I've reworked a bit like
this used to just be a pathway then I've
added in like the six by six corners on
each of these and that adds a lot of
extra space for wither skeletons to
spawn might add a few layers I might
start automating things with pistons
later I'm not sure here's another one it
just helps to add more spawning spaces
for these guys basically I gotta stop
picking hips Oh
outside of beacon range I can't sprint
oh man we're good everything's fine once
I'm in beacon range everything's good I
need to set up a few more of them II but
yeah let me show you what's in my ender
chest gradual ease guys inside my ender
chest we have 46 wither skeleton skulls
I'm getting a lot of them just by
working on this and that means maybe big
wither fight maybe I should just grind
them out and kill them I don't know um
but I gotta get some beacons again soon
I got no spare ze but yeah that is our
farm right now kind of rushed over this
but I thought I'd show you because
it's been a while they're at it again
yes I figure I get about 10 to 20 wither
skulls per hour at that firm now which
is just great I love it it's actually
really fun to hunt them too with the way
I got it set up is eerily you're running
around you're jumping off balconies
you're one-hit-kill and everything it's
it's actually pretty fun I used to hate
like farming with her Skelton's it was
the most boring thing in this game now I
would have to say nether quartz hunting
is probably the boringest thing in my
world here so hopefully we don't have to
do too much of that if we if we use
quartz I wish you could buy it from
villagers please umm but yeah we should
probably get to the comment here we're
running out of time it says etho do you
prefer modded minecraft or vanilla
personally I think they're I think that
there isn't enough things to do in
vanilla so mod it is nice to add more
goals and possibilities but that's just
me I really enjoy both of them I've been
having a ton of fun of my single-player
lately just like been wanting to play
like I spent 15 hours or so since last
episode playing in the world here just
because I wanted to doing like
off-camera stuff um I don't know I think
if I had to pick one I would pick
vanilla um I find people get bored of
vanilla if they run out of ideas and
yeah modded minecraft is more like
you're taking in contents like the mods
are your content and you're going
through it which means it has more of a
end life to it like it ends like even
with the crack pack I found I kind of
guts
we took damage got a little uninspired
with it towards the end like I
kind of felt like I did everything you
know which I find modded minecraft has
that problem a lot it's got a shorter
life to it but there's a lot of variety
in it so you can just mix it up and it's
fun again like I've been even though I
got sick a crack pack a little bit I
have
crash-landing which I've been having a
lot of fun with Terra Firma craft so now
this two different ways of playing the
game I find vanilla is more about coming
up with ideas and being creative mod is
more there's a bit of that to it but
it's also more just taking in the
content uh-huh anyway that's it for
today guys I hope you enjoyed our
episode and I will see you again in the
next one take care have a good day bye
bye