[Music]
eggie readings everybody this is etho
and welcome back once again to another
let's play episode so here we are
standing in sandy city sandy city or
meme city as it has become oddly enough
the llamas aren't really walking around
anymore I think I think the guy died or
teleported or something he's not there
anymore yeah might need might need some
fixing but you know we started this a
long time ago this was part of the biome
enhancement project we just had a field
of sand here and wanted to do something
interesting with it right so we started
out with the city gates and to this day
I still actually really like these geese
I think they're pretty cool we added in
the walls the walls are kind of like
their whatever they're they're okay
they're not great they're not terrible I
don't think and we also tried like doing
a combo house here so it's like eight
buildings combined or something in kind
of a weird pattern again it's okay it's
not great but I don't feel it's bad
enough that I should tear it down
maybe I should I don't know anyway sandy
city's kind of like a whatever kind of
project right to begin with here I
thought I would try to give it a little
bit of an update see maybe I can get
inspired to finish it or something if I
make the right changes to it the big
problem I had before is not a lot of
stuff goes well with sand still in my
field but now that we have the stripping
bark I kind of want to try try some
stuff out here cuz I feel most of these
go kind of okay with it
even when I was building this a lot of
you guys recommend I did I used like the
orange sandstone with the regular
sandstone by fine they clash quite a bit
like the color the color difference is
pretty extreme Wow if you look at like
the Keesha down here I think that works
a lot better than than that now so I
kind of wanted to try that out like
maybe
like for example it's thinking about
putting in some lines in the build we
got to get some more color into this
build there's a really important thing
maybe we could do stuff like this just
like do that's turn it over and now we
have like a little bit of color mixed in
right
even I don't know if you can see it but
there's actually some smooth stone here
which I tried to make it stand out a bit
more but you can't really see it cuz
it's the same color
maybe we get rid of those and just add
that in here and basically I'm gonna go
around the city here and try out a bunch
of a bunch of detail that might be cool
right even on the walls we could do that
like maybe you might want to do it over
here just run like color color strips
around here I think it'll look kind of
good for the houses this dark oak
I find stands out quite a bit so I'm
thinking either we change it to this
like that looks a lot better in my
opinion or we might even change it to
two oak this is what color I wish
sandstone actually was instead of the
kind of the brighter yellow this would
be perfect for sandstone okay and I
think we're gonna like start putting
stairs here create a bit of a shadow
make it stand out a bit more something
like that
uh-huh yep yep so I did that I did some
stuff here some stuff got done and let's
check out some of said stuff all right
so overall I think it looks a little bit
better now I'm I'm happy with that the
oak stripped bark is pretty nice it's
that sandstone color we all wish we had
but just mixing in with the sandstone
does kind of bring the overall build
towards that color at least I did that
in a melon tree and with the buildings I
just added in some color strips on the
sides as well using different colors of
clay you got yellow and green on the
side added some flower pots here some
banners we got the original etho banner
there
and I'd do anything on the side it's the
banner over there banner I barely know
her um never heard that one before no
all right so I do like the gates with
the acacia here I put it all along the
walls here and I think that looks a bit
weird right
am I crazy I don't think I'm crazy I
think it's too much too much of the
lines so we'll probably want to tone
that down a bit I think maybe change to
birch or oak strip logs instead still
have this stripe but make it not stand
out so much so that the gates look kind
of special you know yeah just a little
bit of an update I think that's good all
right I did want to try something you
know we never do really it's I don't
know if we've ever done this breed the
llamas I'm worried they're gonna wander
off and start dying and I went through
so much to get him here do they eat this
stuff I thought they did where do they
want this don't you get hurt Sofia yeah
how do I get you to follow me yeah you
got to use the leads apparently they
don't follow any food item not a single
one and then they do that Caravan thing
so I'm having trouble getting them to
breed he's eating my food but not
getting hearts I don't know why these
are the last two llamas - I think one of
them got out and I don't know where he
is because two of the gates aren't
actually closed oh there it is there it
is aha oh yeah and by the way I tried
tried adding some more melon cacti there
- mmm tell you what let's try feed him
if he gets hurts we'll bring him over
aha okay you're the guy I want then get
out you can't get out you're stuck good
job come on all right yeah I'm wondering
how did we get them here originally did
we just bring two over and then breed
them twice because we got four llamas
total ones in the llama Vader and then
we got these three
thinking maybe maybe the babies can't be
bred for some reason cuz only those two
can I thought I could make him grow up
with that no oh yeah you can't okay no
hearts maybe cuz he was just bread let's
go I'm actually curious now let's go to
the Llano viewer guy and see if we can
maybe breed him - oh good it got hurts
wonder what's up with that one guy yeah
he's not here he's definitely not here
it occurred to me he probably died
because of the water updates as it
weren't perfectly fine for so long and
now he's is gone so I'm guessing some
physics of changing the game and he got
stuck somewhere and drowned in the water
but anyways guys it is that time again
where I do something I know I shouldn't
do but I'm gonna do it anyways and you
can't stop me haha I'm going to be not
ending the episode like you thought I am
going to be starting a new project
that's right aha we're gonna be making a
game called mastermind I'm actually
pretty excited about this a little bit
of backstory I played this game when I
was like I don't know how old I was I
was a kid right and I have never once
seen this game again like you know when
you go to someone's house and you check
their closet they got monopoly if if
you're lucky they might have
scattegories or taboo or something or my
all-time favorite board game guys you
know what it is it's the best game
careers if you've never played careers
before you you've not lived or not had a
good dinner party or whatever aha
anyways play the game called mastermind
a long time ago haven't played it since
I'm gonna try to recreate it in
Minecraft with slightly different rules
possibly because I don't know the rules
I read the wiki article on it and I
still don't quite understand
and them so I'm gonna do what's easiest
in Minecraft and it'll be pretty close I
think anyway so this is like a puzzle
game don't worry I'll guide you through
what we got to do here yeah so these are
the basic rules to mastermind as I
understand it what we got to try
recreate in Minecraft here it's meant to
be a two-player like puzzle game the
second player what he does is before the
game starts you get these six color pegs
we're gonna use concrete powder to
represent them
and he's supposed to set up a secret
code you have to try guess before the
game starts so he might do something
like red red yellow green okay and he
sets that up a I'm not allowed to see
that as a player guessing the code and
what I do I have up to 12 guesses here
where I gotta try figure out what the
code is so I'm up when I first started
out I'll probably just do something
random like I might do green red purple
blue and then if we go and check the
sighting player then like looks at what
I did and he's supposed to provide
feedback on how close I was to guessing
the the code here and he does it in two
ways first he checks if any of my pegs
line up both in color and position so
green and red don't line up red and red
do purple and yellow don't blue and
green don't so he would award me because
I got one right I think he would give
you a black peg and he would put that
next to our guess and as you would
expect if we had gotten two of these
rights just by some random lucky chance
let's say we had a green one there
instead the red and the green both lined
up so we would have gotten two black
pegs so we know we got two of them right
but we don't know which ones like it
could be any of the four right so we got
to keep making guesses try to figure out
which ones it is by alternating up our
colors and there's one more way that the
second player is supposed to give us
feedback he checks if any of the colors
in our guests matches the colors in the
answer so if that was our guests over
there
and this is the answer there's no purple
in the answer there's no orange but
there is blue we guessed one blue and
there's two blue so I think we would get
one one white peg no black pegs because
none of them line up in position all
right so this is all the feedback we
would get if we were to do like green
blue purple purple then again nothing
lines up no black pegs but we do have
green and our guests and we have blue so
then the next guess we would get awarded
two of these so essentially our goal
with this project is to recreate the
second player out of red stone because
they don't really play the game they
just give us feedback on what we're
doing the reason for that is because the
game was made in the 1970s right and
they didn't really have micro processors
to put into games back then right
so they used the second player to give
to do the work of a computer basically
to give us feedback because we can't see
the answer otherwise it ruins the game
they need someone with that knowledge
that can provide feedback on what we're
doing so we're going to try to recreate
that a red stone it's really just like a
single player game there was a system
like where you would play multiple
rounds and the second player gets
awarded points based on how many guesses
it took you to get the answer right up
to 12 if you go over 12 you kind of just
lose the round to get the full 12 points
but we're gonna avoid all of that part
of the game and just make a single
player puzzle game basically so let's
get to it here now here's the thing
about this game guys it's actually
fairly complex like you think of a game
like paper-rock-scissors even that's
kind of challenging to do a Minecraft
and the more complex a game gets like we
have a lot of input data here
16:4 colors means we need at least three
bits per peg rights if we're to convert
a purely to redstone then you get four
pegs three times twelve or three times
four is twelve twelve guesses if we want
to store all the guesses somehow that's
and 44 bits of data guys insane right so
we don't want to purely make it out of
redstone we need to come up with tricks
and and clever ideas using minecraft
mechanics to make the game easier this
is what I came up with recently this is
why I'm so excited because I think this
is the answer what we're gonna do store
the answer in item form like that and
we're gonna use minecraft item stacking
mechanics to simplify this game a lot so
let's say our guess is green red red
green okay that's our guess what we're
gonna do
convert the blocks into item form we
will throw one this way Green doesn't
stack with orange so it goes to the
pressure plates red that one does stack
red goes to the pressure plates green so
we know one of them or no two of them
lines up we know we need to award two
black pegs by doing that right that's
that's the trick this is how we're gonna
do it hmm you know I just realized this
might be a bit more complicated I
thought I thought we could use a golden
pressure plate for figuring out the
white tags and after doing some testing
on paper here I realized no it's a bit
more complex but let's look at another
example here so let's say the answer is
purple green blue yellow this is our
guest purple orange orange green so
purple and purple line up in both
position and color we would get one
black peg orange and green nope orange
and blue nope green and yellow nope so
just one black peg but we do have green
and our answer and we have green in our
guests so we would get one white peg
that's where split we're supposed to get
one black one white if we do the
calculation here ooh you see that stacks
orange goes right through on both of
those and green also goes through so
three of the pressure plates will get
pressed down this is how we figure out
the black pegs depending on the number
of items on pressure
it's we have three so for three we would
get one black peg if there's none that
means we won we guessed the code
correctly because they'll all stick to
our answer they'll stack their fall four
of these pressure plates are down that
means we get no black pegs then what we
do guys we take the same exact item
stacking trick and we use it on guess on
figuring out the white pegs as well so
it's almost like we're killing two birds
in one stone here we're doing the two
most complicated calculations in our
game using the same item stacking trick
so we had orange orange green on the
pressure plates here we take those and
we run them through our answer this way
orange orange goes right through all
four of those but green will stick all
right so there's gonna be two items in
the hopper and I thought we could do
this but we can't after some testing the
actual calculation we need to figure out
or that we need to do here is 4 minus
the number of items in hopper so we got
2 4 minus 2 minus the number of black
pegs awarded in this case we got 1 right
so 4 minus 2 minus 1 equals 1 we should
get one white peg that's how we have to
do the math so we have to incorporate
these pressure plays into our number of
items in hopper and somehow make a
redstone device to figure that out
that's gonna be the toughest part of
making this game I think cuz I I haven't
figured that out yet but wait a minute
Etha how are you gonna create the 4
colored code are you crazy
can't be done cannot be done right snow
obviously it can it's probably the
easiest part of the whole process
creating random codes in Minecraft is
nice and simple thanks to droppers we
only need 6 colors if we wanted to make
the game more difficult we can't expand
up to 9 though and whenever we hit the
button here obviously we're gonna get
random colors out of the droppers red
red purple yellow we need the code in
item form like the
- so that works out great we're just
gonna drop the items on the ice and then
run our our guesses through it alright
problem with doing it that way those
we're gonna be limited to five minutes
because that's how long it takes items
despawned even if you stack an item with
it it doesn't renew the Rhys or the
despawn timer so you're limited to five
minutes but I think we can play a game
in less than five so I'm not too too
worried about that it would be nice I
would love it if we had a copy of the
answer as well like habit an item form
hidden where we can't see it but also
have it like at the end of our play
field here and when we guess it
correctly or when we run out of guesses
when we use all 12 of them up have it
drop have a piston like reveal the code
like in front of us that would be the
dream but I don't know how to do that so
I don't know if I'm gonna bother like we
could have a stockpile of like there's
no way to like I need a block or a
machine in Minecraft that can place
blocks it would be so nice like if we
could place the concrete powder somehow
would be great but we'd have to have
like a big stockpile of it somewhere and
somehow figure out what the random code
is using item filters probably and then
like send send the colors through some
bubble streams or something up to the
area there I don't know probably won't
do it too complicated right as far as
inputs in the game I think we're gonna
do something like this let's grab the
colors I think we're gonna stand up here
just like this we have a nice view of
the play field we need to be able to see
our previous guesses of to make
intelligent decisions here writes so
nice and easy you got a good view of
everything oops yes okay so I think when
we make it yes we're gonna do it like
this it's not again it's not gonna be
perfectly nice but it's gonna be pretty
good I would say so if we wanna do
yellow yellow green red we have to place
it twice
which is kind of the unfortunate thing
about this we want the top
one two go on the play field where we
can see it and reference it for later
guesses and then we'll use the bottom
one to convert into item for them all we
got to do is like what where is it
yeah dislike drop it on a slab with
water above when it hits the slab it'll
break it into the item so if you have we
have any slabs we got no slabs guys I
break the crafting table oh I did it's
about despawn no got it just in time I'm
sure you know what I'm talking about
though if we drop concrete powder on a
slab or a sign or something ban it
breaks into item form and if there's
water above that it'll it'll push it on
the ice so that's how we're gonna do
that the only problem is we want to keep
the answers all nice and condensed like
this is possible and I think there's no
way well let's let's press this to see
what happens I think the items are gonna
bounce pretty far though so that'll one
one set goes on the play field the other
set falls through and it ends up at the
ends here yeah you see like two of them
went to that side one there none there
one there so we gotta keep them separate
somehow keep them from stacking together
or going into each other's Lane oh man I
gotta say guys like doing projects like
this is so much fun for me this is the
ultimate minecraft experience
I love problem-solving in this game I
love doing redstone contraptions you
know like when I built firms like mob
firms and whatever I have a lot of fun
with that but at this point I feel I
know it so well already like I always
use the same redstone contraptions
there's maybe 20 or 30 different ones
you hop you got hopper clock so you got
RS nor latch is monostable circuits you
just kind of combine the the pieces
together in different ways and you end
up with the unique farm which is it's
cool like I do like like doing that
stuff right but when you do a weird
obscure project like this Oh
and you gotta really think you got a
design new obscure redstone project so
you would never use anywhere else so for
this we need to take like four concrete
powder like this and split it up a bit
so that each one gets its own separate
Lane and they don't merge together so we
had to make us splitter over here so
check this out so let me grab more more
powder actually get a little bit more so
it's gonna work like this go down oh I
fell inside its where do we want to go
that's the top of it I'm lost where's my
way down over here yeah so this is our
our separator so basically I wanted to
make sure we don't put anything under
the playfield here too in case we set up
something that removes the blocks
underneath and all the concrete powder
falls down and goes into a hopper at the
end of a game would be nice that way
we're gonna have to remove it manually
so I'm trying not to put anything over
here this direction so I had to pull the
powder like it falls down right here we
activate this once you see the sticky
pistons I'll extend it pulls it back
this one retracts first and then this
one we got a two tick delay right so
some of it goes sideways here like that
so one of them fell down here onto the
slab and broke into an item form the
other three are still here we do that
again there's more Pistons there's like
two over there I think this one attracts
first and then this one and it falls
down that hole so we split it
we got one falling down there one down
there one there and there we got a one
block gap between all of them and you
can see we got them waiting here for us
I decided to put in some trapdoors
so that they all line up and when we
release them they're all perfectly in
sync with each other so we keep them
suspended in water so that when they the
trapdoor opens they they move
and then we got another water scream in
front so they can pick up some speed and
cross the ice here for that calculation
we need to do they all hit the pressure
plate at the same time and then we have
to run them through that way too
to figure out the white peg so the first
pass is for figuring out how many black
pegs we need to dish out and then the
second pass is for the white pegs all
right that's kind of cool
such a weird thing to make but it's it's
really cool so for the trapdoors I just
put we have a torch up here red stone
running above them they open downward
actually because items float on water
I had them opening the other way before
like I had them aligned at the top and
the items were getting kind of stuck on
that so we have them opening downward
instead so the item doesn't get caught
on them and initially I was kind of like
is that actually gonna work yeah yeah
you know it will because if you have ice
under the trapdoor it still retains the
slippery effect on the trapdoor while if
you don't it just kind of it gets
stalled out right because items gonna
fall off the water stream there and kind
of land on the trapdoor but it slides
just enough that it gets another water
stream so that's all good
so I guess our thing for generating the
code is gonna we want them to land right
here here here and here at the cross
sections so we'll probably just set the
right spot no we gotta go forward one
more probably have our droppers with the
random colors in don't I put in the
wrong place again right over here before
the match starts we just have to
activate these once and then we got that
five minutes to finish the game unless
we want to create a device step to
update them so that they don't do spawn
but I don't know if that's gonna be
necessary it's gonna add more
computation to the thing and we probably
just need to do it like this so the item
will shoot out it'll hit the wall here
and then fall down
uh-huh all right guys well we got a
pretty good start on this here today I
got a little bit more done here I'll
show you
but I just try to mock up we got to find
some way of displaying the black and
white pegs as well on our field here I
tried like doing it vertically and
having them in block form so for example
if for this guess here we would have one
one black peg and three white ones maybe
maybe the way we'll do it but this has a
few problems kind of hoping you guys
have some brilliant solution that you'll
post in the comments and I'll just steal
it because I I think this is gonna have
a few issues we have to have some kind
of filler material between the pegs as
well because if this is all empty space
like where the orange sand is then we
can't push it with pistons and we need
that this all to line up perfectly with
our guests so that's kind of an issue am
I gonna be able to sleep oh I can
there's been a zombie in a cave nearby
for this whole episode and he's been
driving me nuts
okay anyways I got some more of the
system hooked up to what we figured out
before so there's gonna be a tripwire
above us I think pair a few of them so
that after we enter our guess basically
we have to jump then to officially put
it in
the bottom layer of the concrete powder
falls down below to our separator and to
our water and ice system top layer goes
onto the field so we can see it and
probably like five or ten seconds after
we we jump here then maybe the sides
will update with the black and white
pegs for our guess that we just entered
in after does the calculations but
anyways from the tripwire here we got
its we got to go into our Pistons piston
system over there
it also branches down to our separator
remember we had to send this thing to
pulses so it goes to a monostable
circuit here and we do a split here so
on this redstone path has very short
delay it gives time for the wire to turn
on and off and then after six ticks it
goes on and off again so there's two
pulses to our separator we also branch
off here then and it goes down to our
trapdoor system so everything gets
synced up all nice and it goes through
our ice calculator let's see if we can
catch it in action here and then we got
one more problem I just discovered I'll
show you that - it's not a big problem
but it's it's a problem okay so we enter
our guess we're gonna run downstairs
real quick
see it here use the separator trapdoors
just opens uh-huh
so I guess with this thing watch this we
have to like have the items in a dead
stop before it lands on the ice
otherwise look what happens here okay
that one wasn't too bad sometimes they
really slide around though and they'll
actually slide out of their Lane you see
these are kind of on the edge but
they're okay I realized I can put some
end end rods like in the block that the
dropper shoots into that helps to keep
it more in the center but you see they
kind of slide after they hit the ice if
they have a little bit of momentum look
how far out it's supposed to land here
and it went all the way over to here so
we have to not just drop it on the ice
we have to totally stop it before we
drop it that's not hard to do we just
have to set up a water stream for each
of those anyways it's a good start to
this if you guys got any ideas or
feedback on it please let me know in the
comments and I'll try to try to
incorporate them into the build if
they're good but anyways guys we're
gonna get to the comment of the day and
it's gonna be fun because last episode I
asked you what's the weirdest thing
you've seen someone do in public if you
didn't read the comments of the last
episode there was some really really
weird funny stuff lots of gross stuff
too obviously but yeah somebody like for
example somebody said he saw someone put
pour a bowl of cereal and he put the
milk in the bowl before he poured the
cereal there is some messed up sickos in
this world I tell you what that is one
of the weirdest things I've ever heard I
picked out another one of these comments
it says I once saw a guy at my school
watching with his girlfriend one hand
holding hers the other hand down his
pants not his pockets
straight down the front of his pants I
watched him walk with his girlfriend
across the whole campus like this
I picked this one out because it's not
just that guy it's it's it's a it's a
weird phenom phenomenal
can't say the word I had a friend as
well a long time ago that kind of did
something similar he was always putting
his hands down his pants and it was the
weirdest thing and before I met this guy
I always assumed like the way you become
popular because he was a popular guy I
thought the way he became popular was by
having unbelievably good social skills
and social awareness and whatnot but
this guy was oblivious I think to help
people viewed that it's not like he was
like putting his hands down his pants to
grab something really it was more like
he was using his pants as a pocket I
think or maybe did just things I don't
know it was very weird and he would do
it in front of girls too and they would
get the funniest look on their faces all
anyways yeah it's weird there's weird
people in the world you don't have to be
you don't have to have good social
awareness to become popular though
apparently is what I learned I was wrong
anyways hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching and until
next time take care have a good day
bye bye
[Music]