oh hello everybody how are you doing
today
this is etho and we are at our library
project again we're going to work on
this just a bit to start off today's
episode last episode we got this door
wired very nice very nice that will lead
into the library itself and now up here
I started laying out a patio area sort
of kind of maybe we're going to get some
chairs and some tables up here maybe
some umbrellas over the tables we'll see
how much space we have and you might be
thinking what kind of library has a
patio in it and I don't have a good
answer for you well what I'm kind of
what I kind of want to do here is bridge
the line between library and restaurant
almost here in Canada we have these
bookstores they're called chapters there
it's a big franchise or something I've
only been there to to them a few times
but in chapters stores they have a
Starbucks which is like a coffee shop as
I'm sure you know but you know some of
my viewers are not from this part of the
world so maybe they don't know yeah they
have a coffee shop in them and sometimes
I think they sell like cookies and other
snacks too and there's a gift store so
that's kind of what I'm I'm doing here
I'm having fun with that idea we're
gonna have a villager up here selling
cookies or something and we'll have
tables to sit at and enjoy the cloudy
weather where's the Sun oh it's setting
come out here during the day and bask in
the Sun as we read our books or whatever
that's that's the idea with this and we
have our our railing here to hold us
hold us in place I added in this window
has a nice curve to it
and from this we'll be able to look down
into the library itself and see
the books and whatnot down there once we
get that built the question I'm having
now is how much bigger should I make
this should i I'm if you go up some
stairs and then have another area up
over here on top this this corner piece
or what or should I put a roof on this
corner piece I'm not sure how to end the
building or how to top it off from down
here oh it's dark it's really dark isn't
it I'm having trouble with lighting my
my building because I don't know there's
I don't like torches in this game too
much but I think we'll have to use a
month on this build I did have some
glowstone in that hidden in here but
there's only so many places you can hide
that stuff before you run into trouble
especially on big builds where you have
a lot of area and not too many places to
hide it maybe what we'll do I'm going to
try put some stone slabs on top of the
corner there and see what that looks
like see if it'll highlight things like
this I still want to have that library
sign out on the front I measured it out
and it actually goes from actually I can
show you if I do the 3x3 letters it goes
from there to there it is what I counted
that looks kind of cool okay we'll do
that
then maybe we will try to put some well
I guess we could go full blocks then
write some full blocks here should we
make it go up higher oh man
see I can layout part of a building but
the actual tying it all together is
where stuff gets tough for me it's like
how do we put a roof on this now and how
do we connect it
to another part of the build and that
kind of thing yeah mmm yeah I don't know
if I want a tower there I think I might
just put another patio up above there
hmm see what this looks like filled into
this it's been bugging me all right
yeah that's that's okay we can probably
do something else with that the library
sign is going to go like up there I did
experiment with making some pillars to
sort of rest it on I put them I put two
pillars here two by two pillars didn't
really look as good as I hoped so I
don't know what I'll do about that
actually what we could do if we make
this go up a little bit we'll have a
patio and then we can create a wall if
you follow my mouse kind of over here
that connects to this and against that
wall we can put our villager and is his
little shop for up here and that'll be
good I think
yeah we'll build like a little raised
section because we got to go over top
that for sure it's got to be raised and
then we can do stairs kind of like that
hmm or we might just do it like that
that works yeah so I did some more
shaping up here tried to move things
along with this roof you know what I'm
going to do I don't really know how to
make peaked roofs you know like roofs
that are slanted and all that especially
on a building this size I have not a
clue so instead we're going to keep it
mostly flat like this and we still need
a reed farm for this library to get
paper we're going to put that on the
roof we need a wheat farm for cows to
get leather for the books that kind of
thing so we'll put the that stuff on the
roof and I was also considering having
an each road that comes up to here and
maybe we'll make that dock on the roof
somewhere and if I do that kind of thing
I think I didn't fill most of space that
I need to on the roof without actually
having to make a roof yeah so I think
that's what we'll do I tried these rails
they don't work I don't like them
um I instead of doing that so I think
we'll do the cobble ones like we were or
at least try that I went back and I got
a whole bunch of this decorative kind of
stuffs
maybe we can dress this place up a
little bit
these by the stairs here for sure I want
to put something and I thought it would
look good to have a little bush you know
just the log into the leaf box both
sides oh and I'm not gonna be able to
place that unless I do that's okay now
we're going to go back up I did work on
the inside a little like I'm I guess
what I'm doing on the inside is just
kind of shaping it so we'll have a half
slab floor like this this this wood
block stuff is just placeholder so that
I know the shape of the building and
then after that we can choose different
colors a wood or different blocks you
know where it's that I just want to know
that where I'm going with this make sure
I can shape it properly before I decide
on how the outside is going to look you
know because if we just focus on the
outside the inside it's going to look
really bad so okay that's kind of cool
so we'll have that then up here the
place I'm going to put the villager a
little shop like the cookie shop or
whatever is over here and I don't think
we need to get too fancy with it just
like a little counter would counter and
have a trapdoor in there somewhere
if I guess the thing is a villager can
jump over that still right so we'll have
to lower this half a block so it'll look
like well then he might not look over
the counter properly hmm oh well well
see what it's like and we can change it
later if we don't like it but yeah well
lower that half a block and then oh man
go down go up go down go up over and
over okay get that and like on the
outside of this window I put the wood
there just so we know how much space
that's going to take Oh also yeah with
this what I would like is a little
overhang we will take that out put that
there see what this looks like yeah
we'll have like fences that go up and
then these will go to just like a
covering for overtop the villager so
it's not in the rain or something like
that
could make it out of wood or we could do
colored wool oh you see that
skills yeah um I fell again okay let's
do it
I think we're about done here for today
we'll have to do this library in little
steps like this because it's such a big
project and I am very finicky about
details and takes me forever to get
stuff done
oh you know what I did want to try one
last thing before we're done here let's
I wanted to try grow a tree washi no I
wanted to make like a a pot for the tree
if we can poop what would that look like
I just know that's not going to work hmm
how do you make a pot for a tree without
it being too big like if we do this it's
a pretty big pot and doesn't even
connect to the ground mm okay well what
we'll do just have a soil block like
that we'll put our tree on it will grow
it hopefully we'll get a good tree yeah
a tree and then we could put the brick
around here maybe I look okay
and it is extremely dark man see if
that's another reason I want to put the
tables up here because we'll be able to
hide some lights on that and
get some lighting around the place
because otherwise it's going to be so
dark yeah we could do that just go down
something like that would be good maybe
move it a little bit further away from
the rail though huh anyway that's all
we'll do for over here for today let's
head on over I made some progress with
Wilson so we'll go check out my new plan
with that yeah I don't know if I showed
this last episode but I did finish the
stairs to get in and out of the cave
anyway our new entrance which is very
nice very very much needed I'm going to
use this a lot I think I still want to
do some terraforming outside here and
I've always wanted to build a bridge to
go across this river so we might do that
at some point too but I got to finish up
the walls and do a ceiling in here and
something at this level to something
cool hopefully but yeah Wilson let's go
visit Wilson our are sad and lonely pet
that's that's not alive he's waiting for
us to give him a brain our poor guy here
so a little while ago I posed that
problem I don't know if you guys
remember it but I was having some
trouble figuring out where to go from
where we're at now with Wilson sort of a
redstone problem and I posted that
hoping I was going to get the answer
from somebody like somebody was going to
tell me how to do it in a 3x5 area using
some comparator trick I hadn't thought
of and it was going to be amazing but
now that never happened it's just it's a
complicated problem with no good
solution from what I can tell because
what I got to do let's go back up to our
problem here is I got to do some
calculations in the game basically like
real number calculations converted to
redstone which is possible in the game
it's definitely possible
but the problem is making it's not
gigantic is one issue the other issue is
making it so there's not a ton of
redstone running all the time that's
going to like my world out and you know
making making everything connect
together is another challenge because
it's sort of a mess back there if you
saw like it's it's orderly but there's
so many wires all over the place but the
general suggestion I got from people is
I should handle these one at a time so
trying to convert them all together
which yeah I think that is a good good
plan but still to handle each of these
individually the thing is like these
numbers by the way they represents the
number of items I need to flow from one
of our variables here this is how I'm
doing the variables for Wilson just the
hopper hop or combo and if we want
addition or subtraction to it we power
one or the other and an item will flow
from here to here or else from here to
there right and then we get a different
signal length depending on how many
items are in in one of the hoppers right
the thing is to make three items flow
for example we need to power the thing
for 3.5 ticks per item so that would be
go brain 10.5 redstone ticks to get
negative three right and if we got a
pill to build a pulse extender for each
of these it's going to get kind of big
and messy and leggy and it's a it's a
big problem but I did think of one way
we can simplify it a little bit I don't
know for if we got enough figured out to
to use this but it's sort of a better
way of doing it instead of doing that
hopper hopper combo like I was going to
what we can do instead is have a
comparator like this put a block in
front and then redstone comes back to
the comparator like that right and what
this does is it's a way of generating
quick pulses in the game very very
easily like if we do that nothing really
happens but if we switch this to
subtraction mode the power comes back to
the comparator and it does this it emits
a quick pulse which does like the game I
can feel it already but what's this
instead of doing long pulses with a
hopper hopper combo we're going to do a
dropper dropper combo one of these is
going to be addition one of these is
going to be subtraction and so for
example if we power this ah it doesn't
work darn it I didn't test it I thought
it was just going to work darn it no
what what do we have to do to make it
work that's not going to work
that's not going to work oh-ho still no
- that's not changing
darn it these pulses are too quick well
that worked
interesting I thought they fixed that is
it not sharing though oh no it's going
ok so we can make items flow very
quickly and very precisely if we do a
system like this instead and then we
only have to power this for like a much
shorter time compared to if we do a
hopper hopper
thing so that'll reduce the the redstone
we need for the build which will be a
nice improvement like let's see actually
let's just do a quick test here how many
items can we get flowing with just a 4
tick out good game now ah ok we're right
by it trying to do some redstone here
figuring out the problems of the
universe here and the stinking creepers
wrecking our day think I could sleep in
time oh he missed he missed he doesn't
know where I am
ahahaha oh these skeletons man they're
just so annoying jeepers creepers I can
handle that was my fault I wasn't
looking around I liked it what else did
we get we got everything ok where were
we yeah we're just going to do a quick
test here we're going to pulse this
really quick and see how my items flow
from here to there with just four ticks
on a repeater look like to a 2 mm still
not so much super but we can really make
things smaller that way so it's like two
ticks instead of 3.5 the downside of
doing this though is now we have nine
slots instead of five slots like we have
a hopper so mm we'll have to use more
ender pearls instead of regular items or
something I don't know but it's just an
idea I think we should use droppers
instead well anyways guys we're going to
have to end episode here for today sort
of a shorter one and I do apologize for
that but not to worry it's going to be
April soon and I'll have
time then to put into my recordings
again
and hopefully get back to daily uploads
and I do want to start some new series -
coming April so hopefully that happens
but I picked out three comments today
since it's a bit of a shorter episode
first one hey Ethan what's your favorite
food
please put this in the next detail plays
minecraft which is today this episode so
my favorite food I'm going to have to
say I hate to be so generic but I think
it's pizza I think it is pizza and
there's so many choices with pizza
usually usually I like Hawaiian pizza I
guess I would say um I also really like
cheese Jake like baked cheesecake New
York style it's very good very delicious
so that might be my favorite dessert
and of course ribs and and meat meat is
very good anyway next question Etha what
do you think about sim city it looks
like your kind of game I would love to
see you play it so I can see how it
would turn out SimCity
well I had SimCity as a kid for a Super
Nintendo and I loved playing that and
then SimCity 2000 came out and I got
that and it was it was pretty cool but I
was starting to get lost in the game
then SimCity 3000 came out and I really
got lost in the game because there was
so much customization and my cities
always died because I didn't know what I
was doing and then I got lost interest
in the game I never got SimCity 4 and
now SimCity 5 is out and apparently it's
a lot more simple now I could probably
pick it up it's more of a casual game
but I've heard terrible terrible things
about the game and I don't really plan
on getting it because that's the whole
only being able to play online doesn't
sound like it turned out too well so I
think I'll avoid that one um Etha what
happened to them
making series did you simply get bored
of it are you out of ideas I don't know
what you're planning with this map but
you should definitely implement the new
scoreboard maybe it's currency
scoreboard is definitely being used
already and possibly to function with
that currency biology enchanted cetera
etc the map making series I have put on
hold for the time being a lot of people
were getting bored of watching me work
on this the starting platform so I
stopped with that I'll continue it again
once I get stuff done instead of like
building it with you watching me build
it we're going to go with I'll show you
how it works after it's done style if I
resume it just so people aren't aren't
bored with what I'm doing but it is
progressing slowly but I am working on
it here and there and the ideas are all
planned out I just have to do it and
it's it's coming along slowly so
hopefully one day I'll get it done but
that's going to be all for today guys
thank you for watching have a great day
I'll see you again next time bye