hey what's up everybody this is etho
and welcome back to our let's play
series here
all right guys we gotta get rid of these
guys
i think poison potions are the way to do
it um
yeah i'm noticing it already lately in
my world here i've been having some lag
issues and i'm guessing it's these guys
it's either the version of minecraft i'm
playing
how or it's uh
it's the ai on these guys slowing things
down i'm not sure
i've been waiting for them to die off
kind of naturally because every night
they get in
in fights with skeletons in that and one
by one they've been dying but it's taken
too long
so we gotta speed it up here
i have to like restart my game every 30
minutes because otherwise
the tick rate just gets so low
yeah i'm guessing it's these guys
because things are acting
really wonky right now you'll notice
like the potions are getting thrown
slowly and then they're speeding up
all right i used up a whole double chest
of poison potions now we're gonna finish
them off with tnt hopefully
this will make them mad at me though i'm
pretty sure
jay well uh he one shot me
come on i had armor on
oh my goodness these guys are the worst
they're like rats i can't get rid of
them
we friends again okay we're friends
again
yeah he once shot me i can't believe
that protection for
protection for projectile protection
okay we weren't
fully armored up but we had quite a bit
of stuff on us
okay well we killed one anyways
it's a start uh
there we go let's let's just get away
from those guys
like that one okay we killed another one
or two
why you are looking at me like that
all right so this is like an hour or two
later guys i've been working on
the pumpkin farm we started last episode
and
during the time i've been doing this no
lag so i think those guys were
definitely the cause i first noticed the
problem when i upgraded to
like the newest version of minecraft and
i thought it was the culprit
so i downgraded but even after i
downgraded i still had
lag and i thought maybe it had something
to do with the new sounds
that they introduced in the game because
there's so many new sound files i
thought
maybe that messed it up um
but it was it was those iron golems just
that too many of them
uh at my spot i have like the cow farm i
got the sheep farm i got the
the pigs and the rabbits and iron golems
there
there's a village there's a lot of
entities like a lot of mobs
always loaded because they're my spawn
chunks so
i guess out of all of those though the
iron golems were just a little bit too
much for my game to handle
all right so i'm gonna go ahead and
finish this up
um and we will see what kind of rates we
get this should be pretty cool
when it's all done here
here check this out guys i was uh just
doing some trading at
my village here i needed some materials
some glowstone
and uh apparently there's a new trade
for clerics here
uh you can get ender pearls now it's
kind of cool
night time um yeah i guess this used to
be
i have ender here i wonder if they
changed that on purpose or if that was
an
accident i don't know like that's an old
villager that other one with the ender
pearl is a new one
awesome so check it out guys we got the
pumpkin farm pretty much all done
here ah yeah i don't know if i want to
make it any bigger it's pretty big
already
it's 222 pistons i counted them
and about 230 plants or so something
like that
and just watching it here every time the
lights turn on that's a pumpkin
growing and getting harvested seems to
be pretty good
i say that and then nothing grows it's
like one every
i don't know three or four seconds maybe
seems to be about the right uh i did not
put in a nighttime operation mode yet i
might do that
but even as it is right now i think it's
pretty good
all right uh there is the odd pumpkin
landing on the dirt here
i put in these like last things above
these dead zones
um because if any pumpkins land in those
dead zones
then if another one comes by it
automatically stacks with it
and totally jams up the farm so that
is a big no-no actually i'm not seeing
any pumpkins
on the ground here it happens every so
often but it's not too common
i could make this more efficient if i
just like did something like this
um but i don't know if i'd like to look
at that too much so
it doesn't matter that much all right
so the next thing we got to do is get a
farmer villager over here so that we can
actually trade the pumpkins
with them um there is a range of
eight to 13 pumpkins per emerald we want
to try to get eight
eight pumpkins per emerald uh if we do
that
like every everything every row here is
going to be about like a stack of
emeralds basically
what it'll convert to i made a little
area down here so we've got
three double chests of storage and
i'm gonna put the villagers over here we
got spot for two of them
if we want to trade with them it'll be
nice and convenient
um probably the best way of getting them
over here is to
just look for a zombie villager though
right and then
see if that works i'm gonna try that
look at all those creepers over there
oh man uh so far this has not worked out
very well because we only got a one in
ten percent chance
of getting a zombie villager i've not
seen a single one yet
and since there's five different
professions of uh
villagers it's like a one in fifty
chance
that a zombie is gonna be the one we
need and then after we
after we uh convert it or whatever then
there's like a one in four chance of it
being the right one
so we're like we're talking like one in
200 here
it's not very good we might just want to
get him out of the village
oh bad time not to be able to sprint
oh that's the first one i've seen all
night but it's a white coat
okay i feel a little bit silly right now
i've been trying to
like solve this problem like how how
we're gonna get the villager we want
here
uh there's one one and five of getting
the right profession then there's a one
and four of it being the right type in
that profession
and then like there's a chance it's
gonna be eight pumpkins nine pumpkins
ten pumpkins eleven twelve
thirteen so one and six of it being the
right amount
these are bad odds guys bad odds but it
has occurred to me we actually have a
device in our world
for this exact problem
the zombie purifier totally forgot about
this thing
hey there's a guy here oh and it's an
old school cleric too he's he's got
glowstone right at the front here
that's weird yeah this this is what we
want guys
okay oh there's stuff here oh pistons
oh man this is awesome all right
how does it work good thing i left signs
uh
okay that shuts the lights off in there
there's a zombie uh spawner in there by
the way
oh he's taking damage and
oh down a zombie okay we don't want just
anybody going through here
we want these ones to die
so yeah there's a one in 50 of us
getting the right type here
might have to wait a little while oh
i think that's it yeah that's one that's
one
okay how do we do this again
oh i don't want to mess this up i think
we have to flip this until he goes by
oh no i messed it up that might have
been a butcher though
i couldn't quite tell
we got him off you go
all right no keep going keep going he
doesn't want to go
okay i think we got him just in time i'm
noticing they're not actually
falling they like see this guy and they
want to get him
they're just like waiting above them uh
maybe we can get this guy
out of here i forget how this all works
villager medicine villager transport
let's click this button i guess
oh yeah that worked good good
oh and now they're like where's my meal
where'd it go oh
the little baby zombie got in there
that's not good
oh i don't think those existed when i
built this
all right let's uh he's freaking out
oh and all my trip wires are probably
gone here too now that i think of it
so this probably doesn't even work
properly let's see do we have any string
here to repair it
yes we do thought ahead
all right where were the trip wires they
go
right over here okay good now this is
gonna work
i'm gonna add in a little crusher here
too i don't think there's any way of
killing these guys
much quieter
i made a mistake i accidentally let the
farmer guy out
at least i think he's a farmer he might
be a cleric
it's hard to tell uh maybe i'll just
tame him here
he doesn't seem to want to go past these
tracks
so he's kind of changed right now it's
all good
i'm just hoping he doesn't go after that
uh cleric we got over here maybe i'll
just block him
all right uh i'm gonna try to get a few
more though because we only got a one in
chance of it being a pumpkin farmer
nope failed it's a fisherman i think
we'll let this guy out
let him convert him again oh no
he found out he found out the trick so
you go
no you go towards him go towards him
oh man he's not gonna get killed is he
no no no no you want to go you want to
go get them over here
doesn't want to cooperate you got to do
a quick you're going to convert any
second here
okay tell you what i'm just going to get
rid of this track you can cross now
not for me though go for the villager go
for the villager no no no he tastes
better
he's right over here it's right over
here yeah yeah
no not me uh what i gotta do
trap them together oh i was too late are
you kidding
i have to block the door here too
because like all the zombies in the
world have found us
okay we need a new plan here guys
because this is taking way too long
will you pick that up please yes you did
good
so now if it's uh daytime outside i
should be able to
transport them right is it daytime
it's daytime okay yeah because it's
gonna be really hard to get them to the
pumpkin farm too is the other problem
oh i kind of want to fix that
here i can throw that away okay so this
way
he should follow me all the way there
because there's no easy way of getting
villagers to
where you want them to go so
it's it's easier to transport monies
like this so we'll get him there and
then we'll convert them and hope
hopefully it's a farmer if not we will
uh
get them infected again and then try to
convert them over and over until we
finally get it
okay that was a very long walk uh
didn't really think of that but we made
it should have brought a speed potion
though
now i gotta figure out how to get him in
here is
the next problem okay that's where i
want him to go
he's not gonna go down there though is
he
oh oh yeah i'm gonna weakness him so if
he attacks me i don't think he'll
do damage in yeah okay and
he won't ever walk down there if it's
more than a three block drop so we got
to put something there for him to fall
on
and now i think i can uh
break it
okay that'll drop him we'll cover him up
so he doesn't burn because eventually
that helmet is going
to break okay
and give them an apple
and there's a one in 24 chance we're
gonna get the one we want here
which is not great odds but any farmer i
will take at this point
and then maybe in this other one we can
try to get a the perfect one
the eight pumpkin per emerald one
ah it's just a fisherman so
sad uh
yeah no kidding all right so i'm gonna
have to try
infect them again so next night time uh
try get a zombie to kill them and then
keep them trapped and convert them and
all that stuff again
oops i accidentally stopped recording
that but basically a zombie pushed the
villager into the wall
and it suffocated instead of converting
him
somehow they killed him like permanently
so
yeah all that for nothing
it's really hard to get like villagers
the ones you want
in this game
i think i'm going to set up an infinite
villager breeder instead because this is
just a
huge waste of time otherwise
uh yeah i think that's what we're going
to do here we'll just set up one
maybe temporarily oh is that one
oh sweets yes that's one guy okay maybe
we can
get him going here then too
oh that was lucky yes some justice in
the world
okay let's get rid of the fool
and then do the same trick we did before
so weakness oh hey no no
man everybody's out tonight
oh i got weakness too though now i won't
be able to kill this creeper probably
have to do crits
oh man i didn't expect him to be there
okay it's all good
it's all good as long as this guy does
what we want him to do
okay you come down here quickly
quickly come get me okay good good good
cover them like we did before oh it's
not going to let me
all right i kind of wish it was daytime
now
wait a second that's not how we do it
we do it like this and
good okay he's in give them
oh happened my apples
no what did i do with apples oh here
they are good
okay all is good i'm panicking a little
bit
because i'm very worried that creeper's
gonna land on my head here
and every time i do that it makes me eat
one i don't know why
you cannot like you cannot give them
the apple without eating one yourself
well bad news he's a fletcher he's not a
farmer
so we're gonna have to keep trying here
i think if i try to convert him again
he's just going to die like the last one
so we're going to go ahead with this
infinite breeder idea
uh basically the way these works is
pretty simple you need a bunch of
farmland
in order to make the villagers breed
they you either have to trade with them
or you have to feed them
and if you put a farmer villager like
that fletcher guy in here he's going to
harvest the crops
feed the other villagers and make the
babies basically
alright so we'll put a fence around here
uh people usually like do solid blocks i
think that's probably the best but i'm
just gonna try a spruce fence i think
maybe zombies can attack them through
this i'm not sure though
we'll try it out this this is probably
just going to be a temporary setup we
might set up one permanently though at
the library
so we can get some good librarian trades
all right do all this and then like
i think you need a six block gap if i
remember right
so one two three four five
six and then you build a platform or you
can go below
like six blocks below or something uh
but at this level then you need to put
down your doors
and since these are outside the reach of
the
villagers down there they just breed
infinitely you got to put a villager up
here though as well
okay and you need i think
six doors minimum one two
three one two three cover them up so
that it counts as
a actual building
like so and put some walls around here
so we got it oh
we got to get a villager up here as well
it can be any type though
and then we need a farmer one down there
and then whatever other random one we
want
and that should do the trick but it's
going to take a while for them to really
get breeding too
this is not a quick method either
well this is pretty brutal i've spent a
whole night looking and not a
single zombie villager to be found
unreal maybe it's not one in ten
or else maybe i'm just very unlucky but
i've had a hard time finding him
uh i'm trying to get one close to the
pumpkin farm that way we don't have to
walk them so far but it's not really
working out too well
is that no those are normal
well they're back they are ah
i hate those guys
look how slow the redstone is running
what is going on man there's only like
four or five there
oh no oh no no no i don't know what's
going on
my game is like dying we gotta kill them
quickly
i shut the water off on the snowflake so
hopefully they fall straight into the
hole
um i don't know how they're
oh yeah one fell right in okay he's
dying right now
that's good could
could like four or five of these guys
really cause that much lag though
seems kind of crazy
yeah listen to it though
like the game's running at half the
speed right now it's so bad
all right where's my other stuff do not
want to lose my wings
above everything here
okay you have like such a limited
area of reach on these guys too like
they can pretty much reach just as far
as you
it's so hard to kill them
uh but anyways guys it's time to wrap up
the episode here
unfortunately i wasted a lot of time
looking for zombie villagers and trying
to convert them
and i'm out of time to record
that was kind of a flop not not my best
ideas
alright so the first one here says etho
will you ever do another uhc for old
time's sake oh yeah and with the
villagers by the way i'm going to
uh just like find them when i find them
i think a looking form is a mistake
because
when you look for them you can never
find zombie villagers it seems
um it would be cool to see you playing
it again
unless you just find no fun in it
anymore
like if you want to see another uhc
uh so i did a uhc kind of recently the
the hermitcraft one
i wanted to try it again because it was
a long time since i last did one
but honestly like during it i just
didn't find it very fun
um oh man
i don't know it's become like a formula
you know like back in the old days it
was
so much fun because we never knew what
was gonna happen
and things just seemed to work out
perfectly you know or or something cool
would always happen
now it's like you get geared up
you look around for some people you
can't find them for an hour or two
you find them and then like you're so
out of it at that point or at least i
find i am that
uh you're like half asleep during the
battle
and you i don't know the battle lasts
for a minute and then you
either die or you move on if you die it
really sucks if you're
if you don't even get a kill because you
just feel bad after and then people tell
you you're bad
i don't know i just don't find uhc very
fun anymore so i don't think i'm gonna
do any
i'd rather look for a different pvp game
that's my thoughts on that anyway uh
second comment is
the golden skeleton looked like you had
a really fast horse
i think we'll go uh go try them out uh
the the skeleton is gone
it's still lagging like crazy isn't it
i'm gonna try to restart my game i guess
i don't know guys like the lag was gone
when i restarted so maybe it
isn't the iron golems causing it but i
don't i don't really know what
is
oh yeah he is yeah this is a much faster
than other ones
for sure
it's pretty good actually not super fast
like
i definitely have faster horses but he's
decent
what's his jumping height can you do
three
now you can do three four
is like really good on a horse if you
can get four
nope just three so he's kind of like an
average maybe a little above average
well anyways guys i hope you enjoyed
today's episode
thank you for watching and i'll see you
again in at the next one
don't know where the those came from did
i place those
i don't remember replacing them uh but
yeah have a good day
thanks for watching take care bye bye
you