Hey ladies welcome back to ethos lab I
thought we'd start out today doing an
enchantment here a level 48 one and I
hate to start out the episode on a rant
but I'm going to say it
enchanting system sucks it's terrible
not not the whole system I like most of
it but the one aspect of it that really
really sucks is the level selection it's
stupid I'm mad because I spent 15
minutes just clicking trying to get the
level I wanted and I was even aiming
like super high like it's not like level
50 or or else I'm not doing it it's like
47 48 49 or 50 either of those four I
would have been happy 15 minutes before
one finally showed up and that is not
fun okay it's not there needs to be a
slider bar you choose what level you
want get it over with zero to 50 or zero
to whatever many books you have around
whatever it allows because I don't know
this it's silly there it's they tried to
like to have a fun aspect to it by
giving you a random choice between three
that would be okay if if the leveling
system worked in front like if each
level was an equal amount of XP I
wouldn't mind choosing a level 18 right
now but because of the way the XP works
you pretty much have to use up all your
levels when you enchant something for it
to be worth it and that makes it
frustrating and if you feel 15 minutes
and skip past the level when you finally
see it then that would really tick you
off too so yeah that's my rant for today
anyway we're going to do a diamond
shovel I've never done a diamond shovel
before let's hope for the best
ideally chant mints for enchantments I
would want efficiency 5 and unbreaking 3
apparently according to the wiki you can
also get silk touch and fortune
although I don't know how useful those
would actually be so let's see what
happens here
ah I forgot how it works
give me 15 minutes yeah yeah I'm an
idiot whatever here we go again I got
another 48 oddly I noticed might be a
coincidence but whenever he hit a high
level it's always in the third box down
for some reason could be just a
coincidence or maybe that's the way it
works I don't know you click there not
not the actual shovel unbreaking 3 darn
it that is not what I wanted oh and I
would do another shovel but I have no XP
and I don't have 15 more minutes to do
that ok anyway that the reason I'm doing
shovels now so I finally got a pretty
good stash of picks here add that in
yeah I got another fortune 3 one along
with this older one I had I still have
the silk touch iron pick and newly added
efficiency for silk touch one as well so
that's a really nice one cool yeah ok
on with the show yeah so I just want to
show you guys what I got going on down
here now
haven't changed a lot but I did do the
ceiling with the nether brick and I
managed to sneak a little bit of
sandstone in with it like I wanted to
and I'm happy with look I think it looks
good I've been putting stairs along here
instead of full blocks I'm not sure
that's
I like that more or not no is this
trying to give it a little bit more
personality I guess yeah and so we're
gonna have grass a lot of people
actually recommended that I should use
gravel which shocked me a bit because I
thought to thought gravel was like the
one block everybody agreed to hate in
this game although I have noticed the
texture changed a bit on it in one of
the recent patches it's a little
smoother not so hard on the eyes but
yeah I'll probably keep it grass and I
wanted to have a border on each side I
don't know
I got stone brick here as a boarder not
trick I'm going to keep that I might try
brick in general like regular brick and
I want these because it'll match the
stripe on the roof kind of kind of go
together but today this is the project
for today everybody I want to start a
potion room somewhere for brewing them
Location Location thinking may try to
sneak it in just over here somehow
make a room over here
so there's empty space over here so it
should work out okay
maybe I'll start clearing that out and
see see how it goes
got a fair bit of space cleared out here
so we can start working on the potion
room pretty quick here also been
cleaning up this area a bit wasn't fully
happy with the looks here I'm still not
I don't know what to do
I tried switching the stone bricks with
wooden planks here because I thought the
transition from grass to stone brick was
a bit harsh I don't know what I think I
really should do this is kind of bugging
me these stairs here and it would still
doesn't look right if it's solid blocks
I think would I actually need to do if
I'm going to keep this nether bridge is
a move this down one block because we
really only need this would be three
blocks I not four so move this down one
block then move the sandstone words
nether brick is and replace the
sandstone with more another brick do it
that way
might look better yeah this is really
bugging me here this is only four wide I
would really like it to be five wide
didn't think of that when I positioned
it and I would hate to have to move it
but I don't know what to do oh yeah I
thought it correct myself about
something too it's been brought to my
attention that you can put redstone in
that on pumpkins so I was incorrect
about that last episode
okay I think we're ready to begin here
finally I brought over a double chest
with some potion stuff I have a pretty
good idea of all I want to include in
this potion room it's not just going to
be like a five by five room it's gonna
be fairly large don't know exactly how
large it's going to be yet we have to
figure out a couple things here let's
make some some stands first oh they
stack
I have played around with brewing a
little bit in the creative mode I know
how to brew all the potions I'm pretty
sure I just haven't tried them out and
there's some other things I haven't done
either okay let's get our bottles
that'll make us well it makes quite a
few we got three stacks so I'm going to
check out one thing here I never really
understand the point the point of the
cauldron thing can we fill these from a
straight spring we can so yeah I don't
think the cauldrons are really needed
are they what about if we have flowing
water say we have water flowing like
this can we take it from here nope
oh it doesn't use up the water source
even interesting and do these stack no
they don't
uh-huh see on the wiki it said they did
that might what how did I throw that
what I'm right-clicking on the water and
it's throwing my plug oh that is weird
what I guess because my inventory is
full it throws it when you right-click
on the water yeah that time it didn't
that time it did that's cool so you can
just you just do this to fill your water
bottles I like that
okay so it probably only Coltrane's what
I want to figure out next is the size of
the route this room is going to depend
largely on how quick we can actually
keep up filling these brewing stands
with stuff like there's no point having
a hundred of these if we can't keep up
oops you know what I mean and I also
want to check one thing do these cause
block updates because that might give me
a few ideas as well I'm going to get
some distance just to check that okay if
I was to guess I would say they probably
do cause an update because the graphic
updates when you put bottles in I don't
know if it will update though when it
finishes brewing I kind of don't think
it will
we'll see though those are just my
guesses
okay let's put a bottle in see what
happens when we put an empty bottle in
oh you can yeah so every time you do
that oops every time you put a bottle in
or take a bottle out it'll probably
update let's try it again yeah okay I'm
gonna try weapons you put water oh you
can't I'm going to try brew something
here see if that does anything water
bottles are over here oops this will be
our first brewing attempt okay and again
I'm going to make an awkward potion see
that set here we go so no update when it
starts brewing and probably not one when
it finishes either I'm going to make a
cauldron just since we're goofing around
here even though I probably won't use
any of these i guess 'sir yeah they're
probably just fear brewing in the nether
you'll need these let's put it over here
whoa first time I've ever placed the
cauldron in this game so weird you can
go in it you can put water in it and
three three uses before it uses the
water up yeah definitely using a water
source block is easier okay what happens
if we can remove these with a piston
lu-chen
I try it yeah yeah then when there's
water in no well maybe I ten seems to be
more difficult there you know hey I'm
still in it that's cool oh not anymore
mmm okay this did not update by the
looks of it
can we move these with a piston nope
okay good to know I can't think of any
well give me a second I think if there's
anything I'd want to do with that update
probably not though yeah I don't know I
can't really think of any positive or
practical benefit to doing a block
update on these brewing stands I thought
I'd check out the cauldrons though just
in case somebody's interested I'm
guessing they do yep let's try it again
yep another time
and fulfilling yep so all four of those
cause the block updates and I got
another thing going on here I got ten
brewing stands here now full of water
bottles I just want to see how long it
takes me to put a wart in each of these
see if by the time I get to the end if
this one's done or not see how far along
it is so here we go because when I do
the brewing I'll probably do it in mass
quantities like this so I want to be
able to do it as quickly as possible and
have isn't brewing stands ready to go
and I'll probably put the bottles in
first and then put the ingredients in do
a big batch of something and then put it
in a storage chest so mmm you see it
just finished so that's ten stands I
think that's a good number right there
can't really do it any quicker because
going at an average speed there okay
yeah so I've been thinking about how I
want to do the potion room for a few
minutes here and I came up with a plan
that I think is pretty awesome it's
going to be a lot of work though I'm not
going to go into all the details of it
today just because we'll need at least
one more episode to do it but I'll give
you I'll give you at least one detail
here it seems like the most tedious part
of brewing these potions is placing the
water bottles in these brewing stands so
if we got if we got 10 brewing stands
we'll have to manually we'll have to
fill the water bottles and then pick
them up put them into here for all 10 of
them and that's going to be a huge issue
if the water bottles are all over the
place
so this is my first idea right where
this torch is is a really nice spot
because I can reach
all the Brewing stands pretty much from
this point so I'm thinking have like
four on this wall here then three one
two three over on this side and then
three on this side for a total of ten
probably won't have one in the middle
here and then I'll have a water source
above me here just we'll just test this
out like that so when I need to fill the
water bottles I should be able to kind
of fill up my inventory here should be
able to just right click and it throws
them straight up and lands right at my
feet like that so when I go to fill the
brewery stands and I take the water
bottle out of my inventory to put it in
here a new one will go in its place and
I'll just be able to fill it without
having to go to a chest to pick up the
water bottles or whatever that we all in
that one spot so that's my first idea
for the water bottles just going to say
something else I can't remember now
before we end today though I'm going to
play around with some brewing so I'm
going to make some haste potions here
maybe some fire resistant ones because
those are the two that appeal to me most
and give me a sec to get the ingredients
I never did check what happens if you if
you break one of these stands with
potions in it so maybe we'll do that and
also I found out you can shift click
them out of the brewing stand you just
can't shift-click them into it okay
let's see what happens here oh it does
drop them that's cool
I was worried it when it yes I got
five sugar and we're going to make some
whatchamacallit fire-resistant ones so
let's say you make the magma cream form
so we'll be five and five see how this
goes I think that's what you do I
probably won't do a whole lot of like
tier two potions that use glowstone and
probably won't use redstone to lengthen
them either just because I don't like
those are really important resources to
me maybe on rare occasions I will but in
general use I'm not going to just use
the the crummy potions there we go
that one just finished fire resistance
yes let's it's pretty easy to get a lot
of potions here the only one I've ever
tried so far is the potion of swiftness
here's a new sound fort woohoo that's
awesome
finally we got potions I'm wanting these
for a long time ouch nice and smooth
stairs here get particle effects now
different colors that's cool yes I'll
probably be using these all the time
once they get to start once I get to
established with them
actually what I want to do I want to
take a fire resistant potion to the
nether and jump in a lava and see what
happens so I will see you in a little
bit here I was like I so excited to try
out the potion here I completely forgot
that as at level 40 here ya go jump in a
pool of lava at level 40 I would never
hear the end of that one so I finished
leveling up to forty eight year we got a
forty seven ready to go took five
minutes this time you're going to do a
sword for sword here I'm hoping to get
looting let's see what happens well that
is nice that is yes I got safely tucked
away here really happy about this one I
think lootings the rarest enchantment
for swords but I could be wrong don't
quote me on that and I think we're ready
to go to the nether this is all I have
on me I don't know what's going to
happen when you jump in the lava just
doing it for fun hopefully I'll survive
but we'll find out I'm going to keep the
iron armor on me just in case it helps
me survive and if I lose it I don't care
this is a slight jump into the deep end
in a pool we we just got to do it J and
maybe as we walk here I'll talk about
some stuff oh yeah let's go to the slime
farm it's still working even after the
changes take this thing I don't know if
it's as good of rates anymore they
probably spawn in other places but they
do still spawn here yeah so about the
video uploads I'll tell you what's going
on with that when I up out my upload my
videos
I set them to private so when the ads
did apply to them then then they
automatically get switched the public
that's that's the way most youtubers do
it that way you don't lose out on any
money to your videos but I have a really
folk quite often when I upload my videos
they don't get approved for some reason
which is really frustrating for me and
I'm sure you guys too
I know you guys find it frustrating - if
my videos go a very long time without
getting approval I'll just switch on the
public myself and usually after a day or
two pens if I got more videos ready to
go or not - sorry about that the
recording got messed up there like -
yeah like I sang also try videos the
public if it's picking up day or two
usually just to keep you guys happy and
keep the schedule what it is and I like
to get your feedback on videos too
frustrating if I have to wait sometimes
because sometimes I won't record another
LP episode until I get your feedback
just because I need to know what you
think about certain things sometimes
yeah so here we have but my buddy who'd
talked to a guy about maybe getting me
premium partnership he talked to the
head of the gaming department of YouTube
for me that minecon there so really nice
a good hopefully something happens there
and I can get premium partnership I
actually got an email from the guy who
talked to nothing is definite yet
there's a good chance that we won't get
premium partnership but if I do do then
I'll get instant approval on my videos
and then we won't have all the silly
wages all the time
yeah I'm just going to do it oh wait I
thought there's a lotta hope crap the
full damage killed me almost wow that's
good it won't let me eat I want full
yeah so I'm just a regular partner on
YouTube but there's also what I think is
called a premium partnership and if you
get that then you have that that feature
to add shows to your video and you
instant approval on your ads so really
hoping that happens for me just it'll
make everything better but I read em
might only be possible if I live in the
u.s. or the UK or France and I live in
Canada so might not get it
we'll see yeah I usually don't talk
about the business part of YouTube but I
make an exception today oh yeah and I
also got a Twitter account you guys
finally so when I upload videos
sometimes I'll tweet tweet about it my
twitter is etho LP e th o LP i'll try
put a link to it in the video
description if I remember well this was
fun you guys but now how do I get out of
here yessuh yes I'll do that off camera
anyway I'll tell I'll end the episode
here today thank you for watching next
time we'll work on the potion room gonna
be a lot of redstone involved and until
then I'll see you later