hello everybody welcome this is etho and
i have fixed the firework show i am
pretty sure don't know don't know until
we try it though I guess last time the
firework show was cut short because the
the fire randomizer was burning itself
ah
there's so many mom's below me I think
this time I fixed it I'm I believe we're
gonna check it afterwards just inspect
for any damage but it's set up where I
can launch it with a piece of sand I'll
do something more fancy later let's get
our song going and see the fireworks
show as I intended it hopefully all
right here we go
it's original beauty I'm getting away
from the mobs and I'm scared it's
looking good looking very good oh yeah
let's go look from some different angles
here - ah so cool it hurts me you know
some people have been complaining about
the fireworks being a useless feature it
is awesome I mean I can understand
people complaining about the cats and
that like Mojang listing their time on
that but fireworks ah
this is a great great feature you play
games to have fun and I don't know what
could be more fun than fireworks
seems like it might be slowing down
maybe not oh it's so cool
another thing people suggested in the
comics is I should have some kind of
finale to it so I'll work on that too is
yeah the best part of the firework show
is the ending so we want a nice finale
to it I don't know exactly how I'm going
to accomplish that but I'll get
something I walk too far away from the
music phew it's still going man I think
it's okay let's just go check spec there
fire randomizers
I also have it now I can load the
dispensers from below here instead of
having to go in the water
which was the pain all right this one's
still going oh this one's gone darn load
them from here and see I can't make it
any faster so it's just kind of a flaw
with the randomizer design all right
this way mmm think I'll have to play
around with it some more maybe there's a
way I can fix it that one's okay sounds
okay let's go over here so far only one
is burnt this one's gone mmm see I want
them to go for at least 50 shots they
could they could handle 50 shots I'd be
happy this one's gone it's not lasting
nearly that three of them gone four of
them gone wow I'm a little surprised by
that actually another one John even with
the faster faster rate huh that's crazy
I don't think I can make these any
quicker as a problem like if I get rid
of that repeater I don't think it's
going to work so yeah can we get this
going quickly I got this
got it get up put out the fire
this bear oh yeah something over send
the power through even hmm all right
let's change this to one of these and I
gotta get this extended okay should work
well not not that should work if it if
it's going to work it should work
oh ho ah yeah I don't think I get any
faster just spazzes out then mmm did
still burn well cuz it stopped oh yes
yeah that makes sense
oh well I'll think of something
alright here's what I did guys I
reloaded the firework show but I tried
it out on peaceful mode and that worked
a whole lot better like big big
difference to the point where I think
that's that it was an acceptable level
that wool would still burn but it would
shoot at least you know on average I
could see it going at least 50 times
which is what I wanted so if I don't
come up with a different randomizer I
think that would be acceptable we would
just have to do the fireworks show on
peaceful uh-huh but yeah I have an idea
for today this is what we're going to
check out I haven't built this in
creative mode I thought it would be fun
to investigate it in in the let's play
and kind of take you guys along on the
experience basically the other day let's
go over here I was I was in a ravine and
I didn't have any blocks to get out of
it so I used a water bucket to climb out
and while I was doing that I noticed
something kind of interesting which
we're going to check out today let's
just see if I can replicate what I saw
so basically I had a flat wall I was
trying to climb up with a water bucket
so
maybe it works different here yeah you
see that you see what I just did there I
kind of went up really quick mm can't
get the angle right
maybe it was more like this maybe I was
yeah right there I just did it there you
see how quickly I went up that those two
blocks basically that's what we're
checking out today if you are swimming
in water let's find some water there's
some water if you're swimming in water
normally you just Bob up and down right
all right so I'm holding the spacebar
bobbing up and down not really moving
that quick vertically but if you're
about to jump out of the water or like
if you approach the edge it like shoots
you up really quick if you look to the Y
it like it goes up really fast and you
hop out of the water actually same thing
happens if you have a straight wall and
water pouring out on the side when you
get to the top you kind of jump up so I
think if we have dispensers shooting out
water buckets at just the right timing
gluing the mic just the right timing we
could possibly make a pretty quick
elevator using this there's a good
chance I won't be able to get the timing
right and this won't work but I thought
it would be fun to check out anyway so
that's that's kind of the plan for today
okay here we go we're going to build it
now or try to build it my general idea
is to have like a wall of zigzag
dispensers with water buckets in and to
get the the jump boost when you're going
out of the water I don't think the
player can be in water so the time I
jump out of the water is when I want
the water budget for the next dispenser
to put the water out so I'll be in mid
air and then it will force me back into
water and hopefully try to get the speed
boost every block we go up that way so a
problem I foresee is since I'm going to
be doing like a lot of sensitive timing
stuff with this I need to make sure I
can get into the elevator exactly the
same or pretty much the same every time
so the way I'm going to do that let's
just have water stream guiding me so
I'll go on at the same rate every time
because the water will push me the same
same speed we're going to make this too
wide so that we can have a fence or or
glass planes glass panes not planes
where we'll go in between this look this
will make sure we're in the middle
oh that's not going to work mmm well
I'll just brush up against this I guess
when I go in we'll do that so I'll go
right up next to this go down I'll be in
the center so that I can get affected by
both dispensers then I need let's have
we're going to build the wall here so
our first dispenser maybe let's just put
it here and we'll build up our wall next
one we'll go here I love the whole shift
like you can normally if you right-click
you go in the dispenser if you hold
shift now though it places a block that
is really good very useful
all right so that's going to be our wall
and I'm going to just to keep things a
little cleaner when we're testing this
but signs here so the water gets held in
place every level when this is all set
up properly the water shouldn't spread
like it'll go out and then dip suck back
in before has time to spread but until
you at the timing is right that's not
going to happen have a wall to keep the
water in as well there's a good chance
this will work
OOP sorry glass all right we need it to
be too high get in and as as I'm
traveling along here I'm going to hold
spacebar so let's have a little bit of a
thing like this hold spacebar so that as
soon as I get to this open area I'll
jump up and it's going to be time just
right so that actually I'm going to open
this up to you
yeah maybe old oops yeah right there
maybe I'll do that hold the water in
alright next I'm going to have trip
wires to detect where I am not there and
since the water is pushing me to
constant rate I should be able to time
it just right
so that I can control it within one tick
get our string
that's the out Oh brush up against the
plane the pain not not the plane brush
up against this when I get under here
I'll start holding jump I'll hit the
trip wire that will activate my redstone
and I'll have it time just right so this
thing dispenses at the right time all
right now for the redstone I'm going to
skip the redstone part of this and just
set it up myself because that it's
probably take a while I'm going to have
a monostable circuit to get the timing
just right and actually with these
dispensers I'm going to do this have I
got to be careful about double
activating them so I'll do that and then
have repeaters oh wait no not like that
I don't want to do it I wanna do it like
this I think just to be
yeah like that so the repeater will be
will go through a block before goes to
the dispenser just so there's no
interference or their problems and one
more good all right so I'm going to do
the redstone I'll be back in a sec all
right well I've been playing around with
the timing for a little bit here and
it's not hard to tell if it's going to
work or not so far it looks sort of like
it's not going to but I don't I'll let
you guys see this is as close of timing
as I could get with this setup hold
space bar
so that was two blocks we went up so I
guess let's just keep this thing going
and see how see how it goes if we go to
the next third and fourth one that's
with a one tick difference between the
dispensers okay so we're going to use
half slabs and go up to here and here
this will know for sure at this I think
if it seemed like we're going up pretty
quickly after four blocks there's a good
chance we could make a full-blown
elevator out of its if it seems like
we're kind of getting stuck in the water
then there's a good chance it's not
going to work get that one at three this
one's at two this one's at one and we'll
see what happens here I've got to put
water in all right and it almost seems
like it could work though too because
those we went up two blocks pretty quick
it's not going to be the fastest
elevator in the world but just another
alternative
ooh that wasn't too bad man I think the
water was going up too quickly though mm
that's going to be and it's like where
do you slow it down you know oh did I go
to fifth level no try keep this one at 2
and this one at 3 then see what happens
water this is just playing around with
the timing all right here we go again
yeah it's still too quick hmm yeah
that's not a good thing son was it - oh
I shortened it why did I shorten it
about that at 4
that one probably won't be able to get
to work let's try it one two and four
for the third one
hmm it's really hard to tell if it's any
quicker or not I want to keep messing
with it yeah I figured out something
important here
even with two water budgets there was a
problem already look at this I can't
jump out of the water
so it knows it knows I'm trying to cheat
it now I probably got to get rid of
these signs in this glass or something
to make it work it like I'm trying to do
so I'm not getting the speed boost from
the second one or the third one or the
fourth one and this is what it does when
you have three ticks between each one it
doesn't really sink in too well before I
give up on this so I'm going to try with
just single dispenser row instead of
this alternating thing see if that works
better because it's almost like it's
tossing me to the left and right now
without the signs there hmm okay guys I
am back here it's been a while actually
I've been messing around with this
trying different timings and all sorts
of different things and and learning new
things and I'll tell you what I learned
so you can see I got the one wide set up
here instead of the two wide originally
I had it where the dispensers were like
one on top of each other like one there
than one there all the way up but that
wasn't working out so well no matter
what I time did it so I started doing
the spacing thing and that worked a lot
better I kind of understand why now it's
a second I think you're gonna sleep
beautiful son sit ah sweet dreams
nightmares
oh no flags ah I couldn't quite tell if
it was working like it was actually
making me swim up faster so I built this
other model here which would do pretty
much the same thing right what I've been
doing now is holding forward and and
spacebar at the same time and this is
the rates you would normally swim up one
of these things so I I've recorded
little sections of this to of and then
played a back frame by frame
to figure things out this one takes me
four seconds to swim up the eight blocks
well my vertical position changes leave
blocks as I do this so four seconds
that's equivalent to about two blocks
per per per second yay brain this one
though this is the dispenser setup and
we'll go through this again aha so this
one is what I write down here two point
two three seconds two point two three to
go up to eight blocks so it's quite a
bit faster actually I don't know if that
speed would continue if I extended it
further but just from this test it looks
kind of promising pretty cool ah so yeah
does what I wanted to do actually I'm a
little surprised the wiring back here is
a mess because I just kept adding to it
but I think this is one thing that
worries me it's not like an even timing
between each one I have to keep
lengthening it so I'm thinking maybe if
I extended it long enough it would
actually level out to the same as that I
don't know for sure
but the first one at zero then this one
goes to two ticks next one is at at four
for ticks
and then the next one
is it for ticks okay this one's at zero
this one's at two this one's at six and
then this one is at eleven so the
spacing is getting further and further
farther it goes I might not have the set
up ideally either though I don't know
all right and here is some other
interesting stuff basically when I jump
out of the water like this my
y-coordinate goes to seventy one point
five roughly at the peak so I'm when I
jump out of the water I jump half a
block out of the air all right
my actual acceleration starts occurring
down at sixty nine point six so even
before I'm out of the water I start to
speed up vertically and that's about a
span of two blocks so that explains why
it wasn't really working for me when I
had them one on top of each other
there's there's a period of time when
you're in the water still that you
actually start speeding up but I know
it's kind of cool I don't know how
effective it is or anything but hey it's
quicker than that so got some results
out of it anyway I hope you enjoyed this
little experiment and maybe one day all
set up a full full-blown actual usage of
it somewhere how now what has happened
to my village oh they're real we were
near here I checked and see if it was
loaded or not maybe stuff happened it's
my dog my dog where you got nothing you
stay out it looks like there's only
three villagers still I don't think I
was in the area actually the pig is
still here though I saw him jumping
around
awesome yet no more villagers all right
everybody here are the comments for the
day I picked out three number one the
1.5 I firstly said hey II thought there
was enough space so I cut it out the 1.5
Update also called a redstone update
possibly and the existence of bud
switches is this something that might
cause a new LP world considering you use
a lot of butts which is no the only
possible way of maybe I would make a new
LP is if I if world generation changed I
think that's the only reason I would
change it but I'm guessing even if they
do that I could just walk out further
and I would get new the new features so
even even if there is no generation I
probably won't start anyone so I'm I'm
probably going to keep this world
forever
yeah alright II thought like even if
atomic bomb went off in my base right
now and I couldn't recover I would just
move to new area basically etho would
you consider if you desperately wanted a
certain enchantment getting the levels
and making a backup just before then
chant happens to save time and resources
trying to get that Chapman when you can
try from a backup and save time or would
you consider it cheating I would
consider it cheating because there is a
luck factor in this game and if you do
that you're kind of avoiding that that's
just my view on it I have two very good
XP farms anyway so I don't really want
to matter too much I can just enchant
another one really quick but yeah in
general I wouldn't recommend doing that
number 3 wow I downloaded the world and
it's so old it's like from episode 100
what the heck etho in high-pitched voice
it's it's coming out today guys assuming
everything went well check the
description for this video and I should
have a new update I'm going to work on
that right after I finish recording here
and that is right now because I'm ending
the episode so thanks for watching
everybody and I'll see you next time