[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
Keith oh and welcome back we're here
once again with another let's play
episode and guys this is number 499
which means next episode is gonna be the
big five oh whoa whoa episode which is
gonna be a World Tour we're gonna go
around check out some of our builds and
see all the cool stuff again last world
war not world war world tour we did was
450 right I'm trying to do them every 50
episodes now I know we've kind of slowed
down with the episodes lately it might
not feel like a lot has changed but
actually in the last 50 we've done a lot
of stuff in this world so it'll be kind
of cool to check everything out again I
think especially for the new people and
as well I want to try to get you guys a
world download if possible right now our
world is about one Gideon sighs so I
have to go through mcedit and and delete
some of the area we've explored but I'll
try to leave all the the buildings and
stuff in the file and hopefully get it
down to like 200 Meg's or so so that you
guys don't crash the site when you
download it yeah today I think we're
just gonna go around the world do some
building on our old projects and and
hopefully do a bunch of cleanup because
like any time we build something I
always leave remnants behind like little
things chests and garbage and whatever
so I'm gonna try to clean that up get
the world nice and and good for you guys
when you check it out but anyways since
last episode I have rebuilt the cannon
remember it blew up at the end I don't
know if it's good now I did like to test
shots and it was fine what I've done is
I've lowered that platform one more
block so the item frames aren't popping
off anymore and I've also added rings
around the dispensers there so hopefully
when the TNT launches it it rams into
the slabs here and then falls straight
down all right let's go for let's try
hit that red wall over there maybe so
that's gonna be a corner shot maybe
throw TNT in there we're gonna ramp our
power way up let's go for that shot
delay I have no idea let's just try it
out and hopefully okay it works
cannons still intact yeah just making
sure
so then explode this time let's try that
one more time we'll put the TNT where
are we
we'll just do a couple test shots and
then we'll get on with things here let's
try over there instead
hopefully I'll go more this way Oh too
far this way yeah we don't really have a
lot of range with this cannon that seems
like it like that hit over there the
other one was like way over there right
and if we make the same shot again I
don't know if it's gonna very much oh
why did it go over there I thought I
threw it in the corner okay there we go
oh that hit the [ __ ] that hit some
silverfish yep uh-huh
anyways what we're gonna do first off
here I have gathered some stuff guys
let's see over here I've prepared some
resources a bunch of glass some dark oak
and we're gonna use those resources to
work on one of our oldest projects in
the world here that I get hounded on the
most of anything I think we're gonna go
to the library today guys I know we
won't be able to finish it we're just
gonna spend a few minutes here I'll do
mostly building off-camera but I wanted
to change I don't want you guys to get
the world downloaded and it's like hey
this is the exact same as last time you
know we might have worked on it since
last time I can't remember but for sure
I want to try to get like a roof on top
of it today if we can over this main
area to be fair though guys this is like
the biggest structure I've ever built in
Minecraft actually now that I think of
it like if you look at the man cave
everything is like six blocks tall at
most and it's just a bunch of little
things compiled together this is like
one being
giant structure and I'm not really good
at building those as you can tell so
yeah we'll see what happens with it here
today
I have decided a couple things with it
like guys looking at it here trying to
figure out what to do and I think we're
gonna put a glass roof on it so that it
stays Bright's inside during the day and
also I'm gonna try include another block
type in the build here because right now
it's like all wood you can't hardly tell
the difference between those colors
actually cuz a little lighting glitch
alright I may be a little bit actually
yeah we're gonna try to mix in some
orange clay in this build because right
now it's like all wood and there's not a
lot of color besides like the
bookshelves and and this middle area
here so we tried a bunch of different
clay colors when we were doing the
windows we tried like red and green now
usually when I do clay in Minecraft I go
for red or blue those are my two
preferred but lately I have found out
orange clay is really good with dark oak
and like regular oak and spruce it's a
really good mix when you have these
together so I'm gonna change out the
windows to orange clay and that way we
have a little bit more variation in the
build here that's impossible
it can't be done I'm telling you there's
no way guys can you jump four blocks in
Minecraft I don't know actually I've
never like gotten good at parkour I
can't make this jump though I feel like
I should be able to one two three four I
don't know I don't know I know I can't
if I do that that's kind of cheating
that's trying to save an ender pearl you
know they're so valuable
I still slipped off oh my goodness I'm
trying to get up here and I get
distracted easy okay we're gonna go up
here we're gonna see a comparison of
orange and and just oak so that's that's
the new window that's the old one I
think this
a lot better right so we're gonna change
out those ones as well and let's add a
ring of slabs on top of here and Bob
would make lots of little changes around
this building to add a bit of variation
to it one of my design flaws with this
when you center of the buildings here
right and if you walk in usually when
you walk into the building you want to
see a nice open view of the building and
we're gonna walk in right into a wall
basically so we might put like two doors
on it's like one here one over there I'm
not sure yet though all right let's put
a thing I poked around this alright good
stuff
I like that all right this is it guys I
hate working on roofs but I've put it
off too long now this is my plan we're
gonna try to do like a dome ceiling made
out of glass so it's gonna go like and
then back down to the other side and
we're gonna try connect that to a wood
beam that runs along here it's gonna be
like just a long cylinder that runs down
the building here it's gonna be pretty
simple because like I said I don't I
don't really like making grooves I'm not
good at it don't really know what to do
let's let's connect it to this log here
so this is gonna run down the length of
the building and I matched up work next
to it's actually probably easier just to
go on top of it yeah let's go on top I
think it should connect to that post
over there let's just make sure okay
yeah here we are so now if we go down
here and connect this up that should be
our dome brace or whatever so for this
entire distance here it's gonna be like
a cylinder dome that runs along the
building is the plan whoa okay so now we
got to like create the dome I'm gonna
try let's try come out here and kind of
line it up with the window here I guess
and let's grab some garbage blocks that
we can delete
let's see let's go up like so now we'll
start curving it a bit more we'll go to
and fill up here and we'll go another
two and then probably yeah we can do the
center now I think so then we'll go
three or five or something I guess three
and then it'll start going down let's
just check out that shape see what it
looks like
alright to run over here can't really
tell let's go to the middle of the
building I think that'll work right so
that I'll connect to the other side
alright guys so this is gonna be really
simple like I said basically I copied
that curve or that wooden arch over here
to the other side connected it to that
post
and then added some wood slabs and
stairs and stuff here just to add a bit
of variation to it also kind of makes it
look like the glass is being supported
by something and now we just gotta fill
this all in nice and simple and since
it's a glass roof it's gonna let a lot
of light in down below and hopefully the
building will look pretty good we'll
have to add torches everywhere ah yeah
yeah so check it out so that is a pretty
big chunk of the roof finish just like
that kind of cheesed it a little bit but
I don't think it looks too bad alright
it'll be good
now these are other sections like over
here we'll do something different like
these side areas they still need a roof
- I don't want to do the same exact same
thing their exact same thing same there
is that what I said uh-huh anyways so
let's try to connect this open area to
the this portion - I just will just go
up with this see how that goes up over
here boop-boop-boop and I think oops I
think what we'll do is extend the window
up a little bit - let's do like this
so that'll come over and just kind of
fill this all in all right oops
okay that goes there let's punch this
out to that and that and then we'll fill
that in with glass too
all right so I think that wall is all
finished up the only thing that might
change is the villager head there a lot
of you guys don't like the librarian
villager I know I have not figured out
what to put there instead though so it's
it's gonna stay there for for now
anyways until I think is something else
one thing though that I've kind of
realized is we have to do something
about these little pillars or whatever
so we should probably extend them to the
roof as well right now they're just like
chopped off and it doesn't look quite
right so let's let's hop up on these and
try to do something with them my plan is
to like put some bookshelves in here -
all right so this will go up to the
glass oh I am stuck here okay move over
yeah that goes up there and like this
alright and then how do we do this let's
I want to replace these with oak just
for a little bit more color they're just
kind of there for decoration and - to
stop mobs from spawning - and then I
think we'll hook some bookshelves in
between here and make it go all the way
up to the top probably hmmm that doesn't
look quite right does it it looks weird
just like the glass sitting on top of it
to me what do we do what do we do and
the bookshelves are a little bit weird
too
especially on this side cuz it's not 3d
so I'm thinking we also add arches from
this side to the other side maybe we'll
try it out alright everybody so I don't
want to spend the whole episode building
here at the library we'll try to do some
other stuff even though I got nothing
planned right now but I'll just show you
the the final results of the building
here I did a little bit more so we got
the arches I think that looks a lot
better now and that is actually the very
center of the building so it kind of
works out it's like 10 blocks of glass
on that side and 10 blocks on that side
so that's cool and then just to break
the break up the bookshelves a bit more
I added some trapdoors here tried to
make it look like it connects with the
wooden stairs and stuff up there and
then I also worked at fiddling around
with this area so we did like an orange
sky lights I think it looks pretty good
I'm happy with that flower pots for
decoration and stuff connected all these
beams up to this part here and I think
that should be good for now I think
that's all we're gonna do on the library
for today so we still got this big big
area here to work out and we're not
gonna extend that roof don't marry it
anymore we'll probably change this up
and turn into a semicircle or something
I don't know exactly what we're doing
we might even put the doors like over
here to get into the building I'm not
sure yet but that's it for today so
let's go do some other stuff here it's
time for some cleanup we're just gonna
wander the world and look for anything
that needs to be done here one thing for
example we should move the comments of
the day to the library if you don't know
like it takes a lot of time to go to the
library from the man cave here like a
minute or two so at the end of every
episode I don't actually put the
comments in the library I just leave
them in these chests which are totally
filled up right now so I'm gonna move
all these to the library get them in the
right place in case you guys want to
check them out yeah so over here in the
libraries where we actually archive our
comments of the day keep them in
long-term storage it split one chest
every 10 episodes so like 466 would go
over here into the four 60s
for 64 and then I try to organize them
in the proper order too unfortunately a
while ago one of there was a bug that
deleted a lot of our books like the
common inside so it's only gonna be for
like the last 100 episodes or so I think
all right did this set of chests here
this little workstation has been here
since we built the the Korus farm I
still haven't moved it haven't clean it
up because every time every so often
like I'll be in this area and it's like
okay what's in these chests and then OH
I might need some stone or some dirt at
that time and I'll take a another thing
out sand slowly little by little they've
been empty but it's it's time let's just
totally do it now
ether you spent so long building the
Nexus and you never use it what's what's
wrong with you why did you do it
aha I actually do use the guy's just
nuts on camera usually but this is a
perfect opportunity since we're in
cleanup mode this is one of the most
wonderful features of the Nexus it
automatically sorts stuff so I
understand drop off all this garbage and
it will go into the proper Ches all
right this has been here since we built
the smelter not anymore you know I think
today is the day guys this wall has been
with us for like 200 episodes hasn't
been used in like 200 episodes I think
it served its purpose finally we're
gonna tear it down I know I know
it feels feels weird tearing it down cuz
it's been with us for so long I've seen
so many comments it's like is he ever
gonna tear that down and I didn't want
to do it because because of them I kind
of I kind of like to see you guys suffer
with them but it's time I haven't seen
one of those comments in a long time you
guys have like grown to accept it so
it's not as funny anymore so let's let's
take it down homeboy okay there's a lot
of stuff actually guys a lot more than I
realized we're slowly getting our main
area cleaned up here but I haven't even
left like our main world here's all our
little side projects we've done yeah
it's getting there at least something
happened today guys something wonderful
just happened to me let me tell you
about it so earlier today I had to knock
some snow off of a roof right and I was
like okay what do I use what do I use
I didn't need I didn't need to do much
just a little bit so it's like okay
there's a broom next to me that will
probably work I picked it up I shook it
on the ground a couple times to knock
the dirt out of it you know and sure
enough while looking up at what I was
doing there was no dirt falling out or
anything but sure enough there was like
one giant piece of sadhus still in the
room it fell out went right in my eye
and you know sometimes you get something
in your eye it's like oh oh man I gotta
get this thing out but other times it's
like it hurts so bad today it hurts so
bad
I just like stopped what I was doing and
ran inside crying out of one eye and
after like five minutes or so finally
the piece of wood get so soggy from the
tears it didn't hurt as bad anymore but
it took I just finally got it out it's
been like eight hours in my eye I
couldn't get it out as much as I tried
before so I'm feeling so much better
right now I'm so happy it's finally gone
it's left me oh man this is kind of fun
because I don't know what I'm gonna find
either and I just realized I saw there's
a chest at the windmill there from when
we built it I don't know what's inside
it's kind of like opening a present
right now we got to do it quick okay
some flowers and dirts and nothing too
exciting I guess I was hoping for like a
couple stacks of redstone but that
rarely happens guys I just found a chest
at the old ice tray machine here like
this is from so so long ago what's
inside is there redstone like this is a
redstone build there might be some
garbage oh and that got me wondering
what's at the ice cube over here that is
actually two double chests Oh empty okay
and just a little bit of garbage
nothing too exciting the portal glitch
got to clean it up
how much obsidian is here probably yeah
probably listening to stats actually not
too bad alright everybody well I think
we're gonna have to wrap up that pisode
here for today we did get some building
done though and got it relatively
cleaned up there's still I know a couple
chests like at the which firm and like
at the Guardian forearm and there's
probably a bunch I'm not thinking of two
that could be moved in some stuff that
could be cleaned up but for the most
part we got quite a bit done today so
we're gonna check out our comment of the
day this one's actually kind of
interesting I thought says hey etho are
you still into hearthstone if so you
have how have you enjoyed the new
dungeon runs oh if you guys don't know I
actually uploaded to hearthstone videos
in the past quite a while ago actually
I've been playing since beta I think
like three months before the official
release pause and pause actually hooked
me up with the the beta key a long long
time ago and I've been playing it like
off and on ever since usually like not
to too much but I'll I'll play a game
here and there or do an arena run every
now and then I had a pretty good card
collection in our stone actually I've
been been doing like a free to play
account only and up until I think it was
whisper of the gods I kind of stopped
playing the game for all like six to
nine months or something or three
expansions I think I kind of missed out
on because there's like hey Drock C'thun
and you win the game I thought that was
really stupid so I kind of lost interest
at that point but I kind of got back
into it during the Frozen Throne and
also I have tried out the dungeon runs I
did two dungeon
they were really easy up until like the
final level I did finish both of them
though but they don't give you any
rewards right or is there some way to
get rewards out of it I I don't know I
don't think I'll play any more of them
because like what's the point but
they're kind of fun but you know I need
cards too
you got to get my cart collection up so
I thought that was kind of weird you
don't get anything from them
yeah I still like the game every now and
then I like to pay it uh-huh
anyways thank you for the question thank
you guys for watching the episode and I
will see you again in the next one take
care bye bye
[Music]