Oh dum dum welcome back guys how are you
guys doing today
this is etho we're back in my
single-player world here and to start
off with guys what we really need to do
today is some speed mining we need I'm
totally out of redstone I'm totally out
of clay pretty much believe it or not
I'm even almost out of diamonds I don't
know how it happened
never thought I'd run out well actually
you know I do have I still have quite a
bit so what I wanted to try to do here
we're going to check out this new
enchanting and repair system I guess
just a repair system I want to try make
a super duper overpowered pickier
because repair costs have gotten really
cheap in the game so to make an
efficiency 5 fortune 3 unbreaking 3
definitely possible costs 5 levels all
right and then we can name it hopefully
Oh No Gusti levels Wow
let's call it our Opie pick I guess oh
yeah
I'll probably be making a bunch of those
because what I've been using up to this
point is these ones which are just
efficiency 5 unbreaking 3 they don't
have so touch or or anything like that
on them so I'm gonna go do some speed
mining and then we'll see if we can
repair this
whoa all right that's good I still do
that thing where I try to get a
supercharger creeper I was doing the
mining it started thundering like crazy
oh come on it's right above me all the
strikes are happening nearby what was
the fire over there so what I do oh I
think it stopped let you instantly stop
oh no there is still going there's a
creeper out of the trees oh if I see a
lightning strike I run towards it and if
there happened to be a creeper there I'm
guaranteed to get a supercharged of
creeper so it's it's a pretty simple
process but you still gotta get really
lucky with it
this storm this is one of the craziest
storms these trees aren't good though
the prairies would have been better
oh I'm almost dead oh no oh no I wasn't
even I was not watching my health oh
there's a guy right by me okay I'm gonna
run away
I don't think that we're gonna get one
guys but I'm gonna keep recording just
in case
well whoa
this can't be normal well unfortunately
even though that what's the craziest
thunderstorm I think I've seen in this
game no supercharged creeper
nope which is unfortunate because now
that we have this locked difficulty if I
do find one I can probably keep them I
don't have to worry about them
disappearing on me again like you did
last time be cool so I'm gonna keep
checking I might you keep checking
whenever there's a thunderstorm and
hopefully eventually we will get lucky
and find another guy because I miss I
missed that one we found I've been doing
the speed mining it is so much nicer
with the fortune on the pick because
before I would carry two picks with me
the regular picks with just efficiency
and unbreaking and whenever I would have
come across redstone I would have to
switch between the pick I was using and
and one with fortune on and it was just
a lot of hassle so it's much nicer now
with this new pick and we are gonna see
if we can repair it which I'm pretty
sure should be able to I hope because I
made three of them actually so if it
doesn't work I'm gonna be very sad all
right let's go check it out so I think
my let's see I get lost underneath here
because it's so dark oh I'm hungry
that's why I can't run alright where is
it this is like a coal mine man there's
nothing but darkness I don't know where
to go dude where are my chest and my
enchanting table oh here's a creeper we
will save him and he will repay us for
our kindness
I'm lost I can't find my stuff there it
is thank goodness okay so should be
pretty cheap I would imagine
oops here let's let's unload some things
first drop off the compote we got a guy
coming up behind us to kill us too
oh no he's in he's on the lower layer
we're fine okay yeah so I made two more
exact same picks and I'll probably make
a silk touch one two eventually we got
over a stack of redstone umm let's grab
this and this so Oh Matt's five levels
that is so crazy
um do it that way it's seven uh-huh so
definitely possible still still keeps
its name and it costs five levels that's
pretty crazy awesome so now that we got
all that redstone guys we can make some
more whoops
some more power rails here you can see I
made a bunch already I want to have a
track that goes out to my Mesa biome and
we need to finish up that wither
skeleton track because we ran out of
gold other day we've got lots of gold
again wow this is actually the end of it
it took a lot to make these tracks but
we can get more very easily thanks to
those changes we made to the gold farm
let's see I may be able to see how far
these will take us ah you know what it's
the end of the gold let's just use it
all alright so how many is that 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
Oh stacks it looks like a lot but that's
only I think like 700 800 blocks of
track so yeah that was a stat and a half
of gold blocks so I'm gonna start laying
these down and hopefully it's enough
I don't believe it guys we were shorts
we were short just barely almost that
enough so from here and beyond is all
power rails I did the Mesa track as well
this is the one that goes up to the
wither skeleton farm so from from here
to there we need to change out yet
it's like 30 blocks unbelievable let's
go for a ride though it is really cool
so fast
oh yeah that's the money shot right
there let's see our frog thing yeah into
his mouth oh yeah I fixed the turn here
too by the way that's weird it almost
looks like we're going backwards it's
doing like a weird visual glitch like
it's still doing it I'm looking at like
the netherrack on the sides it's kind of
like when wheels on a car start spinning
in a certain speed ups like they start
going backwards that will make you go
crazy if you look too long so yeah this
is where we end up obviously it's not
too fancy at the moment there's no
proper starting or exiting or what would
you call it starting and departure
stations sort of thing there is the farm
over there which I'm very scared of at
the moment because I don't have armor on
that's pretty cool I'm gonna head back
I'll show you the Mesa track oh and I'll
show you the turn I did here - gate here
comes the turn this is how I did it oh
it was a little bit laggy hopefully you
saw that but it's pretty smooth it was
laggy but it's smooth yeah that makes
sense
normally if it's not like you it's a
smooth turn but I did a loop 'ti loop
sort of thing so if it hits a slanted
track it doesn't derail so every time it
does it turn here it's a slanted track
minecarts when they hit a track like
like this a straight track they always
go towards a positive direction so
positive would be this way so that's why
I can get away with with doing this
because when the minecart hits this it
goes this way this direction those the
negative
so I do a loop-de-loop it's downward
slant and it goes that way so it's
pretty cool
let's just let's try go around this one
more time hopefully it won't be as light
you this time oh I should have jumped
out darn it now I got a walk but yeah
that's let's turn there ah I don't have
anymore yes oh that track is gonna see
me a ton of time that is a terrible walk
as I just experienced off this way is
the new Mesa biome track let's go for
ride
pretty good acceleration when you got
solid power rails
this one's a lot shorter though I did
that thing again where the illusion
where it looked like he was going
backwards at least to me anyway
so yeah the Mesa biome is just off to
the side here and I've never shown where
I get my clay or how I get my place and
maybe we'll just check that out too real
quick then I'm gonna mine up a bunch
right so here is the Mesa biome and
honestly I do not remember remember
where I get the clay from it was
somewhere around here though let's see
if we can find it they think it was
that's the creeper yeah I'm looking for
a beacon there's a beacon around here
somewhere
all right the beacon is right over there
right by the portal so let's go check it
out
don't remember I had a path to it
somewhere maybe not and instead of strip
mining the top layer I decided to go go
down and dig it out that way that way we
don't wreck the terrain here
not that I'm really using it but maybe
eventually whoa okay cool
so here's one of the rooms I mined out
oh and I have a bunch of your colored
stuff you're already did I go down
further no that's just for the beacon
this is a haste - oh it's just haste one
that's right you don't need a haste -
for clay
you just need haste one and efficiency
five to mine it oh man I'm a little
disappointed about that I thought I had
a bunch of iron over here in that beacon
but it's just a 3x3 beachin went one
layer anyway so I'm gonna do some mining
guys I'll be back in a little bit
excellent so we have clay again guys
filled up our chests here
plus there's over a double chest over
there still if I need to pick some more
up it should keep us going for a while
see I wanna bring this this I don't know
if we'll use these we're gonna start
something here I don't know what
happened to this guy but he's he needs a
bath
very badly we're gonna head down to our
cave with this guy our buddy I have a
skeleton spawner and he's following very
good whoa dodge the slime
I got a skeleton spawner over here did
he no doubt he's fine I thought I heard
him fall down the stairs
I feel like we need to do something with
it we talked poured it over I thought
he's gonna close the door yeah just to
the right here this wasn't really
planned but the way the key worked out
it went right by this sink which is
pretty cool
and I I don't really need bones or
anything like that I don't really need
experience points anymore because like
honestly that experience points are
almost meaningless in this game now due
to this enchantment changes but well at
least if you're in a world like mine
where you play forever oh okay so I was
just gonna wash it down to cave now good
stop
for good all right you got his bath oh
look at that he got clean amazing I knew
all he needed was a bath very good I'll
have to keep that in mind all right
come on guy so what I want to do is take
out I don't know what I want to do
actually I want to make I want to put a
wolf inside here and have him chase the
skeletons or something along those lines
I want it mostly for show because we
don't need bones like I said we don't
really need experience points but I feel
like it's a waste if we don't do
anything with this this spawner so let's
try to shut it down oh and I got another
torches that was bad planning be right
back yeah okay so I got it shut down I
got rid of the floor in it and the water
and instead we're gonna have them fall
straight down here into some sort of
glass cage with our buddy inside
and hopefully we can make something cool
out of that like try to get him to chase
them or I just or just have them run
away the thing is I can't really have I
can't have this guy up and running
around chasing them because then he will
teleport to me oh wait a minute
what about my glitch dog I wonder huh
you know how I have that one dog
although he's stuck sitting down isn't
he yeah that's right he's useless
I think you man if I could get that guy
in here and have him run around without
him teleporting that would be ideal
I don't think that's gonna work all
right so I'm gonna make a cage and just
to start off with we'll have the this
guy inside and just see what happens all
right boy you ready I don't know what
I'm doing here i'm hoping this gives me
ideas of what we'll do though how to
make this entertaining all right
Skelton fell down oh he's after me what
a jerk oh and he sat right back down
that's interesting you what is he
sitting no I think I have him standing
right oh it's cuz he attacked me that's
right so if they're sitting and I get
attacked he will chase them can I
survive without any armor he wants food
you can't have the steak
I'll give you rotten flesh later just
just keep doing what you're doing
oh he got shot Oh get out of here knee
jerk what huh I thought they would run
away that's not working out too well
okay you get a treat I wasn't expecting
the skeletons to fight him
huh all right all right all right we're
shutting it down I have to think about
that now okay we're gonna try this cage
match thing again except this time I'm
gonna leave the cage and we'll just
leave these two go at it hopefully he
won't come out after me here all right
should get skeletons there we go now
they're still fighting them on earth
I think they need somewhere to run to I
think that's the problem yeah let's open
this up otherwise they will like if they
feel trapped the skeletons they will
fight the wolf let's try this one more
time yeah see they run away if they can
as long as they have somewhere to run to
they won't fight the wolf that's
interesting where did he go Maddie
outmaneuvered you they're supposed to be
fast okay I came up with one idea that
we could try here I don't know how
successful it will be but let's make a
glass floor for this thing so that we
can see the skeletons from from like
over here we'll be able to see upwards
have a wolf in in this corner and then
hopefully try to get the skeletons to
run to this corner drop down then we'll
have another wolf over here which will
hopefully I'm asking for a lot here I
don't know if this will happen try get
this wolf to chase them through a zigzag
pattern thing left right I don't know
how far they'll run but left right left
right
far as we can and then at the very end
of that maybe drop them into lava or or
kill them with a wolf or I don't know
something something along those lines so
don't know how successful it'll be I
will try it out and if that doesn't work
we will try come up with another idea so
we are going to try this out the first
step to the whole thing I got the glass
floor down I got our wolf buddy in the
corner here Haggai and our goal is to
get the skeleton school to go down this
hole here to do that we will do the
trapdoor trick and with them right here
there should be no way of the skeletons
getting across this gap over to here I
also hollowed out a bit of space here so
that they can try to paths find this
direction if they don't have anywhere to
run to they won't run it so we need some
space back there even though it's not
being used um okay I think that's that's
good enough let's give it a try oh oh oh
yeah right off the bat that is very
promising let's just have a few more go
though I was I was expecting this to be
the most difficult part but looks like
it's pretty doable yep yeah those wolves
are really effective alright so we will
try the zigzag thing next alright second
wolf in place
skeletons freak out when they fall down
that is confirmed Oh are they after me
you jerks oh oh oh oh no oh no
shut it down shut it down oh the other
wolf felt weirded down here oh I was so
tough to get him up there to okay so
that didn't work okay here's our second
test
oh I i've noticing they want to go that
direction oh oh that's right that's
right work together now that guy is not
moving at all oh he is he's trying to do
the zigzag but this guy won't let him oh
man work together guys come on Jin
zigzag oh this one skeleton its resting
the whole thing there we go No
change his mind they're going backwards
did he run from this wolf up here cuz it
it looked like he was trying to get out
and then he came back yeah he's running
he's running
yay so there's a few issues to work out
we got to get rid of that block space
there cuz they're trying to run that way
these guys go through I don't know if
they're really trying to run away from
the wolf at that point or if they've
just pathfinding out here hmm anyway
lots of jams lots of problems so from
what I can tell the zig zag idea will
not work once they get like to this
point here they don't really feel the
need to run from the wolf anymore and if
they get to the pit it's because they're
just normally trying to pass find out of
here
but for the most part they're getting
stuck because they can't see where to go
uh-huh so I may get rid of all this wall
stuff and just leave it as a regular mob
farm that uses wolves although I am kind
of concerned because that first layer
works pretty good let's see if we can
find it's something to attack us outside
I'm worried that if I'm just doing
day-to-day stuff and I attacked by a
zombie like over here if those wolves
are gonna teleports and I'll have to
reset them constantly see there's
nothing around here to attack me though
I get this guy to attack me oh man those
guys I don't think I've ever been hit by
one of those guys that was a lot of
damage
okay the wolves didn't teleport you I
don't think they would fight that guy
though any zombies around she tons of
zombies in this village yeah I don't
hear any I gotta remember to close this
oh wait oh did he forget I jumped down
here don't leave forgetting he might
kill me there we go come on guy come on
are you trapped again we gotta go read
the comments come on let's go that's it
that's it
sometimes they do this sideways step
that looks really funny
oh yeah there we go it's kind of doing
it so quickly Oh where's it going man
whoa oh oh he's chasing the skeleton or
not all right
oh come on that was a cheap shot oh I
almost killed it that was a cheap shot
hey whoa hey guy what's your problem
dude easy they increase the movement
speed on those guys he's moving really
fast anyway here is the comment I picked
out for today it says etho if you could
be on any TV show slash game show what
would it be
I'm gonna put game show from this and I
think I'll go with fear factor fear
factor before they start doing those
nasty food challenges because that's
this gross I would not want to do that
the fear factor I used to watch that
show like every episode when it first
came out and it always seemed like a
cool cool game show to be on because it
did you stunts and there's like riding
helicopters and all that kind of cool
stuff yeah so it seemed like like one of
those shows that would be a lot of fun
and also like when you watch it's like
man I could do that so much better than
those guys but then when you get there's
probably not like that I don't know yeah
fear factor I would not really want to
be on a word show or like an
intelligence show because there's always
that risk that you're gonna totally bomb
and it's gonna be on like the tonight
shows and people like make in front of
you that would be that would be a little
scary all right anyway that
is all for today thank you for watching
guys nope
oh they do green sparkles now I don't
know that thank you for watching I'll
see you guys in the next one bye bye
[Music]