awesome aha incredible oh they're so
strong now stop it
Oh fantastic terrific Oh baby
Oh magnificent excellent oh ah splendid
wonderful wonderful Oh superb Oh
unbelievable
now that was tremendous great caving run
look at this stuff all these goodies we
have two stacks of iron no no no three
stack four stacks of iron oh my goodness
47 lapis and the main thing I went for
oh yeah fifty gold is the redstone stack
and a half pretty much that's great
wonderful magnificent I'm going to stop
so this redstone updates it has been oh
I've used up all my words I'm out of
words
yeah it's just so cool I've you know
when it first came out is like okay so
those comparators all right
not really sure how I can use that and
then there's hoppers and
you know that's kind of clear you know
you can automate farms and all that but
now I'm really starting to see how you
can use them to do some pretty cool
stuff or to use all this all these new
features to do cool stuff ah my redstone
supply though is very very low as usual
so I have to go teeming specifically
forts and we would take some of this but
you can automate anything now like you
not me furnaces you can automate brewing
automate farm ah really cool stuff yeah
my missile smell the goal too but you
can also like this is what I like about
the stuff mode ring introduces to the
game like sure it's pretty obvious some
of the uses for this stuff but there's
also a lot of like like you take
comparators and hoppers and you can
combine them to make other key
components to making even cooler stuff
when you combine those key components
and it's just you get all these cool
cool features from just a few new blocks
redstone blocks and we're going to get
into that a little deeper today this is
going to be again kind of a redstone
themed episode although I'm not really
going to focus on the redstone I'm going
to focus on the logic and all that stuff
that's everyone can appreciate that hope
we're going to have to pick let's
enchant the pick now let's enchantress
sword we're going to do a sword yeah
oh the neck I can't quite tell like it
for a while I thought maybe my framerate
dropped but maybe not yeah we're going
to make us we're going to make a coal
sword today you actually got a s what do
you call it a solid-state drive another
day I haven't installed it yet though
but when I want to get that installed
them into all my recording to that and
my framerate should be a lot better when
I'm playing Minecraft and recording I
hope I have to get around to doing that
though alright and looting nope oh it's
bedtime ah you know I don't actually
have a bed down here
otherwise I'd go to sleep mmm I have one
in this chest let's want to try try this
out I'm wondering how close that song
plays towards where I can get the
morning song to play because it might I
may have to wait a few seconds longer
after that song
all right so pretty soon after maybe
even right after I hear the nighttime
song if I sleep I didn't hear the
morning song I think anyway I'm gonna
I'm gonna bust this stuff up get a bunch
of redstone and I'll introduce you to my
my plan for today all right so here's
the plan for today as you guys know in
my single-player world Here I am all
alone nobody here with me I'm not
necessarily lonely but you know I
wouldn't mind having a companion
I need my Wilson you could say so I've
thought about maybe taming a wolf or an
ocelot have them as a companion I've
tried that in the past though and
honestly they always die usually they
get in my way were they or something
happens to them they disappear
especially when there was all those
glitches with them teleporting in yeah
anyway so I don't think I'm going to go
that route what I would like to do is
build a pet uh-huh and we're going to
use redstone to program our pets oh it's
dark out so I'm going down send you one
down all right so somewhere in my cave
I'm gonna build them and basically I'm
trying to I haven't done anything with
this by the way
there goes both multiple note blocks
what the heck because I logged out I bet
you yeah yeah I don't know what that was
it's a logo glitch anyway that the goal
is to kind of emulate Tamagotchi in
Minecraft if you guys know what
Tamagotchis I'm sure most people know
what it is it
I've never owned a tamagotchi but I know
when I was a kid I had it on my computer
and I have vague memory of how it worked
but I looked online for white and sleep
for the game mechanics behind that and
I'm going to try emulate that so I want
a face for our pet first of all so let's
try pick out a face we're going to build
a screen sort of here so I think I'm
going to try a seven by seven and see
what we can make out of that
we want our pet to express emotion if
possible so happy faces sad faces what
is that one two three four that's only
for that kind of thing you know I really
like about this quartz block by the way
you can break it easy look at that so
it's good for building temporary things
like this we're going to move this oh
yeah we got to figure out a spot for it
too what is that three six seven okay so
I think that's about the size of screen
I want for our pet and give it some eyes
and maybe a mouth oh yeah definitely a
mouth let's just do let's do a happy oh
yeah all right that's the future face of
our pet so he's going to have different
moods I'm going to try program different
moods into him different happiness
levels so I think that will be happy
happy mood let's try give them a neutral
what's this look like this is all the
skeleton oozes okay that's a good
neutral face and then I just the
opposite of a happy face is a sad face
let's see
oh yeah that's going to be our sad face
and maybe day we need a dead face too
let's try let's just do this I think
this will work
that's kind of like the impact man you
know the ghost looks a little too lively
though let's let's thinker with eyes a
bit sure
why not okay that's going to be our dead
face and that face actually if we do
that what's it look like if we have our
sad face back all right that's going to
be like beyond sad this face here this
is like I don't care about anything
anymore you don't you don't treat me
right face and if we do that reversed we
might have a like a super content with
life oh yeah super content with life
face let's that's above happy face
alright so we got we got six different
faces there we have super happy happy
neutral sad and I I hate you
and then our dead face cool okay I'm
happy with that that's a good range so
what I did here is I just took a moment
just to write a book pet project plan
it's a best-seller people love it
this book here outlines some of my plans
for our pet here for our game and how
the mechanics are going to work and not
I did this so you guys can see kind of
the end goal for this what I'm aiming
for I haven't built this in creative or
anything so your your hand along on the
ride with me here we're going to try
figure it out together it's going to be
very complicated it's going to take a
bit of time we're not doing it today
totally but yeah this is what we're
shooting for so with our pet we want him
to have stats he's I found I figured out
I want these
six main stats that yes and the
mechanics for this by the way again is
based off of Tamagotchi I went to the
Tamagotchi wiki page and read on it and
I broke it down into these six stats is
what I think we want our pet to have so
he's going to have an age over time well
actually I'm not going into the details
just yet age happiness under health wait
attention these will define how well our
pet is doing okay so like with our face
here this is going to be a direct
reflection of his happiness level so if
his happiness level is full he's going
to have this face if it's all the way
down he's going to have that I hate you
face and if health is all the way down
he's going to be dead and he'll have the
dead face okay that's that's kind of how
that mechanics going to work and we're
going to have stat bars beside his face
one for each of these probably the H bar
is going to be over top as head here
we're going to use lamps to show to show
this information and basically with a
game you need like four key components
you need a timer so a game a game timing
that constantly loops and every loop
it's it does different calculations and
updates events and causes stuff to
happen in the game right so I just made
a tutorial on the hopper timer that's
what I'm going to use to do stuff so
like over time
age is going to keep increasing and
we're going to use the timer to do that
for example or hunger is going to
decrease constantly over time all right
we also need what do we need we need
logic in the game so we're going to do
that using redstone we're going to
connect the different stats together in
different ways for our logic and we need
a way for the player to interact with
the game so we're going to have like a
hopper we can throw food in to feed them
stuff like that
and importantly here we need variables
each of these stats is a variable and
thank you or thanks to the redstone
update we can actually do variables in
this game sort of these hoppers are
amazing this is like my favorite
mechanic in the game right now
when you put two hoppers together you
can do amazing things so I kind of found
out a way I can do a variable if we do
this and then put a block beside it with
a redstone torch like that we can do
some pretty cool stuff and then we can
control it with redstone like that so
let's put actually just just a second
here we need comparators I don't have
comparators I'll be right back all right
so check this out this is my example of
how you can do a variable in this game
now this block and redstone torch combo
here is very cool because it allows us
to control which hoppers feeding into
the other one not one of them is always
going to be powered one of them is
always going to be unpowered with that
then I also have a lever up here which
powers both of them or it like freezes
everything if it's powered so if I
switch this when it's frozen nothing
happens and what we can do with this
lever is basically control addition and
subtraction in our variable so we have
64 plus 28 items in here this is just
enough to light up five redstone spaces
or or five lights here now if we
unfreeze this nothing happens because
it's on subtraction right now we could
say if we switch it to addition it's
going to start going this way so we can
add or we can subtract from our variable
very easily with this and then we can
freeze it
so like when an update happens we can
either take away or add to a stat very
easily depending on how long we
unpowered us and whether we're adding or
subtracting yeah and there's also this
is another cool trick by the way if we
if we use an item that doesn't stack as
much like ender pearls or eggs we can
make go quicker too so we have we have
like a four times speed mode here oops
2 2 2 2 2
whoops stuff is still sticking there we
go how many do we need 1 2 Oh another
one still another one still we had it
right darn it okay so now watch how fast
this changes compared to before pretty
fast switch it starts going the other
way and yeah you get the idea so you see
where I'm going with this then I think
it's going to be a lot of fun I hope
you're excited so let's go back to our
pet project plan for each of these stats
I kind of wrote out a rough little idea
of how I want them to interact in the
game so age down here every update add a
constant amount to age so our pet would
get older at a constant rates and
basically if he gets to his full age
which will probably be represented by 15
laps then it's like we win we kept them
alive then under hunger that needs to be
fed frequently hunger drains at a
constant rate so our game clock is going
to keep draining away the hunger hunger
can be replenished with various meals
and snacks so we throw food into the
hopper and it goes back up so there's
going to be meals and there's going to
be snacks I think in Tom
gachi Emile's good for repledge
replenishing hunger but a snack can
replenish it a little bits and it also
will replenish or increase happiness a
little bit so it will interact with more
than just one stat that way and also I
think it increases weight too so
happiness is a reflection of all other
stats maximum happiness requires pet to
be full health to be perfect wait to be
bounced and attention to be satisfied so
it's going to be an overall look at all
the stats how well the pet is doing it's
going to change slowly I think health
pet being overweight or underweight will
cause health to suffer so you want the
weight to be average starving is bad for
health so if we neglect our pet and
don't feed him regularly and his health
bar goes all the way down is that's a
health bar hunger bar hunger bar goes
all the way down then his health is
going to start going down as well
messy living conditions is bad for
health severe lack of attention will
cause depression which is bad for health
I might change it getting sick is bad
for health pet always has a random
chance of getting sick but this chance
increases at lower health and messy
conditions ah attention attention stat
will decrease at a steady rates can be
increased by interacting with pets so I
might set up games somehow that we can
play with our pet I don't know how that
would work this whole idea is a little
bit crazy wait feeding pet increases
weight weight decreases slowly over time
snacks increase weight more than a
normal food overfeeding pets increases
weight more so
so if our pet is full and we keep
feeding him his weights going to go up
more than if we just feed them normally
and weed is bad for health so that's
kind of like a rough overview of what I
want to do with this ok so we kind of
got to figure out an interface here to
for our pet we have our face figured out
these emotions are going to be
controlled by Pistons in the back
and they'll be connected to the
happiness bar and the health bar it I
don't know if I said it but if health
goes all the way down our pet dies and
we lose we lose our friend so for the
overall look at I think I want 15 lamps
over top the head for the age that's
like our our progress bar on our score
kind of if we can keep them alive if we
neglect our pet he will die
that's kind of the overall idea behind
this and I guess maybe we'll just have
like a border going around the face that
comes out one right yeah we'll need to
get light in here too
probably otherwise the face is going to
be really dark hmm do that and then
maybe one back we'll have our stat bars
and I think I want these to be five
blocks or five lamps total let's just
see what this looks like I'm running out
of quartz and it'll mine some more two
three four five and twenty four if we do
that we can stack probably three
together then two on the other side and
then at the very bottom we'll have a way
of interacting with the pet like will
feed them there I think that'll work out
good I'm gonna snag the stuff okay
Oh dead lose one No
okay okay and a border here should I
build it out of quartz guys tell me I
love quartz I use it all the time now
and I probably will if you don't stop me
so just the warning and then yeah like
our next our next step bar is going to
be above this one like one block above
yeah and then another one above that I
think that looked pretty good because we
can do that pretty sure yeah because
this the wiring to light up the lamps is
going to be one block in and that will
be flush with it so that should work out
and we're going to need how much space
get out there this looks like 1 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 so 14 times to
like 27 probably 27 blocks wide because
it's an odd number that's a bit of space
and a lot of space in the back for
wiring and this will be 3 7 9
oh man probably 12 tall 11 or 12 tall
total mmm that's a lot of space okay so
we've got to find a home for our pets
where do we want to keep them it should
be an area I'm nearby quite often but
kind of out of the way mmm where to put
our pets where should we put them I've
been looking around my area here trying
to figure out the best place for it ah
the place I visit the most probably or
where I spend most of time in this cave
is a storage room furnace area so we
want it kind of close to that because
I'm probably gonna have some noteblocks
and stuff where he can communicate with
us in in some way
so I want to be within range of that
hopefully so I didn't hear it crying for
help or something like that so this
would be a good spot for that there's
also no no other projects if we go keep
going this way so I'm not going to hit
anything that's going to get in the way
I would have to hollow out a bunch of
land here though this isn't exactly
shaped right so that's one idea put it
there
maybe put it back here somehow but I
think trying to think if that would hit
anything I don't think I have anything
there either so that could be a
possibility although the mushroom farm
that's there yeah if we keep going might
hit that somehow the other idea is we
could put it over here somewhere
definitely wouldn't hit anything and
there's a lot of space kind of figured
out already like opened up Hey
but this is probably too far away to
hear noteblocks and same with tree farm
area I think that's too far away so I
think we're going to put it up over here
would be best all right so we got our
plan for our pets we're not actually
going to get to building it today
unfortunately I did wasted too much time
talking but I will work on it and then
I'll bring you guys in when we start
moving further with the plan so I'm
going to build the interface and then
we'll start putting stuff together um I
think it's going to turn out pretty good
though I'm hoping I might it might be a
little bit too difficult I'm not sure
we'll see as we get to it though also if
you guys have any ideas on the pets
design or pet project or Dean mechanics
behind it please let me know in the
comments and I will hopefully see it I
do read
comments every episode I put out and
we're going to reach them right now
publicly so here we go you should try
out Dwarf Fortress so this is in
response to me saying what type of games
I liked last episode I have tried out
door fortress before I thought it was
going to be a game I really like because
the game design and game mechanics - it
seemed like something I would really
enjoy and I'm not the type of person
that usually cares too much about
graphics the game being fun and cool is
more important to me than actual looks
or anything like that I keep believing
my camera like this that's really
annoying alright but you know I tried
Dwarf Fortress out and I realized I have
a limits on graphics it was at the point
where I couldn't comprehend what was
going on in the game I couldn't tell
what was happening so I couldn't enjoy
it so hopefully they'll update the
graphics to that one day and maybe I'll
try it again and enjoy it then but I
didn't really enjoy it to be honest just
because of the graphics alright second
comment though for me you are the
biggest and best video maker not that
big I'm not fat and best video maker on
YouTube and I really mean that I've been
enjoying your videos from the starts
thank you very much I like reading nice
comments like that every every now and
then it's good to see them and I really
appreciate your guys's support so that's
going to be it for today guys thank you
for watching and I'll work on work on
some of that stuff we talked about today
you