oh that darn Enderman got me I was
messing around with them I shouldn't
have been I tried to push him into a
hole and when I when he fell in the hole
I must have looked at him he got mad two
hits and I was dead that was it level
one again what can you do
ah I need to get some cows going here so
I can make a leather armor because I'm
still very vulnerable at right now
and I don't really want to use my iron
on armor I'd rather save it for other
things but yeah I've been working very
diligently on our wheat farm here let's
turn out pretty good I got stone bricks
along the bottom two blocks I don't know
what I'm gonna do about the walls I
don't want it all stone bricks but it
should be something it's got to be
something right otherwise it won't exist
so you got to figure that out
I added lava lighting on the sides here
I guess that's the front yeah that's the
front that's the back so I'll have a
lighting on the front and back we got
the lab behind the pistons and I also
did the pumpkin thing place them under
the water so pumpkins are light level 15
at the water it's 13 because water
reduces light by two instead of just one
so 15 13 12 with the fence 11 10 9 and
you need light level 9 or higher to grow
wheat so it worked out perfect because
the libel behind the Pistons lights up
everything within these three blocks
mm-hmm so everything is lit and
everything is hydrated and now I have
water hidden down here and on the side
as well to take care of the few blocks
that we didn't get last time
I hooked up a redstone how do I get back
there you have all a little hole here
wait which side has a weed on okay I'll
show you with the side so water is above
the piston arms here open it yet a
little bit of leg from it but it's
temporary and it'll flood everything all
the weak will go down to the stream
below but the mobs won't be able to
because of the fence and it will go to
over there so yeah it's coming along
pretty good
it's almost done the wheat farm part you
got to work on cow stuff now our cow
crops so the first thing we need to do
with the cows is we got to make a cow
shoot so it's some way of us to get the
cows from the surface down to our farm
here nice and easy so I'm thinking we'll
have the cows come out here on both
sides like that have this like that
there'll be a wall here okay and then we
need a hole up to the surface so we may
as well put it here I guess oh I hit
something oh just that okay not a big
deal that to a farm land yep
okay so I will use gravel to pull her up
and dig my way up to the surface it's
always good to have a torch under you in
case sand falls or something oops
another hole
okay so I will see you in a little bit
you died again got stuck in the water
against a bunch of skeletons can it move
that no bow on me what can you do Mary
oh so we came up in one of the worst
possible spots in the middle of some
water
Oh give me a moment to click myself here
aha okay so I built like a tree type not
really a tree fake tree hut thing here I
decided to use the water to our
advantage
Oh got creeper to FYI
what I'm going to do put one of these
fence things in the middle of all this
right over here
open it so the animals léopold to the
center here and there'll be a hole below
so we just need to lure them to this one
of these water streams that's all we
have to do and they'll fall down to our
farm hmm a little bit worried none of
the wheat I have planted in the center
seems to be growing I don't know why I'm
hoping it's a coincidence
I know wheat does grow at different
rates depending on how it's placed and I
don't mind if it's slow I just hope it
does grow still trying to avoid putting
lights above the wheat farm and you'll
see why in a little while but I might
have to if it's not growing or I could
just put like I said before just replace
one of the tilled soil with glass and
laughable Oh or something
or a pumpkin okay so we're back here yes
let it rain it's a long ways up oh I
never put ok I got a bit like tubing
around there too in those open spots
above but then what we're going to do
here is we're going to make a water
break for the cows or whatever animals
we push down okay we can't push chickens
down or they'll get stuck in the water
break okay and then they will either go
left or right here into their pen and
then they'll be stuck down here and
we'll have to pretty it up later
actually most of this wheat is grown
already so I'm thinking it's time for
our first harvest here we go
see how it goes
ah very nice very nice that's what I
like to see let's see if anything got
stuck anywhere and of course I got to
hook the two sides together with
redstone wiring but for now it's just
individually operated yet nothing looks
like you got stuck on the sides anywhere
that's perfect all went down nothing in
the fences down below there that's good
yeah so that turned out pretty good
nice 74 seats so I I planted about 50
there so now we have 20 more or so very
cool you ready let's do it I go over
here you go into the stream nope you go
into the stream that you're following me
now you're drowning don't drown okay
okay another very cal cal you're not
doing this right you're not supposed to
die okay come on
yeah okay we'll do it this way come
through no cat look I have food okay
Daisy is that your name Daisy come here
what you're afraid of water now food see
good food follow good it wasn't supposed
to be this difficult
oh you gotta be kidding me are you dying
again I got to fix the water around here
no you're not ah freezing gel just going
going going going
ah yes finally
do I need to modify this a bit that that
was too painful yeah she's fine down
there let's head downstairs very cool so
now we just need at least one more oh we
got childs and pigs little baby pigs and
little baby cows I never knew that they
followed the babies around
they're pretty annoying okay I just
checked the forms in someone dark one
dark one sent me a message about the
wheat here apparently
I've been doing it wrong you need light
level 9 above the wheat not on the wheat
so it's like all this week's is 1 light
level lower than I planned so what I'm
just going to do is gonna I'm gonna put
a pumpkin in the middle and that should
take care of it let's see 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
I think this is the middle right over
here and I can't place a pumpkin down no
don't you do that to me I am your master
and you are my supper
ok 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
good so we got a pumpkin there we'll do
one on the side and that should take
care of the whole deal 1 2 3 and yeah
that should take care of it
so we got a family here when I went for
the cow to pigs followed me all the way
home too so that's why we have pigs for
now but I do plan on making this mostly
a dairy farm so when it gets established
these guys might disappear mysteriously
we'll see
oh sweet justice did you burn right he's
not dying
yes ha ha that's what you get so there's
something I want to show you guys I
found a new cave area this is where I'm
getting my lava from now on for the time
being its quick way down to the lava
level not not quite down there let's see
where is it it's down here yeah we're
here go to the right and I've been
playing around with lava lights let me
know what you think of them pretty
simple but they light up the area very
nicely
I have not explored a whole lot and then
the lava is just down here and I found
the most amazing thing most amazing
thing there's redstone and not only that
there's more redstone over there and
even there's some iron over there so
it's awesome I'm going to harvest one of
these right now just to show you how
excited I am awesome yeah so are our
crops are developing nicely down they're
growing quite a bit
now on to the next part of the farm
there is a reason I built this in a pit
and this is the part where you find out
what a monster I am with the ladder here
just we're just testing it first get our
fishing rod who wants to volunteer mmm
not bad not bad air on that guy that
might work trying to figure out what
height I need so the idea behind this
farm is you could either go down there
and harvest animals or you can fish them
from above mostly for fun just something
different one idea I had was doing
something like this have a half slab
floating in the up above with a way of
getting to it so that's what I have set
up here I don't think it's going to work
though like we can move around here
without falling and get back out by
jumping it's good the only problem is I
think a lot of the times animals will
hit their heads on this glass I don't
know I mostly been aiming for the pigs
oh good air pretty good air
oh I might have to change it so yeah I'm
going to try make this work we'll see
we'll see how it turns out I can always
change it after if I'm not happy so how
how do I do this I can't really build
here can I the tough spot to be in right
now what I'm going to do let's see what
level of my it the idea is not just fish
the mobs up here and let them die from
fall damage that's not what I want that
was just the test I want to collect them
okay so water will be at this site here
which the pig flew up to I believe I
want to make about a nine by nine cube
around this point at this height at this
level yeah nine by nine seven by seven
might work I don't know can we get rid
of this and this I want one of these
there that's five by five we gotta go up
two more mmm that really sticks out
quite a bit that's fine and I'll
probably add glowstone or something up
here eventually to make it look cooler
all right I'll see you in a bit
yeah I don't know don't know exactly
what I'm doing here but we'll try make
it work I was going to use glass on the
outside but I'm going to use leaves
instead you look cool
and I have to go up one more block so I
just put a layer of gravel down that I
liked how leaves don't disappear anyone
if you place them yourself that is a
very cool feature okay there we go now
I'm going to flood this with water just
stay with me I'm going somewhere here
I'm sure plug this with water weight and
feel a little bit like from that yeah
this is strange
actually I should've did now whatever
will do this for now I needed another
layer of water now that I think of it
and I'll remove this gravel I've got a
stack of these offense gates and I'm
going to put it underneath all the water
now like that this should work I'm
hoping I don't want to redo all this
fence deeds are placed there open add an
extra ring of leaves to make it look
better I don't know
now I need your the soil in the gravel
I'm hoping if I break the soil drive a
little break below cool so I'll do that
now
and it should be ready for testing again
there it is
that's what it looks like as funny as I
dropping gravel bombs on the cows below
and they were freaking out yeah that's
what it looks like I messed up a little
bit with the fence gates I might have to
change it if we keep this some of them
are facing different ways and they don't
quite look right it reminds me of a UFO
kind of it's perfect you know a UFO
above the cows here and it sucks them up
it's just perfect
I don't know what we should call this
farm asset has to do something with UFOs
I think the name anyway I don't really
have a setup here
but we'll just go into it like this for
now fix this and here we go we're going
to try it out hopefully they don't hit
their head on anything good chance they
will though go for another Pig oh that's
another problem
ah darn it oh my goodness
oh man Jamis curtsey oh okay we're
having problems here though
unfortunately ah how should I do this
let's try to get at least one no I don't
think it had enough height it's not
enough height darn it it's one block to
up to high ah that's too bad oops
double hook it midair again no height
now our Chow is heavier or something or
what's going on the pigs had no trouble
dang
let's try pig I have picked Cynthia more
air
hmm okay well it's not quite right not
quite right we'll have to fix it or
figure something else out
too bad that would have been perfect ah
I think I'll leave it here for today
we'll end it here I'll think about this
some more and we'll try to finish up the
UFO part of the farm anyway thank you
for watching as always I'll see you
again next time