good readings everybody this is etho and
we're gonna start off today with an
enchantment going for looting three it's
like five knocked back to decent decent
not bad
alrighty so for today's episode I think
we will take a little bit of a break
from all this timer stuff I've been
doing lately just for just for variety
just crush the creeper and there's a
creeper in there how did you get in
there OOP okay well we'll stay clear of
it let's see if we can kill ya we're
gonna take a break from this can't see
me doesn't want to jump now either I
should I hear a few more of them around
they think yeah we'll we'll work on this
some other time
pair squirrel has made a video about it
how I can do the redstone a lot more
compact and efficient he seems to have
it working properly which is good so
I'll probably just copy what he's shown
so that we can get the timer working
like I want but another day today we
will you know I can't do it and I gotta
kill just wouldn't be right there we go
for today we'll probably just do small
projects again I got quite a few on mine
that I need to do and we may even go to
the nether to work on the blaze farm if
if it works out the first thing I wanted
to do was hook up that golden door and
get it actually working so at the moment
I just have a lever controlling it and I
stick in look at the wiring down here I
think the way I want to do it is just
excuse me I hope you didn't hear that I
was just drinking coffee I'll probably
do this like I did the potion room door
I just had two buttons on the side I was
thinking of doing like pressure plates
that you walk over to control a T
flip-flop and then when you walk on the
other said it closes it so it'd be like
open-close open-close type thing but
this wirings kind of in the way so I
think I'll just stick two buttons on
this one alright so that's the default
so we would need to put redstone over
there and over here so let's get our
proper blocks and I'll probably just
hook them up to a T flip-flop two
redstone there and some over here hmm
you got to be really careful here
because this redstone torch is powering
this block so I think oh there goes my
framerate I think to avoid that I'll put
a block there and then we need to hook
the wiring from the T flip-flop we just
built up to the wiring for the door and
it should be done
that's simple let's give it a try here
hmm it's working oh that's weird yeah
it's working except these buttons are
causing this corner one to mess up it's
opening last when it shouldn't be
why don't think it should be doing that
it's diagonals from the piston weird oh
I know why because it's sending power to
that log we just broke I bet you if I
break this one I'll probably work
I have no idea why Oh cuz I put that
there and now it's working
hmm so I might do the pressure plates
after all these buttons are interfering
all right give me a minute all right so
that switch has been made we're using
pressure plates now instead of the
buttons on the side of the door seems to
work really well at the top of the
stairs here we have three wooden ones
and over it opens it then on the other
side of the door there are three stone
ones here which close it when you walk
over them and then it works in Reverse -
that way because we're using a T
flip-flop every time you press it it
switches so this is the wiring for it
turned out pretty nicely above here this
is the stone pressure plates here here
and here they power this wire which goes
underneath the other wiring we had then
it comes back up over here and then
above the wood is the wooden ones here
here and here so all six pressure plates
joined together on the same wire and
then that goes to this redstone torch
which controls a piston T flip-flop here
and this is I saw this in a video by
minecraft addict he found a way I think
he did of he calls it super charging t
flip-flops because and normally the way
that you have them they're unpowered by
default so when you switch them it takes
quite a while to switch you gotta wait
for the button to be pressed but with
the supercharged ones you have it
powered by default and then you gotta
put a button over here then it switches
pretty much instantly
as soon as you press the button so it's
much quicker that way in fact I think
okay I could run up the stairs and get
through the door while it's opening
let's try it out the double tap still
have trouble sprinting yet that break my
stride that's nice alright so I think
that door is done finally we can move on
with our lives
okay another project I wanted to do a
little bit with is a slime farm here
this is not the final version like I'm
not happy with the way this is right now
one feature I wanted to try add was a
slime reducer to get them all to the
smallest size to have that option and
the way I was thinking of doing that
usually people do a drowning system that
shrinks them down but I was thinking of
trying something a little different I'm
gonna try make a lab a blade rate in
that corner there and that should get
rid of the large slime so they split
into mediums and then beyond that we can
try shrink the mediums down with a lab
of blade to hopefully so I'm gonna get
start I'm gonna get started on working
on that and I will be back in a sec yeah
I think I got all the stuff we need to
do this should be pretty quick I don't
know if you'll be able to see it working
or not working because it's hard to spot
the slimes in time see I think I'll put
it over here
yeah because slimes they have a unique
characteristic where they won't jump
around when they're in water
they'll just ride the stream which means
we can we don't have to worry about them
jumping into the lava like the smaller
ones they should stay put so there
should be should work okay so we gonna
run it over here and let's see it will
go here like this and make it all nice
and pretty
I'm just gonna use a piston to hold the
LAV in place see and we need the
lavatory four blocks is its maximum
distance I think one two three and then
one more for the air so ya stop there
lava goes here then we need the piston
over here just use a regular piston and
this is what will power to turn it to
turn the LAV oblate on or off and yeah
that's it so
fill this in gonna be ready to run here
lap ah oh no we forgot something I'm
gonna use a sign over here to hold the
lab up and that'd be nice and simple way
of doing it
oh we got slime coming please be a big
one please be a big one
nope ah these guys I don't know try to
do the medium ones too somehow
anyway that's all there is to the big
ones I think that'll take care of them
because they're 2.4 blocks tall and they
will be I don't maybe that's too high
see they'll be on the stair and then the
top corner of them will just graze the
lava so it might work I'll have to keep
an eye on it
all right we got a big one coming see
what happens
oh oh not enough damage darn it move too
quick one it might be because he's sauce
and he started moving quicker I have to
add one more lava blade these guys I
wonder if they favor aside or not
doesn't seem like it hmm
so I got this set up here to hopefully
reduce the size of the medium slimes
without killing the little ones when
they split we'll have to see how it goes
so does have a piston in it so I can
control it and it's very tricky place
this there we go
one two three four in there
Oh
mm that figured something wrong here oh
dang it
what happened there one two three four
I'm not sure why it did that
all right clean-up on aisle four yeah
that's something I didn't know before
apparently lava travels further from a
sub lava source and it does from the
main source so main source four blocks
and a sub source is five or a sub stream
or whatever you want to call it one two
three four five
very weird I find that weird because
water doesn't do that let's see one two
three four five six seven eight you
wondering about the cobble it's from
creeper creeper explosions filler got
cobble all over the place under the
ground yeah so that goes eight and if
you do a sub it also goes eight so that
might be a bug actually that the lab is
going further than it should very
strange
I guess I'll do it like this I'll have
the lab aright here this thing can still
control it listen and hopefully that'll
take care of the medium ones I'll have
to watch this and see what happens
small one let's make sure he can get
through because there's about a there's
a block clearance a little once you get
through that they like to jump if I'm
standing here I wonder if that'll be a
problem and I added a second Latta blade
here for the big ones because they
weren't taking enough damage I saw I saw
another one go through and he had the
same problem so we'll leave it at that
for today and keep an eye on it I guess
whoa I put some block stoppers at the
bottom there to hopefully catch some of
the medium and large slimes so we can
see if this works or not but yeah I'm
really starting to think that lava thing
is a glitch because a few minutes later
here now and it has decided to shorten
its toll shorten itself to four blocks
instead of the five I don't know what
caused this if it's just it updated or
what but it's shorter now which is an
interesting okay so another thing we
might do today or at least start is
minecart track for the slimes I would
like it to go around the tree farm I
think so all around the edge here all
around that back wall there and then the
the other side here and it will probably
come well I still haven't fixed that
leaf there probably come up here
somewhere and they'll probably go around
this area - a little bit I'm doing it
just because I want more life in my cave
here I love this space but I like it
when things move I like it when sounds
get played and stuff like that I want to
hook up more note blocks and I don't
know things that move especially if
they're random or very nice to look at
in your minecraft places like like these
cows for example very fun to watch so
I'm gonna get started on clearing some
more land here and hopefully I might go
for like a wooden look for the minecart
track and maybe raise it up a little bit
higher than the sandstone here we'll
have to keep it at least I think we'd
put the track over here we need at least
one block away from the trees otherwise
the signs will suffocate in the trees as
they go by okay well we finally caught a
big slime here took a while we're gonna
see if this works or not going to try oh
I gotta be careful here don't try update
this so it goes out further oh great why
does w have to be next to cute give me a
minute
awesome so we finally go to test this
I've been waiting for this chance let's
see what happens
get out oh he's still lived
hmm not entirely sure what happened
there okay it needs some work yet okay
change of plans here I had a new idea
while clearing this out that I think is
gonna be a lot cooler what we're gonna
do we're gonna make the slimes the big
slimes go underneath the half slabs so
just the top of their heads will be
sticking out above the half slabs I
think you'll look really funny because
they don't take suffocation damage going
through half slabs so we can run a rail
over here with them in we will have to
get rid of all these blocks on the side
so otherwise they will suffocate both
sides so have it nice and open like that
you won't be able to see it though
because it'll be covered and then you
can have your minecart and basically
you'll just have half slabs above like
that big slimes will be in it and
they'll be free to travel underneath the
half slabs and I think just like their
eyes will be showing it'll look really
funny I pretty sure so that's the way
we're gonna do it we'll have them go all
the way around all these areas that I
have the block missing I might make them
go down Isles - I'm not sure yet because
glowstone will won't suffocate them
either I don't think so we can have them
go down here the only problem is these
are evenly spaced it's four blocks so it
wouldn't be symmetrical which might be
an issue but yeah I'll basically go all
the way around the tree farm and we
might make them go a few other places
yet - oh what
mmm-hmm let's go over here it's over
here I've changed a bunch of lighting
around so now there's probably a dark
spot somewhere we got another one here
and I have moved the lava
so instead me in the corner it's it's in
a place where I think they'll stay in it
a little bit longer and we'll see if
that does more damage without causing
any slimes to die here we go
Danny's moving quicker than he should
oh yeah much better
ouch these guys
oh they passed straight through that so
I need them to be in the lava longer too
so I should maybe move it um it's tough
to move it though cuz I can't put signs
down here or it'll block the water so
I'm not sure what to do about those guys
that seems to work for the big ones at
least we can probably even get rid of
this corner one man I tell you this
whole episode I've been hearing this
slime finally found it he's up there
driving me crazy I don't know how he got
up there why 50 I musta made his way
somehow oh he came up hmm that's weird I
don't know where he came from delta-t
what I came up here
nothing down there I don't know that's
strange gotta fix this one day I have to
you yeah I got this track all set up now
it just does a full loop around I'll go
on a little ride here so this is a this
is a path the slimes will be taking the
big ones
there's a ravine to the left here like
right next to here so I just got to
cover this up and it should be okay I
got these power rails space maximum
eight blocks apart and that's just so if
there's no slimes in the cart for some
reason the cart will keep going around
still and I tried it out it works the
cart will go on its own and I made sure
I stayed here while it went around just
in case it unloaded or something and
stopped on the track but it was fine it
made it all the way around this other
side it takes a long time though it's a
big loop so it should be pretty cool
we just need to hook it up to our slime
thing here we know how to get them into
the carts already we just need to figure
out how we're doing this front good cool
I don't think the signs will despawn as
the carts going around I don't think
it's far enough away yeah so that's
that's gonna be cool
yes I didn't kill him did I anyway guys
I gotta get going here so I'm going to
say goodbye for today next episode we
are committed to this already we're
gonna be killing the dragon once and for
all
and I'm not gonna make I don't know
I don't not gonna make a big deal about
it like it's I kind of him but obviously
the fights not gonna be hard we're just
gonna try have some fun with it and if
it seems like it's gonna be boring I'll
just skip most of it but I'll get
potions together I'll get gear together
and TNT hopefully and we'll try have
some fun but if it's seems like it's a
lame fight which is a good chance it
will I'll just skip most of it because
the dragon does flies around for like 20
seconds 30 seconds and it swoops down
and attacks and then it flies around on
another 30 seconds and then it's hoops
down it's so at least make them shoot
something you know like a gas does it
would be just a little bit more
interesting but oh well we'll see what
we can do we'll try have some fun but
I'll see you guys next time
thanks for watching today and take care