here we go here we go come on come on
nobody's watching except for me and
everybody else and even that guy hiding
behind the bushes there come on they're
not going to do it okay
I welcome back to everybody to another
episode of Minecraft here there is a
librarian here though and I get very
excited whenever there's a new librarian
do we have paper yes we do so there's a
chance for super duper ultra amazingly
lucky here we can get the mending and
frost watching enchantments from this
guy which would be amazing otherwise I
got a fish it or I gotta go find it
somewhere yes that was enough nice Oh
what else do you want you want more
paper don't you do we have any more
paper around I didn't plan this out oh
we got books no all right we're just
gonna spend a hard-earned emeralds waste
them on this guy just to unlock the
trades yeah we'll buy a book bookcase
okay what we're doing it's give us the
trades oh it works nice okay
glass yeah I'll take that just do three
just just to do it okay is that enough
no you want more more my money oh we had
the glass there okay there we go
so there should be our first or our
second book enchantment there's three
total you can always get yeah okay what
is it what is its efficiency three and a
blast protection darn it okay you're a
dud but we tried let's see let's tell
you what guys let's head over here now I
did a few things off camera here Oh
go come on give me a baby librarian the
most exciting thing about this village
for me is whenever we get a librarian
nope didn't work okay yeah we're going
to head up to the brewing station now
so yeah they they changed it so you need
blaze powder in these brewing stand so I
filled all of these it took like a
double chest of blaze rods it took so
much blaze it was a blazin um okay so
now I'm going to turn it on for the
first time and just double-check
everything still working here okay okay
that's not good
put more bottles in are we out of
bottles we might be out of bottles I
hope so
no I think we have lots of bottles oh
yes there's there's more bottles than
you could ever dream of uh oh it just
took a little while I think it went
double check now yeah it's going it's
going okay so I thought it was gonna
take one blaze powder every single time
you do a brewing but it turns out this
this fuel bar here it ticks down pretty
slow you do a bunch bunch of brews off a
single blaze powder alright good so
that's good now let's try turn on the
main thing here and just double-check
that the actual potion brewing is
working that's just for making the
awkward potions there okay and if you
don't know how this all works I built
this a little while ago and it basically
it chains them down the brewing stands
here and they end up in all these chests
one step it advances every time it goes
through the brewing yeah here we go yeah
so I don't think ya get anything got
broken actually that's good yeah it
looks great
all right I come to you out of
desperation I've looked around my entire
base
not a single dip Strider book to be
found I've used them all up
and I haven't gotten one by enchanting
in a long time so we need to buy four of
them sixteen emeralds each and now we
have to combine them you better give me
that XP I want something out of this I
thought we had a dip Strider three
librarian here but I just not I must
have left them at the village and he
died or something cuz he's not there
anymore I checked alright now we combine
and combine and we get them Strider
again I can't afford it we will get it
though okay everybody so do you know
where we are right now huh
any ideas we're on earth
fools duh no we are at the witch farm
future which farm project if you you
probably need that base pot based on the
episode title actually now that I think
of it but yeah we we came here a couple
months ago now and started clearing some
of the land and that's about all we did
put down some markers and stuff and
today we're actually going to tackle the
project start building it and all that
kind of fun stuff so right here is where
the witch hut is all right and now we
got to start converting it's the the big
thing above us here is going to be our
Sun blocker so I got to fill in all
those spaces and then it should be
perfectly dark here so it extends out 15
blocks from the spawning area all around
blocks out all the lights
yeah we're going to start clearing this
out start laying down our floor and
stuff this is gonna be really fun though
for me because I've never built a witch
farm is there anything in here actually
not really there's a cauldron cauldron
graphical table and I think like a
flower pot or something yeah I've never
done this before so it's going to be fun
and recently they made the change where
you can't glitch mobs through the floor
anymore so a lot of the standard designs
aren't aren't really applicable and that
was a voicecrack applicable anymore so I
sort of have free rein to do whatever I
want here without being tempted to go
the standard method you know so I've had
a couple ideas with this I think it's
going to be pretty cool all right
especially since we're building it out
of ice you know it doesn't get get much
cooler than that oops so it is a seven
by nine area and there's three layers
and you start it at the the foot of the
witch huts is the way it works so I'm
going to fill these in then I'm going to
fill in our Sun shield here and we'll
climb up the ladder and just see if we
can get any spawns here
I haven't lit any of the caves and that
we haven't finished clearing the land
but I think during the day we can
actually get witnesses spawn here and we
are just about done with the Sun shield
now I just built it out of grass because
I'm going to move it proudly
so I'm going to tear this all down and
rebuild it officially once I figure out
what height I want it and what design
we're going with but yeah this is this
is all kind of figure it out as we go so
far know mom's okay I didn't think there
would be because we haven't left that
area as we get a little farther away
chances of us getting a witch to spawn
they're pretty low I don't think it'll
actually happen and I'm assuming they
spawn on packed ice I'm that's right
right oh it better be right or this is
gonna be a big disaster I recall that
they do though there's so many facts to
this game I often forgets so many of
them that I that I know at some point
and then it just gets pushed out of my
head by another one or two facts that
come out okay but let's look at our our
II so near the top left there easy Roe /
ish we want to climb up until that gets
to like zero so I made sure to build
this pretty tall once we get up to about
192 I don't think we'll have any mobs at
start decrease now we're going down 60s
50s 40s 30s 20s Oh actually there's
going to be passive mobs so it's not
going to hit zero now that I think of it
and squid and stuff okay but at this
point I think everything in the caves
has D spawned we're probably too far
away for any witches to spawn there as
well though so let's climb down a little
bit I don't know the exact height we
want to be and we're going to have to do
this until I light up all the caves this
is this like a temporary thing okay
let's slowly go down until that number
starts to increase and then we're going
to jump down and just see if we got any
witches yeah it's starting to go up now
so we'll go here did we get any please
please please oh yes oh wow we got we
got six or so that's somewhat of a
result okay that's good that means I'm
comfortable moving ahead with our design
all right it's very good so now we know
for sure that they're going to spawn on
packed ice here and in this area now we
can move on to the next step so we need
some way of clearing them off of our our
spawning platform here the current best
method is probably to use water streams
now that they fix the glitching them
through the blocks method I'm not
exactly sure though but I want to try
something crazy something wacky if you
were hoping for a high-efficiency which
farm I am sorry to let you down because
that is not what we're doing here I've
made a lot of mob systems in this game I
like to make them a little bit different
from each other every time though just
so it's a different experience for me
different challenges and stuff and in my
world I have so many arrows I don't know
what to do with them I keep saving them
I can't stand to just throw stuff away
but I thought you know what let's make
the witch farm
shoot arrows at the witches the clearing
off the platform and I did a little
testing creative it takes between one
and three arrows to clear a witch off of
here like if the witch spawns like right
here I think it takes three to shoot
them off the end if they spawn like at
the end here though that's that's only
gonna take one right and we're going to
be using spectral arrows as well so when
when the dispenser hits the witch we're
going to be able to see through all the
blocks and stuff we place here clearly
every time there which spawns which i
think is going to be really cool and
just to double check just to make sure
it's going to do a button it seemed like
it went to the end of the platform when
I did it yeah even at the bottom layer
here ideally for mob firms oh I don't
think you want to put the anything at
the bottom layer here like at this
height here that reduces the spawning
rates but we can't really help it with
these dispensers we need we need to put
them down here because I'm going to do
tripwires to detect whenever a witch
spawns that way we're not wasting arrows
needlessly just if like a witch spawns
in this tripwire then we want this to
repeatedly shoot until they're out of it
is the plan so going to do tripwires I
guess we can't wait a second I have not
thought this out very much so we're
about to have some trouble but maybe we
would do the tripwire here we need at
least one block wide for them to fall
down here yeah maybe we'll do one there
and the other one I want a little ways
away from this dispenser oh no I forgot
you can't you can't put the dispenser
here because then the tripwire doesn't
connect ah that's gonna be a problem
yeah that's gonna change things a lot
here actually uh but we're still going
to try to do it still going to go for
the arrow idea problem is we can't be as
precise with our mob detection so
instead we're just going to detect the
whole platform here
so if there's a witch on here anywhere
then all these dispensaries are going to
fire at once downside of that is it's
more wasteful the upside is it's going
to be a lot easier to build this and as
well it's probably going to work a
little bit better too because if there's
a PAC spawn on the platform here it'll
be able to take them all outs you know
pretty quickly or if they're moving if
they like dodge out of the way of one of
the arrows that that was meant for them
then one of the other ones is going to
hit them so it's a trade-off but I think
we'll do it because we don't have a
choice we can't just put the trip wires
on the dispensers either because that
locks them we can only shoot one arrow
and if it takes three to get them off
here then we have a problem all right
okay so yeah I'm going to fill this up
with tripwire let's get out of here
though I'll do that off camera then on
one side here we'll have wire running
all along the trip wires they also can
potentially fall off the side here now
too if they like bump into each other
they might fall off the side which we'll
have to account for unless I put blocks
lower down but that that'll block the
spawns a little bit ah lots of lots of
choices with designing this what we're
going to do though see trying to be
careful not to block any spawn spawn
points I'm gonna put a tripwire actually
no we need a repeater first repeater
we're going to do a comparator clock
like this so and then that's thinking
thinking right now how do we want this
to go so that'll that'll send out the
signal I guess so we want to go back
then I need a repeater though too before
we go into this if we do it like this I
think that'll still activate all of them
right we'll try that out okay so if any
any of these are triggered I'll just try
push a button to mimic it yeah that'll
work
we want to slows down though for sure
otherwise we're going to waste arrows
well I tell you what guys I want to try
to do a test here and just see how this
works as it is right now this is what I
did so we have the redstone wire goes to
a block then to the repeater comparator
clock this has to travel three blocks
before it can go to the repeater
otherwise the repeater gets locked on
and then we have a delay on that it will
stall the dispensers and then to
actually get the arrows circulated
through the whole system we're going to
have hoppers doing that too so let's go
into the dispensers then we'll probably
have you know more hoppers above going
sideways and as long as these are filled
up there's always going to be hoppers of
it not hoppers arrows in the system
uh-huh and we'll just have to drop them
off into HS somewhere basically all
right so let's do a little test here
that will do 32 arrows in each of these
just going to manually put them in this
time maybe I didn't bring a lot of
spectral arrows with me on this trip so
I will only have 32 we'll just put them
in one if we're lucky we'll we'll get a
guy to spawn in the middle and we'll be
able to see it okay this is what it
looks like right now inside oh and I
didn't did I remove the torch I don't
know if I did know I didn't we
definitely got to do that too all right
they're nice and dark I'm going to climb
up the tower and see if anything happens
yeah I see the arrows on the ground
there okay I'm gonna hop down I see a
lot of arrows oh my goodness wire oh no
an arrow got stuck in the top and it
stuck the tripwire oh that's terrible
as a huge flaw
this is why we want a depth Strider by
the way I've I've used it a lot oh we
got which spawn all right I got hit by a
spectral arrow why is it why is it still
going though oh come on there's no
arrows anywhere in there guys
why is the tripwire still activated
I tried lowering the droppers by the way
did you see where an arrow is stucked I
didn't I'm gonna have to watch that back
oh right right oh right okay I know what
it is it's because every time the
dispenser shoot an arrow that arrow
flies through the tripwires so what I
need to do is change the redstone so it
waits until the arrows are outside the
tripwire before it tries to detect for
another mob yes that's what I'll do
all right I look at this now and I'm
ashamed guys I'm ashamed of my redstone
yeah the thing about the comparator
clock method I had here it's simple to
do but we have one two three four five
six delay before it fires the first
arrow and with mob systems you want to
get the guys out of there as fast as
possible
if you're going for efficiency which I'm
not really not but you know if I can get
it I'm going to try to get it so the new
method is going to be something like
this I do believe it's just the very
basic clock don't ask me why but I have
a lot of trouble figuring this out I
ripped out the comparator clock though
the the tricky parts that kind of
confuse me is I needed to invert it
before going to the clock and the very
important thing about this it
deactivates this redstone torch and then
it deactivate or it reactivates this one
so that's only to delay compared to the
six delay we had before so it's still a
little bit delay but it's a little bit
faster and it now checks as well or it
gives enough time for the arrow to get
through which is important that's the
main reason we did this
so yeah we can set the delay over here I
don't know what that's going to be yet
we'll have to do a test so let me just
throw in some arrows and we'll just give
it a quick activation like a mob spawned
why didn't that shoot
oh I digestion I don't know where the
arrows might they're not going in there
though what oh come on don't give me so
much trouble I can't click because the
stupid trip wires in my face so I have
to go down lower those should be in here
they are in there why why just why I
don't know let me let me double-check
this what am I doing wrong this is
getting powered right oh I fall again
yeah it's getting powered okay so
there's arrows in there and it's getting
powered I'm so confused
is this an ice thing Oh what was that
skewer that there is arrows in here
right yes dispensers can be weird
sometimes it's because it's being
powered diagonally isn't it here let's
try the one down something goofy is
going on here if we put arrows in here
I'll bet you'll go yeah okay let's
unpowered this now I don't know we got
to give it one quick pulse
it's shot twice that's bad news let's
add a little bit more delay still shot
twice or is the one next to it shooting
now okay so rather than trying to figure
out how to recontact all the Redstone
and redo it I just threw in a repeater
here does the trick now now we've got to
find a delay where it doesn't do this
yeah getting stuck in a clock if we add
more delay it should stop yeah let's try
active it again it's good yeah so it's
giving the arrow enough time to clear
the tripwires before it tries to go
again
so it'll only keep going if there's a
mob in here now instead of just arrows
let's pretend I'm a witch once I get
knocked off at you stop oh I was short
oh I just if I'm at the very edge it has
a chance is not making it all the way
but yeah it shut off on its own this
time that's good that's what we wanted
okay okay here we go
yeah they got knocked off all that was
sweet that was like two three shots and
and both of them got knocked off one of
them got hit by a spectral area arrow
yeah I think this is going to work out
okay so we've got to copy that to the
other two floors and then set up some
better containment stuff and then next
up we'll come to killing chamber and
then all the fancy other stuff but I
think we got a good start to this anyway
today but yeah anyways guys it's about
time to call it again for today let me
know what you thought about today's
episode by the way I tried to do it a
little bit more of our old classic style
where I show you more of the behind the
scenes and the design process the fails
lots of fails a little bit more of what
actually goes into recording an episode
the downside is we don't get as much
stuff done though so I don't know if
you'd like that or not maybe maybe like
this once in a while I don't know see
what you guys say I just punched the
villagers I'm seeing if he's still mad
at me seems to be fine because they were
stuck in this fence they were never
gonna get together you know unless I
moved in oh did they make a baby oh they
did yeah I punched them out of the
fences here now that now we got a baby
from it yes
score okay anyways here is the comment I
picked up for today it says nice work
Ethel I have to ask have you ever found
yourself talking to the computer when
you are not recording just while playing
a game for your own entertainment did
does he say when I'm alone
he doesn't say when I'm alone does he
have you ever found yourself Teknik beer
when you are not I'm playing a game for
you yeah if there's other people around
I will often comment eight while playing
a game for sure in fact that's one of
the big reasons I got into doing YouTube
um I used to make my friends laugh a lot
when I when we played games together
because I would really get into it and
throw my controllers on the floor and
all that kind of stuff I'm very
passionate about video games anyways as
far as like talking to myself or
something like that I don't usually do
that sort of thing unless maybe if I've
gone all day without talking to anybody
I'll think out loud a little bit or
something just because I haven't used my
vocal chords all day but generally
speaking I usually don't talk to myself
but I do talk to other people in playing
games for sure uh-huh
anyways I hope you guys enjoyed our
episode here and I will hopefully get
that which firm finished up next time
okay and I'll see you until then take
care bye bye