hey how's it going everybody
this is ESO welcome back guys to another
another episode I'm glad that I did it I
can't believe I was actually able to do
that back for another episode today we
are in the nether here I'm trying to
continue improving things in my nether
because as we saw there's quite the mess
to work out I want to continue that
elevator we started all the way up to 2
there if I can but we have bedrock in
the way so the minecarts
stopped over there and I want them to
continue straight up but we got this
bedrock there's probably a couple more
pieces in there there might be like five
pieces of bedrock solid there I don't
know it so I'm going to try remove them
using the dark oak tree trick which
apparently is still in the game which is
awesome I was worried they might have
fixed it and I want to be able to do
this because I would like like it's an
OCD thing I I want I want to go up right
here I don't want to go up here I want
it to be centered and continue so
hopefully this turns out if you've ever
tried this for yourself it can take a
really long time you have to get lucky
with it and it just takes so many
saplings to you'll go through tons and
tons of saplings ouch so I'm I'm like
doing a dark oak sapling farm and
chopping down wood to as I do this
starting to fill up a chest so this tree
that is grew should have removed some of
the bedrock at least let's check it and
there goes a piece there and eventually
if you do it enough times it will take
out more and more pieces and you
further and further down yeah we
actually took quite a few pieces so
that's good
but anyway this is going to be a long
drug a long long thing to do a long
thing to do there's a better way of
putting that long progress no anyway I'm
going to I'm going to do it off camera
is what I'm getting it so I'll be I'll
be back and hopefully it works I've been
here for a while quite a while but I
think I'm getting really close this this
is one last piece that's giving me a lot
of trouble from what I can tell if you
want to wreck a blot you got to put the
tree next to it like to get rid of this
one I wouldn't really want the dirt over
top it I want it like one block away
from the dirt so we might get it this
time if it'll Griff this will grow it's
not going to grow darn it
that's the other thing you have to get
rid of all the bedrock around it that
prevents it from growing so I think it's
not liking these blocks so it's like a
real puzzle you got to you got to work
your way down like get rid of these
upper blocks first and then you can get
the lower ones oh man
there's the sound hmm
wonder if it'll grow if I move it over
one so should still target that block
whoa
darn it
all right let's try it out I'm not sure
if this will actually grow but if it
does oh it did grow okay so I think we
can get it if we keep growing it in that
spot we might have got it even I think
we got it yes we did
oh yeah clear sight all the way to the
sky now that took that took a while but
it's fine it looks good I'll appreciate
it later I'm sure
and while doing this I was able to
collect lots of wood which I'll use in
the future - aha
look what we have here we got an
endermite eye I forgot about these guys
I am in the hope he's chasing me I am in
the 14 w 11 B snapshot I was just doing
a supply run for for building an
elevator and I i teleported in there and
this guy appeared because I used an
enderpearl
which happens on a low percent chance so
maybe let's just check this out for a
sec I'm wondering how much damage he
does take off my armor at 10 hearts one
and a half one and a half one and a half
okay so they're pretty powerful I'm
wondering at Mojang you're gonna still
add like a unique ability to these guys
because they're I think they might be in
development still which would be cool
but I'm not sure like what would they do
would they like if they hit you maybe
they would make you teleports randomly
nearby I don't know what they could do
what you just disappeared
what they don't go in grass dude I
wanted to see if they would enter stone
I didn't I didn't play around with the
new snapshot yet so I just updated
I saw a few videos on these guys but I
haven't checked them out for myself yet
yeah you just disappeared guys maybe
maybe later we'll head over to the end
and just experiment a little bit more
with them but we are back in the nether
for right now everyone because I have
just finished the elevator so let's give
it a try here it takes us from y 64 all
the way up to about 240 so it's it's a
pretty pretty tall elevator
you just hold right click and you you go
up pretty quick and that kind of rhymes
it slows down as I get towards the top
because zombie pigmen are causing my
game to like when they're entering the
portals but it's it's very quick I like
its notice how much like I got there
it's like you hit the button in 3
seconds later 4 seconds later finally
does something so this should hopefully
drop me down here I have this such a
really quick time at the moment yep cool
so when I'm up there for a certain
amount of time I'll get knocked back
down and I'll be knocked down to an area
where zombie pigman will stop spawning
so that they don't get out of control
going through the portals I'm just
pretty cool and pretty much anywhere I
want I can get out too
it's dangerous to do that though in
certain spots I died several times
building this from falling like this but
overall it's pretty good sometimes I can
catch the corner of the minecart if I if
I get out as I'm falling down but it's
it's tough to do for sure
but anyway that's our elevator ooh
oh I don't find you down because every
time I get out it's gonna try a jecht me
here oh you know what I made a made way
down here that's right um I was thinking
about mob abilities like what the
endermite could possibly do or future
mobs and this might be really really
annoying but what if there was a mob in
this game that knocked out your items
like it it knocks on it like stole items
from your inventory like if you were if
you had a sword in your hand and they
hit you maybe he has a chance of
stealing your sword and then if there's
like zombies chasing you too maybe
they'll pick them up pick your sword up
and then you're totally without a weapon
that would be a pretty powerful mob
might be really annoying though that's
an idea there's a lot of games that that
have enemies kind of like that it might
be interesting in Minecraft so another
big change in 14w 11b they are redoing
minecart physics quite a bit and they
did some awesome stuff with this I
wonder if it still works it does so they
go really fast now I think although I
might not have enough power rails
I'm going really slow I don't think I've
enough power is I think it is slowly
picking up speed
but minecarts eagle a lot lot faster now
which dad you talk about pretty quick
right now actually I don't think I'm
going to back speed even so that is
really cool I'm glad no come back I'm
glad that happened before I got around
to totally redoing my mother track and
everything here because I was
considering using horses but if mine
carts are actually quicker than horses
they're actually feasible again to use
one thing I would like to do is extend
this track out here because currently
the track doesn't really work I'm
missing power rails and also this needs
to go quite a ways and this will take me
to my wither farm if I can set this up
because right now I have to walk there
every time and it's pretty far so I
might go and do that right now and I'll
put down lots of our rails hopefully and
get going full speed and try that out
okay oh snap I think I got them going to
the wrong portal right now they're all
out in the open and I can't help myself
I can't resist we're gonna do it guys he
was gonna be the unlucky Pigman
this is such a bad idea
oh I missed there we go oh oh
oh so it turns out
zombie pigman trotty is a little bit
laggy and now that I got hundreds of
them tracking me the team has freaked
out and I really hope they can't get up
here otherwise I'm probably already dead
I was gonna run and have them chase me I
don't know if that's really a good idea
now I'm probably dead as soon as I
stepped down maybe I'll try it or or
they're just really slow we'll find out
not slow did you see how fast that guy's
running oh darn it it's fine though all
despawn as I approach here but still I
gotta get my gear back if any of them
picked it up alright so where was that
must be a bit further down I realized
now I had at least half a stack of iron
blocks on me I think which I'll be very
sad if it's gone
most other things I don't mind losing
but iron blocks
was it not here oh no I thought it was
right around here I'm gonna pause and
check the video again because I am NOT
gonna lose that now it was a little bit
further that was the tree I was on oh
he's got my sword
oh there's a few of them around
friendly you friendly guy I'm surprised
these friendly I'm surprised there's
actually more than one of them here cuz
I I'm sure it was over 144 blocks away
so they should instantly de-spawn as
soon as I arrived oh he's got my boots
that's why does this guy have something
in mind then - you might have got a
sword or something off of me all right
such nice zombie pigman aren't they they
they shared my gear between themselves
one guy didn't just take it all so
thoughtful bunch of nice friendly jerks
alright we got it and boots where did
that there there okay I'm all
disoriented oh it wasn't half a stack I
only had 22 block blocks of iron I guess
alright what does this guy have why is
he still around
oh there's my bow mm-hmm if there's
anything else I missed anyway so I'm
gonna head back to the nether and do
some things Pete be right back
ah my gold files getting pretty small
here guys I think I'm gonna blind it all
out actually because I replaced part of
my beacon with some of this that's where
those iron blocks came from but also
we're going to be making that time and
power rails for the track because I
would rather use gold for that than the
iron on the tracks so it's gone a lot of
people actually said they liked the coal
so I don't know if I should change this
out to cool or what I think it's gonna
be too dark those the thing I don't know
I don't know what to do about this room
now I do like the bridge the bridges and
stuff I got going around I'm not sure if
that would really work with the coal
but anyway huh I ran out of power rails
I wasn't expecting that so I got most of
the way to the wither skeleton farm but
not quite all the way we need at least
400 more which is quite a bit actually
let's go for a ride it is definitely a
lot faster like you don't really notice
it too too much here we're picking up a
bit of speed torches are whizzing by
there's no power rails where I'm at
right now so we're just kind of coasting
but we're here we reach them and then
whew so much faster we are flying so
cool but there's this thing where you
derail if you're going too quick around
a corner I haven't decided the way I
want to deal with that just yet there's
a few tricks too to it some people have
been putting like unpowered power rails
unpowered power rails yeah before I
returned and that slows you down really
quick is one way of doing it I found
though that if you I don't know if this
is going to be possible but like if
you're you on this way and you hit one
of these kind of sections a slanted
track you instantly go around you don't
lose any speed and it stays on the track
so if I could come up with a way of
doing that going both ways because going
this way I'll just I'll derail it but if
I go this way that works if I can find a
way of doing it for for both directions
it will be perfect yeah let's keep going
here
such a great change like horses as they
were I think they were about right like
it didn't make sense for horses to be
faster than mine carts because mine
carts you gotta go through all this
extra work of laying down a track and
collecting tons and materials for it but
that's just a little bit further down
that way but to mine mine carts were
slower than horses horses they felt like
they were a good speed though I think
they did a good job at 50 how quick
horses were they're a lot of fun to ride
the way they are
and I wouldn't want them to be slower
but the only way of really dealing with
that was to make mine carts faster I
think that was the right choice I know
this was like talked about a long time
ago not like when even when notch was
working on the game people were asking
for faster mine carts and oh dang guy
you wrecked my ride oh no no no run away
Mike hurt there we go I think not said
though that things couldn't go any
quicker because chunks couldn't keep up
with loading on that at the time anyway
there's all obviously been improvements
and optimizations in the game so it
seems like it's possible now like I
didn't have too much trouble with chunks
loading even while recording here things
are a lot slower and it was able to keep
up so that's good when I'm not recording
it's super smooth so I I'm definitely
like in the hooker travel time
so guys I have a little building project
in mind for my nether here for my track
because my mother is a bit dull it needs
more character and the other day I was
browsing minecraft screenshots that I
think I was looking for building
inspiration or something I can't
remember what I was doing but I stumbled
across this one screenshot of a really
really cool thing and I want to copy it
into my world here just because I liked
it so much so this is not my design I'm
copying this from something someone else
did but I think it'll fit nicely my
nether so I'm going to build it right
here and I may as well just skip ahead
and show you guys what it is so here we
go alright everybody we're gonna go
check it out I got it built it's nothing
too fancy but I did use a last my gold
on it so I'm gonna take more gold soon
I am a big castle crashers fan by the
way that's kind of why I wanted to do
this it's the the weapons room you know
the Frog from Castle Crashers
I saw the screenshot the other day
someone built this and I just had to
have it my world dear so it kind of
suits the nether because the nether rack
looks like the inside of his mouth and I
don't have to make a few adjustments to
it though the screen shot I saw he was
made out of wool which wouldn't really
work out too well in the nether the gold
blocks in that are are vulnerable to gas
shots but he should hold up okay I think
uh-huh so that is what I did I'm
considering putting like a shoe
shoopdawhoop or whatever it is over
there to or some other kind of
crazy-looking thing that you go into the
mountain I don't know anyway so we got
we got this guy done and that's probably
going to be about it for today so let's
go do the common thing so I saw this
question and I thought it was a pretty
good one it says hey etho what new
redstone mechanic would you most like to
see in a future update of Minecraft
personally I would like to see
dispensers break blocks if they have a
tool in them that would be pretty cool I
really did like the the breaker and
deployer features of red power that the
red power mod and there's a lot of mods
that do similar thing I think that would
be a good a good thing to add but I
think for me I would like to see
something similar to the drawbridge from
thinker's construct that is a really
cool mechanic because for a long time
like Pistons are really neat but they
can only move one block around at a time
and there's sort of a limit to how how
far out they can go like you can do 2 or
3 blocks and the device becomes really
large but is
possible but it takes forever and it's
not really practical so a drawbridge
sort of breaks breaks those limitations
and from what I saw it seems like it was
implemented in a way that's not really
too ladylike there's other mods I've
seen that pistons can push like a block
16 blocks instead of just one and those
look a lot more prone prone to bugs and
other problems but that the drawbridge
looked really cool and I would like to
see that I think that would be neat so
that's going to be it for today guys it
looks like that chicken farm has a ways
to go before it's ready for the target
game but I hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode I will see you again in the next
one take care have yourselves a great
day bye bye