[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of the
let's play series hope you're having
yourselves a wonderful day today I am
eating the microphone I hope you're
enjoying it hello hello everybody this
is etho and welcome back guys to another
episode of let's play series what you
got guy mmm-hmm
three black four one that's not bad
I still haven't bought anything from
these guys like it's just so much
cheaper to get it in nature rights like
you did he mostly just sells flowers I
thought I'd show you guys this so to
start off with we worked on this very
briefly last time basically we're trying
to do this biome enhancement thing in
our world where we fill up all these
plain empty spaces we have like we got
that all these empty planes here
it's nothing exciting right it's very
standard we're trying to transform them
into something unique that stands out so
this is just one idea I tried out which
I think turned out pretty good like all
we did is we put a path in here I've
lined the sides with leaves and these
are not custom acacia trees these are
just regular ones but like you never see
a forest of acacia trees right they're
just scattered and savanna naturally so
by putting them together like this it
kind of is a unique thing just on its
own and what I did is I planted them two
blocks up so they're a lot taller than
normal and then I replaced the dirt
block with logs and overall this is this
is the final effects we could decorate
this more even but just after like maybe
10 minutes of working on this it it
feels pretty good right that was I
thought that was kind of cool like the
big problem is if you're doing this
biome enhancement thing is it takes a
long time a really long time to fill up
space so that was like a nice quick
thing that turned out pretty good I felt
anyways let's go over here we have this
lake thing here which I wanted to
decorate a little bit I saw a really
cool post on the Minecraft reddit a
while ago and if you guys didn't see it
like this is a neat idea which you might
use yourselves someone had the idea of
using glass panes and then you put sea
pickles on top and it kind of looks like
a cat tail right it would be nice if
they were a bit more Brown the sea
pickles but I think the effect kind of
works I think it's a cool trick I'll
probably scatter a few of those in here
to decorate it a bit more
uh-huh so as you guys can probably tell
I am playing around with the audio
settings a lot this episode again thank
you by the way very much for all the
feedback on the last one for helping me
with my my issues and also for being so
understanding about the less than
desirable quality of the episode again I
wish I could tell you like I read
everything you said and everything's
perfect now but I'm still really messing
around with it trying to get it perfect
I have solved a lot of the problems
based on what you guys said mostly the
static and chirping I believe is gone
and the echoing effect
I hope let me know if I'm wrong about
that but now the big the big question is
should I use an equalizer or not in the
episode so I started off eating the
microphone with no equalizer on then
that little intro I did was with the
equalizer with a lot of the bass removed
from audio and now probably for the rest
of episode here I'll be talking like
this with no equalizer just the raw my
raw voice again like we did in the
previous episode I'm about two inches
from the microphone which i think is
about the the right distance it sounds
kind of kind of cool and I'm really
close to it but it's like yeah you get a
lot of that pot sounds you know which
isn't very good anyways let's get to the
episode here I'm gonna talk about stuff
we're doing here so I did work on the
lake here I lined the borders of the
lake with coarse dirt I think it looks
kind of cool we got some cattails
planted a few random plants and stuff
like dead shrubs you can plant bamboo
and like keep it as a decorative thing
if you put string over top of it it
won't grow so that's kind of a cool
trick and this area really reminded me
of the area behind my etho Corp on the
minecraft server so I've I rebuilt my
first custom tree I did the little lake
monster which i think is kind of cool I
like that little guy I think this is a
slightly different version I couldn't
quite remember how to do it I don't
think the other one had arms this one
has arms but anyways guys we are going
to
get started on a pretty big project here
today I was just collecting some
resources together for it and is like
okay I gotta go get some hardened clay
but then there's like wait a minute
we got all these Brown mushroom blocks
still we were using them as fuel before
for our super smelter but now it's like
what do we what do we do with these so
maybe I'll use these or try them out
today instead of using hardened clay or
our main building material cuz these
don't look that bad right like this is
the texture now it's acceptable and like
we have so many already cool cool all
right so we have made our way out here
we've taken a long journey back to this
illa dirt fortress and it is it's a
nasty place it's really bad
so our goal today is to try to make like
a a mob firm out of these guys
basically it it'll spawn in these
bannerman every so often and whenever we
kill them we get the bad omen effect and
it stacks like I think it goes up to six
if I remember correctly so then when we
enter a village it'll spawn in a raid
and we'll get different guys like the
guys with the axes and the witches and
Volkers and we can farm them for
different materials like emeralds and
stuff but also when we beat the raid the
villagers if we set up some villagers
nearby they will give us gifts so we can
get quite a few resources from this we
can get experience from it overall it's
a potentially a pretty good mob farm I
have not really seen how anyone's built
one of these like I've seen creative
versions but I haven't seen like how do
people go about surviving and survival
because I was thinking about is like
it's gonna keep shooting me if I kill
them they'll just respawn right they
spawn in a pretty big area around this
fortress I think maybe our first order
of business here is going to be setting
up a beacon
oh no they found me that was Gary that
block oh they're still getting down
resistance too
and we want strength and regen maybe ah
you know what it's actually not too bad
now while I was setting up the beacon I
think a lot of them wandered like
halfway down the cliff and they're not
really spotting up here anymore this is
the odd one so that's cool that a little
allow us to work in peace here so the
plan is oh hello guy hey we got the
regen in the strings and stuff so if
they do spawn we can deal with them a
lot easier now but the plan is we're
gonna put a villager in the center of
this tower probably like around here
protected so that they can't kill them
and then but they're attracted to it
like they'll try walk up good to kill it
so we're gonna then drop them down a
hole and then all we got to do is build
a platform so where is the center here
probably right here right I'm going to
assume so we'll probably go one two
three or I fall down uh yeah maybe we'll
try 16 blocks out to begin with like
from the center here sixteen blocks out
all around do like a circle we can go up
to 35 blocks out from the center point
though but if we want but if we go like
all the way to 35 it's gonna take the
guys a long time to walk up to the
villager here and fall down
right so we don't want them to have a
long transport time oh that's really
hard oh snap okay hope they can get up
here I don't think again earlier they
would have already yeah so we'll fill in
mushroom blocks but my plan is to go
vertically instead of horizontally out
so we'll probably have several layers oh
and you can see they can spawn like when
I'm up here even like right next to me
which is kind of interesting one thing I
did test out that I thought was a little
odd or a little different like when
Guardian farms came out if you had an
old world and you went to the location
where they should have spawned in your
worlds there would be no temple or
anything they're like no structure but
if you place water down they would be
able to spawn in that water but with
these outposts I went to a location in
my world here where one should have
spawned and like nothing that things
spawn there like it never created the
zone where they can spawn in and there's
no structure there either so we have to
go really far out in our world to find a
spot like this where they will actually
spawn in there's none close to our base
that we can use and with our build here
I don't have any super detailed plans or
anything like that we're kind of just
winging it as we go here so we'll do a
couple tests as we're building this to
figure out how we need to change it so
we're gonna go away here and come back
and just get an idea of how quickly they
will spawn on that platform and how many
spawn and then we'll know if we need to
increase the spawning space like maybe
go 20 or 24 blocks on the circle and
also like you how many layers we
probably need to do if we come back you
can see there's a bunch of them not on
the platform it's one there one there
one there so if it was a bigger platform
they would have spawned on it got one
guy in the middle I can see guy up there
couple guys up there actually
uh-huh overall I think only one maybe
two spawned on it actually so that's not
very good that's actually a lot worse
than I expected I thought we'd get maybe
five or something like that let's try it
again coulda got unlucky that time go
away and come back should let them
despawn and respawn here all right all
right it'll be better once we remove all
this land that they're not supposed to
spawn on too
um
[Music]
you
hmm oh we got one alright so yeah we
probably need a lot more space alright
very good very good we've been making
some progress here that's probably an
hour or two later now and you can see
I've started on a second layer I have
expanded this first layer to 20 blocks
radius and I've even been clearing
underneath here so I switched the beacon
over to haste and probably go down at
least another 10 blocks here
okay I'll quickly spawn down here though
it's crazy so I discovered something
here that made me very sad I thought one
of the biggest problems in this game for
the long shot here should it's very
annoying annoying working in my way I'm
constantly getting shot people try go
get some visibility potions we got to
refuel on food we're out a mushroom
block so our tools are about the current
stuff so we gotta head back for face oh
yeah ghost blocks those blocks
everywhere guys I did that whole ice
farm like cleared all the land for it
without encountering a single ghost
block I thought they fixed it but
they're still in the game I'm so sad
about that do all the arrows bouncing
off of them like it's so bad there's so
many of them I know I've said this
before many times probably but one of
the best tricks that I recommend people
do is always bring several ender chests
with you always have them on you not
only is it very convenient you can
access all your stuff right but if you
ever go out on a exploration adventure
or whatever and you want to get back
it's always nice to be able to just
break them down and have obsidian on
hand so you can make a portal look at
this beautiful didn't have to go mining
for it or anything
and of course you always want to
complete the corners of your portals
don't cheap out alright and there we go
see where this picks us in the nether
another thing I kind of recommend is
like when you build your nether tunnels
if you can go out the four cardinal
directions
and might try to have the tunnels set up
around 0-0 so like when I'm out here
let's see if I can find it so I know we
we got to go this way to get to zero and
I know my nether tunnels are at zero so
if I come out at a random spot in the
nether I can usually find my tunnels
just because they're at zero zero I
think oh we gotta go this way probably
though it should be somewhere around
here I would think I think I have them
at y 64 yeah right over there look at
that beautiful awesome alright guys so
we are back at the main base here and we
have reared two got our tools
re-equipped in and stuff we're gonna
head back after we do a couple harvests
on our brow mushroom farm here so we
plant the brown mushrooms in the holes
and then we go over here I did write
down like the instructions cuz I kind of
forget between harvests always so step
one plant them put them in the whole
step to grow press to grow hit the
button that sends bonemeal to all of
them all around the farm here does
involve popping up haha I'm playing with
my by the way I'm playing with my field
of view a little higher than normal
eighty some of you guys said it was bad
before even though it's like it was that
what I normally play at so I guess we'll
try it out for today but it feels a
little weird to me I don't know
and then step three here we go harvest
one thing that's kind of changed since
we last use this farm is these these
stem blocks are actually collectible now
before they would just turn to brown
mushroom blocks now they have their own
texture which we can use for building
and they're nice that's pretty cool so
we got it all harvested now we need to
collect all the drops together so we
just go back over here hit collect and
that sends water down releases some
minecarts underneath that go and pick up
the drop
in the whole I think I think oh yeah
there they go like where are the
minecarts I don't hear him alright good
stuff I think we got the second layer of
the mushroom done um I wanted to try
something now so we did we did grab some
potions when we were back home
invisibility potions I won't try those
out we also have golden apples and
weakness potions if we can find a zombie
villager cuz we need to get Azzam or a
villager for the middle here and like
the closest village I found is a few
hundred blocks away so it's not gonna be
practical to move them um I think we may
need to take off our armor right this is
like one of those things you can regret
really quickly I'm gonna jump down and
it's gonna pincushion me I know it
alright we're invisible
oh I've actually never seen the icon for
that yet that's kind of cool oh hey guys
how's it going we we buddies can you see
me looks like I'm totally invisible yeah
I can I can clear safely oh that guy
found me okay not not entirely invisible
I think when I selected my pick maybe
hey Sam no he can see me already - okay
get the gear back on that's not gonna
work alright run away run away
oh snap everybody we finally did it here
I have been clearing land for hours you
know I got some videos going in the
background you know it's fine it was
enjoyable but yeah hours and hours of
land clearing here I thought when we
first started this they were gonna spawn
I'm not done you see one guy spawned
here but for the main area we got most
of it done here I thought they were only
gonna spawn maybe 10 or 15 bucks
underneath the outpost but no it goes
way down like 25 maybe 30 blocks
underneath finally at this layer here
the villagers stop spawning and hostile
mobs are spawning so above that hostile
mobs did not spawn at all in the area
and interesting like interestingly like
one layer above this or maybe it was to
both hostile mobs and the pillagers
could spawn together there's like one
layer or two of them where that can
happen otherwise they they spawn
separate from each other
also while building this I had one
pretty big observation I didn't realize
beforehand here but they seem to prefer
spawning in dark areas over light areas
even though they can spawn in the light
areas like if you if you look in here
like they're spawning inside the kind of
looks like an ice cream sandwich I've
got the two layers of the cookie and the
vanilla in between or whatever they seem
to spawn in there a lot faster than they
do on top even though I do see the odd
guy on top every so often so and when
they were spawning down there they
seemed to always spawn closer to the
dark area instead of on the outside so
darkness seems to be important we'll
probably want to close off the walls of
our farm here you guys want to see a
cool trick check this out so with the
scaffolding let's start at 60 here we
can use them to measure vertical height
actually which is really cool
so we started with 60 we have 32 laps
that's 28 blocks up huh it's like a
vertical measuring tape it's awesome
good stuff all right so I think the next
order of business to building our farm
here is we're gonna start slapping maybe
let's go for this stone slabs a little
bit fancier I'm gonna start slapping the
top of his mountain here so we've
cleared out all the land main reason of
that was I was curious how far they
would spawn from the tower but also we
made sure there's no hidden caves inside
the mountain there that they're gonna
spawn and get stuck in or also they were
spawning on the side of the hills all
over the place so now we don't have to
worry about that well what we do kind of
want to stop now is hostile mobs from
spawning here because I think that'll
take up the mob cap and we want to keep
that free for the villagers to spawn oh
yeah very good very good so we got it
all slab doubts on top of the hill there
so no more hostile mobs in that dark
spots or during the nighttime it'll be
completely empty so that's all good we
just got a cut away like part of the
cliff there probably like something like
that to stop them spawning on there
where I see one guy there already but
overall I think we got most of the prep
work ready for this farm and
unfortunately I just checked the time on
episode and that's pretty much all we're
gonna be doing today I guess I've been
at it for a while here but before we
wrap up here I at least want to show you
the idea we're gonna try it with this so
we got to get a villager at the center
here for each layer right the thing I
want to try out which I'm not sure if
it'll work I kind of think it has a good
potential to work it might be cool for a
lot of mob farms is I'm gonna probably
set up trap doors in the center
OOP not there something like actually
for the top one we got to do differently
I think we're gonna do it like this yeah
we'll make them come out like this and
then like that I think is the plan
there will be water like a water column
in the center
so those trapdoors hold it in place this
will we want to keep this open so that
the villagers can see the villager in
the centre here he's gonna be in the
water and we're gonna set bubble streams
so that he'll like float up and down
through the water so that we don't have
to have a villager on every level and
because he's in a bubble stream he won't
suffocate either I'm pretty sure the
thing I'm concerned about though is as
he passes up here there's this brief
opportunity where they can shoot them
and kill them but I think there it takes
like a second at least so I think in
that time they'll see him but he's gone
by the time they react and then what we
got to do probably is like remove some
of the ground here I think if we have a
trap door here and one here they will
walk off there as they try to get them
but we won't know until we can test it
out because I haven't done that yet
like I said we're winging the farm but
hopefully that works I think that'll be
a cool idea and you can use that for
assuming it does work you could use that
for other firms like with wolves and
ocelots like if you're doing in a
hostile mob firm you know that might be
a cool thing like the one we have
underneath my sand pyramid it's got like
over 20 dogs and cats in right that's a
real pain to set up it's nice when it's
all done but like if you could get away
with just using one wolf and one cats or
one villager for this farm it's a lot
easier in survival to build that but
yeah anyways guys I think we're gonna
have to wrap up the episode here for
today and we're gonna do it's talking
about of course audio problems it will
probably keep doing that until I get
them rights but yeah I want to thank you
again for the feedback on the last one I
think we did get a few of the issues
solved thanks to what she told me but
again let me know if you hear static or
audio artifacts or anything weird I
don't think I have the best sense of
that like usually I'm pretty good at
picking up subtle new
bounces or wheel details and things but
when it comes to audio not so much I
find so it's really hard to like figure
out what sounds better and what doesn't
so your feedback is much appreciated I
guess let's get to the calm in the day
here says so the 80/20 35 that's the
microphone I'm using is a condenser XLR
microphone so it's not USB it's a
special audio cable that needs proper
phantom power to power it's an analog
signal you need to hook it up to a USB
audio interface set and supply the
necessary voltage to it so that audio
interface converts it from an art analog
single into a digital one and it
connects the computer with a USB cable
then otherwise it will not work properly
and yeah I have done that I didn't
clarify that on the last episode I have
the focusrite scarlett solo I think
second generation audio interface with
phantom power enabled so that shouldn't
be an issue but even with phantom power
enabled I'm finding a really hard to get
enough gain on the microphone enough
volume I got to pretty much crank to the
maximum on the audio interface
thankfully I was able to get rid of all
the software games I was using which I
think was distorting in the audio a bit
but yeah maybe what we'll do let's hop
over to the equalizer and I'll show you
guys what that how that works
uh-huh yeah so check this out this is
pretty cool this is the equalizer I'm
using and hassun talking here you can
actually see the wave shape of my voice
at the top here you can see the
different categories of the waves so we
got the sub bass on the left then it
goes bass low mid mid eye mid and treble
on the far right that's like the really
high-pitched sounds like s's you see
when I do that it goes mostly into the
treble or also apps while sub bass is
like whenever I do the p's you know
but generally when I'm talking its base
to low/mid not a lot of mid and like
very little high mid so this is what the
equalizer settings I played around with
what I figured sounded the best to me
I'm gonna start turning them on here and
it should affect my voice as I enable
them so right now I've got minus 5 DB on
the sub bass then we turn this one I got
minus 2.8 DB or decibels on the bass and
then if we go to number 3 that'll go
minus 3.5 DB on the low mid so the kind
of yellowish color here at 4 is the mid
that we got that at minus 4 DB and then
for 5 I left at 0 & 6
I set the minus 2 DB that's the the
treble the high-pitched sounds because I
noticed when I was doing s's it kind of
lingered a lot you know they were over
pronounced I think by lowering that it
helps it out so overall I felt this was
the best I could get with the equalizer
it removes a lot of the bass from my my
voice it makes it a lot more punchy but
I'm not sure really if I should change
any more of this I maybe raised the this
step a little bit more oh I don't know
if you guys can see that let's go let's
maybe set this I had it at 5 before you
guys said it sounds like a tin can
microphone so maybe we go up to 2 or
something and then this I don't know I
feel like I feel like I need to change
something though it's not quite right so
maybe if you guys got any feedback on
that let me know and yeah those are the
same settings I used in the intro when
we were around the lake there and at the
acacia trees the first two minutes of
this video so if you like how that
sounded or did you prefer the rest of
the video I don't know
anyways I'll probably end it here for
today hope you guys enjoyed it thank you
for watching have a wonderful day
take care bye bye
[Music]