okay here we go I have a new plan
something I want to build these are tape
spider spawners I found last episode
while exploring the abandoned mineshaft
it's a these are about a hundred blocks
away from that other cave spider system
I set up my new plan I want to make an
enchanting room and a cave spider system
combined into one here this is just so
perfect they're so close together this
is going to work out very well we also
have a ravine right next to us which is
nice lots of space the plan is I keep
saying the plan is the problem with the
last cave spider system is damaging the
mobs it's a little bit tricky I tried
messing around with cacti didn't work
too well haven't messed around with fire
or lava or anything yet just because
it'll be really messy I know but with
this this will work out perfect because
my plan is to I said it again didn't I
the idea is to go down make the spiders
fall about 12 blocks or so downward
because that takes spiders they have six
hearts health so if we drop them how
does it work out basically every block
they fall counts as half a heart of fall
damage so minus three blocks that they
fall at first so if we drop them ten
blocks they would take that's a 10 minus
3 is 7 and then
7/2 is three point five hearts damaged
now a stone sword does two and a half
hearts damage to two mobs so that works
out to six arts total so that should
kill them but I would like to go a
little bit further just to be sure
probably drop them down twelve blocks so
I'll set up like an enchanting room
twelve blocks below the center of these
two so like twelve blocks below here and
there'll be a one-hit kill with the
stone sword it should be nice yeah I
think it'll work out so I need to build
two dark rooms for them up here the
water streams will meet together drop
them down then there will be an
enchanting room nearby and I got some
other plants too we'll see how it goes
I'm going to get started here though
I'll probably skip most of it because
you saw it last time don't want to bore
you too long and it's easier for me to
do it off camera okay here's a little
update for you guys on the project it's
going well you've got the dark rooms
built for both spawners
and they connect these rooms are eight
by eight and four high and that's to
maximize every single possible spawning
location for the spiders so the spiders
spawn as quick as possible so water will
flow from this wall to here and then
from that wall to here then we'll have
water down here hopefully I can get out
good that glitch is still in the game
where you sometimes can't get out if
you're facing a certain direction
okay and that goes to that point here
and then we put water in this one they
meet eight blocks long so no no need for
signs or anything which is always nice
and this as well as eight blocks long so
won't need any signs to hold the water
back and yeah I don't think the water
streams will conflict here should be
fine
and then yeah dig down I'll probably
have a piston shutoff thing to prevent
spiders from falling down if I need to
disable it quickly and I'll probably do
the lighting thing in this one as well
so I'll see you again shortly when I get
more done here so I have to set up a
little bit now I will need to make a few
adjustments of course generally with mob
systems you don't want to have a one
block hole from ops fall down because
usually they'll bump each other around
and they won't want to go down it there
there are tricks to making it work
though one thing I will need to do is
lower these these to one wide streams
one block at least that way when the
spiders bump each other they won't get
bumped out of those streams and fall
damage so far has been pretty
inconsistent sometimes the spiders die
from the fall
sometimes most of the time it's a
one-hit kill like I wanted other times
it's a two-bit kill and sometimes it's a
three-hit tool so it's hard to get it
consistent
and I just have a very rough setup down
here for now so you can see 1 hit 2 1
hit 2 1 hit kill most the time it's good
there's a lot of dead spiders down here
yeah I got a half slab at the bottom
there so it's 1 2 3 and a half blocks
high which allows the spiders to I'm
around in there without taking fall
damage or I hope it does anyway because
mobs take damage if they fall more than
three and a half blocks but anyway yeah
you can see some are dying there um I'll
have to keep adjusting it and hopefully
I'll get it working the way I want it to
so I'll see you again shortly yeah so
the cape spider stuff is going well I
decide to take a little break from it
though I did get up to about level 35
and I enchanted a diamond pickaxe so I
got unbreaking 3 on it and fortune 3 so
that'll be very handy when I go mining
hopefully I'll get some extra redstone
and stuff when I use it I'll definitely
have to start wearing armor though
because I don't trust not having armor
and something that valuable on me
but yet I wanted to start will not start
something but repair something I'm going
to do some work on the mushroom farm
here a lot of people like how small this
thing is it's pretty cool it's fairly
slow though it takes a long time for the
mushrooms to grow
I'm going to try and prove that a little
bit today by making it a little bit
bigger I planted down some mushrooms
here I wanted to see like yeah the way
it works as I've covered already you can
only have five mushrooms within a nine
by nine by three area I think that's
right
but the brown mushrooms and the red
mushrooms are separate so you can have
five brown mushrooms and five red
mushrooms in that nine by nine by three
area no problem so I'm going to I'm
going to put some brown mushrooms next
to our red mushrooms here give them a
little bit more space to UM see how do
we do this break down our glass we'll
have to get in there and some people
have been wondering about the iron tools
how come I got them all enchanted or how
I've been doing it I've just been doing
level one enchantments on all my iron
tools so far and you can't get some
pretty good stuff just doing level one
enchantments it's really cheap you see
this one even got two skills I wasn't
impressed by that I got that fire skill
doing a level one enchantment so it's
not bad really okay so the water should
be here yes I'm going to get rid of that
and their pistons are below here yep
that's our seed mushroom take that out
for now I wanted to say thank you to
Jonathan he donated $100 the other day
so I could buy a new mouse very nice of
you dude thank you I'll fish early get a
new mouse it's a second Mouse I've worn
out playing a Minecraft now and of
course I appreciate everybody's
donations I still get a few
the thinking of maybe just making a room
similar to what goo did in his in his
minecraft server thing with everybody's
name and that who donated just so I can
get everybody's name in a nice compact
room close together and then when that
we get more developed here I'll start
working on the Rube Goldberg machine
again and then everyone can have a
little piece of it is what I'm planning
okay what do I what I want to do here
I'm thinking I have blocks here go back
three spaces the mushroom mushroom will
probably still be here and then I'll put
the water here Oh actually the piston
will go here too just where it was yeah
maybe I'll clean this up where are my
special favorite blocks oops
oh it's fine okay water will go behind
there and then see we'll have a block
above the mushroom here let's just put
the mushroom in again where it was like
that and then we'll just expand more
over here yeah I added it up the other
day - in total like since I started with
that donation thing I've received about
just over $2,000 from everyone about 50
to 60 donors so that's amazing thank you
guys always appreciated okay I'm going
to get rid of that we're going to try
make all the mushrooms come to
the center here and we will have brown
mushrooms here and stone block above
this will be nice they'll have more
space to grow so it'll be more likely to
grow and then we'll have the two kinds
as well so we'll definitely get more
mushrooms this way water will go there
okay and oh yeah we want another piston
over here and yes I just look straight
down because I'm awesome like that um
okay well make these nice I'll probably
go to the nether soon I want to get into
that potion stuff play around with it I
haven't really done that much yet oops
don't know why I did that
okay and then dig down again like we did
before we'll have to move oh that's a
stone block I have to move this over one
and yes this repeater was unnecessary as
many of you pointed out I don't know why
I put it in but I did and getting close
to the cave spiders okay
hmm maybe I'll skip the wiring and we'll
just go over it after all right this is
the wiring here you got wire directly
below the pressure plate in the middle
here
and so basically when you step on it
blocks go down and water gets free this
wire goes to a redstone torch to invert
the signal then branches off to these
two blocks and there are the sticky
pistons directly above so the wire sends
power to the block which powers the
piston above pretty simple got that
there so we can put our water in oh but
before we do that put glass blocks so we
can see our mushrooms and hopefully I
got the water streams right otherwise
I'm going to have to redo a lot of this
but I kind of thought about it before I
started so it should be okay I'm hoping
so we'll stick one that's fine stick one
there and one over here and it looks
okay
yeah very nice so they all go to the
center pressure plate holds the water so
it doesn't pour everywhere that's very
nice cool
very similar to the one we had before
it's just a little bit bigger and it
does both mushrooms now yeah we can I
think that's it just fill us in yeah and
there's a so one two three four five six
seven plus five plus five no plus 4 7
plus 4 11 spots for mushrooms to grow in
here so up to four for each kind will
grow they'll have to fight for these
middle spots but it should work out fine
ok and that is it mushroom farm
new-and-improved still very simple
some people say idea you can stack these
two so maybe well I'll probably not play
around with that but if you want to play
around with it go ahead should be okay
as long as the mushrooms or three blocks
higher than any other ones they'll
continue to grow now what I want to do
is try out that pick with the fortune on
been really excited to see that but
before we can do that I want to make
some armor this is our first set of
armor guys we're going to enchant it
just level one stuff legs and then I'm
going to head down to the caves and
hopefully find some redstone or
something and see what happens yeah
okay level one projectile protection to
level two wow that's cool
come on come on still takes a while and
then to ten ah passed it okay
be back in a second hmm I don't know
guys what do you think it's a pretty
scary pretty terrifying
do I look like I could kick your butt in
my glowing pink and purple armor here
it's pretty manly isn't it terrifying
I think the creepers will be stirred
mm-hmm what about you are you scared are
you scared are you scared of me are you
are you God
what about now haha yeah we got
projectile protection too for the feet
protection one for leggings protection
one for chest plates and respiration one
for the helmets oh yeah
okay how do I get off this view I'm
still using a pre-release four don't
want to use pre-release five just
because of the water bugs and all that
stuff I heard my farm doesn't work
anymore stuff like that will wait
another patch see if things change or
not
okay let's try fortune fortune 3 on this
iron here oh yeah okay nevermind I guess
it doesn't work on iron now that I think
about it we got one coal three coal
that's what I'm that's what I'm talking
about
that's not normal right usually only get
one
that's nice I liked it three oh I love
this pic this is awesome one oh that's a
bad sound figure out there's live out
there yeah I don't know a lot about two
enchantments and stuff yet anyway so
this is all news to me get out of here
yeah and slimes are different in pre
five so that's another disadvantage for
me like all that coal but here's the
real winner I want redstone lots and
lots of redstone what happens we got
five that's pretty normal I think try
again
we got five again I want like just I
want like a whole stack drop out of one
block that would be amazing five again
come on 64 64 5 again mm-hmm
gonna have to play around with this some
more I want more more redstone oops no
no regular blocks was I using my iron
pick did I oh shoot that might have been
I'm gonna have to rewatch that footage
yeah I was using the diamond one huh
strange I only got five see I knew I
saved these for a reason now we can try
it again let's see if we get 5 or more
or less
five come on this is one thing I wanted
to work on the most five yeah it doesn't
seem to for name for that makes me sad
makes me very sad okay we got to go find
some diamond and I want to try it on
lapis pretty sure gold won't work I
think it's the same deal as the iron
because if it worked on the iron and the
gold you could duplicate the blocks
replace some duplicate and replace them
it's only only makes sense it works on
blocks that you can't place back down
but yeah let's go try to find some
diamond or something I think there was
some over here somewhere yeah um there's
something wrong here
something very wrong with this I was
going caving we were at Y 26 and I just
started hearing farm animals above me
there's something weird here there must
they must have fell down a deep hole or
something oh ouch
what is that my farm back yes my farm
why's your chicken in my farm I am so
confused right now okay I guess a
chicken fell down the hole there and our
spiders are up there okay it makes sense
now found some gold but I really don't
think it's going to work on it one one
one one one it doesn't work on gold good
to know though just to be sure I finally
found some lapis here let's try it out
normally you get four to eight from
these okay well I'm pretty sure it works
when one from one block that's amazing
alright whenever I find lapis there's
always only one or two it's pretty sad
found a skeleton spawner let's go check
it out most challenging of all the
spawners not counting cave spiders blaze
and possibly silverfish most challenging
still haven't found any diamonds but
note it like crazy
ah
yeah once you have iron armor on it's
like nothing can hurt you anymore uh
weak very weak sounds like there's a few
more around yeah he just has his little
tiny space all to himself that's awesome
okay well it was time to head back
because I was loaded had a nice run
again here lots of coal mining coal is
actually fun for me again now that I
have this fortune 3 normally it's it's a
real drag I don't like doing it but now
it's fun got lots and lots of lapis do
not find any diamond didn't really find
any redstone on the second trip there
but oh well maybe some other time but
I'm going to call it an end for today
let's go check our mushroom farm nothing
probably grew because we were away most
of time there we got one mushroom anyway
awesome and I can't pick it up because
I'm full of garbage good garbage yes
anyway um we'll probably be doing the
race for the wool again soon so look
forward to that we're having a hard time
scheduling it though because like on
team Jed's I'm in Canada
Jim's in Germany Joker's in the UK and
statics in Australia so that we're all
over the world it's really hard to find
a time where you know it's not 4:00 a.m.
for someone
and everybody's free eight people we
have to schedule but hopefully we get it
going soon well they'll probably be a
few episodes of that if we can do it and
should be fun we'll do better this time
I promise okay I'll see you guys again
another time oh yeah I should probably
mention the other team we're going
against a will be fighting or racing
against team 10,000 meat cakes or meat
cupcakes I'm not sure what it is and
that's a Detroit Michael MC gamer and
Grey Goose should be a fun match