[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back we are home sweet
home here guys again in our let's play
world let's go up to the the nastiness
here
how you doing things are good I thought
to get us going here to begin with we
would spend some more time at our
stronghold base on this crazy bomb
factory project we were working on so we
got that working very well last episode
if I do say so myself but we needed to
build a mob sorter still which is what
we're what I wanted to show you at the
begin with here there was a lot of
confusion about that project basically
our goal we built the bomb factory so we
can remote detonate creepers wherever we
want and ultimately I would like to
build a tree farm where we can remote
detonate the creepers to explode the
wood and then and then harvest it
automatically you know what I mean
that's that was kind of the original
intent with this whole build here and
we'll see if we can pull it off still
but it's kind of just for fun too so
let's talk about this mob sorter thing I
decided to change it we're gonna try do
like a vertical sorter here and we're
gonna separate the mobs by sighs first
off so the smallest mobs maybe zombats
they're gonna fall down like random mobs
down this tube and you can see this
first set of Pistons over here there's a
block there right behind this one right
there we are going to have the mobs
stand on that and you can see this
piston over here it extends and then
this one retracts at the bottom very
quickly and then extends again so this
piston up here is gonna push whatever is
over here against this wall so we want
to push baby zombats which are only one
block tall through here and they'll go
into a water stream over here and then
we can move them wherever we want so
that's like our first little step to
this let's block that up
so they'll be water here I think so the
baby zombies they get pushed that way
and then anything left in that tube is
gonna fall down when this retracts and
extends and they'll fall to this next
set of Pistons down here which we will
separate the creepers out of because
they're the next smallest mobs and to do
that let's see so they get pushed over
here they are over one block tall so
we'll have to move this block here to
put a trapdoor there and I think we'll
have to do a little bit of a ninja move
here oh just in time so they'll fit
through here and then we'll have another
water stream to move them and then
there's gonna be zombies skeletons and
witches and not the last bit of the mob
mix which we'll have to separate
separate out a different way because
they aren't different sizes from each
other okay creepers okay that worked
pretty good did any creepers get stuck
in the mix down there I don't see any
yeah that worked really well actually
I'm happy with that
any creepers in here you know if there
was they wouldn't have exploded
I should probably close that that could
have been bad all right so we got one
baby zombie there he just walked through
on his own without the Pistons help even
and you can see like we can have mobs up
there and at that level there and then
they kind of switch places when we press
this I think yeah
seems to work pretty good so we'll have
this probably running on a clock or
something every few seconds to separate
them all right it's very good very good
so we got the baby zombies and the
creepers getting separated out now one
thing we're gonna have to watch out for
that's if we get to my mom's in one spot
the mob cramming is gonna kill them I
just blocked this up right now so they
don't really have a spot to go when
they're getting backed up what we're
gonna try to do now is separate the
zombies the skeletons and the witches so
I've started building a thing here we're
gonna put a wolf right on top of this
cyan block here and then we're gonna
break this and I guess I forgot a block
back there we put one there without
triggering all the mobs yeah okay
put that there we'll slide this guy over
to his spot and then he'll stay there
forever hopefully come on guy this is a
really old wolf and I think his AI is
broken like a Python to stand up he
doesn't actually follow me anymore so
it's kind of a good stout wolf but I
think you'll still work okay come on get
to your spots and there we go so we're
gonna seal them in there so the
skeletons are gonna be able to see them
when they're in that spot right right
where they are
break all this and I'll try to explain
the plan here so you see I moved the
villagers well he's in front and the
zombies can see him I think I left us
left it open anyways all right so they
got a direct line of sight to him so
they're gonna go that way towards the
villager the wolf is gonna chase the
skeletons away this direction so they'll
run down this tunnel here and then we
got the trap door trick going on so
they'll try to walk overtop them they
they see him as full blocks and then
they just fall down so we got to break
that block
which block is it I find it really hard
to work with this glass like it plays
with my eyes a little bit I can't tell
what is what I think it's this one here
oh and oh we can't oh they're in the way
so you can see that piston over there is
gonna retract and then any skeletons in
there are free to go this way and
likewise there's a piston over there
let's just make sure I've never moved
that block oh I did it
so basically we're giving the mobs a
choice here that you neither go towards
the villager which the zombies will
hopefully do or they can run away from
the wolf which is what the skeletons
will hopefully do or they can choose to
do nothing and that's what that piston
down down there that one we're looking
at is four it'll retract and then any
mob that decides to do nothing is it's
gonna fall down into another chamber
which will hopefully be for the witches
and maybe for chicken jockeys as well
and this is what we got controlling the
whole thing so that we send power to
this block here it'll cause that piston
to retract for the zombies this piston
for the skeletons and then after eight
ticks here then it's gonna retract the
floor and drop down the witches so
they'd have like 0.8 seconds to decide
if they're gonna go somewhere if they
don't then they get dropped into the
default chamber which is hopefully
enough time if not we can add more delay
here later and now all we got to do is
add some sort of clock to this thing and
I think we'll put a pulse extender on
this as well he's my plan let's maybe do
it like like this so we'll run wire here
then we will put blocks here and here
I've got to go back a bit more and maybe
like this yes very good
okay now we got to set up a hopper clock
to go to that so that'll make the signal
four plus four plus four one point two
seconds long with this pulse extender oh
boy you know what guys I made a huge
mistake tonight's huge I had spring
rolls for supper you know it's been a
long time since I had spring rolls and
it's like like at least a year or two I
was like why why haven't I had these
these are delicious they're fried food
like come on who doesn't like spring
rolls right and I had some and now it's
been non-stop cabbage burps for the last
like five hours
nasty most disgusting burps in the world
and I can't get rid of them I tried
drinking coffee they like cover it up
and have like coffee burps instead nope
didn't work it's been torture hopefully
I'll remember for next time don't don't
eat spring rolls even though they
they're pretty good it's not worth it
because there's nothing worse than than
cabbage burps I tell you all right
we are just about ready here I think run
this to here up our staircase and this
is about ready to go we just got to turn
on the clock it's probably not gonna
work if we have a bunch of mobs piled up
here we need to sort them like one or
two at a time if possible so we want
this to run fairly frequently and let's
throw in some items here how many I'm
gonna guess maybe six we will see
okay and let's go over here and just see
what's happening with this because I'm
not sure if it's gonna work the way we
have it and it's not working it's
supposed to be a clog it's supposed to
keep running what's wrong
I built the hopper clock wrong got to
use sticky pistons not to regular
Pistons I should know that and there we
go okay let's get this going again
we'll try six items and let's go see
what's going on where is a good place to
view its how about over here
yeah we need a spot for those creepers
to go to because they're all totally
backed up nope that one piston is not
working at all hmm the one in the back
here this one here why not
there's supposed to be a piece of
redstone here there is okay is this not
oh I know why this is supposed to be a
repeater
but then this won't get extended by this
um okay well let's try without that for
now oh okay let's go take a step back
now I cleared out some of the mobs let's
see what happens now zombie falls down
here's the important parts oh did you
see that he fell right through okay we
got to change of timing on that then
No
oh you stupid dog
how did the wolf get down here like I
noticed he was itchy inching forward a
little bit
hey creeper
separated okay zombie he landed that's
good
and he did walk towards the villager we
got two zombies this time and will they
both do it they both did it good sign
zombie and skeleton so there's oh okay
that wasn't good
oh man it's a little bit of a mess isn't
it what's wrong with that skeleton like
he's not going at all maybe he needs
more time for the pathfinding to kick in
or hizzy
is he over a little bit and he can't see
the wolf anymore not sure
that worked fine they both tried to go
but they couldn't there we go
get them out of the way yeah alright
guys well I've been doing some tweaking
watching this trying to figure out how
to make it better in the end of things
here we're gonna disable those three
Pistons after all we're not even gonna
bother trying to separate out the
witches and even still having a lot of
trouble you see how long it takes the
skeletons to run away that's our big
issue here
it just takes them a really long time
and usually like if we were to give them
that much time the whole system would
back up quite a bit
sometimes the zombies will walk that way
too I tried giving the skeletons a
bigger platform so that they would go
there quicker run that direction quicker
it didn't seem to help though and I
think it just made the zombie
pathfinding worse because sometimes they
don't chase the villager they'll run
that way too and we have two wolves one
at the villager there and one over there
I'm not sure that made a difference but
at the very least the skeleton shouldn't
get stuck around the corner or something
like that and all in all I think it's
good enough whoa the good news is the
creepers work 100% there's no issues at
all with the creepers which is a really
big part of this this is the skeletons
and the zombies and the witches that are
a little bit tricky because we can't
really control it entirely we have to
rely on the back finding here we go
everybody this is the big moment
I've worked double time on this I got
the bomb factory hooked up now and we're
running our first test is it gonna blow
up I have no idea that's what makes it
so exciting and possibly frustrating I
thought we would have got some mobs by
now come on I cleared everything out
okay here we go first skeleton I'll try
explain this as it goes though we're off
to a terrible start okay there we go he
figured out what to do he's good so you
can see the creepers now take a new path
here they go they fall down and you see
we got skeletons in that tube creepers
in that one and there's a trapdoor there
holding them in place if we press a
button down there it's gonna flip both
those trapdoors and let them into the
bomb factory that's the one thing I'm
manually controlling right now cuz I
don't know if it's gonna be explosive in
a way that it'll destroy everything so
let's manually do it possibly it'll send
down more than one mob is what I'm
worried about
that'd look pretty good skeletons still
stuck on that snow golem though okay
okay
might not blow up now cuz I took a long
time okay very good first first one that
could success oh yeah see we got two
skeletons in there mmm is that gonna be
a big problem if that keeps happening we
kind of got to keep this thing running
otherwise it backs up you know uh-huh
okay this time we got one skeleton
that's good yeah let's keep it going
keep it going
so this will probably run on a clock -
maybe not as quick as that bill uh-huh
they're not blowing up though because
it's taking the skeleton too long to get
there
and then the creeper loses interest I
think they're all primed properly so I
think I think we're good
so go ahead skeleton skeleton shoots
creeper ants
kablammo nice size shirt in the tube
here just so that the skeleton again to
place quick enough that's one thing
we'll have to look into in the future
how to make them travel long distances
without losing interest in each other
which we kind of figured out already we
just gotta keep them close to each other
oh and snow golems dead that's why we
can't really detonate this close to the
thing uh-huh
it looks like it's gonna be working
that's good we'll probably use minecarts
to move them not water streams
especially with the new update coming
out that's gonna change all the water
stream mechanics I don't know what's
gonna have to change with what we built
here but we only have like four water
streams and the whole thing so hopefully
not too much trouble I'll get the dog
he's like shaking his head at us yeah
anyway so we got our mob sorter pretty
much working there maybe eighty ninety
percent accurate and we got our bomb
factory hooked up so I'm pretty happy
with that and we'll probably expand more
on that later but we still got a few
minutes left this episode I thought we
would change it up do some building and
I have a great idea absolutely
magnificent vision for this building
here are you ready for its it's gonna
look pretty weird actually probably if
you guys don't remember this is our sand
machine how does this work the end hold
shift right click
yeah it still works so the yellow sand
turns to orange sands and then goes into
storage down here and there's some
garbage here too apparently uh-huh but
we still don't have a skin for this so I
thought we tried make a building around
it's it's so we don't see the Pistons
and stuff and I have an idea for an
abstract build which might look a little
funny we'll see if we make it look cool
we're gonna mix prismarine the dark
prismarine with orange maybe terracotta
maybe sandstone would be cool because
this is a sandstone maker right if we
mix some of that into it would be a good
idea if I want to do like basically the
rough idea is to I hope it doesn't stand
out too much in this area too is another
concern of mine cuz it's gonna be a
little bit different than what we built
over there basically we're gonna have on
one side of the building like a curved
up like that and then on the other side
we're gonna have a curve going the
opposite way
let's space it let's see one two three
four five six seven eight nine maybe
nine blocks apart so we'll go up like
that and then start curving it this way
and this is gonna be the big curve so
it's gonna go like amazing right I know
uh-huh very good okay let's go see it
this is gonna be amazing
oh my goodness
so beautiful alright let's remove this
eye space the two more blocks apart so
it's 11 wide very simple concept right
looks incredible I don't know how I do
it
basically all we gotta do now is fill in
here with orange clay probably mix some
sandstone in with that too and then
we'll take it from there we'll see what
it looks like
okay let's just do a little bit actually
and then we'll we'll step back and look
at it and be impressed oh yeah
incredible I think the curve is too long
I think we got to remove one of the one
of the tails there you know what it's
hard to tweak perfection but I found a
way somehow here so I made it a little
bit less crazy a little bit smaller and
I don't think it's quite as wide anymore
either
and I think this is our shape I think we
got it figured out kind of reminds you
of day of the tentacle huh no maybe a
little bit that is the inspiration for
the build which is why it is such a good
build okay so now what we got to do the
trick guys with all builds is the
details right always with the details so
I want to try put the tentacley thingies
in I don't know they're called the
suction cups you know go to for I guess
maybe three oh hello
okay very good
what if we go to two three only because
the kind of messes up that the order
here or the proportions yeah yeah okay
okay now next plan we are gonna grab
some of this glowstone and possibly
fences dark oak let's make some dark oak
stairs as well do that and let's use the
cool crafting system there we go we got
some dark oak stairs and what we're
gonna do
it's good it's nighttime million I see
we can get a better idea of how the
lighting is gonna look here we're gonna
make this come out two blocks then
stairs then glowstone yeah that helps a
lot okay and then around that we'll
probably put some trap
do we have screws yeah I did bring some
all right yes yes it's very good right
very good but it's missing our secret
weapon
what does every build Nev Nev oh I gave
a little spoiler need is birch leaves
aha so well not virtually any kind of
leaves really add a couple couple leaves
to this thing that's maybe too much too
much leaves less is more excellent okay
now oh yes I like it I like it
problem is it's only the facade right
now we still got to finish the building
let's do the test - I'm scared to do
this how bad does it actually look from
a distance it's not that well in my
opinion it's not that bad the prison
brain actually matches the grass color
here so it kind of blends in that's
interesting and the orange isn't too far
off from the dirt color I didn't even
think of that that's pretty cool this is
one of those builds where some of you
guys are probably like that's incredible
and the majority of you're gonna be like
are you kidding me AHA this is no joke
people this is this is style all right
so to make it get wider what do we do I
feel like oh did I put all oh no now I'm
stuck forever great put all the brews
Marines back in the chest and I yep
go back up I think what we're gonna do
is take the tail here and start wrapping
it this way and go across doesn't need
to be very wide right like there's not
much to the actual build there
alright everybody well I think it's
that time I'm gonna wrap up the episode
here for today I did try mixing some
sandstone and I think it's okay all
right and it suits the build because
it's the sandstone maker I like it
I ran out of inspiration and time for
the side so I gotta figure something out
with that and this side we could copy
the other one there if we want or try to
do something unique with it haven't
decided and I kind of just filled in
over here and I think that's fine maybe
could add a couple more details to that
too I guess yeah I guess just uh let me
know give it a rating between 10 and 20
let me know how much you love it and
let's get to the comment of the day for
today so this is the question you've all
been asking why aren't you releasing
these episodes so frequently I
personally love them and this is my
favorite series of yours it would be
great if you could release one week and
if you can't could you explain why they
aren't coming out so fast mm-hmm so it's
a little bit of a tricky tricky
situation the best way to explain it is
I guess like the spark is missing right
now making these episodes I know it's
it's really easy to watch them but to
make an episode it's kind of like you
know when you were in school and you got
to write an essay and I've written like
five hundred essays now and there's
always that constant pressure oh I'll
get write another essay before so on so
time otherwise people are gonna be like
where's the next episode so that's a
little bit stressful and to be honest
lately I've been taking a little bit
easier with YouTube taking some time off
really enjoying it cuz like been doing
YouTube for I think about eight years
now it or is it the ninth year
anniversary I don't know and for the
first six years for sure I was in pretty
trihard mode like all my spare time was
spent on YouTube all my free time and
that led to very little variety in my
life
and it's nice to have variety oh my
goodness I can't tell you how much it is
nice to just go hey I kind of want to do
this today and then do it instead of
like oh I got to make another video for
today out of all my series this one is
the most difficult for me to record part
of the reason for that is because it's
been going on for so long right it's a
vanilla series so I'm very limited on
what I can do within the framework of
this series unless I make some drastic
changes which I don't think you guys
would like yeah so it's a bit of a
tricky situation like obviously the
easiest thing for me is when they
release new content like we're getting a
new snapshot soon there'll be a little
bit of new content with that but usually
that's not much the best the two best
things I think we've gotten recently
that I've really added to my enjoyment
in like vanilla minecraft is the lighter
wings and shulker boxes had so much fun
with this series like the first two
three weeks shulker boxes are out but
you know we need more stuff otherwise I
got to come up with more and more ideas
and with so many episodes it's getting
harder and harder guys but yeah that's
the general gist of it I would say kind
of a little bit lacking inspiration
right now and trying to take it easy as
well so those two things combined make
for let less let's play episodes
hopefully that will change and if you
guys ever have ideas like if you maybe
you got a random build idea for me or a
challenge for me post in the comments a
single comment might give me inspiration
for a whole episode which would be great
that's exactly what I need right now
more ideas I need ideas guys oh there's
a creeper in there but regardless of
what happens I know some of you have
been worried about me I'm doing fine
things are good having a lot of fun with
project ozone having fun playing arc and
some of you have been checking the
YouTube stats I know the
not great for my channel right now and
they probably never will really pick up
again just because of the way YouTube is
now even if I get really good at YouTube
and super try hard mode I don't think my
stats will ever get crazy just the way
the system is right now but regardless
of that I'm doing fine I'm okay
financially I know some of you worry
about that I'm good I've had a good run
on YouTube so far and have ever and have
had a lot of fun with it
and hopefully will continue uh-huh
anyways I want to drive this out too
much what please you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
as always and I will see you again in
the next one take care bye bye
[Music]