[Music]
hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back thank you for joining
me today
for this special milestone episode
that's right we have hit episode
oh snappers that's a big number uh we're
almost at the nine year mark
now in the series just about we're like
one month away from that and just about
the 10-year mark for
uh the series if you include the
previous map we played in as well
so we've been at this for quite a bit of
time guys and
as many of you know every 50 episodes we
try to do a world tour we go
and check things out in the world see
what's changed what we've built
stuff that's broken unfinished projects
all the fun stuff
uh but uh yeah i guess to get us started
today i think i'm gonna smack you guys
with the
go get your snacks because it's gonna be
a long episode the last world tour
was an hour and a half long and in the
last 50 episodes we have built far more
than we have in
any previous 50 episodes we've done a
lot a lot more stuff to see
and i'm gonna have to talk faster tell
fewer horrible jokes and just
get through this as quick as we can
uh-huh so what better way to start off
our tour than a long
drawn-out history on how this series
began
season 1 started december 17 2010 in a
world that we called
chocolate island that ran from episodes
1 to 104
until the minecraft release officially
came out and that introduced many new
terrain changes
which broke our previous world pretty
badly and we decided to upgrade to a new
world
which started season two that's the one
we're on currently
which began in episodes 105 to now and
yeah i guess that kind of brings us to
the point of these world tours why do we
do them
well it's for uh you know people that
watch this series it's kind of nice to
go back and check out some builds
maybe that we don't see too often it's a
bit of a nostalgic trip
try to give some background information
on some stuff maybe you'll learn
something new you didn't know before
but uh mainly these world tours are for
new people
that might be you uh for
for someone joining into this series it
can be a little daunting to start at
episode 550
oh there's so much stuff we're missing
out on right well note we're trying to
condense all our key builds down to a
single episode
so you can check out stuff and get
caught up with everybody else and maybe
this will be
a good time for you to join in and
watching the series
if you like what you see and if you want
some a backlog of content maybe go back
50 episodes or so and start watching
from there
anyways i think we're ready to begin our
tour here we're gonna start off with the
man cave this was our first
base and still kind of our main base in
the world
i just can't get away from this place i
love it so much uh we began the world
starting off in a cave and kind of liked
it you know so i decided i want to build
my base down here
and whenever i build a base in this game
i try to set certain restrictions
to try and make it more interesting so
one of them was like all the builds have
to be underground
we got to use grass for our floor so i i
grew the grass down here this was back
before silk touch was in the game
all the grass had to be grown and also i
set a rule that i don't want to use any
torches in the finished areas it's got
to be all hidden lighting
the grass and the nature theme of our
base really worked out in our favor
though in that regard because
we didn't have carpets and a lot of
other ways of hiding lighting in the
past so that we were pretty much limited
to like hiding it under water or
pressure plates
or a big one that i used throughout the
base here that works well with the
nature
theme is hiding it under leaves we got
bushes all over the place
with lighting underneath and that does
the trick for the most part
also in a lot of places in the ceiling
there's lighting there's a daylight
sensor thing up there that turns light
on
during the day and that goes off at
night time
um let's check out our our storage room
here we still use this to this date
many people want me to move on but i
just love this thing so much the
shutters open up and then the
exposes the hidden lighting behind the
chests and lightens up the room
a lot of people like that uh in these
chests we have a little bit of
everything
that's our nighttime song
see the light went off over here now
oh yeah it can be tough everybody living
in a cave never seen the sky
you don't know what time it is you run
out the door and you get creepered right
in the face
not with the nighttime song we know it's
night time now and we also have a
daytime song
that triggers in the morning and uh
we're going to be switching into
creative and spectator mode throughout
this tour
a lot of people get confused about this
we do play the series in survival on
hard mode with no
mods no data packs no
optifine nothing is vanilla minecraft
but for the world tours i create a
backup and that's what we're on right
now so we're free to destroy stuff and
go into creative and all that kind of
stuff
so these are our day and night time
songs up above us they get triggered by
daylight sensor
right over here and of course with every
storage room in this game you need to
have an ender chest nearby we got that
under the water
anvil hidden over here and you need a
crafting table as well
that pops out of the ground like a so
and also it's nice to have a smelting
room next to your storage room so that
is what this is over here
we can smelt stuff every time we put in
something
it plays a little tune the light turns
on and also uh
these lights over here turn on if
anything's smelting in the room
hmm i just realized these might be
backwards
i think they're supposed to play the
tune when they finish smelting
so you know they're done even if you're
not in the area but i guess just light
turns off
we got wire access over here if we want
to check out how the redstone works
i made the smelting room back when bud
switches were new in the game
block update detectors um now we have
observers which replace those
for the most part and as our world ages
we try to keep our older builds looking
pretty much the same as they did
originally but we do make a little
modifications
you can see we got a stone cutter here
now and the grindstone lanterns
shulker boxes in the ceiling those
aren't weren't there nine years ago i
tell you that
up the stairs here we have one of the
very first farms we built in the world
the pop-up sheep farm
um that we added this section a little
later in the series once hoppers came
out
but uh the idea is we can run along here
and share our sheep
like a so some of our builds in the
world
have broken due to updates and this is
one of the farms that
definitely has many times because it
uses so many different game mechanics
which
keep changing um but we tried to fix
stuff in this world as well so i think
at the moment this is working but not as
good as it did
originally
always interrupting me so the way this
farm works is we got a block above the
sheep to hold them in place they're
about a block and a half tall so they
can't get out of this this air space
here
and uh originally when we would shear
the sheep the wall would always land
within a three by three area
now it can jump outside of that a bit um
and then we would use water to push the
wall down a grate here
and it would always land on the pressure
plate
now it can get stuck on the fence rarely
and when it would trigger the redstone
the sheep goes down
and then grass grows to the dirt block
there triggers a bud switch and then
when they eat it it triggers
it again and they pop up so
let's just head to the end here where we
got our controls so there's a water
bucket control
over here sends water down to push the
wool
down the grates and then all the sheep
that have their wool sheared would go
down
and reset the ones that didn't have it
sheared before would stay
but you can see it's a little a little
broken
so we also have a manual override to get
everybody down
aha and then when they regrow their wool
they pop up the lights turn back on
above here we got the water system the
pistons move out of the way and drop the
water down
we do it that way so the piston kind of
matches the wood color up there
and then below we got our two stage bud
switches
i designed myself i was pretty proud of
them at the time
which uh trigger when the grass grows
and they eat it
and then we also have the water below
those pressure plates over here let's go
creative
that's where the wall ends up going to
spawn some in here
that's this it runs down a channel
on both sides water on ice over here
and it goes to a dropper elevator right
over here
up to this chest and then you can see
it's ending up in here and it gets
collected together and then we manually
take it out and put in the
different colors and shockingly this is
the only sheet farm we've ever made in
this series
i do plan on eventually making a new one
with the shears and dispenser mechanic
that's
sort of newish but this has been
sufficient so far for me actually
because i don't build with wool very
often
but if i need a lot of it this is
definitely going to be disappointing
because it's not that fast over here we
got our ender pearl
station loaded up with ender pearls over
there
and then we stand here to get them it's
pretty nice i use this thing all the
time
um downstairs we have multiple branching
paths in our world
enderman's stealing our stuff as usual
another one of our very first farms
is pretty gimmicky mushrooms would grow
in there and then the water would
harvest them
now they grow out here
we got a jukebox station we can we can
put records in here
lights turn on when we do that so the
general idea with the man cave was to
fill up any empty spaces we might have
with contraptions or
farms or anything we want to build and
then link those together with paths and
then
finally decorate them and make them look
nice and
honestly i think that's the most
practical way of playing this game like
i've made many bases since then
i find this works a lot better than like
pre-building a base and filling it
this is the very first enchanting
station i ever made in this game guys
and i'm pretty sure this is the first
enchanting table i ever crafted
actually still got it still know where
it is
um that's another cool thing about
having an old world it's like oh yeah
that was the first time i did that first
time i did that
it brings up a lot of old memories you
know uh so
in the past it took 50 levels to enchant
something and you needed 30 bookshelves
not just 15 like you do nowadays
and when you enchanted things your
levels went all the way down to zero
so a lot of times people would block out
the enchanting table with torches
and the way i decided to do mine since i
was a redstoner at heart you know
i decided to hook up some sticky pistons
to the bookshelves and then you have a
fine
control over what levels you would get
i keep a lot of junk up here as well in
these i think i added this later this
stuff up here
um but yeah you can control the levels
easily that way
uh-huh and this is a little hard to
explain but we have a man-made
river running through our base which uh
originally the plan was to have a water
transportation system like a boat road
running through the whole base
and it just never worked out and we
ended up just keeping this here as like
a decorative thing
and a way of getting around we've got
lily pads over top of it we can walk
across
which is kind of cool back over here
again this is like
the part we branched out to shortly
after we did this area
uh we got a pumpkin and melon farm very
simple one
step on it pistons push the ground up
this used to shoot out a hoe at the end
here we would use to till the ground
because
originally pumpkins and melons would not
grow on regular dirt like this it had to
be tilled
and then we would step on this it would
go down and they would grow again we can
store our stuff over here
something that is true even to this day
everybody
is whenever a new block comes out in
this game it never fails that's the
block i gotta build with it's my new
favorite thing
i think sandstone was the hot block for
a long time
and then when i generated this world it
was the same time that nether fortresses
came out in the game
and also i believe it's the patch that
introduced the end the strongholds
so that's what we got in the walls and
uh
also abandoned mine shafts i think came
all came out in the same patch
so of course we built the base the man
cave
in a giant abandoned mine shaft and
there's still the remnants behind here
we got uh dual cave spider spawner
somewhere is it over here oh yeah here's
the other one
there's one there's two and uh when we
stand over here
it activates both of them for a long
time this is where we used to kill them
there was a crushing system here
and we ran them up a spider elevator
thing i designed
it it brings them up there's a whole
wacky thing
it goes up over here and then
i think this came from the other spawner
they merged together
it keeps going it keeps going there's a
horse over there
and then it would drop them down get
them down to a one-hit kill
and somehow i managed to make it where
they wouldn't stick to any walls and
stuff oh it was amazing this was my main
xp
farm for a very long time pistons were
also fairly new in the game at the time
we were building this i think they came
out one
patch before the official release back
in the beta
and of course the hot thing was uh
spiral elevators so these would
these would push you up they don't work
anymore as you can see
it would like it would bring you up like
this it would push you on the stairs
and of course every base needs an ugly
brick thing so we got our ugly brick
thing over here
look at this infinite water incredible
amazing crafting
all in one station the water doesn't
flow out because we got the pressure
plate here
yeah hidden lighting oh man just just
incredible guys
you didn't see that there did you no
it's there uh we got to
run faster for speed potions we got live
longer
for the instant health and don't forget
about the hidden chest behind the lava
that's what we would use to refill these
when they would run out because we built
this before hoppers were thin you had to
manually refill things back then
it was really annoying uh don't forget
also about testificates you guys
remember that
before villagers became villagers they
didn't trade at all they did absolutely
nothing in the game for a very long time
and the goal was to collect
all six different guys different colors
in project pokemon here
um never did it though and we can't do
it anymore so
these are empty got some secret chests
here for trading stuff with them we got
paper
for the paper trade we have a button to
cycle through
the guys it's broken now they take
damage a little bit when they get
switched but uh
yeah kind of cool secret ender chest
that's the crafting table
secret ender chest aha
we got a 2x2 door here this leads over
to
um emerald city the plan was to put a
village over here and to make it all
technical and crazy and
oh my goodness my eyes look at this
place right incredible
absolutely amazing so we would drop the
villagers down
over over here then we carted them over
with the mine carts
to our village and then they were forced
to live in these rooms
and now i use this for storage
there is still one iron golem here from
the ancient days though
um and there was also the well i think
there's a villager down here still
there's two these guys are ancient
ancient
i don't remember how this stuff all
works to be honest it was so so long ago
but yeah i had a big plan in mind with
all this like we spent a lot of time
working on this i had to mine out the
whole
area we had a whole system up above here
for the villagers they would get dropped
down through the water
and there was like a storage system
and a way of moving them through the
nether oh i broke it
um they would get held in these areas
and then drop down
to these spots oh that was just for
project pokemon i guess yeah
anyways it's abandoned we don't think
about that anymore we almost never see
it
something else that we abandoned but is
so much cooler was our original potion
room
uh back before brewing was automatable
uh we came up with a system here that's
pretty cool we got the
three by three door with the hole in it
uh we got some storage here for the
potions
this is like our random junk stuff um
you can see it's color coded behind the
chest
there's some wool so blue for swiftness
and orange for fire resistance regen
that was pretty cool we got some pixel
art in the floor
as well as our main brewing area over
here so the idea
is we would stand underneath the water
if we wanted glass bottles we'd hit the
top button
and funny enough with the way the game
is now this
actually gives us filled water bottles
that's
not what originally happened um you
would get glass bottles and you
this was within reach so you'd hold
right click and then they would get
thrown up like this
and filled and then you would use those
to fill up the brewing stands all of the
brewing stands are within reach
you don't have to move at all to get to
them and then like if you wanted
netherwork you would get the netherwart
i guess there's only one left if you
wanted uh
redstone or gunpowder you would hit this
and uh
then you'd pick your final ingredient
sugar maybe for
swiftness potions everything would get
dispensed in this one spot you'd brew
your stuff and then
store it over here which was neat and
there's a whole bunch of stuff
making this work there's a massive
storage room above here
uh droppers weren't out in the game yet
so we used dispensers
and that is why we're getting uh water
bottles now because it's uh
glass bottles in the dispensers at the
water here
kind of interesting dispensers are about
thank you sign
um i guess that's for the door
um yeah anyways the way we would get to
the
room over there is through the gold door
and these endermen
are driving me crazy and there's a
hopper minecart underneath the block
there it would pick up the stuff
go through step on the pressure plate to
close the door and you can access all
the
storage here and refill it and stuff
moving on we got ourselves a bit of a
wacky build the ufo
with the cow farm below this was our
main source of food for a long time
eventually we found a mushroom island
and moved those guys over there as well
but we had a whole thing for fishing we
would stand here
it's like a little mini game i'm pretty
sure it doesn't work anymore
can we get one at least oh we got one
we would fish him up and they would go
into the water above and then float into
holding system oh yeah so you can see we
got flowing water that goes this way
then it would merge in the middle they
would go over here fall down into a
fenced area and this is where we would
kill them
and something else cool about this cow
farm is this square you see this was
actually
part of the abandoned mine shop you know
those weird square rooms that's what
this is
we turned it into a cow farm which we
can get to over here we got a way of
going down
we got some dispensers for looting we
got
that for tilling the crops oh yeah we
used to plant wheat and stuff here too
we got seeds and the wheat there but
generally we would uh feed the guys we'd
go
down here after we killed them
let's kill a couple i'm sorry
i'm sorry we have a bunch of pistons
holding water up
i believe over here and then we would
retract those when we hit the button
oh a lever never mind that would pull
the pistons back the water would flow
down because again you couldn't like
keep
water buckets and dispensers or anything
like that
um all the drops would fall down to the
center and then
get pushed towards us and also there was
an old trick in the game if you had
fences below
tilled farmland you couldn't trample it
and that was amazing
but they removed that pretty shortly
after it was discovered
uh and then there's also a way of
getting back here
once upon a time we had two testificates
in our world named
tom and jeff that ran our potion lab for
us
then one day jeff killed tom so we
trapped him in a cage above a lava pool
we used to point and laugh at him until
one day he just disappeared
the end uh we have our cave spider
spawners we can view through here
as well as a slime pad we built so
another big change around the time we
made this world was slimes used to only
spawn at like
y minus 16 or less then they changed it
to y
40 and less so we made a spawning pad in
a slime chunk they jump off the pad
into the water streams around here
slimes used to sink so they'd fall down
these holes and die
um but now they just float over top of
them
and they go up an elevator here whoop
whole big thing here there's also like
some lava blades and stuff
i think we used to have in here but we
got rid of small slimes
fall down a one by one area and then the
medium ones
medium ones down a two wide area and
then there's the big
boys that land over here and they end up
in this spot
and then there's also a minecart system
which i think is empty at the moment
that would pick up the slimes they would
go down here
a couple uh renegades they'd fall down
and then they run around the track
underneath some
slabs and the reason we did this is just
because it looked funny
and they kind of push you around so when
the big guys here go into the mine cart
we can watch it fall down and go along
here
and also that we had a whole system for
when they would despawn and the mine
carts would become empty there was a way
of detecting that
and the empty mine minecarts would go
back into the system
it ram into a cactus and go into the
dispenser here to be reused
so it was a whole whole big thing and
also there's a viewing window for that
over here
okay so we got a lot of stuff to cover
in the man game let's keep going here
uh we haven't gone down this path yet
this is to
an empty room this is unfinished as you
can tell the idea was something out of
uh
donkey kong country the big hoard of
bananas we were gonna stash a big pile
of diamonds here or
emeralds but never ended up doing it
then i wanted to store my
broken tools here we got a few of them
but then they introduced mending into
the game
so yeah it's like
unfinished area got a branching path
that goes across our river
goes down here it's a little decorative
area we don't build a lot of new stuff
in the man cave anymore but
recently we added a bunch of stuff here
except for the vine wall this was here
for a long time
so we get our shears vines grow against
the wall
sometimes they land in the water most of
the time they don't and then there's
hoppers below to pick them up
this is a very odd contraption there we
have a long history of burning diamonds
in this series so we made a contraption
just for that when the blue fire came
out in the game you get the diamond you
throw it in the fire
and it turns blue incredible
and then we hit this one so we can burn
more diamonds
uh we made a fern farm recently as well
uh with this one we load up some ferns
in our off hand and then we get our
shears and just hold right click
and electric every so often the
dispensers bone meal the
ferns so that they grow tall and then
you get two ferns each one of those
and get more that way and they end up in
here
uh also we added a concrete maker
recently this was a bit of an oddball
idea i had so we built it somewhere in
the world we can maybe forget about it
if we wanted to
we do the layers again
like so when we land on the pressure
plate it shoots out a tnt
and usually in that time we have it all
loaded up if we don't
pause
[Music]
and then it's pretty good
if you get into the rhythm but that was
pretty bad bad example of it
but yeah it gets blown up in a blast
chamber here and all funnels down into
the chest
there's also a chicken farm over here
which is a bit odd as well
we don't really have a good chicken farm
in the world this was supposed to be for
a mini game where they would shoot the
eggs out and we would shoot the chickens
as they fall down
the way the man cave is laid out it
makes it kind of tough to go in order
so we're back over here again we're
going to go to another old build
a very old important build the tree farm
look at the tree farm guys this thing is
super
important to our world not really it but
the people behind it guys
so if you don't know the story a long
time ago on youtube when i first started
you couldn't really make any money
doing youtube the partnership program
was brand new at the time
um things like machinima were around but
oh
they were sketchy i almost joined
machinima at one point and then
it's like the guy that was recruiting me
asked me to join on xbox 360 to play
call of duty or something and i didn't
want to
because uh transformers war of cybertron
was my game i was like one of the top in
the world at that game
and then he was like making fun of me
for it playing some kitty game
even though it's not a kitty game it's
an amazing game um
anyways it seemed really unprofessional
to me so i i
opted out of joining machinima but i
watched the movie social
code and it's like man i got to start
thinking of ways of making money in my
life
and i almost quit youtube for a while
and i thought
let's just open it up uh to donations
and see what happens and oh my goodness
guys we got a lot of donations
every one of these trees represents
someone amazing that sent me money
in the early days helped keep me
motivated and making videos
and eventually we did get partnered and
uh started making money through ads and
then we stopped taking donations once uh
that became sustainable but uh we still
have their memories here and i
i thank everyone for that because that
made a huge difference
uh also along the tree farm here we got
a cool mural
different biomes in the game we got like
the tiger cold biomes on
on this side of the wall then we got the
hotter biomes over here
desert mesa little uh
bryce cannon or whatever i don't know we
got a sand temple
miniaturized as well as like the forest
and plains and stuff on this side
it's a little bit tough to see it when
the trees are grown in here but i've
always been a big fan of the ceiling
design we did in here as well
uh it's it's a simple design but it
looks pretty cool i think
and over in the corner we also have
a grass farm what would you call this
again flower farm sort of thing
you hit start you get stuck
loud you hit stop
hit the button up there water gathers it
together
and then we can store it there's also
composting for anything extra we get
that we don't want
and uh yeah we upgraded this recently so
now it's faster and does nialam and
stuff so it's pretty cool
those of you that have been watching the
recent hermitcraft episodes you know
i've gotten
pretty good with note blocks that's not
always been the case though
i've always been a big fan of noteblocks
didn't know how to use them for a long
time but even
during the series here i have tried
making some noteblock songs and some of
them turned out pretty good
i think it's moon song from cave story
got our map wall our kitty
if you leave the trap door up it keeps
playing in a loop as well
um over this way is our netherwort farm
we built this when magma blocks were
introduced in the game
and another word i believe as well new
blocks guys new best block in the game
gotta use them uh there is a button over
here for harvesting
press the harvest that shoots up the
water
and funnels them all to the center where
they go down a hole
water shuts off and then we gotta
manually replant because there's no way
of automatically doing it
not yet in the game anyways and then
they go up a dropper elevator
goes up and then down into the chest on
this side
excellent so i think we covered most of
stuff in this area we're not done with
the man cave no no no
there's still a lot left to go but this
area is done
uh down this way we have the end
reporter we'll get more into that later
we also have a path that leads to the
stronghold base and i think this
connects to the
guardian farm although i might have
covered that up recently
then this was just a open space we had
so i put something here we got a
flower farm
super fast
slimes always jump on the pressure
plates and trigger it when i don't want
them to
and legs of the world it's great yeah
it's great design guys
you can see our cave spiders oh yeah and
this is where we actually get the drops
from these guys so let's go check this
out
so they used to go up the spider
elevator and then we changed it so they
just fall down
they land on the trip wires and then
that makes the minecart
get moving here picks up the drops
through the slabs
and deposits them in the chest and uh
another one set up exactly like that as
well
and it's got a little creeper face
design on the slabs
um fishing got improved in the game at
one point so you used to only get fish
just the regular standard fish and then
they added the
looting and leer
yeah i think that's the two so we made a
fishing shack where we could uh
just fish yeah uh
this is the man-made river kind of
branches out through
different places in the base as well so
it comes down to the fishing shack and
fills up the pond
and we also have the river branching
down here it creates a small
decorative waterfall which i think looks
pretty nice down to the lower section
uh this area is mostly decorative but we
do have a little bit of a farm here this
used to be a rabbit farm
which is why we planted the carrots all
around it um
in the past you had to tie them to
fences on leads otherwise i think they
would get away or despawn or something
was weird with it
and then you would feed them through
here
some remnants still remain i think they
all disappeared eventually i don't know
why
but then there was some stuff for
oh i think we'd use the water so they'd
hop around and make it easier to feed
them
and then there's poison to get them down
to
i don't know one hit kill or something
and that was for collecting the drops or
something i don't know it's all very
confusing
um eventually they all disappeared
though so we turned this into a pig farm
who also eat carrots so it worked out
great
this goes down further this is mostly
unfinished down this way
but we did put down an eats road in here
as well which is a
transportation system i invented a long
time ago
doesn't work in the game anymore but you
could ride boats down a track
i'm a pretty big fan of branching paths
if you couldn't tell so
at the intersection we can also go this
way this leads over to the creeper face
and uh oh we just saw it shoot arrows
out of its eyes that's
cool back up to this way um
we got two important things along here
this is a part of our snowball fountain
system
and also snowfall snow farm so you
left click with the snow shovel hopper
minecart automatically picks up the
drops and then they funnel down to
assist them below
and this is a mini farm the very first
one we built in our world
check this out you stand on the pressure
plate
piston moves the dirt up and down like
that hold right click and the dispensers
are full of bone meal they grow the crop
and you get a little extra every time
amazing um also works with wheat
potatoes
even beetroot seeds guys look at that we
get beetroot like crazy
and the cool thing about this one is uh
pressure plates on a jungle log so you
can use it to grow
cocoa beans too the very first thing we
ever built in this world was the lava
creeper face thing you see before us
lava larva lava whatever weird way you
want to say it
uh the idea behind this was to pay
homage to our first world the chocolate
island we had a giant creeper face in
the middle of our base
so we built another one in the middle of
this base behind it
is our nether portal to get to our
netherhub
and it's very treacherous to go through
it
always but i've gotten into the habit of
doing it properly now
um behind the window here is our very
first horse
zenith we used them to fight a wither
one time and he actually survived that
was like
incredible that's the snowball fountain
i've been talking about
it has a player detector on it so it
only fires when we're nearby
uh also you saw it shot arrows out of
its eyes that's controlled over here
we have a way of refilling um
the arrows and then uh there's a
randomizer for it as well and stuff
oh there it goes and now we arrive at
the moment many of you have been waiting
for
through this tunnel lies our very best
friend in the world
because it's a single player and he
doesn't talk so
he's the best we can settle for wilson
our tamagotchi pet in minecraft
well son yeah so the idea behind wilson
is he's sort of like a mini game within
minecraft our goal
is to keep him alive as long as possible
and
over time his age bar ticks down and he
wanted to get to the very end if
possible but it's difficult
he takes a lot of a lot of maintenance a
lot of care because he's got these
different stat
points um he's got a weight bar a
happiness bar and a hunger bar
and then also a health bar which factors
in the other three
and does some math and decides if the
health should go up or down every update
um so if all his uh stats are in good
shape his health goes up if they're in
bad shape
his health goes down uh also as his
health goes down he's more likely to get
sick
and he's sick right now you can see
because he's got a zigzaggy mouth
in order to cure his sickness and he
gets a major health penalty when he's
sick like the strains a lot faster
so in order to cure him you gotta feed
them
golden apples uh one second
uh he's got a way of preventing it so
you can't feed him too often
and it was it was it was out so we
couldn't feed him at the moment
but yeah if we feed him a golden apple
here's a sickness
now he's just kind of sad because his
health is low um in order to
get him happy we got to keep him in good
shape for a while so one way of doing
that is by feeding him you gotta get
his hunger up to five bars
and you can feed them cookies as well
cookies give them
less food but boost his happiness and
also increases his weight faster than
normal as well
the idea with the weight was to keep it
bounced you don't want it too high or
too low
otherwise he would lose health and
the really cool thing about wilson is
he's got lots of different expressions
he can make let's uh just run through
those
so at five lights on with the health bar
he's got the super happy expression
at four lights he's still looking pretty
happy at three lights he's neutral
two lights and he's sad at one light
he's just wishing for death at this
point
and if you neglect him if you don't take
care of wilson his health bar will drain
all the way down and then he gets the
dead face where his eyes are closed he's
got the zigzag kind of like the sick
face
but uh once he once he dies you cannot
revive him his heart stops beating
and doesn't matter what you do his age
bar stops ticking and that's
your final score all right good stuff so
let's go take a look behind the scenes
what's going on in wilson's body
a whole lot of redstone so the history
behind wilson is we started working on
him
around the time the redstone update came
out that's when we got hoppers in the
game
comparators and i think maybe droppers
but i don't remember
and i got super excited about all the
new possibilities about what we could do
with the new features
and i wanted a technical challenge so
that's
where wilson uh started being made and
while working on them i figure out lots
of cool stuff like how to do variables
counters in minecraft um we got a
sickness randomizer based on health
levels so this is a variable randomizer
depending on his health level he's more
likely to get sick
it like operates in three different
stages um
also so that's like his immune system
he's got a stomach so as we feed him it
takes a while for him to digest his food
if you keep feeding him
before his stomach empties then he gains
weight faster
also he's got a bladder system over here
i think
so every once in a while he takes a poop
and then his weight drops by a bunch um
and it's supposed to like
flood the room or something and you have
to clean it up otherwise his happiness
would go down i never implemented that
and also a lot of people give me a lot
of credit for inventing
the hopper clock it's a commonly used
redstone
circuit in the game and i'm invented
that while working on wilson actually
this is the i think the first one ever
made in the game right over here
it's wilson's hearts so this regulates
how often it gets updated it's a
variable
timer system every time it updates it
runs all the
logic behind wilson ah alright so we
just have two more branches to go down
in the man cave down there and we can go
down here
both kind of blend together as well so
this leads to a viewing window for
wilson
and check out the redstone and this was
supposed to continue on and expand the
base but we haven't
gone beyond that yet then we can go down
this way to a new room this is
like a flooded area so we're on a pier
and it's mostly just decorative we also
have
a horse elevator here for our horse
stable
again this leads back to the creeper and
uh
this is where we used to keep our good
horses until the slimes let a bunch of
them out and they died in the water here
that's when we moved zenith behind the
window so he would be safe
from the slimes uh this i don't think
works anymore but we used to be able to
ride a horse up the elevator
hey look at that maybe it does work i
don't know
probably probably 50 50. and then we got
slimes
to land on if we want to go down uh
through here
is a mushroom farm this is for brown and
red mushrooms
and uh it's supposed to continue on if
we want to keep expanding
we've got some goodies over here for
growing them and
this is also a musical mushroom farm
all right and then from here we have
another branching path that goes down to
the go get your snacks machine we saw at
the beginning of this episode
i've never really had a standardized
intro for the series and
one episode i just started with uh go
get your snacks
and for some reason that caught on
people really liked it
always want me to say it at the start of
the episode and i'll do it every once in
a while so we made a machine there to
kind of visualize it and then this is an
armory
you used to be able to put armor stands
in mine carts you can't do that anymore
but we had a swapping system for like
picking them up and then another one
would drop
down but uh all the minecart stuff broke
with that now i just
store some random tools and stuff here
this leads back to that area we saw
before
yeah so a lot of the things we've seen
so far some of them are useful some of
them not so much
but pretty much everything down this
path of the man cave we use
all the time like this is an area we
frequent this leads to
ethos lab this is our auto brewing
system
which replaced the old potion room um
it's complete with the netherwort farm
inside just a simple one
and there's another one over there it's
mostly for decoration though there's the
on
off switch for turning it on
but you didn't expect that these lights
tell us if there's
uh awkward potions available for brewing
and basically we can brew every single
potion automatically here
and it does it in a chain system so at
the start there's awkward potions
then it adds an ingredient and then we
got night vision then it adds the
redstone
and we get extended fermented spider eye
it becomes invisibility and then finally
splash
and at every step of the brewing process
we can pull out the
potions however we want them and
some new potions got added to the game
after we built this so it doesn't
actually brew
everything anymore which is a bit
unfortunate
and then there's a main system here for
brewing the awkward potions if we flip
this up
it'll auto brew awkward potions and
we can fill the water bottles up over
here although that is totally
automated now that you can fill water
bottles with dispensers
and above the potion lab is a giant
minecart system for distributing the
awkward potions to the different brewing
areas
it goes around through these junctions
and delivers the awkward potions
wherever
needs it and then returns to pick up
more when it finishes
moving on we have another piston door on
this side of the lab this one was kind
of special
used to be able to open it by selecting
a golden carrots there was a
oh it does still work okay never mind
there's a rabbit hidden behind the wall
that gets excited when he sees the
golden carrot in your hand
that leads to this other intersection
room or tunnel
this one's uh pretty decorative though
we got a bunch of plants
on the podzole down below water down the
middle and you can see
like plants hanging down from the
ceiling roots from trees
and i think i hit a bunch of water
buckets above above too so it like leaks
down looks like it's filling up the
water blow oh and i guess there's water
coming out of the sides here too
that makes more sense actually this way
is our
main mob farm in the world which isn't
doing anything because it's probably
night time
it's fairly efficient but it's nothing
super crazy i think i still got a lot of
dark spots actually
in this area that i got to light up but
over time just
just based on its position we're like
always near this thing so it produces a
lot of the
bones arrows powder and zombie flesh
if i need it extra drops go in there it
all gets sorted
uh they just drop down
through a chamber goes up to a bunch of
spawning pads here this is a system that
uses
cats dogs and villagers and then they go
down and down here there was also like a
way of switching what path they take
we could make them go this way we were
building an arena at one point
but uh never ended up finishing that or
doing anything with it really
if we take a right at this intersection
it leads us to an unfinished room this
is what we called the pixel it's a
another tech project a storage room
system
i invented a way of searching shulker
boxes
to uh find stuff so we had like a menu
where you would choose what item you
were looking for
let's say we're looking for glass this
probably doesn't work anymore
i'm just saying let's see
that did not sound good no i don't think
it works at all anymore okay how about
this we'll watch a
clip from our old world tour when this
thing still worked and
young etho can explain it to you with
the the old microphone
let's say we want some sand select it
from the menu there you throw it into
the hopper
and then it'll check all those uh
shulker boxes for any that have sand in
and they should end up here so that has
sand in
and then if you want to cycle to the
next box you step on the pressure plates
this one also has sand in
another one with sand we got a lot of
sand apparently
and then they end up back in here also
the menu item back
ends up back in here all right well that
was a little weird but thanks etho you
got me out of a jam there
so the recent redstone changes seem to
have broke this thing even
further it's it's like getting stuck and
stuff now
so we might eventually tear this thing
out but the way it worked is it would
take an item out of the shulker boxes
and then match it with the
item from the menu it would put this
into an item filter
and if any items from the shulker box
came out and went into the item filter
it would know
that it was a match and then it would
have to
put that item back in the shulker box
and it does that at another stage and it
was a pretty complicated thing
if we keep going straight here we reach
our underground village
this was a replacement to the emerald
city thing we did
um we built some phony little facade
houses here
this was back when uh villagers worked
in front they had to have
skylight in front of doors to counter as
a valid village
villages don't even exist anymore so
this isn't necessary it's much easier to
do
underground villages now but we built a
bunch of little houses around here
and some weird random contraptions we
had a way of killing the villagers over
here
because he used to get a penalty if you
killed them yourself where
i guess you still do don't you where
trades cost more
there we go turn it on turn it off we
got a school
so the baby villagers used to go in here
they would get separated from the adults
and then when they would grow up i would
decide if they should live or die
they would go on to the good life if
they should live if they have good
trades
if they had garbage trades we would send
them down here and they would go up to
the surface and get killed by zombies at
this end of the village we had a
contraption for
trading zombie flesh with our villagers
which isn't really necessary anymore
um there's a weird guy staring down at
us
i made some weird things in the past i
tell you i don't know what i was
thinking
half the time if we keep going up here
there was a
zombie spawner this used to spawn in
zombie villagers i don't think they do
that anymore
and we would cure them and then we would
send the cured villagers to the village
if we ever needed to repopulate it
and we also got an elevator down here if
we want to get up to the surface we just
hop on the llama llama vader takes us up
activates some tripwires on the way we
hop off and
uh there we go we're out of the man cave
nope not yet
we still got another branch to go down
in the man cave and then we're done with
it
this is a quick one though but man we're
at 50 minutes here
uh we might just need to skip the man
cave in future tours because it takes up
a big chunk of the time
uh so behind this door is a randomizer
for a firework crafting machine we can
refill the ingredients
there um we go down and we can access
the actual room to it over here so this
is the firework factory
i don't know if this still works i
haven't used it in a long time but you
stand underneath here
and i don't know i don't even know if i
remember how it used
to use it yeah it gives you the
ingredients you use those to craft your
fireworks star
like so and it's random and then once
you do that it gives you more stuff
those end up in storage and then you can
use them to
randomly craft a firework with uh random
amounts of stars you can select how many
over
here with this item frame how many
gunpowder you want with this
hit the button i don't know where they
come from i guess over here and it gave
us a random amount of stars and
gunpowder
matched with the what we got set there
nothing in behind there we got uh
elevator and potion lab
wire axis this is just if we need to uh
check anything out or change anything
easy easy to get to the stuff that way
all right let's keep going
got to keep moving so we saw this
already this is above the
ethos lab we ignore that guy
oh actually we can use them check this
out
we put the shutters down and we're
perfectly safe for mobs while we use one
of our mini farms
yeah this mini farm doesn't work anymore
it used to block out the light with the
slab
now it light shines through slabs and i
can't plant the crop
either there was a hopper underneath to
pick up the
the plants when they would pop off and
it was pretty nice but it doesn't work
anymore
let's keep going a little decorative
wheat field there
and we built another mini game over here
this is like a simon says memory game
never got it finished though so let's
just
all right we killed them when the
concrete powder came out we made a way
of uh
switching walls just like a fun goofy
thing
there's a bunch of different patterns oh
man
trying to do it for and cycles through
them but
never fully hooked that up either and
then it is dead dead ends here
all right we finished up with the man
cave guys we can move on and check out
some other stuff in our world some stuff
above the surface now
and uh we're gonna fly through the
secret tunnel behind the waterfall
we made this uh before you could rocket
launch yourself
with the elytra so we had to get the
slope just right to make it through
and uh we used to have a conveyor belt
system here
um there was a thing you could do with
pistons for a long time called the
piston translocation
it was in the game for two years and
they even had some updates in that time
and then they were like oh hey let's
remove this uh
this feature from pistons and it broke
so much stuff in my world
and i had to uh tear out a bunch of
conveyors and elevators and redo them
and stuff
oh it's nighttime there we go that's
better so the tunnel brings us to the
library this is our longest running
unfinished project in the world and i
kind of don't ever want to finish it
just because of that
uh we got an enchanting station with the
anvils and stuff there
and this is part of a book matrix thing
we have a way of storing our enchanted
books and then we can request them
using the buttons aqua affinity let's go
for a punch
and efficiency then they get delivered
to us
right around here there we go
you can use those for enchanting and
stuff which is
great it's a little bit slow though made
that a long time ago
and uh we got grandma wither bottoms up
there
might tear that out still i'm not sure
yeah so at the end of every episode we
do like a q a thing where i pick out a
comment from the previous episode
uh if somebody asks an interesting
question or brings up a good topic
or has a good idea for me i like to
feature it as the comment of the day
and we got those arranged uh every 10
episodes gets a chest
and they're all in order and we got them
all saved unfortunately there was a bug
a long time ago that deleted a lot of
them
um so we lost a lot of information that
way but we
have them also on the other side here
older ones
these are the ones i think that got
deleted
alright so back at the man cave entrance
i guess let's just fly up and give you
an aerial view of what's going on here
so that's the library where we were just
at um it's a little bit
chaotically arranged i would like just
build random things and you know they
wouldn't really match the theme or
anything so they got like snow mixed
with
forest and sand all over the place
doesn't make a lot of sense so uh
doesn't have a lot of cohesion to it but
uh you know it's our world we've gotten
used to it
this is the snowflake when i first
started in the world i kept getting lost
i needed some kind of beacon
back before beacons were in the game so
i
put a giant snowflake in the sky and i
could see it from a long distance and i
stopped getting lost around our base
then
because remember we were living
underground so we had no structures
above here to help locate it either it
was really
really tough eventually we turned this
into an iron farm as well one of the old
school designs
this is in our spawn chunks so
it would run all the time am i gonna die
oh i lived okay
iron golems would fall down here and
then the lava would kill them
which i think i removed
i mean poppy farm yeah it's a poppy farm
not an iron farm
it might be best if we just take a walk
through the swamp actually so let's go
for a little stroll
we've seen this already that's the
project pokemon and emerald city stuff
we planted a few mushrooms here to make
it feel a bit whimsical
um this is i think the true spawn of our
world so we used to have a way of
sending ender pearls here from the end
and they would get stored without us
actually having to go to the overworld
uh that leads to a mine shaft we'll
check that out in a second but let's
just
go through the swamp i'm supposed to uh
plant some trees like uh make it look
like it's connected to the canopy above
i haven't done that yet um but we got
some
mushrooms planted throughout here the
reason i haven't done it you guys i
hate walking through this place i wonder
why
just get swarmed every time i go through
here it's insane
but we got some mushrooms we built a
mushroom house
over here as well
yeah yeah got like a fireplace a little
cozy
cozy decorated bedroom upstairs
all right we made it out of there
there's still a lot of work i want to do
with that we gotta
dress it up make it look nicer but the
goal was to make the swamp film a little
bit more interesting than just the
default so this was our mine shaft one
of our first projects in the world
this goes down we got a bunch of chests
for storage
um this is where that eats road connects
to
from our base and it's a pretty long
tunnel actually
we had like a snowman walking around the
top here that would make the lights
flicker
i don't know if he's still there
probably not i think that's for speed
potions
and healing and then uh
we had a way of converting boats into
planks it used to be a trick you could
do
so you could turn like jungle logs into
oak planks that way
and again kind of like the tree farm at
our base we
dedicated a mine shaft to people that
donated and this is how i used to get
most of my redstone before uh
speed mining was a thing and then we can
ride the rails back once we're done
mining
oh and it still works look at that cool
and then when we wanted to get out we
could enter pearl through the lily pads
oh that also still works oh cool uh-huh
so going back to
the whole using boats for transportation
thing you'll see we got a lot of water
around our base and we actually have
like
probably a good thousand blocks of water
connected together
uh most of that is because i actually
carved out um
the river myself it's like man-made to a
certain extent and we
put trees along the banks so it looks a
bit nicer
could ride our boat through here made a
fake waterfall
there and then it we joined it up to
this
lake where we got the you've been ethod
thing
this is a throwback to the minecraft
days
um it was b-dubs that verbalized the
you've been ethod it's like you've uh
been destroyed or you've been beaten
sort of thing
um and then someone turned it into an
animated gift and i like
made a 3d version of that in my world
here and
it's become like an iconic thing uh near
the you've been ethod we got the diamond
door
oh you guys remember the diamond door i
did a big thing where i teased people
that we were gonna open it and then i
would never open it i did that for so
many episodes
then eventually i opened it and there
was another door behind it and that just
that just got people so bad and then
eventually we did open this and you can
see the reveal for that on episode 404
if you're
curious there's like a special episode
as well
um and then eventually we actually did
put something behind here it's
our redstone room if we want to a
redstone project it's like a safe place
to
work with a nice flat area so at one
point in the series i got this idea that
we're gonna do biome enhancement
um so like the swamp biome we built a
giant canopy over that
and we were trying to add mushrooms and
make it look like its own unique biome
uh same sort of deal with this desert we
had a big giant desert right next to the
man cave
and it was just like a big flat yellow
patch and it's like i
want to make that look good somehow i
don't know how eventually i decided to
build a city next to it which we called
sandy city and it's still a work in
progress
has been for a long time uh
yeah the man cave's just right over here
we got a gate to get into sandy city
and i think let's just test this out
there's a switch that activates if we
got frostwalker on
i think there we go
gate automatically opens up oh we fall
down
and then automatically closes that gets
us entry into the city um
so we had this building here for a very
long time
um wasn't super happy with the way it
looked and it discouraged me from
building more houses here so
this is all we had for a long time it's
not really done either there's no
interiors
to speak of there's a bad
uh but then eventually i decided to
change the style a little bit and we got
the stripped
uh wood in the game as well that made a
huge difference for this area
and then i built a blacksmith building
is a
little bit cooler you know it's got its
own unique style to it
over here is a brewing system auto
brewing for night vision potions
and then the most recent building we
added was this one over here
it's like a got a market stall out in
the front we used to have a villager
there but he died
and then no interior
i'm working on it and just just give me
time guys i've only had nine years
cool cool and uh if you check it out we
got a wall that runs all around the city
which fortifies it
we got three castle gates it is super
protected against mobs no mobs can get
in here during the night time
it is absolutely great and then uh
just outside this one we have a giant
sugarcane farm he's after me
which we used to use a lot to trade with
villagers this was our main source of
paper
and actually still is to this day
can't get me just run along like this to
harvest it
and just outside of sandy city we have
this giant pyramid
with a beacon on top it's not really a
pyramid it's
people keep telling me it's a zebra knot
or something but
uh the main purpose of this was to hide
the mob system we had to build this
above the ground and we had this big
giant
clay cube for a long time looked
horrible
so now we have like this uh crazy
looking
thing instead if we go through the other
gate this direction there's not a lot of
stuff this way but
we do have a weird contraption for
turning uh
yellow sand into orange sand there was a
way of doing that for a while but it's
been patched out of the game now
it's a redstone contraption a little bit
cheaty but not super cheaty
and then it would go down there um
the plan is to maybe eventually expand
out to the mountains that these paths
are for we do have
a couple things built up here we got a
woolly mammoth
woolly mammoth hanging out up here along
with our penguin
and this is one of our main ice farms
for a long time um
a minecart runs underneath the pistons
and it pushes all the ice up
into a giant 10 by 10 by 10 cube of ice
so like a
thousand ice blocks i had to do the math
when uh it's ready for a full harvest
which is pretty cool
and uh there's also one other little
thing here
oh yeah it's still here i don't think
this works now
oh it might be oh there we go
he used to spell out etho on fire but
now the fire doesn't ignite
when it shoots underneath the block
excellent so we're almost done with this
area i think it's worth checking out the
cactus farm here as well
this was a remake of an old old farm i
made
back before i even started youtube i had
like three worlds before the chocolate
island one there
so i've been playing this game for a
long time uh originally this was made a
cobblestone though
and uh the cactus would fall down the
sides here into the streams
below i didn't know you could like block
water with signs at the time so i had to
calculate exact lengths for everything
for the water
make sure there was no dead zones with
it then i had a way of going down
here with pot lights uh to light up the
area
all the water would merge together and
uh
end up over here except without a hopper
i think when
clay got introduced into the game the
terra cotta i got like into a clay
phase i thought it looked amazing so we
built a road
uh that leads up to the library area and
every one of these lamps turn on at
night time they each have it their own
daylight sensor
good stuff let's keep on going here so
back when we started the biome
enhancement project my goal was to fill
up our world a bit more try to get it
looking
a bit nicer and fuller and i took huge
inspiration
from b double o he's uh he's a pretty
good builder he always had these
different areas in his world and he
would connect them together with paths
so i started putting paths in my world
as well
to connect the different areas together
and it just it helps so much
makes it feel more alive like
it's actually a lived-in world you know
um and also it just helps fill up space
and then along the paths we have fences
and uh
b-dubs was always big into making custom
trees so i started making custom trees
as well
got some dark oaks out here uh these are
like custom
like triple acacia trees mixed together
and then changed the wood type out uh
along with the biome enhancement project
we started uh
a giant wheat field over here this used
to be a planes biome
well it still is but now it's like a
little bit more interesting right we got
a dugout
there's a scarecrows in the field with
hay bales there's a tractor
and the big thing here is the windmill
as well
used to have a villager that lived in
there but he died eventually
it's almost like a common theme with
villagers they always seem to die
and from this lake we also have another
river that goes out this way
quite a ways that's a man-made one as
well we blew it out with tnt i think
and uh had to build a bridge over top of
it here in a path that goes up to
the you've been ethod um we line the
banks of the river with some stone like
some cobblestone and leaves to make it
a bit more interesting and uh
there's a launcher here too let's see if
i remember how to do this
oh yeah okay i think we're gonna start
checking out some of our key builds now
probably the most important farm in our
world the one i use the most
is the tree farm over here so we mostly
use this for the two by two spruce trees
the way this works is we grow the trees
in the middle there
we climb up the water elevator and then
we just face down
you can actually instantly break these
if you have a hope now which is awesome
get the pressure plate that launches
some tnt from above
well it doesn't launch it it drops it
at precise distances so it gets as much
wood as possible
without destroying anything and then
there's hoppers underneath all the
carpet here to collect the drops
together in a chest
and i'll probably add some kind of item
sorter here eventually i've also been
using this for the new work trees
if you replace the grounder with nylium
it works pretty good too
further this way is a not so important
this is one of those ones we try to
forget yeah i think it's jammed or
busted or something
the lights used to like slowly turn on
and off it was like a dimmer switch
on this guy it's supposed to be the
dragon
it's not the best looking dragon and
then i use the super bold color scheme
down here and the plan was to like
build a room to house our dragon egg it
was going to be at the end there
and uh let's just say people weren't a
fan of the color scheme and everything
all right everybody another big project
you've probably been waiting for the
nexus up ahead here is finally finished
except for the outside but uh in terms
of uh
complexity and size and definitely a
time spent on a project
this is the one that takes the cake in
our world the nexus has been a very long
ongoing project
and it's just a giant storage room
basically
in the front here we have a hexy decimal
decoder that i designed myself
and sounds fancy basically what that
does is it takes two button presses
a code and turns it into 250 to six
different possibilities
and then we have a menu here for all the
items we store in the system so we can
choose what we want to
pull out of storage like 8d we press 8d
on our keypad 8 and then
d i kind of got it laid out in the order
they are
and then we pull the lever here we
should get some dirts
delivered in the requested items or if
we hit the buttons here we can request i
think between
16 32 a stack or two stacks of items
for whichever one we press and then if
we want to put stuff in the storage room
we drop it off
here and it automatically gets sorted
and we're getting our dirt takes a bit
of time to get delivered that's the main
flaw
with this um and then if we want to
manually go
check out the storage room and and see
things we can go this way
this is where everything is actually
stored um
it's basically in sets of four oh
there's some saplings over here and
there's an upstairs to it we take the
water elevator to go up to the second
layer there's also two sides to it so
it's
absolutely massive like just a huge huge
project of course we built it on quartz
because why wouldn't we right let's make
it the cheapest thing in the world
and you can see the redstone from the
hexi decimal decoder it's a
a bit complicated let's go a game mode
spectator maybe for a second here
just get a full full idea of what we got
going on here
so yeah the wire branch is 256 different
ways
there's a whole bunch of stuff
and then we got water streams that run
throughout the whole thing here these
are to put the items into the item
filters and sort things for us
um they also uh take items out of the
system and deliver them to us when we
request an item
right across from the nexus is another
one of our super important builds this
is our super smelter
the goal with this was to try see how
quickly we could actually smelt things
so we have
uh something that takes items out at
eight times hopper speed there
gets delivered to eight different mine
carts
those delivered to the furnaces i think
it's 128 furnaces or 256 i can't
remember
they spelt them spelting always takes 10
seconds though there's no way to avoid
that
and then it gets delivered here pretty
quickly
at three times hopper speed basically
and as you can imagine a smelting system
like that takes quite a bit of fuel and
that comes from our bamboozler
flip the switch and it uses bone meal to
grow bamboo we got
four different bamboozlers hooked up
together
this is like a bamboo farm i made myself
um
if the trap door is open it goes down
and gets delivered automatically to all
the furnaces in the super smelter
and we can also just manually fight it
here if we need to take it somewhere
else this is the ray that
gets created causes a lot of lag though
also in this area we got started on
another new city where we're gonna build
this is a more modern style one
uh supposed to house villagers and stuff
but i haven't got too far with it
but i got a lot of praise for the design
of it and the color scheme and
everything so we might continue on with
this people seem to like it
but it needs a lot of work obviously
i'm not super big on building but you
know i do it every once in a while it's
a good change of pace got another one of
these indie brewing
stations for night vision and there's a
system here for
getting items we can choose between
rockets ender pearls food
scaffolding torches bones wood stone
uh we choose our thing and then
let's go for rockets sure and then we
choose how many we want with this book
roughly hey hit the button and we should
get about 25 rockets
yeah i'm not too sure this might have
broke from the redstone update because i
can't get it to work now
i have a bit of a problem in this series
where i love making mini games and i get
them about 80
finished or so and then i just kind of
stop working on them
usually because you guys are so bored of
the redstone at that point it's
it's hard to continue and make it
interesting but
uh this is mastermind recreated in
minecraft it's close to finished
not quite it's a guessing game basically
we had to create
a bit of an ai for it because it's
actually a two-player game
so our redstone handles the second
player that generates a code
secretly from us we have to try guess
that code
we use shulker boxes to do that which
have concrete powder inside
that gets shot out and then we enter
a yes over here uh we stack
stack it up on the pistons we use
different colored concrete as
the colored pegs in the game there's six
different colors you play with
and then when you enter your answer you
jump
one set of concrete goes down below and
gets converted to item form and then it
gets matched with the
the secret code there to see what
matches and what doesn't
and then the result gets displayed on
the side panels here
this one never got finished and yeah
it's kind of hard to explain it but
it's it's a pretty cool game if we ever
get it finished aha
so also in this area we have another
pretty major farm it's a dual farm
so this main area in the center is for
pumpkins
they grow and then they automatically
get harvested when they
grow underneath the block there gets
detected and a piston
breaks them they all get delivered down
in the chests here
and then we can use those for trading
with villagers if we want
but also we got the brown mushroom farm
on the side that goes all around this
and the way this works is there's
actually
um can we see them there's mushrooms
beside that
in the dark four of them so we'll
automatically grow a mushroom here over
time
we don't have to plant it ourself and
then you hit the
button to grow
that dispenses bone meal to all the
mushrooms it goes all the way around
and then we harvest it with our axe
running along here an instant break with
efficiency
and then after we harvest it all we
press that and water comes down and
pushes all the blocks to the middle
next to our big giant wheat field we
have a village that generated in a
plains biome this was an original
testificat village
when they did nothing in the game we
tried to protect them for so long we
built fences around the area we put
lamps in there to keep it nice and
bright spammed the torches
and they survived in here for a very
long time but i think they all
officially died now
uh we also upgraded their farms they're
all automated like that um
we did a weird thing over here there's a
nether portal actually i never use this
thing anymore i
i should like it still works perfectly
fine
there's a way of getting to the nether
here though i used to transport them
through there
and uh let's see oh
that's where they are
okay maybe they are still alive never
mind i built a beacon there and then i
emptied
out the iron and i guess that's where
they ended up
aha cool well that makes me happy
and then uh right between the wheat
field and the village we built a path
that
it's kind of decorative we made a fake
lake here with some
plants all around it a plant monster
over there
and then uh we got a cool walk through
the trees we got some hanging lamps
these are all well i guess they're not
really custom trees i think we just
added some
logs at the bottom and then it goes down
to
our course fruit farm this is for
farming up perper in our world
we smash the button up there
with a bow or something it shoots arrows
at the top those land and hit the seeds
which pop
off so that we have enough to replant
this when we harvest it we hit one of
these buttons
that sends out water to harvest whatever
is left
to create the coarse fruit it all gets
washed down into a middle channel here
and it's incredibly laggy
then the seeds get sorted out and end up
in this chest so we can replant
water automatically goes away on its own
too
we have a bit of a path here with some
extra tall acacia trees give us some
cover from the sun
and then this leads over to the
blacksmith building
which is where the perper actually gets
smelted it runs down a
water channel underground and uh i don't
think there's an interior for this
building
nope of course not you know i should
make that my goal in the future here
i'm going to try to finish up some of
this stuff but yeah that chorus fruit
ends up in the furnaces and then
it smelts and we can make purple out of
the
fruit just like so
awesome so we are just about done with
the main area we just got a couple more
builds and then we're going to head off
to the nether and
check out some of our farther away stuff
so first off the guardian farm
we've been working on this more recently
but originally we built this guardian
farm
in 1.8 when guardians came out uh it
just so happens my world
there was a guardian farm underground
here because
a little hard to explain but my world
was generated before jungles were even
in the game and once i think they added
jungles they changed
how seeds generates like the which
biomes go where
so if you generate my world now with the
same seed
this is actually ocean where we're
standing and there's a guardian farm
right in this area so if i mined out the
ground
and put water there with spawn guardians
and that's what we did
and uh recently we added a mural telling
the story about the elder guardian we
put on top the windmill
got a mini guardian temple there we
transported the elder guardian through
the nether and stashed him on top the
windmill
where he later despawned for reasons we
don't know
aha so uh if we go down over here this
is where the actual killing
chamber and storage is for it all down
and here they are they're constantly
getting burnt
stuff automatically gets sorted into the
chest
as you would expect and then
cook stuff there when i craft stuff i
store it over here
um and then there's a manual
kill mode i think that gets rid of lava
and there's also a way of sending them
to the nether
yeah let's go check out the nether thing
actually so when we hit that
switch to go to the nether it makes a
water bucket come out here
and pistons extend so they can't go down
anymore and they just funnel through the
nether portal
let's go creative
let's go back to the spectator oh
snappers
they end up in this uh chamber here
where we used to kill them with instant
damage potions and stuff
uh now that mob cramming's a thing in
the game we can't store like
200 300 here like we used to
so it's not really used anymore
and something we worked on just last
episode actually is a new version of the
ender porter which is a system for
teleporting large distances in your
world
you can store ender pearls on bubble
columns now very easily
and then you use redstone to trigger
another one of these
at another area in your world that you
want to teleport to so if you look at
our coordinates we're at minus 240
700 we hit the button that triggers the
ender pearl
at our other base location here at our
stronghold
and now we're at minus 470 and 850 so we
traveled a long distance there
we set up another end of pearl for next
time we want to teleport
we can go back if we want to the temple
and let's go to the stronghold actually
because that's probably what we want to
see next
oh man we got so much stuff left to see
i thought we could do this tour in an
hour and a half but i know it's not
going to happen now
so at the stronghold base we've made
many attempts at starting new bases in
our world
we have a giant mob system here this is
an old-school version they kind of get
trapped in here now
it's not super good there's also a
lighting system with this so we can turn
it on and off
we go flip this lever all the lights
turn on
oh i think we gotta do it to all the
torches actually
oh yeah it's not even controlled all
together
why didn't i put them all together uh oh
let's go spectator so yeah all the
lights are on here so they should stop
spawning
but otherwise they fall down into an
area here we have a mob
sorting system oh i think it does
actually work it's just messed up look
at the pistons
we got an arm out and the arms over
there i think we got to replace it for
some reason
i don't know why they broke or when
oh let's get that one back there so if
we do that then
creepers get stored to the left zombies
over there the baby guys
and then uh skeletons get one way
i think as we we uh squeezed them it
through too quickly there that got
messed up a bit
but uh there's also a system here for
making the skeletons shoot the creepers
and then they would
explode wherever we wanted them to down
over here somewhere
and uh there's also
a chamber here they used to land down
like creepers
zombies and skeletons would get
separated there uh the plan was to make
a base location over here
after the man cave long long time ago i
have a bad habit of not following
through with my
secondary bases though because we got so
much stuff at the man cave it's hard to
leave it behind
but yeah the plan with this was to build
our base above uh
end portal and silverfish farm we made a
silverfish farm by
detecting when they entered the blocks
and then we would generate new stone
blocks at a
stone generator over here with lava
above uh
then the silver fish blocks would get
funneled down a chain and stacked
together into a big block
and this was a way of storing xp back
before it was possible
there was exactly enough silverfish
blocks here to get you to 50 levels i
believe
and do one enchantment so the idea was
to keep this constantly running while we
worked on our base uh we gotta go
survival
and then when we were ready we would
harvest it and i think we used to have
like snow golems and
all kinds of stuff to get these guys out
of the blocks and then we started using
poison potions
and it creates like a runaway chain
effect where they all hatch
at once
oh my goodness i missed doing that it
was so cool oh there was one stone block
we also had ways of like sending them
through the nether to go do mining it's
at locations there's like an a portal
system here
this is a whole bunch of crazy wacky
stuff that
didn't make any sense oh i don't know
what that does oh that lets them free
and there was also a tunnel that we
would transport them through
um they would walk on one side we would
be on the other side of glass
and we also got a couple other random
builds nearby the stronghold
base that's probably worth mentioning
the ice tray this was like the original
ice farm
uh eventually this biome changed so
water doesn't freeze here anymore
but we had a whole system for like
seeding the ice blocks
pistons would go down or up we would put
them down when we wanted the
water buckets dispensed and that would
fill the area with water and then we'd
put the blocks up so it would freeze
faster
and then down when we wanted to harvest
the ice nearby here we also got the
zombie purifier
[Music]
we made a whole giant contraption here
for turning
zombie villagers into villagers there
was a zombie spawner back there uh
used to be able to get zombie villagers
from spawners he can't anymore as far as
i know
um and then we had a lighting switch to
turn it on and off
and then there was a junction if we
wanted to send
the zombie villagers to the curing
stations they would land down here
otherwise they would go to
a killing spot here for the regular
zombies okay i think i gotta figure it
out so
it only works if there's a zombie
villager in here it turns on some lights
and the tripwire gets activated
and then when we hit the medicine button
oh that was really flu only the ones
that have the zombies in will have the
weakness potions dispensed
otherwise it doesn't waste them and i
think there's also
oh yeah and then when they would get
cured that would get them out of the
station with this button
and then there's a furnace minecart to
get them through the portal
and uh coal here in case you need it
some extra apples
for curing them man there's a bunch of
stuff out here i kind of forgot about we
don't really go in this area anymore but
this used to be our sand farm then we
used to fight a bunch of withers out
here
we got our silverfish pit with a bunch
of silverfish stored up and
we also built a 360 cannon out here i
totally forgot about
this was a tribute to my olden days back
before i was even on youtube
back before minecraft i was on a server
for like pvp before survival minecraft
was even possible on servers
a bunch of people like were big into
making cannons there
and i designed a 360 cannon uh that i
was pretty proud of
did blow up no it didn't blow up i don't
know how it works anymore though
this is like a remake of it it's a
little bit fancier than the old one
oh i remember how it works okay i think
we gotta choose where we wanna shoot by
throwing the tnt
in the hoppers here again this is a
remake so
the original one was not this fancy
and then it'll they'll use those as the
ammo
there we go
did it blow up it blew up expected no
less
i think we finally covered everything in
the main area we can start heading to
the nether
we skipped over the crimson wood and
worked wood farm here we just built this
recently
it's a red stoneless version excellent
so let's head back to sandy city
there's a secret nether portal down here
land on the pressure plate it pushes us
into the portal
then it closes behind us and we're
finally
into the nether our nether hub is right
over here
oh i love this place so uh we got four
main branches
tunnels that go up four different
directions here to all our important
builds this one
is mostly just for farming we got a sand
farm
and ice farm down this way nothing else
really so we
probably won't end up going there uh-huh
so something we just did recently
actually is we mapped out our nether and
marked a lot of the key locations with
banners
we're gonna be checking out some of
these in just a second you'll notice a
lot of our nether portals have
buttons on these are for lighting and
shutting off portals and some of them
will light it and then shut it off
after we go through um this is part of
the
portal network which doesn't work
anymore but we used to have codes
to go into different locations uh we
would set the code by the delay on the
repeaters
and then it would break all the portals
that aren't that code and then it would
light the only one that was
i'm trying to think of the best way to
explain this but basically if a portal
wasn't
available if it wasn't lit it would
search up to 128 blocks
in the nether for another one that was
so you could control which one you
wanted to go to that way
and basically get a free thousand block
uh teleport from the overworld to the
nether and then you go through
the different nether portal you ended up
at and it was all linked together with
two-way repeaters and there was a
decoding system to figure out which
portal he would go to based on the
repeater strength
and uh yeah anyways let's uh check out
some other stuff that's a little easier
to understand we got a light show that
goes around here
we also got the decotonizer 9000 at the
hub here so
i was very stubborn about building an
iron farm and i was wasting a lot of
iron on buckets so
we made a way to buy them
it would empty the car out of the
buckets and then they end up in here
no over here yeah and we also have a
horse swapping station we could choose
between a mule or a fast horse for going
down our nether tunnels
if we wanted to transport stuff we would
pick the mule but uh
the game has changed quite a bit since
then we got shocker boxes and
ice roads and all kinds of better ways
of getting around now
and moving things uh we got blue ice
running down the center of our roads
here so we can get around very
quickly now and i'm thinking we'll want
to skip a lot of the
transport time down the nether just to
save episode time
because it's getting super long but we
got about 10 000 blocks of nether
tunnels i think at this point is pretty
insane
uh this is slab city guys this was
another attempt at making a new base
the restriction for this one is we had
to build using
nine by four chunks of building
materials
and it was a cool thought but
at the same time it also made it
extremely difficult to decorate
so i struggled a lot with this and i
don't know if we're going to continue it
or not
i'll see what you guys say about it but
i found it really hard to make it look
good because um by nature we have to
keep the walls flat
and if you want to make things look good
in minecraft it can't be flat
because then you don't get the shadows
and stuff unless you're using
shaders it's a different story we had a
concrete maker over here just a simple
one where we could uh turn the dust
into uh solid concrete we had a minecart
storage system here as well so let's say
we were looking for a block like pink
concrete i don't know if that'll show up
oh yeah there's some in there we also
had a tree farm system
so we would get our saplings
is it automated oh it tried tried to
grow it
what about this one moving on the next
stop in our
nether journey is the amplified base
guys
so at one point in the series when
amplified terrain became a possibility
we did update our world that was one
like uh outside of the game adjustment
we made to our world
so now we get amplified terrain when we
explore further out
and we tried to make this place
work a bit but uh
it became just a big mess basically um
there's a clock over here that would
sync itself to
the proper time i don't think we ever
finished that
um let's see the idea was to use like a
bunch of slime launchers to get around
this place and then slime blocks kind of
broke for a few years well we had a
bunch of slime
launchers for getting up the mountains
and stuff these work now though which is
kind of cool they were broken for a long
time um
let's see here we had oh i forgot about
that that's like a tree farm
this is a cool thing though we had a way
of moving
a bunch of mine carts like a storage
system made out of storage mine carts
we hit the button and it would
automatically move to the next station
in our amplified base area
i think the next one on the list is over
here
they should end up over here if it still
works yep here they come and
everything goes in the exact same order
which is pretty cool and then there's
one more station after this and then
they end up back at the first one there
we had some kind of weird chicken farm
here too they would like get
shot out and fall down a big hole here
and this area is a flower forest so at
the very top of the hill we actually had
a flower farm
which uh i don't think works very well
it's okay it's okay it's just uh
not the best we'd have to manually plant
them next stop down our nether tunnel is
the mesa mining zone
we had a way of uh sending out storage
mine carts to where we would do our
mining
we would send as many as we wanted and
then we would hop on ourselves
and go there uh most of this is uh
kind of mined out we use shocker boxes
nowadays for moving stuff so that's all
kind of pointless
but when we would return the storage
minecarts full of the clay it would go
up into
a sorting system and it would all
organize according to its color
in the chess so white would go in here
and light gray in here that sort of
thing
uh also in this area is drearyville up
these stairs
let's head over there and do the special
and you know i think we're gonna change
it up this time just for a bit of
variety because we've seen this uh
show several times at this point we've
never seen it with shaders on before
so this is drearyville it's a
little village up in the mountain a
mining village uh this is our
disgruntled villager
this is where the tunnel leads up to and
we hit the button
that says do not press off he goes into
his little hideaway and i think most of
you know what's gonna happen now
oh you can see the light through the
wall
holy smokes
he uh hops on his flame thrower and he
just
burns the world down guys
the whole village is going up in flames
we built the entire thing out of wood so
it would be
totally flammable there's coal blocks in
here
we got the minecart that goes up to the
whole deposit up there and
we've got random tnt hidden all over the
place so it's like constantly blowing up
under trees and i just love this thing
i always have i always get a kick out of
uh watching this
the power about the power behind that
flamethrower is insane
that's the big finale to the whole show
and moving on again the next stop down
our nether hub is our
giant ice farm we just go down here
with our silk touch the water kind of
collects it together
yeah we just kind of keep going along
here and then we get to the edge and
then the piston thing launches us
forward and then we
press left on our keyboard and we start
going the other way
all the water channels merge together
and then they go up a bubble elevator
and into the storage over here and don't
forget about
the crimson keep this is a newer project
we've been working on since the nether
update came out
uh the general idea is to take a bastion
and turn it into a fancy bastion
so we've uh got some basics down here
we're switching out the ground with
nylium
building bridges acacia trap doors for
railing
and the big thing we got built at the
moment is a
piglen bartering system so we put the
golden up here
and then it gets delivered to 12
different uh
piglens and then uh runs through a bunch
of item filters at four times
hopper speed and we can get a lot of
items very quickly if we got the gold
which we generally don't have yet but
yeah all the items we get from the
piglens get automatically sorted into
the chests according to where they
belong
which is pretty nice cool so that's
another branch done
in our nether hub now we're back here i
want to go in spectator mode and just
show you what we got going on in the
area
so up above our nether hub is a gold
farm
that kind of got abandoned this was our
first attempt at it
and then we rebuilt another one above
that
which still kind of functions this is
what we call gold farm number one
nowadays and the way this works is a
zombie pigman spawns
it gets pushed off by the pistons
there's some trip wires
um there's a lot of spawning space here
actually
and they get pushed down into these
nether portals all over the place
and then over at this end we have some
buttons for controlling that
that one's for lighting it usually we
keep these off because otherwise it
causes a lot of lag
when they go through we can break them
with that button
and there's also a giant cage all around
this thing to stop
gas from blowing it up and then when the
zombie piglens go through the portals
they end up over here in the overworld
so this is the portal they would come
through they fall down then there's a
crushing system to get them down to a
one-hit
kill we throw instant damage potions at
them and we get all their xp
and then there was a bunch of
hoppers below that goes to a sorting
system i think up a dropper elevator
over here and then all the drops get
organized in the chest
and we got a villager here for trading
if we want to
um zombie flesh in there chicken junk
and
extra garbage in that one and uh overall
this is kind of a nice little build i
like the way it looks
there's a path here for getting to the
library and for sending enchanted
books there was a zipper elevator
those don't work anymore then if we go a
little bit above this gold farm on top
of our roof
there's another gold farm up there we
got a basalt generator
we have a shulker box loading system for
putting the
drops from the pigmen into shulker boxes
so those get broken automatically and
put down in the chest below
when they're full up above that though
at the very top of our nether
this is the spawning spaces for our
zombie pigmen
we added some soul torches to scare the
piglens off and they fall down
and then the pigmen try to get to us
they fall down these chambers
on all four sides and then there's some
piston pushing systems
to get their drops where'd that gas come
from
i think you spawned on the basalt
actually um
it gets all the drops together in the
middle here and the xp gets launched up
a system to us at the top there as we
afk
and then all the items go down
these chambers here to the shocker box
loaders
yeah look at this oh my goodness
yeah they uh they want to spawn here for
sure you know i think we might be
getting a little closer to the finish
now
i can kind of see the finish line in
sights my voice is really starting to
give out though this has been torture
two hours of an episode never again
we'll probably do it in the next tour
again okay so this is our dual blaze
farm this has
this was a key build in our world one of
our main xp farms for a long time
because blazes give 10 xp per kill
unlike most mobs that only give five
so they get gathered together um
down these two cones and then picked up
by some mine carts at the bottom there
they get brought up and then they ram
into a cactus at the top there and if
they fall down the chamber
oh there goes the guy oh yeah and the
pistons squeeze them together and down
the middle
they land on a iron pressure plate and
as more of them accumulate
more and more lights turn on and it used
to be one that would get the five lights
we would get
uh 30 levels or something when we'd kill
them all
but now the mob cramming prevents that
from happening
um we kill them there's a minecart
hopper minecart below that picks up the
drops and they go down to a system we
just built recently
down over here and as well we got a
potion lab down here
there was a way of extracting water from
sponges
just uh we gotta build here for doing
that i'm not gonna demonstrate it though
we're low on time
but we could uh put wet sponges in a
furnace and then it would
extract the water all right and then
further down this tunnel
any of you that have played castle
crashers might recognize the frog there
and this ends up at a nether fortress
this is where we farm wither skeletons
we got the whole area slabbed
there's a portal here this takes us over
to
our gas blaster 3000 another uh
tree farm design we did this one's
pretty special though
because you get attacked when you go
through he's gonna burn everything down
no we got him yeah we got a gas trapped
in the over worlds
oh man then when we stand here
it would open up the trap door
the gas can shoot at us and the water
pushes the ball
down so it would explode on the wood
above the hoppers and it would collect
the wood without losing any
oh i think i figured it out actually so
we stand on the pressure plates the gas
shoots at us he can't hit us because of
the water and then we hold right click
with our saplings
grows the tree and it glitches out
uh-huh i think it's safe to say that
one's broken at the moment
if we follow the beacons up here we
punched a hole through the ceiling so we
can get on top the roof
and this is where we have another gold
farm
iron farm slash villager trading system
and gas farm everything all in one and
it works while we are farming wither
skeletons below that we'll still get
iron
which is pretty neat um villagers are
sleeping right now but
every so often it will spawn in some
iron golems on the platform
oh yeah it kind of worked at the moment
you got to spend a bit of time here
for it to get fully ramped up they fall
down they try to
hit the zombie pigmen in the middle
there but they fall down
and then the horde kills them below and
then there's a minecraft that runs
underneath that to pick up all the drops
with a filter system the minecart gets
one of each of these
as it begins its journey and then
passes underneath the grounds
through a big maze of rails and then
collects all the drops above
delivers them to a sorting system down
below
and then we can pick up our goodies over
here moving on once again the final
branch of our nether hub has
three main builds we could check out
first off is the witch farm
it's uh definitely in need of more work
still it's not very decorated
but the witches spawn up above they fall
down
land on the hoppers die and all their
drops get collected together over here
um i've actually had a big problem in my
world with finding witch farms
let's see we got the area pretty lit up
which is good
because we started the world so early it
was before which farms were a thing
and then we switched to amplified so
it's like impossible to
find a flat area to actually build one
without having to remove giant mountains
and stuff or light them
up but yeah they spawn over here and
then the shifting floors drop them down
below
uh this is good for the most part but a
little bit of the mountains are within
range of
where we stand so it's not the most
efficient farm and it's only a single
farm and i find there's much better ways
of getting redstone actually
so i don't use it too often at the very
end of this very long nether tunnel we
have the
underwater base guys yet again another
one of our
unfinished bases this is the one i'm
most likely to return to though
i think it has the most potential we did
a couple wacky builds here we have an
underwater
tree farm it definitely takes a bit of
time
oh there it goes okay so it does grow so
on the retraction of the blocks it
leaves a little air pocket for a brief
moment and in that moment we have to try
grow the tree
uh if we step here it removes the oak
block in the way
and then there's a dispenser here for
more saplings
and i guess it grows leaves under water
now that's a new thing
it used to just leave the wood we got a
sea pickle farm over here i don't think
i want to demonstrate that though i
don't think it works too well
we have an underwater enchanting station
same kind of gimmick we have to
activate the enchanting at the exact
moment
the bookshelves retract
oh there we go yeah we right click the
note block they extend and then they
retract
leave some air pockets behind so we can
get to level 30 that way
otherwise the water blocks them we also
got a hostile mob system in this area
that's mostly to stop drown mobs from
spawning and attacking us if
we got the regular guys spawning it cuts
down on the mob
cap they spawn on the platforms and then
they move
into a water elevator here
which is a pretty good design actually
they
get flown up a bubble elevator to the
top they fall down
at the end here and land over here
and there's also a way of switching it
i think that makes some pistons extend
and then they end up over here and we
can manually kill them if we want to
i guess there's a light system for the
farm i don't know what that's about i
think there is actually
oh yeah check it out we got lamps above
the spawning pads so
when those are on it's too bright for
them to spawn on the platforms and then
we'll start getting a bunch of
drowned guys spawning in the water
around us and the final build to check
out through our nether hub
is the pillager outpost so this was one
of those pillager structures we
bulldozed
and we made a farm out of it just for
the the funds of it
i actually had plans on uh making this
into a raid farm there used to be a way
of spawning
multiple raids at the same time and then
that kind of got patched out of the game
so now
it's kind of just a gimmicky goofy farm
iron golems in the middle to attract the
pillagers into these bubble
elevators they go up and then
fall down in the middle here and it
actually works pretty good as a
xp farm and if for some reason what you
want to
farm crossbows this is a way to do it
too
yeah that goes down into a system here
for
separating the junk i think we just
press q
oh and it doesn't land in the lava it
lands on the ledge i forgot about that
i was supposed to fix that well this is
it everybody we've seen everything in
the main world
and also everything connected through
the nether hub this
tunnel goes from the man cave to the
stronghold base and this is how we get
to
the end we save the end for the end
so there's three main things to check
out here
first off is the ender ender
1.0 this was the original enderman farm
uh if you don't know the history behind
this this is pretty key to
current endermen farms that exist today
i had the idea of building an enderman
farm off away from the main island
in the past people used to flood those
and light them up and
uh it never really worked out too well
so i built one way off from the island
and uh i made a spawning
pad system up above here just the
standard flat
they spawn on the pressure plates and
get pushed down sort of thing
get down to a one hit kill we brought a
horse over here we could ride around to
punch him to death and uh
it's kind of funny i think it was during
one of my episodes i was here like
looking at the guys and
farming them up as like you know i
originally just made this for collecting
ender pearls
and i was like wait a minute i'm getting
tons of xp doing this and uh
kind of realize this is one of the best
ways of making an xp farm in the game
again this was back when you needed 50
levels and all that kind of stuff
then eventually we outgrew that one and
we started the second enderman farm
out over this one this one's much more
refined we used the
vine trick that the zip crowd figured
out for stacking multiple
platforms together and yeah i remember
building this thing i think i stayed up
to
like 6 a.m that night took like over 10
hours or something crazy
this thing's huge lots and lots of
layers to it
the gimmick with this one though is i
figured out uh we could use tnt
and flame bows to farm them all at once
instead of using our sword
although i guess you can't uh do that
anymore can you
oh the water puts the flame bow out now
it didn't used to
it would shoot through it
although this is gonna be hard to
demonstrate i guess this is broken now
we gotta shoot that and then put the
water back otherwise it'll blow up the
farm
but yeah that's what it would do would
blow up all the enderman we get all the
xp still
and if we stood here all the xp orbs
would slowly flow towards us
and we got the enchanting station with
the cinderman farm we also had a system
for moving ender pearls through these
water streams that would go up to the
main island
and then that would go through the ender
portal
back to the overworld in that uh true
spawn thing we saw earlier in the
episode
so we can automatically store ender
pearls that way
off this direction is the ender ender
3.0 this is the one we currently use
and still works pretty good although
generally if you're building an enderman
farm it's better to build it lower in
the world so you get better spawn rates
but uh yeah we got like a pixel arts
design here
endermen looking ready to fight the
dragon
they're mortal enemies um giant spawning
pad here for the endermen they get
attracted to an
endermites in a minecart and then they
fall down
over here oh
and when there's enderman here there's a
music fox thing that plays
kind of loud uh we can stand here
sweeping edge um you can collect xp
faster than
we can absorb it with this farm so it's
pretty much maxed out as it is
but yeah there's a music randomizer
below this that
constantly plays and generates random
notes
and i think that's about all there is to
it so let's wrap up the episode
here man that was a long tour wasn't it
well it feels like i swallowed some
thumbtacks my voice is
absolutely shot at this point but i
think we did it i think we covered
all the important stuff obviously we
skipped over a few things
but i think we got all the key builds so
let's head over to our fireworks uh
shack here
and pull the lever as we usually do to
finish up these specials
we got a bunch of fireworks hidden in
the lake
uh they don't work anymore
[Music]
oh you know why i think the dispensers
are facing
sideways and now uh
they shoot sideways instead of going up
[Music]
so all the fireworks are exploding
underground
right that's that's a little different
this time um
and obviously we're going to be deleting
this world after we're done with this
tour
this is a backup like i said before uh
this is not our real
let's play world i checked it out and
yep that's what the problem was they're
facing sideways so
let's just end it in the man cave i
think this is a fitting end for the
episode and we're gonna do a reverse
comment of the day today
to save my voice a little bit it says
what is your favorite
build in the let's play world and i'm
the one asking the question this time
so let me know in the comments of all
the stuff we checked out today guys what
was your favorite thing we've done so
far
i'm curious um and uh yeah i think we're
gonna wrap it up here
so thank you guys very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed this tour hopefully
it wasn't too too long
even though it was and i really
appreciate you guys still watching the
series you know we're still doing pretty
good the views are still
much like they were many years ago so
yeah there's definitely still interest
with uh what we've been doing and
uh got big plans going forward here so i
hope you guys
enjoy that as well but i really
appreciate it
with uh you guys sticking around still
it's funny i look at my
demographics and it's like i used to get
of my viewers were under the age of 18
and now it's like five percent
and all you guys have grown up and
you're like in your 20s and 30s now
and you're still watching the series i
think a lot of you so it's it's pretty
cool
you're kind of aging with me and the
series so
yeah thanks for sticking with me all
this time um
and if anyone's new like thank you for
joining me too
so that's it thanks for watching guys
have yourselves a great day
take care bye bye