ah yeah hello everybody this is Keith oh
and welcome back once again to another
episode of our let's play series how you
doing today things are good here thank
you for joining me today guys for this
special occasion today is our 500th
episode we made it we did it guys the
big 500 whoa is finally here and what
the journey it's been right I distract
it's actually been over seven years
since we started this series and the
game has changed a lot since then I've
changed maybe a little bit too in at
least the videos have but all in all
this series has remained the same since
the beginning it's all about playing
vanilla minecraft enjoying the game for
what it is and trying to be creative
with it mostly with redstone and
technical things but we do a little bit
building and stuff too
and the goal for today is the world tour
every 50 episodes we try to do a world
tour now we're gonna go around check out
some of our old projects it's a good
episode for any new viewers like maybe
hey I've heard of this etho guy what's
this all about well today we'll check
out some of the builds and if you like
what you see maybe go back 50 episodes
start watching from there and if you
still really like the series go back to
the beginning I command you
watch him off no any a longtime viewers
though today's gonna be a bit nostalgic
for us because we're gonna see some of
our old builds that maybe you remember I
haven't seen in a long time and I'll try
to give you as much detail as I can as
we go through some of the stuff here but
let's get to it here guys we got a lot
of stuff to see today I'll probably be
talking a little bit quicker than normal
just so we can get through this a little
bit faster I think our last world tour
was over an hour and a half and we've
built more stuff since then so it's
gonna be a real challenge got to be
quick and concise is the plan so just a
little brief history we started this
world back in episode 105 we had another
world before that but we had to abandon
it due to updates when The Hunger team
outs we started here
and it was during the 1.9 pre-release
just just around the time nether
fortresses were introduced in the game
before potions before enchantments and
stuff an idea was to I had an idea for
the base when we first started was to
find a cave system and try not to alter
the shape of the cave too much just kind
of go with the flow of it and add little
contraptions through outs and that's
what we have here this is a man cave
guys this is our main base probably my
favorite thing I've built in this game
to this date and it was pretty unique at
the time because like there wasn't silk
touching the game so to get grass down
here we actually had to like grow it
from the surface all the way down it is
not something people usually did in the
game and I also took inspiration from
the old 404 challenge which was a map
where you didn't use torches you had to
light up the cave as you went along
using lava so when I built this I had
the idea of using hidden lighting
throughout the whole thing so we got
hidden glowstone under bushes and
wherever I could sneak it in you know
got some over here because I really hate
the wait torches look in this game when
it's just like on the ground and stuff
and I really like the look of it without
the torches so I think we did good with
that anyways this is the entrance to the
man cave we have some decoration and
stuff try to like have lots of splitting
paths throughout the build as well over
here is our ender pearl dispenser
machine step here get ender pearls nice
and simple this is a world backup by the
way this is where you load them in so
we're free to destroy stuff and like
check out how it actually works on the
inside if we want this little little
thing here then over here is our pop-up
sheep farm which should be working I
think what we do is go over here when we
want shears or we can hit this to get
them and basically you run through you
shear the sheep and then you have the
option of manually
putting them down with these buttons I'm
like trying to think how this works as
we go and then there's these like open
open areas here with pressure plates
when the wolf falls down it it'll
automatically trigger the Sheep to go
down if there's wool here so if we press
the button let's see if this works still
a little bit broken but it's fine you
see the water pushes the wool down and
when it hit triggers at pressure plates
then that sheep Goes Down and then
there's bud switches detecting when it
eats the grass and when the wool is
fully regrown it pops back up so it's
it's kind of a cool little thing and
actually let's go ahead we don't usually
do this in the world tours but I think
we'll go into spectator mode a little
bit today too that way we can see how it
works there is a path yeah so although
all the wool goes down the stream here
let's follow it
up to here then there's like an elevator
system to bring it up over to here pops
up into this chest let's go back to
normal and ends up in here and then I
just take it out and put it into into
here and there's also a button here for
manually putting all the sheep down
after you share them all it has a cool
effect as you watch all the whites
whites lights go off like that - I like
that I've got a little hidden crafting
table thing here
our ender chest and anvil combo didn't
under the water there this was our first
main storage room and it's it's still
the one I use a lot because it has like
a little bit of everything in the chest
which is nice and very convenient to
find stuff organized by category here
which works out pretty good then over
here is our furnace smelting room let's
see do we have anything ice melt to try
this anything at all netherrack there we
go okay here we go here we go guys so we
throw it in the furnace here light comes
on it makes a little bean bong sound -
each one is tuned a little bit
differently
and there's also some master lights here
so if any of the furnaces are on this
light turns on if they're all often then
they turn off
we got like little wire access back here
for both the storage room and the
furnace room now if there's one thing I
should know about me is I love my arches
and I love my bridges so the man team is
chock-full of them here we got like a
little secret waterfall thing here that
we added when the light ray wings came
out this is supposed to lead up to a
library build we have but unfortunately
in this area is not finished by the way
the piston trick doesn't work anymore
before this would transport us through
and take us up to the library but now
it's broken and that needs to be fixed
okay so we're back up here again and
this is something a little bit subtle
but throughout the man cave we have
little signals to indicate whether it's
day or night time so for example these
lights turn on during the day and
they're off during night time we have
clocks on the wall everywhere and also
my in the ground no we're fine oh it
just turned night time
[Music]
that's our our nighttime lullaby and
then we have a daytime one too so if we
go a little bit further here this is the
main room in the man cave but like the
main intersection where all the paths
lead up to and this goes back up to
where we were little contraptions
throughout the whole base here this is
one of the first things we built in the
world it's a stupid little mushroom farm
that gives you like three of each
mushrooms after a long long time there's
some mushrooms hidden underneath that
block in that one which was killed over
here we have a little record player I
keep saying little I got to stop that
lights turn on and off some storage and
stuff let's see let's go maybe this way
another bridge window to the furnace
room this was our first enchanting
system back when it took 50 levels to
enhance we had flexible bookshelves here
that we could control yet between the
level ranges and then later we added
dispensers and stuff here where are the
buttons
did I get rid of the buttons
used to be buttons up here wasn't there
huh I don't know what happened to him
this over here is a man-made River when
I first started the base I I had a plan
to make up a giant boat system to take
you throughout it's but boats were just
so bad that it never ended up happening
so this is more just for decoration and
stuff unfortunately it's still something
I would love to do but boots are still
kinda crummy
this broken way but this used to be an
elevator to get up why is it closed off
now I'm not sure over here is our our
vine farm that you guys never see this
is just when I need vines break them
they land into hoppers end up in here
nothing down there really let's see
let's go over this way another bridge to
go across leads to a room that's not
built yet it's just kind of empty flows
down here crosses the river again one
thing I love about this base is it has a
nice flow to it like everything just
kind of connects together takes us back
down here more little contraptions here
I guess we'll check these out this was
our first mini farm we built I think we
have three or four of them now just
continually getting better and better as
the game progressed where's our seeds I
thought they received in there before no
let's steal this one I guess stand here
hold right click close the door behind
you so creatures don't get you you know
how it works over here is a snowball
firm basically just hold left click this
fills up with the snowballs they they
end up going down into a system I think
we can get to it actually yeah we have
access to the snowball stuff over here
there's a minecart that runs picks up
the snowballs over here oh I fall down
they end up in this mine car comes by
picks them up when when it needs them
from over here oh I shouldn't have done
that
GG there's water above us and it fills
up a couple dispensers with snowballs
that shoot them out randomly every so
often just for for decoration all right
let's go back up this part of the man
cave we don't see too often in the
videos I do really like it though
there's a spider farm here and here dual
spider farm cave spiders just decorative
stuff and then our fishing shack which
we don't really use too often because
fishing is so much fun in the game
alright get back to our main area here
we have the creeper face which I'm
pretty sure was the first thing we built
in the world and it's just like a symbol
of the of the base or the man cave here
in our first world we had a creeper face
made out of black wool on the wall and I
liked it a lot so I just did another one
here and later we added the ability for
it to shoot flaming arrows out of its
eyes and access to it over here but I
often forget to refill like the snowball
dispensers the arrow dispensers the base
takes a lot of maintenance to keep
everything running actually and so I
think it's out of arrows right now I
haven't seen it shoot in a long time
we got Zenith here our super horse
actually killed the wither while riding
Zenith which was very difficult to do
I've tried it again since and I haven't
been able to actually leads and and
speed potions for our horse stable here
it's where we keep our guys and
basically oh we can hop on exit it
triggers some tripwires there the block
goes down we can go out and then when we
want to park it again block goes back up
that way they don't wander aimlessly
around our worlds alright I just went
and got some food here for Wilson our
buddy our pal everybody's favorite
Tamagotchi pets and Minecrafts if you
don't know what this is basically it's a
mini game within the game where you got
to try keep him happy and healthy make
sure he doesn't die on you ah and it's
kind of like a mini computer almost
where basically that's his happiness
level that says his food is overall
weight and then that's the important bar
you there his health depending on what
level that is that it affects his face
like what what expression he has if it
hits zero he dies and you lose
that's his age meter there it goes up
the older he gets and right now he's
sick he's got the zigzag so in order to
cure him you got to feed him golden
apples he'll randomly get sick every so
often depending on his health he gets if
his health is low he gets sick more
often oh he's like fluctuating between 1
and 2 then you can feed them you gotta
wait after everything every interaction
for a little bit for that to to go back
but we'll cheat and we just fed them so
now his food went back up and basically
it calculates like depending on that bar
that bar in that bar it adds up his
total value and it either adds or
subtracts to is his health there and
despite what a lot of you guys think
Wilson is actually a fully functional
build like it's it's kind of finished
but it could be improved a lot I've been
tempted to like start a new one now that
I know a lot more about redstone this
was like a learning project for me
mainly like we started it around the
time the redstone update came out so I
was learning about hoppers comparators
droppers all that kind of stuff and it
was actually during while I was working
on Wilson that I came up with a hopper
clock idea so learnt a lot of stuff
learned about variables like how to do
variables and Minecrafts counters all
kinds of crazy stuff
but it's it's a bit of a mess because I
didn't really know what I was doing and
I didn't plan it out as well as I
probably should have I couldn't have
done it a lot better
behind the creeper face of course is our
nether portal I had a real thing for
sandstone emeralds for a while oh yeah
and you can like turn on and turn off
the portals something I do every so
often let's see where should we go next
guys where should we go next let's go
this way I guess this is the older part
of the base it's not quite as nice as
the newer parts I don't think got our
slime farm there made that one the slime
change came around they used to only
spawn at Y 16 or lower then they changed
it to 40 and lower so it's like right at
the maximum height and then water brings
them up to another part of the base and
kills them or it'll pick up the big
slimes and make them go around the
sandstone ring here this was a very
important build for me this is our tree
farm where basically I thank all the
people that used to donate to me or that
donated in the past I don't accept
donations anymore it's just something I
wouldn't feel right doing anymore now
that I make a decent amount off to the
ads on the videos and stuff but when I
first started youtube these guys really
like motivated me they were a big part
of like keeping the the channel going
making sure I keep making videos and
stuff there's more in another part of
the world too
which hopefully we'll get to see and
it's something we did recently we added
some a mural around the walls got a cool
roof in here I like it a lot this is a
flower farm for getting the blue flowers
minecart runs underneath and picks them
all up here and as you can probably
guess this wall here isn't finished we
still need to add one more mural and
then I think this tree farm is done and
we just gotta like connect that part of
the base to that and like deal with this
stone chunk here and then it'll look
pretty nice I think once we finish that
we're not going in any particular order
with this world Tori they're like not in
build order we're just going whatever's
closest this is one of the more recent
builds we did the nether wart farm the
big one which i think is has a really
unique look to it I like it a lot
there's a button somewhere here I should
mark it a bit better storage for the
nether warts automatically goes here is
this a button that's the button guys so
water comes out on all sides brings all
the nether work to the center and then
it flows and goes up an elevator into
those chess it's time so it the nether
work all goes towards the middle once it
all reaches the middle then the water
disappears and we got to replant it
manually unfortunately there's no way to
do it automatically this is a slime
thing by the way it automatically picks
up the big slimes and then they go
around the sandstone here don't ask me
why I did it I just thought it'd be
funny they get picked up over here this
is where the big guys lands medium ones
land here small ones land here we got
Cthulhu chillin out over there back at
our main parts we have a pumpkin and
melon farm here you used to have to hold
the ground in order to get the pumpkins
and melons to grow so this would
dispense a hole at you and you would run
down pull all the all the dirt and then
put it back but you don't have to do
that anymore thankfully so that an old
elevator the old spiral kind which
really you have to get really lucky with
it
yeah those are a super common though a
long time ago thankfully we got better
ones now our ugly brick thing every base
needs an ugly brick thing guys it's
probably the best thing I've ever built
all it is is an infinite water spring
but I thought it was really cool at the
time I don't know why this is like the
old part of the base by the way so like
the first area we built stone brick in
nether brick you can't find that
anywhere else in our in our man cave
every area is a little bit more area a
little bit unique from each other which
I like this goes up to the UFO basically
you stand there and fish cows it really
doesn't seem to work anymore
unfortunately that's as high as I can
get them and also like the collision
might have changed with this I keep
hitting I keep doing that it like this
sinks down I'm hitting the slab I think
I'm not sure anyways they used to been
pull them all the way up to the water
here and then they would get funneled to
a certain area didn't you just kill them
it was for fun um let's see
got our map over there of the Worlds and
over here we used to have Jeff in this
cage he escaped don't know what happened
to him and we have a viewing window into
the spider farm there the chief spiders
we got our two tall flower from here
what did we call this I don't remember
but it there's bone meal and the
dispensers here wow that's causing a lot
of leg for some reason what my framerate
just tanked well that was running very
intensive flower farming I've got a
passage to go down to the cow farm here
this is what was my main source of food
for the longest time we've switched over
to golden carrots now though once you go
all the cows ebolas lever it releases
some water to gather all the drops
together and then they end up over here
it's not automatic or anything you got
to pick them up and put the stuff in the
chest because it was before hoppers and
that team out of the game let's go a
spectator mode
for a second when we first made this
world's cave spiders were really
important actually like they just came
it out in the game and then the chanting
came out soon after that I believe so I
was pretty keen on figuring out how to
farm cave spiders for their string and
spider eyes but also like when
enchanting came out I wanted the XP from
them because people were mainly just
using single skeleton spawners to get
their XP and cave spiders it was really
easy to find like two spawners together
or more so I tried to figure out a way
of affirming XP this was our first
system we used to have water above these
fences they would take damage even after
falling it onto the fences here with the
water above and it would funnel them all
to this area here and you would stand
here and and kill them then later I at
least I believe it was later I set up a
new system which was our main XP system
for the longest time in the world here
where I figured out how to move them up
vertically because they would always get
stuck that was a big problem with teve
spiders this over here if you're ever
wondering what this is this was our old
chief spider farm it's broken now but if
we go spectator mode you can see just
how crazy it was basically like this was
a spiral elevator if you follow water
streams here the cave spiders used to
funnel in here and then go up through
this big maze of of water streams later
this broke though they would get stuck
in them and then they would fall down
get down to a single hits that the two
spawners converged it up there to get
down to a single hit and then you like
throw a potion to kill him here get tons
of XP and I spent a lot of time just
standing here back in the day I spent so
much time cuz it took so long to get 50
levels and then later I added a timer
system so if I afk for a long time the
game wouldn't crash from like spawning a
thousand mobs or something it would it
would shut it off eventually
this here is project Pokemon originally
we were trying to collect one of each of
the different villagers not realizing
you couldn't get the green ones you can
now though
then I added a switching system to it
which seems to be damaging them for some
reason now a bit concerning is it
because they're taking damage in Pistons
that might be it
that was a change right this leads over
to emerald village - the goal was to
make a village where the villagers would
do all kinds of crazy stuff
automatically didn't really work out and
you guys really hated the build style so
I ended up scrapping this project after
spending a long time digging out this
area but it was probably for the best we
made a new village later that turned out
a lot better in my opinion although it's
still quite didn't do what I wanted it
to do
oh yeah and to get them in here and you
dropped them down this chute here if we
go above there was a door system it
looks like it's glitched out for for
dropping the cows down and the villagers
down and stuff here into place and
there's gonna be a world download by the
way guys in the description if you want
to check anything out in more detail you
can I would love to get more detailed
with explanations but it'll just take
too long fortunately this was our first
giant potion lab we built this one
brewing came out also the very first eco
door here although this is a spiraling
one not the quick version that I usually
build this was like honestly this is the
first really complicated thing I built I
would say let's go spectator mode again
you see all the Redstone the redstone is
nasty to this thing by the way like each
of these buttons I had to individually
separate and stuff and then wire up here
and basically it leads up to this room
here which if you remember over here
let's go game-mode 0 to get into this
room you there's a hopper minecart
underneath here it detects when you
throw an item in opens up the door and
that leads into here which stores all
the ingredients for the potions and when
you press the buttons down there it
shoots out the items according to how
many you need and they all funnel down
to the
middle here three one alright and
basically you stand right underneath the
middle here and you press whatever you
want here so if you want glass bottles
at that you want another word you hit
that gunpowder and it all just kind of
falls on you here and all the brewing
stands are just within your reach so you
don't have to move you just go around
and that was like as automatic and cool
as you can make a potion system back in
the day then there's a storage for it
here but then later let's go check out
the new potion system I think we're done
in this area this is the one I'm really
proud of ethos lab is what we called it
off over this way it's basically a giant
brewing system with like 20 or more
dreaming stands in over here really like
how it looks it was an a unique idea
basically we chained the brewing stands
together so it adds one ingredient each
phase here and at each phase you can
access the chests so it starts out
awkward then it turns into a night
vision with three minutes then eight
minutes then adds the spider eyes turns
into visibility on who adds gunpowder
turns into splash potions so any potion
you want at any step you can you can get
here store it in bulk and then to turn
the system on this is for brewing the
awkward potions that happens
automatically is it glitched out or
maybe it's full I think it's full that's
what's wrong now we have another work
farm built into this works pretty good
but it also helps to make the build look
cool I think and this is the main switch
yeah that turns it all on let's go
spectator mode again there's a minecart
system above that delivers the potions
and bottles where they belong
there's also a place here for filling it
up with water bottles and they go into
bulk storage and there's a lot of wiring
a lot of wiring it took me a long time
to farm all the courts for this -
alright so moving on here we have
another 3x3 door here you can open it
with the button but we also experimented
with a bunny powered door which few
select golden carats that opens and
closes automatically or it should yeah
it doesn't work as good as it used to
though to be honest something changed
with the the mob path not finding I
think where is he I'm lost there's a
bunny down here there he is he like
jumps up into the water and then
activates this tripwire when you select
the golden carrot uh-huh then we have
this room here this is mostly just for
decoration this intersection I took
inspiration from one of neveress his old
Basie he did this like ring style but he
did like stone brick and and lava and I
wanted a more natural look to it so we
got leaves in here we got regular brick
water some random flowers and garbage
all around this is our mob system here
just regular mobs they drop down into
the hoppers end up in these chests so it
looks full again we recently fixed this
again so it's working pretty good yeah
it's totally filled up if we fly up here
basically the mobs are attracted to
villagers the zombies are while the
skeletons run away from wolves and the
creepers won't run away from the kitties
here we got slabs or carpet here to stop
spiders from spawning okay so opposite
of the mob farm here we have another one
of my more recent builds also probably
one of the more complicated things I've
ever made this is a shelter box storage
system that has a search function which
was a weird idea I wanted to play around
with and it also has a menu system so
you can select what items you want so
basically you put your chakra boxes in
here with your various different items
and then if you want to like find the
night a certain item without ever like
looking through all the boxes there
let's say we want some sands select it
from the menu there you throw it
and then it'll check all those shelter
boxes for any that have sand in and they
should end up here so that has sand in
and then if you want to cycle to the
next box you step on the pressure plates
this one also has sand in another one
with sand we got a lot of sand
apparently and then they end up back in
here also the menu item backs ends up
back in here this does some complex
stuff like I had to for example there's
hoppers that have branching paths in the
system and of course the search engine
idea is pretty unique with it so if you
guys want to check this out in more
detail you'll finally be able to I have
wanted to do something more complex like
a new better system than this but it's
tricky
I have tried off camera a little bit but
I haven't really gotten anything awesome
figured out yet but maybe in the future
we'll we'll get back to that idea
further on here we have the underground
village I love the way this place looks
I think it's pretty nice this was the
alternate to Emerald City got the
schoolroom here you can send the
villagers up to the surface here to kill
them or go on to the good life they'll
stay in the village they go there I
think actually the way this worked is we
we had a block here and then only baby
villagers can go inside they'll grow up
in the school and then depending on what
their trades are you decide if they're
good or bad but later that stopped
working for some reason I believe I've
got another portal here let's see
there's a minecart system that's
supposed to run and pick up villagers
from one side of the village and move it
to the next but that was kind of always
glitchy there's also several weird farms
or mechanisms here what did this do this
is for crafting written books or
something I don't remember exactly for
trading you know I can sell written
books for trading that was a way of like
doing it quickly there
is a way of killing the villagers over
here you pull the lever with the
villagers inside shoots flaming arrows
until it kills them and you gotta try
stay alive yourself stupid little
minigame there's a mini farm in the
village somewhere and also what else we
got our zombie purifier here - lets go
game-mode 3 what oh you know I restarted
that's why uh-huh
you got a villager guy up here up here
yeah so when we first started the
village we had to get the villagers here
somewhere right so they came from zombie
villagers we cured him here they spawn
in the dark areas and then once we get
the villagers we lead them back drop
them down and they populated the village
to what it is today
oh yeah there's also a system here for
semi-automatically trading rotten flesh
here two villagers basically press Q it
dispenses exactly thirty six above you
here and you do one by one and then
storage for here goes to the different
droppers and I almost forgot this was a
another more recent thing we did there's
the llama Vader this actually works
really good I'm surprising what as
building is like oh this is so sketchy
this is never gonna work great but it's
good it's actually really good and then
there's a call button up here too for
forgiving them up voice crack uh-huh hop
on you go down oh okay we're about
thirty minutes into the episode here but
we're just about done with the Mantid
stuff finally couple things we've
skipped over I do want to point out this
room it's one of my favorites actually
has a really unique look to it I had the
idea of like let's make a flooded room
right and then we got the peers or
docking above its I don't know you call
it there is also kind of a unique item
here there's the horse elevator not just
for people it works for people but also
horses too so two by two
oh no it did work for horses oh dear
minecraft guys stuff is great randomly
for no reason
alright I'll have to look into that I
guess by by far and large that's not the
expression more or less things are
working pretty good in our world now
since I know like the last World Tour we
did a lot of stuff was broken we fixed a
lot of things since then outside here we
have the mushrooms to indicate this is
our musical mushroom farm basically the
idea here was to have detectors I wanted
to do something with bud switches all
right I think I kind of liked a little
bit but when the mushroom grows it plays
a little tune chop it down we got
storage here for different stuff as well
as the blocks so this is like where our
red and brown mushroom blocks come from
although we made a new mushroom firm
recently now that I think of it that's
better for getting the browns it's our
armorstand thing I messed it up recently
so yeah but this is like where we store
our our tools and stuff and then there
was a button here to cycle the
armorstands but you see I pulled them
all out this is our get your snacks
totally random build doesn't serve a
purpose just to introduce a video
basically but it's kind of cool the the
fruit just goes around on a loop there
and then it kind of goes underneath the
base here this area looks pretty decent
hello I got really liked how this area
looks to actually we had a rabbit farm
there that kind of stopped working so I
turned into a pig farm because in our
world there's actually very few pigs so
I wanted to save like the one or two
that I I found before they all went
extinct let's see is that it did we do
it oh yeah there's this area here too
so you look down at the Tamagotchi
Wilson wire axis here for making the
business for our firework making room
which we can get to over here there's a
system here for crafting fireworks
randomly it just gives you a random
assortment of dies and firework effects
for crafting the balls and then you can
choose like if you want it's free
gunpowder or something I don't know
actually
I build this stuff and then I forget how
it works it gives you a random out on
the fire balls and gunpowder and stuff I
don't know what's this wire access
uh-huh we have more wire access here for
the ethos lab and elevator and stuff I
like to include little wire access rooms
in case we got to change something in
the future this goes over to Wilson and
what else what else I guess let's go
further on here so another one of our
mini farms that's the turn it on this is
to protect you from the mobs and see got
a nice man my game is lagging like crazy
I've got a nice view of the potion lab
over there and then we also were playing
around with a minigame here
Simon Says where it randomly gives you a
color you gotta remember the sequence
which is still a work in progress so
let's not
and then the random wall changing thing
yeah guys are just demanding my
attention here get out of here okay so I
have to make a button here to turn this
on basically this lets you switch
between different patterns on the wall
using the gravity effect of the new
concrete powder this is a random idea I
wanted to play around with I saw a lot
of people did stuff with this like like
on Reddit and that so that's that's kind
of the goal of this series by the way I
just like to introduce ideas and then
see what other people do with them too
so some people have done some cool
things with this for me though this is
still under construction like a lot of
things right I think we're done with the
mancave now one thing I did want to do
just to show you guys a lot of times
when I'm building something I talk about
space like there's not enough space over
there or over there you should see how
close together all this stuff is to each
other it's crazy like we only see the
facade part of it but when you look at
the wire and stuff it's like all right
next to each other and inter inter wines
and just barely enough space to get a
lot of this to work even oh yeah there's
storage here for the speed potions I
forgot about that
hit in the way huh like this river is
right above here like it's just like all
just barely fitting and it's not square
anything so it's like fun to figure out
how to make it all work together when
you're building it all right very good
very good I believe we have finished up
with the man cave now so we can continue
on our tour outside in our beautiful
world here let's run through the swamp
to begin with by the way I'm recording
this the next day so if I sound
inference if I sound
raspy or depressed I am NOT I am just
I'm just I've just woken up that's it
whenever I record in the morning you
guys are like what's wrong with you
though he sounds so sad ok I'm fine
things are good so after building the
man tube for a long time eventually I
started craving other projects here this
was one of the very first ones we did
besides the man cave this was our our
mineshaft area later I decided to try
put an ice road from the man cave to
here but it broke shortly after so we'll
probably just cover that up and never
speak of it again there's a snow golem
that walks around in the ceiling in here
and it makes the lights blink on and off
every so often it's it's kind of rare
but it adds a little bit of atmosphere
to the builds and the main point of this
build is just to collect resources we
did a lot of branch mining back in the
day but
or speed mining so I spent a lot of time
digging here and the tree farm was
getting so big like every donator got
got their own tree I decided I got to do
something else that's getting out of
hand
so I decided to dedicate each of the
branches to to somebody here so that's
what these signs are abouts
oh yeah and by the way every so often my
world here you might see some blocks
like this in a chest or or just randomly
uh I like to tease them in the video
because people are like he throws a
cheater he's using cheap blocks or
something when they see these what do
what it was back in the day
I tried building this mineshaft out of
planks and in some places are still
playing and it kept burning down on me
so I switched it over to wooden slabs
which used to not burn but they changed
it so that they do now but any any old
structures that use the ones that don't
burn they have their own special wooden
slab that doesn't burn still okay so
also in the swamp biome here we have the
snowflake and iron golem farm combo here
originally we just had the snowflake for
the longest time back before beacons
were in the game this served as a beacon
for me because I would get lost often in
the swamp here or in the mountains and I
could look for the snowflake and and
know that was the direction of home
right I resisted building the iron golem
farm for the longest time but eventually
we needed to build it for the Nexus
because it would have taken way too long
to firm all that iron way too long so I
broke down and built it's and as a
result I never go caving now yeah that's
that's the reason I didn't want to build
on I'm weak I can't do it now it's too
easy just to collect the iron from there
also over here we have the spaceship
sort of build that doesn't look like
anything else this is part of one of our
gold farms we have three gold firms in
the world this is part of the first one
and I actually really liked how this
thing looks I think this is a cool build
actually maybe let's not switch the way
it works is we would send
zombie pigmen from the nether to the
overworld here there's two sets of
portals we go through the one at the top
here and the zombie pigmen comes through
the one at the bottom and now we can go
team mode one and there was a crushing
system in this then you throw like a
damage potion at them and the drops go
in the hopper down there then if we go
back all the drops funnel through the
hoppers here up an elevator into a
sorting system somewhere here over here
yeah and end up in these chests then we
got like a little trading villager here
I said little again I got to stop I got
to stop it uh-huh and there's an
elevator which I'm guessing if the horse
elevator doesn't oops doesn't work this
one might not either okay good to know
and this turns it on and off right all
right let's get out of here
I built this bridge thing a long time
ago I've been thinking about maybe
tearing it out but the idea was to send
the enchanted book sweet enchant at the
gold from there to the library this
build over here the purpose of the
library is to store our enchanted books
as well as our villagers do enchanting
and just to hopefully look good as well
yeah so this thing with all the the
chest is what we called the book matrix
this is what actually stores the
enchanted books you see they're all
labeled you can't actually sorts
enchanted books that I know of there's
no way to so we put them in manually up
there for long-term storage and then
when we want to do in chanting we come
down here and we can choose whatever
book we want just by clicking the
buttons here so we just selected
efficiency and if we click that will get
smite basically we wait a little bit
they come up through the ground here so
that's our efficiency book and that's
our smite book
we got grandma wither bottom up there we
recently just added more to the building
here also we store our comments on the
day here too
about that but this is not a finished
build we still got a lot left to do on
it you can see the library up on the
mountain there we actually built a road
that we're supposed to ride horses down
to get to the library it kind of winds
through the mountains and stuff up to
the library
each of these lights on the road has a
daylight sensor so that turns on during
the night time and I thought this looked
really good when I first built it now I
am like why did I build this and also
we're never gonna ride horses again
because we gotta light your wings in
fireworks so it's one of those things
right this area even though we don't
have anything built here it's a very
special part of the world to me probably
to some of you as well we did a lot of
our redstone testing in this area here
also I spent a lot of time growing trees
and chopping them down here too it's
just an area I've spent a lot of time in
the world's big open field and another
mini farm over here I should give that a
proper place eventually I just set it up
there to show it off and I never did
anything fancy with it yet one day I
decided let's build a cactus farm this
is a copy of a cactus farm I made a long
time ago in my very first world's before
even doing youtubing like my first
Minecraft world ever
I built this farm and I for nostalgia I
thought hey let's build it again why not
there's a spot here where all the cactus
gathers the original one didn't have
hoppers though obviously okay guys so
now it's time for sandy city let's go
check this out one day while working on
the man cave I think I was doing the the
map wall and I got a little bit
depressed to be honest it's like I was
looking at the maps it's like there's
nothing on these maps it's I've built
nothing above ground everything was in
the man cave right so I got the idea to
start this biome enhancement project
where basically this was an empty desert
it was very boring nothing nothing
special about so I was like why don't I
just build a city they're right out of
sandstone earth and try and make it look
good so that's that's kind of how this
all started
and we've done several biome enhancement
projects throughout the world here how
did I get the city to walk around the
llamas like that I don't know it's not
working right now it is in my real world
not in this copy for some reason I guess
the one special thing about this this
build is the while here I think it's
pretty cool you hop in pushes you into
the nether then the portal lights and
then shuts off once you go through so
like when I go through here again it
Sakhalin put me down in the well it's
gonna put me back in the man cave and
like a lot of our projects guys this is
still a work in progress it's not
finished as you can tell there's a lot
of open space here this is where the
buildings are supposed to be but they're
not they're kind of a giant flaw but
eventually maybe we'll get it done one
thing I really do like about this build
though is the city gates I think they
look really cool I designed them myself
I'm quite proud aha moving on outside
here we have the orange sand making
machine if you're wondering why there
was one on the ground there's because I
messed up three I had to redo it and
basically turns yellow Santa orange or
orange to yellow and it looks quite
quite strange indeed alright
another thing we did recently is we put
in this this weird thing how do we
activate this is it just the pressure
plate yeah I don't know if we're gonna
be able to see it haha a long time ago
when the sandstone Wells came up in the
game I decided hey let's make one in the
desert here and I put lava inside I did
it as a troll to kind of get people
curious but none of you realized that
like this wasn't here originally I built
this and there's a button on it I was
hoping I would get a few people with it
but yeah not too many I didn't see too
many people discover that to be honest
and another really important part of
sandy city is the giant sugarcane farm I
think it adds a nice look to the city we
got a
while going around it's a little
sandstone wall but especially like I
used it a lot for trading with villagers
paper trades rights it's where a lot of
our emeralds came from back in the day
we got the pyramid there which should
probably be redone again because you
guys don't like it inside is the mob
system that we saw in the man cave the
pyramids just cover it up so we didn't
have a giant square
Claes structure there that looked kind
of weird up in the mountains here we can
we can get a good view of the river this
is like a man crafted River pretty much
I put trees all along the the riverbanks
there's lights in the water and ride the
boat through it it's kind of nice and it
leads up to a lake over there or out out
into the swamp area there too and added
some waterfalls and stuff along the trip
and then up in the mountains here we
have our wooly mammoth
I like making 3d animals for some reason
like minecraft animals so I made a
mammoth I've made a t-rex in the past
that a lot of people liked got our
penguin buddy up here and in the world
we have to ice farms this is the second
one we built this is the good one where
water freezes in this light one wide
space here then Pistons push it towards
the middle and then you can see we got
like Pistons all all throughout there
that push the ice up word so it makes a
giant ten by ten by ten Ice Cube a
thousand ice when you harvest it if it
all goes well anyway all right let's go
on here kind of got a path running
through here takes a still lake with our
cobblestone wall running across we have
some custom trees here the ender Porter
a lot of you asked about the end
reporter if I'm gonna work on it
honestly I had a lot of trouble with it
whenever the idea is this would suspend
an ender pearl in the water you press a
button and it would like tell another
ender Porter off somewhere else to let
the ender pearl land and then you would
teleport there the problem is when the
chunks would load sometimes it would
just randomly activate when you didn't
press the button which is kind of
annoying and I was not able to find a
workaround to that so I don't know if
that's ever gonna get finished over here
we have a little house mostly for
decoration and then some random wheat
fields and stuff we have the you've been
etho sign some of you might not know
what this is about
back in mine crack I think it was B dubs
that started the whole you've been east
old thing he like made a soda a verb and
somebody on the reddit's made an image
where I'm like don't doing that oh no
you didn't where my head's shaken back
and forth and it was animated and I
thought it was really cool so I like
took that picture and I turned it into
3d art here in the mountain aha
I don't know if that made sense I tried
to explain it anyways for the longest
time we had the diamond door it's a
pretty pretty easy thing basically you
make people curious what's behind
something or what's in something and
then you pretend you're gonna show them
and then you don't and you do it several
times and it's it's funny yeah to me
eventually I did decide to put something
behind here the redstone room where we
have like a nice open space we can do
redstone projects got a redstone in the
chests there and pretty much this whole
area here is just part of the biome
enhancement project this was a big open
field before just empty Plains it was
really boring and I got the idea like
why don't we try to make it look
interesting all right do something with
it so little by little we've been adding
pieces to it like the path the wall this
border around the lake we got the water
the wheat field over there with the
windmill windmill aha I corrected myself
and just little pieces throughout time
and it's it starting to look kind of
good right I think so at least we
recently expanded the path a little bit
more here we added some cobble banks
along the
River here and further on another
unfinished project that we started
recently is a trophy room for that the
ender egg dragon egg that's what's
called I played around with an idea here
is it working it's not working why is it
working we just did this oh it is I'm
congested impatient the lights fade in
and out randomly you see the background
there it's easier to see at nighttime
you guys really hate the way this looks
down here I tried to do something
different that we haven't done before so
that was a bit of a fail I know the
colors are a bit crazy but I should
maybe change it after all let's go take
a look at the windmill I think that's
one of my more favorite builds I've done
I've designed it myself and it looks
pretty cool a lot of you said it's
chunky though it's like really fat and
short but I think it's interesting
regardless kind of crazy stare and stone
action going on there oh yeah and I
really like this path over here this
one's pretty cool too oh I got I got hit
by the guy there's a we moved a guy from
one of the oceans to on top the windmill
aha I like this path a lot here this
goes along side that village this is our
original village to the left here back
before is villagers even had trades and
stuff they were basically useless just
wandering around and somehow I kept them
all alive though and there's still a few
of the originals in there and over here
this leads to our chorus farm which is
pretty cool you go on top of the the
wood there you chop down all the seeds
once you finish that you hit the button
and it releases some water in the back
there it's time still exactly enough
time will pass for all the drops wash
into this water here and then it
retracts there's a sorting system for
all the drops which I think we can get
to over here right yeah
and the the drops end up at that you see
it goes down the path here
the drops end up at that house we just
saw getting quite a bit of leg from the
water there over here the forest root
ends up here to our blacksmith building
and underneath it automatically goes
into these furnaces and gets melted and
dumped in their chests here and that's
where all our purpur in the world comes
from so at the end of the path here we
come across two really important
buildings to our world we have the super
smelter made out another brick there and
we have the Nexus the giant storage room
that's taken over three years to build
and it's not finished yet and that I
could build so much better now if I try
it again yeah let's check out the super
smelter first so this is one of them I
think this is one of your guys's
favorite projects I've ever done to be
honest the idea was to make a smelting
system and see how quickly we could get
it to work like how fast and we actually
smelt something in Minecraft that's
somewhat reasonable right is it 64 or
128 furnaces or 256 I don't remember
it's a lot of furnaces though and like
that's how quick it smells make a lot of
noise it's killing my ears right now
another thing anyways it's pretty cool I
use it a lot actually whenever I'm doing
a big building project it's really nice
to be able to smell things quickly the
Nexus the whole idea with the Nexus is
to make a storage room that you can
automatically sort items so I think
there's there's 256 different items that
can store let in the chests there and
then it also has a retrieval system
which is what makes this unique here is
our hexadecimal encoder where we have 16
buttons and each of the buttons has a
numerical value between 0 and 16
hexadecimal
that made sense somehow and let's say
for example we want some cyan clay here
number 35 this is our menu system I
named all of these items why is that one
blue for a Oh cuz it's an apple golden
apple right right right
so what you do is hit three five on our
thing here hopefully I do it in the
right order here and that changes the
code up there and then you pull the
lever it'll request the item hopefully
or another option instead of pulling the
Liebherr you can press these buttons
this one will give you sixteen items
this one thirty-two sixty-four or two
stacks I think with that one there we go
finally that's one of the big problems
of the system if I was to redesign it
again
I would try to make it even faster at
delivering the items and also I would
like to be able to see how many items
are in this system so I'm kind of like
blindly requesting them with that this
is where the items actually gets stored
kind of a cool little area here at
game-mode 3 if you check out some of the
wiring there's a lot of wiring to this
thing a lot a lot of wiring and yeah the
hexadecimal encoding part of it is crazy
like to get all those buttons to meet up
with the chess it gets a little crazy
with all the branching of the wiring and
stuff but is it pretty cool a little
build I like it a lot not little it's
huge okay let's continue on here further
this way one of our again more recent
builds is a giant brown mushroom firm we
also have an auto pumpkin farm here that
uses daylight sensors where light passes
through the Pistons here if a pumpkin
grows in front it triggers the daylight
sensor and it causes it to break goes
into the water ends up in these chests
here and we have some villagers here for
pumpkin trading we got a perfect eight
guy that's the best trader you can get
with them
there wasn't too many mushrooms there I
don't think yeah I kind of messed up the
mushroom farm here the idea is you got a
spot here for the brown mushrooms to
grow there's one in each of these
corners underneath the the dirt here so
it'll spread to the podzol here
eventually
or you can just plant them manually then
there's a dispenser with bonemeal it'll
force it to grow like we just saw you
chop down you you run along the side
here you chop down all the mushrooms
there's supposed to be a beacon with
speed mining but it's not active for
some reason I think I moved it somewhere
else maybe no I would just wasn't in
range I guess where is this axe to
school I'm in creative like what's going
on here ah chop that all the mushrooms
then there's some dispensers on top then
cause water to fall down it washes all
the drops into the hole here and then a
hopper minecart runs out underneath
picks them up and delivers the brown
mushrooms to the super smelter they're
as fuel so moving on here you can see
the super smelter and Nexus way in the
background there if you come over here
we have the Guardian farm and this is a
little bit of a special case for us
because the world is so old the biomes
actually changed in one of the updates
so even though this was like Plains
biome it got switched over to ocean like
an if you made this world today using
the same seed this would be ocean and
there's there's a Guardian firm here or
Guardian temple I mean so I dug out the
land I set up a glass thing here full of
water for the guardians and this is a my
own special design for a farm you could
do this in the ocean pretty easy instead
of like emptying out all the water like
you normally do you set up these columns
of sugarcane or some other blocks that
can fall through like fence gates and
they'll eventually swim into it and fall
down it won't be super efficient but
it'll work in my case here it's pretty
good because there's no other water
nearby anyways they fall through some
lava here
they all collect together fall down the
pipe here they die above some hoppers
and then they go into a sorting system
and elevator go into the chests here and
this is just a little room we made to to
access the drops and stuff from from the
farm oh me oh my we are over one hour
into the video now guys but thankfully
we only got one one thing left to see in
our local area then we're gonna go check
out some other stuff here starting off
this is I think the first mob system we
built in the world here using my old
design which still kind of works but
it's not it's probably not the best one
you could use nowadays and this is our
stronghold base so this is where our end
portal is I decided I figured out a long
time ago a way of making a silver fish
farm or basically it spawns a silver
fish in and we use a bud bud switch to
detect when they enter or stone blocks
which get automatically generated at a
farm and a farm at a you know a stone
farm like lava and water you know what I
talked about and then they get piled
together in a giant tube here so these
are all silver fish blocks being stored
originally I was doing it so we'd have
like long-term storage for XP back when
it took 50 levels to enchant and I
wanted to build a base here so while we
were standing on the base it would be
constantly making silver fish but we
never ended up building a base here we
just did some random projects such as
our bomb factory thing here where we get
skeletons to shoot creepers and then
they will blow them up wherever we
choose something we did recently and
what else that's about it maybe let's go
to the end since we're here and we'll
start checking out some of our other
builds so we have three Enderman farm in
the world
let's go check out the first ones down
down this way we have an eats road which
doesn't worked anymore
no.3 yeah up over here this eats road
takes you to the first interment firm if
you ever wondered why it's called an
ender ender this was the very first
original ender ender it was actually a
comment I asked people what we should
call this thing and somebody suggested
the name ender ender so that's what I
called it and then other people followed
suit they called their Enderman farms
and her Enders and the rest is history
this is the first design though back in
the day
Enderman firms weren't really a thing
people tried making a few designs like
they used the cone style blaze firm
alots
originally or they just stood in the
middle of their Island they flooded the
island and tried to attract the Enderman
to them I decided to try to do a piston
system where we drop them and it gets
him down to one hit points and then you
look at them attract them and kill them
quickly I did it just for ender pearls
originally but it was so effective at
getting XP is like hey this is a good XP
farm to later the zip crowd figured out
a way of using vines so that you could
stack the different layers and that
became the standard for Enderman farms
and I kind of copied a lot of that in
our second farm here when I did the
ender ender 2.0 here though I did try to
do a couple unique things with its to
make it make it my own
for example the piston arms they work on
a clock system instead of like if an
Enderman activates the tripwire push the
Pistons this will continually push the
Enderman until they fall down because
sometimes they would get stuck in the
piston arms and if you tried several
times it would eventually push them but
the big thing about this farm is there
was a change in the game that wasn't
really well known where what game game I
see what I did there very funny
there was a change where TNT would
actually count as a player kill so
when you kill the Enderman with TNT you
would actually get XP and ender pearls
and stuff before that wasn't a thing so
I designed the farm where they would be
just in the perfect position to collect
all the XP when you stand here and it
worked pretty good I use this thing
quite a bit let's go check out the third
one though and finally guys that brings
us to the end our ender 3.0 this is our
current mob farm and it still works very
very good I like it a lot I get so much
XP from this thing although I do
generally prefer using the our gold farm
for XP because it's automatic this one's
not but the idea is you spawn the
Enderman over a large space they run
pretty quickly now that was a change
made in the game and they are attracted
to an endermite in a minecart here I
tried really hard with this design to
get them to fit in a 1x1 area a lot of
them didn't do that I think people are
doing that more so now and they fall
down the chamber because of the new mob
cramming rule they die if there's like
more than 20 or something in there but
it still works if you kill them before
that happens and below it we have the
random music making machine chess is the
fun little thing so it is randomly plays
music and random notes sounds kind of
cool though alright so that pretty much
covers the end guys we don't have a lot
built there so we'll check out the
nether next this is what connects our
world together starting with the nether
hub here this is our main area that
connects all the branches together I got
a lot of flack for this build guys the
sandstone and purple wool never hurt the
end of it but I like it I don't care
what you guys think I think you're crazy
I think this place is awesome that's
just my opinion alright so yeah we got
the the nether hub here if we fly up
this is also where we have our first
nether nether farm gold farm is what I'm
trying to say how does this work again I
think originally we dropped them down
here and then collected them with them
mine Kurtz if I remember right and then
we changed it later to a portal system
so they spawn in these layers and
there's a lot of a lot of them this took
a long time to build I remember doing
this this is brutal is all this string
broken order that fix it oh I did
actually fix it man I'm crazy there was
a patch that broke all this screen I
guess I took the time to fix it anyways
I'm rambling here so they spawn on the
layers and then if we go over here these
are our controls we can turn the portals
on usually I keep this disabled because
it causes a lot of leg when it's running
and this one breaks them as the zombie
pigmen spawn on the layers they get
pushed through the portals and end up at
that spaceship looking build thing we
have oh why am I going down our second
firms here too isn't it
wait a second I forgot we built one end
why this is our third one one in three
are here there's a cage all around it to
to stop gas from blowing it up here's
our third and our gold farm this is the
one we currently use and it still works
very good very very good this is where I
get most of our XP the idea is you stand
on the platform in the middle here again
nothing spawns because we are in
spectator mode so let's go D mode zero
you shoot the zombie pigmen and they get
attracted to each of the sides here they
fall down into a chamber there oh yeah
because they're aggressively we kill
them and then they they drop their drops
and see there's some redstone stuff
there that's a timing system so it'll
every so often a slime block will shoot
the XP and drops across to the middle
there you can see it piling up oh I
forgot we're not making it's like bad I
can't fly
and then the XP gets shot up the middle
there and right underneath us and that's
how we collect it the
items actually it picked up though
before that in these hopper minecarts
travel down sorting system here somehow
they get ejected down into these
chambers where they get stored and then
this is a shocker box filling station so
basically it fills up the chakra box
once it's full it breaks it and puts in
the chest down below here so these are
all full of rotten flesh for example ok
back at the hub here if we go down one
of these branches every single one of
the branches has one of these selector
systems the plan was to like choose our
minecart destination with this but never
ended up doing it's probably one of the
worst things with the series's might in
the indecisiveness a lot of projects I
have ideas for and then I never actually
do them later the plan was to have
horses to go down the tracks try to
breed very fast horses so we put in a oh
that's speed potions we have a horse
selector system which is damaging them
now apparently unfortunately so you can
switch between the two and then take out
your horse the idea was to have a mule
and one in a quick course another so if
you wanted to carry items you would use
the mule if you wanted to travel down
the path quickly you would use a horse
later we turned it over to an ice tunnel
which is like the quickest form of
transportation in the game to this date
and I'm going to rock down the wrong
path here aren't I
alright let's go check out the which
firm I guess I think it's over here yeah
not really much to say about this this
is our witch farm it's three layers we
push the witches off using water
previously we used arrows but it was too
too difficult to maintain and then they
fall down the chamber here onto some
hoppers
anything back here just the timing
system that's it's still gotta light up
the caves here in order to get it
working quickly and also clear out some
more lands one of the branches in the
nether hub here is actually different
than the others it it's not an ice road
it's a custom tunnel we built this took
forever to build never again keep your
tunnels simple don't go complex because
it just gets amplified the longer they
are but I do like how this thing looks
it's pretty cool we have an obsidian
farm here kind of scared to go check
outs we get back yeah the idea is you go
through you break the portal and then
you run to this portal over here and
it's on the timing system this is when I
first figured out that timing thing that
if you break the portal in 4.1 seconds
after you create it it will break behind
you but still let you through
you hear that piston go just broke the
portal brought us back here so if we go
through again they'll generate another
portal and more obsidian off this way is
just the sand mining outpost we check it
out real quick
there's not really a lot to see here we
just have some storage chests for
filling up of sand and a minecart system
you fill up the storage minecarts with
sand then you send it off through the
nether down that's minecart track we
have and I put in like a water stream
here so if we're doing mining in this
area we can just dump the sand or the
sandstone into the water stream it'll go
to those chests and we don't have to
like make a trip there to drop off this
stuff that was before like shale core
boxes alright so the other two branches
in the nether up here are a little bit
more interesting
this one again has a different style
tunnel this is the original style we
went with there was a system here for
sending the Guardians through the
overworld to the nether so we could get
hundreds and hundreds of them here and
then use looting to kill them and XP as
well of course they give a lot of XP
oh this goes to the oh you know we
missed something in the overworld it's
close to the stronghold this goes to the
zombie purifier that's what we forgot
let's go check that out real quick I
guess timings wrong it was right
actually okay I just wasn't in the
portal when I started it okay so this is
the zombie purifier it's just near the
stronghold base you see the tower over
there you go down and this was kind of
just like a fun little project idea was
- we got a zombie spawner here they
travel through a ton a water system here
you decide if it's a zombie villager or
not this turns the spawner on and off I
think yeah you see it went dark
this one flips the trapdoor so they
either go into this area here with the
zombie villagers or they get killed over
here if they go in here there's a way of
automatically dispensing weakness
potions on them and releasing minecarts
after you cure them and they go into the
nether here and you can transport them
wherever you need a villager so further
on in this tunnel here we come across
our newly renovated blaze farm dual
blaze farm when I first generated the
world I actually had no idea this was
here it took me a long time to find it I
got really lucky with it we just
happened to have - blaze spawner 'he's
right next to each other perfectly in
line and we created the dual blades farm
which was our main source of XP for a
long time in the world
later we renovated it here with the
purpur and sandstone blocks there's like
a switch to shut it on and off releasing
lava so it lights it up and they can't
spawn they get collected down below
there and minecarts they move up ejected
to the middle there then they get pushed
down into the chamber there and as more
and more blazes collect the lights turn
on when it got to the fifth light it
would start crushing them and collecting
the next batch and then you would kill
those guys with an instant Dam
phocion and underneath the the pressure
plate there there's a hopper minecart so
it would pick up the drops through a
block and put it into the chest there
for collecting aha there's also some
other stuff here for example enchanting
station this is a weird device I made I
wanted to see if I could make a system
for extracting water from the spot wet
sponges and we fill up glass bottles
like semi-automatically with this thing
and then they go into a brewing system
down below here this is a design I came
up with a while ago it's an auto brewing
system pretty compact for what it does
and unlike a lot of brewing systems that
rely on some sort of timer like a hopper
clock this one's actually smart it
figures out when to when to do stuff
using a trick with in other words you
guys probably don't see this guy too
often so I'll show it in the video here
just a little memento to Castle Crashers
one of the best games ever and there's
some other stuff in the nether here
we'll probably just skip over like
there's a another village and also our
original fortress we have some stuff
built there like a blaze farm but
honestly never use them anymore so let's
go to the end of the path here to our
nether our wither farm this is where
you'll notice I use quite a few beacons
in the world here these are still messed
up we had a lot of wither spawning here
because I took the time to clear out a
lot of the nether a lot of the lot of
the ground and the rest of it I slabbed
over so there's almost no space outside
of the nether fortress here for mobs to
spawn and we get a lot of wither
skeletons aha
and I also like made some jump pads for
like riding a horse as I kill the the
withers actually we're pretty decent and
then up above here is our second gold
farm yeah this is our second a gold farm
also it was a gas farm the way it worked
is we had some iron golems and
side here and they would aggro towards
the zombie pigmen automatically and for
a long time in the game the zombie
pigmen would not fight back so you would
get free XP free drops and it would be
like all automatic it was really easy to
set up this kind of farm for for a while
and then underneath here we had a hopper
minecart to pick up the drops drop him
off I think I sorted them no it didn't
sort them they would end up in these
chests here uh-huh
worked pretty good used it a lot till it
broke and I don't think it works to this
day right I haven't tried it in a long
time though alright one last thing to
check out here
I'm trying to hurry with the video
because it's so so crazy long yeah but
in the fortress there's one other thing
over here and I accidentally deleted
this in the world download so you guys
aren't gonna be able to check this out
yourself unfortunately it's too lazy to
fix it but we have the gasps blaster
3000 here
aha
to send me automatic tree farm where
basically you stand here and then the
gas shoots at you
yeah why where do we plant this stuff I
don't remember
anyways you would like hold right click
down it would plant the trees it would
push all the wood together here into a
strip the ghast would shoot the the wood
and the water would direct the gas ball
downward so it would hit the wood and
because it was right above the hoppers
the explosion wouldn't cause any
destruction to the wood and it would all
collect together in here ah this farm is
a little bit broken I think one of the
leaves destroyed some redstone I am Not
sure I have to look into it
haven't used it much to be honest
alright so we're checking out the final
branch of the nether hub I think there's
only two more builds we need to look at
before we're done the episode here first
off we're gonna check out the clay
mining outpost this is something I set
up to mine clay easier there's a system
for automatically sorting the different
colors into the chests here and also for
like if you want a storage minecart you
hit that sends it down to where you do
your mining and then when you return it
it goes up into the sorting system so
you and mine clay and you don't even
have to come back to drop it off and I
have done a lot of digging here later we
had the idea of making like a rude is it
rude or rube I think it's rude right
Rube Goldberg machine hmm you know what
I am going to cheat a little bit this
villager will not leave his house for
some reason so it's supposed to be a
villager here yeah and then basically it
releases the water we got some stuff
built with this Rube Goldberg machine
but it could be added to quite a bit but
first step of it is the waterfall which
is pretty slow so let's get another guy
we'll just put him in there and
apparently that didn't work is this
string missing oh that string update I'm
tell you it was the worst thing ever
yeah all the string in my world got
deleted it's so annoying he goes over
the gravel pile
but villagers apparently have the
ability to control mine carts that's
what I love that
oh we got a guy we got a guy okay here
we go here we go what a fail it's all
gonna get fixed to the next updates
villagers will no longer be able to
control nine carts or other mobs they'll
actually do what you want them to do
anyways after they go through that
initial step there's supposed to be a
whole bunch of other stuff and
eventually they'll end up at this parts
where they go into the the cliffside
it's like wait what's going on
is this the end and he shoots his giant
flamethrower at this village dreary
Ville is what I called this something I
built I think for the 400th episode
special if you want to check to this out
in more detail that was supposed to work
and basically he he's mad at the world
he wants it to burn down and he destroys
the mining outpost here and hidden was
throughout the whole place here we got
some TNT under like the logs and stuff
so as it burns slowly more and more of
it starts to tonight's the horse was the
enemy I believe then he was trying to
kill the horse which he succeeded good
job
I just wanted to build a flamethrower
basically and have something to destroy
that's that's the whole essence of this
build now he's starting to blow up and I
built it like entirely out of wood so it
would actually burn but then there's the
finale and hopefully maybe I think
there's several layers of like houses in
front of the finale it's like inside
there and once that burns
ah I'm so easily amused alright that's
pure evil here we go guys this is gonna
be the final thing on our list to check
out today I decided to skip over the
mini bass the one tall bass one high
bass whatever you want to call it
because I don't know where it is I can't
find it so this is the amplified bass
part way through the LP series here I
decided to switch over the world to
amplified it's just MBT Ted you have to
change in your level that file I believe
and so we got this amplified terrain
which looks awesome I really love how it
looks and the idea with this bass was
we're gonna use a lot of slime blocks to
do everything and that was like when
they first came out and I later realized
that the slime blocks aren't as cool as
I thought they have a lot more
limitations than I I wish them to have
but we did do some stuff here and I
think over all the stuff we did looks
generally pretty good we have the mobile
minecart system and what else did we do
here oh yeah the clock I got to finish
that clock cuz I actually really want to
see it working there's a clock that like
syncs itself properly to the time of day
in Minecraft
it just needs like a skin and a couple
couple little tweaks with the redstone
where is the mobile where's the mobile
minecart thing guys oh yeah is playing
around with like slime launchers to go
from one side to the other here I don't
know I would be so surprised that this
worked how did it work yeah it doesn't
work at all ah very cool slime blocks
are very frustrating for me because I
have like ideas I want to do with them
and then they never work out because of
some glitch or some other issue they
stick to things you don't want the
piston to or they can't move as much as
you want this looks like maybe it's
glitched outs there is a way of sending
the minecarts from one of one of these
bases to the other and the other and I
have it like all done I do
had to finish the minecart track I think
or something there's one really small
change I had to do to finish it and I
didn't do it because I'm lazy well
anyways guys that is gonna do it for
today's world tour episode let's get the
show on the road
and hopefully you enjoyed it I don't
know if I went too quick too slow I
tried my best guys if you want to see
things in more detail
like I couldn't use all the machines and
stuff and show you how they worked I
would have loved to if you want to see
it more detail either check out the
world yourself or watch the older
episodes where we go through things one
at a time well let's finish up as we
usually do here with the comment of the
day we have a very insightful comment
today from some guy 1 2 3 who says oh
thank you very much for for sharing that
with us much appreciated and I guess the
only thing left to do guys for this
episode is to give you a big fat thank
you thank you guys so much for being
with me all this time I really
appreciate it I started off this youtube
series this YouTube channel not really
super confident in myself or anything
like that I actually had no plans on
doing this long term and I was fully
planning on deleting my videos soon
after I uploaded them but thanks to you
guys the support the series has gone on
the YouTube channel has gone on you have
been actually very very nice to me very
rarely do I get negative comments you
give good criticism when you do and also
like even though I don't feel I'm very
good at heads at what I do here the
channel has gone very well for me it's
it's gotten a lot of views over over the
years here and yeah it's just it's
really cool so thank you guys so much
for for everything
hopefully you enjoyed today's episode
I'll see you again in the next one
thanks for watching take care
bye-bye
[Music]