[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series I was on my way over
to the Enderman farm to fix up my tools
and that this thing caught my attention
again how did you steal oh you jerk
you stole the music I can't believe that
I had an idea though maybe we should
move this because if I ever spawn the
dragon in this things get destroyed
anyway and it's not in a good place and
this portal got moved maybe we should
move our music randomizer over to the
Enderman farm I think that would be a
good idea I'm gonna do that to begin
with here today but first I'm gonna fix
up my tools like maybe maybe down here
would be a pretty cool spot for it ah I
just did something really stupid I set
up a comparator clock here and without
even thinking about it I just flipped
the lever try it out make sure it works
except I had already put all the items
in the in the droppers here now they're
all over the place and I have to put
them back in which was really annoying
because I basically got to put one at a
time alright awesome so I fixed my
little mistake there I got all the items
back into the droppers here I got 9
items in total whenever it's Alexis
stone sword then this comparator sends a
signal a distance of 3 and activates the
note block so that's kind of how this
all works it's actually really simple if
you guys ever want to try to copy this
it's it's not too hard to set up so what
I have to do now is put the hoppers
above here we got a Enderman proof this
as well we don't want them teleporting
down here and picking up the dirt blocks
or you know getting out of a farm so
we're going to cover over everything
here with water as well when we're all
done
so I'm just going to put like glass
probably at this level here and then
can't put it right above the note blocks
but I can put it one above and then more
water above that maybe is what we'll do
and I got the note box positioned on the
left and the right so it's kind of like
stereo sound got our comparator clock
over here which activates all the
droppers down the middle and we're going
to tune it to the G B major pentatonic
scale if my voice changed it was because
I was looking down there at my notes I
don't know anything about music I'm just
copying what you guys told me so we got
ten note blocks in total and then we're
just going to copy it on the other side
but we're going to tune it so zero
clicks two ticks clicks even 4 1 2 3 4 7
3 4 5 6 7 9 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
somebody said this makes it sound
oriental which would be cool 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 8 9 10 11 12 then 14 16 1921 alright
are you ready here we go
[Music]
beautiful music composed by ito
I love this thing this thing so cool I
noticed something though check this out
if I switch it to the one tick like it
sounds really cool
at first the the increased tempo I like
it a lot but I can't keep it at one tick
because then these repeaters they get
stuck on right because it's sending the
items into the hopper faster than they
can flow back out so so yeah the fastest
we can do it is at 2 but I got 9 items
in the randomizer if I decrease the
number of items we can get a faster
tempo and I think I'm going to try that
because I really like tell that sounds
great when you turn it on before they
all get locked up you know alright so we
got six items in each of these and with
the set two ticks let's try it again oh
I oh I did it again I didn't put the
hoppers back oh you know what it's
activating more note blocks but it's not
a faster tempo we can't get the faster
tempo gently darn it
it's this activating more note blocks at
once let's think about this if we how
about we send it I like how that sounds
I want to do that it's okay I did it on
purpose this time okay guys so here's
the deal I tried one or two other things
with the the randomizers there but I
just couldn't get anything to work
because of the speed limit of hoppers
they can only go so fast so in this in
this case we needed something something
better so I think I might have invented
a new type of randomizer here or at
least it's one I've never seen you know
there's millions of people playing
Minecraft I'm sure someone out there has
done this too but it's a design I've
never seen it's going to be my new go-to
design for randomizers I think because
it's in a lot of ways better than the
hopper dropper one this is a dropper
dropper randomizer so the idea is this
redstone line activates this first
dropper and then this one's facing into
it right they're both facing each other
one tick later one redstone tick later
it shoots the item back into this one
alright so
the cool thing is like it randomizes
going into this dropper and then it
randomizes coming back all in the same
sequence so it's like a double
randomizer which means you can do more
with less compared to the hopper dropper
ones anyway I think so
the only catch with this that I found is
you have to start it with one item in in
the dropper that you're detecting the
signal from otherwise the comparator
doesn't seem to update if it's because
it goes keep you real fast in out um and
in that one tick the comparator doesn't
change unless there's an item in already
alright so let's give it a try here ooh
super speed
randomizer haha you know that's not bad
just as it is yeah we might leave it
like that like I can add more items into
here if we were to put so if I want to
add items I'd put it into this one you
put in even stack them like that alright
you see it's kind of randomized to put
the sword back into here so pretty cool
so here's another really cool thing
because we're using a faster randomizer
I think we have avoided a problem I was
having with this one um you can see it's
still running but you don't hear any
music because I have left the end and
came back and sometimes when I do this
this gets stuck on even though it's not
supposed to but just from the chunks
unloading and reloading it messes it up
so I I constantly have to restart it
this one I've tried leaving and coming
back a few times and it doesn't suit
be affected by that see the clocks still
running oh never mind
really uh-oh because the items got
messed up
it's the comparators that the bearers
are messed up for some reason
if we shut off there should only be one
item in here there's two now okay so
this might have another problem if we
leave it running
darn it now it works that we restarted
it nope here's what I'm gonna do guys
I'm gonna put a stone pressure plate
right over here right over here there we
go
and the Enderman are going to land on
that if there's any Enderman here there
will be music and then when I fly away
they will be spawn once I get over 128
blocks away and that is before the
chunks unload so as long as I don't fall
in the void or something and die this
shouldn't mess up I think oh yeah let's
turn this down it's actually pretty loud
when when you have so many going here's
the next thing I want to try out
typically with Enderman farms you have
to put a roof over them and you can't
have more than like two and a half
blocks spaced like between the roofs and
that kind of sucks honestly so what I'm
gonna try here if you don't put the roof
on you get intermittent like all over
the place like this they teleport out of
their holding chamber here I'm gonna
take over the world I brought over some
maple blocks what happens if we
let's try this for right now I'm going
to do that
they only teleports when they hit the
ground here I've noticed or probably if
I punch up to land and they die for some
reason oh I just going to stop every
time I kill him - I didn't think about
that oh hey how did he do that he walked
over the magma block without dying
alright guys so I've been testing this
out here the magma blocks they seem to
be working pretty good actually
I don't think I need to put a roof on
this the idea is pretty simple basically
the Enderman up there they're in there a
grow at an endermite in a minecart right
and then they fall down they can't
actually get them but they stay agro at
them and when they hit the ground
because they're a grow they have a
chance to teleporting out of the holding
area they're on to the you know whatever
I build over here typically you got to
put a roof on this and then put water on
top of the roof to keep them from like
this watering your Enderman farm but
because they stay agro on the endermite
they also try to attack it and they'll
run to where he is which is like right
above here so they run right into the
magma blocks as soon as they teleport
[Music]
the only downside of course is you have
these stupid magma blocks right where
you want to click your stop but I kind
of liked it actually I think I'm going
to keep it okay guys so we're gonna do
something else now we're back over at
the man cave area and something I got to
do quite often in my world here is empty
my mob farm because it's got like arrows
bones gunpowder and especially zombie
flesh I don't just throw this away I
usually trade it for emeralds and I did
that earlier today before I started
recording and as usual it's kind of like
this annoying chore
I find it very annoying trading with
villagers I like getting the emeralds
for doing it but there's there's
something about the trade window let's
see if we can find a good villager here
I have a 36 cleric somewhere yeah okay
so here we go so if you trade with a
villager you have to like click to pick
up the zombie flesh and you guys drag it
over click to drop it then you gotta
click to pick up the emeralds and then
you got 28 left in the window here and
you gotta click drag put it there and
then put that back down and it's this
whole big process to do all this
eventually I figured out of course you
can shift-click can't you
okay you can't shift-click you should be
able to I thought you could if you put 2
in here it doesn't work so basically you
get one emerald at a time and you have
to click like 5 times it's really
annoying so we're gonna build a machine
to do this for us a little easier I
realized today while trading you could
do it like this you could have exactly
36 zombie flesh or however many they
take then you just have to press 1 while
hovering over the window you want press
1 to put it in there and then you press
Q on the emerald to throw it out and
then get 36 more that seems like a much
better way of doing it so we're gonna
try setup a machine to do that here in
our village hmmm
you know what I'm looking around our
village here I'm trying to find a spot
for our little gizmo but this place is
pretty cluttered already not a lot of
free spots left I think this is the best
place for it maybe right over here so
well dig in and we'll get started on it
a fairly simple idea really
but basically maybe we'll go in over to
here what I want to happen is I'm going
to set it up so that there'll be a trap
door above us
this will open up upwards any items on
top of the trapdoor will then fall down
on to us so we want 36 zombie flesh
ready to go we don't want it we don't
want to wait for it to get dispensed we
want it's like as soon as we throw the
Emerald in we get 36 more hopefully so
then we're going to have hopper in front
of us over here probably that we throw
the Emerald in once we throw an emerald
in we get this will open up drop 36 Dom
be flesh on us and then probably like
right over here there'll be a cleric
villager that we're trading with locked
behind a block or something and then
have I said and then I think I have will
have a bunch of droppers full zombie
flesh that shoot items out so if we're
doing 36 we might go for like 9 droppers
9 times 4 is 36 so we'd have to activate
the droppers 4 times to get what we need
or we could do 18 droppers that seems
excessive though we'll try it with with
9 oh the joys of moving villagers right
guys Oh such a pain alright I tracked
this guy down he almost got away from us
we got them into a spot here and I think
I got this setup now so this is our
little circuits I decided to use a
piston to pushes up into the trapdoor
because I forgot when a trapdoor opens
up upwards if there's any on the part
that's like the thin slice the items
just go up like an item elevator so yeah
I was thinking of old old game mechanics
where stuff will just fall through so
that that's a good way of dealing with
it basically if there are any items
going through this item hopper then
comparator turns on which then activates
a little bit of a pulse extender here so
this repeater
this wire here at along with this
repeater which n goes to a comparator
clock over here and up a little
staircase to the the nine droppers we
got up there the nine droppers are
powered right over here
I hear zombie think we're safe I think
we're safe yeah you see a piece of
redstone there right in the middle
dropper activates six of them and then I
got the repeater going through here and
back to the other three
trapdoor above here to make sure no
items shoot out and basically drop off
the zombie flesh in this chest goes to
all the hoppers that way into the into
the droppers so nice and simple let's
try it out close this all up I'm out of
blocks all right so to get it going you
throw in a block or an emerald or
something into here alright that gave us
36 items I guess I want my number one
slot opened up here so we got 36 zombie
flesh so all I got to do in theory is
press 1 and Q 1 and Q 1 and Q how to
brain for a second here's the other
problem though it's gonna get to the
point where you can't trade anymore so
maybe I should carry some extra emeralds
with me when I do the trading and I am
by some random garbage and refresh your
trade that way so yeah I'll keep 64 on
me alright help but it refresh itself
good 1 and Q 1 and Q how fast can we do
it oh I messed it up alright throw an
extra one in I guess 1 in Q I'm throwing
them up there maybe yeah let's do like
this guys this is a good idea I put a
trap door over there and then a slab
above it this allows us to collect the
XP nice and easy and it'll prevent me
from throwing the emeralds on top of the
block like I was doing there so let's
try this again I got some
we fish on me 1 and Q yeah good okay so
much easier Oh are we out of zombie
flesh already started but you get the
idea I think it's a cool little thing
yeah I didn't fill these all the way I
bet you one of these is low oh no wait a
minute yeah this one was empty okay that
makes sense so I got to make sure I fill
this up all the way
Wow decide to try out the horses today
guys see if any of them can break the
previous jump record and all of them
have failed gone through about ten of
them now this is our last horse to try
beat it
oh and he loves us let's try it out here
so we got to try to get on top the snow
here nope now I don't know guys it's
been about at least 50 or more horses
and none of them have been able to get
past this points alright guys so now
we've headed over to the amplified
terrain base and got something to try
out over here last last thing we did
over here is we built this kind of mind
thing we got started on it guys pretty
cool I like it something I've had a lot
of trouble with though with the
amplified bass here who is picking out a
building theme and also just building an
amplified ring kind of sucks to be
honest because there's like nowhere to
build I find I'll give you an example
like everywhere you go is these little
like tiny slanted slopes and there's not
really much flat ground beyond what I've
done over here this is like the only
good spot I've really been able to find
so I think we're gonna have to create
terrain and like put in midair so I'm
gonna try build or maybe not today but
we're going to try to get some houses
over on the side of the
Hildur if we can the main thing I want
to show you though here today is the
building theme I have recently thought
of that I think is going to be pretty
cool if you watch my modded series we
got the diesel bunker steampunk city and
I really like the color scheme we have
with that and I got thinking you know we
could probably do that here in vanilla
actually so let's give it a try here
then I've build a little bit more and
then underneath this dirt we'll have to
give it some sort of supporting
structure to make it look cool but
basically how we can do brick
I think brick would look pretty good
nice red people don't use brick a lot in
Minecraft mostly because it kind of
sucks to to collect it but yeah you can
do brick and then you can do the dark
oak like we have in the modded series
and the main other thing though is the
yellow yellow ground the Sandy bricks we
don't have that here but we can do path
blocks which are yellow so this is kind
of a good color combo we got here but
yeah here's a quick little sample I just
rigged together to give you an idea what
I what I had in mind really not much to
it we got some brick mixing some stairs
every now and then to make it look more
interesting mixed in some hardened clay
to make it look like the bricks falling
off
um maybe spruce fence windows I'm not
sure then you can do some nature stuff
like leaves and grass got some coarse
dirts spruce planks every now and then
would look good then use note blocks
like in the modern series I'd like to
hang a light from this - that would look
cool and we could do like oh you did
there and have have it kind of climbing
up the mountain and may go forward a
little bit as it goes up kind of a
rickety crazy-looking build
but yeah I think that might be cool let
me get know what you guys think of that
we don't have much time to get into it
today but I just thought I'd show it off
and I'm actually really excited to try
out this building style if not here
somewhere else because it could be cool
I think but yeah guys I think we should
wrap it up here for today's episode the
comment I picked out says etho why don't
you use the light rod thingies that you
can make from the new ender stuff you
know when these first came out I was
really really excited about them I'm
always really happy at new lighting
options my biggest complaint with these
and where I think Mojang might have went
wrong with them like they of course make
sense in the end
like even here I use them and I don't
really like them because they have this
purple bass thing on them and I very
rarely ever use the color purple in my
builds most blocks in the game are more
medieval themes right more neutral
colors and that kind of thing so it
doesn't really make sense to have these
purple and they can really stand out
whenever you use them because of that
so in general I haven't used them too
much maybe it's because I haven't
experimented enough with them but I feel
they only fit in certain situations and
not in general aha anyways hope you guys
enjoyed today's episode thank you very
much for watching and until next time
like what you could never use it here
red and purple no orange and purple no
green and purple yeah anyways have a
good day take care bye bye
you
[Music]