[Music]
gear readings everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys once again to another
let's play episode so check this out I
have set a new record for myself ever
since the villagers changed I've always
wondered like could you totally lock out
the trades with a villager and I got
this cleric to lock out five of the
seven trades which I've never done
before so there's a slim chance here we
might actually do it I thought I would
start recording and just see if it
happens so here we go do it one at a
time now it's it unlocked them okay so
five is my new record we didn't get
beyond that all right that was kind of
anticlimactic
what is your guys's record have you gone
beyond five is it possible I think it is
but very unlikely so the plan for today
guys we're gonna be working on slab city
some more here tried to figure out what
we're doing with it a little bit better
I just introduced the idea last time and
you guys seem to really enjoy it so
that's cool it's a simple idea but I
think it has a lot of potential looking
through the comments the main thing you
guys mention is oh I can't believe Ito
is working with with even numbers he's
crazy and I was doing that because I
wanted the these slabs or tiles or
whatever we're building here to align
with the chunk borders here I thought
that would be a cool thing and we never
build with even numbers it would be make
it look a little different cuz you use
different patterns and stuff when you
work with even numbers but you know I
thought about it more after you guys
mentioned it's like yeah I think we'll
switch over to odd because anytime you
do like technical stuff like with water
streams or minecart tracks or red stone
building with even is just terrible it
really is so I think it's a good idea to
change we're gonna go to 9 by 9 by 5
tiles instead of 8 by 4
aha
very good so it looks almost exactly the
same to what we had before but we have
switched over to odd numbers nine by
nine by five tiles but they share
borders with each other so for example
this this is the border with this style
but it's also the border of this style
so it's like nine by nine by five minus
one on all the dimensions so eight by
eight by four which is what we had
before so it's really no change except
we have odd numbers now does that make
sense sure it does makes total sense
uh-huh okay so what I want to do now
guys I want to start adding some details
to this maybe not to the point where
it's totally finished but so it looks a
little bit better because right now it's
really plain and then we'll start doing
some other building here I'm gonna do
something I don't think we've ever done
in this series or at least I can't
recall any time I've done this we're
gonna use jungle planks oh my goodness
if you don't know I actually don't like
jungle planks but I'm starting to not
hate them as much I think I think we'll
try it with this bill just for some
variation and maybe let's do our ugly
brick thing over here instead because
every base needs an ugly brick thing
like no question has to be done let's
try just do a simple thing here maybe
some stairs let's just do a few things
here together and I'll do a bunch
off-camera and then we'll do some
building okay because I do want to make
a lot of progress on this today - let's
make this come over like this huh
perfect amazing beautiful and we'll put
that there
then I'll do dark oak like a so dark up
here and then orange clay in the
backgrounds because that looks amazing
and we end up with something like this
so a lot of this stuff we're doing is
this going
a trial to begin with like I don't know
if we're actually gonna keep it I'm
gonna try keep it there for a while and
see if we liked it after after a bit
here still so just gonna add some last
couple decorations to it and I think
let's actually get rid of that and try
to get the dark oak showing so I made
some slabs no that doesn't work what if
we put stairs I'm out of stairs well
back to the crafting table okay get a
couple more of those break is one of
those materials I don't have a lot of so
I don't want to get too carried away
with it either looks a bit better I'm
gonna try we're not gonna do it exactly
like the manty where we do both sides
like oak but I'm gonna try to do just
one side here with oak because I think
it'll look a bit better we want to keep
some stone brick with this build though
we don't want to get rid of it all for
sure oak is good cuz it matches the path
block there and it'll go with a few
other blocks were using so I I kind of
like that right we could even mix in
some jungle wood with this alright so
check it out here we've added that some
details to our builds and I think it's
feeling a bit better I think it looks a
bit better now but it's not all the way
there is it at least that's my feeling I
feel like something's not quite right
with it but we're off to hopefully a
good start
so you see we've got the jungle wood
mixed in here I've added some coarse
dirt in places some brown concrete some
flowers and grass underneath here I
added a design with the slabs this feels
very plain up here still we should do
something with that maybe turn it into a
water tower with a pool of water you can
see at the top right now I think it's
still just grass there isn't it let's
double check
yeah so maybe we'll put like a pond in
the top there for a bit of variation - I
think that'd be cool whoops and made
sort of a a door thing here this is
gonna go into a building I think and
yeah
okay so I have expanded over here we're
gonna start in a new territory we're
gonna build our very first farm with our
new place here a lot of the farms were
gonna build to begin with are gonna be
pretty simple I think not like anything
super crazy or super automated just our
basic needs and one of the things I
think we need is a tree farm so let's
focus on that so I'm gonna send me
automate it though I do want to try to
do something a little bit cool with it
observers you need observers so I'll try
show you the plan I want to be able to
plant the tree like right here have it
automatically grow and then push the
wood out of the hole up to this level
here kind of like we did in our our
Brown mushroom firm we built recently
although I did just design a new thing
for doing it so it's gonna be slightly
different because I couldn't remember
how I did that and I was too lazy to go
check okay so we're gonna have an
observer block check whenever the tree
is planted and then we want it to shoot
out bonemeal at the tree out of a
dispenser here so this will be full of
bone meal okay so I just ripped up the
ground here so I can show you how to do
the redstone for this real quick
hopefully first thing we're gonna do is
put a repeater here so now when we plant
the tree you can see it activates that
repeater and we want to send this a
bunch of pulses so first thing we'll do
is set up a a timer a long delay or
whatever so now and we wouldn't do this
you see it slowly fades out there so
it'll keep this comparator active for
quite a while and then we do a pulse
pulsar like this so signal goes around
and back to itself in subtract mode and
it'll send the pawl
- this constantly so now all right so
that'll be our tree growth system very
good all right so the next thing we want
to add is some way of pushing the wood
blocks out of the hole here because
after the tree grows there's gonna be
two logs in there and like if you go
chop them down
guess what you're stuck down here so as
a little convenience thing we'll try to
push him out with the double extender
that goes upwards right the reason we're
going to blocks down though is like if
we were to try to screw the trees on the
surface you have to have the dispenser
next to it like that right and it's
gonna be sticking out of the ground plus
you need all the redstone to do the
tricks so that's gonna be on the surface
- and by putting it two blocks down we
can hide everything and try to make it
look nice even if you do it like this
where you have the dispenser facing up
to a tree like that that has bonemeal in
it doesn't hit the sapling it hits the
dirt block so that won't grow the tree
otherwise you could hide it underground
pretty easy but unfortunately that's not
the case if you have a grass block here
it tries to bonemeal the grass so you
get the sparkles but it won't grow the
tree either aha nothing happens anyways
let's get to it here so I prep the area
here again for our double extender or
vertical the extender and what we got to
do this is the block that the sapling
grows on so we want to get two sticky
pistons facing up under it's like a sow
and now we've got to activate them in
the right sequence so the trick is to
put a block there next to the dirt block
got a block there and and then what I
think a regular piston goes there
an observer facing the other way we want
the observer to get activated by the
piston arm extending
it's really hard to place in the way you
want sometimes okay so this is the site
that detects its so when the piston arm
goes up this detects it sends power to
that and that'll activate this piston
when it's up here makes sense yes it
does okay now to activate this in the
right sequence we set this to four and
then we do a branching path so I think
for for this one and thirteen ticks on
this side so that's four repeaters we'll
leave one at one and do that so if we
send a pulse to the wire here it'll make
the block go up and then make it come
down it activates it twice let's try it
out Oh observer okay let's let's check
it out again that's like as fast as you
can do it with this
so we still got one last thing we got to
do with our design here we have to
detect when the tree grows over here and
then tell that double extender to
activate basically we could check using
this observer like when the sapling
turns into a wood logs and cause
something to happen but that's actually
really difficult to do it gets really
complicated so we're gonna do it the
old-fashioned way where we're just gonna
set up a second thing here that goes
like this and we keep this powered so
that when the log appears over here when
the sapling turns into a log then the
signal can pass through and then from
here we tell to go to that extender
basically the problem is if we do that
we run into another problem those double
that double extender they're the piston
comes up to here and then this for Peter
powers it so it prevents it from being
able to retract so we have two unpowered
as' at the right time too in order for
that thing not to jam so this gets a
little bit more complicated because of
that we have to add an RS nor latch here
so piston piston here and basically they
when this pushes the block over this
gets unpowered and then we just got a
time it just writes so the timing is for
set that to four and then we need four
repeaters set it for here
okay and that keeps a count of like how
long it takes the double extender to
extend and retract basically next thing
we got to do you see we got a trapdoor
down here like we saw before if we send
this a pulse that activates this twice
and
oh and then where is it cuz of that
thing did that mess it up oh whoa oh
yeah work that time hmm well basically
from this we're supposed to branch down
to here and I don't know why that didn't
work actually let's just see what
happens if we put a log there oh good
that was good that's what's supposed to
do okay looks good okay we might be fine
let's give it a test test run here so
we're gonna plant a sapling yeah I think
we're good to go
okay there we go so I copied our design
three more times here we're gonna have
four trees in total and the reason for
that is just because we have no way of
clearing the leaves with her or gizmo
here so they have to de-spawn naturally
which which takes a bit of time right if
you're just doing one tree at a time
waiting for two despawn it's not really
you're not gonna use it even for is kind
of on the low side but it's something
well we got it covered over here so
we're gonna do our first real test with
this now we find out if it's actually
practical or not you can design
something and then when you got to use
this like well that's cool but no no
we'll try it with the different
different trees here - so spruce works
oh it did stop okay good whoo
acacia might be a troublesome one that
looks dying okay I think we tried oak
already birch trees Oh
purchase good and jungle trees so we
can't do dark oak with this that's the
only limitation but this is something I
wanted for our base to just having a
nice open field here so if we want to
plant two by two trees we have a place
to grow it's you know because a lot of
our base is gonna be these little 9x9
areas and this is a like two of them to
buy two of them right we've got quite a
bit more space so we chop it down and
you see we don't have to go down there
to get the wood we might want to put a
block over top or some glass so that we
can reach it all yeah cuz I don't really
like that and having to Pillar up to the
gravit right so I was thinking of
something here I don't I don't really
like this having a chest with the
saplings in because you got to go over
here and grab for however many you're
gonna plant and then like put them back
and what I would like is some way of
dispensing for saplings at a time for
whichever one we choose so we're gonna
put put a device over here for doing
that I just figured out how to do it is
this is one of the jane kiaus Treadstone
jobs I've ever done but it works it's
like really weird the way I got this
thing to to work so I think we will go
in a little bit here just so it's not
totally flat walls either you know and
I'm gonna use dark oak for now but it'll
probably change this to something else
later but this is our shape like this
and then we're gonna have six dispensers
for the six different types of trees or
droppers I mean over here and then we'll
do it like this where we have some stone
brick or some other block down here like
so and then let's grab six buttons and
we'll align them over here so basically
press the button here we get four
saplings for whatever tree goes there
okay oh you know what guys as we do this
I got a story I could tell you two today
well not
a story more like a personal experience
which might get you encouraged or
motivated so about a month ago I made
the decision that I'm gonna get into
exercising like really commit to it
in general I've I'm in decent shape but
which one are we missing dark oak let's
go up there I'm in decent shape but over
the years I've been getting worse and
worse shape to be honest like I used to
play sports I used to do tennis and and
baseball and hockey and all kinds of
stuff and it's hard to focus but all of
that is kind of ended also is like very
physical with my work and stuff before
and doing YouTube I'm sitting in a chair
all day right so it's not it's not so
good so I decided I want to get into
exercising I keep hearing it's really
good for you both physically and
mentally you should try to exercise at
least 50 minutes every day so finally I
decide to commit because honestly I was
starting to feel really sluggish like no
energy even if I had a good night's
sleep I was just like tired all the time
and I had I had that couch potato
feeling you know where you go to where
you're sitting down and you don't want
to get up I kept like feeling that it
was like something's not quite right
right so I decided to get into extra
exercising so I've been doing about 5 to
15 minutes of exercise every day for the
last month or so and honestly it has
been way better than I expected like the
results are way better than I could have
even dreamed for one thing I've gained a
lot of muscle mass which is nice but
especially in terms of energy and stuff
oh it's so much I'm like never tired now
like unless I didn't get enough sleep
right but I feel good in general and I
and in a good mood much better mood than
I was before in general so that's really
cool
and like when I first started I didn't I
made sure not to overdo it that's a
mistake I've always made whenever I
exercise in the past like I do as much
as I can push myself to the limit and
then I'm sore for four or five days and
in pain it's like man that really sucks
I don't want to exercise ever again
right this time I've been taking a lot
more easy a lot easier whenever I do
exercise not really pushing myself to to
the pain where I destroy the muscles
quite so bad right and that makes the
next workout a lot easier cuz you know
you have to recover as long right and
that's worked out really good so like
the first time I exercised I only did
like ten sit-ups right and it's fairly
easy it wasn't hard I didn't enjoy doing
it of course but I I stuck to it and
after about the fourth third or so
workout I actually was starting to enjoy
it like it wasn't so bad at that point
what I do here uh-oh I'm a little bit
lost with what I'm doing I think we need
okay so the buttons over here I think we
need redstone torches here so it locks
the dispensers or the droppers above but
yeah basically what I'm trying to say
guys is if you're on the fence about
getting into exercising I highly
recommend it it's worth it definitely I
was just doing it more as a trial and
like if it didn't make much difference
after a month I probably wouldn't do it
as much but I'm definitely gonna
continue I think it's I think it's worth
it for sure and like I'm doing more than
just sit-ups I'm doing like push-ups and
I got some weights for my arms and doing
back exercises I'm trying to get a nice
range of things doing squats for my legs
nothing that you need any fancy
equipment for though just like stuff you
can do at home don't
go to the gym and before I started I
wasn't really sure what kind of results
I would get so just to give you an
example from my own experience here the
one exercise I've been doing the most in
this last month is sit-ups like I'll do
sit-ups and then I'll take a day or two
break from it and then I'll do them
again because you're supposed to give
your muscles time to recover I don't
know how long it you're actually
supposed to I don't know much about
exercising but I've just been doing it
like every second or third day basically
and that seems to be working out we got
four but like I said I could only view
about ten the first time and after about
a month I can do it 80 like in one shot
or one set or whatever they're called so
in a way it's almost like I'm eight
times stronger within a month just by
exercising that muscle so that is pretty
significant if you ask me what was that
sound is that a new cave sound I've
never heard that before
I think cuz I've updated I have the new
sounds but I'm still on the old 1.12 but
yeah anyways this is something I'm
excited about right now so I thought I'd
share my experience with you just in
case it encourages you definitely
nothing bad about exercising but let's
get back to this so those redstone
torches lock all these droppers so you
can see even if I send them a signal
doesn't shoot anything out it's only
when we press the button it unlocks the
dropper turns the redstone torch off and
then we send it four pulses and we get
forced saplings pretty simple so yeah
like all of these receive the four
pulses all all six of these droppers but
only the one that's unlocked will
actually shoot the items out and in
order to get four pulses we have to run
this extra set of observers in the back
there which we trigger with a trapdoor
so we have a lot of decorating and stuff
to do around here still
writing this I don't know it's better
right uh maybe you should put clay here
instead of wood it would make more sense
baby I don't know we got a lot of stuff
to do though let me know what you think
about this part of its like is this a
good or should we change it I don't know
today was more of a technical day
because that was what I was in the mood
for
we still need to decorate this I'm gonna
just put a border around it I think
that's definitely an improvement it's
important we do technical stuff though
and actually build farms with the space
otherwise we're not gonna come here and
and use it right and it's not gonna have
much character if it doesn't have unique
farms like this is something we don't
have built anywhere else in the world so
it's kind of cool all right that feels a
little bit better this is ugly though
what do we do about this we save it for
another day because that is the ephah
way all right guys I think we're gonna
wrap up here for today actually so
here's the comment of the day it says I
am loving this new base idea as someone
who really enjoys modular design like
this I think it's great how it will look
my only slight worry is I think it will
be a lot harder if all the slabs are
stone brick and grass I think possibly
it should be reserved for garden slash
outside slabs either way love your work
keep doing what you are doing that's a
good that's a good point
I think definitely anything inside the
slabs or tiles is gonna be something
besides grass and I think we will have
different themed areas like deserts
maybe snow mycelium lavas areas maybe I
don't know it'll be easy to transition
between different teams though my
concern is how do we avoid using so much
grass like what should we use instead I
really like the way grass looks
personally but
don't want it to be too much like the
man TV either I don't know
I'll see what you guys say in the
comments about what we built here to
date and where we should go in the
future but that's gonna do it for today
so hopefully you enjoyed this episode
thank you for watching as always and
I'll see you in the next one
take care bye bye
[Music]