[Music]
hey how's it going everybody this is
etho welcome back
check out this crazy place i found today
it's pretty cool looking isn't it i like
it you got like
all these arches and and overhangs you
got lava falls waterfalls
crazy cliffs check out this mountain up
here
some pretty amazing scenery
pretty pretty scenery huh
take one good look at it because it's
about to get destroyed
so i don't know how much of you care
about my
resource gathering i do most of that off
camera but
the desert where i have been getting
sand from i realized it's actually
kind of connected to the desert
right by our man cave so if i keep
taking sand from there
eventually we're gonna have a giant hole
right next to
where we live we gotta do it
gotta do it so i decided rather than
like keep taking sand from there we we
gotta find a new spot um
i think i gotta place it there come on
come on yeah
oh man so this is our new spot amplified
terrain area it's pretty cool um
you know when i first converted my world
to amplified i thought
maybe we would have sand that's like
over 10 blocks thick in places like
maybe 20 blocks or 30 blocks thick
because like what are these tall
mountains made out of
um unfortunately no it's just like a
normal deserts that you can't do like
the torch trick and get
crazy amounts of sand all really easy
because the majority of the mountains
actually sand
stone not sand like it's
very very thick sandstone in a lot of
places
but yeah just thought i would show you
guys do we have any more sand to drop i
guess there's that up there if we want
okay this might be a pretty good one
here let's try it out
oh yay that was pathetic
here let's try a little further it looks
like there's a bunch connected though if
we
do here no it's
it's not happening guys it's not
happening
huh there we go i didn't get that though
darren i thought it was gonna do a whole
chain around the the lip here
guess not yeah most these overhangs
won't fall because there's sandstone
underneath
but i just had an idea but we'll have to
make a backup for this so
here we go okay so here we are
this is a backup and i
i removed all the stone and all the
sandstone in this mountain so that we
could do this one thing
because we have to do it we just have to
it's going to be amazing
all right here we go and
no that's not the right spot no that
won't do it
we should start low so it'll climb its
way up maybe let's
try this looks like it
might work
let's do it here okay here we go
oh man it's starting it's happening
oh my goodness now that is a sand fall
if i've ever seen one oh and there goes
the frames
the lighting updates are real oh what
happened here
oh that's interesting it didn't do it
all the way because it must start
um sloping downward there
let's do the other side then
uh this is what you live for in
minecraft moments like these
they're just so much fun
okay so enough gooping around let's get
to it here i'm just gonna dig up an
inventory of sand and bring it back
um this is not very far away from our
base either it's like 2 000 blocks out
or so
and i got another tunnel that goes here
so it's it's not
any farther to get to than the other
place really
uh but yeah i'm gonna get some sand then
we're gonna use this to make some tnt
because we got a lot of gunpowder just
laying around and taking up space
let's pop the chest all right
so we are starting to get quite a bit of
tnt in our world here
like we got over a chest of it at least
and i'm not sure
what to do with it all so if you guys
have ideas let me know
because i use it a little bit with
demolition but
not like quick enough to how quick i'm
getting it now
so we could we could blow a bunch of it
on something fun
but anyways guys i have made my way over
to the amplified terrain
area again we're gonna do some building
here
i have decided on a path style so let's
try this out
well we're going to work on this area
particularly so i think
it's going to be like a worn down path
style
in the middle it's going to be these
slabs mostly
we'll make them too tall and then
kind of next to these we're gonna
scatter different types of stone
and grass and stuff so it'll be like
let's see let's get some of this stuff
like we'll have
thawed piece of cobblestone every so
often mixed in
let's see how this is going to look
then maybe some of this cracked stone
and regular stone just just a bunch of
random stuff let's see what else should
we try
i was going to put grass for sure so
we'll have
just little pieces of grass and i think
if we
do this on a large scale it's going to
look pretty decent
uh-huh that looks pretty bad
it's going to take some practice to get
it looking good i think
let me try it out here though i'm sure
if i get the proportions right
and mix it properly it'll look pretty
good
you guys will have to let me know if you
like this or not so this is what it
looks like on a larger scale um
i kind of like it but at the same time
i'm worried
it's too busy too messy i know not
everybody likes this kind of look
um you don't you don't want it to be too
random too messy because then it looks
like it's
somebody just threw up all over the
place so
one thing i might try to tone it down a
bit
is replace all the the slabs with gravel
to lower the contrast and maybe it'll
blend a little bit nicer
so let me let me attempt that yet
uh no i think the contrast was good
actually i don't like this at all
changing it back
so i'm just going to wait for you guys
feedback before i attempt any more
adjustments to this path so
let's move on to something else here i
want to add a guardrail for this
this pit because i'm clumsy
i'll fall down it if there's no no
safety rail
so let's do that uh we could go for iron
bars i'm going to try fences first
just see if these are any good maybe
every second block we will place one
all around
over there and then on top we will put
slabs
these ones here let's try these see what
this looks like
and put it there
maybe there okay
oh and good
that doesn't look too bad right
goes all the way against good let's
let's take a
look from a distance see if we like it
that's not too bad i kind of like it
then
to add more character to it let's create
some stairs
see my crafting bench is here
i got no blocks oh man
always prepared i sure wish i had a
backpack or something in this i never
have enough inventory spots
all right let's get
let's get it over here maybe we'll do
those kind of stairs and let's put a
block below
we'll probably need lighting too so i
did bring some sea lanterns
maybe every second one we will add a sea
lantern below
so we'll put one there and have that
going all around
can i reach i can't reach you know i
should have do this first
i'm building in reverse which is never a
good thing
and i also brought some of these blocks
to put by the sea lanterns let's try the
dark ones
yeah i think that could work they
actually go pretty good with stone
bricks don't they
uh-huh let me try that out all right so
there we go i think that's pretty good i
like that
i love these prismarine blocks man they
are so cool they go with a lot of stuff
too
like i saw doc was using it in his world
tour with spruce
and they they blend pretty good with
spruce wood even
um i like them with nether brick and
they look good with stone and pretty
much everything
in my opinion anyway so now
i want to make this opening a little bit
bigger
you know i when i play minecraft i
usually
don't go for these really tall buildings
or
tall tunnels or anything like that
i think i should get into that more
because it makes things look a little
bit more
epic you know and
tada there we go so it's it's not super
tall but it is a little bit taller but
like four or five blocks just makes it
feel
a bit more spacious a bit more open i
like it
so maybe one more thing we will do
i'm thinking about adding a staircase
here so we'll go
up a little ways and then maybe switch
back i wonder we should maybe think
about switching back already
so maybe it's kind of hard to see
how much higher is it to the top of the
mountain here
not not very tall one two three four
five
six seven eight nine or so blocks i
think that's
probably a good spot for a platformer
over here
then we'll go in a bit and then we'll
start going up
this way
yeah let's go over um
actually we probably gotta go a little
bit higher
whoops let's go a little bit higher
okay maybe here and then we will go
and make a platform at this level
okay and then
go in a couple blocks this way like two
or three and then starts
our next staircase going up so like over
here
and let's just see where this takes us
um then after this yeah we might do some
slime block stuff around here
oh this is right underneath that boat
thing i made
that's fine i think we're gonna take
that out anyway
all right and yeah
yeah i think that'll work
awesome so we got quite a bit done here
today guys i'm happy with this
um there's a staircase here still needs
some work
though quite a bit of work but just i
just wanted some basic way of getting up
on this mountain because i
i have to ender pearl every time i want
to come back up to the
these chests or to my bed or to the
portal so just
get something a little more permanent
set up would be nice
and the reason we're doing the path like
this or at least
possibly doing the path like this is
because the buildings are going to be
mostly
spruce wood so if i did the path like
what we had
here and then the buildings are spruced
everything's going to be brown
that's that's probably not going to look
too good so just to add more contrast to
our buildings around here
i figured we should pick a different
path type so let me know what you think
about
that we're gonna go set up some slime
block stuff
now and even though we have the
staircase i still will probably jump off
of here every time
because this is way more convenient
isn't it
all right where do we gotta go whoa
we're fine we're good two hearts didn't
hurt
okay well that's guilt in there it's
kind of scaring me
okay he doesn't see us we gotta make a
slime block thing to launch us
from here to this side of the path
so let's experiment with this
uh maybe we will put it
i guess to line it up we would want it
about here right
so let's try that out we will plan to
put a piston
down here slime block on top
all right and in order for it to not
stick we got to use
furnaces
okay very good and i'll put the pressure
plate
to activate it in the front this one
here
so you would walk up like this and it
should launch us that way
and to do that we will have to go down
see the pressure plates there so we have
to put a piece of redstone underneath
here and i'll do it i will do it don't
you worry
i got in trouble for something i can't
remember what it was but i did not put
redstone on stone brick one day or in
one one
episode of something and people caught
me for it so i gotta make sure i do that
uh because it's one of my rules i do
just so i know what blocks have redstone
on if i'm ever digging around and see it
from
the the underside or whatever i know not
to
not to break that block okay now we
gotta go
up we're gonna have another piston over
here
steepest in okay slime block there
so this one will shoot us up this one
will shoot us sideways
i wonder how much of this land we're
gonna have to clear for that to work
though
all right anyway let's not worry about
that too too much let's just get this
working
and i will i'll turn these around later
let's just get them there for right now
so we gotta get run the wire up to there
and again stone brick
get a repeater going this probably won't
work for you on a server if you
attempt this so if you ever do something
with more than one
uh piston you're gonna have trouble with
latency so
any of these double slime block piston
things
don't really work too well on servers i
have found
all right we'll put a block there and
redstone there
actually let's move this to the other
side
we're just doing a staircase up
basically
okay good
like that and that should work
and i did not fully heal even so get
ready for a splat
let's try clear some more land just to
make it less likely
all right i was having trouble with it i
think i see why now you probably noticed
this
i did not break the block above the
redstone here so it wasn't actually
staircasing up
this one right here okay now let's try
it
no okay
it might not be powerful enough let's
try it again
this time i'm gonna actually like run
and and change my looking direction and
stuff so that
hopefully we go a little bit further so
i'm gonna
run into it and then turn left while
holding forward oh wow
oh okay
and oh we hit our head
ah i think we're hitting our head that's
why it
might not be working so i gotta clear
more land
yep that's what it was i was still
hitting my head on a few blocks so i
cleared out some more space got it
working and it is
really cool uh check this out guys so
you just run up to it and
huh isn't that cool that's that's quite
a distance let's
count this actually one
okay that was control not shift
whoops thank goodness for uh
feather falling am i right i would have
died so many times today without it
two three four five six seven
eight block gap here plus like the one
two three four
five six yeah that's
that's like almost 15 blocks so that's
pretty cool
let's try again seems fairly consistent
i say that and it fails you gotta hit it
just right though you gotta be right
between the
yeah right between there we go
when it works it works but you gotta get
the right positioning
oh oh no
oh no oh i think i let go forward
i think that's why i fell i didn't have
as much momentum
oh no okay i gotta try it a few more
times
i can't have it failing like that
um let me get my stuff again
yeah it's super consistent guys never
fails never
never fails okay maybe we'll just try it
a couple more times try a few different
things to understand it better
so i'm going to do it once without
sprinting
and without holding forward
wow okay that makes a huge whoa i almost
died again
that made a huge difference you gotta
sprint you gotta hold forward
all right i i didn't just die or
anything that's not why my levels are
lower
it's not what happened okay we'll try it
again here
um it seems like holding
just forward isn't enough either but
just for the video i'll do it again
it's close it's very close but i think i
got a sprint as well
we'll try it now with the sprinting and
holding forward
oh skeleton let's get back up there real
quick
and okay sprinting and forward
i think it's because i'm turning
there we go yeah if i turn too soon
it doesn't work and that's why it keeps
failing
so let's try that again i just got to
get used to it
oh i would have made that if i was
positioned better i think i
stuck on the wall too long it it's it's
tricky
it's definitely tricky oh
crazy slime block okay one more time
don't shoot me
oh
so maybe i'll make it
one block of a short one block shorter
so that there's no risk because it's i'm
only off by one block if i
am that's what keeps stealing me
okay we gotta figure it out
all right everybody we are back at the
man cave and
we have a dancing spider
what is he doing all right he's done
we have 10 more horses or about 10 more
horses to try out here for our
our jumping thing that spider has got
some moves man
he's using all eight of those legs the
best he can
okay so last time
we did not get any improvements
this time we will see and so far
not looking too good first guy is a fail
we basically are just trying to get the
horse to be able to jump up to the
snow here all right let's try this guy
and it does not have to be a fully
charged jump to get a full
jump guys
just has to be close i keep trying even
though i think we've done it but
just to be sure yeah can't do it okay
yeah if you're one one tick below a full
jump it still counts as a full jump with
the horses
what's your problem dude come on did i
not give you sugar
okay now he's cool with me apparently i
didn't even see the hearts
what was up with that yeah this guy's no
good
all right so if none of these guys show
any improvement i think we just have to
say goodbye to this
project these guys are getting annoying
because this is like actually my 40th or
50th horse
attempt and
if no improvement with that many horses
okay have not given up then we
possibly have an improvement here i'm
gonna stash this guy down here
oh man it's about time
i knew this was gonna get hard later
where am i cooking
but i did not expect it to get this
difficult so soon
because we're only at like 4.3
block jumping height and it goes up to
5.5
get a mophie yeah you make them run
all right let's check this guy out
nope no good
no this guy's no good whoa
oh no
i'm not getting a straight jump but he
looks pretty low on
the jump height there yeah not even
close
all right and oh this guy jumps pretty
high
not quite enough though not quite there
last guy to try out let's let's see what
the brown guy can do
come on oh he's fast
compared to other guys anyway but
on jumping heights he kind of stinks
okay
so that's it we got one improvement
uh let's take him to the jump height
checker
okay let's try this guy out and see what
he actually can do can you do 4.25
yep no problem let's go one more step
up yeah no problem can you do 4.5 that
is the big question
that's what i want to see uh-oh
uh oh no i don't think so
no you can't darn it
so the two horses i was using for
breeding one of them was a 4.25
one of them is a 4.375 so
now we'll have two two parents that are
4.375 so it's like half a step
improvements
and from 40 to 50 horses
and we got to go from here all the way
over
here gonna take
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of horse breeds i
think to do that oh man what do we do
should we keep going i don't know
well i'll try it for a little bit more
until we see no improvement i think
all right everybody so it is that time
again we're going to wrap it up here
um i haven't done this in a while but
maybe i'll ask you guys
what would you like to see me do for the
next episode is there a specific project
you would like me
to work on or maybe something new i
should start
uh give me your feedback and i'll try to
judge the collective
direction i guess and maybe we'll do
that next time
um so here are the comments for today
this one says etho
do you ever get lost in the man cave
uh i get lost pretty easy
in this game and in real life but no i
don't get lost in the man cave
because i built everything here so i
have a pretty clear idea
of where to go i am curious so if you
guys get lost like i
try to walk around it as much as i can
especially when we're doing these
comments
um but i do a lot of jump cuts in my
videos and sometimes i worry that
might make it difficult to follow like
where i'm going or where i am in the
world
or like where stuff is located in
relation to each other
so i don't know hopefully it's not too
jump cutty um anyway second comment says
what happened to the map making series i
miss it because i would
i would love to play it that is in
regards to battle bane
so i did that uh mad bomber challenge
thing
just the other day had a lot of fun with
that
i want to get back into the map making
stuff again soon so i'm going to really
try
uh it just kind of got forgotten again
it i don't know it's it's tough to do
that and be a youtuber because that's
something i really enjoy doing but it's
not something that really gets views
so yeah i have to
anytime i spend doing that is time i'm
not doing something else i should be
doing
is the problem so i'm gonna try to get
into it again though
because i i really do enjoy it and i got
so many ideas for other
like map projects that i would love to
do if i had the time
so i don't know we'll we'll keep trying
at it
anyway that's it for today guys i hope
you enjoyed
i will see you again in the next episode
hopefully until then
bye bye
[Music]
you