welcome home everybody we're back in the
cave again we're going to take a break
from the nether for a little while I
could tell people were getting bored
with it they seen enough for a while so
we're going to do stuff here again and
not just them I had a really bad
experience yesterday in the nether and I
don't want to go back there for a while
myself I got trolled I got trolled so
bad oh person that trolled me
I'll give you applause because wow you
got me good in the comments of last
episode somebody posted these
coordinates to an area in the nether
that had three blaze spawner x' so
obviously I had to go check it out all
right there's no way I could resist that
um the thing is it was like they said it
was like a negative 500 X and negative
1000 Zed so I wasn't really thinking
about was like okay I'll just go check
it out and I started walking didn't
really have much stuff on me when I left
I had I brought one fire resistant
potion with me a couple speed potions a
little bit of food a little bit of wood
my pick was pretty much worn out when I
left oh and it was just a nightmare
because that was a long long trek and I
fell in the lava
early and I used my fire resistant
potion so I was on edge the whole time
my pic broke so I ended up using stone
picks and just digging through the
ceiling at points I ran out of food
eventually and I had to like scour the
area for mushrooms and I only had enough
wood on me to make like four bowls so I
couldn't leave my crafting bench behind
or anything like that I had to be
careful anyway I get there there's like
a fortress nearby so I'm checking all
these fortresses nothing there's a big
fat lie that's what it was big troll ah
and then I had to go back and it just oh
he got me good
took about two hours total to get back
there and back just about died countless
times and I had my good tools on me too
I had my my axe here and I had my silk
touch pick I had a fishin C pick so I
really didn't want to lose those made it
back live just took a long time anyway
today I want to work on cleaning up this
cave area some more to start out with
anyway first things on the list is the
potion room I keep saying I'm going to
complete it off-camera but that never
happens so if I make a point of it maybe
it'll actually get done alright awesome
that actually worked
I got it finished here took me a couple
hours but it's done are you ready to see
the complete potion room you better have
said yes okay here we go
door still works got rid of the wood I
tried stone bricks didn't like them at
all so then I just went netherrack so I
it's a little bit of a darker feel to it
but I actually really like it I think it
feels good I did the sandstone striping
on the top which I'm pretty happy with I
also have kind of a I don't you'd call
it it ring on the ground here to kind of
match the top oh yeah I added nether
warts above here with lights above it's
kind of cool I like it the nether wart
obviously won't grow but it's just for
looks
I like these corners they kind of match
they have glowstone at the bottom at the
top glowstone at the bottom and at the
top and that's CA 2 your words so for
all four of these corners which has a
nice feel to it still got our pixel art
swiftness potion on the on the floor
here I like that
and our chess system top chest does work
because I have nether brick stairs above
so we can open it still and over here
are the positive potions so ones that
give you good effects so we have
swiftness potions on the Left fire
resistant ones on the right regeneration
potions on the right that says top boxes
are for splash extended and level two
potions or tier two ones that's it's
this top box here because it's a
farthest out of reach and over here on
the left is strength on the right is
healing and I did the color coding at
the back so the color behind the chest
kind of matches the color of the potion
just help me remember it and to tell the
difference between these just by licking
without having to read the signs is the
idea so and it looks pretty awesome I
must admit because we got glowstone
underneath the chest which lights the
wool up really nice behind especially
the magenta here so light blue for
swiftness orange for fire resist magenta
for regen potions there's like three
potions that have a red tinge to them so
for the strength when I use netherrack
and for the instant health potions I
used red wool then over here is the for
negative potions and also there's this
white coated thing is for misc items so
any empty bottles or whatever garbage I
have potion stands anything like that I
would put
in these chess then we got potions of
harming on the left those are kind of a
dark gray red I think I just use black
for the back so it reminds me of evil
and these are kind of like evil potions
because you would turn these into splash
potions and throw them at the mobs most
likely this says the same thing poison
over here dark green obviously slowness
is a cyan should be a little bit darker
but the color the color code should be a
little bit darker it's like a murky blue
but a while that works and then on the
left is weakness I got dark gray wool
for that these are all empty
oh those don't belong there almost look
kind of pink don't they hmm and yeah
that's the potion room all done tell me
what you guys think if you can suggest
any improvements tell me if you like it
or not I'm pretty happy with it so I
probably won't be adjusting much the
only thing I would have liked is that
get a crafting table in here somewhere
I tried it a few places and it just
couldn't get it to look good I might do
a excuse me a block replace add a block
switcher somewhere and then just one of
these wolves will get switched with the
crafting table when you walk up to a
pressure plate or something I don't know
up here is actually a poem somebody
wrote in the comments of one of the
episodes so let's check this out I
thought it was would be kind of cool to
add this says enter at your own peril
peril enter at your own peril past the
piston door where impossible things may
happen that the world has never seen
before in Ethos laboratory lives the
smartest man you've ever seen the
creepers blow his experiments to
smithereens
there is gloom and doom while things go
boom in ethos lab
poem by x-man 374 thank you dude for
that hopefully you don't mind me using
it in the world actually and that's the
potion room alright so I'm going to
challenge myself to do one more
polishing thing in this episode I'm
going to try move this spider staircase
thing like I said I wanted to a long
time ago it's just I haven't done it at
this corner here needs to be over here
to balance out the symmetry of this
place it's just for looks
purely for looks moving this thing not
that I'm going for a super symmetrical
look with this cave but just this front
part should be these types of things
tend to get neglected because they don't
make for interesting video in the lp so
I have to do them off-camera
so generally they get ignored unless I
make a point of it like I'm doing today
and this stuff here is all working good
still a spider XP farm here we got our
our pumpkin and watermelon farm which
apparently is going to have different
rules in the new patches
you don't need tilled Soilers or
something like that for the pumpkins or
watermelon to grow so who knows I might
make another one of these in the future
with the new rules alright here we go
I'm gonna I'm going to see how much I
can get done I'll be honest with you I
used to shut it to your for every glass
block I broke but now I actually kind of
enjoy it it's fun
good times good times
okay I thought I'd show you guys that
the path this takes before I put the
walls up and fill it all in because then
you won't be able to see it
the spiders come out here go up around
go up here this is in the right position
now it goes up here and then this part
just connects to the existing part I
already had it's a little challenging
positioning all this because I I ripped
out the middle of the stair section
basically and I had to reconnect the two
ends but worked out pretty good I got in
the right position that's what I'm
mostly concerned about so when doing
these spider stairs of course you build
the stairs first then you put up your
walls put up the signs to hold the water
in place then you put the water down and
you fill in any remaining blocks you
need and that's all there is to it 4d
smokes more down here added a lot of
slimes incredible all right awesome we
got that renovation complete here you
can see the spider XP farms worked and
do it again I actually discovered that
some of the Redstone was busted so that
was really lowering the rates of the
spiders and I got that fixed up so it's
working even better than before now and
this is the elevator hopefully we'll see
some guys coming up here a little bit
busy but I like it
you got glowstone at the bottom and at
the top there and in between that is a
pillar of leaves and you can watch the
poor little buggers go up to their death
which is nice kind of cool worked on
extending some of the ceiling stuff a
little bit this you can see the side and
this sides a little bit of a mess I
don't know what to do about it just yet
leave it at that I'm going to replace
these stairs here with the half slabs
the reason for this is normally if you
run up stairs your sprint stops but if
you run out pass slabs it doesn't you
see a spider over there poked through
the corner of the block okay so this
place is coming together a little bit
better now maybe we will work on another
project alrighty this should be fun we
got our work done so now we're going to
do a fun project here
I'm calling this project Pokemon there
are six different types of villagers and
our mission is to try collect them all
if we can and get them back home ah it's
a little challenging to do though that
is for sure
uh-huh and while we do this I'll try to
talk about things if I tend a lot of
people have been asking me about the ad
situation not because I said before I
was having problems getting ad approval
on the let's play videos and this was
delaying them and causing all sorts of
problems good news that's been fixed
thank you everybody for your concern hey
you went the wrong way I have a youtube
buddy brainy beast some of you might
know him Thank You Benny for your help
ah if I'm ever having trouble with the
YouTube issue or something he seems to
soup down from the sky and offered me
advice and once again he's done that and
he has solved my problem YouTube is very
picky about the way you monetize your
videos apparently when I used to do it I
would monetize while I was uploading but
I guess no this way you're supposed to
do it is after they finished totally
uploading and processing and once I
started doing that as brainy suggested I
did not have any problems anymore so the
last ten videos or so I've uploaded have
all gotten instant ads which is awesome
this allows me to get the videos out on
time and I make more money that that way
which makes me happier and just works
out best for everybody so that's awesome
all right awesome you got four guys so
far or girls or whatever they are only
two different types so let's try get
another type at least there were some
white robe dudes or dudettes over here
yeah let's get these guys or girls or
whatever
actually there was actually a surprising
number of people sending me private
messages regarding the ad issue which is
really nice it shows you guys care so
that's kind of why I wanted to address
it it's taken care of thank you
everybody for your concern and like
people have really been taking their
time really been taking time out of
their day to help me with this to like
page long two-page long messages I'm
sure took oh at least 15 minutes half an
hour to write so thank you everybody for
caring I really do appreciate it this is
more challenging than it looks
these are all rails I got from the
abandoned mineshaft ooh so they were
they were all freebies which is pretty
sweet all right um I think if I
right-click on the minecart it'll
actually eject them and put me in it I
did that by accident let's try it
yeah and weird out think you can do that
with other mobs can you I almost want to
try it with a creeper inside now
oh don't that's this part oh I just
launched
I also want to say welcome to all the
new people subscribing to the channel
get in there now normally the growth of
the channel is pretty consistent but on
all this last month has been crazy crazy
increase mints and growth get in there
this is so difficult to do you got to
move the minecart to them not them into
the minecarts that's the trick this come
from
yeah usually I I was getting like 300
subscribers a day but this month
unbelievable it's like some days it's
400 some days it's 500 some days were
600 I think I even had one day that was
700 and I don't really know why I've
been getting this kind of growth somehow
I'm getting more promotion from
somewhere I'm not really sure where or
maybe it's a few different places I
don't know but it's it's great so
welcome all newcomers dead did we lose
one of the white guys one two three four
five I think we did
he must have got out mmm oh there is no
no that's the original day moving around
somehow oh I hope you didn't fall down
the well I got to get rid of this track
there's a minecart down here with a dead
person in it no okay
who
yeah for all newcomers my channel I have
a let's play
that's this I usually try to get an
episode out every 2 or 3 days for the
let's play oh there he is and I also
play vex maps every every odd day those
are my two main series and I also do
tutorials probably once one a week or
one every two weeks and then random
stuff in between like speed challenges
I've been thinking about doing those
again I got a long list of ones I want
to try and I had just haven't done them
and then play race for wolves sometimes
it's always fun and stuff like that so
I'm going to go ahead and try collect
all these guys off camera and then we
will send them back alright so I was
setting up the track and when I came
back this is what I saw somehow they can
escape the minecarts got one to two that
have steeped one guy up by the well here
nobody fell in except for me of course
um I'll have to reach etch them I ran
out of all know the big gut free no you
don't you go back you go back um y'all
have to reach etch them and seal them
off when I'm not around them because it
can still get us get away from me that's
awesome I think they're ready to go that
one looks like you got it now he's
stalling okay thought he got out of the
minecart again by it's a graphical issue
you can see it like appearing and
disappearing yeah I think they're ready
to go so in total there's ten that we
caught I think there's only three or
four different types so so we are not
done our mission with this village but
it's a start and I'm going to try see if
we can push them with these brought to
for extra power
awesome having time of their life I'm
surprised that well they're getting up
the hills and everything too they're
pretty much pushing each other
gather gone who needs who needs furnace
mind hurts well they're coming back no
no no Oh dead stop you see that so much
power
oh it did it on its own that's just
about to push it yeah so this will come
to an end I ran out of my cart tracks
before I could finish loading
this is a challenge okay so when they
get to the end I'm just going to build a
little building for them to stay in and
then I'll set up something at my base
for them so they can stay there
permanently later this is the sand
quarry getting huge yep all right that's
the end yet oh no he got free it's good
thing that wasn't any deeper or is it
alright so I will set up a building
around these guys for now just to be
safe I don't know if these with these
minecarts if you put more : if they'll
last longer or if you can only have one
: at a time I put three in so maybe
it'll last longer I don't know nobody
ever uses them so nobody knows anything
about them or at least I don't I'm sure
I'm sure somebody knows something about
them awesome
alright anyway guys I am going to end
the episode here thanks for watching
I'll see you again next time probably
start some new projects maybe we'll deal
with these guys and yeah see you again
next time