hey guys welcome back this is you so Man
1 just 1 by 2 and now we got two more
coming ah one of these days one of these
days I'm gonna put an off switch on the
slime fun cuz it drives me crazy this is
the most annoying thing I've ever made
and it goes non-stop any time I go in
this area over here I always through the
noise barely hear myself think you
shouldn't be here and they get out
sometimes it's really annoying but
anyway not today not today well maybe I
just got back from another caving
adventure I go on caving quite a bit
because I like to where I always need
redstone and I always hope I will strike
out big and get lots of red stone that
rarely happened so usually I get
everything but red stone in fact if you
want red stone branch mining that's the
that's the trick to getting it and I'll
probably just end up doing that because
I never seem to get enough when I would
caving for it I only got like 4 or 5
stacks this time and I got tons of other
stuff though but we do have 30 levels
I'm going to enchant a sword to start
off with I think of all things you can
enchant in in this game I find
enchanting swords the most fun because
looting swords I love looting swords and
they are so rare while like getting
efficiency picks in that that happens
all the time it's nothing special so it
there's a much lower chance of getting
what you want when you enchant a sword
oh ah hmm
looting - its it's a good sword that's
better than I expected
so just really quickly R to start off
with I want to put a staircase right
here I think just a small one because
this is a high traffic area for me now
and we'll probably just use that style
so let's get going with that it won't
take long
um I was good today guys I was really
good as you know I have this problem
with starting new projects all the time
and not finishing existing ones I had an
idea for a new big project and I was
very very tempted to start it today and
it's like no no you know what I have I
have a few too many things going on
incomplete at the moment hey I got said
of course the library I haven't worked
on that in a long time we have the
brewing ethos lab thing that we just
started and still working on and there
is that mob farm stuff at the other base
we have now the underground village we
started that recently we could always
work on that and of course Wilson the
neverending project so I got quite a few
things I should be working on before I
starts or at least make some headway
with them so we're going to go check out
the lab pretty quick here but first
let's get this going it's a lots I find
it a lot more fun to start projects than
to finish them well not I I do really
like finishing projects to I just don't
like working out the little details of a
project like it's the small details I
find boring but just hashing out the
idea and all that is the fun part to
begin with but there is a lot of
satisfaction actually finishing a
project while if you constantly start
new ones all the time well you end up
with a world kind of like mine where you
got a lot of stuff and not a lot of
finished stuff but I have finished a few
things in this world don't get me wrong
okay torches for now we'll fix that
later and I'm out of dirt so we'll leave
it at that
let's head on over to our lab we'll show
you what progress we've made with that
got some floors down over here and I
redid the wiring I decided to use my old
old wiring design the original which is
two blocks wider as I said but it's
going to work a lot better and it's a
lot easier to do so this is all this is
all the wiring down here in the middle
and I've got I have to put a top on this
still but we have the filling thing up
here for filling up water bottles and
putting them in the chest storage and I
believe I have this at the stage where
it's working I just turned it on briefly
just before I started recording here I
have nether warts a sugar redstone and
gunpowder in here so this should make
splash extended splash speed potions and
of course we have the strengths on this
side that we were messing with last time
these lights here they tell us if we're
out of water bottles or not this this
one's about to run out so let's start
this up and we'll be able to see it
running I have not changed the redstone
down here since last time so that'll
start the clock up let's go over here
alright so that look the bottles go out
of the brewing stand and in about 10
seconds from now these broom stands will
refill with bottles I believe how are
things there we go alright so that put
the speed potions into the next stage
here getting the redstone into it and
we got awkward potions being made into
speed three minute speed potions and
water bottles being made into awkward
potions this is just about done eight
minute speed potions now they they leave
there go into I can't get that back now
go into the droppers no no they went all
the way up there in this chest right now
so after the next twenty second interval
they'll be able to go into this brewing
stand and that's the final stage to the
brewing for this setup there they go
these ones are going these ones these
ones here's our water bottle supply uns
chest
and that's it brewing is done for this
this setup actually what I want to do
when I set set all this up properly I'm
going to have one more stage for the
speed potions to convert them into
slowness potions because I might want to
use those at some point too but yeah so
this chest is going to fill up full of
these as I let this thing run it's going
to take a long time now because it takes
20 or now 40 seconds each set of three
potions you make so it does take a long
time to fill up this chest but when that
fills up then this one's going to start
filling up of speed potions that are
eight minutes but they're not the splash
potions this one will fill up then with
the three minutes be potions once this
one's full
and this fills up with awkward potions
and it sort of makes its way down the
line so it's all virgin right yeah I
think so
and you see this light turned off
because it ran out of water bottles ah
so things are going okay here and it's
just finishing up what was left in the
system so you can see there's no water
bottles in here because it ran out but
these are still going through
till it's all done and I have no
ingredient in here so it'll just pass
through into the final chest well I just
mind up a whole bunch of courts again
which got me to level 30 because I ran
out while building does that's where you
guys often I'm running straight and I
just stopped for no reason Oh so let's
let's enchant on that another sword here
another sword for these a better sword a
great sword needed okay okay okay it's
fine that's fine let's head back down to
the lab there's actually a lot of things
I want to do with this place yet and I
don't like this mushroom farm I'm gonna
admit that I do actually really like the
ceiling in it like that's my favorite
part of the whole thing but probably
going to redo a bunch of stuff here just
because I don't like it I'm not a big
fan of spruce wood like when it's the
main the main thing you're looking at
and also this is acting as a slime farm
pretty much there's a slime chunk like
in this moat the majority of this
bacteria so there's always just tons of
slimes in this room so when I redo it
I'll have to put half slabs down
somewhere but - oh oh what is this I'm
going to put the entrance to the potion
room there and if I redo this I'm going
to slice the entrance diagonally
probably have a diagonally trance which
will give me more space to work on the
entrance for this thing here not not too
sure what I'll do for the entrance I
just was messing with it didn't really
come up with anything go through here I
have it shut down at the moment because
I ran out of nether warts and this
backside I was considering putting a
ladder in the back here to get up on top
it's access to the water bottle
refilling thing but you know
since we're having so many of these
things in this room it's probably worth
me making a system just for making
awkward potions so that's what we're
going to do instead instead of having
one of these brewing stands dedicated to
awkward potions I'm going to have mine
carts running around the top is building
feeding awkward potions to each of these
things instead of just straight water
bottles so one of the things we're going
to have to add into this build because
of that is a section dedicated to making
awkward potions probably lots of them
and a minecart system nets that
distributes them throughout the whole
place what else do we want to do I want
to I think I'm going to put in to
another word farms at least one on the
right here one on the left for looks and
also because we're going to be going
through nether work quite a bit and I
don't have a single nether wart farm in
my world here yet it's one of the things
I haven't built see what I'm talking
about you see what I'm talking about and
I got to live with this noise all the
time constantly every part of my world
that's the big downfall of living
underground okay
so a long time ago I made a tutorial for
another word farm which I never ended up
building anywhere and I've always wanted
to so let's let's try to incorporate
that it's it's just a really small
simple thing to it's like I think it was
a bunch of slow sand
I might lower it even I'm not sure and
we'll put oops it was like a piston that
pushes a slow sand which makes all the
nether wart pop off then at the other
end there's a smart piston that pushes
it back right away
so that gets covered up we will have to
have a button here probably
I'll give this inventory nice and full
okay so that will push this alright and
then after after a second I think we
want to push this back because this
piston stays extended for a second we
can't push it back till it retracts
unless we set this up as a monostable to
activate this piston then we could push
it back a lot quicker sure all right
this is a slow part let's put a bunch of
stairs above here okay do I want it in
yeah I think I do want in give me a sec
I'll work on this and I'll show you it
afterwards okay so I got the farm set up
here I got one on each side each of
these has room for 10 netherwart so
that's 20 total we might want to make
some more farms in other places this is
kind of a mix of decoration and for
function helps to break up the room a
bit having and add some color to it so
the way it works piston pushes that
right then we have another piston over
here which pushes it back this is a
smart piston over there and a smart
piston is basically a name I made up for
Pistons a long time ago which indicates
that they're intelligent enough to know
when a block is in front of them and to
automatically push it back so kind of
goes like that you pick up the nether
wart and replant it as you walk by you
have to walk on the slow sand
oops you don't have to walk on the
slowest end with this farm design which
is nice it's a straight line so this is
a smart piston setup
if let's just snag one of these if a
block goes above this redstone torch it
will send power to this dust and then I
have a nine tick delay here because we
need to give time for that other piston
to retract before this one extends so
watch what happens so your computer's
light up and then that goes and it
pushes all the blocks to the left
wow that grew really fast yeah that's
cool
and of course we got lights on the top
here which help help that too looks and
also light up the ground here I am
considering making some changes with
this so I might want to lower this slow
send down one block because it doesn't
look very nice I don't know what do you
guys think does it does it add to the
room or does it take away from the room
if I lower it I kind of need to add half
slabs or something here to prevent me
from from walking on it though like if
this is down one block I don't want to
walk on the slow sand that's the
advantage of having it up place it is
and of course if I have half slabs up
here I can have lights up there I'll
have to put them on the side somewhere
but yeah so that is another word farms I
can't remember if I said this but we
might have some more in other places
here as well I got some pots and some
plants I want to sort of add some more
decoration to this room I'm trying to
keep out clean clean simple look to the
room but a few plants here and there
isn't going to mess that up too much
it's almost too plain as it is right now
yeah if you're going to put something in
pots these saplings are my favorite
thing they look like a little fern it's
pretty cool alright and another thing
I'm considering for this room I'm
dreading making a ceiling for it like if
I make a huge ceiling it's going to be
it's going to take me a long time to
finish
project so what I might do instead I
might cheap out and just put half slabs
over the top like this and then hang
lighting it in the ceiling as well
because I need to get rid of these
torches and places like here if we could
just have a light above close to the
ground that would work too let's see
what this looks like if we do do it a
little ways and of course if you guys
have ideas let me know um this is just a
way to simplify doing the ceiling all
right how does that look I could live
with that
doesn't even have to be half slabs I can
add a pattern to it if I want to use
pillars or even a different block type I
might use this clay instead of this I
think I should use something with
colorant above instead of it instead of
this actually yeah okay well moving on
here I did want to talk to you guys a
little bit about Wilson this episode I
have a plan that we're going to check
out Wilson our good friend I haven't
forgotten about you so one thing we have
with Wilson is his hunger and the way
that's going to work as I've explained
many times before but over over time
he's going to constantly lose hunger
points so this is going to slowly drain
down based on time at a constant rate
and the thing is we also have this
happiness stat and that needs to
decrease some house as well and I don't
exactly want them to both decrease the
same way if they both decrease by time
it's it's almost like not worth having
another stat point happiness should be
different than hunger loss happiness
loss should be different from hunger
loss somehow so one idea I had is making
Wilson sort of self-aware like when I'm
in the area his happiness will go up
because he's glad I'm around home and if
I'm off somewheres else in my world I
want is happiness to slowly go down
maybe over time it's still kind of
similar to to the hunger because it's
going to be based on time but it's it's
also based on where I am in the world
and the way I'm gonna do that we're
gonna have to hop into a creative world
here to show you so just give me a
second all right what are we up to here
guys well I got a few things I want to
show you as you may know I have quite
the interest in unloaded chunks lately
and the things you can do with them and
I'm going to show you some of those and
also how we're going to use these with
Wilson so first up we have a redstone
clock here and every time it goes every
second here it says redstone because of
this command block and we are at about
1600 X and 0 Z so we're quite a ways
away from spawn at the moment now if we
if we teleport to 0 0 that clock keeps
running even though it's in an unloaded
chunk the chunk stays loaded to a
certain extent because of that clock not
everything works like it doesn't a
normal loaded chunk like random block
updates no longer occur so so like wheat
won't grow or trees won't grow or a
burnt-out redstone torch won't turn
itself back on that kind of stuff
doesn't happen but like redstone keeps
happening a good guy and we can control
things with the redstone even like if we
if we head back there let's change our
time time set 0 yeah I got it right if
we head back here we have the Spencer
full of TNT here we can activate
dispensers or a number of other redstone
devices let's get ready to go back ok go
forward
okay I don't want to mess this up
because I want to leave as soon as it
starts going okay so the next one we go
got press up twice okay so we can hang
out here for a while and meanwhile
that's sending pulses to the dispenser
we had three stacks of TNT in there when
we left now we can even go in the nether
here and it's still running hey everyone
so pretty cool however what is not
happening is that TNT entity that's that
gets created when the dispenser shoots
out the TNT that is not being processed
so when we return we're going to have
like dozens and dozens of TNT all going
off at the exact same time here well
probably one's going to go off and then
at under is going to go off because we
saw one you out already so let's return
all right hope this doesn't blow
anything up oh okay well you see I
wasn't quite full oh and look at that it
just missed everything I said up here
that was beautiful
okay so one of my plans with Wilson is
to have a clock running similar to this
so that when I leave the area stuff with
Wilson is still happening it like he's
still he's still losing hunger as I'm
outside of the loaded chunk area um
so I can be off far far away and he's
still losing hunger points and he can
still you can still process everything
right another chunk loader design I saw
this was made by simply Sark is he
figured out you can just have to hoppers
stitch between two chunks so we're
between chunks right now look at the
z-coordinate it's a negative zero if I'm
here and it's a positive zero if I'm
here so right down this line is a chunk
of boundary right here so this items
bouncing back and forth between the
hoppers and that's going to go to a man
block that says say hoppers so when we
leave I find this I don't know if it
always works the
secede yeah I haven't been able to get
this one to work
but I know for a while it was okay so
that one's a little more finicky 1600
and the world's not loading um
one second what do I do i press at three
a now I might have to reload here this
is pretty bad i over teleported the game
didn't like that okay one sec all right
we're back I don't know why that happens
but sometimes the world just refuses to
load like that you have to real aughh
but I did get this hopper one working so
let's try it see if we can show it
didn't work go back there we go okay
it's working it doesn't always work same
with the redstone one that sometimes
doesn't work but you can see we're by
the portal here which is at 0-0 so that
those two hoppers way out at like 1600
are definitely in unloaded chunks but
the chunks are getting forced loaded by
the hoppers because it's passing an item
in between two chunks and so it's
keeping them keeping them working to a
certain extent but not everything is is
working in that or in the in the chunk
so entities like this mine cart stops
moving once I leave if we have an item
on the ground it's not going to de-spawn
when I leave even though the chunk is
being loaded to a certain extent by this
just entities don't get processed like
if I throw an ender pearl it's going to
stop moving until I come back
um maybe I'll try to show that and
hopefully the hopper thing stays loaded
throw it right by the hoppers
okay let's get good ready to move oh and
the hoppers didn't the hoppers stop
started okay it's still falling you see
the hoppers running but when we return
the enderpearls gonna reload and we're
going to get teleported somewhere aerial
so even though these were running the
enderpearl wasn't moving so there's a
demonstration
so to summarize my plan basically I'm
going to have one of these clocks that
keeps the chunks loaded or hopefully
does and then a minecart or some other
entity that's doing something that we
can detect it's it's moving or doing
whatever if the clock is running and the
minecart is not moving that means I'm
far away from Wilson the chunks unloaded
if the clock is running and the minecart
is moving that means I'm close to Wilson
so that's that's about it so that's how
I'm going to determine if Wilson should
gain or lose happiness if if I'm close
to Wilson he'll gain happiness if I'm
far away he'll he'll get sad and he'll
lose happiness and this guy just wrecked
me he got me down to three arts and
before he finished me off he decided
he's gonna move and get a closer shot
and he got stuck haha
but anyway it's it's that time again
everyone time to call it an end for the
day I have picked out one comment for
this episode very nice comment I really
appreciated this one it says etho you
most likely will not see this but you
have brought so much inspiration to my
life the past years or so and I would
just want to give a really big thank you
for everything you have done and all the
ideas you have given me I would have
quit minecraft if it wasn't for you I'm
pretty sure that many people feel the
same way so just keep doing exactly what
you are doing you know the right recipe
for this youtube thing even though you
may not think it thank you again for
everything
very nice comment very nice I like that
one ah thank you for that and of course
well not of course but I want to say a
big thank you to all the support I got
last episode actually it was crazy just
about 40 thousand likes last time I
checked which I'm pretty sure is the
most liked video of mine now and also
just insane amount of feedback on it too
like I just looked I can't remember I
think it was 12,000 comments or 20,000
just lots lots of great feedback so
thank you everyone
much appreciated that's all for today
thanks for watching see you again next
time bye bye