[Music]
hello everybody this is etho welcome
back guys I had to start recording here
because guess what I just found without
even looking for it I just stumbled into
it totally forgot oh no I'm glitching
out why am i glitching out remember and
I jumped off it looks like I'm getting
my stuff back after all oh and my
teacher woods here how did that happen
yeah so I have set up a portal to get
here now I got too much stuff on me it's
a problem and I just checked out the
area outside the portal here let's see
can I pick up any more of this I will
make a chest you know why cuz ender
pearls are actually rare for me now I
don't visit the Enderman farm as much as
I should and I totally am out of ender
pearls almost so I will collect these
in fact when I go to the Enderman farm
again it's probably not gonna be for
experience points I have almost no need
for experience now what I do need though
is just the ender pearls all right
Enderman Farms basically gonna be for
farming and the pros from here on out I
think alright it's very good huh those
diamonds are still here oh they don't
really matter alright so yeah I finally
got a track out to here this is way out
by the way it's just three thousand six
thousand so it is quite a ways what on
earth this is natural the scene here I
did not put this here
what that looks ok man maybe it's not it
might not be no I think it is cuz this
would be Kabul if I pillar it up right
and I don't ever remember pillar hang up
here I I don't know that's kind of weird
I'm pretty sure I didn't do that
such a strange pillar okay where's my
portal my portal is right over here
let's just go through real quick so yeah
as it's checking out the area outside of
where the portal was here and I ran into
that stuff but yeah that's oh I think a
sheep came through and fell down
turns out weird things are happening
okay he's he's over here but he's
glitching out here let's let's help him
out there you go all right so the
fortress the wither skeleton firm is
just up over here it's about a hundred
blocks away this portal and of course we
built the track to get to the fortress
here so I can get pods all really
quickly now it's not far away at all so
that is pretty cool and as you can see
we even have lots of wither skeletons
around and other mobs cool cool all
right I'm gonna grab some puzzle okay so
I had to investigate the pillar I dug
down right below it to see if I did
pillar up and forget about it and
several times I have cut through rock
like this and and like to the correct
block is in the correct place it's not
like it was smooth stone all the way up
so yeah it's it's a natural pillar it's
very strange very good now that I got my
puzzle here I can finally change out the
dirt in this tunnel room with it so this
is the before and this is the
after oh yeah pretty cool huh
so I just got the puzzle down and I
started loading it up with all sorts of
grass and leaves and and flowers and and
all that good stuff totally filled it
out lights it might be too much stuff
but it doesn't look too bad actually I
like it really busy like this especially
from above when you're down here it's
like whoa whoa ease up boy but when
you're up here kind of looks like it's
an overgrown area like it's an area
that's not really tended to as it would
be down there or it can't really be
accessed so it's grown wild and yeah I
think it looks pretty cool I like it got
some lily pads in the water and all that
kind of stuff too while I was doing this
I figured out what happened to my my
lost redstone the other day I was like I
wanted to do a redstone project and I
could not find it anywhere
apparently I must have dropped it off in
this chest here because I got a bunch of
pistons and yeah actually there's not
much redstone in here there's only one
and then two two torches so 30 to
Opera's oh that's that's pretty valuable
I'm glad I found that today you know
what I would I really need to do is get
this villager out of our village here
and into the gold farm so I'm gonna move
him I have my obsidian I don't darn it
let's see if we can find him let's make
sure he's dead not not dead let's make
sure he's not dead before we try to move
him
is this them I think that's where he was
when I left him last time he hasn't
moved yeah okay so we got to get this
guy up to our gold farm and portal to
the nether and then portal from the
nether to the gold firm's gonna be the
easiest way I think all right guy come
on let's go get your bags it's moving
day the other villagers don't like you
you're getting deported let's go come on
the fence is banned oh whoa oh oh oh
he's not gonna let me put a block there
it's all good all right now go down the
stairs moving villagers is always just
so much fun
hey hey you this portal is not for you
how did you get up there alright
hopefully no one went through all right
now should be at my nether hub very good
pushing him I put up oh wait wait wait
no no no no we don't want to go to that
portal we want to go back to this one
oh you guy no no hey all right I thought
he was gonna come through that other
portal turns out no so let's put a
backing on this so he can't run out um
let's go back over here he's got a 40
second cooldown and then he can go
through you're gonna make me a lot of
money you know that yeah all right cuz
you buy a junk and give me good stuff in
return it's wonderful and did it work
oh that's not a good sound I think he's
fine
alright alright just a little bit
further there you go your new beautiful
home enjoy it for right now I'll make
you a nicer place in just a second
cool so that went off without a hitch
that was good I'm sure I gave him more
space than he needs here let's let's
make you nice and confined if I can
perfect ahaha yes it's finally payday
I've been waiting for this for a long
time actually because I've been saving
up zombie flesh for so long this chest
is full and it's it's at the point where
it's like what I do with this stuff it's
all over the place I just emptied this
out into this one but this one's pretty
much full I've got
this one full this one full this is just
loaded with it and I also have a whole
bunch of it over at my stronghold base I
have in the man cave all over the place
so I'm really looking forward to getting
rid of this stuff and I'm also curious
to see how much or how many emeralds
we'll make from this so the plan is
we're going to trade with trade with
this guy over and over 36 zombie flesh
this is gonna be a pain so my plan also
oh I didn't get very further so once
that oh I can't do this
uh-oh what's going on here
this is not according to the plan what's
going on wait a second both his trades
are cancels my plan was to trade zombie
flesh and then trade emeralds for
glowstone to renew it mmm this is not
good oh yeah the XP words can't get out
alright that renewed it that's good did
it remove the glowstone one yeah okay
not sure what that was about
so I want to set up a dispenser
somewhere that will constantly dispense
the flesh on me because otherwise it's a
real pain to do this alright going good
that is really annoying you got to put
in every single time I was hoping yeah
there was a one that would have 32 so at
least you could do or get two emeralds
for a stack of it but 36 seems to be the
lowest all right second I fix it
yeah it did cool so I'm gonna do a ton
of trading here and I'll show you how
many emeralds we end up with in the end
here
speaking of XP being useless it's like I
don't know if I like how how they made
XP kind of useless now like once you got
the tools you need it's so cheap to
repair them that you don't really need
levels in this game anymore honestly you
just need like maybe three four hundred
levels total to start up with and then
once you got that and you got your good
tools you'll never need levels again
really I may have messed up here I'm a
little scared that this guy's wrecked
now all his trades are getting cancelled
so I can't trade those things with them
anymore when his when this one was
locked and the last one was locked I was
able to fix him by trading him redstone
that didn't fix it this time then
trading lapis didn't do it
so gold and ender eyes are my last
choices I'm gonna try an ender eye which
is just gonna kill my profits I don't
know no I think that did it okay and
that stinks though that was ten emeralds
for nothing ah this guy man he is
tricking me I'm trying to figure out how
he works I ended up buying another I
have the ender though there's gotta be a
way to avoid doing that and sometimes
when I trade with this guy he does
something really weird let's see if we
make it happen
bye bye or if I trade them enough zombie
flesh and it cancels out I leave the
trade he gets the particle effects you
can still trade them zombie flesh it's
so so interesting so weird that happens
quite often actually
I think it's a random thing that it
happens I thought it might be like after
last time when I bought that I have the
ender with him I
I got like good credit in his store cuz
this kept happening and that that's not
what it is though because I bought
another one and I I lost this trade
really quickly so I'm not sure you see I
wasn't able to trade too much there so
it seems like there's a lot of random
randomness to it let's see it refreshes
again this time it seems like I'm able
to get lots of emeralds off of them for
it again and it refreshed so I think has
a certain percent chance of it
refreshing afterwards and also there's a
certain chance to it that or how many
times you can do the trade before it
cancels out still I think it was that
way before oh man so while I was
recording here or while I was doing the
trading my skin change fellows said and
I went back to Steve I had to relog and
I started downloading something I tend
to record my LP episodes in the evening
sometimes it goes to midnight even which
is what happened today yep so it's April
1st
I suspected it I suspected Mojang we're
doing an April Fool's thing all right
well I teach whenever I click something
in the menu they see leak
nice they were heavy oh he says stomp
stomp when you run stomp stuff I tried
to turn it up by ten can't really turn
it up though I don't think does he uh
you see when I cut stuff down job job
job job this is awesome alright so the
rest this episode I'm just listening to
what everything says I thought was just
a village the villagers it's everything
now it makes the noise oh man I hope
this is a setting you can set in the
future even after April Fool's Oh
[Music]
all of this is open then ear closed
I don't know how much you could actually
hear Joe chop jump jump jump jump jump
job I'm really distracted oh it's the
portal making that noise I did it now
that you all right yeah I'm really
described it here but I will try to show
you quickly here the outcome of the
villager trading 30 going too much so I
did oh man
it's like impossible to do anything down
that all these sounds are playing okay
so I did did a bunch of trading
everything these bottom two rows is
basically what I got knocked out in this
class so it's one two three four five
six and a half stacks emeralds all the
zombie flesh we had up here plus like
another double chest and then another
like three more chests a zombie flesh in
addition to what we had here went from
levels 31 to 51 or something like that
I believe so got quite a bit of
experience points and trading itself the
way it seems to work now
oh my goodness so every time you trade
there's a chance to trade with it
cancelled right every time you do a
trade there's a chance it will renew the
trades like all the trades so that's why
sometimes when I trade zombie flesh and
it gets cancelled and I leave the menu
it will renew itself no no I don't want
that
I got trade I got trade - all right I'm
so distracted now though okay there is a
chance like this trade will get
cancelled this one with it cancelled a
whole bunch of other ones will get
cancelled every time you do a trade
though there's there'll be a chance that
they all get refreshed so you should do
your ideal trades first trading for the
eye of ender here was really dumb I
should've did the gold trade instead
when they were all canceled anyway so
villager trading is pretty good still
it's not like now that I got this guy
here I have unlimited emeralds instantly
it's I spent about half an hour an hour
just trading him zombie flesh and got
quite a few emeralds out of it but not
like tons
it's not even stack of blocks of emerald
so it's not
that's super LP all right one of the
most amazing things ever we're spending
the rest of episode going around the
world now
[Music]
this is like the best thing ever
I'm gonna head over to the man cave I'm
sure we'll hear quite a few new noises
there actually let's try out the
minecart just really quick - and the
buttons he wasn't saying stomp stomp
stomp he was seeing stone stone stone
and if you're on grass he says grass
grass grass wondering if they changed
the note blocks I guess they did but
they didn't tune it the thing that was
my nighttime song by the way you see
them pick that up all right let's try
grow some trees are you saying dig
this that doesn't make sound okay I was
hoping there'd be a boying sound but
it's just a resource pack right so only
things that played sound will play a
different sound I am a big amazing
that's the water stream so loud don't
think that reset though is there water
here I have a feeling there's water here
hey do you say things missing all the
horses are the same Zenith have they
infected you too out your normal okay
whoa
I know there's water here please stop
that she does made noises Hughes I
thought there would be new ones let's
try fishing wait where's my fishing rod
I'm not closing up opening strife
fishing will they announce when we catch
a fish if we catch a fish usually
there's a splash sound when the fish
goes towards it this Sheen oh here he
comes
nope that's pretty normal
alright the mobs in particular are the
funny things let's head over to the
stronghold I want to listen to the mob
spawner there and maybe we'll go to the
end too
just really quick and yeah let's go
listen to the cows
[Music]
this water
I regret using so much water actually
being out here at night times probably
good - that was a spider that's what
that I heard before spider Oh Cooper
blast should exclude I didn't make any
noise when I died and yes I know I lost
51 levels big big deal
it's not like I'm gonna use them on
anything it is a nice day let's go
listen the slimes quickly - that's one
of my favorites all right
oh my goodness so the skin changes
because I'm a villager now I guess yeah
just gets worse and worse
let's try shooting these guys
I tell you bit here anything I just keep
here in the water zone just normal I'm
gonna click this oh my goodness so much
water so much water alright let's see we
heard Enderman I think we've covered
everything pretty much except maybe the
nether
[Music]
this place is pretty crazy actually if
this guy hits me uh probably gonna die
ha
my bones who knows we're gonna have to
hit a zombie pigman at some point here
we'll save that for the end all right so
here's the comment though what is your
favorite genre of movies slash video
games for movies I tend to prefer action
comedy movies although most of my
favorite movies are not really those I
like I like movies like the majestic
Ocean's eleven Armageddon was like a
really good all-around movie but in
general I prefer action comedy what do
you see so scary here interfer games I
find out at least lately I really like
roguelike games a lot games like faster
than light and those kinds of things
where you have I'm definitely getting
this resource backed afterwards it's too
good
yeah like games that are randomly
generated and every time you play it
sort of a different outcome
same with like lucky
all right I think I'm about to die I
don't actually want to die here because
my stuff might burn let's see the zombie
pigman and we'll call it an end
I guess I'm Way too distracted did you
play it now all right you can be you got
more of them coming
hellooo oh please don't kill me please
don't kill me oh let me oh no I just got
like boots ah that I got no Armour oh
that's that's not the way to go yeah
this it was over there Stilton alright
guys that's it for today thanks for
watching I hope you enjoyed the April
Fool's thing as much as I did there's
probably more to it to that I didn't I
didn't see or hear I should say
yourselves a good day bye bye
you