[Music]
hello everybody this is etho endo I'm
gonna regret this aren't I
we are back over here at the mastermind
game today you guys remember this thing
we worked on it a while ago like three
or four episodes in a row we got tons
done on it we were kind of getting close
to the end of the project and it was
getting very difficult and I just I just
left it I left it outside like
yesterday's trash I haven't touched it
since as it's been sitting here
collecting flies you know as I thought
today we would we would take another
stab at it was kind of in the mood to
work on it again at least until I
started it's a lot more complicated than
I remembered actually uh-huh yeah so if
you guys don't remember we're trying to
rebuild mastermind in Minecraft like
it's a real-world puzzle game with a
little bit of complicated logic to its
and we're trying to get around a lot of
that complicated logic using a built in
mechanic of Minecraft the item stacking
mechanic we can use to do comparisons
and last time I worked on this we found
out something a little odd that kind of
broke the whole thing item stacking is
inconsistent the way it works like if we
throw that sometimes it'll stick and
stay put and sometimes it'll combine and
keep moving right what we found out is
that the item stack with the most items
always is the one that stays and the
other one combines with it so like if
for example we have two items in this
stack and it combines with that one this
is the item stack that's gonna survive
and it'll keep moving aha
always always always so what we got to
do with our game here we have a system
for generating our answers like the the
random codon and I hold down uh-huh
little part core up here we got this big
complicated thing over here so basically
when we press this button
it'll change the random code here and
then it'll shoot out that random code in
item form down below here item streams
take it to this area down below oh and
there's our code right but it's only a
single item so when we were passing
another item by here to check if they
stack together or not we were having
issues where sometimes they would stack
together but they would either stay put
or they would keep moving
we need those items to stay put though
otherwise it's gonna break the logic in
our game so to do that we need to
probably send out two items so that that
stationary stack is bigger than the one
with the motion that the stationary
stack has two items and the one with the
motion only has one when they combine
the stationary stack will win and the
one with the motions gonna lose its
motion and they'll just stay put does
that make sense it's a little bit a
little bit weird anyways I've been
staring at the redstone here for like
fifteen minutes trying to figure out how
it works again and I think I see what we
need to do I think we need to set up a
second area branch here so it'll send a
pulse here it'll shoot out the items
right and then a couple seconds later
it'll go down this path and do it again
so it'll send out two is the plan will
it make those combined but also we have
a system here for detecting when the
items are in the dropper and it only
shoots out one we need to change us so
it shoots out too for some reason I have
a delay on this like a really long one
I'm not sure if there was a reason for
that but it doesn't make sense to me now
so I'm going to change that make a
monostable here so short pulse let's see
alright so I do I do
okay
well we're gonna change this so it has
two pulses instead of just one as well I
think we do that fine what's this for
been doing anything I guess it's kind of
covering that up so items don't fall out
okay probably you can do this one and
then we'll make this one with the wreath
or something actually it'll probably
work better if we just do like a
continuous clock as long as there's
items in the dropper it'll run instead
of like only doing it twice oh yeah that
should work
and then I think we just need to somehow
send a pulse to this block right here to
try this let's see if it'll shoot two
items out now I heard two clicks oh no
items though why not let's extend that
maybe a now Chapter two awesome okay so
now every time we press this it should
send out q1 - okay cool cool so let's
see if we can shorten the time on this a
little bit so that it'll happen faster
we want everything via short of time as
possible in our game logic oh yeah that
worked okay let's see if in shortened it
any more
that way we don't have to wait around as
much when we're playing the game one oh
I think we found it there okay so this
is the absolute shortest amount of time
where it'll still shoot up - good good
okay so now the other question is is it
gonna do that when we generate a new
code is we also want it to send out -
then new code should right yeah -
oranges - Purple's great
all right and let's also just double
check that they're actually stacking
together like down below here and not
landing like next to each other
something stupid yeah it looks like
those are stacked right there's two in a
stack cool cool so now we know like a
purple whenever comes by here it's
always gonna remain stationary awesome
alright so that's one big problem solved
on our game here but don't you guys
worry we got we got lots left I think
that updates might have broke a couple
things on on the game here like the
Minecraft updates
cuz I'm noticing this I was testing it
out and look what happened now a bunch
of the concrete breaks instead of
falling down like it's supposed to do
and I wasn't doing that before so I
think something has changed so probably
just gotta change the timings on some
things here but I gotta figure out what
now it's looking like an easy fix
actually so all these pistons are
tracked and we just have to change a
time before they extend again I think we
do that here we'll just add one extra
tickin that see if that'll do it go back
up here through our parkour take a jump
ok now let's try it again
you would jump into the tripwire here
yes awesome okay that worked wait a
minute this isn't gonna work this will
connect to this that's that's a no-go
hmm maybe let's go this way this button
this is getting exciting guys we're
getting to the point now where our games
gonna be like totally non-functional not
working
- like semi functional we're almost at
that point where we can kind of play it
actually which will be cool and then we
just keep adding more and more stuff to
it um let's see here let's go up to here
so we have the system with that double
item thing only because like it might
take longer than five minutes for this
game to be played and items despawn in
five minutes so we need to refresh those
somehow and basically every time we put
in an answer we need to clear the
previous items and then refresh them so
we're connecting a wire up to that spot
that connects up to this tripwire
now whenever we activate this tripwire
it should send two items down below I
hope your they come cool cool
everything's good hmm yeah okay so those
are in place now we also just added
something to clear those after every
every time we put in our answer let's
test that out now so this is the answer
key this is what we're trying to guess
in the game normally you can't see that
but we know what it is right now because
it's it's open there's like a shutter
there to close so if we go orange green
green we're gonna get one of these right
and one of these lights should turn on
on the right side here but we're gonna
hop down here and just see if they clear
what we got below there
a little quick though Oh twitch wait
which way over here the pass-by I added
that orange acacia a pressure plate
there oh we got extra items again oh so
those items arrived before we wanted
them to also how is that green why is
this over here I'm gonna have to watch
that back oh yeah we might have a
problem here so basically the green
concrete there it was aligned like on
the very edge and normally it should
just keep going right but like it ran
into the corner of like this block here
for example I don't know does that
happen always like it ran into this
corner here even though it was aligned
on the side I think or maybe they had a
little bit of horizontal momentum cuz I
don't think that should happen right
oh no we'll have to keep our eye open
for that that's probably another problem
we gotta solve let's go let's go back up
to here though so we saw those other
items arrive before we wanted them to so
we're gonna just add a little bit
delayed to this wire we just we just add
it on maybe let's try like four
repeaters or something should be enough
okay so after a lot of trial and error I
think we might have it now we'll try
again here so we got orange yellow
orange purple as our code they're in
place let's go ahead over here we will
do orange we will do do I have any
purple on this yeah let's do a purple
here and then for this one let's go
green maybe so three of these should
line up the oranges and the purple green
doesn't line up with the yellow here so
we should get three correct answers
three of these lights should turn on but
we're gonna flip our switch
we put our answer we'll go down here and
just see what happens yeah everything's
looking good so far
[Music]
minecart comes picks up those items and
then the next batch falls down okay so
that's good none of these got picked up
by the minecart running below they're
ready for the next round they got
refreshed cool cool let's go back up
here looks like we might even be able to
lower the delay a bit it almost took
them too long to me to arrive and yeah
three of the lights turned on so three
the three answers were correct and it
shows on our scoreboard here so that is
great we're making some progress so we
added a thing over here that when the
items passed by they hit this pressure
plate activate some redstone below there
and that sends the minecarts to clear
the previous round and then it gets
refreshed so this this is the minecart
that picks them up just runs underneath
I've noticed a little bit of an
inconsistency with the items here like
sometimes they won't go into this hopper
like they're supposed to yeah they'll do
that they'll get stuck on the corner or
something right we we can't have that
happening so what we're gonna do try to
align them using stairs here we'll
waterlog stairs so now that ensures it's
not gonna go right against the wall and
then we do that same thing on this side
have another stair lining it this
direction this will have to be water and
we'll have to have another pressure
plate here I guess like so and now I
think they'll always go into the hopper
let's try it with blue they'll always be
like center-aligned have enough momentum
mm-hmm
yeah you know I don't think the hopper
needs to be here though I think we can
move it forward one block
and that'll fix the problem entirely
right let's move it over here alright
let's put this thing through some
testing now we'll see if we can trick it
up see if it ever fails you don't want
it to because if it fails I have no idea
what's what's wrong
so for blue none of those are blue so
this should return a zero zero of these
lights should be on yeah we got zero
okay that's good let's go for a yellow
and blue blue on all these that'll match
up with this one that means one of these
should turn on right please yes please
yes please yes come on come on
we had to hooked up any of this yet
though yeah one turned on okay that's
great that's great
let's go for maybe purple go yellow
let's go for some green here just to
change things up a bit you know so two
of those should line up the oh no that's
an orange one of them only lines up the
purple alright it's only one of these
should turn on only one turned on great
great let's try to do what I was what I
wanted there go orange do those are
right purple and orange on the sides now
two of these should turn on right no we
got a problem somewhere dang zero or is
it one it's zero oh okay so it's the
left side that's broken yeah okay okay
interesting why is it broken I don't
know I have no clue somebody help me
I think um I'm gonna change that I think
that little change might have fixed it
but we're having that green concrete
powder issue again like where it hit the
corner there sometimes when it comes out
of these trapdoors it's not going
perfectly straight it has a little bit
of sideways momentum and it like goes
off off to the side or something I think
that's why it the corner that at one
time so in a tri stop that from
happening I'm gonna just I'm gonna put
last long the sides here so it'll
hopefully hit that and then straighten
out it's working it's working oh I'm so
happy guys I think we got it now so I've
been doing some tests here we did orange
and three blues only the orange lines up
that's supposed to give us one and it
did that wasn't working before like the
left side was broken now I think I got
it fixed second row only the orange
lines up so again we only get one I did
the orange and purple again so we should
get two and it gave us two like it like
it's supposed to orange and yellow on
this one there's no Reds so again that's
two orange and purple here all right so
again that gives us two now let's go on
to the threes make sure those are
working off as well and then we'll try a
four I don't know if we implemented the
wind condition in this or not like it's
supposed to win us the game if we get
all four correct there's like some note
blocks I saw down below and I'm not sure
if that will trigger so this should give
us three orange yellow orange orange
yellow orange matches got three okay
let's try another combination here let's
go oh that's not where we play some
yellow orange or full we'll go blue so
this one won't work and I meant if this
works we'll try all four see what
happens
Oh yellow orange purple yellow orange
purple should be three excellent okay
let's go for the full thing now I'll
probably try a few more combinations
off-camera just to make sure the games
actually working and there's no like
rare case where it doesn't for some
reason okay so this should be the
winning code all four of these should
turn on oh I did hear a note block only
three turned on hmm got a watch and see
how many times that pulse is there I
think one two three or so it did go four
times but for some reason for light
didn't light up oh that time they did so
a general rule in life like when you're
trying to solve a problem you need to be
able to identify or narrow down what the
problem actually is so in this case only
three lights are turning on when four
should be we don't know though is that a
problem with the display is that a
problem with the game logic or maybe
something else it's not really clear so
we got to narrow down the possibilities
so I've been watching that wire there
that goes up to the display how many
times it actually pulses it's
alternating between turning four on and
three on the time only three came on
though it only pulse three times so
that's telling me it's not a problem
with this display logic like all these
hoppers and stuff over here it's it's
actually a problem with the game logic
down below so I've identified where the
problem is
I got a traffic out what is wrong with
the logic part of the game so this is a
lot easier with if I had another person
with me but you gotta like trigger it
and run down real fast and record what
happens and then watch it back in slow
motion
yeah so none of these turned on right
hmm I didn't catch it there I'm gonna
have to watch that back let's see how my
lights actually turned on though oh here
oh oh okay that was weird it's not an
answer I was expecting and do it again
bass go fast it's that time only three
of these turned on you see that that
that last one didn't for some reason so
I'm guessing only three lights turned on
let's go back up
you heard the note block though so it
detected all four of them yeah okay is
so weird understand okay okay so that
looked good to me let's see if all four
turned on you late I'm coming by that's
fine yeah all four turned on so that
time it looked right let's do it again
though it looks like something weird now
yeah no items nothing came out of those
trap doors right I'm not imagining that
I'm not crazy
does that mean they are
[Music]
there they are why are they there what
happened why why did they get stuck why
it doesn't make sense
so that's what's happening when when
it's zero that's why sometimes it's zero
they're getting stuck first part of this
for some reason I find they went through
okay I think I know what's going on here
so we're using trip wires to activate
everything right I jump into them they
activate our redstone here it goes
straight into all our redstone stuff I I
think the problem is I need to clean the
Redstone you guys know like with
electricity how like if you live in
North America you want 60 Hertz of
electricity in real life right sometimes
you might be getting 59 or 61 or
something though right so they sell
these things called like they're called
something I don't know electricity
cleaners right so that it makes sure
it's a perfect 60 Hertz and everything
is like exactly what you want kind of
same thing with our redstone here trip
wires are pretty nasty to use with
redstone because they are not consistent
right sometimes like they'll activate
longer than other times sometimes you
know item will just go right through and
it doesn't activate you know they're not
really great in that way so I think
sometimes it's activating longer than
other times and that is affecting things
that's why I'm getting inconsistent
results here so what I got to do is
clean our redstone so it's a perfect
length of pulse every time excellent all
right so I just added a monostable
circuit here and sticky piston with a
block on top this is connected to the
tripwire that goes into this and it
turns it into exactly a 4 tick pulse
with this repeater so now it's I've
tried it a few times and seems to be
good now do a couple more here just to
show you guys all right that's the
answer again so all four lights should
turn on we should hear the music block
no block I mean and
I am for lights but anyways guys I think
it's that time again where we have to
wrap up our episode here sorry if it
wasn't your cup of tea all there how the
Redstone and stuff for a complicated
project like that I kind of like to do
it like at the full episode on it
instead of just like five minutes
because it's otherwise it doesn't like
re explain the project every time and
it's like five minutes isn't enough to
really do that and work on it you know
so I kind of like just seeing a lot done
in a single episode which is what I was
in the mood for today so that's why we
worked on it anyways the comments says
hey etho just wondering what are your
thoughts on the sudden popularity in
Minecraft also how do you feel about the
current direction of the game great
video as always ah that's great man if
people are enjoying minecraft again or
whatever people that fell out in love
with it and are coming back I think
that's great I think it's a great game
always will be there was a weird thing
going on for a while I don't know like
in my comments I was seeing this a bit
weird like people were saying they were
getting made fun of in school for
playing Minecraft like people were the
kids were moving on to shooter games
like fortnight and stuff right and kind
of making fun of anybody else in their
class that was playing Minecraft still I
think that was kind of a lousy thing so
I'm hoping that has kind of ended
because you know different games for
different people all right and it's not
like minecraft with became a bad game it
was still a good game people just moved
on from it right so yeah I think it's
cool also how do you feel about the
current direction of the game I think
yeah Mojang have it pretty down pat now
I'm like I used to kind of get upset
with some certain updates like they
would do things that would bother me
that hasn't happened in a very long time
I think they're pretty good at
implementing things now without breaking
too much in the world you know any
blocks for example you know the way
they're doing honey blocks is great they
look good they have a function you use
them alongside slime blocks you know
they're decorative beehives look cool
honey blocks look cool you got the bees
new mobs and also you can farm them so
it like appeals to everyone
it's decorative its farmable its new mob
potential and stuff so I think they got
it down pretty good now I hope they keep
adding stuff in that way but yeah
anyways that's gonna do it for today
guys hope you enjoyed it thanks for
watching as always I'll see you again in
the next one take care bye bye
[Music]