[Music]
hello everybody etho here
in the nether again working on the blaze
farm
uh this is a big project it's taking me
a long time i admit it
getting getting it done though so i was
working on this today the holding area
got a little bit done
here um
yeah so we got the design figured out
for the crushing and
everything big thing now is just wiring
it all up
and what i've done is i've run two
buttons here
one on the left one on the right
and uh i decided to hide all the wiring
in the ceiling
hopefully so this is all going to be
covered up so you won't see it
most likely and
there's this side profile of it so the
button
goes this torch then up to that one and
then all the way up there
same on the other side
and then this piston is kind of on its
own this is a crushing one
that goes down and gets inside the blaze
heads and
suffocates them and then this piston
and this one are the gates
this moves this last block so they can't
fall down
and that one cuts off the lava so those
two are hooked together
on that line over there the crusher ones
on that line over there so
made a little way to get back to get up
here and
now i just need to
do the wiring here so there's going to
be two hours snore latches i need
and a long timer it's going to take up a
bit of space so that's why i want to
hide it in the ceiling to keep it as
sleek as possible down below here so it
looks good
hopefully so it's just a little update
on what's going on and i'm gonna get to
work there
good news i got the wiring all done now
took me about half an hour to an hour to
do
that room up there is a little bit
bigger now you can see
but uh turned out very well and happy
um so blaze collect here
left button
causes the gates to close and the
crusher to come down then after
a certain amount of time to get the
blaze down to
one hit hopefully that pops back up so
they
stop suffocating that's where the head
their head will be in that spot there
then you can hit them to kill them
or use a potion like a instant damage
potion and kill them
collect all their blaze rods all their
xp and then when you're ready for
another batch of
blaze to come up that are collecting
below in the lava there
just hit the right button to open the
gate
that pours down so they can swim up and
that's all there is to it
okay so let's head on up um
so yeah just two buttons side by side
which is nice
and i've kind of shown this wiring
before so i don't know how much detail i
need to go
into uh
there's a few slight changes from my
blaze farm tutorial though
so this is the left button input right
here
and this is the right button left button
goes to an arsenal latch here
which controls that
gate so pressing the left button
closes the gate and then this is the
right button
when you hit the right button it opens
it
and that this is where it goes down to
the gate there
[Music]
right to those two pistons when i say
gate i mean those two pistons the one
that controls the lava and the one that
controls
the glass block for them to stand on so
it comes down to there
and actually i never really showed the
wiring
it's just uh
just wire there straight to that goes
down to a
torch here and then to that one which
powers that piston
i can add a repeater here if i want to
sync them
don't know if i will or not
okay and then the other rs nor latch
controls the crusher which is uh over
here this is a crusher one
um and that's the output to it to that
one piston right there
that's what this wire goes down to so
hit the left button powers this goes to
that
and then it activates this long delay
here
and then it shuts off after that time
goes by so this is that
new pulse sustainer i showed you about
five episodes ago
i was really remember i was really
excited about it because
i will probably use it a lot and i have
used it in this blaze farm so
instead of these repeaters being four
ticks each they're actually eight
with this setup it doubles their length
so in my other blaze farm i think i used
23 repeaters or 27 maybe
this i'll be able to use about half as
many so
be a lot smaller amount of space i need
for it
but this is not fine tuned yet i might
have to add a few
more here yet or remove a few
i'm not sure yet i can i know already
that this isn't set up right because
just an example of the fine tuning
that's not right
this crusher piston seems to be coming
down before
the gates close
which is bad because if that was to
happen it would push the blaze down
into where this glass block glow where
it goes
because it's not there yet so we need to
add a little bit more delay to that
and uh once i fine-tune all this i'll
probably show it to you one more time
so yeah i can just make this longer and
maybe add a few more i don't know
alright so the blades are falling down
they're getting pushed over to the lava
then they swim up and this is where
they're collecting
and i've adjusted the timing i think i
got it pretty close
to right now got 39
in there i'll probably have to use
splash potions or else a stone sword or
something with this because they
do take a bit of damage from the pistons
although it might be because i don't
have that set up properly yet i need to
add a regulator
to the conveyor belt there because we're
losing a lot of them
from suffocation you see they're they're
dying right there
so we need to control that a little bit
better but anyway here is an example of
it working
we will lose a few from this
and this should take them all down to
one hit all the ones that survive i hope
yeah so it's pretty cool
and uh i do have this open i'm not sure
if i'm gonna leave it open
oh this guy has a little bit more health
doesn't he
i think one of them snuck up as the gate
closed
it's hard to tell that is another issue
i seem to be having the xp
orbs are falling through the glass
i might have to lower the lava block
over there
down one more just so
it they definitely won't burn in it
because i'm a little worried about that
or change this glass block to something
else so that doesn't happen
but yeah splash potions would definitely
make this better
and then when you're ready for the next
ones just hit that
and uh yeah
so they can see you for a little bit
that's why they get the flames
if i block that up or put a block in
front of this
i won't have that problem there is
actually a piston right below
this at the moment i'm just not
using it
it's pretty cool i like it
it's gonna be very cool once i get it
all working perfectly
anyway one more last quick look
up here i just
in case anybody does care about the
redstone i added three more
repeaters here for a total of one two
three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven well
i think twelve and then
yeah twelve main ones
all set to four and then i had to
put uh two repeaters here because
uh the crusher kept activating before
the gates
which was a problem
all right so next task is to control
that a little bit better and i also need
to
connect the light on off
lighting thing of these two together
because right now they're separate and i
have to go up here
and manually flip the lever to shut them
off
and it would be nice if i have a switch
down here somewhere that i can just
flip to turn them both on or off
okay i've been at this for another hour
or so here's another update
i did replace that glass block with the
sandstone one so we'll see if that helps
getting very laggy about 53 there
we're just checking to see if the xp
will fall
down like it was before and gets stuck
in the lava or something dumb
so that could be pretty bad
oh i really wish i had a splash potion
oh it looks like it's falling down again
you see how it's kind of popping up
um worried about that
so weird when you have them all clumped
together like this and you hit them you
can't really tell if you're
killing them or not
i'm not quite sure why that is
there we go does any xp gonna go
into us when we get closer here
no okay that's good it might have uh
fixed it having the sandstone here
uh but in other news
i have also lowered that one lava block
down one just in case
that is a problem and uh should keep
them from being able to see us
as easily too because it'll be i noticed
they were kind of
jumping up and you could see their eyes
like before this other lava team down
all right and i've added some character
to this
i kind of like it kind of sticks out
same with over here and i have even
added an on off switch down here
for both sides which is great
maybe i'll get rid of these guys and
then we'll continue
all right that's better so this button
here
goes up there
and connects to a t
flip flop
over here
you can see the torch is behind there it
goes up into that block there
and it it's powered right now that turns
it off so it's a supercharged t
flip flop so it's a little bit quicker
and then
it's when this switches it sends power
to
that direction and then also runs over
this top here
to there so
pretty simple you can control it from
below here i'm thinking
i'm trying i don't want to get into the
pattern of you only using sandstone here
so
we're going to try and make this pretty
close to it we're going to start using
some wood
it's thinking that maybe putting leaves
uh for the top here maybe
would be cool or have uh maybe cross
sections with leaves
in between the crosses
uh up here i have modified that room
again
and those i know i said we weren't going
to go up there but we're going to go up
there again one more time
so it's all stone just to gas proof it
because i don't want anything to happen
because i'll never
remember how to fix it probably and
yeah so when this is all done
that stone will all be covered with
something so
don't worry about that it's not going to
be gray and same with this wiring
over here i'll probably wrap something
around it
to hide it and over here
although it does look kind of cool
without it even but yeah
when i was building it i was very
careful not to
make one side different than the other
just in case i didn't cover it
i wanted it to look symmetrical
and yeah turned out really well
so now paths will go to the right there
and to the left
gotta hook up the netherwart farm
somewhere or farms
uh over here i'm not entirely sure what
i'm gonna do
i was thinking about doing a zombie
pigman farm too and just have an exact
copy of that on this side
the same spacing and everything so it
looks symmetrical
but i don't know we do also need to
get a portal somewhere and
a minecart track maybe
but yeah i'm gonna there's gonna be
grass and stuff and trees
when this is all done so it's not gonna
be all red like this
i know that's why people don't like the
nether this is probably my most hated
block this texture right here
and it's a shame the whole nether is
made out of it pretty much
and i'm sure a lot of people share that
feeling so
yeah you really get a feeling of the
size when you look at it from down here
it's uh it's a big project
hey it's a big project that's why it's
taken so
stinking long to finish it
and everything seems to not want to work
so i have to keep working at it keep
fixing it and there's only one thing
left to do and that's to add a regulator
here
so it's getting late here
i might give it a shot we'll see
uh yeah i'll try it out
hopefully i can finish it if i finish
that this is all done pretty much and
just
fine tuning and finishing touches
afterwards
all right so i was looking at that over
there and it seems like there's one spot
where i can sneak a piston in
right over here and uh
can control the fall area
so to make a gate basically
and if it's like this they won't be able
to fall down and if it's like that
they can so we're gonna test to see
what happens if we close that off and we
have a bunch of blades in there
if uh they start going crazy or if they
neatly fall into that hole
i'm not really oh yeah so used to going
up there
okay so hopefully we're still in range
i think uh
maybe a few problems with this i don't
know
if this does work
right because they won't stay on so
it'll constantly
pulse like that
they're not taking damage but that is
annoying
i don't know how else to do it really
and then you still have problems
i don't know
this is such a tough thing to figure out
i would have to hook it up uh
maybe on a clock i don't really want to
use a clock but i might have to
or it would probably be the simplest way
of doing this
all right let me think about this
what could be done maybe is uh get rid
of those first
two pressure plates here
starting ones and
by default have it like that so they
fall into that holding area right over
there
and then when you're ready to send them
through have it so
this one goes back first and then
right after that one pushes
that'll push him over one block and then
have this one push right after that
again
and then that one over there retract one
more time
and that should uh push him through
and then you would just have to
alternate between
this one and that one back and forth
every
few seconds or so and it should be
good
yeah probably the best method that i can
think of
so i will try it hopefully
and we'll see what happens
i think this is gonna work i think it
will got the pressure plates gone
see they're gathering 14
or so in here it's getting really laggy
uh this one is inverted
so it's holding them back in there
because that's extended right now
the other one is on a delay
okay and uh oh nuts they saw me
they can see you through the pistons
here i think
okay well i might mess some of these
guys up
but uh
yeah i messed them up
okay well try this again without them
seeing me i guess
[Music]
okay we got a bunch there again and i
guess we'll try it one last time
but i don't think it's gonna work it
seems like it should like
that retracts that one pushes
them over one block then that one pushes
them again
onto the pressure plate and then that
one retracts again
and resets it seems like it's
done right but it just they glitch
through the pistons
oh you know why because it's you're
getting shot from
pressing against each other
ah it's kind of same issue as having
with the silverfish
glitching through blocks and stuff
which is a little discouraging i'm a
little out of ideas at the moment so
i'll probably have to leave this for
today
um if i ever did this again i would
never make a conveyor belt like this as
much as i love it like it's really cool
and everything
it sounds and looks cool but it's just
full of problems
anytime you push a mob with pistons it's
i don't know you're gonna have problems
so i better shut that off before it
crashes my game uh i guess
i gotta go to sleep here so
we're gonna end it got a lot done
but i'll have to think about what to do
about that i don't want to tear it out
either but
i don't know don't know i'll have to
think about it
but this is really cool and works really
well too
they're all they're all gonna die from
the piston damage
okay well i will
talk to you guys later i guess and uh
thanks for watching
oh yeah funny story remember i was
talking about the video editors
about that what was it cyber link
i got it written down somewhere here
cyberlink powerdirector or something
well anyway turns out just by chance
the other day i happened to see an icon
on my desktop and i
guess i have the program installed it
must have come
with my computer so i do have it
i looked at it it's it's so so
i'll have to play around with it a bit
more but uh
sony vegas was what most people
recommended or else
few people suggested adobe premiere
i think the verdict was that adobe
premiere is
better once you figure it out but sony
vegas
is just for
general use better i don't know but
600 bucks or something crazy but i may
may look into getting it
um anything else to talk about i don't
think so
i don't think so uh we'll probably do
something else next time
i'm i've spent quite a bit of time in
the nether today
so bye bye