[Music]
hello everyone welcome back this is etho
and today we're going to be working on
the slime farm a little bit
we set up this area here i think a few
days ago maybe a few weeks ago i can't
remember
i've just been watching it making sure
it's working well getting good numbers
and yeah you can see it's getting good
numbers it'll be even better once i shut
down the other slime farm too
so i think we're ready to go ahead with
this project
and start automating it so we'll have to
set up water canals all around
the perimeter of it might try
to set up a shut off system for it to
prevent the slimes from
spawning have to play around with that
idea
possibly might separate the different
sizes too
so we have small ones medium and large
um yeah i find as long as i'm within
this area
i get tons of slimes here because
other mobs despawn but these guys don't
unless you leave the area if you go 128
blocks away from them then i think they
all just disappear so
as long as i'm in the general area of my
cave here
uh this this room fills up with slimes
that's how i get so many
okay let's get going here
yep so the first thing i've been doing
here is i'm trying to polish it up a bit
i got rid of the rough cave walls and
replaced them with stone brick
and the floor all the way around in the
middle i put soil down and then i
brought
a few uh grass blocks that i got with
silk touch
so we got grass spreading here give the
place a little bit of color
and on this side we have a nice viewing
window
so you can see right out there is the
tree farm actually so we'll be able to
walk up and look inside here and see
what the slimes are up to which is
pretty cool that's a neat thing about
having the slime farm
up higher and having cave system like we
have here
so the actual height we're at right now
is
y 40.6 you bring up this menu pressing
f3 by the way
as you probably know i tried going one
block higher
i had this whole spawning pad one block
higher just to see if it would work
and no slimes are spawning so i think
this is
absolute highest you can go 40.6
keep that in mind what i'm going to do
now
we can't really have torches on the
spawning pad like this i'm just doing
that
temporarily because i think they count
as an
as an obstructing block
so they'll prevent slime spawning a
certain
amount but we need to light up this
place a bit
so that we don't get the other hostile
mobs with slimes though the lighting
doesn't matter
we just don't want the other hostile
knobs in here so
i know in the past you could use
glowstone in the floor
but i think that might not work now
because the
glowstone is treated like a glass block
again
so what i'm going to do i'm going to
create a backup of my world here and
then i'm going to replace
this floor with glowstone as much as i
have
and we'll see if slimes spawn on it
hopefully
so i'll go i'm gonna go ahead and do
that now
okay so we're gonna check out the
results now it's been about an
hour i left my game running while i ate
lunch and stuff
killed a few spiders in between um
the usual stuff you know went down to
the other slime farm it was loaded
this one did not have enough glowstone
to do
to do the whole pad so that's why i have
these torches here i wanted to
just make sure that they're an
obstructing block too
so no slimes on this side let's check
out over here
this is all the glowstone i had
not seen any
nope so i don't think they can spawn on
this
on the glowstone so that means i can't
really
or i shouldn't really put the lighting
in the floor i'll have to put it in the
ceiling
to prevent the other hostile mobs from
spawning
again it has the lighting conditions
have no effect
on slimes you can have it super bright
or super dark it doesn't matter
but i just don't want like creepers and
stuff in here
okay that's good to know i think i'm
going to load my backup but i might try
and chant something
at level 37 here so i gained a few
levels killing slimes and spiders so
if i did something good maybe i'll keep
this
and instead of going to the back up
we'll see
i guess we'll do 36 here on a pick
yeah garbage
all right the backup is loaded here and
i think we should try to figure out
how to do the lighting so right now i
got a
four block space from the spawning pad
to the ceiling
four blocks i'd like to keep it at that
because
when the big slimes are on here i want
them to be able to make it to
the edges quickly without jumping and
hitting their head
and they are uh 2.4
blocks high so i think when they jump
if we had a
only a three high ceiling they would hit
their head on it
so i'm gonna try to keep it at
four and uh let's see how this works out
if this was glowstone
this soil block here that would have a
light level of 15
and this would be 14 13 12
11 10 9 8
so it's spread out like like that
diamond like that
yeah it should work i'll have to space
some
two three
so try to alternate it so this works a
little better
i might have yeah i'd probably have to
either put glowstone here
if i want to keep it symmetrical or
i could put one here next
and then it would do a three blocks out
like the one before it
for minimal lighting anyway minimal
glowstone
okay i think i got that figured out
so i think now we're gonna start setting
up the water canals for this thing
and our goal is to get the slimes
to this corner here
okay so i think the way i'm going to
start this is just
set up the water so it ends just shy of
that
we're gonna have like a three three by
three area here without water on
uh this is going gonna be quite the
challenge for me i don't know if you
know this but i've never actually made
an automated slime farm before so this
is
kind of new for me this one will go
here yeah that's where we want it
um
good so it'll end here and then we'll
figure out what we
want to do with them after that because
i don't quite know everything
that we're gonna do i'm making this up
as we go along
uh we will have signs then
and we're kind of we're doing the water
canals backwards here
oops sort of
and i don't have any more signs hmm
okay um yes it's gonna be boring so i'll
skip it
and uh give you progress updates maybe
all right here's the first attempt at
the water canals so
like we saw before this one runs
the full eight block length and at the
three by three that i want
then i use a signs over here sign on the
sign trick
there's stairs directly below the water
source blocks here
so the slime should be able to get
pushed up
um then there is a one two three
block water stream there
and this corner i don't know how this
corner is going to work but i got three
water source blocks there
and one here and it does
this
so it should hopefully pull them around
the corner
but there might be a little bit of a
problem with the big slimes this
one water source block there is going
this direction slightly
i'm hoping these ones overpowered
because they're going straight that way
but we'll see i'll have to watch this
it's tough making this because i don't
have
i'm not using single player commands or
anything like that so i can't exactly
just
spawn a bunch of slimes and see how they
react here
now this water stream here is seven
blocks long
one two three four five six seven
again it meets up with the stairs here
to bring them up
and this one is a full eight blocks
length
i'll probably have uh this a three by
three column up to
the ceiling here too i don't think it's
really necessary to have this
open space and it simplifies things
if you don't have to make the slimes go
around a corner so that's why i did that
this side same thing eight blocks
seven blocks stairs
weird corner thing
and oh i forgot to put water
there it does also go
over slightly in places so i might have
to put a sign
like where this water is flowing over
there
if it's causing problems in total
there's 12 signs
used in this
there it is but i do have water here and
here as well
goes upstairs
and then another full eight blocks so
i think i'm gonna watch this for a while
and see what happens
and we'll see if any big slimes get
stuck in the corners i'm not sure
and i think next i'll do the lighting
here
i'm going to try to figure out a pattern
to do
i used paintshop pro to help me figure
out a pattern for the lighting and i
found one that i
i like pretty good pretty well pretty
whatever
um so we're gonna count
to the center so one two three
four five six seven eight oh that is the
center
i just uh i think that's the center
i just put down that water randomly
kind of use my eyes to figure out where
the center was i guess i got it right
awesome okay
so right here is our center
i'm gonna put four glowstone here
like so and then from the from the
corners
every two blocks will put a glowstone
and that will this is a symmetrical
style we figured out before
so provides a little bit more light than
we need
but that's okay i don't mind
uh sacrificing a few extra glowstone
it'll look better in here if it's
brighter too
okay and do that for the four corners
uh race for wool is coming up again too
guys i think we're playing this friday
get redstoners versus mine inc so
should have a video of that sometime
soon
i haven't really been working on my
ctm map too much i would like to get
into that again soon
it's really hard to find time for that
stuff
i'm behind on making videos too so it's
not helping
and mind crack um hopefully get some new
episodes out of that too again i haven't
had a whole lot of time to play there
i would like to do something with doc m
sometime soon
if that works out
one there and
another one right here
and then from that 202 blocks out i'll
finish this up and then i'll i'll let
you see it
there it is the lighting's all done this
is the pattern
so in total that is 32 glowstone
uh i did put one
up here i don't know just in case i tear
this out
uh this room is 22 by 22
and every every two blocks from the
corner
you put a glowstone then two blocks for
this one
all four corners and it creates this
pattern so
very simple i think we're gonna leave
this
uh slime farm here for today though i'm
gonna watch it for a while again
make sure the water canals work
and everything so we'll seal it up
got all the torches out of there now too
awesome okay
let's go check out our visitors make
sure they're doing okay
whoa lake hey
how's it going he's happy
every time i approach him they're not
looking at me and then they do that epic
uh
head turn to look at me it's funny
these guys
you still there i probably will
be redoing this room a little bit even
though a lot of people liked it
just because uh got a few other plans
with these guys
which we will get into some other day
probably
gonna do the airlock thing like a lot of
people wanted so two doors
keep them from getting out and i might
even set up a nice
area for them not sure yet
okay what else are we going to do today
cows are still there i did kind of want
to
we should clean something up polish
something up i think i'm going to get
rid of this ladder here
and instead we'll do
like a water ladder thing
uh actually let me get me let me get
some signs and then we'll do it
and yes i know what you're thinking i
know it why did he make another crafting
table
when he had one in his inventory already
i can assure you there was a good reason
for it but it's too complicated to
explain so just
just take my word for it
okay uh this is the messiest part of
the cave i would say past experiments
and random blocks everywhere
we're going to try to give it a little
bit of order today
not much just a little uh
the idea originally was to have like a
drop down to the farm here
this is the drop down
and you're at the farm and this is the
climb back up
so i think what we'll do
instead of having ladders i want to have
just a water
system to get back up so we'll replace
this with stone
brick oops
all the way up
like so
yep so i'm going to put uh alternating
signs and water all the way up here
much like a mob system tubing thing
uh this will be up
this is more of a personal preference i
guess and to give it a little more
character
um over compared to like a ladder
going up and this is something i believe
i
timed before in the past and then we
take about the same time to go up a
ladder and to swim up a water
thing like this so
not a big deal the water might actually
be
quicker because you get a little bit of
acceleration boost
uh right off the bat when you when you
jump so you go
pretty quick right right at the
beginning there
and then it slows down to like ladder
speed
i think
although might be something worth
testing
but anyway i would i prefer to hold
space to go up
compared to holding w
just just my preference
yep i don't know about you guys but i'm
really looking forward to
a new patch hopefully one comes out soon
um i know it just feels like it's been a
while
since we last got a new patch because
when 1.0 came out there wasn't really
anything new in it compared to 1.9
and i think it's been a few weeks we got
the snapshots of course but i haven't
been checking those out
personally is it
not a big fan of them they're kind of
like
the pre-releases which i did like the
pre-releases except
uh problem with the snapshots is they're
not taking the time to make sure
any serious bugs are out of it i don't
think
i thought i saw a creeper i could be
wrong about that
but i'm a little eerie about using them
i heard in the new snapshot that ladders
aren't going to have a collision mask
a little bit disappointed about that
because
that means that's another really hard
hit for each road
although it's still possible you just
have to use no
no no no no what did that do
it's all right guys it's all right it's
all right it's got a little wet
let's try this out
that's not bad yeah eats road will still
work you just have to
use full blocks or trap doors or
something else
above the boat but just can't use
ladders anymore
and the thing is uh
like the issue with the ladders i think
the reason they changed it is because
they're so glitchy now if you try
to
like break them you can have serious
issues or
place them even sometimes like you'll
place them against the wall
and they'll go to the side
or behind where you're placing it which
is weird
but in the past it wasn't an issue
because
i don't know it's like a bug they
introduced
that they don't know how to fix now so
they're just getting rid of the
collision
as a cheap way of fixing it in my
opinion
but whatever
we have trapdoors they do much the same
thing
there are a few pretty cool things
coming out in the new patch though
whenever
whenever it does come out that i'm
looking forward to like
people have told me that i'll be able to
get the wheat farm going again
because the cows won't trample the crops
and somebody told me
even if they jump on the farmland that
it doesn't trample it
so that's good to know
and of course we have the wool regrowing
on sheep
and i think that's about it
from what i've heard
cool to get some new blocks or something
in the game
all right well we got a little more
order over here not much
but it's something cool so
i think we're about to end the episode
here maybe we'll do one more thing
i had a lot of people wondering what
being of
oh i can't say it can i arthropods
arthropods arthropods
that's what i'm sticking to they're
wondering what it does so i'll show you
what that does and also we should do a
slime farm check here
we got at least one guy
let's check the corners uh
yeah just one slime spawned in that time
so
don't see any drops sitting around
anywhere so
it's gonna take some time to see how
this works
i guess
yeah so bane of arthropods allows you to
do more damage to spiders chief spiders
and silver fish and
just about every time i hit these guys
it's a one-hit kill with
level 5 and
diamond sword
but occasionally you gotta hit him twice
but
it's pretty powerful
any more around um
nope and it does regular damage to the
other mobs so just for spiders
cave spiders and silverfish
okay i'll and possibly spider jockeys i
haven't tried
anyway i'll see you guys again next time
thanks for watching