look at this look what's happening right
now I thought I saw some fireballs
flying I have a blaze chasing me up a
ladder right now I think I've ever seen
that before in this game that's pretty
crazy so if I stop climbing that jerk
how do you hit me so many times can you
grab the ladders with the lighter wings
I don't think you can nope nope you
can't what a jerk I could climb all the
way up now and he's waiting up there for
me Oh nope no let me go by there's no
way of getting by him without telling
him I don't think oh he got me again
all right we're on our way to the tree
farm get out of here crazy guy aah
oh all right that does it
Oh got him not today not today there's
another one where did you come from
where did it go
I think that's a song isn't it where did
he come from where did he go yeah it's
gotten I joke okay well welcome back
everybody this is etho and we are once
again in our Minecraft world here over
at the tree farm I wanted to show you
guys where it's at right now so I've
worked on it some more it's just about
done function-wise we've still got a
certify this area a little bit's it
looks a bit nasty but yeah as you can
see it is doing okay I've tried it out
for quite a while here
the only issue I'm having is the very
odd time one of these Jeff's fireballs
will still hit me and I'm not exactly
sure what to do about it's like one in a
hundred maybe it's very rare but it can
happen and as you can see I've added a
couple things on to it so we now have
two Pistons over here that that come out
sand stopped me from planting any more
trees until enough time has passed that
is to give oops
okay still having issues with branching
they don't stop it but they are annoying
I have to break them afterwards
I'd say give enough time for the
sandwich maker there to move all the
wood out of the way if it didn't do that
this whole thing would jam up eventually
so yeah they just extend for a little
bit in order to do that I set up a
hopper timer out here let's go outside
right over here this times how long they
stay extended depending on how many
items we have in there
I've also hooked up a leaf crushing
system flawless absolutely flood
flawless system here you can see we got
saplings all over the place I'm gonna
have to redo this
look at this all these saplings are
supposed to go in the hopper over here
and we have absolutely none exactly as I
intended let me show you what's going on
here so yeah we have a big wall of
pistons they crush the leaves pretty
much get most of all the leaves and and
the leaf or that not the leaves the
saplings are supposed to drop down into
these hop
I had carefully placed down below here
but we collect absolutely no sap things
with this thing which I found a little
bit surprising I thought that would work
I'm pretty sure that's how you you're
supposed to do it traits but what
happens I think the piston head counts
as a solid block now so you know instead
of falling down the saplings either go
up or they go out into the wiring they
don't go down right let's let's check
that out actually I was a little
surprised
do we have any spare pistons around here
okay let us check this out I'm not sure
if I got my facts wrong or what I forget
so many things in this game or things
change and then it mixes me all up I
don't know what's going on anymore but
I'm pretty sure this is not a full
collision box right yeah I threw I threw
items through the piston head and they
go on top to arm as well lower then then
the top of the piston head right so I'm
not sure why that's happening even I'm
pretty sure in the past if you did
something like that let's just double
check so it should stay in the piston
arm I would think okay it did oh and
then when it retracted it shot died oh
maybe that's what's happening then let's
try this one more time see what happens
okay where'd it go guys I think our
sapling ran away did it shoot through
over here somewhere I think is this gone
all right so it doesn't always go into
the piston arm area for sure so I'm
gonna have to change my setup there with
that but other than that we are pretty
close to a fully working tree farm here
today I want to make this area look
nicer though and do a couple things
around here we do have the zombie
spawner as well would be nice to do
something with this turn it into an XP
farm because we're going to be afk here
anyways it would be cool if we
got something out of it all right let's
give this a try guys so I changed out
the regular pistons the sticky pistons I
moved them all back by one and then put
trapdoors on them so the trapdoors are
we're gonna break the leaves and because
they don't take up a full block I
believe we'll find out
I think the saplings should fall through
or land on top of them if they're open
instead of flying up and out onto the
wiring hopefully there wasn't enough
space to do it in the on this side
though so I'm going to leave them as
regulars and hopefully won't be too big
of a problem also we got wiring over
here so I kept these ones as solid
blocks it's not perfect but basically we
just need to get one sapling from each
tree we chopped down here right so that
we'd never run outs with regular oak
trees I think it's one in 20 chance when
you break a sapling
jungle trees I think is a one in forty
chance and I'm not sure about the other
ones all right let's go tree tree has
grown and trapped us inside let's break
that okay what did that do
is there any saplings on the ground
outside here or in the wiring I don't
see any all right did we collect any we
got two yes success okay that's okay
let's take a quick peek inside yeah all
the trap doors opened or most of them
anyway
that's too bad maybe we'll try one more
see if that messes it up
I was hoping they would stay flat you
know better all right
now what has happened uh yeah I think
it's okay let's check our our hopper
here again so you've got any saplings
we got one okay as long as we didn't get
one every time that is good enough and I
just did one last thing here guys I made
this wire go up to the dropper over here
so the idea is I'm going to manually
fill this with saplings of whatever type
I want like if I want birch trees or
jungle trees I load that up before we
start the AFT session rights with
whatever type I want I guess we'll have
to enter from this side now okay and
every time we grow a tree this should
give me one sapling back and I fixed the
wiring to siliceous then now yeah we
just got a sapling from this good
I couldn't make it automatically fill
this too but I don't think it's worth
worth the bother all right guys very
cool so this tree farm is just about
done now we just have to spend a little
bit of time here making it look half
decent hopefully I'm gonna try see what
happens is this gonna make the water
spill I think I'm okay to break these
right I hope a water terrifies me it's
like it's redstone's natural enemy if
you didn't know especially when you just
finish a building you're and you're
happy with everything there's nothing
worse than when the water washes it all
away and then you gotta figure out what
what broke all right maybe I'll put a
light right there otherwise it's gonna
be pretty dark here and we might hook up
the zombie spawn or two I think that
would be a good idea but yeah let's talk
for a little bit oh and by the way the
plan is I think this is the middle right
here this block in this block so we're
gonna line the portal up so that when we
come out we see the gas base you
staring right at us then we walked to
the left here and we're gonna walk
underneath this line of logs it's the
only way of getting over here and then
we'll walk up to the spots I think
that's the best way of doing this but
yeah 1.9 is coming out guys are you
excited are you happy with the changes
they made with this release let me know
your thoughts on it in the comments um
if you haven't played it yet are you
excited if you have played it what do
you think of it hmm I don't know guys I
don't know about this I like the red and
green
maybe the orange maybe the yellow you're
gonna hate me for this so I have to say
it's I think the polka dots have to go I
think they have to go guys wait let's
try this let's try them over here yeah
terrible that makes it worse nope no
fences don't do the fences I think I
think the orange clay was better though
right yeah I think that's what we're
gonna have to go with but yeah for me
guys I think this 1.9 update has been
pretty good I'm happy with it the big
thing I I look for with an update is
there anything that wrecks the game for
me with an update if yes then I'm maybe
unhappy with it if no if it's only like
things that add to the game I'm happy
with it to me 1.9 has only added to the
game since I don't do a lot of PvP I
mostly do single-player the changes
haven't really affected me like some
other people some people like them some
people don't
I haven't done enough like multiplayer
pvp to really know if I'm happy with the
changes yet so I'm kind of on the fence
with it still we're out of green I want
more green started
in single-player though I do find the
combat changes have been beneficial like
for instance I've gone teething recently
and I've had situations where I get
overwhelmed with mobs again I in the
past all you got to do is spam click
you'll never they'll never get you you
know it's not really all that exciting
now you can actually get overwhelmed you
can get surprised creepers in the face
since I don't carry a shield with me
like it hurts you can get a lot of
damage from a creeper again which I
think it's kind of cool skeletons I
don't know about them though they are
almost too annoying almost but they are
definitely much tougher
I like the skeletal horse change I think
that's that was a great idea it's a good
way of allowing people to get horses on
servers that otherwise you know somebody
might kill them all or take them all
that was good they rebounce the armor
and all that - if you didn't know like a
lot of people just think of the swing
speed change but no they totally changed
a lot of aspects to the combat so now I
think the armor is a little bit more
fair you can no longer become invincible
basically if you have max protection
before you would take like no damage now
you can definitely get hurt still and
they rebalance the potions so strength
potions aren't crazy overpowered anymore
which is great they didn't really adjust
the bow to matter too much which I'm
happy about cuz I love the bow the way
it was I don't think it needed any
tweaking the only thing they really did
is they added more arrows which again
good good happy with that more content
is always better in my opinion some
people have been negative towards the
update though I think it's I think
people expect more in less time I'm kind
of in the same boat like if they did
everything they did in this update in
three three months for example that
would be awesome
instead it took like over a year and you
know with minecraft being as big of a
as it is you would think they're top
priority would be updating it keeping it
interesting for everybody so that they
sell more copies and that doesn't seem
to be the primary focus for some reason
which I find confusing but at the same
time it's a game I've gotten more than
my money's worth out of so if they never
updated it again I couldn't really fault
them with that either so I'm happy with
every update we get as long as it
doesn't wreck anything for me which this
one so far has been awesome and they did
a lot of things like they added more
sound files which has been nice they had
a command block change so now you can
chain them and there's a repeat feature
to them that's huge like that simplifies
things a lot when doing command block
stuff to help map makers out a lot and
all in all I'm just I'm good with it
I think it's it's been great light your
wings are awesome yadda yadda yadda I'm
gonna keep building okay I don't know
what's going on with this building guys
isn't this like weird though I feel like
we're inside an abstract painting of
some sort like it's so colorful got red
we got yellow we got green we got orange
all over the place I don't know how it
happened like I well I kind of do I
brought four colors of clay I couldn't
decide which one I wanted to use for the
wall and I just ended up using all the
colors why not why not and it's it's
created a an interesting style hasn't it
I do like it though like I don't know
what it is about it I think it's kind of
cool
so I'm hooking up the zombie spawner now
zombie spawner is right here this worked
out perfect
I didn't plan this but like it's right
here towards a positive we go one two
three right next to the gas stage is
where it ends and then towards the
negative we need it to go four so one
two three four gives us an 8x8 the
maximum spawning size
the spawner and we're gonna put water
against this back wall right and push
them this way towards us because we're
gonna be afk there and we'll collect
them all together I guess we'll have to
figure out maybe with the iron golems a
way of killing them
so that they'll automatically drop XP as
well well I just realized we have a
problem here it turns out like we're in
hard mode this is not spotting any
zombies though so either this update is
messed up and spawners aren't working or
we have some other issue but yeah
probably won't be able to test this
today then oh man ok guys I think this
is it well it's very very close to done
we just can't do the zombie spawner
thing today until that gets fixed it
might be fixed in the latest ones I'm on
pre 2 still but yeah very very close to
done and I'm really happy with how it
turned out this is a really cool project
I got rid of most of the torches so it's
all hidden lighting we got like lighting
up there in the corners here of the the
ghast we got some lights as well kind of
lights up all around still got these in
you know I realized we don't have to use
water for the zombie spawner either we
just use a villager we don't have
running water all the time I did a
trapdoor wall I realized though it's not
gonna stay like this once we use the
tree farm cuz we got redstone right on
the other side it's gonna update it all
it's more hidden lighting up and and
down in the water here we got the
hoppers facing into this chest so this
is where the wood is gonna collect and
yeah let's just give it a try make sure
it doesn't catch on fire or something
crazy
yeah that seems good
are we on fire are we on fire right now
we are not on fire that is what I like
to see let's try out these other trees
too so jungle trees make sure they can
grow they're gonna grow it definitely is
taking longer than the oak tree wait a
second oh there goes there goes get good
let's give a acacia trees try as well I
never did try it in the tree farm now
that we got it all finished seemed fine
it's gonna branch out which might cause
problems if we run it for a long time
but as long as I clean up the stray
branches from the tree it should be good
okay very cool very cool guys I'm happy
with this oh I just got hit by a
fireball oh yeah I never did fix that
did i I think because I move forward
there though that's why that happened so
there is something we need to try here
it's something very cool
I don't think they fixed it in this
update yeah oh man that is faster than I
expected
oh man that really whips around when it
starts turning yeah I got to ease up on
there he's up on the turning I wish I
had a bigger sheet of ice now to try
this that's crazy
Oh where'd the boat go wow there's the
boat alright so yeah you remember when
yeah you could move quickly on the land
I showed that a couple episodes ago each
you still can't move on the land it's
too slow again so they they fix the
friction for that but they never fixed
it for on ice
and it seems to have this weird effect
where you can like drift on the ice and
move super fast it's really cool isn't
it
oh that was awesome I wasn't even
holding the controls and I would like
got into a spin they're not touching the
controls yeah you you keep spinning
that's awesome I guess we got a bigger
patch over here this is where we should
be trying it you cannot go from the
water to the ice though I I really don't
want them to fix that that is kind of
cool all right guys well it's that time
again we're gonna have to call episode
here for today but we do have a comment
of the day which says Dokdo etho any
plans to do stuff on the new hermit
craft server yeah so if you guys did not
see hermit craft has just started season
4 um it's very exciting everybody's
excited but I have not started playing
on the season 4 map I do have plans for
a series it involves another person
though and that person is not around at
the moment so it might be a few days
before I can get started with that
it's the plan assuming you know that
other person still wants to do it and
all that kind of stuff it's not definite
but if all goes well we should be
playing on there in a few days all right
ok yes
very good so I hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
as always and I hope you have a
wonderful day take care bye bye
you