[Music]
greetings
i have good news the storage room is
basically
complete now i can comfortably say it's
done
i would decide to go with pattern number
three with the dot
it was i believe the most voted one and
i have
come to like it myself as well the
creeper face was cool
except it looked a little bit empty in
this room
and uh i did like pattern one but i
think i
prefer this one now
and good news we have fixed the
stairs or the shutters not opening and
closing correctly
it was a block updated issue after all
now they all open together and close
together it's great
i have cleaned up the wiring room here
we'll go look at it very quickly
this is something i do now with my
redstone projects i like to put ladders
or
signs or something at the stairs like
this
in case i accidentally spill water it
won't wash
all my wiring away you know because i
tend to do that quite often
but yeah so basically pistons are
underneath
this block here and this one here uh
before i had the repeaters on top these
blocks here
and they were sending power above
now we have them powering the pistons
from the side so there's no
diagonal powering issues
which was causing the problem i don't
know exactly well
yeah we still have that bug in the game
don't know exactly
what was going on i almost think it was
like just steal this temporarily
i almost think like if this repeater was
powered
it was powering this block here well
this one here it was powering this block
and i think that was affecting the
piston diagonally like
like this not like diagonally from the
repeater
like that i think it was doing that as
well but i think you're doing
like that was the problem but i could be
wrong it was
i still only exactly understand why it
was doing
woohoo i wanted to go down anyway
i don't know exactly why it was doing
what it was doing because
this this stair was opening before this
one even though this one had a longer
delay
with all uh block update issues i've had
with pistons usually
if there is a problem they will open
together
so i don't know exactly what was wrong
and i have also expanded over here
a little bit we're gonna round it out a
bit more
i might just make a big deep hole there
i'm not sure
and i have moved
this rail over one block
before it was over here and we're just
waiting for that grass to grow
i decided to light this part by putting
a pressure plate over
a glowing pumpkin and i'll probably do
that more often
there's another cool trick people have
been showing me too
do i have fences i do
you can do something like this um
oh i do have pumpkins too i am so
prepared
uh i think i went that one too far
you can do you can have like the pumpkin
then a fence
and then the pressure plates and like
how like if there's wood around wooden
planks
that's another way you can do it which
is pretty cool uh
as long as you're not walking over it
because then it might be a little
strange
but that's one another way of hiding the
lighting really really well
uh what we're going to do first here is
make a staircase here
and i'll probably just show quick clips
of it like i used to do i've kind of
fallen out of the habit
of my uh old editing trick i learned
from
zysteru zisto
zesto i have such a hard time with his
name
uh we'll probably do a staircase like
this where it
goes out six blocks then there's a
switch type thing and then another six
blocks
so here i go
[Applause]
okay so this is attempt number one at
the stairs and it's
not going to work like this it's way too
gradual
we're going to use real stairs instead
of the half slabs
to make it steeper downside of that is i
won't be able to run
up them like that but that's that's just
the price said yes
um i could like start doing the half
slaps further back
like from here for example but
i want to keep it extended out further
like this
so that we have a nice view of this area
here
and it would look really weird if we had
half slabs
going for miles so and switches the
stairs
and it should work a lot better
okay so i spent a fair bit of time
tweaking this i had to rip out these
stairs and rebuild them about
five or six times i think i'm gonna keep
it
like this it's uh it's regular stairs
now
and there's a one two three
four five of them then the platform over
here
which is at a pretty good height before
i think it was two or three blocks
higher and the bridge was at
your eye level basically now it looks
like the bridge is up higher
which is good and it's not blocking this
window like i had before
as much
and then again this is one two three
four
five so it's the same
and i'll probably do the sides out of
wood like the regular wood like this
and at the bottom here i'm thinking we
will do a water pool in the middle after
all
i know i tried that before and kind of
didn't like it but
i'll probably try it again
have a round water pool or something
there
with uh like a three or four wide
walkway around it
over here with the a rail around it as
well
and move this and have
have a walkway that goes around like
this somehow
is what i am for seeing doing
but for right now let's just finish this
up see how this
looks
um my good axe is about to break here
well not about to but it's it's getting
old
i did get a new pick finally a good one
and i got a fish
efficiency five one as well yet so happy
about that
see
and this we will make go up two blocks
and i may still put something over here
not sure yet though
um
put that there i'll just see how this
looks
there
feels like i've been making a lot of
stairs lately
you'd think i'd be a master at it by now
but nope
yeah i don't know if i'll i'll make it
raised like that
and then we'll do the fences like uh the
other stairs by the tree farm
up up to the right there
oh yeah we won't want it to connect to
the wall like that that'll look weird
do that
should look pretty good i think
yeah that's good i like it
i'm not sure how to do the lighting
will probably have a rail that connects
to here or something
okay so i'll tweak with this a little
bit
and we'll see how it looks
yeah so it doesn't seem like there's
enough space for a mushroom
over here because there's really only
six blocks of working space
um got a new idea though because i want
to put something here otherwise it'll
look
empty going to put
a jukebox station here
so that we can listen to our records um
and we're gonna try do a little redstone
with it
so the center of this seems to be one
two three four five
six seven eight nine now we'll put the
center
two three four five right here
so this is where i will be putting
the jukebox gotta make it
very good that'll go there
and then thinking of putting
chests i've been
really making a lot of sounds this video
for some reason
i don't know why uh
these will hold their records
it's not going to be a big station just
a little
very nice and we can see them coming up
still from our stairs except uh we can
see them going up
coming around and up but i guess we
can't see
over there anymore that's fine
i got some jungle wood i think that'll
look good with the jukebox
it's kind of the same color
yeah see how that looks uh maybe we will
do
something like that
then in the back
and we'll do something with the floor
there too i think that's
pretty good um yeah so we're gonna rig
this though
so that we have lamps here that come on
when we put a record
in the jukebox to do that we're going to
do a bud t-flip
bud t flip flop over here so do we have
pistons
we do not have pistons let's go get some
yeah i think this will be pretty good
uh where did we leave them
oh there we go
how's it so cool i like that room that's
very good
uh we will put the piston right behind
the jukebox and that's what senses the
update when you put the record in or
take the record out
the jukebox updates
and then that will
let's build it out of cobble maybe now
we'll we'll use the redwood
we'll move that and then
this is a design i saw on
recon jeff's uh channel
it's one of my favorite t-flip-flop bud
switches
yeah that's this is in the way already
hmm
nuts okay we'll have to
i'm gonna see if i can move this out of
the way
okay i think we can do it now i took the
wiring off up here and
and moved it down here i wasn't able to
lower it
here because i guess the elevator for
the cave spiders
is right there so we need to keep these
here otherwise they'll
escape um
it doesn't give us a whole lot of
working room here but i think it'll be
okay so when the piston extends this
block goes out above the redstone torch
which will then allow
power to flow from this block to this
wire
when it's extended that will go to
another block oh dang it
dang it dang it dang it dang it oh the
wiring
did not have ladders where i needed them
yeah it's annoying happened so often for
me
anything else wrecked put that back
okay wire there um redstone torch here
we'll power that block
that'll come over like that
to another wire there
and repeater set to one over here
and then i think we need two more blocks
yet
we'll have to go up a little higher
take this out too
and that should do it
so now if there's an update
extends retracts extends
retracts good i'm gonna make sure we
don't lose our record or i'll be very
sad
then we could put that there
that there um
[Music]
and i want these to come on so we'll put
redstone torches there and there
okay so that'll do it it's just in
reverse right now
see we'll change the floor
get our regular planks for the for this
uh
what would you call that what i have the
the wood on the left and right a
highlight i don't know
i'm sure it has a proper name um
so we gotta switch this over
it's one way of doing it
usually i use repeaters if i need to
switch a t flip flop you just add a
delay
one delay and now that we put that there
it should be
at the right state
yeah so it's off by default with no
record in
put a record in lights come on
uh they'll stay on even when it finishes
playing
it they only shut off when we take the
record out which is good
because that'll add a little extra
lighting here too because it'll probably
most the time always be on
and then we will try to merge this into
over here and over here
[Music]
i don't know having a really tough time
trying to merge
stone brick into this red wood doesn't
look very good
so
may have to do something else here
if you got ideas let me know and
thinking what i
probably have to do is just use the
stone
all the way through
and we'll see how that looks and then
where these pumpkins are
we could have lava with iron gates in
front or iron bars
but if you can think of another way of
doing it that doesn't
uh get rid of the wood look let me know
or that looks better in general
um yeah
then i don't know maybe use the nether
the nether brick like we do with the
this stuff here
although i hate to have that in this
part of the cave because i was trying to
avoid using it
but i don't know
because i can't really change the stone
brick here
because we use it throughout the whole
slime elevator there
i don't know i'll try
i'll try switch that with nether brick
and put lava there and we'll see how it
looks
there we go so that would be the other
option another way of doing it
that carries the stone look from there
and there
and keeps it going uh if i
if i do keep it like this i will
probably
not make it completely flat on the top
i'll try maybe
do a little give it a little shape
anyway
i've also put these here these pumpkin
lights
not sure if i'll keep those either but
they do
oh mushrooms
they do keep or they do light up the
place quite a bit those three
that i have here um
what else should we do i think i'm gonna
end this episode pretty quick
uh with the villagers actually let's
grab a door
just want to try something
the villagers over here i'm going to
start hopefully working on this
soon
you're gonna escape
oh dang it
give me that iron okay
one oh damn we're missing a bunch what
happened
it's only three in here now we had like
seven or
eight or
the heck
no ah it was a trick
seriously where i don't have any doors
in my base where was that
um anyway
i'm gonna somehow have to get that guy
back in here or else kill him
these two are having a stare down oh
interrupted
oh
that's weird almost like they're talking
i want to try
um this is not where don't you go down
there
it's not working too well
we're going to make out a 2d pole for
them
and put a door here and just see what
happens
if they'll go down it
it's a house
it is go
no that's not going to work
anyway the plan is to add another hatch
like this
over here and then get rid of
get rid of this lava wall here and we
will
make a village for them back behind
the wall here somehow we'll i'll have to
dig out a big area
i kind of know what theme i want to do
already
but i guess they don't like this door
anyway another day another day
i wonder where that other one went to
your boy no he's probably long gone
yeah he's gone
i can't i wonder like there no zombies
should have been able to spawn
in there i wonder what happened to all
the villagers
oh well
very strange i thought maybe
it was these but all the doors seem to
be here still
so i have no idea what the zombie broke
down
oh yes ha ha suckers
that worked so now i can work in this
room safely without them escaping
which is good that's what it's trying to
do
so that's probably all we'll do for
today got a little bit done anyway
i'm gonna go watch the hunger games the
movie i haven't seen it yet
been hearing mixed reactions about it
but hopefully it's good
yeah i knew i wasn't gonna make that
it's okay oh that will kill me
nope i'm okay um
the hunger games in minecraft is quickly
becoming popular as well there's a
really cool map for it
and i've been getting a lot of requests
to play it
we i actually did a few days ago pause
and pause got
a bunch of us from the minecraft server
together to play it
and it was it was a lot of fun i played
three games
recorded it i was going to upload it if
it was interesting but
all in all it wasn't overly exciting
even though it was fun but
i found most of the time i was just
running through the forest looking for
people
and i never actually found anybody like
i was hoping for random encounters but
it never happened
the only time i would actually any
actually see anybody in it
is uh at the very beginning when you go
for your chest and
towards the end when everyone dies and
you go
to the center to get more stuff
but anyway there was one funny clip i'm
going to show you
and uh hope you like it
and thanks for watching don't
move don't move
darn it i'm facing a tree me too yeah
i don't know we're starting in five four
three two someone might die
one
i'm going for it please don't kill me
oh this is terrifying is it getting dark
yeah is it getting darker oh you finally
got me
i wanted you so bad
i see you you're a hunter
um i have you because i gotta go it
should be daytime
all right
[Music]
uh how do i fly slash
gm want that bow man
oh sweet give me that bow it's still
nighttime
see you guys give me the bro
it's on the ground it's yours take it
and we never speak of this again
[Laughter]
oh my god i've never seen that sign of
evil
it's terrifying
that's crazy
[Music]
oh
wow squid survived