[Music]
hey hey how's it going everyone this is
a though and welcome back thank you for
joining me for another episode of our of
our nightmare oh man guys this thing
what have I done why didn't I just build
this at a water temple would have been
so much easier but it's it's really
close to to being at the point of a
water temple
we gotta flood it you got I got the ice
all around it
we're gonna flood it in just a moment
here but first very important stuff has
gone on in the world of Minecraft I
tweeted about this even I'm in the 14 W
30 C snapshot now we had a lot of
trouble with the last few snapshots I've
tried this one and extreme improvements
like oh it's so good it is so good
they're doing that multi-threading stuff
and it they're working out the the bugs
and the kinks with it and it's working
really good on my computer some other
people have said they haven't had as
great about performance increases like
others but for me it is pretty good I
tried like when I'm not recording I can
get like 300 to 700 frames per second
just like looking out at the horizon if
you look up in the sky your frame rates
go even higher of course if you if I
turn it to 32 chunks that's another
thing they added an option where you can
go up to 32 chunks I haven't tried this
while recording this might be bad while
recording when I was not recording I was
getting about 30 frames with 32 chunks
on which is like not really great but
it's like not super leggy either it's
actually going pretty good I don't know
if they've loaded though I don't know
they're still loading
yeah they load a lot slower when I'm
recording that is for sure
otherwise it's like Zoop it's done oh
man we can see the world look at this it
just keeps going and going
thirty two chunks is actually almost too
far like you can't really see anything
that far away eventually there's this so
many things in the way like like in the
real world if you look at the horizon
you can't see infinitely right like the
stuff gets in your way and it blocks
your view and the more things there are
that that render or that you see
eventually you can't see anything past a
certain point type of thing anyway I
don't think I'll ever play on 32 chunks
it's just too far honestly there's
there's no point but like 24 chunks is
pretty good I like that but when I'm
recording I'm gonna stick to 16 probably
anyway so it's going good for me the
ghost block issue seems to have
disappeared and I was having to it I do
get it occasionally but it's nothing
like what we were having so anyway
enough technical talk let's get to our
thing for today the guardian farm here
has been quite the time investment but
we're at the point now where we can
actually have a lot of fun with it
hopefully oops I really need to do some
Enchantix i I know I've said like XP is
way too easy to get but I've gone
through so many tools digging this hole
it's insane that I actually just need to
sit and chant things I haven't got the
water Strider depth Strider enchantment
yet even cuz I just have had the levels
for it that's all going towards my pics
and stuff WAIS is still hard to break
his stupid haste beacon I can break the
the ice easy like going along this way
but then I hit the wall
and then I break two blocks but yeah I
made a backup of my world before I
started like placing this ice here
because I'm not sure we're gonna exactly
want to flood this just yet just in case
there's an issue and it's like oh I wish
I didn't flood it I should have did this
before I flooded it
I want to back up because once this is
flooded it's flooded and I am not
removing the water ever it would take
way too long even with like stacks of
sponges to get rid of all the water
that's gonna be in this hole no not
gonna happen so I thought I could just
zip by and break all the ice and then we
could see it flood on camera and it
would be amazing but this is so slow
come on we're almost there so I'm just
gonna do one layer to start off with I
want to confirm what what layer these
Guardians spawn at because I'm not sure
if they do exactly spawn on on this
bottom layer we'll have to see here it
goes
will it be able to keep up rendering
while recording it looks pretty good
look at that there's no sometimes when
you flood big areas like this like you
you don't see it it just happens all at
once
instantly it can't render it it's it
seems like it's keeping up really good
though let's get in front of the wave ah
it's so cool such such a good snapshot
all right so that's one layer done I'm
gonna just like wait a while if we're
extremely lucky we might see it happen
on camera here even but I want to see if
anything spawns in that yeah it doesn't
look like they're gonna spawn in just
this first layer so maybe it's outside
of their spawning range we're gonna
flood the second one we got quite the
mob trap going down there - under the
water
have to light it up oh man that looks so
cool yeah we're just gonna do one layer
at a time here until we confirm that
they start spawning somewhere and then
we'll do them oh yeah right there
we got one already we got two this is
the lair this is where they spawn so we
were one layer off there that why well
when it says why 41 is what you want at
at your head they don't spawn at this
first one okay
hey guy all right good to know so that
means for the rest of this flooding I
can do pillars up I believe so instead
of doing it like block here block here
and then breaking them I'm gonna go on
top and I'm gonna do just pillars all
the way up and then break them going
down kind of like yeah here I'll show
you one Oh should we go higher I think
this is probably good I think we can
just do this we break when we break all
the columns of ice then the whole thing
will flood it once and this is a lot
easier um so it might be back up loading
time guys because if you look above us
there's like at all times 15 to 20
guardians in the water here and it's
only two layers deep so their spawn
rates are pretty good a lot better than
I was expecting
which means this hole I dug might be
SuperDuper overkill so rather than
filling this whole thing with water
we'll just make a little tank in the
middle and fill that with water I think
is the way to go here yeah
all right guys let's fast forward in
time now and check out my new fish tank
I loaded the back up and I just built a
tank in the middle here we're about to
flood it and hopefully this works out
okay or I'll be very sad
it is spotting them in already even
though there's not really any water here
so yeah like I said earlier or last
episode this whole thing is an
experiment for me I'm having fun just
testing things out seeing how it works
and so I might change things around
every every so often with this but yeah
this should work I'm pretty sure it'll
work the cool thing is since we dug out
all the sides even though that was a
waste of time we have this awesome view
of the thing left side view that we went
in a pet before it's not a total waste
straight where they spawn er they spawn
II on the top or in the streams I've
never you know I've never figured out
yet
if squid and and like these guys spawned
oh you know what we can't tell if they
spawn in flowing water or if it has to
be source blocks the thing is there is
source blocks in in the wall there so
yeah this isn't a good way to figure out
Wow even with this just a little bit of
water look how many we're getting in
such a short time
it's pretty crazy all right
anyway now I can't go in there because
they're gonna kill me ah darn it you see
that dirt block over there that's what
we need to get to and now I'm not sure
we can do it like they're guarding it
the guardians are guarding the whole
thing here
we this feels like a waste I kind of
wanted to do it from the inside but I
don't think we can't because they will
kill me as soon as we break this this
ice here it should create water all the
way up to the top maybe we will
enderpearl to the side try to do it
quickly and wait will that create water
hey guy hey how's it go what's going on
don't know if that's gonna create water
actually it's we need a block below but
just in case let's go oh it is going
look at that holy smokes
oh that's so cool you can actually see
water updating now like I've never
before I would just be like nope
can't see it oh it's all done Wow okay
yeah I do like having the sides open
like this so that you can actually watch
it that is pretty cool okay so next part
of this we have to actually make some
way of funneling them into a water
stream so
oh yeah and since we're doing it down in
the hole here we'll probably later spend
time decorating the sides here with the
prismarine blocks and and maybe putting
some on the aquarium too just so it's
not a giant thing a glass everywhere oh
man so let me show you my idea oh hey oh
hey no run they're getting out there
getting out guys yeah I'm gonna show you
guys now my idea of how we're gonna do
the water streams and stuff why are they
all going to that spot oh hey wait wait
one second one second I just hit one of
these guys with my sword and in this
snapshot something has changed
they take fire damage now they didn't
before so that means you can kill him
with lava probably okay so here's what I
want to try out guys
instead of like doing a whole thing of
signs along the bottom of this that they
fall through or like fence gates at the
very bottom we're gonna try put Reed's
going vertically and I don't know if
that's gonna be any good we will see the
reason for this is like if we were to do
it at a water temple and cover like the
full 64 by 64 it would be so much easier
to do it using Reed's I kinda want to
just test out the idea compared to using
fence gates at the bottom because you
got to harvest all the wood and then you
got to place them and you can't place
them unless you put a block below and
you know how it goes so for a more
survival friendly
approach I want to try this read idea
cuz reads are really easy to get and
they're easy to place might be a bit
tricky to place them with those guys in
the tank we will see I brought some
invisibility potions I don't know if
they help at all
but we will try them got regen
night-vision all that stuff to you okay
so you would have like a back wall here
and then this one this water on this
side we're gonna make it travel eight
blocks this way
and it's gonna bring them towards the
middle and the dirt we're standing on is
where the reeds go so basically they'll
fall down through the reeds land on the
dirt and since they bounce around a lot
they'll bounce into this water and then
they'll get carried to the middle is
what I'm trying to achieve and we will
see what happens with that actually this
is probably fine as it is we can get
going on this so you need water on both
sides for the reeds because they need
water to be planted right reeds hold
water up so this potentially could work
out pretty good
let's get our stuff going do that one
visibility you might have to take the
armor off I'm not sure I've never
actually used it to try dodge mobs
before because I kind of heard it
doesn't work but I'm not sure exactly
let's see can we if we do that that's
fine yeah
would be easier to do it from inside the
tank
but just get going here oh hey where'd
he go
oh no he sees me he sees me maybe we'll
use him as a test if we take this off
hey guy oh oh my goodness it does work
unless you get really close I'm guessing
like if he touches you oh no it does
totally work that's awesome okay that's
gonna make this easy very easy
hopefully I guess we'll enderpearl in
and hope for the best here we're all
cool everything good guys oh but I would
like my helmet on so I could see better
it's actually starting to work already
okay whoa
hey no oh oh drowning drowning yes water
breathing potions I should have brought
I speak like Yoda Yoda I speak like okay
that's gonna be an issue I should have
brought water breathing potions although
if I have the reeds here I can just put
my head and then every so often to you
but yeah the idea is build them up all
the way to the top then when they pass
through them they'll fall through into
our collection area down below so I'm
gonna do that with a few of these rows
or at least one row and just kind of
watch it for a bit
am I gonna be able to get out yeah okay
alright everybody go get your your pen
and your notepad because you gotta take
note this is how you do the reeds
you gotta place a big column of read
somewhere this is pretty efficient
there's a lot of reeds maybe this isn't
quicker than placing signs I'm not sure
it does take it takes a lot of reeds
that's all I gotta say this is little
this is a time just for one of these
and in total I'm gonna do two or three
seems to work pretty decent though I've
been here a while but all of them have
pretty much fallen through all right
guys I got a whole column of reads
placed we're gonna go run there as quick
as we can here to see if we can catch it
in action see if it's any good or not
all right it's just starting they're
just starting to spawn it looks like got
a few through already most of them have
hit the bottom though mm-hmm it did
actually take longer to place the reason
I thought it would - it's a lot of
blocks
although see the thing is some of them
are swimming around up there so if we
just put signs at the bottom here they
would they wouldn't really do anything
for those ones up there it only would
work on the bottom dwellers hmm all
right well I guess I could do both yeah
let's do both so I'm gonna change out
this glass here with signs we're gonna
leave these recons
at the two ends I guess and that should
work pretty effectively
so modifications have been made and it
is turning out pretty cool let's go down
and take a look it seems to work pretty
good have a lot of adjustments to make
to it yet though so it's not even close
to finished or anything but you can see
I got the fence gates all over there and
they fall down through that if they are
swimming around up top usually they will
swim through the reeds and they'll fall
down quickly like you just saw there and
here's here's an issue I'm seeing it
when they get to the edge of the water
stream they they hop like that always
it's like one of the things that they're
programmed to do I guess
so I'll have to deal with that somehow
but I got them all funneling towards the
middle right now and if we go that guy's
falling down very slowly if we go down
these stairs get ready for this the the
Guardian particle accelerator is in the
works oh yeah not exactly sure what I
want to do with this yet but it's a
mechanic that just seems like so much
fun we have to do something so if you
don't know this since these guys hop
around a lot for some reason if they if
they're on slime blocks they just get
crazy air time like they fly how many
blocks is it three four five six seven
eight I cannot even count them from the
bottom 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 15 to 16 ish I would say it's pretty
cool
and though this bounce and bounce that
is not pistons launching them up that's
just them on on the slime blocks and
they do that even if you don't drop them
on the slime block so just bounce their
way up and get higher and higher until
they reach maximum height like this so
that's pretty cool we need to add a
killing thing for this and the portal
thing to bring them to the nether in
case we want to have some fun with that
you can see they're bouncing around the
top there they're having trouble falling
down so I have to do some adjustments
yeah anyway it's a good start to the
thing seems to work pretty decently and
spawn rates are good it's good to see
we're getting lots of ink sacs as well
even though a lot of them fall on the
reads a bunch of them fall down here and
yeah it's pretty cool so lets us take a
look at a comment before we end our
episode for today it says I would like
to see what you will do with the new
banners in 14w 30a oh yeah new banners
guys I am very excited about them I
tried playing around with them I made
one that I liked the look of a lot but I
haven't made one that identifies me
really like if somebody saw it that they
would know it was mine without me
telling them type of thing don't really
have an idea of how to do that besides
maybe doing it an E but like the letter
E that's all about all I can think of
but yeah it should be fun I want to try
get a supercharged creeper - I tested
that today like you can get player heads
or not player heads mob heads when the
supercharged creeper explodes next to a
mob
I tested to see if it works on players
though today and it doesn't and I was
kind of sad about that because that
would be a cool way to get player heads
- but it's just some op eds but you need
those for the banner recipes for certain
patterns anyway should be a lot of fun
play around with and today I learned
also wait a minute
apparently there's a recipe for the
course dirt I thought you had to go get
it I totally missed it that there's a
recipe for it so let me show that real
quick just in case you guys don't know
either it is due to dirt and gravel
makes coarse dirt and grass does not
grow on this stuff slightly different
texture than normal dirt pretty neat I
like it so that's it guys thanks for
watching and I'll see you in the next
one bye bye
[Music]