[Music]
hey what's going on everybody this is
etho and we are back against the guys
with another episode of the next plays
series hopefully you're having
yourselves a wonderful day today and
everything is good um last episode we
worked on that raid farm if you remember
and pretty much got it all built might
do a couple finishing touches on it
today but overall I think that it's like
good to go
and I looked into how to build the
second part of the firm like where we
actually start doing and molds and it's
looking like we're gonna need some
villagers I hate to say it if you if you
don't remember a while ago there was a
big raid on our main village like when I
was when I scooping around with the raid
feature and we lost most of our
villagers and for whatever reason I
haven't been able to get the village to
repopulate they won't make it a baby
anymore
despite my best efforts eat the food eat
it right now yeah so if that village
would start making babies we would be
able to like take the extra disposable
villagers and move them through the
nether so wherever you want right but
it's not making them for some reason so
I have another plan I just unlocked a
trade with this guy for bells like you
can only get these from trading with
villagers or you can steal them from
existing villages so I haven't really
had any bells now we got a couple extras
here I think what happened here we have
like five to seven villagers left in
this village they're not making babies
though we do have a few beds around
right I think what happened is the raid
guilds most the villagers in this part
of the village and it's like these guys
aren't finding that hey you know what
this house over here and has beds in it
and that house has beds and that house
has beds they're not wandering over to
this part of the village anymore they're
all staying up at the top of the stairs
there so they they don't think that the
village
get any bigger they don't see all these
other beds around here so we got to make
them come over here so that they'll
start going in these other houses so I
got a bell
and I've been like trying to place
workstations around the place as well I
think if we ring that or no that makes
them go inside right
I think they'll they'll come here though
to gather during the day right well he
went over here that's that's good
anyways if we can get them to this part
of the village I think they'll start
making babies again and it looks like it
kind of worked like I Ieft aid in this
village four days
you know after feeding them and oh don't
you mad at each other I fed them I
traded with them they just wouldn't make
the babies they wouldn't explore put the
Bell down right away it worked
uh-huh so that's great that seems to be
working again but still gonna take a
little bit of time for the village to
repopulate so I think we're gonna work
on the underwater base today that's kind
of what I'm in the mood for you guys are
probably like what etho has a underwater
base since when
uh-huh yeah it's true we haven't done a
lot on it to be honest this is it just
this you built an underwater tree farm
that works and we did like a mob system
here that's not finished but uh yeah so
I finally figured out what I want to do
with this base though I came up with a
pretty good idea I think so we got the
plan now we just got to get the building
I'm not gonna go into detail of the plan
just yet cuz it might be a hurt a bit
hard to explain without setting it up
first a bit better but I have a
direction to go now so I think we're
gonna work on this mob system first stop
it's not really functional at the moment
first question I have is what glass
should we use for it's like what's the
most transparent glass for underwater
stuff
this is blue glass this is clear glass
light gray gray and whites
I'm thinking we might want to go or the
clear actually like now that we don't
have all the streaks through clear glass
in the new texture pack it actually
doesn't look too bad
right we do have the lines though whoa
yep yep so I think that's what we're
gonna do here we're gonna have clear
glass with the I think light gray clay
bordering it and then red clay kind of
sticking out just to give it a bit of 3d
depth you know so it comes out of block
I did try over here as well just to keep
it flat which is fine as well but it's a
little bit more plain right so that's
how this is gonna go what the plan is
it's pretty simple we're gonna make them
go up about 20 blocks or so and then
drop them they'll probably be some kind
of mob separator at the top of this
eventually but for right now we're just
gonna drop them to either a one-hit kill
or to kill them for their mob drops
okay good stuff so we're just about done
building our tube here we can start
killing these move these mobs what we're
gonna do is get rid of the water in here
a little bit's alright and we're gonna
get rid of water over here mobs are down
there right they'll swim up through the
bubble stream get to the top here then
this water currents gonna take them over
to here let's extend this doesn't one
update over here that work yeah okay so
it makes it all the way to the edge here
and then we go down uh-huh so they're
gonna go up the bubble stream here to
the top if there's no mob separator
active they'll just go down over to here
and fall down and either die or not die
if we want to kill them ourselves for XP
but I think it's about ready here to
test out so let's let's do the nasty
thing here and let them up there we go
we replace the water because it's
missing there put it back over there
another bucket back here them dying
right now okay so I think that'll work I
mean yeah they're going up to the top
it's airspace here so they fall down now
what I'm trying to do is find the sweet
spot where you hear they're dying right
now where they won't die unless we smack
them once okay so we got it figured out
here the sweet spot is right where that
red clay is so on the back we're gonna
have some sticky pistons that will
extend and push the blocks if we want
the mobs to land at this level and not
die we want to firm them for XP
otherwise it'll stay open like this and
we'll just fall down and die and the
drops will go into a hopper somewhere so
at this level that means we'll probably
want to build a room over here with a
floor where the glasses and we're
also gonna need to be able to swing in
there and kill them so we'll probably
just just try this for now
maybe we'll just try to keep it open
like this and see how that works
cuz XP needs to be able to flow out of
there too
now one of the big things we're gonna
have to deal with when building
underwater is how are we gonna do
redstone like we got to power these
Pistons somehow and we don't want to put
a giant casing around some redstone
that'll look pretty nasty so I don't
know if this is a well-known trick but
this is a trick we're gonna be using
extensively throughout our base I
realized what we can do is just put some
observers under these Pistons like so
detector side over here and these
actually get updated by bubble streams
if you don't know that
so if we have soul sand down here this
will have to be filled with water though
of course and when the bubbles reach the
observers up there it actually activates
the Pistons so now you see it's extended
and like if we want to switch it we
either move the soul sand or cover it or
something and then look trigger again so
it's like vertical redstone through
water which is amazing so we're gonna be
using that trick a lot I thought that
was pretty cool I guess let's trigger it
one more time probably picking Pistons
up to the soul sand here is gonna be the
best method so if we put a block at the
top it destroys the water source those
are extended yen so let's see how this
thing performs these guys the zombies
won't be a one-hit kill because they
have a little bit of armor but all the
other mobs will these guys will be like
two hits probably it doesn't really
matter too much show cuz we're gonna be
using a sword to kill these guys anyway
so if they're not exactly a one punch
kill no biggie
yeah anyways let's give this a try so we
want the XP to flow out of here we don't
really want the items to land on the
calamus there's any way to stomp that
like you see other zombie flesh is on
the glass there that's not really ideal
because we're gonna we're gonna trigger
the red clay there to move back and then
the drops will fall down every so often
we're using this oh yeah looks like the
XP flows out no problem which is great
the other thing we got to worry about is
we need to be able to activate the
redstone with this like if we want to
control this thing the problem is like
if you're doing redstone under water
again that legging just plays a button
you know right so we need some sort of
button like device that works underwater
and I think trapdoors are a good option
for that or I think we might just use
note blocks a lot too peoples are like
two of the best choices you could use
fence gates and some other stuff as well
I like the way we could control this is
have note blocks if you right-click them
they don't play a sound because there's
a water block above and they need to
have a air block above to work but they
will still trigger an observer so
basically we run this down and then we
make it activate a piston to move the
soul sand here yeah so check this out
this is actually gonna be pretty simple
to do we'll have the note blocks over
here easy to click at this level right
observers going down we can easily put
some blocks in front of these if we want
to hide them and this guy there's some
blocks down here and he's messing with
them
let me get those for you guy yeah all
right so server comes down I put some
sticky pistons over here and the sole
stands right next to it so basically all
we got to do put some sand stone there
make sure this is air I did not grab any
redstone some reason let's grab some
redstone 2 pieces in here that'll power
the Pistons and then this will come down
I think we just need to put a block over
there that'll send power to the redstone
dust now and I think it's about good to
go here fill that back in so let's give
it a try so if we just right click yeah
look at that amazing a little bit of
delay to it because the bubble stream
doesn't activate instantly but it's it's
pretty good good stuff alright so now
that we got this built we have a source
of XP at our base here it means we can
repair our tools without having to leave
the area and be super useful also we got
a bit more to do on this we want to add
a collection system for all these drops
and that that'll sort them as well and I
also want to add a way of turning the
farm on and off I think by putting
lights down at the spawning levels and
will control that here too probably
but for a bit of variety let's actually
try to build something at this base
besides this I'm thinking now that we
have a source of XP here we're gonna
want to spend it right so let's maybe
put an enchanting room next to this I
think would be a good idea and I was
looking into it it's actually kind of
complicated it's not as easy as I
thought
like enchanting tables require air
spaces actually the work and more than I
thought like if you put it in Genting
table like this
only goes up to level five all right
these don't actually get registered even
though they're in the right position I
check it against the level five right
you know maybe let's go up to the
surface
does this go up I guess it does okay
great let's go let's go onto my hand
here it'd be a little easier to
demonstrate this yeah so check this out
if we put down a bookshelf like we had
before there now it goes up to level
seven right there's a couple blocks that
still don't get waterlogged like
pressure plates right so they're kind of
like air blocks but they're they don't
count for enchanting it has to be a pure
air block not just like a mostly air
block right so if we put that in front
there you see it goes down to five so
this actually cancels out the bookshelf
so we can't do any tricks like that and
also it's two vertical air blocks we
need I thought it was only like it next
to the bookshelf like we need these two
blocks to be air box if we put like this
there you see it still goes down to five
if that's gone it'll be at seven so how
do we get air blocks underwater it has
to be pure air blocks that's that's
gonna be the challenge here so now it
would probably be a good time to talk
about our base design strategy as well
like how we're gonna grow and expand our
base I think we're gonna do kind of like
we did with the man cave where we build
farms and redstone contraptions and then
later link all of them together and try
to make a nice looking base and we're
gonna make things pretty organic as well
like for example our enchanting room
here I'm not gonna put it in line with
our mob farm like it's not gonna be
straight across from this it's gonna be
offset a little bit even though we want
this close to this we don't we don't
want it perfectly symmetrical right so
that's gonna be a big part of our base
design strategy as well so what we're
gonna do with this enchanting room I
think is kind of similar idea or similar
trick we used for that underwater
tree farm and if you don't remember what
we did with that good good it's gonna be
a surprise for you
basically we're gonna use pistons to
remove the water temporarily because it
takes a split second for the water to
return after you retract the piston and
we're gonna use that to upgrade the
enchanting table for a brief moment
let's see here so I think that's all the
pistons we need right wait we gotta move
do we have to move these ones no because
this will come forward yeah that's right
that's that's fine I think we got it
right now right yeah okay mumbling to
myself anyways let's get back to this so
what we're gonna do to power these
Pistons
I think observers are gonna be our best
friend for this this whole build I think
we can power this just by yea like this
right so we update this yeah that
triggered both Pistons good yeah okay
and it's kind of like a t flip-flop so
then for the rest of these same deal
just vertically like this and put blocks
above one more over here cool so now
we've got to run like some redstone or
something under here to update all five
of these in in unison right oh yeah and
there's something I thought I'd point
out here so we did a trick earlier for
like vertical redstone through water
yeah using the bubble streams but
there's also like a horizontal trick as
well using leaves now a lot of you guys
have wanted me to use this we probably
actually will use this trick in the
space a fair bit not in this case though
I kind of want to explain why so if you
don't know if you place like a log next
to leaf box it actually causes them to
update because then the leaf blocks need
to know how far they are away from wood
to figure out if they should decay or
not
so you can use observers to detect that
and trigger stuff from a distance right
and the nice thing is these are these
work underwater right if this was
redstone we'd have to surround it with
blocks to keep it from washing away
while this just takes up a single block
so that's really nice actually a couple
things about this though like we can
chain them together over long distances
if we do little breaks like this oh I
thought I guess if there's two at the
same spot it doesn't trigger it right if
I'd never actually use this oh yeah now
it triggered that piston there at that
time okay so you will notice I set these
up so we can see there is a bit of a
delayed this so if we place the snare
see that piston activates first and that
one then that one one tick apart from
each other so in the case here where
we're doing the enchanting table this is
not a good way of doing redstone because
that delay is gonna mess up the system
we need all the bookshelves to move at
the exact same time and like the further
the redstone travels the longer the
delay is gonna be so that doesn't really
work in this case so we're gonna use
actual redstone here so this gate seems
to work pretty good actually what we do
we flip this trapdoor up we flip it down
so it squishes us down right and then if
we close this one I think water can't
get in and we're free to do our redstone
and then we just have to exit really
quickly so it doesn't wash away that
work we lost one there but we don't
actually need redstone in that spot yeah
because it goes under this observer
there aha so again I think we'll just
use a note block to trigger this so when
we right-click this we want the
bookshelves to move I think an easy way
of connecting to that redstone is just
to do this
Oh misplaced the problem is I think we
might need to have a little bit of a
delay to this otherwise it's gonna be
it's gonna activate too quickly all
right and it's in Reverse oh why those
come out of the sink okay so these two
bookshelves here kept going outta sync
with each other so I had to extend the
redstone one more block it goes
underneath this piston now and that
seems to update it properly so check
this out I did they all go together they
all come back this is water over here
again all right that's not air we go to
enchant something it only goes up to
level five because it's surrounded by
water but if we retract this and put the
book in at just the right time
you see it's level five still messed it
up there we go we got level thirty so it
matters when the book goes in the book
has to go in once once those air spaces
are there so there's like a fraction of
a window to get it right now actually
not as hard as to do as I thought though
got it again I think it'll be a little
bit easier if I set this up so that it's
like we have to click this twice I only
want to click it once so I think we got
to put some repeaters in this as well a
whole snappers I think we got it now I
just put a repeater at the end here set
it to four I found out I didn't use
daylight sensors as a block that doesn't
get waterlogged so I'm free to like
adjust the repeater here it's kind of a
building a ship in a bottle you know
like you have to control the Redstone
and then seal it up afterwards without
it getting washed away do that yes okay
we saved it amazing all right so check
this out
we click it goes out and then back so
it's only one click now instead of two
and it's a lot easier to time this
because we have
we have more time to do it we got 30
there try it again
30 again that time we got 16 so if you
do it at the wrong time sometimes it's
like harshly flooded and you can get
like a lower enchantment so we actually
have three ranges have been chanting
here with this too so we can go for a
level five a level 16 or 30 depending on
when we put the book in 30 with practice
it will get easier to use I hope it's
not too bad though it's not too bad all
right so now we want to decorate this
little bit and I think we're good to go
here now the question comes up what are
we gonna actually build out of well I
did this if we look over here though the
building styles a little bit difference
I think we're gonna change it up quite a
bit in different parts of the base like
over here we have no terracotta we use
strip logs few different types we use
the dark prison marine regular
prismarine lots of it and then we just
spam it with coral and sea grass and
kelp and stuff afterwards and it looks
pretty good right it's not bad color and
stuff I think on the inside of our base
though we're gonna use a lot of
terracotta for our walls mainly and
different colors too like over there we
got red here we got grey probably use
oranges and maybe even blues and stuff I
don't know it's gonna change a lot so it
it'll feel different in different areas
you know as far as the ground goes I
really like using birch planks for the
floor like it really stands out it's
nice and bright and we got a mix in some
prism reen and bogs and stuff throughout
as well and that's kind of the general
block pellet we're going with sea
lanterns a lot for lighting and we gotta
get some dark prizren in here let's see
here
a few stairs get a few slabs and I guess
we can probably put it underneath this
somewhere yeah let's put it over here
and over there let's let's break this
maybe how's that look cool cool alright
I kind of want this to stick out more
maybe it's looking a little plain maybe
we'll just do one of these I think on
the floor we will mix in some oak planks
as well just to break it up a bit so
it's not like one solid color no I don't
have any candy go away
let's go down one more with that I
wanted to get an enderchest in here as
well maybe we'll put that over here and
up in front where we can use it pretty
easily still oh yeah and we got to be
able to open it too ha ha there's always
a problem let's see let's go back here I
love having all my blocks in the ender
chest makes building so much easier well
maybe let's put a stair in the back here
break this out stare nice so now we can
open that no problem and don't think you
can water log anvils right no you can't
okay so that's gonna stay like that
alright so well I added a few more
little details listening I'm pretty
happy with it now right
he looks okay I guess I'll find out in
the Carn so you guys are gonna be like
Oh F oh that's that's horrible what were
you thinking uh-huh you guys are my
clarity you know you help me you help
keep me in check whenever I do something
crazy I don't think is that bad though
right I think it's okay so there's our
first little module to our underwater
base and as we build more modules we'll
connect them together with hallways and
stuff this is supposed to be that
inside of our base like it will be
covered and you're not gonna see the
full height of the mob system either
it'll probably be several floors break
it up so it's not one big giant thing
that's gonna be like the center of our
base I think anyways I'm adding one more
little contraption here to our
enchanting station we're gonna put books
in one of these droppers and then lapis
another three because one of the main
things I enchant is books so get a
bubble stream to bring them up to us and
now whenever we right-click it's gonna
give us three lapis in one book go to
enchant throw our lapis in oh it did
change oh yes I should have tested that
really maybe maybe when I throw the
lapis in it causes it update again so if
I okay so I have to put both in and like
the lapis will be the last thing I put
in it will let us enchant though right
this is level 30 yeah we did do a level
30 enchantment okay so it's a little bit
more finicky than I thought uh-huh
anyways that's the plan here oh yeah
that's good oh dear
it's a challenge guys okay okay or try
to do things a little different at this
base not exactly optimized a fun little
challenge here there we go I got it
piece of cake this might get annoying
after a while if I can't I can't figure
out the timing it's so much harder doing
- I might need I probably need to add a
little bit more delay to it that'll make
it easier
uh-huh anyways I think we're gonna get
out of here though you know there's
something we really need guys I haven't
been here in a long time the wither farm
we need to get more beacons in our world
so I might spend a bit of time farming
wither skeletons but we're gonna wrap up
for today's episode with the comment of
the day like we usually do so this one
says hey etho I was wondering if you had
any plans to plant you world
now that it's come out I remember your
old series on it and I and was hoping
you would try it again now that it's
actually releasing longtime fan here
keep up the great work
Julian check you guys then see cube
world is now available on Steam I'd
leave with a little bit of an update I
believe it's a good game you know I
enjoyed playing that I just think about
it I should I actually play it and I
stopped back to like when I did you
world before I was like I couldn't have
done more than 5 episodes I can't
remember though I was like when I was
doing that as like man I really suck at
commentary because in that game all you
do is like grind killing monsters right
pretty much you gotta you gotta fill the
space with like talking is like what do
I talk about because usually when I
played games I talk about what I'm doing
or game mechanics and you can't do that
in cube world you have to actually be
entertaining it was like oh this is
tough time I will talk about random
things like my hatred for onions and
stuff but it's hard to fill a full
episode with that so I don't think I
might be doing aq world playthrough
uh-huh a lot of people ask me about it
though so I thought I'd mention it but
anyways that's gonna do it for today's
episode guys I hope you enjoyed it you
have any comments or things to say feel
free to leave them below until next time
thanks for watching take care bye bye