[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys how's it going
what's going on what's new how's the
family things things good with you
this is a really jerk thing but whenever
someone asks me like how's your life
i always say better than yours
no i don't always say that i i rarely
say that i want to say it all the time
but it's such a jerk thing to say
it's kind of a bad joke uh but yeah guys
we are
we are here at the flower forest
base thingamajig
whatever it is oh is this going to work
it's been a while
oh i did it look at this okay i don't
actually want to go up there though i
want to go down here
woohoo yeah so we're here guys the
reason
we are here i really want to make a
flower farm today here
flower forest is like the only place you
can get most of the flowers
and i want the flowers i want
i want the tulips i want the azra bluets
and uh and the onix daisies
i don't know what i'm saying what are
they called again onyx daisies
oxi oxide that's right i forget
uh so the thing about it though i'm
having a hard time finding the location
to build it
uh because the way it works in these
flower forests
and i was just doing a little bit of
testing it's
the flowers they always generate in the
same spot
and it's hard to find a place where you
get where you get all the different
types of flowers in a very small space
um and where where you see the flowers
right now
is not where they generate it's like
random
this the flowers that's that
explain yourself etho what are you
saying uh the flowers that you see in a
flower forest are not
what spawns there when you grow them uh
usually i think so
i guess we just try somewhere how about
we we go over here
i could be wrong on that actually
so these are the red ones see if we get
red ones
i think this just grew here this purple
one yeah so this is not like where you
find these
if you grow them here and if we break
these
we will always get those in that spot
and that block
see we just got another one there so we
got to find
where to build this thing and apparently
you can
even get dandelions here i didn't
realize that i found a spot that grew
dandelions
over here somewhere yeah look at this so
they don't spawn in the biome anywhere
but there are spots where you can grow
them so
it should be fun i'm going to look
around a bit try growing a few different
areas and see if i can find
a good spot to build the farm okay i
don't know if this is the spot but we're
going to try it
top of the mountain here i cleared out
all the flowers that were here before
pretty much so that we can get a good
idea
of what's gonna grow here without them
you know like
affecting or confusing us like what
grows where
um and i figured it would be best to do
like a long narrow form
instead of a like a square one so that
we can
cover as much area as possible
okay we got poppies here poppies
and i'm gonna try
i'm gonna pick the spot that seems to
give us
um all the different types in as little
area as possible we might have to build
a pretty big farm
but we will see okay so i found a pretty
nice spot
right here this looks like where we're
gonna build it
i drew lots of flowers so we could
clearly see
uh where they where they grow which what
shape they make
uh in their growth pattern and like from
here to these poppies
is good this is great because we have
every single type except for dandelions
in that we have poppies we have these
helium or whatever the as are blue it's
we have the red tulips orange tulips
white tulips the pink tulips
and then we have the oxide daisies
and that's about it right just
dandelions we're missing dandelions
but i haven't found another spot for
them this is the only one on this
mountain top that i found a spot so
not going to worry about them so my plan
is to flatten out the top of this a bit
and then
start setting up some pistons or
dispensers or some
some stuff like that and here it is
everybody so i just finished building
the flower farm tested it out for a bit
and it seems to be pretty good actually
uh we'll try it again here in just a
second so it
is fully automatic it will grow
the flowers then it will harvest them
and then it will collect them and store
them in chests so
all i gotta do is flip a lever and it
does its thing pretty much
i just emptied these all there's nothing
in them
so let's see what we get with however
long we run it here
um redstone it's always like a
parkour experience trying to get
out of it and in it and yeah anyway
so here's the lever
and i'll explain it as it runs for a bit
pretty cool so all it is is you got the
grass
pistons push the grass to the left and
then those ones push them to the right
and
every time the blocks shift it forces
whatever's planted on them to pop off
and then we got all these mine carts
running underneath these hopper mine
carts
they have they can pick up
whatever's above through the blocks and
then they drop them off
at these hoppers i'm curious to see if
they'll be able to keep up i'm not sure
this one's been here for a long time
why is it taking so long to unload
and why only this one oh you know what
maybe yeah look at this it looks like
the flowers are all kind of going
to the left side a bit i wonder if
there's a preference to that
like which way they hop the right side
doesn't have many
left side has a ton
there might be some tweaking and stuff
we need to do this with this
all right did this finish yet not yet
or did it just pick up more i'm not sure
all right anyway we got all these
dispensers on the left and right side of
the thing
these are filled with bone meal and
there is one two three per side four
five six
total
uh and the chests are filling up with
the drops as
the hopper minecarts drop them off seems
like they can keep up pretty good
i actually built another
collection area over on this side so
that
we could uh have two hopper mine carts
going back and forth and they would
bounce off each other
like if it couldn't keep up that's why i
put these ones in here
but it seems like it's it's good with
just one minecart so i might be able to
remove these
and yeah it seems like it's okay
let's let's shut it off for a moment and
make sure it's picking up everything
because i'm not sure if it actually
is
all right
all right yeah you can see some stuff
disappearing
looks like the minecart at this row is
dropping stuff off at the moment it
should come by to pick
them up or you know it might be getting
backed up
like as i run it longer here oh there it
goes
this one for sure is taking the longest
though
this row for some reason that's kind of
weird
um where is that mine cart
okay it's over here oh it just picked up
a lot of stuff
um see
the thing is there's more than five
different types of flowers so
on a single pass i don't think the
minecart can get them all
all right let's see if it'll pick up the
rest of these because i'm not sure
hopper minecarts can have trouble
picking them up if they're like right
along the edge like this
which i think might be what is happening
yeah then grab them
should be on this end
i think it's bouncing back and forth
like he can't grab anything else yeah
okay so all this stuff on this edge is
not getting picked up for some reason
i'm guessing it's it's like the north
south or west south or east south or
whatever
i forget what the the rule was uh but
the negative
towards the negative
right yeah this is negative so that that
direction has a problem compared to
towards the positive
okay so just a couple more things about
this farm and then we'll go do something
else
uh turns out the dispenser
underneath here was not working at all
so got that fixed
and also i never really explained what
this is this is a monostable circuit if
you couldn't tell
that makes it so it just sends a quick
short pulse uh to the whole thing that
way the pistons don't stay
extended for very long they just push it
and then go back
and then this is the timer right here
and let's take a look
at those mine carts are really annoying
me
i should maybe make a shutoff for those
as well
uh this is the thing i'm using to
make the minecarts unload so when they
arrive here
uh when stuff is passing through the
item hopper the comparator turns on
goes to redstone torch then up to this
block
to the left and then
when this block is powered the power
rail's on the minecart has something in
it
uh this turns on this turns off this
turns off and the power rail turns off
as well so the minecart stops at this
spot to unload um
yeah so that's about it uh oh yeah and
this is what we got for running it this
is like
two minutes of running the sad thing
about
this farm is it's like too good it's too
good it's kind of fun to watch it do it
do its thing here but we have enough
flowers already that will probably last
forever there's a definitely a
preference towards the pink tulips
although one of the dispensers wasn't
working so
yeah like in this area here it looks
like there's red and orange tulips there
and maybe some white ones that we
weren't getting
um but yeah pretty cool
the reason i i built this by the way i
was like walking around
the surface of like above the man tape
and
i got to thinking you know just if i put
some flowers around here some bushes
it would start to look a lot nicer and
it's like i don't have any flowers so
that's why i built the farm here so
maybe
we'll start adding details to the
surface of our world
a little later try to make things look
nicer
oh yeah and uh i let this thing run and
it ran out of bone meal and all the ones
that were
on that left side they they kept
bouncing off and then eventually they
all got picked up
too so it wasn't a problem
what what what what what stop
who
no no
well he just died how did he get his
head
no no you don't run out no you don't
nope you can twirl all day i'm letting
you out
i just can't stop by here to try find
some snow and
i guess they're dying in blocks
all right come on i gotta put this i
gotta put this here
get your ugly nose out of the hole
all right everybody so today we are
going to be doing something
starting something that i've wanted to
do for a very very long time
in minecraft and i just i just never did
it
i tried to do it i just never really
got dedicated into it i guess um
for the longest time i've wanted to make
super horses in this game and i
like see if i can breed two crummy
horses and get them to the point where
they're really really good uh
this is something i sort of tried to do
on the minecraft server originally
but the idea just never really worked
out because i couldn't test things
accurately because of little bits of
latency and and whatnot
but in my single player world here it
should be pretty easy
two three four five six seven eight
um two three four five six
seven eight so basically if you guys
remember i'm setting up the jump wall
that i had on minecraft server
where we can test the different heights
that the horses jump
and my strategy my plan to this whole
thing
is to
breed two separate lines of horses
basically i'm going to breed
one line for speed and then one line for
jumping
we're going to start with the jumping
just because i think it's going to be
easier to
figure out it's a lot easier to visually
see
what what their jumping height is and
you don't need to build anything too
fancy or
or question whether it's accurate or
anything like that so we'll start with
this
the jumping and then
we'll breed them for speed and then once
we got a super
fast horse or a bunch of super fast
horses and a bunch of super high jumping
horses
we will then try to combine them to get
a super fast high jumping horse
yeah i think i'm doing this right these
snow slabs these are really important
i'm using them because they allow us to
go by eighths of the block which is
about the highest accuracy you can get
in minecraft
for vertical height so it says 68.0
every slab adds a one or a 0.125 to the
block height
with this set up so we should be able to
figure this out very accurately
and so the reason i'm not like doing the
two
stats at the same time on the horses
it's because it's very unlikely
especially when you get to the higher
extremes with the horse
speed or jumping that you're going to
get both stats to be
better on the baby horse
so oops
so we're gonna just try one stat at a
time
if that goes well then we will try for
the very rare chance of getting
two stats to be better together which
is very rare but we will we will see
what happens with that
oh we're out anyway i'm going to finish
this up i got a bunch of horses i've
been breeding over the past few episodes
we will
bring them here and start testing them
out and uh
and labeling them i guess sounds wrong i
think we'll keep them at the village
here too
maybe we'll make a little some stalls
for them
over along this fence or something but
actually the the reason i built the gold
farm originally was for this
project i wanted the gold farm for
golden carrots so that i could
breed them easily and just
up until this point i still haven't done
it so
i'm very excited to finally do this
project and we'll see what happens with
it
aha so let me show you guys how this is
going to go
because organization is going to be so
important to this
if we don't keep track of the horses and
and their
their jumping heights and all that we
will never figure it out so i
all along the back wall of this village
i set up
like 40 stalls or something crazy
which we will store the horses in
according to their jump height so i got
it written on the back here what their
jumping height is
i moved all the horses over here from
the man tave all the ones that
we bred with zenith and my super horse
um so these are like the best horses i
can get and we're gonna start off with
them
um so basically we just gotta go up to
our wall here
start categorizing them and drop them
off in their
stalls i got labels on the wall here
let's see what this guy can do
this guy is not going to last long
unfortunately pretty much every horse
that we breed in this project is going
to get killed eventually
um if they're good jumpers it will just
take longer before they get killed
or before they get the axe
all right sees i think he's below
average
if i remember right three was the
average for horses
okay he's getting there he's almost a
three
oh oh he's very close to three can you
do three
oh he's just short so he's just slightly
below average
i believe so he's a two point
eight something something another
so let's go write them off to a stall
and i'm going to be doing that with all
these guys and then we're going to take
our two best ones and
and work off of them so let's see
two just under three right
yeah so he would go in this stall here
can he make it over the fence even
just barely all right
cool so let me diagnose the rest of our
horses here i think there's about 10 or
so
maybe a little less
so here we go this is what we ended up
with and all these horses they had the
same parents
but there's variations within them with
their jumping heights by quite a bit
so the best guy over here is 3.375
and then we have three here at 2.75 so
there's a bit of variation there
so what we're going to do we're going to
take this guy here
this one here um if you take their
numbers
3.125 plus 3.375
best case scenario it's gonna randomly
roll
a 5.5 for the new horse so over here
so add 5.5 add those three numbers
together you get 12
and divide that by three and best case
our
our baby horse is gonna get a four
worst case scenario it will be
let me check this 2.56 so
probably somewhere around here
um so let's do it and we'll see what
happens
see i guess i'll just jump them together
i don't know
all right oh yeah i can figure out which
one's the baby because it won't have a
saddle on two which is important
otherwise i'll mix them up really easily
for some reason in this snapshot i'm
using oops
the baby horses are like full grown here
i don't know why i still haven't updated
to the latest one so i don't know if
that's fixed or not yet
i can't get on this guy oh this is
terrible
i guess because it's baby right let's
feed him
how about now well that is weird it's
doing something
very strange with the camera
oh man what is going on
it like makes the camera jump every time
i click them
alright let's grow him up a little bit
more i don't think he's fully grown
no still can't get on
still can't get on i don't know what's
going on here
there we go okay so now it's fully grown
we gotta tame them right oh we tame the
first time
probably because i gave them extra sugar
get the saddle on
get them out of there and we'll go test
them out so again best case
we'll get a 4.0 out of him
but it's most likely going to be more
average than that
okay it's not terrible it's not terrible
3.25 there that's pretty good
let's try here oh i think that might be
it
try one more time yeah so it's a
3.25 which
uh let's go back there i can't remember
i think that's better than
what it could have been better than like
the average between the two yeah i guess
it's right right between them right all
right so
next time we will breed this one with
this one and
eventually we will slowly work our way
up here and that's why this is a
long-term project because
i can't just like breed this guy with
this one right now we gotta wait 10
minutes or so and yeah
so it might take a while to finally get
to the end here
but it should be fun we'll do little
updates of it as i go
hmm well aren't you an interesting one
this what you like to do on your spare
time
some kind of game maybe
all right then nice touching with you
all right everybody so i couldn't just
end it there like this is a project i've
been wanting to do for a long time and
uh i just kind of been semi-afk
here i've been playing on the minecraft
server while
recording or not recording breeding the
horses in my single player
dual minecraft efficiency i tell ya
that is the key um so
been getting lots of horses it was going
really quickly at first like we got to
i think around here the 3.625 horses
hey creeper and
then i kind of hit a brick wall like
they just they didn't really want to get
better
very very slowly i got them to the 3.75
and then i read them like six or seven
maybe eight times
and finally got a three point eight two
five but we haven't hit the four block
thing yet but it is going okay
oh i may have lost
a few horses to creepers already
uh but yeah this is our best jumper
right now
pretty good and like i was surprised i
thought they were gonna get really slow
and and crummy horses but so far the
speed on them has been really good
so i'm happy about that but anyway here
is the comment i picked out for today
a really useful one possibly we're going
to try it out it says
if i had to have it yes i'd say that one
of your villagers with the funky trades
is what is corrupting your chunk
it's been the source of a problem for me
and vex posted a video showing a similar
problem
i'd recommend backing up your save and
killing the villagers in that chunk
one by one to troubleshoot which
villager is ruining
your day and i saw a couple other
comments saying this as well so we're
gonna actually go and try that because
last episode we had an issue with the
corrupted chunk and it was killing our
blacksmiths
and i couldn't change the chunk with its
um without the changes being saved
so we're gonna i'm gonna make a backup
we'll head over there and we'll start
killing some villagers
so the villager in question is this guy
here
this is the trade i thought was supposed
to be the fish trade or that used to be
it
and i had some people confirm it as well
and for some reason
it has turned blank so apparently
this guy needs to go
the ultimate sacrifice he must die
so that the blacksmith can live
or something like that i don't know
let's kill him
all right i'm gonna reload the world and
we'll see if he comes
back
all right well
it's not him is it you
i'm going to reload again we'll see what
happens i'm going to place some blocks
too just
just so that we have some other
reference besides villagers
okay okay this is good news
the chunk works again i guess it was
this guy i killed the wrong one
ah i'm gonna load the back up we'll
try this again all right so i was not
expecting this guy to be the problem
because his trades look pretty normal
don't they
oh if i kill him i lose a steak tray too
i really like this one
but you must be sacrificed
for the greater good
this is some messed up stuff i tell you
he came back he came back maybe i gotta
kill both of them then
just gonna place these again i'm gonna
kill him try reload one more time
nope okay well i guess we gotta kill
both of them then
it's the only way
yep that fixed it so i guess they both
had a problem with them that was
corrupting the chunk
and now that they're both gone we have
no problems
so that's good right
kind of sucks we just killed like two of
the oldest villagers
we've had in our world but
i don't know i think the trading didn't
quite work
properly with him anyway so
i guess we'll get new villagers i'm
wondering maybe we should redo this even
i know it's an old old part of the world
but
what do you guys think should i try
update this like
currently in the new trading system
there's 11 different types of villagers
so maybe we could like add more spots i
don't know
let me know what you think and we might
go through with that
or i'll just if not i'll just go get
some other villagers
and fill these spots with them
but yeah that's gonna do it thank you
for the comments
and comments guys uh much appreciated
if you missed it i have my internet back
if you if you didn't watch my terra
firma craft episode
so all is good in that department i'm
able to record and upload normally
for now anyway uh until the next problem
so yep thanks for watching guys i'll see
you in the next one
bye bye