[Music]
hey hey how's it going everybody this is
etho welcome back guys to to another one
of our episodes yes oh man I got some
bad news guys today's episode is not
gonna be let's cheer some sheep while we
talk it's not gonna be up to our usual
standards I don't think yeah we're
having some problems today guys today is
episode number 404 and as many of you
suspected we are getting the 404 error
in our episode today so I logged in all
our chests appear to be empty and as you
can imagine it's gonna be a little bit
difficult to get things done today so
today it might be a bit short it might
be a bit weird and crazy and all that
kind of stuff but we'll see what happens
here
so we got to sort of collect a few
things all our signs are like messed up
today there's lots of things missing I
don't like it just gonna work I'm like
I've been going around my world just
trying to figure out what works and what
doesn't what's gone what's there alright
that seemed to work ok that's good
manual resets all right all our animals
are still here that's good I did notice
our ender chest is empty and wheels
they're good yeah pretty much our
storage room cleared out today oh look
at the signs man what is going on man
I'll try to do the best I can today guys
but no promises on a on a proper episode
is the coal gun in the furnaces it is
okay these are all empty I'll lay I'll
lay it out for you straight guys so
usually I'll log into my world here log
in to work and first thing I do those
buttons Oh what first thing I do I got a
little secret room here I've never shown
you guys this is like the staff room
like I come in here to hang out for a
little bit we got a TV some speakers and
I just kind of go over the script for
the episode of the day and well
unfortunately I saw this today so I got
no plans for today's episode I didn't
rehearse anything it's just gone we
might need this for later I thankfully I
have a pretty good memory though so I
looked at the comments on the last
episode one of the things that was
suggested is we add a daylight sensor to
the castle gate so we'll go do that we
can do that for sure I do have some
redstone on me okay okay we have a
slight problem here guys I should have
suspected this but it's fine we're gonna
make the best of this so usually in Etha
plays minecraft it's up to the writers
to come up with the designs of our
builds like the castle gates here and
then they usually give me a redstone
guide on how to how to do the redstone
but our redstone guide for today is an
error 404 but don't you worry I am a
great actor it a great actor knows how
to improvise when the writers don't do
so good so I'm going to do my own
redstone and we're gonna hook up a
daylight sensor to our castle gates look
how look how easy I can make this look
there so now during the day the castle
gates
open and only closed at nighttime and if
it closes at nighttime then I just push
a button to open it up yeah works
perfect okay maybe it's supposed to be
is this supposed to be switched can't
switch it well what should we do I've
been wondering wondering oh this is
tough I don't know how the writers do it
without that script I got no clue how to
entertain you guys it's not as easy as
you might think I do have one idea one
idea today's episode has been as fun as
a bag of onions so far huh
that's an ether joke not a writer's joke
yeah I've been hinting I've wanted to
look behind the doors here for quite a
while and every time I try the writers
they stop me because they think it's
funny or something I don't understand it
myself but today we don't have a strip
so I don't think they can actually stop
us today and actually if we're lucky
that door the sea lantern door might not
even be there might be missing like so
many other things are missing huh uh-huh
I think today's the day all right guys
are you ready here we go no no it's
still there okay never mind
hello mr. sheep how are you doing today
good to see you we have like 15 minutes
left in our episode here could you
entertain us for a little bit please
thank you
he said something oh look at his eyes
he's doing something funny with his eyes
look how dirty they are that is
hilarious
yes best 30 seconds ever okay we're just
gonna do it anyway the door is there but
it's fine we got nothing else to do
today guys although I'm pretty sure
there's a reason we haven't gone behind
this the
yes are you ready
today's the day okay okay I don't like
this guy's I I don't think we're
supposed to actually do this Oh what was
that
so freaky oh it stopped
thank thank goodness oh no it didn't
stop oh oh no nope nope oh I can't stop
them No what is that
where'd he go always by the crafting
table watch
I do not like that thing whatever it is
I think it's trying to kill us although
he's pretty much ignoring me now hello
are you evil
yeah he's ignoring me now okay tell you
what let let's go inside but let's close
the door behind us so that you can get
us I'm trapped in the door one second
alright yeah nothing should be able to
get in now I think we're safe although
still hearing the sounds Oh what is this
fun little cube I don't think we're
alone in here guys oh there we go um
there's something around this corner
hello
that's that's me hello me are you
friendly
oh the eyes are back
can we yes let's just kill this thing
whatever it is okay good good good okay
let's try to stay away from that thing
hello etho friendly oh okay
he's not really looking at me yes
are those the missing pages do you have
the missing pages in your hands Etha
there we go yeah he said yes okay I
think he's I think he's cool we can
ignore him I just heard something else
okay
another defeat right oh good more spooky
sounds I saw something moving trying to
figure out what those are it sound like
a minecart hi there this is like some
bad nightmare how are you guys doing oh
you have some missing pages too they're
not attacking me that's good you will
just let them do their thing okay then
well that's the portal to the dream
world obviously okay so you didn't quite
understand that don't think we can get
in there though this guy is having a bad
day oh this is nice
that makes me very happy actually you
know guys whenever you go somewhere it's
important to leave a message to those
you love in case you're you're not
around when they when they read the
message you know or chase they wonder
where you went or or what you're
thinking so I'm glad somebody left the
message for me there yes that made
perfect sense okay let's go down because
we got nothing else to do that is a
chicken hello mister chicken are you
friends with mr. sheep
okay I don't think mr. chicken's messing
around here pretty sure he's yeah he
doesn't like us very much okay then
we're gonna have to kill this guy
I'll get he dies easily at least all
right well we got two choices here guys
we either go to the right or the left I
think I'm gonna go this hallway looks so
weird by the way it looks like it's
really close but it's actually really
far isn't it yeah
that's like an optical illusion almost
let's go to this one first no let's not
go to that one hey I'm pretty sure he's
mad at us oh oh I got slowness okay he
was a he was a pushover at least very
good let's keep going down this long
crazy hallway and he hints to what's
behind this door okay I think I think
this is getting bad guys yeah this is a
bad dream right now are you friendly
this guy's friendly what about you I
don't want you sneaking up behind me
either I don't think he's alive Oh
well he almost killed me we got quite a
few choices to where to go guys I'm not
sure what we're looking for but I guess
we'll just hit up these doors one by one
maybe that's me over there okay
what's behind this door alright what
about this door oh I like this room this
is a good room
very good I'm just gonna leave that one
going I watched the whole thing it looks
beautiful
alright so let's keep going down the
line here there's a laughing coming from
this store or not I can't tell oh no we
blew off the lever actually the whole
door is gone what am I saying okay we
got a battle on our hands on this one
and we kill this thing is the question I
think we one shotted it Wow okay that
works it is dead right
it looks like it's dead just in case
it's not I'm gonna put up a another door
here don't want that thing getting out
[Music]
these sounds are starting to drive me
crazy let's go to this one yeah this one
okay that looks like me yeah
good-looking guy is he the one laughing
oh oh this is not a friendly one oh
maybe
oh he's not hurting me don't get your
snacks it's just like me it's a real
etho hey do that again awesome oh
there's another guy thanks for watching
everybody take care thanks oh this is
awesome thanks for watching everybody
take care bye bye the days of you buddy
alright let's go guys thanks for
watching everybody take care everybody
hey what's up everybody this is Ito
thanks for watching everybody thank you
Oh welcome back everybody
go get your snacks Oh me what's up
everybody this is thanks for watching
everybody
take care that's right welcome back
everybody get your snacks
I think hey what's up everybody this is
thanks for watching everybody hopper get
your snacks hey what's up everybody this
is etho thanks for watching everybody
take care I think that
anyways guys hey what's up everybody
thanks for whoa
[Music]
we got to get out of here right now
I hate mazes I don't know how to get out
of here I thought you came in over here
anyways this is it this is it I stood
out of here bad Oh stay stay in there
all right then let's go check this one
out
oh no no I think we got a battle on our
hands
yeah state these schools out
whole snap there's a lot of them in here
too
come on what you got pushovers all of
you alright
The Laughing sounds like it's coming
from this room after all oh no oh this
is an angry guy whoa what's going on
stop it stop it stop it
oh he's gonna kill me he is definitely
gonna kill me
stop it whole one heart left that was a
little too close oh I almost walked
right on top the creeper what am i doing
alright
chocolate island you say let's close the
door on this one just in case this guy
comes back that just leaves I believe
the main door this one over here you
would think with common sense this is
the first one I would go to because it's
the only one with the guard it's almost
like I tried to avoid going here first
purely coincidence
oh man okay yeah he's actually a tough
guy can we take them out please
we got a heal up here hello grave
[Music]
alright then I don't think the arrows
are actually working on this guy this is
a strong bow otherwise he has a ton of
help let's try the sword oh yeah that
did it okay oh these sounds are really
messing with my head now let's get out
of here all right so we got what are you
friendly hello it's an out-of-work
villager okay nothing to worry about I
have a feeling it's weird it's like I
almost know what's coming next this is
the only non scripted episode of Etha
plays minecraft we've ever done and it's
like I know what's happening in the
future the most of any episode it's the
total opposites what do we got here oh
man this is what I think it is
[Music]
oh I don't believe it spaz is back and
he grew a pair not arms but heads it
looks like hey spaz
how you doing man it's been a while
oh he's not activating anything though
those guys don't see me good we might
have to let him out he seems maybe a bit
broken guys
come on spaz this is supposed to be an
epic boss battle and you're just you're
failing oh he's down he's down all right
oh he's gonna kill me let's get to the
other side here oh oh it's not TIG this
time that is a nuke that is a nuke guys
dad we just got to heal up a second oh
that is so creepy he's like looking
around the corner
come on come on hey
[Music]
I think you're broken dude
yeah he's broken
all right let's go in for the final
attack or not oh and the music just
stops
[Music]