[Music]
hello everybody how's it going
uh we're just going to do something
really fun to start out today
i was in this area for a little bit
installing lamps
and whatever i am about to leave but
i thought before we go we're going to
let these guys out and see what happens
watch them all burn maybe watch him kill
me
since i'm leaving anyway have a little
fun instead of letting them
be spawn
wow they did damage quick
that was uh that was intense
they didn't all get out either man they
just
took like nine hearts away from me or
something right off the bat
and a few of them didn't come out
wow
man that's crazy i wish i had some
health potions
there's still a lot there wow
um oh wow there's a ton there
or 95
a lot of oh that's probably the arrows
and the bones and everything
it does look like there's at least 20
though
okay i'm gonna run in front and use my
blocking
wow
okay i gotta get out of here i don't
wanna die i really don't
that's awesome
oh are they fighting each other they are
that's so cool
okay maybe one more time one more time
we'll go in
um
that doesn't work
wow that was a lot of arrows
okay that was fun uh
i think we're gonna go to the silverfish
spawner again i did a lot of work there
and i think i solved the problem so
let's head on
down there there's still a few camping
out there
in the shade that's cool
yeah they killed me anyway we're back to
the silverfish
uh this that's the machine back there
this is a room
i set up to store them temporarily while
they work on it
uh and it's full so i'm gonna
let them out
so to get the chain reaction to happen
we are going to have to hit them
a few times to really get them out
it comes really easy when they're piled
like this as far as
how i'm going to set up a killing room
and all that is going to work i'm not
quite sure yet
i'm guessing i'm going to be dropping
them so they're
only got two punches on them maybe
so that every time you hit them it will
cause them to spawn and then
one more hit will kill them i think that
would be the possibly the best way of
doing it
but for right now i'm just using my
sword
there's a lot of silver fish
whoa
yeah you don't want to get in a hole
that is a lot of silverfish oh no what
did i just say
[Music]
nope nope okay
okay that's it for me ender pearl oh
dang it i thought about it too late
yep so that's
definitely gonna have to set up a good
chill
a good uh killing room for these guys
because this doesn't work
just like this
and all right um
just give me a minute to clean up here
all right it's time for enchantment
break i needed a new shovel
and i'm going to be doing a little
experiment here usually i go for
level 50 whenever i enchant the tool
uh i'm going to try level 41.42
for a little while and see how how that
works out for me
efficiency four okay so that's not
that's not
terrible uh because i find efficiency
five
doesn't really work a whole lot better
for me as far as speed goes it's
uh it's pretty much or pretty similar
anyway usually when i'm mining
i do the quick mining trick anyway and
having efficiency 5 doesn't make that
any quicker
so seems like it would be better just to
go for lower level enchantments because
going like from level 40 to compared to
level
50 level 50s a time and a half
over a time and a half more experience
than level 40.
so it's a big difference
anyway let's head back to the silverfish
okay so we're going to be doing a little
bit more experimenting with these
silverfish
and the machine here and their behavior
and stuff like that um
i do also want to point out i said that
they can't enter
cracked stone brick and mossy ones last
episode apparently they can
a lot of you have commented and even
shown me that they can
but when they do they turn the block to
the regular
stone brick texture look so keep that in
mind sorry about that mistake
and also they can do it with the circle
stone bricks that aren't in the game yet
as well um as far as this machine goes
it's actually working pretty good at the
moment
better than i was expecting it to i just
after last episode i hooked it up to
that piston i put underneath them
and it seems to be controlling them
like they can't they don't seem to be
beating
the bud switch like they were doing
before
the only thing that's not keeping up now
is the cobblestone
or smooth stone generator so
we'll have to tweak this a little bit
yet we either need to add a delay on the
cobblestone generator or make it quicker
or else uh make it so these guys won't
ever group
like they're doing right there because
that's what causes
it causes this thing to jam
if you want to check if your silverfish
factory is foolproof
get a bunch of them in that spot like
that
then walk a little bit away and see if
it jams up mine
will hear for sure but i think it's
because of the
generator being too slow and not
actually the detector
which is good let's try it out
yeah yeah oh no
that silver fish got through because i'm
just in a block down there
no it's still going
i wonder if they're seeing me or
something these guys
this guy needs to get a life i can't hit
them or else uh
yeah you see the lava back there that's
because it's
messed up or at least one side did
actually it still might be okay
i'll get lost
nope um
fish okay it's jam there's ever a silver
fish
uh where they're supposed to be where
they're supposed to go then it's jammed
so i i don't know if it was this that
jammed or the detector
but it almost seems like it's the
generator
but anyway uh we're gonna try to
regulate it so that they
when they spawn they actually go down
there instead of like having
20 or 30 of them stuck in this water i'm
gonna
experiment with that a little bit today
because they spawn a lot slower than
this machine can actually work
so there's no reason it should jam on us
and i also replaced this room with soil
are you still following me
so hopefully uh they don't make a big
mess like they did before
and i was going to show you how this
works uh
this is a group smart piston type thing
um what you do you just put a torch
underneath
the very last one it pushes to and that
will power this wire
and then it goes up to all the pistons
all along there
but you you should put in this repeater
even though it's not
technically technically necessary
i find sometimes this first piston will
fire but
all the other ones don't for some reason
if if there's no
uh repeater it seems to force the
current to stay on
a tad longer maybe possibly
and uh when when a block
gets this last one then they all extend
like that and it's ready for another 12
so
it is possible to use a piston to push
up to 12 blocks
so every piston can move 12 blocks so if
you're
if you got to figure out how many blocks
you need to move just divide that by 12
and that's how many pistons you need to
do it
at best
all right so this piston here this one
below
where they all gather that's just hooked
up to
over here on the bud switch
uh it branches off to the generator
there and
also goes down low
to here comes down
got to go into these two repeaters just
to try
stabilize this redstone wire and also
i think it might extend it hopefully
kind of like a cheap way of doing it
real simple
um again i'm going to back away here and
see if it jams
or how it jams
yeah so generator could not keep up
one thing i could do is put
a bud switch next to this lava
so that if the lab was to make it all
the way down then it could
detect that it's jammed and reset itself
as well
that's one idea at the moment i can fix
it just by
doing that
oh wait no there was no block to push
there we go
but uh generally it doesn't jam on me
because i don't have
like 20 or 30 in there at once usually
hmm it's a jam
nope it's not jammed there we go
yeah so i think one thing we should try
today is
get rid of that drop because they try to
avoid drops
and they swim against the current to to
try avoid it
i also want to try
oh boy there's a lot of them here i also
want to try
uh maybe putting half slabs under the
water
so that they can't touch the ground and
jump
to maybe prevent them from swimming
against the current as strongly
so we'll do that first and then we'll
try to get rid of the drop and see
how they work out i'm going to try to
store these in blocks so before i do
that
yeah another thing i want to mention is
a lot of people are wondering why i was
using flint and steel last episode to
kill the silverfish
it's because if you kill them with
environmental damage
like fire lava falling whatever
it won't cause anymore to spawn if
there's some nearby in blocks
they spawn if you hit them and don't
kill them
so if you punch them with your fist it
causes lots to
spawn every every time you hit it it'll
spawn a few more if they're in the area
if you use flint and steel you don't
have that problem also if you have a
diamond sword with at least
sharpness one on or a bane of arthropods
i think would probably do it too
you could one hit kill them and they
won't spawn anymore from blocks either
so once this sword sword's done i'll
probably go get a
sword with sharpness one or something
anyway i put half slabs down here i'm
going to put water
above it fill it in
gonna let a bunch spawn here and see
what happens
all right this is uh this is pretty
weird actually
the silverfish are able to fall through
the water and walk around
i've never seen this happen before with
any other mob but
since they're slightly taller than half
a block
they will actually take suffocation
damage from the water as they're walking
on the half slabs which is a little
strange
then uh the other ones that swim in the
water
that don't fall through they're still
they still are able to fight it like
they were before so
yeah that's not gonna work so we're
going to try lower this then
so that it's even with the the
detector block or whatever the block
they go in
yeah oh yeah i should probably prove
that they're
half a block so they're tracking me
oh now he jumped up bad timing for that
to happen
come on oh we got one
see he can't fit through that he tried
but he wasn't able to
all right i'm gonna adjust that and we
will try again
okay so now i have it lowered one more
block it's level with this
so now they should have hopefully no
reason for fighting the current so
they'll just go with it and
get put in the block a lot quicker
hopefully that's the goal with this
and if that happens it's a lot less
likely to jam up
so let's try it out turn it back on
step back and watch what happens oh i
didn't put the water
um
it's all good
let's try this again
nice all right no they're still fighting
it
kind of hmm
i can't remember if it's jammed right
now
nope
hmm they don't seem to be there we go
it might take them a little while i
guess um
all right let's just watch it for a
little bit so i heard uh
minecraft is coming out on xbox live
arcade
that hey whoa hey
mm-hmm that could be pretty cool
at the local split screen is especially
appealing to me
uh if you have some friends that would
play it i think that would be
pretty fun
i don't know why but the mobs there was
a hole here and they always are getting
stuck in there
like on their own there's at least two
creepers in there
and a zombie keeps happening
uh this seems to be okay so far
but yeah local split screen on minecraft
would be a lot of fun
plus thing i think you can play on the
internet too like with
16 people was it i don't know
i'm excited for it i'll definitely be
getting that i won't be
recording any of it because i don't have
one of those uh hipachi boxes or
anything
so i can't record
uh okay well i'm gonna sit here for a
little while and see if it
if they all gather here or if they keep
entering the blocks like i want them to
so
okay this thing seems to be working
really well actually i'm
pretty surprised that clip was about
four minutes long i sped it up
six times the speed uh and this is still
going it hasn't jammed yet
just that regular rates like it would
get
it seems to keep up pretty good
uh yeah so i think it's stable enough
for right now anyway i can probably
comfortably
build the storage rooms now for the
blocks
uh without having to worry about maybe
moving this or anything i think it's
good the way it is and they will fight
the current if they're facing that
direction but
generally they seem to have no trouble
getting there
um yeah a lot of people were saying i
should adjust the timing on this
generator uh
so that the bud switch can keep up and
so that i don't need
this piston here but the thing is this
is actually set right the way it is
i have played around with other timings
and it doesn't work
i've tried lots of different timings for
this and different
ways of syncing it up but the thing is
this is one delay here
torch adds another one
and this generator pushes the block
after two so it's the same that one's
two
and this is two they meet up at the same
time if you extend this longer
this piston on the butt switch will
extend twice
i believe so the way it is right now is
proper
and this piston i am still
this one i'm still is very i'm still
very convinced that we need it
um yeah
and as far as killing them um i don't
know
i think i'll set up rooms that are
that store the blocks in a 12. by
let's see 12 times 12 times 6
would get us pretty close to 50 levels i
think
so i think that's what i'll aim for and
i'll probably do it
much like this uh
probably 12 by 12 horizontally and then
six vertically silver fish have
four hearts so they can fall 11 blocks
without dying
so that should be okay if
that would work out all right i could
make a room that's 11 blocks high
and put them at the very top so that
they'll take quite a bit of fall damage
when they spawn because they they always
spawn with four hearts
health and then i could maybe use poison
potions or
the instant damage potions to finish
them off
i don't know we'll see we'll see
and i was talking about maybe building
my storage room and mob system here
instead of that other area the idea is i
would have the floor for the storage
room maybe
like right at this level here so that
when i'd be walking around
doing stuff i would be within range of
the spawner here
and yet still outside of the range of
the silverfish so they
they would do that on their own without
tracking me
because they fall down quite a few
blocks and i think we would be out of
range
of them so
could be could be pretty cool and this
is not just an
xp system some people are wondering why
i keep building all these xp
systems it's because i like it that's
probably my favorite thing in minecraft
is uh
doing stuff with mobs and uh
if you've watched my lp series from the
beginning you can see
that's what i've been doing pretty much
since the beginning
my favorite parts but silver fish
also this is full by the way
also would be very good for digging
you could spawn them in this room for
example
and then walk them to wherever you want
to do some digging because they all
follow you
and then if you go outside of range of
them they will all enter
blocks all the stone blocks
remember minecraft is mostly like
minecraft world is mostly made
of stone so
they could do a lot of digging if you
were to leave the area they would enter
the blocks
then you can make them spawn again and
they would break all those blocks
uh then you could get like a hundred
spawns
leave the area again they would all
enter blocks again
hit them they would break a hundred more
blocks and you could dig pretty quick
doing that you know
just repeat that cycle you could dig a
deep hole really fast
i think so that is a
another motive behind this i want a good
digging tool
for large projects maybe and i think
they could do that
all right we're back home again here i
just stopped by to get some splash
potions to kill a little silver fish
that's how we're gonna end
this episode getting around that time
again
uh also i did some mining the other day
i got another
close to a stack of diamond i think we
were
running a little low-ish got a bunch of
iron again other stuff
some more redstone even though it's very
low still
i think one of these days i'm just like
one of these days soon
i'm just going to make a proper mind
somewhere like with a nice entrance and
nice elevator up and down type thing
uh away from here because as it is right
now
my mind shaft or mine shaft is
branch mine whatever you want to call it
is actually really close to here
and i'm worried about lighting it up
once i dig through it
and making it clean looking because it's
so close to our home
if we do ever build a mob system here i
don't want uh
it dark this is where i've been going
just down here
i don't want to darken the shaft mine
because then we'll get mobs spawning so
i've been very careful so far
to make sure i light it up i've been
very
ocd about it but if i build a
mine somewhere far off i won't have to
worry anymore i could just dig
very leisurely like this these torches
are all spaced
a precise distance from each other so
that
no mobs will spawn
if i if i
oh maybe they're not ah see what i mean
i have to go through this one
and do that but if i build it somewhere
else i won't have to worry anymore
so i should do that sometime
uh anyway we're gonna i'm gonna get some
potions and we'll head back to the
silver fish
okay i found out which one i lit up very
carefully
it's uh this one
so every every 10 on the zed
is where i would place the torch that
way it's easy to figure it out
you don't have to count it you just look
at the z number
and it's easy to figure out stuff by
tens i think you can actually go
i think by twelves and the light would
be enough
but uh it's just easier to go by tens
he's been staring at me for over a
minute
he's not moving
it's really freaking me out
why is he staring at me
all right hopefully this works out
better this time so
we're going to end the episode here
today
thanks for watching as always
and we'll probably take a little bit of
a break from this project just
because i know uh
people get bored of stuff if i work on
it too long
or for too many episodes
yeah man i got full
iron armor on this time and there's no
holes to fall into so i think i'm gonna
win this battle
anymore
that's it that's it
[Music]
wow
never have i seen such a thing
they're not taking any more damage that
was uh all they had
i guess that's the first time i've used
the poison potion
like a splash one
although although maybe an ooch i used
one i can't remember
and spell down caves anyway
[Music]
awesome i got more i do
so yeah if i was to do a 12 by 12 by 6
that would be about 800 silver fish so i
might have to
uh do half of them at a time or
something because that could be
pretty hard on my game
[Music]
that's a lot of silverfish whatever
level we'll get up to with that
that's like 1 6 of the way to level 50.
about level level 20 or so
so i'm kind of hoping to make more lp
episodes like
get them out a little bit more
frequently i'm going to put the effort
out
i think i've been averaging every every
three days or so
hopefully going to get that up to two
every two days
i'm gonna try no promises
uh i haven't had to work at my job as
much as i thought i would have to this
year
so i got a couple extra hours more a day
than i thought i would so i
should be able to do it hopefully
we'll see but i'm gonna say goodbye
bye