[Music]
oh
no man
this is bad news uh you guys know how i
uh afk
at the village here for the horse
breeding
i i like went and made coffee got a
snack when i came back
it said i was dead and i was hiding my
little house there so
something bad spawned in the village and
i don't know how long ago i died so
there's a very good chance all my stuff
is going to despawn too
villagers are there though they didn't
die
what on earth how are they getting into
the village
that's the house right there how how
how how on earth okay my stuff is still
here
i gotta figure this out because somehow
zombies or something are getting inside
this village
and i have no clue where they would do
it or how they would do it
i'm so confused oh why did i jump there
i like just randomly jumped i did not
press the space bar i swear
uh so i may not have been killed by a
mob i keep randomly starving to death
when i'm afk which is
very strange i think i jumped there
right
or did i imagine that uh yeah so i
may have start starved to death
apparently uh zombie sieges have been
added to the game
uh there's a possibility uh zombies
recruited like uh you know when they
take damage sometimes they spawn
reinforcements
there's a chance like that may have
happened inside the village
and there is also another thing i
noticed the difficulty
is at 5.72 i've never seen that higher
than
nine or something is what's usually at
it's three point something anyway
so i don't know what's going on anymore
lots of changes or oddities i don't know
i haven't gotten very far with the horse
breeding it's getting
really really really difficult now oh
new color
actually like this color of horse
alright so let's see if we can get
anything good
yeah it's i've kind of hit a wall with
it like it's really difficult to get
anything better now
uh give him some sugar
we're gonna head over to the man cave
pretty quick here i've done a lot over
there like lots
i played for a few hours just like doing
detail work there
and had a lot of fun with that i've been
really enjoying playing
survival minecraft lately
a little bit addicted to it um
come on horsey give me them hearts
give me the hearts right now
did i miss the hearts
no he didn't give me the hearts what a
guy
come on horsey
you're keeping everybody waiting
there we go holy smokes that took
forever
all right get the saddle on let's go
check the jump height
let's see let's do jump heights oh it's
terrible
nope not even close to anything better
so we're at 4.375 right now for the best
jumper
this guy's not even a four so he's not
gonna
be with us for very long here
okay so check this out guys i got a
couple horse tricks to show you
first one oh well that's the second one
first one we'll call it the first one
it's a little weird
i'm not pressing the space bar there
if i you see how the horse is standing
on his two legs there
and then as soon as i hop on it the next
time it instantly jumps
it's so weird like i'm not pressing
space bar there
i wonder how long i can wait before oh
it still did it look at that
oh it's pretty cool i like that one
let's wait uh a few seconds here so as
soon as i hop on the horse without
pressing spacebar
the horse jumps again
so you gotta like hold spacebar then
press shift before
before it jumps and if it's standing on
the back legs like that
that's when it works the second one
or the second trick you gotta like jump
the horse and get off of it
right afterwards it takes a little bit
of practice
but it looks pretty cool yeah check that
out
especially if you have a high jumping
horse it's pretty cool
oh did the other one
as you can tell i've had lots of time
here between the horse breeding
and uh you gotta do things like this to
fill your time
anyway i thought those were cool uh
we're gonna head over to the man cave
i will see you guys there and we'll take
a look at a few things that i've done
yeah so last episode we kind of went
around the man cave here we
renovated a few things fixed some broken
stuff
and added some new stuff even
i enjoyed that a lot actually so after
the episode ended i
i did i wanted to do some more and i
fixed a few more things and
the day after it's like i want to do
that again so i did some more stuff off
camera and then the day after i did some
more so
there's been a lot of like really little
changes around here lots of detail work
and let's just take a quick tour around
i'll point out a few things
most of it's like really small changes
that aren't even obvious though
like you got pictures around around
there now those weren't there before
um we had a lot of like those red
poppies and
yellow dandelions around the cave and
i've changed a lot of those out with
these new flowers
and added some flowers where where there
weren't flowers before like around this
tree we got these orange tulips
just because i like them a little more
added some flowers here for example some
over there
some potatoes along the wall there just
for
i don't know because i felt like it this
bridge i think was just
oak slabs before and i added a fence
here and the lighting
and some stuff on the roof it's it's
this area is still pretty
unfinished but it helps a little bit
uh if we head down the majority of the
changes are down here
oh yeah added a table here
change the change the flowers there i
don't really like those ones though i
think i'm going to change those again
what is that oh that's a cat what are
you doing here kitty
he wasn't there before uh one of these
horse stalls was broken i fixed that
that's all good
oh yeah last episode actually let's head
up here real quick
we were working on the villager thing
right and i had to redo that door i
fixed the door
skeleton fix this door so now opens and
closes again
there's like a button up here opens
vertically
pretty cool uh around
the mini farm and the snowball
farm i've made a lot of changes
yeah over here this is all new this used
to be
just like a plain oak wall never really
liked it
so i like i did a bunch here
we got like some flower pot stuff cactus
painting
there's some lighting hidden behind that
uh
bone meal in the chest mushrooms on the
floor there
uh it looked pretty weird without these
stairs here they looked pretty plain
so i added those just for some extra
detail
because this kind of goes in line with
the arch theme i have
throughout the cave this thing here and
then
yeah anyway uh what else
oh yeah i did fix the snowball farm this
wasn't working last episode
now it is so what i did
uh this snowman he wasn't on the block
here
so it wasn't making the snow i got
dispenser here now
so i just added four fences and i pushed
him in the middle of them
and now he's always like in between
these four blocks
and some people are saying he won't work
because
he doesn't make snow below y64 or
something that doesn't seem to be true
still seems to work just fine which is
great
i added a painting here armor stand
changed out some of the oak here with
spruce wood added some more hidden
lighting and flowers around the river
here
still have a little more to go still got
torches
in a few spots let's see
flowers up there now uh there was a
bunch of torches scattered throughout
here now i have these
glowstone lights in the wood pillars
i made some adjustments to the front of
this fishing shack too like
this clown fish and i think these lights
weren't here
um yeah just lots of little things like
these
let's see head on down here
don't think i changed anything here i
just i added this cauldron
spider there is a new path i'm starting
down here this is all new
uh this path goes over to to here
this part of the cave i'm gonna put
something in the wall here
for sure maybe on this side too
um added a spruce pillar no archway
spruce archway here um
some lily pads in the water
this was all just grass before now i got
some flowers and leaves and stuff there
uh added a light up there fixed the roof
here as well this was pretty messy now
it's a little smooth
smoother anyway
fix the elevator this wasn't working
whoa still doesn't work for players i'm
surprised i got that high actually
but uh works with horses now
let me show you so what i did
i got rid of one of the slime blocks
there where the piston is and i put a
clay block
i was worried the horses were gonna die
on that when they
when they dropped down but it seems okay
yeah as long as i'm aligned against this
wall if i'm aligned on this red wall
then i think the horse would die if i
fell
um let's see
anything else anything else
i guess i did a little bit over here as
well
uh this extends a little bit further
added some bushes and stuff
and that's about it i think
i probably missed a bunch of stuff i
don't know if you notice any changes in
the cave that's probably what i did
um anyway i also did a bunch of resource
gathering like uh
uh sands so i could make some some glass
bottles and
got some potions brewing in there again
because we were running low
and i got sand for tnt because i've had
tons tons
of gunpowder but i haven't been able to
craft it into tnt until now
so this chest is pretty full of tnt we
got lots of tnt which is great
oh man guys we have our first ice cube
it finished
[Laughter]
oh i love breaking ice in this game it's
so much fun
and this is a 10 by 10 by 10 cube of ice
thousand blocks oh man how should we do
this
this is going to be so satisfying shall
we
i guess the logical way is go from like
the top down
i think the fun way is just going to be
like rip right into the center
and just go crazy i think that's what
i'm going to do
let's see silk touch yep all right here
we go
first harvest
oh man
i love that sound so much
i wonder if this pitch is even going to
be able to make it all the way
is it pushing us up what is it doing oh
yeah it's pushing up so that it's
actually 11 layers because
there was one layer it wasn't able to
push up and now it's it's able to do it
oh yes all right guys i'm gonna i'm
gonna finish this up off camera
and then we'll go do something else
okay i got it all this is what it looks
like in in the chest
compared to like what we just saw just
two rows
but that is over 1200 blocks of ice
right there which is pretty cool
literally
hmm
okay guys so now that we have all this
ice from that ice farm i was trying to
think like
is there anything i actually want to use
that for
or is it just like an overkill farm have
all the like thousands
of blocks of ice and i'm never gonna use
it uh but there's actually a project
i think we should do today
chomp chomp jump uh we're gonna head
over to the end here it's been a while
since we did a project in the end like
i think the enderman farm was the last
one actually
[Music]
because the end is scary
not the enderman i don't care about the
enderman it's that void
the stinking void just terrifies me
because i've lost so much stuff in it
uh but yeah we here maybe let's take a
look at this first
to introduce the idea so for our first
enderman farm over there we built this
rail line underneath the path and
the idea was like when i'm over there
dropped some ender pearls in a storage
minecart and then it will
take off and go over to here then we got
a bunch of
get out of here man got a bunch of
chests here and an unloading station all
the ender pearls would get unloaded
oh there's still something the mine cart
would return and i could
fill it up with some more and and yeah
it sounds good in theory in practice it
it worked okay it wasn't great though
the main issue
like i would be over there i'd drop off
a a whole inventory of ender pearls into
the storage minecart
send it back and then it would unload
over here right and it would never come
back so
couldn't really send a lot of ender
pearls
um when i was over there because the
storage minecart never came back right
so what we're gonna do
for the new farm we're gonna use water
streams instead
no mine carts is there a center to this
i think that's it right yeah
we're gonna build an item elevator first
of all underneath our
our portal let's see
yeah i think that'll be okay so we gotta
dig straight down here
actually no we don't even need to dig
through the ground do we
should i just send him through the end
stone i guess it's the same thing
yeah maybe we'll do that so basically
save some work for myself all you gotta
do
do a plus sign thing all the way up to
the the end portal make sure there's no
air spaces
actually let me check the location of
this
just so i get it right hopefully there's
no like secret air pockets in between
uh this and the bottom of the island so
we're at 73
and negative nine
good okay i'm gonna fill that back up
we're gonna head down
got a ladder here oh this is going to
take a while
as you can see my end situation isn't
the nicest i have to like traverse these
one wide
dirt paths to get up this ladder and
yeah
so i want to do some adjustments on this
let's break this break this did i bring
any other blocks i wonder okay what was
the location again
73 negative nine so you gotta go a few
more blocks
this way i'm so scared to press any key
right now
okay let's get f3 back up
is that it no one more block so this is
the center right here
uh so i'm going to do that plus sign a
glass all the way up
and then we need to build like a loading
thing for this
so we're going to build an item elevator
here that doesn't use any pistons
basically this is the center this fence
the back one and
need solid blocks next to that so it
does this plus sign
shape right then this front fence we
want
something it doesn't attach to on the
sides
like that and then above
the middle one you gotta do the plus
sign like that
right um then we got a
here let's add some ice
and some more glass
all right i guess we'll probably have
glass all the way down here
i just want to test this make sure it
works first
so let's just throw down some some water
here
see if we can get it working so
we gotta align the items right next to
the wall as well i think
yeah there we go it worked right
yeah i think that was good here maybe
we'll build a little bit higher just to
be sure
i'm gonna have to go all the way up to
the bottom of the island with this glass
and then it should send items through
the portal automatically
okay let's try it again
seems like it's jumping out i might need
some more blocks here
oh i do have a block there i thought i
didn't
hmm why you no work
okay tell you what we're gonna do it
proper make sure we do it right
here let's grab this it kind of has to
go around a bend that way it aligns it
against the wall fisher
yeah now it works okay so just throwing
it against the wall
was a little iffy i guess okay that's
cool
so basically we got to build an ice an
ice water stream
all the way from the enderman farm out
there
carry items all the way here when they
hit this fence though
or not that fence the that fence over
here
they will flow up and go through the
portal
all right well this is a little bulkier
looking than i would like
because our path is only three blocks
wide and then we have this
giant three block wide water stream uh
but i'll i'll put another one on the
other side that way it's symmetrical
maybe and maybe i'll do the arrow look
that i got on the ground here
and and put that in the stream too here
but
uh i i want to see i want to make sure
it's actually working because i can't
quite
tell so we're going to throw an egg
maybe an obsidian i really need a second
person here to help me with this
oh it looks like it goes up
i don't see it fly anywhere it just kind
of disappears
uh so what we'll do we'll go up
and then we'll go through the portal and
just make sure
it's it's waiting there where it should
be
um should get picked up by the hoppers
we have at our spawn
oh did i just get him no
or did i i heard a a click did you hear
a click
i don't have the egg or the or the
obsidian we threw though okay
okay let's see if we picked it up going
through here
don't think we did that's good oh i
gotta walk all the way back to spawn
we're at the the guardian farm so one
second
okay so if it worked oops i'm gonna go
across the bridge
i get lost throughout my own place all
the time uh yeah if it worked it should
be in the hoppers here that we set up a
while ago
two obsidian one egg at least
no well where did they go man i can't
tell where they're
disappearing oh man
all right i'm gonna head back i gotta
try to figure this out
well you all know not to dig straight
down but that is especially true in the
end
uh okay there is no hollow spots in
between
the bottom of the island and the top of
the island so that's not what happened
just wanted to double check i think what
we'll do
to test this again let's go back
up and rather than trying to send the
items through the portal let's just try
to send them to the top of this
and see if they can do that because i
don't know
what is happening to them it looks like
they go up the elevator maybe they just
are not going through the portal
properly
maybe because i'm putting them in
putting them in from the bottom
instead of dropping them in i don't know
all right so hopefully the items end up
right there
let's go back down
okay ouch
okay let's try sending some netherrack
here
make sure it goes around the bend
properly
do some glass and maybe a piece of end
stone
okay it looks like
it looks like it goes through right
okay let's go back up
oh that scared me i like jumped and then
or i felt like i jumped and i missed the
ladder i thought i jumped off the edge
here
okay let's go up come on
i really need to set up an elevator for
myself here too
no they're not there so they're flying
out somewhere
aha so i found my problem i made a
mistake i had
ice underneath that fence there
it's not supposed to be ice it's
supposed to be a block that slows them
down
like a normal block so let's try it
again
oh and it seems to work even
now when i throw it
yeah look at it go looks good very good
okay now we're going to try to send it
through the portal again
oh so scary
yep items are here that's good finish
the elevator again
i'm gonna send up some more items then
we'll go check the hoppers
okay so i'm just sleeping away the night
these are the hoppers i threw i think i
can't remember if it was one or more
pieces obsidian
a fence and three snowballs
nothing nothing nothing
ah
darn it
nope they didn't make it through so they
might have got stuck in the portal i'm
not sure
i think i got it this time i'm gonna
throw an iron bucket out of confidence
that it's gonna work
all right and maybe a sign
and some arrows
good okay let's go check the hoppers
once again so what i did i ended up
moving this
elevator over i think about three blocks
or so
when i removed the other one i was
digging down and i like dug the glas
the um as i got towards the bottom there
was some air apparently
some air spaces and i fell and i dug the
ice like the very bottom icier and i
just about fell in the void but
the water saved me i like
swam up really quickly um
but yeah almost died anyway
no hit the ladder please nope
nope
okay so here's how i did it now
i did it to the side of the portal so
that the items can drop in from the top
because i think what's happening
they're going in for in from the bottom
but they're
the portal block is is like a little bit
higher up or something i'm not sure
exactly
um so if they drop in from the top they
should work for sure
and it goes up the item elevator there's
a water stream that carries them over
and drops them down
i cannot find my packed ice anywhere is
am i crazy didn't we get packed ice on
that episode
i don't remember using it anywhere even
like it's just gone
never existed i don't know what the deal
is
all right there we go we got some some
arrows
that's filled up good the budget's there
so it works now uh that's great so i'm
gonna
finish up that water stream make it go
all the way to the enderman farm i'm out
of time to record today but
hopefully before next episode i'll get
that done
so it's comment time again guys let's
let's see what this one says
you have a library etho i think you have
a place to keep your librarians
hmm putting librarians
in a library
no i'm sorry you're crazy on another
subject how many pistons do you think
you could reclaim if you implemented
slime block connection into all your
existing devices
a lot less than you might think the
thing about slime blocks
is they tend to stick to everything and
wreck things so in most cases you can't
actually use them where you would want
to
maybe maybe the gold farm the zombie
with the zombie pigmans
like i have all those piston pushers
maybe there
i could save a lot of pistons but in
general
i think they would wreck the string
though maybe
i'm not sure um
yeah it's kind of tough to use them in a
way that they'll save you a lot of
pistons
generally unless you really design the
thing
to use them anyway
that is going to do it for today guys if
you have any suggestions for what you
want me to do next episode
don't be afraid to leave a comment
otherwise i will do
whatever random thing i think of at that
moment
like i do in most episodes uh anyway
that'll be it for that'll be it that's
it for today guys
that's it that's all we're finished
goodbye thank you for watching have a
good day
i said goodbye already uh take care
i have to say goodbye again bye bye
you