hello everybody this is Issa welcome
back guys to another episode I am here
at my my underground village and decided
to check on it because it's been a while
since I last did and you hear that you
hear it not a peep
no villager making any noises I do have
my sound down all the way there we go
that helps but yeah I arrived here today
I checked it out and all the villagers
were gone pretty much we had three left
and I've been trying to get them to
repopulate for the last little while
here and it things are on their way
again which is very good so a baby
zombie probably got in here somewhere
which is fine it's it's okay because I
actually wanted to clear out some of the
scrubs here anyway because there was a
lot of low quality villagers around and
I wanted a generation to come in um
thankfully though this guy survived
because one of the reasons I checked
this place out today is planning on
moving him so this is this is the clear
the cleric we got earlier and he is
running away from me oh that's why two
people don't go through the same door at
the same time or four people for that
matter because then you can't fit this
guy turns out he's pretty much a perfect
cleric
just about just about so I did some
trading and creative with these guys
to see what the actual ranges are on the
things I guess um
rotten flesh ranges from 36 to 40 so
this is perfect gold 8 to 10 so it's in
the middle redstone you can get between
1 and 4 so this is again perfect lapis I
believe is 1 or 2 I didn't see a three
when I tried it so I think that's
perfect as well possibly unless I missed
it I have the ender I didn't really pay
attention to this but no I saw it
costing 11 a few times so this is
probably a good price too
the only thing that's not quite perfect
is the glowstone unfortunately this can
range from one to three that they will
sell you for one emerald so he's in the
middle I would have really liked if it
was three because then he would be like
perfect perfect this guy it's his only
shortcoming but I'm gonna move this guy
over to my gold farm today I believe try
set up a spot for him we should probably
set up the spot before we move him
though but I'm glad he's alive and well
so let's head over to the gold farm and
we'll do some work on on some things
there so here we are everybody at our
gold farm and this is where we crush and
kill the zombie pigmen to get their
precious gold and then we store it down
below here these chests die just here
two drops I think I heard two Falls
there or did I imagine that that was a
little strange or did a zombie pigmen
fall down
no I don't know what that was
I'll have to rewatch it that I just
heard something strange I guess anyway
uh so looking at this thing you know
it's okay the way it is but we could
improve it quite a bit for one thing it
doesn't make sense for me to collect the
experience here and then I hop down to
the enchanting table and there's no like
there's nothing here to hold books or or
lapis or anything like that so I usually
don't even use this enchanting table
because it's so poorly set up at the
moment I think we should move this up to
here have it right by the ceiling area
and then have a book and a lapis
dispenser sort of thing so we'll do that
I also have to hop down from that portal
to arrive here and when I hop down I
usually take fall damage so we should
deal with that somehow
and I often go up there too to leave
this area so I have to I have to climb
this ladder and then jump across here
and sometimes when I'm feeling the
zombie pigmen there'll be one zombie
pigmen up here that would hop down and
kill me which is really bad this is how
I leave and then I fall in it's it's
messy is what I'm getting it so probably
the first thing we'll do actually we'll
set up a at this dinella Vater to take
us up there I think that would be a good
thing we should like yeah and have
something to dispense instant health
potions as well we should build like a
building or structure around this gold
farm not just have a floating thing up
in the sky like we do at the moment I
think that would be a lot better if we
can do something kind of nice because
that looks really bad maybe even have a
boat elevator to take us up to the
initial platform too but anyway touch is
cheap let me do some things here okay
very good we got our
I'd still care package together here I
believe we can get going on our elevator
and if I figured this out right this is
where we're going to be standing as we
go up at these two missing blocks here
so we'll start it like this we'll have
slime blocks in case we fall we want to
take fall damage and I think if we got
to go here next I might make them few
mistakes here so forgive me if I do I'll
correct them later but I'm going off
from memory and we're going to go for a
6x4
elevator design here there are smaller
ones like that there's a four by five
design that's pretty popular but in this
case I think this will work out better I
hope otherwise I got to make it come out
one more block further if I do the four
by five and even at this we might have
trouble because I'm building as close to
this redstone as possible and the
redstone for my elevator might line up
with this hopefully it doesn't we'll see
how it works out though get a backing on
here all right and then I'll frame in
all this stuff like I'll make it look
like a column or something so you don't
see all the Redstone later um so I think
the way we do this if I didn't remember
something like this I'm just going to do
a little bit on camera and then I'll
finish it up off-camera just to give you
an idea of what I'm doing and how it
works I think we get repeaters at each
of these set to to another one over here
okay and then half slabs and there one
there do like a staircase of half slabs
like that repeater on all these and
they'll stick out hopefully this lined
up okay we'll see in just a second here
go over there whoa I thought it's gonna
fall down that hole that was a close one
oh I think it might work okay let's see
can we get around this might have to do
a bit of messy wiring but I think we
might be able to bypass it yeah that's
good
okay so that's the general idea to it
and then with this design the pistons
extend left and right instead of coming
out this way if they come out this way
they try to push you off so you need to
have a glass backing as well I think
with this one you don't need a glass
backing which is a little nicer as well
but anyway let me do a little bit
off-camera here and hopefully it works
out okay oh yeah we got our elevator
guys the guts of it anyway we might want
to pretty this up and put skin in front
of it of some sort but I haven't fully
decided what kind of blocks we want for
this building we're doing but the way it
works piston pushes this one out I
thought that was a bear as like what was
that noise that confused me for a second
I thought maybe I left the YouTube video
going in the background it's a zombie
pigman anyway so this pushes this out
and then this red clay gets powered from
the back by all this stuff here and it
snakes its way to the top so it goes
then then then then then zigzag all the
way up and that makes us go up and every
every tenth of a second one of these
Pistons will push you up a block so it's
ten blocks per second here we go
I'm still tuning this thing it it
punches me every time like a boxing
glove and slime blocks prevent you from
taking fall damage on the way down so
it's pretty good don't punch me start it
so I found out something cool too if you
don't know this with slime blocks if you
jump right when you hit them
you don't bounce up and you don't have
to wait 10 seconds before you're on the
ground sort of thing so that is pretty
cool you can use it for getting down
because of that like it's it's pretty
easy to do you just have to jump right
as you hit it so that's cool maybe let's
try make this thing stop punching us if
we get just the time is a bit more I
keep hearing zombie pigman suffocating
I'm worried the Redstone is getting
activated over here mmm he seems to have
died getting run quick enough oh it is
getting activated no oh no really I was
sure I did this right where is it where
does that happening I was so careful
guys I swear I went all around the
wiring where is it connecting
I don't think it's connecting anywhere I
think it's is updating the pistons maybe
oh and not down I go be right back
mm-hmm that's what it was guys so this
these hopper timers they are affected by
block updates to the Pistons so when
this is receiving power it's causing an
update to it even though it's two blocks
away because that's the way it works it
is redstone effects up the two blocks
ways anyway I thought about it though it
doesn't really matter I could try to
lower this slab down one block then I'll
have to run the wire a little bit more
crazy again but it really doesn't matter
so I'm not going to bother with it
because I'll kill the zombie pigmen
before I leave the area so I don't have
to worry about the elevator killing them
oh did it really fail that's the first
time I failed I did it Phil
I might have moved or something I don't
know I moved the portal up to here as
well and I worked out another problem I
was having so when I was going through
this this portal here it doesn't take me
on top of my nether because you can't
teleport up to above Y 128 in the nether
so I always would get teleported into
one of these these things and this is
almost like being in a trap if I don't
have ender pearls on my hotbar there is
no easy way out of this night to not
press my inventory selection even so if
they're not on my hotbar I'm pretty much
doomed I have to break the one of these
blocks and fall down basically so to
counter that I decide to put a portal
over here and it seems to do the trick
okay it's a little bit awkward where it
is but it should be fine uh-huh also I
I've been messing around with the slime
block stuff some more just to correct
what I said you don't have to time the
spacebar pressing and just hold spacebar
when you hit this so it doesn't even
take steel it you just hold spacebar if
you don't want to bounce which is pretty
cool so yeah now when we go up
this thing's pretty good though it only
really fails if by I just I should aim
for the slime blocks if I go up right
against the wall on the right side here
but if I'm in the middle or even right
on the left side like all the way here
it seems fine course it will they'll
probably Hut it'll probably give you
trouble in S&P all right so yeah we
takes us to here very good hmm
say hello to your friend so they don't
like each other look at that guy run oh
no no no and he attacks quick doesn't he
first endermite I ever killed amazing
creepers are definitely having trouble
in water
yeah you can barely move so I wanted to
hop down here to get a side profile of
what we've built now that we got the
elevator on because we're at the point
where I I really need to think about a
building plan what is the layout going
to be what blocks are we using like the
style of the building so it is pretty
tall it's going to be a tall building we
don't really need a lot of floor space
so and I think since we used all this
clay let's go for a a somewhat
futuristic look to the building maybe
like some high-tech office space would
be cool and a little bit abstract as
well would be nice mmm you know it would
be cool I think what I want to do let's
do poops
you remember my honeycomb Labs or
beetles lamps from feed the beasts I
think I want to do something similar to
that the hexagon I really like how
hexagons look in Minecraft but instead
of doing Oh
instead of doing the full-blown like
honeycomb layout let's just do like
three hexagons together and see what
that looks like like kind of lay them
out like that um and that might be
pretty cool and have it like go up way
way up to the top of the elevator there
hmm
so I've tried out the hexagons I don't
think it's going to work though I was
trying it here and I decided I want it
to this part of the building to stick
out about up to here right if I did a
hexagon the walls of the hexagon end up
being like from here to here so there's
no I want like a walkway to get to the
other side of the building so that
wasn't really working so instead we're
going for more of a custom shape this is
more like an octagon I I suppose and got
it going around like this and we'll make
go a little bit further and what I want
to do I want to have like windows going
from the ground all the way up to the
top of the building which will probably
be the height of elevator I suppose lots
of open air space don't want to get too
crazy with the details and I suppose do
we just want to to remake it widen out
here I don't know mm let's just keep
going like this or you know what here's
what we'll do let's figure out where we
want the enchanting table so I want some
some free space here because it's where
I like to stand when I'm looking at the
zombie pigmen so maybe 1 2 3 4 5 up to
the chest maybe we'll start the
enchanting area beyond this chest let's
just extend this out and we will lay
down oh you know what oh wait a minute
this is even numbers enchanting areas
are usually odd number base straight
oops
that's not so good maybe instead we'll
have we got to get the villager up here
to is the other thing so maybe we'll
have like we'll split this into two so
on one side like over here we'll have
the enchanting area set up the other
side will have like a villager counter
sort of thing where we can trade them
zombie flesh in that I think that would
be a good way of doing it and that
solves our even number issue I'm just
making the ground all cyan clay right
now I might change it out later to
something else you know what I need I
need a Home Depot guys I'm using up all
my stuff today
ran out of redstone earlier now I'm out
of clay this is like the last my clay so
we can only do a little bit more here
and I'll have to go get more um but
maybe people just try something here see
I want to maybe instead of having all
this clay floor like this plain boring
clay floor we'll try to incorporate some
of this into the flooring and see what
this is like
maybe we'll bring this over Wow well
most likely have a block of something
here to cover up the redstone too so the
path will have one block of clay on the
left and on the right we'll bring this
out Oh
building it's so much fun I never know
what to do let's bring this out so I
feel like I want this to be almost like
a tunnel these side paths that I got and
then this will be a big room and then
we'll have a big room a bigger room over
here for these side paths these tunnels
we won't do too much let's see
where is the middle that's a question
one two three four five six seven eight
nine kinda so two three four five I
think this is sort of the middle right
here alright so maybe let's go out a
little bit with the clay with red clay
get some color in I feel like I want a
window on it maybe or no let's let's go
out one more block like this
aha now we're doing things and we'll get
some clay over here so I brought some
blue stained glass let's see what this
looks like with it
I've tried it with red clay before and I
really liked it but it might just be me
I might be crazy
we'll see let's do a window though this
oh you know what let's let's also do
this two three we'll go up to there for
now see what that looks like go one two
three and we'll put red over top like so
do this okay and then we'll make it Bend
back this way and we'll see what that is
like very futuristic like there's not a
lot of people that have blue stained
glass in their house hmm I feel it needs
some work yet it's not terrible though
let me think about this let me do some
off-camera I got to try to make this
look better so that's how much clay we
have left guys 21 and 12 but I was able
to set up sort of an example of how we
might
do the building here if you guys like
this so red clay blue glass cyan clay
stone maybe maybe the dark oak is well
for furniture and that kind of thing and
we'll have plants as well in here like
clay pots and plants not entirely happy
with this wall I'll probably change it
but yeah we got a gray glass for the
ceiling could work what do you guys
think of that and again like most these
walls will have a lot of windows in so
should look pretty cool
I hope but that's about as far as we can
get with this today you know what let's
look I never to check from over here
that's pretty important what does it
look like from a distance because that's
how we're going to see it most often all
right it's it's so so if I dressed up
the outside like I didn't really pay
attention to the outside whoops yeah
yeah I think that's fine though alright
everybody so let us wrap up this episode
with a comment
this one says hey Ethel I'm sure you
have seen slash her Dinnerbone talking
about maybe redoing PvP after he's done
with the inventory updates is there
anything you would like to be changed
about PvP or is there anything you would
like to see added in the future updates
a very good question I like this one so
yes I think some stuff needs to be
changed the bow mechanics in this game I
feel a really solid I like them a lot
I don't think they need to be adjusted
too much um I don't like the random
damage aspect to combat in this game
like bows and swords both have a random
factor to them I think damage should be
more consistent that would be better I
like like you want it to be predictable
right it being random makes
more fun but I don't think a lot of
people really notice it until light
unless you're watching the the the fight
back frame to frame you you probably
won't notice the random damage so I
don't think it really adds anything to
the game um I feel the bow might benefit
from a bit more accuracy for long-range
shots because at a really long range
shot it's almost like a 1 and a chance
even if it's perfectly lined up just
because the shot sort of goes to the
left or right a bit we're up and down um
which I don't know I think that being
inaccurate is good to an extent but
maybe not to the degree it is I think
they could make it a bit better the big
thing though sort John bat we need to
get rid of this like hack-and-slash spam
clicked as quick as you can thing we got
going in the game because it's pretty
much one guy runs into a guy swinging a
sword the other guy runs back swinging a
sword and it's like a 50/50 exchange use
usually unless somebody gets a jump jump
on the other guy or some guy has a
benefit with the ping or leg or whatever
the big skill involved with swordplay is
keeping your cursor on the guy that's
true and I think that's good people seem
to like strafe around left and right too
but overall it's not I don't feel it's a
really good exchange of blows it's more
oh it's unsatisfying I think they need
to change it so that the tacks are
slowed down a lot more like maybe one
every second or two and you go wait for
the cooldown before you can attack again
yeah and also I think they should
incorporate blocking into combat like if
you're blocking somebody hits you then
it negates the damage you know but again
I think blocking should have a
cool down as well so you can't diss Pam
blocking um and with some mechanics I
think they could work out a pretty good
sword battling system with that the
other big change I would like to see
this is a really simple thing that I
definitely think they should do is make
it so splash potions you can hold right
click wait what would you use to throw I
think it's right click yeah hold right
click to charge up your throw and the
longer you hold it the farther you throw
it so maybe you can throw it up to 32
blocks or maybe a little bit further if
you do a full charge but you can adjust
how far you want to throw it by health
how long you hold right click because as
it is if you're running and you're
throwing damaged potions you run into
them and it's really dumb anyway
those are some of my ideas so that's
going to be it for today's episode guys
I hope you enjoyed it hope you have
yourselves a good day and I will see you
again in the next one bye bye