[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back we are in our
let's play series again guys over at the
mushroom farm this little nasty project
of ours this is supposed to be one of
those eight-hour projects and I'm well
into it now I just redid the water
system so we got two dispensers there
last episode we tried it out with just
one didn't work so added a second one
I'll just jump up here and show you the
wiring because I know I know guys you
can't sleep soundly tonight unless you
see it you must know how it works right
I'm going to show you so basically we
have to power these four dispensers
right so we set repeater going into this
block which then powers this redstone
dust and this is pointing all four
directions of this redstone dust so it
goes to this and this dispenser then
into this block which also powers this
one in this one and then we bolus Lido
through with this repeater now if we
just had like a piece of redstone dust
here for example it wouldn't work
because then this goes up and down it
doesn't go to this dispenser or this one
amazing right you can go to sleep
soundly now all because of me you're
welcome haha I know you don't care
anyways Oh had a redstone problem with
this thing and I could spend thirty
minutes trying to figure it out this the
answer was so simple I just want to
smack my head against the desk like
really so when we went to use this some
of the pistons were getting left in the
wrong spot like they were would stay
over here and some of them were going
down like they're supposed to they were
retracting on these double extenders and
I could not figure out why why were some
working and some were not so I set up a
thing here to try it out and I was
playing with the timings and trying it
out and all seemed good
that's basically what we want to happen
and then I would set it up here and it
wouldn't work and I was like well what's
going on what's what's wrong with this
thing guess what guess what the problem
was some of them had sticky pistons and
some of them didn't that's all it was
and I couldn't see it like this one
didn't get retracted oh I wonder why
because this is not a sticky piston here
supposed to be a sticky piston so simple
anyways I'm going to go and that fix all
these and then this is going to be
pretty close to done then okay very good
very good I think the double extenders
have been fixed we'll test them out in
just two set in we're going to try to
have the whole farm working before we
try it
so we have our bonemeal dispenser thing
that works we tried that before it'll
grow the mushroom then we chopper down
the mushrooms land on the dirt here then
the water streams will will fall down
and push everything towards these holes
all the way down and we set up the
minecart stuff already down here that
runs underneath those those holes so
we'll have hopper minecarts running on
this track and like a bug here is one of
the holes it'll pick it up through the
through the ground and make its way all
the way around the farm the last little
challenge though is we don't have a
start and stop to this minecart track
thing so what we need to do is send like
six or seven hopper mine carts down the
track all at once and then unload them
somewhere and like I would like to do it
like this right but you can't like where
you put the hopper my card in the
dispenser and then when you want to want
to use it you just send it down its way
and it'll pick stuff up and then when
you're done pop into the cactus that
splits minecart Tsin into pieces though
and I was thinking about that today does
anybody actually like that because I
sure don't like that's that's the way
the game has always been and it's like I
can't think of one instance where I
actually prefer it that way I I think
when a hopper minecart it's the
droid I want it to be a hopper minecart
or a storage minecart should stay at
storage minecart otherwise it
complicates things right it limits what
you can do in my opinion so what we're
going to have to do is keep the hopper
minecarts like in their minecart form so
how do we stack six or seven hopper mine
carts together that's what we got to
figure out let's figure it out so I
think I think we can do it like this
let's see what are we doing here
oh I don't want those to connect though
so maybe let's go up one block higher
we'll try drop it on a minecart track
and see if they stayed together or if
they like push each other and not stay
in the spot if you know what I mean
you probably don't you'll see okay so
that's the block back there do we have a
lever we do very good so that should
drop it down and they'll stack together
the question is do they stay in that
spot or does them being together push
them down the track we want them to stay
in the spot it looks like they're going
to stay in the spot okay good that's
what we want and then when we tell them
to go do they all go together because
that's also what we want they do okay
good actually before we commit to that
idea let's test it for realsies here on
our actual track we will let out six six
hopper mine cards here all in the same
spots and then we'll turn it on the
reason I want to try it out here is
because this is all very time-sensitive
this micro track this detector rail
flips the junction for just a certain
amount of time and possibly having six
of them together here we'll mess that up
yeah that's what I was afraid of huh so
they're moving faster now because
they're together what do we do about
that okay maybe we'll try to keep them
minecart separate after all keeping them
separate we're less likely to have
trouble but it'll take up more space and
be slightly more complicated but yeah I
want to try something out here if we put
cobble in this one and then we put
coarse dirt in there and let's put
regular dirt in this one let's let's see
if we can unload through the slab here
break that one break that one break that
one okay so they're going to be on top
of each other like that Pez dispensers
style then Oh
oh yeah they all owe ya that works out
really good actually because they all
drain to the bottom one right and then
if if they can get picked up through a
hopper here yeah oh that will work out
just fine yes not as complicated as I
thought so then then we just want to
send one off all we got to do is this so
why did that get moved okay I guess
we're gonna have to have blocks
surrounding this too because this should
have dropped on the slab and it didn't
alright everybody so that is the idea
we're going to go with here I got the
PEZ dispenser stack setup so let's try
it out make sure it works
for realsies so I left a little bit of
space in k-6 minecarts is not enough we
might be able to do seven or eight let's
go for six right now so those all line
up nicely in our our Pez stack here and
then we'll have some way of activating
this such as a button it only lets one
through and start it is it still going
too fast what's going on here oh man
like I tested that all out before let's
try now watch
uh-huh there we go
okay something has changed in the latest
snapshots definitely mine carts are not
moving at the same speed anymore okay
never mind
I just realized what's wrong it's
because when I tested this I wasn't
using hopper mine carts I was using
regular mine carts which if you didn't
know actually move slower a lot slower
okay actually made it through okay yeah
it was regular mine carts that's what it
was all configured for so I'm going to
have to make some adjustments okay so no
big deal really I just got to replace
these three power rails with regular
rails and that seems to slow it down
enough and don't have to make any major
adjustments here happy about that okay
so I think our goal with this mushroom
farm guys is to get it down to two
button presses the first one will
activate the mushrooms growing so it'll
activate these bone meal dispensers will
grow the mushrooms chop them down and
then after they're chopped down we press
the button the second button that will
activate the water streams to collect
all the drops together and then those
water streams will hopefully
automatically retract after a certain
amount of time but also that second
button press we want to activate our
minecart thing here now we don't want to
press the button six times like if we
have six hopper mine carts here right so
we need to do something a little bit
fancy with the redstone my plan is to
set up a tripwire thing here we will
detect if there's any mine cards here
and when they're all gone then we shut
shut this off we're going to set up a
clock that runs to activate this piston
that's that's the dream here so let's
see if we can do this quickly all right
get some string there can we place the
string where the minecarts are I don't
think so oh please
[Music]
I don't know I don't think it's
happening guys we might have to bust
them all yeah most likely anyways what
we'll do is then put a torch this is
going to have to go to a monostable
circuit so the stare into the monostable
circuits then we want a T flip-flop that
this thing controls so set a repeater to
one tick like a so and I think we'll
Bend back this way now this will go to a
sticky piston with a redstone block so
depending on if this block is extended
or retracted it will turn the clock on
or off which will activate this so the
clock we want to lock I think will go
over here it'll activate this redstone
dust will shut which will shut the clock
off I think probably a two two by four
clock will be big enough yeah let's put
a redstone torch here and then three
repeaters well set these at four just to
begin with but we'll probably be able to
shorten the time on this to like we
don't want to send all the minecarts at
once because then they'll bump into each
other too you know we have to space them
out a little bit which is why why we
want this clock here yeah and then this
will go to that and send off the
minecarts then when they're all gone
this will shut off I think it might
actually be set right right now if if
the tripwire was there anyway let's see
what happens uh-huh
they're actually getting sent pretty
quickly aren't they oh it's the well
they're bouncing backwards I know that's
what I was afraid of so I probably sent
them too quickly there okay I think this
is good to go now guys I got rid of the
redstone torch that was here put a
redstone dust there and I made the clock
a little bit bigger too so there should
be more spacing between the minecarts
and I put a redstone torch here so this
is retracted by default so this is our
startup the way they look to actually
start this thing we sent one redstone
pulse to this piston so I got a button
here to do that and that should send the
mic rats on their way that'll activate
the clock right yeah now that's a really
long time ago I put a redstone torch
there before that's that's why it's so
fast and this clock should run until
they come back then this will get
extended again oh is that a problem
wait a minute wait a minute it'll take
them a little while to get back here so
I'll just throw one in oh yeah that
retracts that piston over there okay so
we're good so it's it's back the way it
was at the starts until we press this
button again alright so we got this
working like I wanted to and like we saw
before if that top minecart has
mushroomed blocks in they will funnel
all the way down to the bottom and
that's where we have two hopper here so
it's going to pull items out of this
bottom line kurtz and go into that chest
and i've added on to the puzzle over
here another piece that we will check
out this will fill up with mushroom
blocks and we have the storage minecart
here and you can see it's within range
it'll you'll get the items so that's
good this is something I'm actually very
proud of I for the longest time
struggled with figuring out how to
detect when a minecart is full or detect
when it's half-full or whatever this can
do it and this is a very compact way of
doing it - I would say so basically this
block keeps the minecart from rolling
down the hill here it's on a detector
rail and if a storage minecart is on a
detector rail you can use a comparator
to figure out what or how much stuff is
inside so there's nothing in right now
this is off if we put a little bit of
stuff in this will turn on probably with
the signal strengths of one as it fills
up the streets
signal strength gets stronger this is in
subtract mode at a power level of 15
because the levers right back there oh
well there goes my cards so if this is
at 15 and this gets to 15 15 - 15 0 and
then this retracts aha let's go catch up
to it so this tunnel here goes down to
the super smeltery building we finished
that just last episode and now we have
the the furnace fuel our mushroom farm
thing pretty much all done now this over
here is the Nexus by the way that we
just passed under oh don't don't bump me
back now that doesn't look quite right
it's a visual click temperature okay
we're almost there anyways so this goes
up to the internal workings of the super
smell tree it's over here and to an
unloading go for saf here okay tell you
what I'll just put a block here while
while we talk so no creepers sneak in
but yeah the micro comes up to here to
this unloading system goes right into
the chest and this chest has hoppers
that go to these chests over here
anyways I think this is going to be the
big moment now guys this is where we try
it out so we've added a lot of stuff on
to this thing since the last test
there's a good chance something will go
wrong but I don't want anything to go
wrong we wanted to work flawlessly so
here we go first step grow the mushrooms
that's so cool
oh man it causes so much lag though to
see uh-huh I think they're just about
all done yeah so we're gonna have to
keep that lever flip for quite a while
it seems yeah the last thing to do with
this farm is to like do something about
these loose wires the redstone we want a
control panel somewhere that has these
in all nicely situated you know we have
three wires that's kind of randomly
placed right now which isn't so nice
anyway so we grow the mushrooms now we
run along here and I wonder how much
your ability to take off our axe
probably quite a bit but chop them all
down
and this is something we won't have to
do very often I don't because we are
going to get that Sun from this oh I
fall down okay so the finish chopping
both sides
I guess maybe there's another step I
didn't synched up with this let's sleep
real quick I think we got to eject the
mushroom stems actually before we do the
water so we are going to press this
button this is something I'm very scared
about I think that works doesn't look
like they glitched out and then I have
to run down the middle here and get rid
of all this loose garbage but I leave
these two blocks there Oh some of them
are still glitching oh that one didn't
work for some reason okay this one
didn't work for some reason this one
didn't work for some reason no I don't
know why I'm just seeing there's got to
be a problem with the wires didn't go
all the way or something tell you what
yeah we're having an issue we're having
a big issue I think I might have broke
the wire at some point when we were when
I was trying to get this to work let's
just double-check somewhere down this
main line yeah right here okay whoo easy
fix
okay we're really pushing the
five-minute D spot on on these items
we're going to have to hurry here so
just finished chopping us all down all
the mushrooms now because it was messed
up
at first there this won't happen again
just this time because it was messed up
and I replaced these blocks so the water
doesn't wash our mushrooms away okay so
now we do the water screams now
hopefully these are good we want
everything to go down the middle there's
gonna be
few blocks on the on the side here
that's fine this is looking very good
okay so they all watch to like over here
see them down there and now we want the
minecart to pick them up through the
block that's the next really Oh their D
spawning No
okay okay we got to go here what's the
minecart one oh it's this button over
here right okay that'll send the
minecarts yeah okay long story short
here this did not work very good all the
minecarts got stuck for some reason
possibly because I decided to shorten
this delay I'm going to extend it again
ah man
okay so I just did another full run I
grew the mushrooms I chopped them down
did the water stream thing and then when
the minecarts went they got jammed again
like the first one picked up a few
blocks but I don't know what happened
because I did a dry run with this longer
delay and it worked absolutely
flawlessly and now that we're actually
picking up items it got stuck and I
don't know why all right let's run
another test here the one ID I haves
maybe mine carts move faster if they
have items inside I know that was true
at one point like when they were when
they did the SuperSpeed minecart
snapshot the more items you had in the
minecart the faster they moved those
look pretty neck-and-neck to me this
one's not full of stuff though let's put
more in
ya know they seem to go to the same
speed I don't know why it's Jamie no
clue I haven't changed anything here but
we're gonna do another dry run just to
see what's going on see if you get the
jams and if it does why so here we go
like once one of them jams they all Jam
that's that's an issue I've noticed but
why are they jamming like there's a huge
space between them there's no way
they're gonna run into each other uh-huh
uh-huh now that it doesn't oh how did it
catch up okay well that's the problem
why did it catch up I don't understand
oh there was some items on the track is
it when it picks up items it speeds up
but in the moment it picks them up let's
do another test okay to mine carts both
of them empty we'll start them out empty
then I'll throw something on the track
and see if their distance changes so
okay nothing happened
I threw it directly into it though what
if we throw it on the track nothing
happens okay what if it picks it up
through the ground like it's doing in
the farm and nothing happens what is
going on guys this is crazy I can't
figure it out I don't think it's I don't
think it's item related I think I don't
know I don't know what I think anymore
like that one was going so fast right
when I collided with other one why does
it get such a speed boost Oh actually we
can do it like this yes okay
this will be fine I mean put a repeater
down here and then we can bridge the gap
like this so instead of doing this big
fancy rail thing like
are doing or just going to make the rail
go in a straight line because rails are
evil today for some reason
so we're ripping out this section here
and it's not going to do the bet the
bouncing back and forth thing anymore
it's going to go in a straight line so
this gets replaced this gets broken we
bridge the gap here the reason I didn't
do it like it like that before was
because we had redstone here I thought
it would be a problem but all we got to
do is break this go down one blocks and
that's it's pretty simple that's not a
repeater there we go all right guys well
I think we are going to wrap up the
episode for today here it's it's about
that time to do so so I'll finish up the
rest of that off-camera I showed you
pretty much everything I wanted to today
though just fixing and stuff to do yet
and then we can finally move on to some
new projects I feel like we've been
working on that super smell tree and the
mushroom farm for so many episodes now
but I just sets the price you know you
guys always want me to finish projects
it takes a long time if I don't skim
over things it actually takes a really
long time to finish some of these things
but I had some fun with the minecart
mechanics today hopefully you guys
enjoyed that and let's get to the
comments of the day it says are you
trying something different with your
voice or microphone because you used to
sound deeper and smoother now you sound
kind of uppity and dorky yeah just got
off of a long shift so maybe it's just
me aha so I haven't changed anything
with the microphone at all so if I sound
different it's because I'm speaking
differently probably a lot depends a bit
upon like what time of day I'm recording
if I'm recording in the morning I
usually sound drained or worn out
deeper voice later in the day I have
more energy generally and I'm not
stuffed up and stuff oh hello
also depends on my mood and stuff I know
sometimes when I go to record I can
barely string together a sentence other
times it's smooth and fluent sing
yeah I don't know I wish it could be
perfect all the time but I'm not perfect
so anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and I'll see you again in the next one
take care bye bye
[Music]