[Music]
oh
i would say about six months ago i hit
rock bottom everybody i was in a bad
situation
had a tough choice ahead of me what was
that gonna do
what would you do i had to decide that
right then and there
was i gonna go shulker box hunting or
was i prepared to stick it out and wait
for the update to come out and then i
could get them easily and just farm them
ultimately i chose the lazy option and
waited
so i've had very few shulker boxes the
last uh last little while in my let's
play series
here and today we are going to head to
the end and we are going to go do some
shocker box hunting that's what i want
to do i'm pretty excited about this
actually
a couple things i want to try out with
it oh
oh careful oh not so far we actually
have to do some stuff here
uh okay let's go through one of these
portals actually no wait first
first everybody let me tell you just in
case you don't know the story
right over here is the wall so this is
our end
mapped out the way i've been doing this
is every time i go
in city rating you can see the purple
dots over there
i've mapped out the ends just so that i
don't accidentally cover the same area
twice because that is very frustrating
if you're
looking for end fortresses and then you
find one and you're so excited and
then it's like oh i've been to this one
already so each of these is about two
thousand by two thousand and you can see
i actually haven't done
too much uh rating honestly for uh
how much i play in the world here and uh
you know you would expect more but i
just don't
really like doing it too much part of
the reason for that is i'm trying to
keep my world small but also like i do
enjoy the end fortress rating it's the
flying around trying to find them part i
don't really
care for though and that's like you
spend at least three times the
the amount of time looking for the
fortress and actually reading it i find
which isn't the most exciting thing uh
but yeah we found a new one over here
it's got guys inside what we're gonna
try to do today
is uh play around with the whole farming
thing
so i got him to hit himself there but he
did not duplicate i don't quite know how
this mechanic works
but apparently if you can get them to
shoot themselves they have a chance of
like
duplicating and then they teleport so
what we gotta do is get them to
shoot themselves oh it just happened
yeah shoot themselves when they're
when they're opened up like that if
they're closed i don't think it can
happen
okay so this is going to be a little bit
tricky actually
it seems like there's four conditions
that have to be met for this
so one of them the lid has to be open as
we discovered already
the other one is if they are at less
than half their health there's a 25
chance it's just gonna fail so you want
them to be at full life
otherwise they'll teleport without
creating a new one third one is they'll
they have to teleport within a 17 by 17
by 17
area and if that fails uh four times
i believe then uh it just doesn't happen
what if we do this uh and the final one
is each shulker box within like an eight
block area lowers the chances by
20 for each one so if you have five
shulker boxes within eight blocks of
each other
it doesn't create any new ones putting
them in boats seems like it might be a
good idea i'm just like in the thinking
phase right now how are we gonna build
our farm let's
do a little bit of experimenting and i
decided let's actually just hop into a
creative world here because it'll make
it so much easier to test because
shulkers are
very difficult to control in survival as
you can see they're not affected by
slime blocks my idea here was maybe
let's put a snow golem
to shoot at the guy and
if this is extended the snow golem can't
see him right chalker can't see the snow
golem
but then when we retract it
i thought we would get him to shoot him
and then like slime block the
projectile into the shulker get him to
shoot himself that way
but it seems like the shulker shot
doesn't bounce off the slime block it
just uh
it just breaks it so that's that's a
no-go idea okay so i just discovered
another important thing here
shulker boxes must be able to open
without ramming into another shulker
um so if we do this and they are both
opening sideways that is fine nothing
wrong with that
if we have a guy going upwards opening
upwards like that
and the other guy above him
oh wait i guess if there's a guy above
him he'll prefer to attach to the side
but if there's no option if he must
attach downwards
then he teleports water test
they don't like water lava tests
hey oh no never mind magma test
oh they're okay with magma now i get
this a lot where people want to see the
behind the scenes like how do you come
up with your farm ideas how do you come
up with your redstone contraptions
and most of it is this little bunch of
trial and error testing things out and
then once you understand all the
mechanics to how something works you can
start
formulating a plan they do not like with
the roses
uh-huh so we're learning things here oh
darn it i thought maybe we could use the
water to get him to shoot himself
okay so we got some weird stuff going on
here water for sure does
move the projectiles we got a bubble
column in front of us and when the
projectile goes into that it gets
launched upwards
i was trying to figure out a way we
could get the shulker to see us without
actually being able to shoot us so i
thought yes walls put some walls in
front of him
he'll be able to see us through that but
his projectile won't be able to hit us
right
well funny thing about these projectiles
is normally they move block to block
but then sometimes they have like a
super precision mode
they go into and they can actually sneak
through things like that
oh he got him and he got him
it did not work at all
oh man we might be getting somewhere
with this so check it out we got a trap
door and from the snow going which we
can turn on and off with redstone to
turn our farm on and off
and we got enchanting table there it's
just short enough where he can still hit
the shulker
and then the only open side for the
shulker to shoot is behind himself
and if it travels at least two blocks he
can hit himself
so as the projectile tries to go back to
the snowglobe he hits himself
and you see the snow golems focused on
this guy that's the one that actually
was there before
so this new guy has full health again
and he reacquires a target on that guy a
new one
and we can have some way of killing the
guys that teleport out
outside the farm the only
issue there's a few of them
uh if the shocker hits himself too many
times without actually duplicating
i think he can kill himself still no
yeah that's what i was afraid of so we
might need a healing station to keep the
guy topped off if he fails too many
times
oh snappers okay it looks like we might
actually have something that works here
believe it or not so i've been doing
some tweaking with this i did add a
healing station to it so that's running
at
five snowballs at the moment basically
we're gonna need some auto brewer
to keep this thing filled up with
instant health have to run it pretty
quickly though
because this shulker does so much damage
to
itself um regen potions weren't able to
keep up
past the instant health or regen too
maybe would work
but uh not just regular regen
so we flip up the trap door there got
rid of the enchanting table now this the
snow golem can seem a lot easier
shoots a lot faster and
after the guy teleports out there's like
a five seconds before he
acquires a new target again he's looking
at that guy over there and then he
switches to the new guy
uh-huh we'll need some way of dealing
with the guys that teleport outside of
there some way of killing them or maybe
i'll just run around doing it i don't
know yet
but uh yeah it's working pretty good i
think it's a foolproof system now
because if
his health can't go below half there's
no way for him to teleport out of there
there's no way for him to kill himself
so i don't think it'll mess up right
please oh and you see that so there is
sometimes where the shot will actually
go through the shulker which is kind of
weird so we have this bubble column as a
safety so there's no way for
him to actually hit the snow golem
because it'll like launch it up to the
roof and then it pops it cool so i think
we got our duplicator figured out now we
move on to
the collection and killing now option a
we can just run around killing them
ourselves which is what we might end up
doing
but uh it would be nice to come up with
some automatic methods right so i
noticed one thing here if you have a
minecart under a tripwire uh the
tripwire doesn't detect that
but it will detect a shulker box in the
minecart
so maybe we use that for something
one idea like this will bounce back and
forth right and then when a shocker
comes within a block of the track guess
what
we can detect that and then uh send them
off somewhere
another option is we can set up a bunch
of nether portals and they'll
automatically teleport
into the portal and end up in one spot
in the nether which i think is what a
lot of people have been doing but i kind
of want to keep this all within one
dimension if possible
so we might just do something like this
have the tracks two blocks apart from
each other
and then as the minecart goes here it's
going to pick up the closest one to it
and then i had an idea
of a way we can kill them then so this
will collect them all together
and so shockers will teleport out of uh
water right but if they're in a minecart
they're not able to
haha so we can actually suffocate them
this way
and then after enough suffocation
they'll die
their shelter shells will float up to
the top of the water
makes a cool sound looks awesome
it's probably my favorite thing about it
uh and the minecarts will
slowly sink down so we can maybe use a
tripwire to detect when uh
they're all gone or something when
they're all dead and then
trigger this so this is a trick you can
do with mine carts they will actually
teleport through a block
through a half slab so if we
switch this over they'll actually
teleport through that and then ram them
into a cactus and send them back to the
start or something
the main issue with these shulkers is
they're very difficult to kill i think
the water is the only thing i found that
works
i thought this might work because he's
kind of touching the lava right
but uh nope yeah i always thought magma
cubes were the hardest mob to kill in
the game but i think
actually it's shulkers because like you
can't suffocate them
you can't even handle these guys i've
tried the drip stone that didn't work
it's like they're indestructible they
don't take fall damage what are you
supposed to do
uh tnt probably the other best option
but they are extremely tanky like that's
a pretty small area it covers
anyways let's get back to the let's play
world now so we've done our research we
know what will work what won't work
and kind of figured out the main pieces
to making
a farm that'll actually function right
now we did not actually build the farm i
didn't build it and test it out or
anything and usually i don't like to do
that i don't like to
pre-build stuff in creative and like
know exactly how it works i like to do
that in the episodes just because i
think it makes
you know things a bit more exciting i
gotta figure stuff out as we go still
i don't know the full picture just yet
and stuff can go wrong sometimes the
stuff i build in the let's play episodes
don't work as good as they could if i
actually
took time to refine the idea right but
overall i think it's just better that
way so
we could for example let's start
figuring this out
we could haul a shulker all the way to
the overworld and that would probably be
the nicest thing
but from a practical standpoint like if
someone else wants to
make a shulker farm i think what i want
to do with this one is
just set it up right here like the most
practical thing is we got the chalkers
here already
we got the end ship right it's a away
from the land we don't have to worry
about them teleporting
outside of the area here
this is gonna be a problem uh
we kind of got everything we need right
here so let's build it
right here you know so i'm gonna start
bulldozing this and setting up our snow
golem
i'm gonna get rid of that guy right
there yeah
i don't think we need him we got two
guys downstairs okay this might be the
toughest part we're gonna try
transfer them where we want them to be
i'm gonna break them out of the boat
and they're right next to each other so
i'm gonna get one of them to move
and then we know he'll attach to
a side of a block so then we're free to
break that and it'll stick to the side
i want him sitting on the dispenser
we're gonna heal him with
and then we're free to break that okay
and now we're just gonna keep him
enclosed so that he stops shooting me
while i
build the rest of the farm here awesome
okay so check it out we got most of the
boat bulldozed now
and uh just been using the bottom of it
as a platform as i've been building the
main unit here so this is the most
important part of the farm
you really don't want to mess this up so
i built it exactly like we built it in
creative
piece to peace uh we got some trap doors
where the snow golem is that's because
it is possible for the shulker to
teleport where the snowglobe is
and then uh creates a bit of a problem
but you know what i realized uh we got a
bit of a flaw here actually because
we got to make sure every single surface
is a teleport proof that's going to be
the really annoying thing about this
farm
so it's possible the shocker could
teleport like right over there
above itself and then not be in the
right position or
uh i think you could teleport along the
face of that as well
so we want to prevent that from
happening we got to be careful as we do
this that he doesn't uh
start shooting at us or shooting himself
and i'm gonna put some buttons in there
so now he can't teleport
in that space at all and we're gonna put
one above them as well but first
actually just to be safe here i did do a
trip back to the base and grab some
potions and stuff
hopefully he that reached him i don't
know if it did
um i just want to make sure if he does
shoot himself i think he's getting low
that he doesn't kill himself because uh
it's gonna be very difficult to get a
new guy in that spot
and this isn't gonna look the best but
we also gotta make sure we
buttonize the outside here or make it so
they can't teleport to the glass on the
outside of the unit because
again they check eight blocks around
themselves that there's any shockers and
if they're sitting on the glass out here
it's going to lower the rates of our
farm
so we gotta teleport proof everything
here
and put some trapdoors on the bottom
layer just so i can still walk
no don't shoot him
no stop it the farm's not ready
oh no this is so stressful i was trying
to add an on off switch for the the
hopper clock below we got a hopper clock
running down here
they group frenzy it seems like when
they when they hit a target
all the shulkers in the area seem to go
for that target oh man yeah this is
tricky
i guess uh we can't use moving redstone
for
our farm at all i was going to send the
signal down to the hopper clock here
to turn the healing station on and off
but uh
if you think about it i can protect it
right now i put end rods all around it
nothing can teleport onto the block
or underneath it but once that retracts
there's going to be one spot where they
can teleport
on the bottom of the redstone block and
there's nothing i can do about that
so we just we just can't use moving
redstone
we gotta think of something else here
yeah so the trapdoor that lets the
snowglobe shoot the shulker is right
underneath that purple block we gotta
keep that powered when the farm is off
so we got a redstone torch there just
for now and then it staircases down to
the hopper clock
keeps that powered so it's not running
wasting potions when the farm
is off right so once that line gets
unpowered the farm turns on basically
now this is the stinky part
i should have just killed all the
shockers and left that one because these
guys
are gonna cause some problems now i
think i gotta get rid of him
but now this guy's frenzy yeah he's
shooting
oh no no no no no don't shoot yourself
how did i get hit no this is not the
time
so if i get unlucky here he's gonna kill
himself
no dude
uh what do i do i gotta leave the area i
think
i just gotta leave the area yeah always
get rid of all the shockers
this is so bad i think if i leave the
area he loses
target and then it'll stop shooting i
hope
otherwise we got a big issue here please
don't be dead
i don't know how i'm going to get
another guy in there if it happens
like i'll probably have to do something
with minecarts and
yeah i don't know
wait did he create a new one no don't
create new ones no that's just a regular
chalker okay
i don't want to attack them because then
this guy's gonna get frenzied again
right so i think what we
wait i don't know if they get frenzied
if one guy just shoots at me
doesn't look like it this guy's not not
shooting
but if i attack this guy up here we're
gonna have that problem again oh i got
hit
so what i want to do is boat them
i mean the boat nope yeah as long as i
don't attack them the other guy doesn't
get mad at me okay that's good i'm just
gonna
boat them out of here get them off the
platform with this guy
and uh now all the stray shelters should
be off of the boat there
cool so i think we got this main unit
finished this is what it's looking like
it's a bit uh pimply a little bit measly
but i think it should work fine we got
the hopper clock down below there i put
slabs underneath it so nothing can
teleport on the bottom of anything we've
built here
you can see even underneath here we got
buttons and stuff and rods
uh just so that every single surface is
covered and there's nowhere for them to
teleport wait a second missed one
uh so now the main thing that can
probably
wreck our farm is if it runs out of
potions while it's running
uh then this guy will stop getting
healed and he's gonna either kill
himself or teleport out of there
so we're adding a lock so when this
hopper runs out of potions
this torch turns on and then we're going
to send the signal to our on off switch
for the farm here
and that'll keep the farm shut down
okay so now we gotta figure out how and
where we're gonna build our platform for
these guys to teleport to
and according to the minecraft wiki like
we said before they check an eight block
area around them
when they duplicate and every shulker in
that area lowers the chance of it
happening
by twenty percent which is a big deal
that means we want this guy to teleport
outside of that eight block range
it's also why we're buttoning everything
so no shulkers will be within that eight
block range
so he's there one block two blocks
three blocks i think this is four five
six seven
eight one more for good measure i don't
know
i think over here is where we want our
platform
if i didn't misunderstand anything here
and they can teleport up to 17 blocks if
i understand right
so we might need to build multiple
platforms as the other thing so when
they teleport they try four times if
they don't find a spot
it fails which means the more
area they have to teleport to the more
likely it will succeed
and the more likely when the shulker
shoots himself he'll duplicate and the
farm will run
faster so i don't know if one platform
is enough to make this run at
the optimal rate i don't know if we're
even going to aim for the optimal rate
because it's a single player
and i don't really care about getting
thousands of shulkers
i just need a few stacks you know oh
snap okay my reading comprehension
skills might not be the best i was like
laying out the platform here and it's
like there's no way
they can teleport this big of an area
right this is a 17 block radius
so i double check the wiki and it says
it's 17 by 17 by 17
centered on the shop here
which means diameter uh in other words
i don't know if they're even gonna be
able to teleport that far up there
because that's like at the ninth block
and they might only be able to teleport
eight blocks
which means they'll be within range
of the 20 failure thing or whatever i
don't know
we just got to try this out and see what
happens because i'm at the point where
i'm not quite sure on a couple things
now this is where the farm is very
likely to break first time testing it
we can only run it for a couple seconds
here and we're gonna run out of potions
but we'll see
what happens with this
oh man please don't die please don't die
see if anybody's appearing up here
not looking good oh no
all right i think we should shut it down
yeah i think we got to build the
platform closer
shut her down now he's going to keep
shooting for a bit i think hopefully
he's got enough health where he doesn't
kill himself
is closed right yeah he's keeps shooting
for a while after
he can't get him there now he gave up
okay good
so we didn't get anybody
right yeah nobody up here test number
two all right so we lowered the platform
here by block we filled it out this is
the full 17 by 17 area
and it should be on the very edge of the
cuboid target we need to reach here so
they should be able to teleport up there
now
uh we got a couple things to check out
first just to make sure that actually
happens
check if this guy somehow can still kill
himself
we gotta check if uh oh i heard a
teleport
we gotta check if more than five guys
can spawn up here
or if they're preventing more from
spawning
we gotta see the rates of this so far we
only got one
so this guy's gonna be aiming at the
snow golem actually which is interesting
now i think you switched targets to me
yep
move uh up these shots though we're at
the snow going
did he die is he still there you still
alive
okay that's good oh yeah we gotta double
check that the farm will actually shut
down when it runs out of potions because
oh we got another one okay still got a
few left there but yeah the rates
aren't the greatest we might need more
platforms to increase the area
okay he's still shooting now he's
stopped okay he's good he's good
so we got to build an auto brewer here
yeah it's out of potions
i think we should test that just a
little bit longer before we commit on
how we're gonna do the platform and the
auto brewer and all that stuff so
we got the lab running right now and
we're gonna just do one more manual
refill
and good stuff all right so we got this
topped off with potions we can run it
for a bit longer
and see how things go here but i want to
try one more thing here
so i gotta admit i didn't know shocker
frenzy was a thing before today even
that's new to me uh i'm wondering if
those guys are far enough away where
this guy down here doesn't get frenzied
if i
i kill him i'm gonna give him my hits if
he gets frenzied i'm gonna turn the farm
on real quick so it
doesn't take damage okay we
hit him is he mad yeah he's mad so the
range is like insane
did he kill the golem the golem's dead
how what
all right we got a new problem that's
not good
yeah it's just one of those things you
know i left it running for over half an
hour off camera
and it never killed the golem not once
and then once you go and build it
it's like hey guess what uh
what are we gonna do about that so i
think i want to
[Music]
get rid of this trapdoor that's our on
off normally
we're gonna be moving that uh can i
break this safely yes
i'm gonna put a solid block there and i
think we wanna lower the golem
so when this is closed the golden can't
see the shocker he's gonna be
standing right here when it's opened he
should be able to peek through that i
think
golem tackle yes got him
okay i'm gonna put a block above the
trap door that's gonna be our new on off
there okay should be fixed what a
disaster
uh you know i'm very happy actually
though i'm surprised this guy hasn't
had any problems like he hasn't
teleported out of there he hasn't died
i built it near the fortress here
because i i wanted some backups nearby
because i thought for sure
like if anything was to go wrong it
would be that guy disappearing on us
which might still happen we'll see but
essentially what we've done here
oh i thought he had to just teleport
he's fine
he duplicated what we've done is we've
narrowed the gap there where the bullet
can actually squeeze through
so now it should be nearly impossible
right
like it's really it's really launching
up now not even close to getting through
that
how are we doing oh we got another
duplication so we got probably four or
five guys up there now
i'm trying to see if we can get past the
five point first five the limit
oh he didn't make another one wait a
second
i thought we were at the cap there
oh it's still going
come on go i'm gonna go check i'm gonna
keep my distance though
i mean we got up there one two three
four five okay so it's still only five
i'm trying to see if it'll go to six
wait was there six
i can't count three four four five six
yeah there's six up here so
i don't think these guys are within
range where they're stopping spawns then
no he's not in there what happened i
leave him for a second
no and the golem died what
oh no this is not working guys so i'm
guessing what happened there
is the farm ran out of potions and then
it like went into shutdown
but he kept shooting like two or three
more times after it was shut down like
like they do it takes like five seconds
for them to stop shooting
probably hit himself every single time
and then just got unlucky with it
uh and he he probably teleported up here
or something i don't know
that's my guess here's my plan so i've
got slabs underneath here
slabs above
what happens when we try to get him out
of the boat now it's too far from the
teleport up here
that's the only spot available will he
go there
we'll find out if i can never get down
no that's a slap you can't you can't do
that that's cheating oh no
what i didn't know they could do that
i've never seen that before he's on a
slab
just floating there what a guy oh i
missed
oh any teleport wait what i think i
checked that spot and there was a button
there
oh i got the boat yes okay no no no no
oh he broke the boat again yeah okay we
got one we got one
let's drive quickly no oh he got killed
got him go go go go go go get away
no got hit where is it where is it
why are you taking damage ah i was so
close
hey we're gonna scoop in swoop in grab
yeah okay and zoom get out of here quick
no he's getting hit oh man
we can make it just being you buddy
yes okay we got a second try with this
okay he's out let's see where this one
goes
what are you gonna do now
oh don't shoot each other they will not
oh we got him yes it worked
what oh he teleported to the shocker and
i think he went up to the top there
all right we had a bit of a hiccup there
but we got the guy back inside and it
wasn't
actually all that difficult so as long
as we just like
bring a shocker down here and like break
them out of a boat or a mine cart
then uh they'll be forced to go in there
so that's not too too big of an issue uh
we're gonna move on with this
i haven't given up don't worry uh i
don't know how to solve the golem
dying problem i don't know what's
causing it exactly we just gotta run the
farm longer to
see which means we should really need
that auto brewer set up
and stuff uh but what i'm working on
right now
is the collection system so i think this
is how we're gonna do the track
let's run it like this and basically
we'll send a minecart down here it'll go
zip around
and be able to pick up from all these
squares i think
and then it will exit over here and
either go down a layer if we want to add
more layers
or it's gonna go into our water killing
chamber probably
uh what i'm trying to decide is do i
want to
cover this because i don't like them
shooting at me
it's not that fun uh we might like go up
like
that and maybe a slab on top like that
and like do a 17x17 they won't be able
to teleport
under this or above it and then
we could maybe have trapped doors on the
side here i don't want them to be able
to stick to anything right so we gotta
build out of stuff they can't stick to
so we might do something like yeah like
this
that would have to go up three blocks i
guess
and then this will meet up with it here
uh-huh okay i think this is a good
improvement so they shouldn't be able to
shoot out of here randomly anymore like
they were before
uh they were always trying to hit the
snow golem after they would teleport and
the shots were just like flying
everywhere all right we got our
collection system set up
next comes the killing system for
getting rid of the shulkers collecting
their drops
and i think i got a great idea now
actually i thought about it some more
we're gonna call this the conveyor of
death
i think this is a really clever idea
actually so instead of doing a vertical
water column that we drown them in and
like having to
bring them up and then drop them down
into the water and like have redstone to
control the timings on everything and
all that stuff i came up with an idea
here that
should be fully automatic doesn't
require redstone
takes very little space it's horizontal
instead of vertical
and just basically better in every way
so that's the plan i'm gonna put up a
glass wall here
actually we probably need more hoppers
so the idea is we're gonna have hoppers
under all these slabs
where did we leave off right over there
yeah then we will
careful i don't accidentally drop myself
down there
and we'll have like a big chain of
hoppers going along the whole thing here
so those hoppers are going to pick up
the shocker shells that drop and we're
going to have a nice window here for
viewing the action
what we'll do is set up uh what are we
gonna do here we're gonna get a sign
just to stop the water over at the end
we'll have one water source down here
this is gonna travel i think five blocks
yeah and then we'll have one more at
this end
this should go eight yeah i'll overlap
the other one there
and i think i want one more slab
here all right here it comes and it
falls down
and it's going to glide along the water
very slowly
and i time this in creative it's going
to be just enough time where a shulker
at full life
will drown by the time it gets the end
of the conveyor of death here
and it kind of self regulates the
timings on the mine carts and everything
we're gonna have a bunch of mine carts
going through here
shelters will die they'll drop their
shells hoppers will pick them up
and then when it gets to the very end it
just continues on its cycle
and picks up the next chalkers that
might spawn in the room there
right does this work please
there's a hopper at the very bottom
there too yeah it's gonna go and
pick up another one if there are any if
there aren't it doesn't matter it'll do
the cycle anyway
so unfortunately i have spent a ton of
time on this and we're running out of
time in the episode so we need to think
about
wrapping up for today which means we
probably can't get around to making the
auto brew of this episode
but i did go for another load to fill
this up we can test it out one more time
here i got a couple more on me if we
need
if we need more um i'm gonna put just
four items in that hopper clock that
means the guy will heal faster
hopefully that solves him teleporting
out of their issue
can't figure out the snow golem one just
yet
um and we want to test all this other
stuff we've built so let's get it
running
and hopefully things go smoothly here
like i don't get how he could shoot the
snow golem right
am i crazy should be impossible
but he did it somehow
okay he's in himself good stuff good
stuff
and again we might need more layers i'm
not sure
because he hasn't created a single guy
yet i don't think let's go up there and
just check
what's going on so i think this is going
to be our spot where we are oh there's a
guy in there okay
you should get picked up yeah you got
picked up
awesome awesome okay and here he comes
and now we can watch him suffer
uh he's not shooting i wasn't sure if he
was gonna shoot or not when he was in
there it looks like he stopped
shooting that's good
any more guys in there oh yeah here it
goes so he's starting to take
suffocation damage so it takes quite a
bit of time like he's got to be in the
water a long time
and if we tried to do that with a
vertical column of water
we would need like hundreds of blocks
probably of
vertical water so he died there
and i don't think he dropped any shells
unfortunately
i'm kind of watching the bullets like
are they going to hit the mine cart it
did hit the mine cart
that'll be an issue if the mine carts
break
there goes the other guy cool cool so
yeah the farm is working
we're just not getting great rates
unfortunately which means we need more
layers
and i don't really want to build more
layers or else we got to spend a lot of
time here
one or the other how's our buddy doing
here he's still alive did he kill golem
friend
golden friend's still alive gollum
oh it must be out of potions yeah so the
automatic shutdown
kicked in that's good anyways let's wrap
up our episode with the comment of the
day like we usually do it says mr etho
question mark oh he's not sure is it me
to answer your question yes it is me
what is your favorite plant
slash type of plant oh asking the real
thought-provoking questions today
i don't know that's a tough one uh
there's so many great plants right
every plant is a great plant once you
learn more about it they're all
interesting
if i was to choose if i had to choose
types of plants i would probably go with
trees trees are big trees are
complicated trees are awesome right they
give shade
they give fruit what's not to love about
trees
uh as far as pacific plants if i was to
choose one
i think i would go for the venus fly
trap just instinctively
carnivorous plants you know how many of
those are there there's actually a few
but uh
it's cool it like if you touch one of
them they'll close up on your finger
they have like sensory organs when you
touch them
they move which is pretty neat uh let's
see
another one that comes to mind is the
nature's troll
the tumbleweed right that's a pretty
cool plant it like
zips along highways it uh piles up next
to people's houses and sometimes catches
fire and burns your house down
it's like nature's troll uh it's great
um maybe there's a plant out there that
actually responds to music it'll like
dance i don't know if any of you have
seen
videos on that that's pretty neat i saw
another video on a plant
that uh emits almost like a gasoline
and it can catch fire on hot days just
like randomly it bursts into flames
so you know there's some there's some
crazy stuff out there it's hard to pick
a favorite though there's so many
don't make cool stuff uh anyways thanks
for the question hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode
have a good one take care bye bye