[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode how are you
guys doing today hopefully everything is
good today we are going to continue our
tour of the ancient worlds today is kind
of like a bonus episode recording it
right after the last one and last
episode I had lots of fun seems like you
guys did too oh that's not as easy as it
looks trust me
actually it's pretty easy but that turn
there threw me off oh man no can't see
menus oh all wrong ender pearls no work
Mary oh yeah last episode was pretty fun
checked out the comments you guys seem
to like it too
so that was cool and uh so this episode
we're gonna check out my second world
and if there's time which sure probably
will because my second world wasn't I
didn't spend a whole lot of time and
it's there's not a lot to it so probably
pop into my third world as well which is
what I started my let's play series on
and weren't we're in my fourth world
just to give you a frame of mind how
many worlds I've had so yeah let's go
start the nostalgic trip once again I'll
see you guys at my second Minecraft
world whoa so we've made it guys we're
gonna be doing this tour in beta 1.3
even though this was an alpha one point
two point two world I believe it has not
has not stood the test of time as well
as my original world every time I was
loading it in alpha it was corrupting
actually so we have no choice we have to
do it in beta 1.3 because in this
version is when the MC region file
format was introduced and that seems to
fix it so we'll do all right so it's
convert it it's gonna convert it to the
see region file formats oh and this
might take a while all right
through the magic of editing it didn't
take long at all all right come on
please work please did this world okay I
think we're good oh we're we're out here
really okay what do I have on me oh I
doesn't work I have to press E oh I
actually had a diamond pick on me
dispenser I was doing something
interesting if you don't know what this
is
this was just and then this is this was
an experiment to see if I could jump
across here by jumping on a boat a half
the time to jump just right see if we
can do it here and you can jump across
this what is it three wide gap which is
impossible otherwise and this is like I
guess we'll go to kill ourselves here
right I'm assuming oh no this is all
water that's a giant giant thing to do
all this whew it's gonna kill me yeah so
some people were asking why I
oh it doesn't work if I'm in the boat ah
darn it oh yeah you can the when you
climb the ladders you don't have to have
a ladder every block you could skip one
block forgot about that one
maybe I'll yeah I should probably cut
here get in a better spot alright cool
there it is guys that is the main base
where I live many of my minecraft days
to finish resting before the some people
are asking why I created this world what
made me decide
like stop playing in my original world
and move on to a second world I had a
specific purpose in mind when I made
this world my mission was to build boat
dispenser 2.0 which is what the majority
of it this this world is all about to be
honest like this is all part of it
this is kind of messy but I believe this
year oh I think I know what this is for
yeah I was seeing if I could jump on the
boat when I team up here and then I made
that jumping thing that we just read all
right let's go inside
fancy double doors did I get it right
this time do they open at the same time
I think they do yeah I think it's pretty
close they don't close at the same time
though yeah I think you got it right
though oh man this brings me back and
there's still all the stupid animals in
here oh yeah I think we should light it
up a little more though it's so dark
yeah once again grass in the base I'm
starting to notice a common theme with
my builds always grass always nature
always a storage room always a giant
cactus farm which is what's above us is
this thing ready even it might be ready
maybe not I'm looking for cactus where
do they I guess the cactus sit on top of
the boats right the whole point of the
cactus farm above here was for my
firework show so when I press this see
if it works
I don't think it works this is why I
wanted to play an alpha so everything
would work properly mm-hmm man I see
cactus up there huh all right anyway
yeah so this is my storage room let's do
a little bit of snooping when I created
this world I believe the nether was out
that's um not still the old stared
texture in this version let's get the
minecart running - oh look at the
glowstone it looks so dark unreal I
don't think I had a proper way of
getting up here ah so clumsy how did
this how did I empower this minecart
even yeah oh there's a why are these
missing I don't understand oh and I lost
it oh I got a spare on me cool okay
I must have planned for that I just this
is where it yeah this is where it gets
powered old-school booster design let's
see if this still works in beta yep
pretty cool it would go around and when
it would go around one of the corners it
would catch on fire yeah easy hey people
thought like when they saw videos of
this they thought there was a sheep in
the minecart that was on fire but it's
just a minecart itself alright let's
continue snooping actually had flowers
and food here let's change the
difficulty to heart to you oh man I
noticed I did not have a lot of stuff in
the past it's not like my current worlds
right to have like noodles of of
everything
oh so the lava and the coroners was to
light the minecart it's also if the
light up the room and this is when I
built this storage room I had this idea
where I wanted to have a display for
what's in the chest so instead of having
signs everywhere I thought it would be
cool to have the block type above the
chest and then I did something similar
in in my let's play world - based off of
this idea slow sand ashes with the slow
Sam's got furnace at each of these let's
check this thing out
this is fountain if I remember right was
a mob trap yeah cuz a little water
glitch you see I can't get out of the
sea and the animals would have the same
problem so I made it kind of deep here
and they would wait maybe not they don't
seem to be drowning they're justing
trapped here I guess but they would get
caught under the water there's so many
animals let's take a quick peek at the
nether some random chat this year I
think I put those there because I wanted
to see if they would grow in the dark
which they do I learned that by doing
that experiment all right don't remember
if there was anything in another here
bad done not to have any torches it
doesn't look like they did much in the
nether in this world probably just went
here for glowstone and the fire sounds
different when you light it doesn't it
something noise it makes now it's like a
whoosh yeah I don't think there's
anything here okay let's head back
you know what chest we never checked was
probably the most important one ah 28
diamonds 13 plus 18 gold yeah not a lot
of stuff no iron in here even where was
my iron I had snow well I don't know but
they're being snow in this world campus
is falling through let's try this again
maybe there was just no no I don't think
it's gonna work hmm
is there no boat up there oh I don't
think there's a boat up there that's
probably why these these redstone
torches up here I had this idea I was
gonna light up my base I was gonna have
a light switch for it right at the front
door here I don't know let's check
behind here I kind of remember there
being wiring back here I guess not hmm
but anyway that I was going to I was
gonna light up my whole base at with the
flip of a switch it would turn these
redstone torches on I didn't really
understand that redstone torches don't
give off a lot of light and especially
if they're at the top of the world like
this they're not gonna do anything
really and I spent a long time oh and
then later I guess I removed all the
redstone
realized it was a flop of an idea
because I had redstone running around
all along here and then I think I added
this this road Koppel later too because
it was burning out what did I call this
thing I can't even remember oh there's
the boat oh it was in the off position
no wonder there we go that'll work I
think yeah in the past we didn't have
Pistons right so we had to come up with
clever ways of moving things around and
doors were a big thing and here I'm
using a boat
the cactus would fall down and if there
they would collide with boats so it
would hold them in place and then I
would release them all at once it does
work awesome and then they would fall in
the lava and they would kind of explode
out and I called it my firework show
let's see I got a bit on me even though
I don't think we had beds back then but
we are in beta I just made one oh man oh
man old bed mechanics you remember that
it wasn't like it wouldn't let you
asleep if there was monsters nearby you
would get like randomly awakened if it
was a dark spot nearby I think yeah
can't remember if the mobs would spawn
or not Oh random - at this logic up
there and this is boat dispenser 3.0
over here and a bunch of tests for it oh
man so dark now I I better go back to
the base and try to try sleep away the
night why is it so hard to hit things in
this cuz they strafe to the left I tell
you I expect them right in front of me
in there
they're moving around me yeah so oh
that's the eats wrote the original eats
Road
it's like putting me in random spots
every time I die I like this
unfortunately I don't have any planks on
me ah all right I'll be right back
same skeleton man and the same spider
they're gonna get me again okay i got
the spider at least i'm guard i can't
hit him there we go oh one heart left
okay get my stuff try to sleep man the
game was so much harder back then yeah
date time I just remembered these dirts
blocks you see those are there because I
had a tree farm up here before the
cactus farm and then I had the idea for
the cactus farm and I kind of tore those
out let's go up here if we can just
checked it out real quick this was a big
project I guess we can try rip into it
get a better look there's like multiple
layers I wanted a lot of cactus it looks
like I had a pretty good water stream
system going on - it looks like it all
meets the middle no dead zones yeah all
right well I just remembered where all
the redstone went for those redstone
torches - when I built the boat
dispenser here I used like 700 800
redstone or something on it and in my
desperation for redstone I ripped out
some of my unused wiring and it went
into this project instead so let's check
this out this is the main focus of the
world and the eats roads but this thing
was fun to make spent a good like 20
hours on it probably at least
all right I got lots of signs the boat
docking station lights indicate if boats
are on oh yeah you could switch between
yeah if you want if you brought a boat
back here you could choose between if
you wanted to store it back in the
system or if you wanted to put it into
the shredder and the shredder works off
of a glitch with here can we go in here
at the time when I made this there was a
glitch in the game that if you rammed a
boat into lava just rights it would
duplicate the amount of wood you got
from it and later I made that let's see
if it's back here I think it is yeah I
made the this thing here if you place
the boat in this middle square here
the boat would hit all four cactus and
you'll get four times the the wood back
returned look at the creeper man he's is
wading through the water they don't care
they would go anywhere in the past no we
got some planks here this is beta so I
dealt this trick works I was so mad -
you know there was this glitch in the in
alpha for so long yeah it doesn't work
where when you cut down a tree the
leaves would not de-spawn on it for like
dude they're fast - I think they move
quicker back then and this glitch was in
the game for so long there was no easy
way to get rid of leaves after you cut a
tree down you'd have to break each leaf
individually so I I was using the wood
duplicating trickier not fixed the the
wood duplicating trick but he never
fixed the the leaves not despawning so I
was so man I had to cut down trees again
and they was such a pain cuz I'd have to
break all the leaves and I I was upset
he didn't fix the leaves decaying thing
when he fixed the wood duplicating thing
this thing also detected if the the
storage was full of boats it would
automatically switch to sending them
into the shredder here which is pretty
cool let's let's get a boat though press
a button yeah pretty good timing on that
actually let's go inside when I made
this world oh that was the one mistake I
made though the boats would always face
this way so we'll need go on it it would
do that flip around thing which really
annoyed me but when I made this world I
picked the seat specifically because it
was right by all this water and I
thought it was a perfect location for
this boat dispenser build I wanted to do
and then when you return it here let's
see
oh yeah the boat would hit the pressure
plate closed the doors would wait for
you to get out I came out with came up
with this idea of this boat thing in a
glass to get out of the boat down there
the water stream was set up just right
so the boat would never break against
the walls how do I get out right click
right click and goes over the pressure
plate here oh we're at half a heart and
a whole bunch of stuff happens let's see
if we can ride it in get another one
it's so much fun
stupid boat turnaround thing oh yeah and
I had that you see those four redstone
torches era I made a clock a redstone
clock just for the blinky light effect
around this thing and it like totally
killed my fps in the game I had no idea
what was going on I didn't realize like
how leggy redstone clocks were on the
game oh it's gonna break its gonna break
darn it ah oh snap
one sec boats alignment inputs oh that's
some extra okay when something steps on
the pressure plate up there that's what
this is for I must have red ripped out
the redstone clock I had here make room
for that so the boat falls down this
thing this is a boat junction I made and
there's basically a door this the door
here yeah there and when it was closed
like this or open whatever whatever it
is and the boat would fall down it would
hit the door and then it would go this
way and up to the boat shredder thing if
the door was closed the boat would fall
down here and go through this rig
America my rowing through here I just we
can just break it and we'll hop down if
weekend whoo this was some yeah this one
here this was a holding cell in case
there was too many boats down there
there was a buffer space for one extra
one what's this is this for I think this
might have been a redstone wire access
area yeah that's what it looks like all
right let's keep going
this is tainted forever guys these world
tours there's too much to see we really
need another episode to check out our
third world but
we made might have to do it some other
time because I don't want to do too many
of these Tory episodes in a row yeah all
right let me up so the boat would fall
down and land in here
what was that me that must have been me
and these are like a whole bunch of
holding cells I made four for the boats
very intricate workings down here again
I did the pot light thing and it looks
like I used wheat for decoration a lot
of stuff in this world was purely
technical I didn't do a lot of building
for the fun of building in this world it
was all technical experimentation I was
really trying to make videos at this
point the everything in this world is
basically from when I was making my
silent videos on YouTube yeah you see
the redstone like going so if there was
a boat there the redstone light would
stay on let's put one more in here
head on down this the redstone to this
one was a lot more fancy than the
original one see I have a button here
yeah so when if you'd press this it
would send out that boat and then that
one would check if there was a boat in
front and if there wasn't it would it
would send it down the line so that
there would always be a boat ready to go
so cool man see extra boats there it
looks like and what's over here computer
room
geeks only
and then there was another door back
there I think that's also to get down
here let's go check out the Redstone
because I am very curious
of course redstone in the past instead
of it being different colors like it is
now it was just black if it wasn't
powered here it is oh man
definitely not done the most efficient
way possible I am very confused as to
what I actually did here to be honest
okay I think this this line of wire was
for the light that shows if there's a
boat there that redstone torch on the
left side oh man what a mess wait how
did I I'm still confused how this works
mmm oh there's a portal down here too
huh I don't know guys this was this was
a big mess I didn't understand and eats
at the time right so this was some fancy
redstone thing I saw in the on the wiki
that I tried to work out and it took
forever it's very very intricate there's
mobs everywhere
alright anyway that's about it for the
boat dispenser 2.0 very fun project
can we go ride it up think we Chen
whoa
oh we hit another boat and it
automatically turned us around awesome
oh yeah
I just yeah we can go check out the each
road real quick too
I guess and that'll probably be about it
for here actually wait a sec let's check
this out here this what goes up must
come down no jumping I can jump if I
walk to lava lighting this was my wood
dispenser
I highly doubt this to setup to work
right now yeah I don't think so
basically I had a stack of like a
hundred boats that I would I would fill
here where is it I had a video on this
like like I said at this point I was
making videos I've I've shown most of
these things and had like annotations to
explain them but I would like load the
boats here can we go down this is
probably dangerous yeah this doesn't
look very safe
whew darn it I want to see what's down
there there's actually a sign down here
it says you shouldn't be down here oh I
knew leap of faith don't be a wuss oh oh
oh whoa whoa whoa doing a water bucket I
think this was just for the boat
dispenser you can tell boats were a
pretty big theme with what I was
interested in everything was boat boat
related it seems because he could do a
lot of cool things with boats back then
like stuff
I don't know they just worked pretty
pretty good I especially like water
elevators and that kind of stuff and
since we didn't have Pistons boats
allowed you to do things that Pistons
kind of allow you to do now Ellis goes
right down to bedrock I think yeah I
think this this is for loading the boats
wait a second we got to try this out oh
man so claustrophobic down here and that
that's weird I had some random dirt
there still oh and I got to be careful
in this version of Minecraft I think of
a boat or my hit's
like one of these block entities it will
completely stop it I think could be
wrong about that or that might just be
minecarts okay we're gonna make a boat
and we're gonna see if we can ride this
thing up and see where it takes us
alright so here we go don't break don't
break don't break oh yeah and this is
when I was experimenting with like
smashing boats against walls
I found out it didn't break them okay
this is where it takes us I think our
head is inside glass right now and see
can't get out of here oh let me out Oh
broke it okay yeah so a whole stack of
boats would get stored in the water here
and when the door would open they would
all flow into this thing towards the
lava this would duplicate the amount of
wood you get from the boat breaking and
then that would feed off into
guessing it's down here yeah they would
drop then all the wood and sticks will
drop here what's this for
oh I never put anything here uh-huh all
right so weird if you hit if you walk
into mobs they actually push you around
oh that was the best wait a second I
think we missed something here is there
anything behind here no okay
nothing there but there is this oh the
water elevators still worked in beta
even oh I've died so many times this
episode why were things so dangerous I
don't understand like I had these water
elevators
did they not kill me before or what I
don't know
alright this thing took forever to make
I remember that does this go anywhere
even or is this like my minds oh are you
kidding me yeah we were just here this
looks like a strip mine yeah right at
bedrock level I don't know if that was
the best place to get diamonds back then
or my it might have just been to get
redstone actually whoa quite the
extensive mine actually you don't get
the speed boost for jumping back then I
guess I was only in the adventure
updates Wow
I mined out a lot here I think that's it
where does this go
I see water up at the end it might not
go anywhere actually did I just stop
here because of the water there's this a
cave system oh it's a cave huh I must
have just dug until I hit that and then
I stopped unexplored to you an
interesting all right so let's head back
let's try this thing out again awesome
okay let's go try out the old eats road
for some reason I wanted to build this
under water and that made it all the
more fun to make not really sure why I
did that got an easy loader here gonna
work oh it does work sweet so with this
version I had no way of holding the boat
at the start I was mostly experimenting
with this intersection oh I remember
this hey that the doors stay closed oh
never mind they just opened basically
you had this opened the door you want to
go for that destination and there was
like signs where you could write like
the location you're going to and see
let's go to north if we can slow us and
yet otherwise it would break
this was just like a short experiment
this miswrote here I kind of want to hop
out here and check out the Redstone
actually where did I put the redstone is
it I think these are just for looks
there must be underneath right okay yeah
it's all down here aha I don't know how
it works oh man
basically I came up with this idea when
I was actually driving in my car at the
time and I was thinking how cool it
would it be to have like highways
railroads in Minecraft where you drive
on the right side and you follow these
rules and yeah ended up coming up with a
boat system kind of based around real
road rules that chunk air there actually
happened in this world I think that's
why I was having trouble getting this
world to work because I was having chunk
air problems and corruption even back in
the Alpha days there was something in
stable about this world
let's check this out really quick to you
guys remember the secret project oh and
look we got leaves that aren't D
spotting secret project this is where
the first instance of it the Frogger
game fortunately I didn't get very far
with it in this world and it didn't turn
out in my let's play world and it didn't
turn out in the feed the beast version I
did either although that one would have
worked except it was causing too much
leg so I never finished it but maybe one
day we will finish the Frogger game and
basically I had boat dispensers
what is it going on here oh it actually
had a timer set up so that oh I was
using a minecart thing here as a timer I
see and that would release the boats
periodically and they had just enough
momentum to get to the other side I
believe right out real quick it's
getting dark we have to have to sleep
away darn it
oh I always do that I have a boat in my
inventory what am i doing alright we
made another one there we go
it's gonna work can I place it I don't
think I can place it there it's not
gonna no I can't place it there huh I
don't know how to load it alright anyway
these were the cars over here didn't
actually set and set up any minecart
mechanics to it though well I found
something else here this is the hot and
cold video you remember that if the
minecart went by the lava it would catch
on fire if it went by the water that the
fire would go out pretty cool I think I
was doing an experiment here to where I
had I was loading mobs into the minecart
and then pushing it away and I think I
found at least at a certain time in the
game if a mine if my mom was in a
minecart it was it took longer for it to
be spawned I think I think that's what
what I was trying to figure out anyway
that's that's what it seemed we got the
loader over here for the Frogger game
see if we can ride it Oh
oh that's weird whoa pretty bouncy oh
we're good things good
totally normal whoo yeah it made it
across and somehow I was planning to
time it just right where you would have
to jump from one boat to another boat
and another boat and somehow get across
which would have been impossible but I
didn't know it at the time look what I
found guys out in the middle of nowhere
here this was my second ether experiment
and the main goal with this one was to
have actual boat holding systems and
boat return systems and docking stations
and and just try to make it a little
fancier than what I had come on man let
me sleep oh yeah
all right let's try it out see got a
boat here yep yeah it works pretty good
oh we have a loading system over there
yeah so with this thing oh and we have a
another door here so if somebody pulled
in behind you they wouldn't crash into
your boat I was trying to design this
for servers like for transportation on
servers with lots of people in mind you
leave it then it goes to the boat
returned and it would get added back
into that yeah and I think let's see if
we can find an area with a few boats I
don't see it anywhere
mm-hmm was that the only place with a
boat I guess so hmm all right anyway I I
think I had a speed boost system with
this dude
let's try load another boat in just to
try it let's see this is the ez loader
and when I design this I I tried to make
it fit into a chunk properly like very
specifically so people could copy/paste
different chunks into their their
servers for some reason I thought that
would be a good idea it doesn't really
make sense but I like design this
intersection to be 16 by 16 and the
roads I made kind of an even number two
I tried making eight blocks wide there
actually 10 blocks wide it does it
doesn't make a lot of sense but yeah I
had well multiplayer in mind but then I
found out later that it didn't work on
servers so since there's a boat behind
here when you hop in this it would give
you a speed boost because this boat
would push it and the boat would start
out at max speed it's pretty cool all
right
anyway so that's this world we don't
have time to check out our let's play
world maybe sometime in the future maybe
10 or 20 episodes in the future we can
check it out again but yeah probably
returning back to normal normal
minecraft and my let's play but it was
fun to check out these old worlds I do
have a few random ones I wouldn't mind
checking out - so many people do that
really quick before we end this so from
our list here I think world 3 was our
first world a world - was our second one
that we were just on
I think world 1 is our third one that I
started my let's play in I don't know
what world four and five are there might
not be anything in them now there's
probably nothing significant in them I'm
just curious to check them out
here we go
building terrain is it gonna work is it
gonna crash is there anything here I
don't think there's anything in this
nope just some random alpha world we'll
look at that landscape that's pretty
nice oh and there's is that snow I think
that's snow oh that that's a birch tree
okay this is an alpha terrain no way hmm
all right nothing on this one what I
don't see anything at world 5 here but
there's a diamond pick on the ground by
spawn which is very strange because like
I never used oh there is something here
wait a minute what is this oh I remember
this this isn't my world even this is
somebody else's world that they sent me
yeah okay this was an experiment yeah
okay I think I know what this is I don't
know if I didn't demonstrate it somebody
made a thing where they put a bunch of
boats here and they had a minecart and
when you get out of the minecart see if
it happens oh it does the work that
happens it would launch you
because in one of my episodes that I
showed a bunch of mobs launching me and
I think they were trying to set up in
such a way that you would specifically
get launched a certain distance
consistently you know it's pretty cool
okay just for funsies we're gonna check
this one out too this was called set up
nine that's what my backup was but world
one so I think this is my my first or my
let's play world my first one the third
world oh oh is it the spaz set up I
think it is hey buddy
yeah oh man you don't know how long it
took to set up I'm so glad I saved this
is the TNT in the back goats chickens oh
I'm coming to get you spaz whoa I think
that triggered the is it gonna work oh
it doesn't work and they're here spaz is
army try to get five creepers in place
under sand without them D spawning there
was no mob eggs back then there was no
creative mode this took forever to set
up oh no blocking that's awesome huh
must be converted this this backup was
called world LP one but it's world one
this might be the very start of my let's
play world before I built anything just
like the island fully intact
whoa whoa what's going on here
where am i why is it night this is it
oh you know what this is before I ripped
all this out I bet this was like my
original attempt at the mob system
remember and I was doing all this stuff
I was trying to make a record firm up
here then I ended up tearing out all
this all these tubes and piping this was
the yeah this is the decompression
system now that's loud when I was
working on making a mob decompressor I
think this is what this is about
yeah and then I like tore out all this
cobble all this glass and I started
rebuilding it from fresh got the old
tree farm there water wall huh oh the
dispenser setup that's gonna use
dispensers or did I use dispensers I
can't even remember now yeah I think I
did have dispensers in the final version
dinner night oh it's been too long had
lots of TNT
oh I had the mob system set up like it
is working
oh hey got the note blocks or key hey
what the heck who did that
darn guys alright that was cool to see
alright let's check this one out this
one was called World lava lava was all
caps its world one so I'm guessing it's
the same world again and it's probably a
setup for something huh okay
storage room isn't fully built at this
point I was messing around with the
lighting I remember I had an episode
where I asked people of which lighting
style they liked the most
yeah I did have dispensers whoa come on
guy I did have dispensers in the final
one I couldn't remember
did I not play on a hard mode before I
don't understand how I survived in these
kind of conditions not a lot bill dear I
don't understand why I called it World
lava though there's no lava around now I
got my house here tree farms still here
looks like I started setting up the
minecart thing that goes around old mob
system down there huh I was pretty good
on keeping backups guys I have I have
this world from all all sorts of
different time periods every backup I
released to the public I still have on
my computer which is cool huh
anything in here yeah I had diamonds I
actually had iron I had a lot of iron
well quite a bit of gold well when I
started my let's play that's when I
really started playing this game lots of
hours yeah
my other two worlds before this so I
didn't have much saved up oh it's called
chocolate island at this point anything
down here it's gonna kill me
got the portal here I did not have the G
all nether mod set up it looks like ah
[Music]
same world again 53 mags this one was
called 800 TNT I think I know which one
which backup this is C what what the
setups like here yeah here we are
oh man beekeeping in the video this guy
surprised attacked me when I was up on
the platform hey guy did this does not
do anything
is there no Pistons Hey
well I have our Mirage good
[Music]
this is so cool yeah make backups guys
you have a lot of fun later
oh yeah that was a good episode oh wow
check it out guys
when I logged in it was on Moody
settings here kind of cool to see it
like this again so that was a lot of fun
I hope you guys enjoyed the double
nostalgia tour it's cool to check out
the old worlds again and relive old
memories but probably won't do chocolate
island maybe in the future like 10 or 20
episodes I just don't want to do too
many of these touring episodes in a row
because not I'm sure not everybody likes
them so I kind of have to you know find
a balance in the future as well though I
also need to do a world tour of this
world again because it's been about 60
60 plus episodes since my last one and
quite a bit has changed in the world
since then but anyway here is the
comment for today it's a special one
says this invokes a lot of nostalgia in
me this world was where I really found
my passion for exploiting the game
mechanics you were doing stuff with
boats and water back then that changed
the way people played Minecraft on a
whole so awesome you definitely have to
revisit chocolate Island in the future
we will Armitage shanks so if you don't
know who Armitage is back in the day doc
and I we interacted with him quite a bit
he he had a let's play series he still
does I checked this channel and he's
still making videos every so often but
on the minecraft forums when I posted
about my boat dispenser he was one of
the first guys to reply and he he posted
a video of like a let's play video where
he took my boat dispenser and put it in
his world and I thought that was so cool
somebody actually used my design and I
could watch him watch how they
implemented in their world and saw that
they enjoyed it
yeah it was cool I liked it but anyway
that's gonna be it guys I hope you
enjoyed the episode and I will see you
again next time bye bye
[Music]