[Music]
hey hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back to another episode
in on let's play worlds I know what
you're thinking right now
he never starts his episode student
stuff what's going on why ZTE
what's he planning I'm not gonna tell
you I'm just doing it we'll get to this
later here let's try this out though I
you know we got these beetroot seeds a
couple episodes ago I never did try
planting them I don't even know what
they look like I don't know if I've seen
pictures of them or if I have I don't
really recall what this plant looks like
so let's try maybe put a few here for
decoration one two three four five like
that's alright okay so they start out
looking pretty small pretty pretty
normal
it almost looks like carrots oh and then
is that them fully grown okay that's
them fully grown then so they turn red
aha
okay well I tried it here guys we got
like a little decorative garden area
just to fill up the spot I'm not sure I
like it though there's something bugging
me about it
maybe it's the color like the Reds
almost too close to the color to the
spruce or maybe no maybe I just built it
too plain I'm not sure I've done this
before though like in in my world I
often use carrots or wieder stuff for
decoration I usually do like how it
looks something's bothering me about
that one though like here I'll give you
example let's go over to here Oh
although the slimes killed most of them
great that example like in here I like
how the carrots look around around this
room anyways let me know what you think
about that I'm still using this this
snapshot with the messed up stairs by
the way if you're wondering about that
there is a new one out but I heard a
trex redstone or there's an issue with
redstone so I don't want to update to
that one just yet until that gets fixed
oh yeah let's try it let's try this out
on the mini farm - I wonder if we'll
it'll actually work because apparently
the beetroot take more bone meal to grow
than wheaten that we did get one they're
slowly getting more seeds I think it
kind of works but it probably needs like
four bone meal or something maybe we'll
just try that temporarily
oh right in the middle of the floor
that's the great thing about having a
grass floor guys you can just grow stuff
wherever you want
one two three four for that time okay
one two three four for that time the
mini farm only puts out three at most
one two three four five oh there must be
a chance of it doing it on three though
one two three four maybe I'm just
getting unlucky here one two three four
or again hmm three is not happening one
two three
there we go so between three and five
from a few times I did it here anyway
the wheat farm knows between two and
three for sure I remembered her this
mini farm two to three to grow wheat and
other crops so it takes more bone meal
haha
I've been doing a lot of decorative
things in the world guys maybe I'll show
you a few of that a few of those and see
what you think about them as well just
kind of got in that mood to do do some
building some some like train stuff I
guess you would call it this area has
always bothered me it's like a big flat
grass area and I tried putting like just
some mini garden things here like with
leaves and and flowers and stuff maybe I
overdid it though actually I like that a
lot more now you know less is more
sometimes
I think I overdid it yeah that's better
right I like that I think these little a
few straps over here good put some
leaves down here a couple blades of
grass there just to try fill in this
area a bit more also I've had trouble
with lighting over here so I put some in
rods above the villagers but probably
the biggest changes guys are outside
here so I'll go show you these see what
you think of them so you come out to the
man cave and then we got a little garden
here now which I think looks pretty good
threw in some leaves and stuff a couple
more flowers over here I'm trying not to
show you to the left here because that's
for the bit the biggest changes all
right grand reveal so wasn't really
happy with the plain swamp we we had so
I did like a biome enhancements from
here like this isn't perfect yet I'm not
totally happy with it currently from
here it seems maybe too colorful right
too chaotic but it looks like I think it
looks pretty good like when you're
actually in it like over here I wanted
it to feel cluttered and like lots of
leaves and vines and and that kind of
stuff around because it is a swamp right
this ground to me looks mushy I just did
like path blocks and I think that it's
like a mushy chaotic path we got going
over here this leads over to the
abandoned mineshaft by the way so we
actually have a way of tying it into our
worlds like visually which i think is
cool threw in some random mushrooms I
hung like end rods off of them I thought
I'd give it like a fantasy look like
it's got growth coming off of the
mushrooms or something I'm not sure if
we'll keep them though I just wanted to
try it if we get rid of them it is
darker this snapshot also has lighting
update issues I find so I do really want
to update but need a stable version to
come out yeah I think maybe these are
these are overkill
get rid of them but I added some logs as
a decorative feature so just threw down
like some sideways logs and then put
mushroom blocks around them to make them
look like they're decaying some of them
have another work by them something like
messed up soil some gross nasty bug
filled mushroom juice soil of some sort
I don't know and also the other big
thing I did here was a custom tree added
another one into our world I think it
turned out pretty good actually I'm
happy with this one I probably should
have built it out of birch leaves though
because some of them some of the leaves
turned a bit yellow cuz apparently it's
a desert over here but overall I think
it's fine I want to add another tree on
this side of the swamp or this side of
the river just to bounce out the look as
well I'm not gonna go stand
ah really
come on it's so far away alright so well
anyways guys let's move on to our main
project of the day today shall we so I
looked at the list this is how I decided
what to do today I looked at the nasty
list do you remember this of all our
never finishing projects we actually did
some stuff though so number 3 Sandy City
we got the walls around there now I
think we did the minecart storage system
might be one or two things left on that
I can't remember I know we worked on it
though and we got the fire work room
designed we did the tunnel to the
deserts Nexus is ump up and functional
and just have a lot more stuff to do on
it do you know what the or storage room
is because I don't know it's on here but
I cannot remember for the life of me
what it was supposed to be and we did
the blaze farm we worked on that we
worked on the nether hub design so we
got a few of these kind of crossed off
but the one that caught my attention was
let's work on number 17 today the Simon
game if you don't remember this I I
forgive you it was like 50 to 100
episodes ago if I was the yes but we
worked out or we tried to figure out how
do it here played around with some ideas
I had a problem though where maybe I'll
just give you the quick reference by the
way so Simon Simon is a memory game we
were trying to build it in Minecraft
here so you got four different colors
and you have to copy the sequence so it
randomly creates a sequence of like
maybe red red blue red blue red red blue
red yellow and every time it adds one on
to the sequence you gotta try copy it
and memorize the whole thing if you mess
up then you lose so we were trying to do
that in Minecraft here using droppers
and clay blocks to represent the colors
but I had a problem where no matter how
I power these droppers they always would
shoot it's like far further than I
wanted like if I powered this the
dropper which shoot maybe two down the
line instead of like the one right next
to it like I wanted you guys gave a good
suggestion though in the comments to
just put a hopper between them and I
tried playing around and creative that
fixed the problem so we're gonna make a
real attempt at building it today so
let's head back to that area we started
that I'll try to clean it up a bit more
and then we can get to building this
hopefully actually make some progress on
it
[Applause]
all right very cool so basically guys
what we just did here is a rough very
rough expansion onto the man cave if you
didn't know we've like filled every
every nook and cranny around here with
projects there's not a lot of space left
to add on like if we want to build
something new so we sort of have to do
this where we build new hallways and and
ways of adding stuff onto the man cave
like this so we got two doors we can put
something behind here eventually if we
want and I've started digging out a room
for our Simon game in here um and also I
didn't want like a just the hallway
though like we have this super long
hallway here which I don't really like
it feels it feels too long without any
breaks but we have like something built
here something over here so we can't
really do much about that but I didn't
want just another hallway over here so I
made it go down some stairs to make it
feel like it opens up a bit we're gonna
put some water here eventually like a
little pond and make make more of a room
than a hallway specifically but yeah
anyways and then eventually this can
connect to the underground village if we
keep going this way but anyways let's
get inside here we'll start working out
the interface to the Simon game what I
want to do with it's got a rough plan in
mind so this here is gonna be our
controls we'll have the four colors let
me try to remember what it is I think
it's red red blue yeah I kind of forgot
now these red blue blue over here I'm
not I'm not forgetting the colors I'm
forgetting what order they go I think
it's green here then and then yellow
below we'll try this I'll fix it after
if I got this wrong because I looked at
a picture of the Simon game like a real
real-life version of it
so yeah we'll step on the pressure
plates in the corners here to make our
choice what color we want to pick to do
the sequence and then in front of us
this is gonna be our screen like our our
visual feedback of what's going on
inside the game so I tried to set this
up in such a way that's not gonna block
what we're looking at here so you'll
notice the red blocks there that's like
the border of the game what I plan on
building I wanted to make sure like at
the blue blocks there that none of that
is visually blocked like if we're
standing over here if we went a little
bit further back you see it starts our
vision starts to get blocked of the game
itself so we didn't want that I I
positioned it seven blocks from here
because of that like if we brought this
in closer
we would have problems seeing the game
if we brought it out further then it'll
be unnecessarily far away so I I just
use this to try age where to put it
it's a nine by nine room by the way and
that is the very center of the nine by
nine so now that we know where we want
to position the screen we can start
building it here so this is the design I
have in mind we're gonna use courts for
the border it's a nice clean white block
goes pretty good with clay like the
hardened clay colors I find and will
make it go up and around this is gonna
be a very very complicated project by
the way I am a little scared of it like
even for me the redstone with this is
going to be difficult alright so we'll
do that and then I think we have to put
like a line down the middle like so
maybe connect so this will divide it
into our four quadrants for the colors
let's put a block here in there and
there and there okay so let's take a
step back oh I missed one break these
let's get an idea of what that looks
like right now
so that's our basic screen and again we
wanted to make sure none of that was
blocked our view of it looks pretty good
so let's start filling the colors in so
that should be red blue green yellow if
I if I figured that out right and there
we go so that is our interface for the
game I think that looks pretty good
though I'm happy with it
I inset them one block so that you get
the the shadows on the clay blocks
because if you keep them flush with the
screen you know you don't get that it
looks really really smooth and really
plain yeah that's why I put them in one
block I also put the lights one block
further in just for a little bit more
depth or detail to it now you can see
these buttons or these pressure plates
correspond with their positions so red
at the top I could have like just put
the screen on the floor as well there's
a lot of design things a lot of design
choices that go into this if we have it
on the floor I think it would be harder
to see what's happening though so that's
why I decided to put it like in a wall
like that and also the reason I didn't
use buttons for this like I could have
had green red yellow blue buttons for
different buttons to make our choice but
when we do that we're forced to move our
mouse that to pick to press the button
you know if we use pressure plates we
don't have to move the mouse we just
have to move our character so it just
looks a lot smoother when you make your
choice well that's why I did it that way
anyways to to like give visual feedback
we want a visual feedback in audio
feedback when we make a choice or when
it's trying to show us something here so
I want to make these pop-out one blocked
as well if it's selected so we're to do
that we're gonna put some slime blocks
in the back here kind of like so and
then wire this up let's put the city in
actually let's figure out where the
Pistons go first before we do that
it's very important if you ever build a
game like this that you figure out the
interface before you do the redstone
otherwise it's not gonna it's not gonna
fall into place correctly oh why did I
do that I put that in the wrong spots
okay let's put how do I get this piston
down this is the most difficult parts
most difficult challenge we faced yet
okay there we go the two Pistons for
each I guess will do and now we gotta
try connecting together so let's put how
do we do this we will put a piece of
obsidian there we got to use obsidian so
the slime doesn't stick to it put
another one there
redstone above on those two pieces oops
that's one way to stack up but yes
alright and then this was the blue one I
just will put a blue wire thing for it
alright and then redstone repeater into
there and that's and I think that should
work just go see what that did
alright that popped it out and it popped
the light out that's good let's make it
so the light turns on as well the light
is over there so we would we could just
throw a torch down below like that's
alright and then make sure it retracts
properly so it's on power it's alright
yeah that looks good so I'm gonna do
that with all four of them alright so
we're off to a good start here check
this out I hooked up the pressure plates
to each of their colors now when we step
on them we can see see what happens and
that's pretty clear I can tell pretty
easily when when a color is chosen here
right so it's a good visual indicator I
would say I'm happy with that so as it
is right now we could probably start
applying some logic stuff to this now
let me show you the
the basic form of it right now so we
have the the wires just running out to
the little gizmo we set up earlier here
so basically just runs up connects to
each of these and that's all there is to
it right now but we have we have to do
some checks and and some complicated
stuff now so very the very first basic
thing you'll notice when I step on the
pressure plate this just stays out as
long as I stand on it right let's let's
add a monostable circuit to it so
typically the way I do these is I'll use
a sticky piston and then the block like
that and then we pull it through take
the signal out here we'll set this to 4
I'll just show you what this does so now
it's like a button almost you when you
step on it it only applies signal once
and for a certain amount of time so in
order to do it again you actually have
to get off the pressure plate the floor
tiles accept another input that way if
we like sit on blue for example it's not
gonna like keep keep picking blue is our
answer until we get off and then either
select it again or a different color
rights so that's very simple ah the one
thing though
there's piston sounds right we want to
maybe get rid of those because it's
close to where we're standing there for
basically every circuit in this game
there's a redstone version and there's a
piston version so we just saw a piston
monostable circuit I'm gonna do a
redstone 1ho piston circuits are usually
more compact than their Redstone
counterparts but redstone circuits are
quiet they're silent which is usually a
nice feature ok so I just put a redstone
monostable circuit on all four of the
wires here this is it right here it's
pretty simple a little bit bigger than
the piston version but is quiets very
important does the same thing though as
you can see
we're gonna have noteblocks playing like
near here and we want to be able to hear
them so if we can cut down on piston
noise we definitely want to do that's
alright now the next step I don't know
how many of you are actually familiar
with the Simon game but there's like two
states to it basically the first one is
a place through the sequence so you know
green blue red yellow red whatever then
when is done well actually during that
sequence we we we don't want to accept
any inputs because it's just showing us
what we have to copy so we want to
disable these pressure plates while it's
doing that then after it's done that
then it's our turn to enter what we just
saw in copy it's right so then we want
to re in a ballades and we want to check
if we pick the right answer or not and
we can combine all those all those
things we want pretty simply here I
think all we're gonna do is maybe cut
the wire here and let's put a sticky
piston here we will use a sticky piston
for this just cuz it's a lot simpler
and this is kind of a complicated thing
we're doing alright so if for example
green is the right answer then below
here we're gonna send power to it and
that's pretty much all we have to do
alright so then only if this is up will
will power be sent through so yeah this
is a nice way of simplifying it guys
basically if all these Pistons are down
it's disabling our input tray now so it
like when it's showing us what to copy
we want the input disabled all we got to
do is keep all the Pistons down that's
nice and simple if we want to check for
a correct answer like let's say Green is
the right answer at the moment then all
we're gonna do is send power to this
piston right you might be thinking
though etho you fool we're gonna destroy
all the wrong answers until we find the
right one right well no because I've
added something else
here only if it's the right answer like
only if the power can get sent through
here does this wire turn on right and I
just set up like a triple triple nd to
lose detection system here so we have we
have three conditions that are checked
the first one is if we're accepting
input or nuts on the game then if if the
game is waiting us for us to make us a
choice then this torch will be off okay
the other wire here is if any of the
pressure plates are stepped on its gonna
disable this torch and if this torch is
off and this one's off well then this
light turns on and we lose GG let me
show you how this works Oh green is the
correct answer right now so we step on
red wrong answer that torch turns off
game over right but if we step on green
look what happens you see that it
cancels it out so since this is the
right answer it sends power down this
line and at the same moment that torch
turns off powers sent to the repeater
and it keeps that on prevents the torch
from from triggering the game over
events all right that's the basic lose
detection logic it's not not too crazy
all right
we're probably gonna want to wait before
we do this other part of the game this
is the tough part over here but we got
to set up the memory and the the thing
that sequences through the stuff and
chooses the right answer all this stuff
that controls these Pistons here we have
to implement now all right
we'll do that next next episode i'll
probably do most of it off camera cuz
it's gonna be boring i hate to say it
but it's it's redstone stuff so i'll try
to get that done and we'll check it out
later
well anyway
guys it's that time again let's check
out the comment for today
it says etho have you ever considered
making a new current intro just the
suggestion keep up the great work man I
tell you guys I tell you what I would
love a new intro I really want one but
why I have I have three I use currently
L the hedgehog he's a youtuber youtuber
guy he made three of the intros the ones
I used most often one of them was for
like feed the beast mine crack though
and I can't use that one anymore
I haven't used it in a while
the other two though is the one I used
at the start of my let's play episodes
here and then I have the outro he made
me which I use at the end and I also use
it as an intro and outro on like pretty
much everything including the Minecraft
stuff and then I got the Raider one too
from Raider and tiggy but I don't use
that one as often because some people
really like it and some people really
hate it and whenever I use its all the
comments are about the intro I find it
not really about the video uh-huh
but the thing is I don't really know how
to make intros I've tried you know I've
tried to think of ways of doing it and I
don't think I have the artistical talent
for it or something I'm not sure I
always I always become a blank so I have
never done one myself it's a tricky
thing to do you have to you guys think
of what video you want to use and you
also need audio and a lot of audio is
copyrighted which complicates things
greatly gotta make sure it's something I
can use and I don't really know where to
get that stuff it's a reason I don't
have like music in my episodes and that
it's it's like a tricky thing even like
if he gets stuff that's you're allowed
to use a lot of times the video gets
flagged
just because it's on other websites or
someone Flags it inappropriately and you
know stuff like that it worries me
even like sound effects not just music
it's a copyrighted so it's got to be
careful with its anyways that's kind of
what's what's the deal with the intros
and outros and stuff hope you guys
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching as always have a wonderful day
take care bye bye
[Music]