[Music]
you know what guys one of these days one
of these days it's my dream it's my
hopes my desires that maybe I know it's
never gonna happen but just maybe you're
gonna go to me and you're gonna be like
yo you know what I cannot believe how
many projects you have finished in your
let's play world you finished so many
projects all the time it's incredible
how do you do it you know take it easy
don't worry about finishing projects cuz
you you do so many rights you're gonna
be like etho how did you get sandy city
to walk around all those finished lama
projects that's what you guys are gonna
be saying and I'm gonna be like oh my
dream has come true okay we're over at
the ice firm here we go so we started
this a few episodes ago and I keep
saying we're gonna go back we're gonna
go back - you guys are probably like no
he's never gonna finish that are you
kidding me I can't find I don't know how
to fly there we go okay
but yeah I'm returning to a tear today
probably not gonna get a finish today
but I'm gonna work on a bunch but yeah
this ice bar here is the perfect example
of why it's so easy to start a project
but so hard to finish one because whoo
man I tell ya
designing it's probably the most
interesting part we did some of that
together and since then I've revised it
so we'll probably spend some time
checking that out again today but spend
a couple hours designing the thing right
and then you got to actually build it
since you can't just build it guess what
you gotta clear the land in the way cuz
you need a flat spots right once you get
the flat spot though I only got to set
up a beacon and stuff for the speed mine
it takes a bunch of time when I see it
the flat spot though you can't just
build it you got to collect the
resources to build it so then you got to
go gather clay and ice and make a
bajillion Despenser's you think these
two stacks with dispensers are gonna do
anything that's not even gonna put a
dent
into this project but Jillian's the
trees died for this and I still got to
kill more it's so sad
yeah you clear the lands all right so
you gather all your supplies and then
you got a place thousands and thousands
of blocks because you see what we got
built here we got a copy this at least
10 to 20 times I would say and this took
several hours to build already uh-huh
but I'm not gonna bore you guys with all
the building I'm gonna do most of that
off-camera while I'm watching TV or
something it's always like a real
challenge how quickly can you place
blocks like ideally you should never let
the override click all right let's get
that continuous rhythm going you know oh
I went too far
yeah I actually got a pretty good rhythm
going on here now I think so I didn't
build one of these these sections I
think in 15 minutes now it's basically
an S sort of shape like this this is the
main thing you got to do just boop boop
and Boop like that's right
solid filled all the way down and then
at the edges here you do something a
little different you get this built up
like this like this right then I'd put
some birch over here as a block that I
can mine with the pic that's not gonna
break quickly like if I run by with a
pic you see I I hit the clay and it just
pops instantly when reminding ice we
don't want to break the frame of our
farm here so using birch wood there and
then over here you fill it in four
blocks deep with PAD ice I'm using all
the way down and then let's see where
does it start I think I put one more
birch log here yes
and then dispensers eight dispensers
boop-boop-boop-boop and that's one one
like tiny section I put that there as an
indicator I'll put one birch log here
and then for each and every one of these
dispensers I'm trying a trick here I'm
placing pistons above them and the idea
behind this is we want these dispensers
to place a bucket of water to fill to
fill the area here to turn to ice right
we don't want the water to freeze right
as it's being placed because if if the
dispenser places water it freezes then
when it goes to try pick up and refill
those buckets
it can't it'll shoot the empty bucket
outs because ice is in front of here we
don't want that to happen so we're using
these Pistons we extend them so it's
like there's a block above here as long
as there's a block above there the water
can't freeze if it doesn't have access
to the sky so that gives the dispensers
time to place the water have it spread
and then pick it up again to refill the
bucket for the nest the next cycle and
hopefully that'll work out okay uh-huh
anyways this is kind of turning into a
how to build this farm instead of me
just building it which is good right
what we got to do next is fill in these
sides here well actually what I usually
do I guess just to show you the better
order of doing things so that we don't
have water spilling out into the middle
here I place trapdoors all above here to
hold the water in place these also act
as a seed to start ice forming on this
edge of the water basically that goes
all the way down then we have to place
make sure there's a solid filled yeah
it's very good
then I place water between each of the
dispensers and again we got to put a
water back in each one that takes a bit
of time to place them all inside then
over here at each section I do another
four like so and one more there and
that's basically one section done here
uh-huh all right so this is what the ice
farm is looking like currently I would
say it's maybe half done if I was to
guess or half the size it's going to be
when it's fully fully finished here
but I always underestimate these things
so what do I know right you can see like
we originally started with five sections
why'd I decide to extend it up to seven
I think that's as wide as we're gonna
make it we're gonna feel like a seven by
seven chunked area with the ice firm
here is my plan and then I'm gonna call
it finished whether or not it works as I
hope it will the dream is we harvest out
a section of ice here right we go down
we step on a pressure plate at the end
of it which will cause it to refill with
water it'll start freezing again and as
it's freezing we go on to the next
section we zigzag our way down the farm
and hopefully by the time we travel
through all the sections and end up back
at the first one we want the ice to be
all frozen it or the water to be all
frozen again I always do that you know I
say ice frozen it's a it's a it's a
tricky mistake uh-huh so we want all the
water to be frozen so that when we get
back to the first section we can just
start mining again we don't have to wait
or anything that's why we're making the
farm so big so that has time to freeze
we're also really trying to make it
efficient at freezing which is why we're
using the dispensers a lot of you were
confused why don't just solid fill this
with water on the side then I don't need
to activate this with redstone or
anything it removes a lot of the
confusion a lot of the trouble with
building the farm if I just put solid
water here the problem with that though
is it won't have a seed place for the
ice to start forming as it is right now
if we fill this with water ice can start
forming next to these dispensers and
next to the trapdoors yeah so these are
all the places where the ice can start
forming originally when we fill this up
with water and then it's got to spread
to like these middle areas here and the
space between the dispensers so on
average I would say it would take two or
three spreads to totally fill this up of
ice while if we only have it forming
along the trapdoors on this side it's
got to travel one two three four and you
compare two to three to four it's
probably gonna be almost twice as quick
using the dispensers here if I was to
guess so that is kind of why we're doing
it
mmm-hmm okay so we're in a little bit of
a predicament here I don't know if this
has happened before but I'm having
trouble finding string I think I've used
that Buller or stashes I'm sure we have
more we just gotta figure out where it
is I need it for dispensers I cannot
find the entrance to that cheap spider
farm we build I think this will take us
to it though is it over here no wrong
ravine is it more oh it's over there
aha you remember this the one that works
with thorns it's broken by the way
because it used a piston translocator we
might need to fix it is there any string
here though that we can snag oh yes hmm
okay so I think when we press that it
would pull us and put us on top of the
piston and then when we would do this
one it would pull us down and then we
get healed with an instant splash potion
[Music]
you know my famous saying what's my
famous saying guys I'll fix it later
yeah I think we have enough string for
today but we will need to get this
working again soon I think we got like
two double chests left that I can find
we could probably get rid of the piston
translocator here and replace it with
like an elevator because it like a water
bubble stream one just switch this whole
Sandin the magma and then we can control
going up and down kind of like we were
doing with this here we go guys the most
important thing I will ever teach you if
you don't know this already how to craft
dispensers in Minecraft the tutorial by
etho are you ready cuz this is the most
annoying item to make in the game I
highly recommend if you're gonna make
dispensers make a full stack because
it'll save time and long run okay what I
like to do make sure you
three stacks sticks three stacks of
string fill it in make your bows and
then you just jam the cue button as
quick as you can
shoot them all out near your crafting
table boop-boop-boop-boop really go to
town on it then spread out something in
your inventory because you don't want to
pick up all those bows if you can help
it and then put your cobblestone in
place you do pick up a few of them
unfortunately like a so get your
redstone in there don't forget your
redstone cuz then you gotta start all
over and then I like to what do I like
to do guys throw that down so get a bow
there make your first dispenser and then
all you got to do get the bow over here
press to press Q 2 Q 2 Q repeat 64 times
you'll get a stack 2 and Q 2 and Q 2 and
Q oh yeah by the way guys we got that
creeper head last episode right we
should make our eat so banner before we
forget about it here if you don't know
if you've never seen this before there's
actually a very cool Etha banner that
can be made in the game somebody showed
this to me when banners first-team outs
I've only been able to make it once I've
always wanted it in our let's play
series here but like good luck trying to
get a creeper head there really easy now
with the channeling on the the tridents
though so that's cool we can finally get
one here so first thing you do you make
the banner if you haven't seen this
before you're gonna be like no way that
is so realistic okay that we get orange
orange dye we do a gradient then I think
we do the creeper head hopefully I don't
mess this up yeah I think we do creeper
head oh and it needs a nice trade I do I
think yeah
so I puts like a creeper face on the
banner and then I don't know if it's
middle or does it matter doesn't matter
okay so then we put on our headbands and
then we wanna do the mask you do lower
right that's right and we got to add
hair I think it's like this there's
another version where you can get the
shirt I don't know I don't know how to
say it sure Indian sure in game the Red
Dot in my eye
you can do it with the notch Apple I
think err or something but it's like
seven steps to do it and you can't do
that in survival only and creative so
this is like the best you can do in
survival I think ah then once you get
the etho banner I'm gonna copy it's make
infinite copies is this how you do it
it's been so long since I made a banner
hopefully that's a copy yeah there we go
okay
it's pretty good right like you can't
get much better at representing someone
than that I don't think I'm the one in
the middle by the way if you couldn't
tell the difference
another for banners uh-huh and you can
actually add banners to shields not that
I ever use a shield let's check this out
though okay looks a little bit funny why
I guess the creeper face is a different
size huh yeah it's not as wide that's
what's going on I think the trick with
this banner is to like chop off the
bottom of it so if we do that looks a
lot better right I kind of got a big
forehead but I think it's kind of cool
that way what if we chop off all right
can I not put I can't put it there oh
right because this is a block up here
but not down there I think it works
whoa oh stop I burnt one of those I'll
fix it later okay so what I want to try
to do there's a new feature in 1.3 where
you can actually mark maps with banners
like mark locations using banners on the
map so I want to try and add a thing
here if we can gotta be careful I don't
throw the ender pearl at the map or it
will pop them off so where is the man
cave
right there okay so we're gonna steal
that map let's head over to the entrance
I guess move quickly we're wasting time
here kind of got stuck in the stairs
there that didn't help okay so I had a
banner down here and by the way what do
you guys think about the entrance to the
man cave cuz you know the more I look at
it it's like it's just a pile of leaves
I kind of feel like I should redo it
maybe but maybe I'm being too finicky I
don't know see what you guys say about
that I can't get it back it's too far up
I can't reach there we go okay so what
we can do we don't have to name it but
if we name it apparently it'll show up
on the map so I want to try that out
let's do man cave entrance okay man cave
entrance is there enough space yeah okay
so then we take that we place it place
it down where we want it it should keep
that name I think I guess right over
there's good it doesn't show up when we
hover over thought it would ok let's try
right click is it cuz it's too far away
oh I think I marked it yeah you see it
showed up on the map there oh that's
cool that's cool
does the name show up if you're closer
to it or why can't I see that I thought
if you hovered over a banner showed up
I just not okay let's go put this back
see if it's it says that when it's on
the wall or if it only says it when it's
in my inventory like that oh this all
updated too by the way all the swamp
area there the wall there the leaves I
think that is uh huh okay go back very
carefully and yeah it keeps it look at
that so we started with a white banner
so that's why it has a white mark so
debate on what color you start with is
what it keeps it doesn't actually draw
all the different layers onto the banner
though
whoa-ohh so back at the ice farm here is
doing more work placing down those
pistons getting those dispensers down
rights and then found out the design is
actually flawed it has a little mistake
in it so the way we were doing it let's
sleep real quick here it's nighttime I'm
telling you it's nighttime there we go
so we send two pulses to the Pistons and
dispensers here using like a wire over
here so this will power both the piston
and the dispenser below we send that two
pulses so the dispenser will place down
water and then pick up the water the
Pistons will extend or tract extend
retract happens very quickly but
apparently in between the two pulses
there's like one or two game ticks I
think we're the ice can form and if ice
forms during that when the dispenser
goes pick up the water there's gonna be
ice there and it it doesn't get it and
messes up the farm so it it can happen
it's extremely rare but if it can happen
it's going to happen so we kind of got
to fix it I thought I could do something
like this where we have two lines and
power the dispensers with this bottom
line and power the Pistons with this top
line make sure that they're extended all
the time while we're placing the
I'm picking it up but it turns out this
line up here can actually power the
dispensers down there I didn't think it
would be able to but it can also has an
issue with bud powering the Pistons so I
would have to like put slabs between
each of these and then there's this a
whole bunch of other issues so this
isn't really gonna work either here's
what I came up with though that I think
is going to work we're gonna have to get
rid of all the Pistons get rid of all
the Pistons and just move them back one
use sticky pistons instead and then we
power the dispensers over here this
block here
no this block up here what am i talking
about this one right here well bud power
them diagonally all right it works it's
all good I tried it and then pistons get
powered in the back here and basically
we send it to pulses the first pulse
though is only gonna be one tick so
sticky pistons will leave the block
behind if it's only one tick and then on
the second pulse it'll extend and then
pull it back so that guarantees it's
gonna be covered over here when it's
placing and picking up the water so that
is the plan and it's pretty much about
the same level of complexity I would say
maybe a little bit more complex than
that over there so I think it's gonna
work out okay but I got to change these
all so that's gonna be a bit of a thing
this is how we we do it too by the way
put a block here oh I got a like a
spider on me oh man ah okay everything's
fine I'm still alive oh snap you guys
might not like this but you know what
I'm gonna do I'm gonna wrap up the
episode here for today it's gonna be a
bit of a shorter one but it is the
second one of the week so maybe you guys
won't mind as much hopefully we'll see
but yeah this is actually the third day
I've been recording this episode
lots and lots of off camera building as
you might guess but that ice forms gonna
be really cool and it's all done we'll
be able to get all the blue ice and Pat
dice and regular ice we could ever want
in the let's play series it's gonna be
awesome because I do use quite a bit
actually whoa big zoom in but anyways
let's get to the comment of the day this
is the question that a lot of you been
that have been asking lately actually it
says so I have this question for you a
few months ago on your let's play series
you mentioned that you started
exercising I just wanted to know if you
have haven't stopped and how much
progress you've made
aha so I started I think around late
winter and got into a pretty good
routine I mentioned this before but I
was feeling kind of like sluggish and
out of energy and just overall just kind
of like a couch potato right so I
started exercising and he had a huge
impact not only physically but mentally
I felt like more alert and more creative
and just overall very good I highly
recommend to everybody start exercising
if you have it you don't have to like go
crazy just do a little bit's maybe do a
little bit more the next time and you
you will find it makes a huge difference
it's kind of what I did just like five
minutes the first time and progressively
added more and more onto it longer
exercising sessions but anyways
throughout the spring I did a lot of
exercising pretty much every day or
every second day got up to the point
where I could do a hundred and twenty
sit-ups that was like the main type of
exercising I was doing sit-ups as well
as some like weight lifting and leg
exercises and a few other things like
squats and that but yeah I felt pretty
good about that but then you know what
happened something terrible guys
summertime in Canada super hot this year
don't have air conditioning so of course
it's like over 30 degrees Celsius just
about
every single day this year in the summer
guess the last thing I want to do spend
30 minutes
exercising cuz guess what you get really
hot even when it's cold out you get
really hot when you exercise for a long
time so I kind of fell out of the habit
of exercising during the summer I tried
to do it like at least once a week like
when it was raining and it cooled down a
little bit but I did kind of get out of
the habit I'm starting up again now that
it's cooler but I'm only at like twice a
week right now still kind of lazy got to
get get into the habit force myself to
do it a little bit's and once once again
to a good habit it's a lot easier to
keep it up nah but that's kind of the
situation right now I'm not as bad as
like when I first started I still got
some of my muscles still kind of like it
2/3 of where I was at I would say aha
but anyways that's the situation hope
you guys enjoyed today's episode thank
you for watching as always and I will
see you again in the next one I felt
like I was gonna ask you guys something
I can't remember no I thought about for
a bit I can't I can't remember I think
it was important though how about this
so it I want you guys to write in the
comments your own personal experience
what is the weirdest thing you've seen
someone do in public the weirdest thing
you've seen someone do in public that's
that's my homework for you today ok
anyways hopefully you enjoyed today's
episode thank you for watching until
next time take care
have a good day bye bye
you
[Music]