[Music]
ah come on
not this again yes we're doing this
again
left chest right chest
do you know which one to choose today
did you learn your lesson from last time
i hope you did you know what the left
chest or the right chest holds
what is the left choice or the right
choice do you know
what i'm getting crazy here what if we
do this
does that throw your world a little bit
uh don't worry they're both empty we're
not doing it again
although i probably could have got at
least 75 percent of you this time
because i forced your choice from last
time but
joking every now and then uh
is good but if i do that all the time
i'm just being a jerk
so we're not doing it today but we did
come across some interesting
things from last time like things didn't
quite go the way i expected
entirely one thing i thought was
particularly interesting is people chose
left chest or right chest
uh sort of favoring whether they're
left-handed or right-handed like
people that are left-handed they chose
left chest people that are right-handed
chose right chest not with not with the
majority of the people but with some of
them
that's the way it worked never like a
left-handed person saying they chose
a right one um and particularly
left-handed people
seem to choose left instead of right
so that was kind of kind of cool uh
seems like the majority of people can
take a joke when
they're the victim which is good also
but the thing that really surprised me
is i thought
just about everybody was going to
mention
that the left chest was trapped a trap
chest
but it seems like most people didn't
notice it of course video quality was
probably a big factor in that
but the ones that did notice it actually
chose that one
because they thought it was special
instead of like
actually realizing what it literally
meant that it's a trap chest
kind of cool so i thought i would share
that it was fun
anyway welcome everyone to my humble
abode here
in the man cave
you're uh supposed to be here holy
i keep doing that to myself flame swords
are not as cool as they used to be
stone pressure plates work again
the little leg there made me question
myself for a second
but it's all good yeah i'm using
17a now and it seems to be a pretty good
snapshot
a lot of bugs have been fixed but i've
been working over here guys oh
yes we're doing stuff so the path
we made just the other day is now going
to branch to the left here
i almost feel like it's uh too many past
but i think it's okay
it's fine uh so it's gonna come over
here this is supposed to be our way down
to
the cow farm and i finally figured out
why my wheat keeps disappearing because
these guys don't really jump
unless they're in the water but on their
own they don't
really jump but what it turns out to be
squitter falling from there and landing
on my wheat and that's what's killing it
uh can't really can't really stop that
unfortunately but anyway let's work
on this for a bit so we have to do
something about a ceiling here these
lights are actually kind of necessary
but we can change them to another type
because they light up the layer above
they shine through the piston
but if we use glowstone or something
that will look a lot better
um underneath the stairs here i
wasn't really sure what to do i added
these uh wooden stairs like this
but now i'm wondering if we take this
out
this might be a cool place to put some
flowers or something
all right and i'm i'm like making it go
around something here what should we
make it go around is the question
should this be like a deep pit of some
sort or should we put a tree here
i think we should put fences
get some fences going here
and go around so it's like there should
be
something significant here otherwise you
should just make it
go straight through here but i like how
it wraps around something
okay we're having a slight issue over
here the grass is spreading to the soil
so we're not planting flowers here
instead i'll actually
wait a second i don't like the stone
behind there
let's replace that real quick
yeah instead we're gonna plant wheat
here
wheat looks pretty good too
i don't think we can grow it all oh
maybe we can yeah we can awesome
how's that look sure
i like how the light kind of makes it
pretty bright there too
i keep wanting to change
this long time ago i built this and i
never
removed this stone that's showing so
we're going to do that
get this back there we go
i think let's try just make a stone
brick thing
with stairs i just want something and
walk into
and come out of here
this is going to be our way up and down
to the cow farm
like we originally planned
that's one way we could do it we should
even hide some lights here
that way we can light up the center of
this grass in a nice way
nice and easy way
yeah it's all right maybe
let's try this too
makes it bigger oops
do that too i'll i should get rid of
that a bit though
if we do this what happens then
that looks weird glowstone down here
let's let's go check this out from a
distance
uh i wish it wasn't all one color
all right this one is still marked up so
that must mean this one was down
so we'll mark that again and then we
will add
new water here see we can only get that
high
let's put i guess we can make it solid
water
cool so that'll be our water liner up
i tried switching to these and i think i
like them a little bit more
uh they take the same block space pretty
much but they look a lot smaller
so that's good i tried tried this out
for the ceiling
i don't think it's gonna work it's
causing lighting errors
uh like if we look from here
although i guess it's kind of dark that
over there but
uh if we put this here
it makes it really dark so
might have to do full blocks for the
ceiling
um and we haven't really used these
anywhere so i don't know if we actually
should use them for this
uh it's looking to me though like this
needs to
continue through the stone brick so
let's try to do that
if we do oh not that
this do that
that's i don't really want to
block the wood either
we need to make it go down somewhere
how's that look
that's okay but if we make it go down
it's not gonna
really work right if we just make it go
straight
does that look okay can we get away with
that
let's change more of this wall to with
stone brick
well guys we got a good start to this
area i would say uh
i do want to do some tweaking to it i'm
not quite happy with it
totally like i don't like these leaves i
tried them out
instead of the slabs but they they don't
look too good
flush with everything uh so we'll change
those
i added in this i really like this just
a little water pool
i went in here before and i couldn't get
out oh yeah it's if i'm
if i'm by this but if i go to the middle
i can
yeah same for this one
that's kind of cool right over here is
one of the spider spawners so i thought
i would try putting a window i'm not
sure if we'll keep that either
depends how much lights it's going to
let in
i don't think it'll be much if it does
these these seem to work okay
[Music]
go back up still need to figure out what
we're putting there
um yeah
anyway let's let's maybe just quickly
finish
up this area too uh
loud cows there's not much to it
i think we'll just keep it all stone
brick let's
try continue this make it go round
torch in there yeah
just very simple and make it connect
back to there why not
uh then let's bring a wall down
how's that look and
slabs sure
we'll go with that slabs uh
yeah we're starting to finalize stuff
pretty good in the man cave i'm
happy with it i love working on stuff
around here it's just so
so easy uh just
ideas come to me and it goes good
usually
and this is the last of it might
actually want to
hide some lights in there but we'll just
make it solid for now
because it does feel kind of dark here
doesn't it
maybe a little bit
um oh yeah and then there's this
i might make a few tweaks with this area
but that's that's pretty good
so it's nice to get that done too uh if
we go back
up i'll work on this more later
um what should we do now guys what
should we do
[Music]
okay here's what we're gonna do everyone
uh we're gonna go
on an adventure we haven't gotten
exploring in a long time
and particularly the thing i've been
wondering about a lot lately
is where are my other strongholds in
this world
uh so we're gonna hopefully try to
locate another one today
and we're also gonna bring a couple maps
with us so we can chart out some world
i hope
so this is actually something i've tried
to do
in the past and failed uh this world is
a bit unique
when i created it it was the time that
strongholds are not
and that all sort of started coming out
so i
think their positions
might be messed up it's surprising and
all my time in my world here i haven't
blown up
some of this stuff around here
um if i remember right one was around
the mountains here okay yeah it wants us
to go this way
so we're gonna go on our adventure
and doesn't this place look cool at
night i liked it a lot
very nice i think we should put a beacon
underneath the snowflake somewhere like
a
oh that's one way we'll
spot a stronghold that's the abandoned
mine shaft
you can kind of see it looks like
there's a few caves i've missed
too i think that's a pretty big one
keep going i remember right it was
oh pretty far this way actually
night time perfect time to go
adventuring
we will drink a potion let's do a check
here
oh
where did it go oh we're gonna die we
are gonna die
oh for real
watch this moves oh he didn't see us
coming
where'd that one go
it's going back this way uh so these
under eyes
they were pretty tricky i remember
it's like they would go one way then
they'd do another one when we got closer
but i'm pretty sure
wants us to go that way now
okay we'll try it i don't know if i
really believe it
and maybe let's take a look at our map
here
that created it yeah
ah beautiful i don't think this is a
section i've mapped out yet
pretty much get the whole map just by uh
by loading it there's just a top right
corner there we kind of have to get
let's go that way
extremely hard to walk around like this
i think we got it all
you can see the lava lake uh kind of
around the middle there
creepers are gonna come up to us like
we're a tourist here and just
give us give us trouble
okay so it is this way if i remember
right it was like just past
this mountain here
the last time i looked for one
but i'm pretty sure their location is
all
jazzed up in this world
look at that it's going doesn't know
where it wants to go
okay now it's it's pointing this way
i think we're getting close our other
one is like
pretty far uh that way like
a thousand blocks that way so this feels
like it should be the spot okay
oh it broke
oh look at this area this is nice
got some planes over there i don't know
if i've ever been to those planes
actually
look at that it changed directions what
do you know
that makes this so fun
i think i may have been this far out i
can't remember now
still wants us to go this way we are
just a little past zero zero
hmm
oops um
check out this river this is a nice
river too i should try to link that to
my other
river
okay let's try this again i need to get
another map
going to it feels like
yeah let's get another map
i think we got the whole thing here yeah
cool
so
are so annoying
they would just miss once or twice it
would be so much better
okay let's go a little further here
that is really cool though check out
those two mountains oh
why are they falling from the sky is
that the new spawning
thing with the zombies
that's awesome they're just falling from
the sky there
very weird oh and we've got a carrot
let's try again here still wants us to
go this way
we're about 200 blocks out now this is
all new terrain guys i've never seen
this
i don't think
i'm surprised how close we are to zero
zero still
yeah going this way cool
i really hope we find a village out here
like one nice and close to our other
our man cave there
no mountains i thought i was kind of
hoping there would be mountains
out this way too
and it actually almost looks like this
could turn into an ocean biome i've
never found
a proper ocean biome yet in this world
still wants us to go this way
let's get another map going oh we threw
it down into the water
no uh where'd you go boy
okay that's not it that's not it
map number eight
hmm
big trees too look at that
if we're lucky you will find a horse
guys you never know
i'm not really looking for one i'm not
until they're
better implemented but that would be
cool
very tall trees around here
wow
[Music]
we found a horse
get there quickly dude i don't even know
what to feed these guys
oh we found we found a whole bunch of
horses
okay okay um
i think they take wheat i'm not positive
i'm gonna check the wiki real quick i
don't want to lose these guys
we still got to go that way
wow what a find okay this is awesome
okay guys i'm back
i've read the wiki and i've calmed down
a little bit
uh it sounds like i can just tame them
by riding them
over and over no uh
i could tame them quicker if i had wheat
though
every time you get knocked off the next
time you have like a five percent better
chance
of actually taming them when you ride
them
apparently we got really lucky there
because i think we oh no
he knocked us off so this would be like
20 chance 25
no don't die don't die please don't die
oh he's taking as far away from the
group though i want the black horse
he looks so cool
i wish i had some wheat i can feed them
apples
you can feed them oh he's happy yes
what a good horse man my favorite one
and he got the hearts right away
like i had a five percent chance there i
think
and i tanked it off shift yeah okay this
one looks pretty cool too
no donkey i would have liked the donkey
but i'm not picky
this is an amazing find i i don't know
if they increased the spawn rates yet
uh i'm worried they're gonna despawn
though because vintage beef
had a donkey d spawn i think on
minecraft
oh this looks so freaky being on the
side of a cliff like this
and have a bucking horse trying to get
rid of us
he's happy okay shift
where those other guys don't wander too
far guys
i'm hoping those ones don't despawn now
that i wrote them
uh if they do
it doesn't really matter because i'm not
going to stay around home all the time
so eventually they will despawn on me
if they do after being tamed i'm not
going to try to stay by them all the
time
that would be ridiculous but hopefully i
don't think they will despawn now that
they've been tamed
this guy really doesn't like us isn't
this the one we wrote earlier too
he's thinking about it no it was that
one over there
oh yeah he likes us all right
i cannot believe i found horses
that is so cool well now what do we do
should we go back and
take these guys home or should we try
go for the stronghold like they'll be
here i think when we return
in fact i would like to test that too i
think we'll leave this area and then
come back real quick
after we get this guy here awesome
we gotta name them all oh man this is
exciting
okay we're gonna go this way ah wolves i
haven't seen wolves in so long either
we're gonna go this way uh make sure
they get
to the point where they could despawn
and then we'll come back
and see if they're still there
i have a feeling we're not going the way
i want to go
oh no this is this is the way home
okay so they should be
pretty far out there i don't see a
stronghold
i shouldn't be looking this way but hey
i can't help myself
okay let's go back just to double check
and hopefully i don't forget about these
guys
were we 500 bucks out when we saw
yeah they're over there it looks like
they're all there
happy that's cool i don't think they'll
get hurt on their own if we just left
them
because i don't think i don't think
hostile mobs attack them so we should be
good on that department
i do kind of want to see where these
ender eyes go
so let's go let's go adventuring still
we'll come back to this area and we'll
we'll bring him home i i don't know if i
can craft leashes yet or not
i'll have to check that too last time i
checked we were not
able to
any villages around here this is prime
village territory
oh we're going back to the mountains
tall mountains
and still no sign of a stronghold
[Music]
very strange
that was a fall let's go up on our
mountain here
check things out
let's just look this way i'm i'm kind of
wondering if there's a village around
here
oh cool
doesn't look like it where those horses
actually
were they in the mountains because it
almost seemed like they were i can't
i'll have to check it after this um
oh what is this
it's lighting airs that's kind of cool
let's do another check
okay it does seem like it's taking us to
a specific spot here
it's not just random
oh look at oh
how awesome is my world
that is amazing that is tremendous
with the one tree on top too that is so
cool
wow
i like that a lot i should really build
more stuff in the mountains oh look at
this
holy smokes you go two steps and there's
another amazing thing
oh man look at that
how cool is this world
and even that the planes back there
those look really good like with the
tall trees
and and stuff what is going on here
that's pretty cool
let's go right on that peak there look
down
wow look at this
this is so cool we gotta go exploring
more often i like this a lot
i try to refrain from it because i'm
world i'm worried i'm gonna make my
world really big and then it's tough to
share it with you guys
uh with the world download let's do
another check
oh we're going back i think we're going
back
i wonder must have passed it
it's around here somewhere i'm not even
going to worry about picking these up
oh oh it's going down i like that sign
oh it went into the ground yes where are
we
we're 8.79
that is a good sign we're gonna dig down
check this out if there is a stronghold
we'll probably have to do this or check
it out
in another episode
i know that sound
this is a new stronghold too because i
generated it
like i haven't been in this area before
so this is newly generated
with all the new changes
oh man
this is awesome
oh yes silverfish spawners
oh how i hate these guys
awesome oh okay i think we're gonna end
it here
um oh what do we do about the comments
so i'd have to go back to read them
okay you know what i'm gonna go back
we're gonna do the common thing like we
usually do
uh we'll come back here i know where
this is now it'll be easy to find again
it's not that far out and we'll explore
this another time i guess
no way
i was walking back and i found more
horses here
i think these are different ones
they're not letting me ride them
that's weird it's like they hate me
maybe because i have something in my
hand
yeah that's what it is
oh he doesn't like you when i pick stuff
up let's get rid of that
oh we got a white one okay let's mark
this location
i guess i'm like 200 blocks off of our
last
trail we took that's why
there's a baby one
it's so cool and a white one i like the
white one
oh i see a creeper
jeez guy calm down a little bit there
you go
cannot ride the baby one
which means it will probably despawn oh
it follows the mother too
all right anyway guys i think we're
gonna head back
uh we will we'll play with the horses
again next episode
uh we'll try to bring them home and
stuff and get leashes if we can
saddles all that fun stuff
don't forget the spot
just wanted to stop by here and make
sure they're still here
looks like we got one two
three where's the other guy
uh what other one was there there was
there was the one that hated me where is
he
i'm a little worried i don't see him
wait no that's him up there okay
yeah we got them all they are all here
they did not despawn
very good news
i just keep finding stuff piggy
i can't stop i came to check out this
waterfall like this cool waterfall here
in this awesome valley
and i'm hearing all these skeletons now
and it's like i'm wondering if there's
actually a spawner here
so let's check this out to you
oh no it's just a cave i think
yeah just a cave oh and not even much of
a tape
that's it okay
let's get out of here uh oh
that's never a good sign this is really
close to zero
zero
the infamous chunk air boundary
or not chunk air but boundary straight
wall
i can't believe i have some of this
stuff
is it just generating now that water
just spread
i thought this was an area i've been
before
[Music]
it's so weird
but so cool
and my world i tell you guys this world
it's a nice one and i've seen a lot of
minecraft worlds
there's something special about this one
well guys i made it back home safe and
sound
and i had to really fight not to go
exploring some other stuff i saw
on the way back that's very tempting but
i
i had self-control don't you worry
i like you guys there with me when we go
exploring because i don't do it too
often so it's a nice treat every now and
then
uh anyway here's the comment
i picked up for today hey etho i was
just wondering if you would ever
consider making a video that showcases
your let's play world
like a tour i've been watching your
videos for a while
but not since the beginning and i see
you zip past things sometimes and i'm
curious to what everything is
and how it works just a suggestion
you know what this comment
or question actually comes up quite
often
and i am definitely all for
showing stuff to people like i want
people to feel as involved
with this world with my world here as
possible
but at the same time i feel like we
pretty much do a world tour every
episode like the cave
here isn't all that big uh and we
zip around pretty much the whole thing
all the time so if there's something
specific you want
you want to see uh just let me know and
i'll try to bring it up
otherwise i think we do a world tour
quite often here
um anyway i had fun today guys i hope
you did too
it's really cool to go exploring and i
was really happy with
what i saw always
it's always exciting to see what my
world is going to generate because
that's what i have to live with
for as long as i have this world which i
think it's going to be a while
still so
looks like we got some nice stuff out
there
anyway thanks for watching guys have a
great day bye