greetings everybody this is etho welcome
back to another episode our let's play
series we are you're having some fun in
a newly generated world we're going to
be doing a little little fun test here
experiment a show I guess it's more of a
show than anything we're going to take
our newly generated world here go into
MC edits and then edit in sky gravel and
I know I know guys you're concerned
you're worried sky gravel is not
something to be trifled with
it is dangerous many of our fellow
Minecrafters have died countless deaths
- its destructive properties as it has
fallen and crushed their bodies when
they least suspect it I know guys I tell
you this I will abolish sky gravel from
my world from the nether anywhere I see
it I will not stand for it
it shall not remain um yes I'm gonna
break this oh come on don't don't crash
on me computer uh yeah so we're
recording here sky gravel is returning
to its much more safety conscience state
of land gravel this gravel will not harm
another soul all right so it's gonna
coat the world with its gravelly
goodness my computer is not really
keeping up with this so I'm going to
stop recording while this happens and we
will continue on to stage three of our
show it took many of fortnight's for our
battle against the sky gravel to be one
but in the end we were victorious
in the future if such a feat such a
fight should be attempted I strongly
recommend you boost your memory and
gigawatts or the only casualty will be
your computer or something yes so that
took a long time I ran out of memory I
had to reload minecraft a couple times
but in the end it worked out pretty good
and we can now have a beautiful pepto
bismal covered landscape to work with
here so now what we're going to do is
we're going to go back into MC edits
select the surface of the world here and
replace all the land gravel with green
life forms also known as saplings I'm
going to stop the stupid voice now I'm
done with it we've we've had enough of
it this is what I wanted to see I wanted
to replace all the gravel with saplings
so we have saplings all over the surface
of the world here I thought it might
like the game but it's actually not bad
like that's a lot of stuff to to render
as it's not solid blocks anymore we're
dealing with saplings
there's a lot more a lot more rendering
to them I think but yeah we're okay here
so now once I turn it today the saplings
should start to do something pretty cool
I think time sit no no no I always do
that set time zero oh I did have it
right it's good it confuses me I don't
know why I always mix them up time set
zero okay now this might get kind of
crazy we'll see because they can grow
now yeah I think they're starting to
grow actually and some of them are going
to become big trees which will prevent
some saplings from growing so it might
create kind of interesting patterns too
I almost I think I maybe should do a
time-lapse of this it's cool though you
seem popping up all over the place it's
not happening as quick as I thought it
would but it's still pretty quick all
right I tell you what I'm going to maybe
get down a little lower over here I'm
going to do a time-lapse of this and
here we go
and this is what it looks like after
about 30 minutes that time-lapse was I
think 11 minutes spit up eight times the
speed and that is a forest man I really
want to burn this down but I don't think
I can handle it
that's pretty cool in the video in the
time-lapse the stuff in the light on the
mountain seemed like it wasn't growing
but what was actually happening is it
wasn't quite rendering so having a hard
time keeping up with all the lighting
updates and stuff so it didn't render
until the closer trees started to slow
down growing anyway this is a line that
was created after after growing over
here um this stuff was outside of update
range it looks like but let's get to our
let's play sorry for the long intro I
was very curious to see what that would
look like though and it was kind of cool
aha
so we finally arrived to our let's play
world here let's not derp around for too
much longer let's get to it the project
I want to start off with today is one of
the most requested projects I've ever
worked on like of all my unfinished
projects this is the one people want to
see it seems Emerald City it's been
sitting here nothing has really been
happening with it we're not actually
going to be working on Emerald City
though I'm hoping what people want to
see is me working on an underground
village not particularly this one there
is a major problem with the way I
designed this thing besides it looking
really weird the other issue is like
when I what I wanted it to do like when
I come through the store I want it to
like look down upon this bustling
village with villagers running around
all over the place and
like walkways around the sides that you
could look down on and as it is right
now we only have four houses in here
just barely enough to keep like three
villagers alive but it's it's pretty sad
and the houses are blocking our view in
fact they're in the way so I would have
to lower this all and make a bunch of
other changes the main thing is there's
just not enough space for what I wanted
to do here so my I have a new plan
with how we're going to do the villages
I love those sound fix huh what we're
going to do is we're going to go to a
new area this is an area I've had
scouted for a long time never knew what
I was going to build here but now I
think it would be a very good spot for a
village and I often get lost going here
so let's try not to do that
think we can get through it this way get
to it through this way
let's go it's down here if you do these
gays they're amazed they go so many
different places this this looks right
though keep going straight up by the
gold
that's my landmark and down here sit
over here oh it's down here this takes
us to a pretty nice nice and open room
here which is good but then if we go
further another pretty nice open room
and then even further
another really open area and it keeps it
keeps going there's lots of open space
around here which is what I'm looking
for when I start a build like this and I
think even further this way there's a
ravine not too far away yeah so lots of
lots and open space here so we are going
to try to build a village in this area
and instead of building full houses like
I was
we're just going to build the front of
houses and sort of hide the villagers
into the walls like yes so I brought a
whole ton of stuff over here we're going
to get to it where would there be a
zombie
it must be we're pretty low down I don't
think that would be nighttime zombies
I hear lava - ah let's let's try build a
house here let's see how this turns out
so we're going to need I'm going to do
the first one out of oak
we'll use this and fences will probably
need fences trapdoors yeah lots of stuff
I brought over some more stuff here too
let's get this in the chest alright so
the houses I'm going to try make about
seven to nine blocks wide just so I have
a little bit of opportunity to add
detail and stuff let's start off with
some stone bricks for foundation oh
there actually isn't a lot of space here
is there it looks like it's a big open
area but it's not that huge five two
three four five six seven eight nine
okay we'll do that
alright then let's add our clay I have
this idea I think it's going to look
pretty good first one we'll try make
every house a little bit different let's
get a door here - do do do alright so
we'll put a door in the center of it
that's the center right that's not the
center okay let's move this over do it
here actually maybe we'll move this all
over one then
and then in front of the door I want to
put like a porch something for the
villagers to come out up come out on and
just stare at what's going on around the
world and give it some windows over here
let's come out we'll make it come out
let's just do one block out and then
we'll have stairs here and oops
hopefully this looks good let's do it
like this up to the edge of the house
yeah and then we can put fences around
that and leave it clear around the
walkway oh yeah all right I like that
maybe did I not bring I didn't bring my
ex I always fruit my ex we could make
one
I'm going to put an upside-down stare
here and there that makes it look a
little more solid and we'll put some
support legs on the corners like that
cool cool now hmm I feel we should like
make a fake roof for this let's clear
out a little bit more space like have
have a roof going like this why did I
put my window there that's not a good
spot for a window nice and cozy house
beautiful all right hey let's replace
the rest is stone up here with this clay
and we should try to get a light in here
too in fact I saw something someone did
on the reddit that I kind of liked oh
yeah I like that let's add some
trapdoors and stuff to it to put those
back alright guys so there we go that is
our first house done pretty much more or
less I would probably do the interiors
as I had time but the main focus is just
to make it look nice on the outside here
what do you guys think about doing a
village this way
I would be able to build it pretty quick
I would think and we're going to make it
a functioning village to like the idea
is we will need to how probably put a
skylight in right here so the door
counts as an actual working door and we
might want to add another two or three
or four or five doors on the inside of
here like on another wall like this that
then go outside here and have another
skylight up above here so there would be
per house maybe six doors or
that are working and that way it'll
function like a real village I'm pretty
sure and the idea is the same as like
what we had at Emerald village I don't
want to just build houses I want to make
it I want to be able to control the
villagers like set up farms that they
harvest whenever they feel like it and
have that's not really me controlling
them I want them to interact with
redstone stuff is what I'm saying and
have them do stuff on their own like for
example one of the main things I want to
try to do is set up a rail cart system
where they're able to enter the mine
carts on their own have them deep parts
on their own and then have them like get
off at a stop on their own like it's all
possible with redstone now and hoppers
and stuff for them to do that no problem
and this is within range so I think I
could set up where they even come visit
me at my man cave over there it's only
less than a hundred blocks away I think
so
they could like let's pop in for a visit
and then go back to their village I
think be pretty cool but that's the idea
I might try set up some more houses here
before we move on to something else just
on my own too dark must be too dark I
think yellow flowers are taller aren't
they huh and it won't be just houses
like I said it'll be farms and other
stuff houses will be spaced out every so
often where it looks like they they
would fit in like any flat wall I see
I'll probably add a house and try change
them up like I brought a different bunch
of different colors here for four
different colors of houses but yeah
that's the idea
I will work on this a little bit more
and I will show you what progress I make
today well we have had some pretty good
progress on this project already today
this is of course the one house you've
seen already I added a few more details
to it
I've built three in total now so so we
have this one actually worked out really
good because apparently this is desert
and that grass is a little bit more
yellow and it sticks to the yellow house
so wonderful I do not know if I don't
really like the dirt under here I don't
know what else to use though I could put
grass I might just do that but yeah
that's cool and then I also added in
this house I decided I wanted to try you
know get a little crazy with it I built
one up in the air like this we have our
blueberry and birch blueberry and birch
house here hopefully the villagers will
be able to use these stairs if not we
can adjust them a little bit got a
balcony look out and ran out of clay
blocks but this is the interior at the
moment we have a beautiful view of our
flowers on the outside just a little
flower box outside the window there's
lights above those trap doors there
there and there to keep it looking nice
and that's probably my second favorite
house third one over here I wanted to do
a cobble and stone and I don't like
problems don't as much for this but just
for the sake of variety I think it suits
the green house pretty good and iron
fences or rails I should say these are
rails and rails yeah iron bars for that
thing and we have like a little flower
bed out here what's the shrub pretty
cool alright guys so that's that's it
for this project for today let's go do
something else I think I have something
I want to do with our river project so
let's head on over there okay so I'm
going to take you guys on a tour of our
River
I have finally it got around to adding
lights to it and it makes it look a lot
a lot nicer at night here I like on
right next to the coast we have pumpkin
lights all all over the place now and it
makes it nice and glowy around the river
it's pretty cool so let's go for for a
ride the new zombies in this update are
so crazy like if you're playing on hard
oh man they they seek you out now like
you wouldn't believe like it's not just
like 16 blocks or anything like that
it's like it almost seems like anywhere
they are they seek you out like that guy
he started coming towards us when he was
pretty far away and if we were to just
stay in the water here we would have
zombies just flood from all angles like
if there was any on that mountain they
would come down here to get us even hey
I like how you can attack from a boat
now - it's kind of cool well here comes
another one
let's get moving oh well maybe he won't
come I sort of thought he would there's
a guy up there maybe there's a height
limit to it another guy coming this is a
constant swarm anyway so yeah one of the
main goals with my world here is I want
to use rivers and and water as an actual
like road if we can like where we can
get around our world using using the
waterway so I've put a lot of work into
that already like I've I built this
River mostly by my myself that wasn't
here originally I created it with TNT
and stuff and put these trees around try
to make it look nice Oh still getting
used to the new steering mechanics with
the boats it's actually a lot better at
first I didn't like it but then I got
used to it like you can't use the left
and right arrows anymore you have to
just hold it forward and steer with your
mouse
but you can do some pretty fancy
maneuvering with it all right so this is
the river I made basically and then it
goes out to here this is the you got a
third place this is also where the
fireworks get launched outside of this
lake and eventually I'm going to hook up
this waterway to go behind these
mountains and and out into that area
where I found the horses if I can oh
this is not gonna end well
oh man oh let's get out of here
I'm not well-equipped that's not gonna
work
let's just uh let's take a boost all
right so the goal this is what we're
going to do today or start to do today
let's go back out to here
all right so we have the bridge it goes
across the river over there ideally what
I would like to be able to do is ride my
boat into the man cave so the bridge is
here we go down the stairs oh I went too
far this is how we get in and out of the
cave we should make it so there's like a
departure and a rival thing for the
water weight on the left and right of
these stairs I think that would be
pretty cool so if we want to use the
river as our transport we just hop in a
boat to the right here and they'll take
us up and out to our river out here
somewhere so to enter the cave and the
mobs man the mobs to enter the cave
let's try to make some kind of a rival
station here if we can it doesn't have
to be anything fancy it could just be a
water drop that then takes us in okay so
I was wondering if you would hit
anything that's the the Cal UFO thing we
go straight the swing now where's that
going to take us are we high enough up
or low enough down I mean doesn't look
like it's where is this
mm should've checked okay so these are
the stairs here got to keep going a
little further it looks like oh so we're
still a little bit too high up that's
fine we can work with that
all right so we'll arrive here depart
here and dig another tunnel out and see
how that's next hopefully we don't hit
anything here we might hit aah that is
there darn it that is the stair tasting
for the spider elevator I don't know how
to get around that we might just have to
do it all on the left side then okay
it's not super fancy but it'll do for
now anyway I got the return line just
about done here I have no way of sending
boats out though not yet but would a lot
of these melted we'll try to get it to
work
probably won't make the water come
although all this way out here we'll
probably have a walkway of some sorts
and then have a departure and arrival on
that side but let's try out the book
drop make sure we don't take damage or
anything
see how fluently we can get into it from
the river to let's pretend this is like
an actual boat ride with a long rope
with a long build up speed yeah okay
here we go it's getting light here I'm
losing my mind
um to do try to make this a little more
fancy - oh it exploded
that's not good hmm I gotta admit I
don't know much about boats anymore
they've changed so much um I it did look
like I hit the wall on an angle and like
I used to mess with boats all the time
if you hit the boat straight on a wall
or at least before aah or even going
slow like that
it wouldn't break it so there's
obviously been quite a few changes we
have anymore no we don't the question is
can a boat survive if it's going quick
if you hit it straight on a wall I'm not
sure try that again do amazing job all
right
if not I wonder how we could slow it
down
all right so Oh Oh this is that was a
terrible terrible it is a little hard to
steer I wanted to go quick but at the
same time I'm having trouble it's only
two wide oh man that really just took
off on its own let's just sleep the
night away here we'll try this one more
time hopefully I don't mess up again do
some B if the zombies have like a helmet
on they can walk around in the day too
so you're not safe during the day in
this anymore either with these new
zombies cuz ill you'll find you they'll
be in a cave and they'll come out and
say hello
I had a crafting table ah me
get one well I just a couple more tries
here to do alright so if I'm having this
much trouble I'll need to make this
easier to get into as well doesn't help
when my frame rate goes down ooh oh man
I suck at this
why is it so hard to steer I got in the
first time no problem okay this is a
pretty straight hit and it broke okay
the a slur has definitely been some
changes with boat collision seems to be
more more definite system like it it's
going to break for sure now before it
was like depending on how you hit the
wall it would survive sometimes don't
freak out guys I see them I got them
almost threw those away well everyone
that's going to be all we do for today
but I have picked out one comment for us
to read together here which says yo
triple exclamation mark please read this
I'm doing it I'm doing it don't push me
I'm doing it do not switch to snapshot
13w 23a I logged in today with a new
snapshot on my world and all the clay
blocks and coal blocks disappeared all
the new blocks in general that worries
me because if you log in with it that
you've been a third statue will
disappear I'm not oh let's let Sun
ignore that last part because people
shouldn't do that
okay so I picked this comment because
this is something that might happen to
you guys it's not because he he upgraded
to that snapshot what happens is if you
downgrade after using one of the new
snapshots anything
that new snapshot you will lose possibly
like any new blocks or maybe even horses
if you downgrade to 1.5 - and then open
up your world you might lose your horses
when you upgrade again so you got to be
careful you make backups I make backups
all the time every time I downgrade I
make a backup just in case I forget to
upgrade before logging back in which I
have done many many times in the past as
has beatable Oh more times than me he
has wrecked his world yeah make backups
I've said it before I say it again and
be careful when upgrading it's it's
really easy to mess up now with the new
launcher because it's so easy and
convenient to switch versions you might
not think about it because it's not like
you have to move jars around anymore
very convenient but also a lot easier to
make a mistake with it
all right guys zenith smile for them
smile ah that's gonna be all for today
guys and thanks for watching have a good
day