hi hello get your snacks and welcome so
I'm pretty sure you can guess what I've
been working on the mob system got a lot
done probably 75% or so we are at y100
at this level here I wanted to get it
all done before this episode but it's
taking quite a while it's a big project
and my time is very constrained lately
so I don't have too much time for
Minecraft lately Oh burps excuse me
actually I said 75% and I have to
actually figure it out I need five more
layers 12 layers total so what would I
press wrong button ah it's about half
done I guess
dope also I know with the f3 you can do
it without the pie graph showing up if
you hold shift it's just a lot easier to
press f3 but yeah this is going pretty
good umm taking a long time lots of snow
this is from down below I am having a
bit of a problem with this though ever
since I started building it I've been
getting a weird leg Oh what did I fall
down well that's one way to start an
episode that sucked that was my old way
of getting down which I never did cover
that's weird I died from that I made
that fall because I threw the ender
pearl I bet you I shouldn't have done
that
ah alright give me a moment well this is
very interesting I think you're going to
get a kick out of this
a very wonderful case of irony and good
fortune has just fallen upon me pun
before gravity interrupted me there as
going to say I've been getting this
strange frame rate issue my frame rate
doesn't really drop like I watch it I
got the fraps counter in the corner and
it doesn't really change but I can tell
the video is very jerky I don't know if
you'll be able to see it in the
recording but I can see it right now
walking left and right here and I have
not been able to figure out what was
causing I thought it was from the mob
system I was building which didn't make
a lot of sense because there's actually
no block updates taking place in it like
even though it has Lampson they're not
being turned on or off red stones not
being switched there's water running but
it's not being updated or anything like
that so I was really confused why that
was causing my game to lay and I was
well there's one hint I was actually
considering maybe removing all the
redstone of it like making a backup and
removing the redstone to see if that was
a cause but you just heard one of the
causes
me falling in this room was one of the
best things ever because look what I
found I have inadvertently made a clock
there that's a detector I made to shut
off the silverfish firm when this room
fills up because it's all full right now
and it's not fully hooked up like the
shutoff switch and now I really think it
should I should get to finishing that
because it's not good if this room fills
up completely and doesn't shut things
off otherwise you get problems like lag
that I'm getting here this block got
moved down probably some wiring got
destroyed from that oh this is
silverfish I'm burping sorry I usually
don't drink coffee before I record but
sometimes I do and it's a mistake it
also seems to be a lot of slimes around
here lots of slime chunks maybe we'll go
hunt them real quick probably they're
there I definitely got to seal this up
I've had creepers come down if you give
an opportunity for a creeper to come
down they do you got to have at least
the three block like over you need a
four block drop look at all this you got
a four block drop mobs usually won't
fall down it but if it's three or less
they will always make their way to it
yea-ah thinking of a future slime farm
definitely a possibility
I actually that's one of the things I
might do today is finish up the old one
because I don't think I'm going to do
anything super fancy with it like I
originally planned I would rather just
make another one here
just finish that one up so much slide
that's crazy oh you know why because I
got the mob system running aha so
they're giving more ch
they're given more chances to spawn here
there's more all right we'll leave them
be anyway the mob system is up and
running I'm gonna disable that right now
and I'll be back because it's still
liking the game until I deal with it I'm
so glad I found that though because that
was really confusing me
alright so that detector there was
definitely the source of all my problems
I got rid of a repeater that was over
here broke the clock cycle and
everything is running super smooth again
which is just great I'm glad it wasn't
anything related to the mob system yeah
I inadvertently made a clock out of this
thing all I have to do is get rid of the
torch there and use a lever or something
else and it will work just fine and I
that's not hooked up though at the
moment just for the future what I wanted
to do oh yeah and people suggested I
should put colored wool behind these
tile things that might be pretty cool
I don't know what color I would choose
if I did that or colors water was also
suggested can't use lava or well
actually maybe I could I don't know if I
would want to though
yeah I think you could actually do lava
or leaves is another thing I was
thinking of doing but actually I wonder
if you were to put wall behind it if it
would be bright enough I guess yeah it
probably would the smooth stone looks
pretty bright back there it'd probably
be good I want to show the rate
as the mob system at the moment so we
got seven out of 12 layers done so just
a little bit more than 50% here we go I
just put some last year temporarily and
you can see we're not getting many mobs
at the moment it's probably nighttime
for one thing not larry'll but yeah
rates are really slow because I have a
lot of caves I need to light up in the
area yet before this thing is going to
get super quick so that will take that
will take time and I also have to finish
the other five layers or whatever and
that will improve things quite a bit as
well so all is good but it's going to be
slow until I do do those things um see
yeah I think we're going to go back to
the other base and work on the slime
stuff maybe I think that's a good plan
I'm tempted to break all these
silverfish things but it should probably
set up a killing chamber before I do
that because this room is totally full
now I got the lights on there so no more
spawning alright yeah let's go to the
other base okay here we are yeah we're
going to work on this a little bit when
I first made this glass thing it was
only supposed to be temporary but we've
kept it for many many months and it's
bug it's been bugging me ever since and
I'm sure it's been bugging you guys so I
want to get rid of the glass we we need
to sort of use a transparent block so we
can see the slimes I just don't like the
glass because the white really stands
out with it so we have to use another
transparent block
so iron bars are an option I was
thinking nether brick fences would be
cool and just tab open air spaces but
we'll play around with this a little bit
get her glass back and I also want to
try a cup the rail a little bit today
maybe because that was as a really cool
idea I think like a fun idea
but I've never hooked it up yet
procrastinating no you know the word see
so the big slimes are two point four
blocks I think all three directions how
is this going to work if we do that and
I guess we could have a one block gap
between like I don't think they'd be
able to fit through that for sure I have
another one here perhaps and here and
I'm just going to leave it as a manual
killing thing originally I planned on
having ways of of splitting the bigger
slimes and having the smaller ones go
into the next chamber and then splitting
them again and going into the next
chamber type thing but that's just not
really doesn't have much point to it
really all right let's see if this guide
you can get through here
all right so he's trapped I don't know
if I like the look of that hmm all right
what else can we do so I'm just going to
keep it like a manual killing thing so
we can walk in and kill him like that
can they fit through yeah I figured they
would mmm they even fit through there so
the medium ones are one point two blocks
in all three directions I believe the
little ones are 0.6 blocks so I don't
know how we would even do the little
ones I think we have to use half slabs
somehow because I'm pretty sure if we
did that they could fit through there
yeah cuz we can mmm
mmm all right well maybe we will work on
the rail line first I'll think about
this a little bit so if I can we put
this on glowstone you know we still
can't I should probably get rid of the
glowstone floor and put the minecart
track here right there OOP secret wiring
yeah I hate I hate messing up the floor
around here because there's a lot of
stuff underneath the ground okay we'll
just put this here from now we'll put
one yeah we'll just do one who found me
how did you find me whoop go like that
and then go this way and if we do this
let's see so hopefully they'll go in
that and then if we have a pressure
plate here over here I think when they
get in the cards they'll automatically
hit the pressure plates and then take
off so I think that might be an
automatic launcher for the big slimes I
hope
okay so I was messing around with this a
little bit and I found something for the
little guys here they can't fit through
that space so if we have a iron bar
that's not connected to the wall over
there and then we have a block over here
we can hold them back or hold them
inside doing that so I'll probably
probably do that for little ones and
have a half slab here maybe we're going
to do this for the medium ones but I
don't think it's going to work because
these count as full blocks with our
collision masks we can't hit through
them
can't throw ender pearls through or
anything like that I'm having a hard
time making it look good I don't know
what to do like something like that
would I believe hold them but that looks
terrible use nether I think they would
work the same as or have the same basic
shape is an iron bar
yeah I wish I was an invisible block
actually no what I would like to try
this might work at we have a half slab
here one here and water they won't be
able to jump if they're in water and
that might hold them down and they'll
drown the little ones will I think the
medium and the large ones would be fine
though that's an idea that looks that
looks a lot better than having these
bars everywhere or glass or leaves or
anything like that so you will try that
I'm just waiting for a big slab to test
this let's see if it will automatically
launch and when it automatically
launches we want it to go down here go
over a detector rail the detector rail
will cause a cart from a stack to
probably go back this way and go into
the position for the next big slide and
if there's an empty cart on them on the
main loop here a detector will send it
back into the stack I think that's the
logic we need to do with this okay so
long story short I got a little bit
frustrated waiting for these guys to
spawn so I went to create a world to
speed things up a little bit and I built
this to mimic the drop for the big guys
just having a too high gap here is
enough to keep them in there it looks
fairly good with the minecart I'm pretty
sure I need to use a water stream and
the key is I have to have it in motion
when it picks them up I can't just leave
it sitting there so whoop-whoop die what
I'll probably do is stick a pressure
plate in here somewhere and when they
step on that like right now it's down
that will make a cart come and pick them
up like that and it will also trigger an
RS nor latch for for picking them up
right and then when when they're heading
back I think I'll make them go over
another pressure plate like if we have
one there that's being press right now
from their huge size and that will
trigger the RS nor latch back to normal
resetting the thing just so that it
doesn't keep sending card after card
after cart we need to control the rate
the carts are our scent so it has to
pick them up and then they have to be
sent away before another card gets sent
assuming there is a slime here which is
pressure plate will tell us so that is
sort of the plan let's see if this guy
will get picked up too
we'll give me a sword this is going to
be a short episode I got to go to bed
here pretty quick and if my episode
seemed a little bit lower quality I'm
sorry
there's not much I can do though just
with work and whatnot very good okay
that's why I think I'll do I think the
RS nor latch is very important for this
for the medium guys we can have a
one-block space or we can use water to
hold them down we're not sending them in
carts or anything so it's going to be a
lot simpler very good okay let's head
back to the LP world all right so I've
been messing with this a little bit more
and I might go with something like this
this is good for the little guys because
the water will Auto drown them if we
choose if we don't want that happening
we can take it out
I'm a hook-up a piston that'll lower
this block and let water in I don't know
looks cooler if the water is not running
though but yeah that'll hold them in
they can't get through this half half
block space we can punch them through
that pick up their drops through that so
should be good for them for the medium
guys you might do something like this it
won't auto kill them but that's not
necessarily bad we don't want we don't
want to kill them because I'm gonna get
all these little slimes running around
all over the place so this will hold
them
and although another thing I could do is
just maybe have one stare here and then
stare there and one over there
just to get that block height so they
can't escape and the water will hold
them down then we wouldn't need this
I got stairs I do whoa that glitch is
still in the game
Auto jumping if we do that let's put
this way I'm worried I'm gonna wreck
some wiring below or something um yeah
we'll just we'll do that not to get
chances do that OOP oh that's not good
that is not good what did we do mmm all
right good put a stopper there I think
ahead sometimes we did destroy one wire
I believe here okay
this is actually looking pretty good I
might keep it like this
we got a slime on the way so I want to
see if this will work
oh no he's gonna drown mmm right he's
fine he's kind of drown I could be wrong
still not drowning so maybe it's fine
let's see if this guy will stack yeah
okay so he's not drowning that's great
we will then put the minecarts over here
so we'll connect it that way sneak it in
and put those there I don't that's
that's kind of a cool effect I like it a
lot more than the glass anyway and if we
get more medium guys that you will stack
there so pretty cool let's out light
because we got closed stone underneath
we'll have to stick our button in
somewhere here all in all that's isn't
left isn't too bad all right well I said
I was going to go and I think I'm going
to go for good now for today thanks for
watching everybody I will try to keep
the episodes coming as much as I can
during my busy season and I will see you
again next time
again tall I'm tired okay bye
you