[Music]
hahahaha the quest for orange sand
continues everybody this stupid thing
has given me so much trouble
you have no idea originally I made it
where you get this like afk and hold
right click in there but it would Jam
every so often so then I made it swear
like gravity would feed it sand and
you'd use the timing of the sand falling
to kind of control it but even that
would jam every so often the sand was
falling too quickly so now I've made
like this hopper feeding system that
we're gonna try out and hopefully this
will finally solve all my problems in
life now the thing is how quick can you
get this running is the question
probably faster than that right faster
oh we're going too quick no this is what
that was afraid okay slow down so it's a
if you go too quick it'll push the sand
before it's it's done falling I think
this is our limit here and then it just
starts spurting out everywhere
uh-huh what did you think it was going
to say actually it's a probably better
you don't answer that so this thing is
it's running good now so we can just
leave it do its thing and every every so
often I just go to the top there and
drop in sand let's head over here I just
saw a tweet apparently they're gonna add
a recipe in the in the release for
packed ice you know the stuff I make the
boat roads out of probably I'm guessing
it's gonna be 9 ice per packed ice and
then it's 9 packed ice for the new block
that's coming out the blue ice so
there's a good reason to start farming
this stuff up and I better I better do
that actually wait we we should curve us
from the top top down is the easiest way
to do it
yeah so this farm is gonna get a lot of
useful again
I kind of stopped harvesting it just
because I had so much stop stop but I'm
never gonna use it right but
this is kind of weird look at that that
detector rails broken it's stucked on
and it stops there what dude we have a
defective rail here why is something no
nothing's powering it it's like we have
an invisible entity stuck on the rail or
something and that's what's gliding into
right oh I bet you there's an invisible
minecart there how do we get rid of it
okay I was wondering why this farm keeps
breaking there's an invisible minecart
here I think if we drop it down
well let that just get rid of it
hopefully I in place a block there maybe
not this is something I've never
encountered before I didn't know
invisible mine carts were a thing I
think this was from one of those
snapshots maybe or one of the updates
made all my mine carts like get messed
up there's another like really weird
thing about this I can put like a
detector rail here right but apparently
whatever is in this spot deletes any
blocks I place in it okay not okay I
take that back maybe only certain blocks
yeah look at this so the stone
disappears so we can place the detector
rails there we can place torches there
for some reason I'm a little scared to
put ice because it might wash away the
tracks so it has a problem with blocks
and you'll notice like I'm not it's not
that I can't place the block there it's
not like I try to place in and
disappears them look at the number it's
actually going down it's destroying the
block I place
well I really don't know what to do
about it so what what can we do right
side just blocked off this spot it's
gonna hurt the performance of the farm a
little bit but it should be still pretty
good unless you guys have an idea of
what to do about it
but I couldn't find anything it's not
affected by gravity or damage or or
collision with me or anything if I try
to push the minecart through it it
doesn't move it it's just like a an
entity with no AI that's invisible lens
I don't know it's weird I had OH
a weird thing happened here with our
mini farm - I think I've showed this off
before but we're running out of golden
carrots we need more food here so I went
to use this and wasn't really working -
well it seems fine now
but if you guys ever have trouble with
this thing what I would recommend you do
like if you if you build it for yourself
add a little extra redstone to its it
seems fine now that I've restarted my
game but before when I was having
trouble I did this and that seemed to
fix it yeah I don't know if you have
trouble do that although I don't know if
this works properly on a server
regardless but if you're in a
single-player and it's giving you
trouble
this should should fix it probably oh no
no no no I had a really close call just
a second ago he was at the top of the
stairs and I didn't see him he was like
right here and I walked up one block
away from him and I freaked out so guys
in the last episode we worked on this
canopy and we built that mushroom house
and stuff and I got called out I got
called out for doing too much building
lately
not enough redstone not enough gizmos
and stuff so hey I love doing redstone
if somebody ever calls me out on it I
have no problem
doing more that's that's what I love to
do so we're gonna do I've been a
redstone to date it's trying to think
what's what redstone project would be
fun what's something that we have to use
our heads on and I was thinking I
haven't really used a lot of concrete
sort of concrete powder not as much as I
would like to it's a new blocked in the
game that has a lot of potential I think
I've seen some really good like interior
design using the concrete's so I was
thinking okay let's let's do something
where we firm concrete right but the
thing is it's like you hold right click
what is it left click ohh I don't not do
it oh I got to switch it right yeah like
it's so easy to farm this stuff I can't
really do anything redstone revolving
around it's like so perfected already
just the way it is right so here's what
I want to do since there's not really
much to concrete right let's let's take
concrete's and really over-engineer
something towards it because we actually
don't have a spot for it in the Nexus or
in the man cave storage room so if we
get a bunch of concrete powder or
concrete blocks I have nowhere to store
it right now so let's make this room for
storing it for crafting it's and just
like we'll make every little tedious
aspect of making concrete's
over-engineered to the maximum sounds
like fun let's do it okay
by the way another weird thing just
happened here this cat teleported to me
and it's a broken cat it doesn't move I
think it's from the mob system but I
don't know why it would have teleported
here alright everybody so I guess let's
get started on figuring things out here
what I want to do is this build the
different redstone components separately
and try to understand how how to combine
them together and then once we get
everything figured out we'll build a big
fancy concrete and concrete powder room
where we we craft and store all the
different colors and stuff possibly
other things to like we might do all the
color
walks in the game like wool and clay and
glass in the room as well like a big
color room but the first thing we're
gonna work on here is a selection system
I want to use maybe two item frames here
for all the 16 different colors in the
game and depending on what we select
like if we go to orange if we're
crafting concrete's then as we're
crafting it it's gonna dispense orange
dye at us if we're requesting an item
out of storage then it's gonna select
the orange items and maybe we have a
button to select between concrete powder
the blocks wool glass and then it's
gonna select life we hit the clay button
then this is at orange then we get
orange clay if that makes sense
anyways let's sleep real quick here so
the challenging part of this is how do
we take the signal out of the item frame
and select like a dropper like we'll
probably have a row of droppers with the
different colors of dye in or different
blocks like orange red pink how do we
choose or how do we make the signal
choose which dropper because we can't
activate them all at the same time right
we'll get all the colors in so basically
this will go for a distance of 8 and I
think the trick with this I've seen this
done before you go I think you add an
extra row on top actually we'll wait
before we do that I think we need
repeaters I kind of know how to do this
already so I think we have a row of
repeaters down here and those go into
set of blocks like this and then I think
you have redstone torches on the other
side oh I hate that if there's grass in
the way it always defaults to on the
ground even if you click it the yeah
anyways yeah I think we have a row above
then and then we make the Redstone go
along the top and then we have another
row of repeaters here it's kind of a
weird way of doing this
I think it works and we set these two
three right we'll just try this out see
if it works and then on top of the
torches we have another row of blocks
it's not super compact or anything but
is a tricky thing to do and I think we
just have torches yeah look at that okay
so it's selected the fourth one and as
we spin this it should cycle through
them that's pretty cool all right yeah
so the way that works over there it's
basically a collection of and dates and
it's looking for the case where this
block the lower block is powered and
this one isn't any other combination
like if we if we go down it goes off
still off still off so it's only when
this is unpowered and this one's powered
that that turns on and that's the only
one where the redstone is is on down
here and off here all the other ones
it's either on or off off is the way it
makes that comparison aha so I think
then what we got to do is probably have
some sticky pistons next to this and the
one that's powered will get extended and
then we put blocks at the end of this
and then run some repeaters into them
probably mmm it's gonna be a little bit
tricky actually we had to find a
situation where like the repeaters won't
bud power the droppers because like this
they will like if we put something in
there it activates it not just the one
where the blocks extended so it'll work
if we have them facing up like this oops
because then like if we put something in
here
there's no block there can't activate it
and the one that has the block extended
over here will work but we want to shoot
the items into a a water stream right so
we would have to then put ice above the
droppers here and then the items might
shoot randomly cuz they'll have to
travel through a block so I don't really
like that hmm I just realized like a lot
of what we're doing here is
to the Nexus so I was like well I went
over there
how did I do though the water streams
there and it was it was like this so we
have the dropper facing into the ice
like that and I just like as the item
goes into the icer raises up into the
water stream above before it shoots out
the other side I think we'll try it out
here just make sure so if we load that
up with items put this on and see if any
of them shoots where they where they
don't belong
are they shooting out no it's just a
visual glitch as long as every item goes
through the water stream that's fine it
looks like it is so that's good and now
I don't know what to do I kind of got
caught there is like wait a bit what am
i doing I've done this before yeah I
don't really just want to copy the Nexus
again I was excited to use a selector
panel because I think it's cool but in
order to use it we pretty much have to
do like what we did with the Nexus
so rather than this let's try to do a
different storage system might not be
like over-engineered or anything no like
I was planning messing with my card
storage system and I had one idea here
where you basically get a hopper mind
curtain like so and then it'll as the
scraps amol here we'll throw it in the
chest basically you know even fill up
these chests you don't have to sort the
items and then like when you want to
grab items out of there you just create
a filter in the minecart like that and
then when it passes by it'll pick up a
few of the items even bounce it back and
forth on the track to get more thinking
about maybe doing something like that
but it seemed not so great I think it'd
be kind of slow and there'd be a lot of
complications to it alright everybody so
not to worry I have finally decided what
we're gonna do with the storage system
here and rather than going like overly
engineered and complex
like a nexus sort of system I decided
let's go the opposite routes super
simple super effective super compact
because yeah I just don't want to do the
same thing again that's not really why
you guys watch me right you want you
want to see a new idea right I think
that would be a lot more fun so we're
gonna do a minecart system kind of like
I was looking at but a little bit
different
rather than using chess we're gonna use
oh I need a hopper minecarts one second
we're gonna use storage minecarts for
the storage instead of instead of chests
here so here I'm just gonna break one of
these snag a hopper so we use this
hopper minecarts to filter the items to
retrieve what we want out of the system
we just put it above the slab there and
then we're gonna build this so quick
it's it's so simple I think that this
level here is where we want it and then
we put some rails above this and I don't
like the rail facing that way I kind of
want it this way if I break that yeah
I'll still they'll still go that way
good good you know what I just realized
these aren't cold storage minecarts
they're called mine carts with chests
who named it that's a terrible name
we've always called them storage bankers
like why didn't they get that name I
don't get it
all right anyway so we put a bunch of
storage mine carts up above here and the
more we have the more storage the
system's gonna have but we got to be
careful with this the more we add the
slower it's gonna be at finding the
items we want so I think I'm only gonna
put maybe 16 in there as our limit
oh is that three four five six I
probably missed counted let's just do
eight to begin with to test this all
right we can put items into those mine
carts just by putting a hopper facing
sideways like that and then above that
we will put a chest so any items we
throw in here will go into storage in
these mine carts right let's see here
let's drop down the ender chest will
actually start putting our concrete in
here if I put it in here there it is
found it alright so basically as we
craft the the concrete or as we want to
drop it off we just throw it in here
nice and simple we don't have to assign
a specific chest to the items they look
let's go into the storage minecarts
according to where they can fit and the
other thing we want to do is kind of
like what the Nexus we're gonna have a
menu system so back here we can have
some chests with items in and so let's
say let's get this going in first we
just have a few stacks items here and
then whenever we want to find an item we
just look in here and it's like okay
throw that's press Q goes into here and
then when we raise that up probably have
some garbage items in here too like
stone for the four of the slots what
we'll do is do I have any ice we should
have after all we harvested today is it
under odd blocks I got an ami okay that
works out basically one thing I'm gonna
do here is add I think at that level
yeah add a little bit of redstone down
there so we can flick it up with a
pressure plate and we'll have ice so
that the items slide on there easy and
then just put a pressure plate on the
top now when we step on this it'll raise
the minecart up underneath the slab here
and then any black concrete in the
minecarts and get picked up and pretty
quickly but again the more of these you
have the slower it's gonna take for it
to find the items mm-hmm so I tried to
give this a bit more of a finished look
but I'm not super confident about my
building here in Slab City just yet
maybe a little keep it like this I'm
hoping as we we build more here things
are gonna start tying together better
and feeling more polished but anyways
let's this focus on the system for right
now here so yeah if you didn't get how
that this works basically what we do is
we create a menu system here with our
different items we plan on storing in
the system Aftab have to add the
concrete blocks here yet but for the
powder for example let's say I want to
get orange concrete powder you do is you
just slide it there and press Q ends up
going into the minecart here and then
when we step on this any orange concrete
powder in the storage of minecarts will
get picked up here if we want to pick up
more orange you can just right click
here and it'll keep grabbing more but
otherwise if that's all you want you
just hop off here grab it
and then move on you drop stuff off here
and it'll go into storage nice and
simple then you want the next time and
let's say we want blue that's not too
bad right it's quick it's easy decent
amount of storage I think it works
really good for this case where we just
have like 32 different items we want to
store and it's like a few stacks of each
of them I think that's good ok so then
the next thing we're gonna do here is
add our farming area on top so I don't
know where's the middle here I think yes
all we got to do now is hook up some
hoppers to this to our chests here so do
I have them yes I do
awesome so just hook up hoppers here one
more and then go on top perfect ender
pearl throw yes ok oh I can't I place it
oh you know what if you if you're in the
middle there you can't jump high enough
to place the next one interesting and
yeah so then we just need some water up
here next to the hopper and let's give
this a
try so let's go grab some concrete out
of the storage here some of the powder
let's go for let's get some more blue I
don't think we have too many different
colors in there right now I know we have
oranges we have blue so I'll just grab a
stack of blue out of there I would like
to make a bit of an elevator or a slime
block launcher to get up here maybe on
another side here anyways we get this
press F to put it in our offhand and
since it's gonna be placed right above
the hopper here and broken the hopper
should always pick it up but let's give
it a try I guess the crafting table
doesn't work does it maybe if I hold the
shift oh okay that was a mess alright
that's working right I think we we have
a winner here so probably a FG here with
with the powder and stuff I guess we
want some way of dispensing it as we're
doing that so we don't run out cuz
otherwise once the stack runs out here
we're gonna stop so I want to set this
up so we just hold right click and afk
oh and then we break the hopper too
anyways so up above here is gonna be a
crafting station I want to set up a big
bulk storage for sand and gravel and
probably a bunch of the dyes will be up
here so we can craft that the powder up
here and then convert it over and then I
guess a dispenser system for shooting
more powder at us so we don't run out
and that'll be pretty much it I think
now how do I get that hopper I guess I
got to throw a hopper there we go we got
it oops if you don't put a filter there
it'll just grab whatever's first in the
system uh-huh
actually let's just try something here
with the dispensing system probably
don't need to do anything complicated
all right we just let's put that there
for right now have the observer
detecting when the block breaks and then
just a dropper right
let's let's put the dropper here for now
face us into a block maybe some redstone
it'd be nice if we could do it without
redstone showing actually strawberry
here so then we can have like some extra
powder in there if we want and that you
can probably make this nicer so that we
don't accidentally misplace the concrete
powder and put some string above let's
just try that right now maybe you want a
different block besides string switch
this pretty simple seems like it'll work
uh-huh well cool I think that turned out
pretty good I'm happy with that we'll
probably add more on to it in another
episode but for today guys it is time to
wrap up here's the book let's check out
the comment of the day it says hey etho
I was wondering if you ever considered a
different way to make nether connections
now that the light sure has been out for
so long
notice I said difference not the
indifference as you guys always think I
say you you think I put an N in
somewheres I don't think I do it you
guys are crazy
different different not DIF different
anyways the problem with straight
tunnels is the distance as going
straight for 400 blocks and then left
for another 300 could be cut out with
just a straight 500 so go diagonal
instead of like one way and another way
what I do is blast holes through the
landscape with TNT and just fly around
through them you move faster with the
light ray it's a more direct route and
you can have some fun I make different
rings to try to fly through on my way as
it keeps me entertained the only issue
that I could see is the possibility to
lose places yeah you know what I think
if you're going like somewhere far in
the nether it's not a big deal just to
fly through the nether with the lighter
wings like usually it's not that
dangerous and you rarely run into
anything in the nether it's pretty open
most the time but I do like having
tunnels I think they're always gonna be
good to have and I recommend you go into
the
they're sealing and just make like a
three-high tunnel or something like with
all the rockets here you're you don't
have any trouble flying through
something like this so you can even make
them diagonal if you want as well as
long as your roof is flat like you if
it's flat you can glide along the top
here and you'll never hit it or gets hit
your head on something you know if
you're not flying perfectly straight
well it's not hard to like move around
in a tunnel like this I do think so as
great as the light ray is for getting
around and stuff I still prefer I think
boat roads are still the way to go for
any like long-term passage in the nether
here like I think they're quicker it
could be wrong but I think it's faster
and the blue ice that's coming I was
gonna be even quicker I think there's a
bit slower to start out but then once
you're going it's it's quick and it's
easy to take a turn like BAM no problem
and it's I don't know I think it's cool
so I recommend boat roads still I
wouldn't really do a light for tunnels
uh-huh anyways I think that's gonna be
it for today guys so hopefully you
enjoyed it thank you for watching as
always and I'll see you again in the
next one take care bye bye
[Music]