[Music]
hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
back guys I got something to show you
I've been trying to figure out how to do
this for so long and I did it today I
saw it happen
it's a controlled case let's see if we
can figure this mystery out I'm sure
somebody's already explained how this
happens but I have no clue I haven't
found any information on this yet but
there's a portal glitch in the game
where if you break the portals in a
certain way somehow it just breaks some
of the portal blocks and not the whole
portal so we have a functioning portal
up here still I can make a 2x2 portal
from this which is pretty crazy let's
see if it still works still works very
good go back through and oh I just dig a
little bit of damage if I do that though
okay but I am gonna update this I want
to see if we can recreate this so
unfortunately even though I made it
happen here I'm gonna destroy it because
as soon as you update a block by it I
found it destroys it so there goes so
the way I made it though does it still
work I was in the middle of fixing this
portal and darn it I need fire let's go
get some fire real quick oh that was so
yeah I was I was gonna go work behind
the portal there on some stuff and I
pressed one of the buttons and it made
water come out and that caused that to
happen somehow I don't know if I can
replicate it or not but if we can we can
figure out how it happens probably so
let's hope we can replicate it here
all right so I'm gonna light it again
all I do is I press this button and it
happened now okay darn it so there is
some special situation where it happens
it's not just the layout there's some
reason it happens maybe if we go through
once and then come back through and I
think it happens when the portal is is
weird like this you see how this block
is different maybe let's see if that
glitched it now it still looks like a
proper portal okay so I guess we won't
figure it out today after all uh but
anyway I've gone ahead and I fixed that
portal so it does three things now let's
let's check this out well I did three
before but now they actually work so we
have you light it you can clear it and
the third super secrets wasn't placed
for a button so I had to hide its
function is do you throw a blocker or
anything over here it'll pick it up and
turns the portal on for just the right
amount of time to go through and then it
destroys it behind you so we can go
ahead and check this out back here I've
been doing a lot of like fixing fixing
things around here and finishing things
around the man team I think that's
really important otherwise I think I'll
become pretty unhappy with the way
things are because a lot of things were
breaking and it's never it's never like
satisfying when you when you're around
all this stuff all the time that's that
that you know is broken so to get it
working again it's awesome oh yeah
there's just there's a bunch of stuff
back here and then we wouldn't decide
what to put for the backing yet one idea
I had actually was maybe we should put
some some maps or something back here
because we can we can totally hide all
the blocks in the back there if we put
maps over top
and it might look pretty cool if we do
it right or even a custom nap but that
might be a pain to creates I don't know
but it still works if you do this so if
we go through now if we close it behind
us takes us to the nether hub but then
when we go back it will take us to the
snowflake like I originally intended so
we're up here on the snowflake honestly
I can't quite remember what my idea was
with the snowflake so I don't know what
I'm supposed to do with it and I don't
really have any ideas I think my plan
with this was just to have a cool high
up portal that you could jump down and
have fun jumping down or ender pearl a
long distance from here because you
gotta have the heights so if you ender
pearl the ender pearls go really really
far where did that take us yeah took us
quite a ways away and the thing is
though I also did that thing with my
spawn where I have the boats way up in
the sky there and I think that's a lot
more fun than if we were to do voting
off of this thing so not sure I'm gonna
make any adjustments to this it is fun
to jump off though gonna say oh not a
good part of town let's head back into
the man cave I got some other things to
show you though just before I started
recording
yikes gotta work on security out here I
started working on the entrance to this
I haven't gotten very far but I'm
considering putting like flowers and
stuff all along here you're making beds
like at different layers might be kind
of cool ooh look at this look at this
what it does to the camera though it
like your vision is really narrow then
when you go down it it makes it really
wide and then it goes back to narrow I
don't know if that's good or not it's
kind of cool though ah but then there's
another thing I was working on over here
let's go take a look
just after I worked on that portal I
worked on this I have put in a little
garden here which I really really liked
you actually it doesn't make a lot of
sense but I think it looks cool i
hollowed out the rocks here and just
planted a bunch of junk and put a lot of
green and some light sand and whatnot so
yeah it doesn't make a lot of sense I
have these things in the front just to
give it some some more depth and also
make it look like it's somehow still
structurally intact I guess and then I'm
starting to make a path going out this
way this goes behind Wilson might have
like glass along here so we can look at
the wiring from from like a bridge or
something here would be cool Wilson's
right down there and maybe make a path
going this way that way a bridge will
like over top this area and another path
going down below it's kind of get that
crisscross feeling going I think would
be pretty cool but I do have a project I
want to do with you guys today so let's
see let's get started on that this
should be pretty cool if we can pull it
off I want to put in a fountain in this
pool of water here I want it to turn on
when we're by it I don't want it running
it for not by it and it's it's just to
be decorative and something fun to look
at sort of thing and we are not doing it
out of water we're making a snowball
fountain which I think it'll work out
okay we have this snow machine right
over here right
know that I was able to pick that up I
thought that might go in the hopper Kurt
ah you just get your shovel whale on the
snow for a little bit and you'll get
like tons and tons of snowballs doing
this pretty quickly this all funnels
down into a storage system that we set
up a long time ago father actually that
empty really quick I can't remember how
I have this set up but I must've did
something fancy oh yeah we got a bunch
of storage chests down here and you can
see they're filling up little by little
so we got to take the snowballs from
here and we're gonna move them to some
dispensers hidden under the water here
is the plan I think we'll have to do two
fountains unfortunately I would just do
one except it's an even number so I
can't really center its which stinks
this is why you must always work with
Eva or with odd numbers it's just I
don't know if you ever do anything even
it seems like there's trouble eventually
so let's try to find out it's sort of
the middle if we're just putting two
dispensers I guess that would be maybe
see this is one two wait one two three
four five the middle would be here maybe
let's put a forward one block and we'll
stick one right here go down another
block so we can hide a hopper underneath
the ground or something going into the
dispenser then we'll put another one
over here and hopefully this works out
okay all right let's just see if that's
centered or not it's not centered we
can't really Center it perfectly but
yeah that should be fine that that's
kind of the middle this way and it's
centered nicely this way I guess I don't
know
so now we're gonna have to set up a
minecart system to move these
snow balls over there so I'm gonna dig
some tunnels and see if we can make her
way from there to there and connect them
together hmm okay this is gonna be a
little tough to do we don't have a lot
of space to work with I haven't I
haven't found the shortest path yet
either the best path but I did find an
easy way in just over here so these are
the dispensers the water is right above
that's the problem
oh I didn't make I lost a bunch of my
redstone stuff like I I must have put it
somewhere I have no idea where it all
ran off to so I'm remaking everything
pretty much now it's um dropper is going
so we gotta get snow balls to that one
and that one from a minecart and make it
all automatic and the problem is usually
hoppers when you're dealing with hoppers
stuff goes downward like we're gonna try
fill it chests with snowballs I think a
double chest between these two and we
will put maybe a hopper here to fill it
and then how do we get from from the
chest to these and we need this one
block above it otherwise like if you
have a block above it you can't open the
chest and stuff from the hopper can't go
into it alright so don't have a lot of
space to work with here but I think if
we just put in a few extra Stoppers we
can make this work OOP oh man come on no
I don't think I can do it it's not gonna
let me can't do it in a jump
nope darn I really don't want to break
that ceiling okay but the idea is we
might be able to make it work if we if
we do it like this gets get these going
like this and break that that's fine
all right and then do that on the other
side and then if we send a redstone
pulse here I think a single pulse will
make make it'll activate a dropper here
one there and the dispenser up here all
in that one shot so if I can get a
dropper there we're gonna have to do it
the hard way I'd yes and yeah we'll take
that out it's just safe to remove Oh Oh
careful careful
better block it this is not easy doing
redstone around water it's the worst
thing in the world all right that'll do
okay so we almost got it all set up here
I put in a temporary lever here just so
we'll be able to watch it from from up
here
I made this go down this goes to a clock
and into these stop I hope it doesn't
make that noise I think if I put a few
snowballs in beforehand it won't because
that dropper noise that dropper noise is
so annoying okay so these go to these
these hoppers from the chest this is the
main storage chest for the snowballs we
fill that from here send a storage
minecart over top and I have a automatic
unloading thing set up right now so
comparator goes to this redstone torch
and that goes up to this wire which
powers the power rail so when a cart
arrives and stuff starts going through
this hopper this goes off until the cart
is fully unloaded so it'll wait there
too it'll stop and wait until it's
totally unloaded before it goes back for
more snowballs which is what we want and
then we're gonna make this come down
to the pickup line it's really not that
far I had to make more power rails to
you because I don't know where my power
rails ran off to you losing all kinds of
things actually let's do it like this
okay cool so we will have power rails
here for sure
get some tracks go in and both our rails
all the way up here there and we can
just power this well let's do that for
now so the carts the store charts gonna
come here
and we got to make it know when to take
off I guess let's see how do we do that
I've done this before but is it not
loading oh yeah it is loading you how do
we make you take off I can't I think of
how to do that right now
hmm I think we can just a second here I
think we can put a comparator next is
cart I'm sure I came up with a good way
of doing this before or there's there's
probably an easy way of doing this I
just need to stop and think of it for a
sec does this not power it oh yeah that
has to be a detector rail for it to do
that
okay so I went into a greater world to
try to work out a solution I don't think
there's really like a super good one or
at least I don't know a super good way
of telling what a minecart is full
I could put a detector rail here with
the comparator next to it and I could
figure out when mine carts fold that way
but if there's a detector rail by this
hopper it's gonna power the hopper and
that'll prevent it from sending items to
the minecarts so there's that and yeah
so I decided to go with a timer so when
the cart goes over this detector rail
it's gonna activate a hopper timer down
below and I don't know how long it needs
to run for is this coming back it come
on oh good timing yeah very good timing
all right that emptied accidentally oh
yeah okay that's a problem so why did it
didn't work at all why is this powered
that's not supposed to be powered
wait a second Oh Oh the comparator is
powering this okay one second we could
probably fix this real quick just by
moving the detector rail over one doo
doo doo
Oh minecarts redstone so much fun move
okay we just about got it here just
about I think and we'll make this a
repeater so that power can't go this way
do this and this and that should do it
yeah okay it stopped good click it
yeah it's filling so this is a hopper
timer it is like a it doesn't run all
the time though this is a special
version where this is a regular piston
and this is a sticky piston normally in
a hopper timer I have a sticky piston on
both sides if you just do it on the one
side when you when you power it here
it'll go and it'll come back and then
it'll stop and that's it so that's kind
of cool so next thing is just to figure
out the timing looks like it needs to be
a bit longer and we will get that going
and then we can go check out the
snowball fountain so let's go do that
all right everybody ready
this is snowball fountain tick number
one here we go whoa wait a minute I
think I disconnected this that's right I
remember now because it was annoying me
oh oh oh oh we're missing it
oh yeah I like it I like it a lot
okay so here's another thing we can do
with it though let's do a couple of
these going if we want them to shoot
higher we got to get make it less water
above the dispenser right now it's three
three blocks of water above we put this
here I'll make it two might even want to
try to make it one but we'll see how two
is okay there we go tape number 200 well
we had one super-high snowball oh yeah
they're hitting the bridge now oh yeah
that is pretty sweet
okay let's see how that dwindled down
our supplies that next thing is we're
gonna have to get this so it's
proximity-based like when I'm near it
only otherwise we're gonna blow through
my stash of snowballs very quickly okay
not too bad I think it took out the top
two rows of this chest and we left it
running for quite a while there these
are all full yet okay that's doable and
this will run automatically the main
thing is we'll just have to go to the
snow snow machine up there and and
refill it every so often but there's I
think three double chests at least of
storage so it should last for quite a
while let's go see it one more time then
I'll try figure out some way of setting
up a player sensor to it
how does that look from up here
I like that a lot that is really cool I
love the splashing sound you hear the
splashing sound let's crank this up what
would that be under let's just turn them
all up
probably ambient in an environment that
would guess oh yes no ball fountain I
love it
another cool idea maybe not here but
maybe some other time we'll put arrows
and lava above and have like a fire
arrow fountain or something somewhere
I'd be cool okay so just doing some
finishing touches on the snow ball
fountain I'm trying to put in the
proximity sensor to it so this is all
full now
I heard it's did a bunch of snowballs
and we got more ready and waiting to go
so when this is all full by the way this
just sits here and waits that's what I
want it to do because there's no point
for it to move if if it still has
snowballs and I got a redstone thing
going up here might need to lower this
some more but we'll see how this goes
then we will connect we'll put a
repeater here I think but before we do
that I don't always snow balls well over
down here this is again a hopper timer
where we have a regular piston on one
and a sticky one here which means it's
like a one time activated timer instead
of always running so we're gonna get a
snow golem right here and he's gonna try
I guess we need glass block here he's
gonna try to walk towards this pressure
plate when we're nearby before within 32
blocks of him he'll do that that goes to
here activates the timer if he keeps
pressing on this it doesn't matter it's
still going so while this is activated
the fountains are gonna be running and
now it's it's in a cool-down state
so this should help to conserve the
snowballs and only make it go when we
want it to and not all the time so the
last thing to do let's get our snow
golem in here I used a cow last time I
think it's snow golems gonna work out
better as long as he doesn't escape all
right there you go and he's gonna wanna
move if we give him a place to go so
let's open that up the cow did a steep
on my last sensor which has me a little
worried if this guy gets free he's gonna
make a big mess which I don't really
want all right so I guess let's do it
get it going
there we go and head on up and all see
how it works
I know my way around here all right here
going that might this might be a problem
though for if we build lower down and
we're always down in the cave yeah this
is Wilson is Wilson no not even close
all right here we are so I'm gonna go up
here and see if it activates oh yeah it
is going woohoo might need to lower it I
don't know or put a randomizer so it
doesn't go as often I want it to be like
a treat when it goes off I don't want it
going off like all the time I would like
to go and I hope that I just don't want
to refill it all the time that would be
very time wasting gonna go again
but pretty cool a little snowball
fountain oh yeah it's going again so
it's gonna go all the time it looks like
currently so we'll definitely want to
slow that down some more okay so as far
as I can tell this is only running when
I start going down these stairs
unless I'm just not hearing it but I
don't think it's been running I might
lower the sensor a little bit yet though
just to make it like if it would
activate right when I got like here that
would be perfect I think um anyway let's
move on to the comments and watches
while we do it first one says hey etho
what happened to the church creeper you
captured in the potion room Jeff our
buddy Jeff he despawned unfortunately he
did have a nametag on him so he should
have despawned but I accidentally must
have joined the game in peaceful mode as
I I do sometimes cuz like I'll if I'm
working on something in creative mode
I'll usually do that in peaceful mode
then when I come into my world this
thing is really going sometimes I forget
to switch it too hard and I think I must
have done that because just one day when
I checked he was gone if we ever want to
capture mobs in the future we're gonna
stick him them in the end probably
because I almost never login in the end
so they should be safe there so if we
ever get a charged creeper in the future
that challenge is gonna be to get him to
the end I think next one hey etho I did
Sarah's song in Minecraft a year or two
ago I'd be happy to give you the notes
and how to do it keep up the great work
awesome as always thank you very much
last episode I asked about Zelda songs
Sarah song in particular thanks for the
offer somebody has already done this for
me dr. Valle Zak
thanks dr. Vose that he has given me a
very descriptive way of setting up
Sarah's song already and all the notes
exactly how many clicks they take and
all that so hopefully get around to that
sometime soon I don't know where I'm
gonna put the note blocks so one idea I
had although I probably wouldn't get
used much as if we put the note blocks
down this tracker it's a very long track
and we could have a activates by
detector rails probably and play the
notes as we ride it but it would only
work going one way and it would be
reversed the other way and I almost
never use this so I might need to find a
better place of putting it I'm not sure
yet though
but that's gonna be it for today guys
thanks for watching I hope you enjoyed
the episode and I hope you have a great
day so take care and bye bye
[Music]