[Music]
ah
yeah feels so good so
good it is finally done
the mob system is built we are up in the
cloud level here
oh that's interesting apparently if you
have
f1 down you can't see the numbers
learn something new every day today
we're going to be learning a lot of new
things but we'll get to that in a little
bit
um f5 f5
there we go uh yeah we're done the mob
system it goes way up here
12 layers 1200 spawning spaces
in it it is very
very big very efficient let's go
down through here there's a lighting
system in it which works
very well ouch as you can see the lights
are on right now
that looks really cool when you look
down at the center like this
by the way if you hold shift the water
won't push you off blocks either
a little trick i learned while building
this
yeah so it's done uh the only thing left
to do now is to light up the caves in
the area
and until i do that it's going to be
pretty slow rates
ouch not another slime
in here even wow
first time i saw one in here
yep so yeah
next thing to do will be light up light
up the caves work on the emp units hook
up the sorting systems and
all the fun stuff starts now the hard
part is done
but really the next thing i want to do
is get rid of
all this land between the mob
system and here so that's about
20 blocks up we got to take outs a lot
of blocks
uh i'm gonna use tnt for that
let's go take a look outside if i can
find my way out of here
oh yeah i'm gonna try maybe
have another tube in the middle and
we'll have slimes going through that
i think that might be cool if we can
find a slime chunk around here and make
it work out if not
oh well oh yeah and the repairs on the
silverfish
room have sort of been taking place
i cleared out the big mess underneath
and killed most the silverfish i think
i broke the blocks encouraged them to
come out and then
kill them all all that i could find
so hopefully that mess is cleaned up got
rid of
a lot more of the lava and i'm still
parkouring around here
i'll cut to outside because this might
take me a while to get out of
all right let's jump off i'll show you
how high up it is
quite a ways this is what it looks like
from down below
it looks a lot better as snow i gotta
say compared to cobble or wood it looks
really cool i might add some more
character to
it in the future but for now i'm just
happy
with the general look of it although
i do have to say i do not recommend
making
one out of snow because that took a long
time to farm all that snow believe it or
not even with the snow golems
it took a long time i went through a
good stack of iron on
shovels and
basically every shovel gets you 64
blocks of snow
every iron shovel is what i worked it
out to be about
and yeah i was using cobble ones at at
first
but i just got fed up with them breaking
all the time so i switched to iron
iron shovels and that just took forever
but anyway it's done yay
uh today we're going to be talking
today's going to be a taki episode we're
not really going to build anything
uh i learned something new today
and this is going to be sort of a
mythbusters episode so
i'm gonna set up some signs and then we
will get started because i got to
share some information
oh yeah so this thing's working a lot
better now
that we have a few more layers on it
but once we get the caves all lit up
around here it's going to make a huge
difference
it'll be a lot lot better so we'll try
to do that sometime
soon but
check it out the signs are set up
charts are already here you are about to
get schooled my friends
today's mythbuster episode is going to
be
about the minecraft hunger system
and i'm going to wager a bet that the
majority of the people that play this
game
have no idea how it works and before
today i was also one of them
and the reason for that is because the
hunger system in this game is very
unintuitive or in other words you
wouldn't know how it works unless
you spent many hours trying to figure it
out
or if you were to
look at the game code you might figure
it out that way
or if you had someone explain it to you
like i'm going to try to
today in this episode so
how does it work oh boy where do we
begin
well let's start from the beginning the
way i originally
thought it worked and as i'm sure many
of you
also agreed i'm going to eat this
another one i'm going to jump around a
little bit
so actually maybe before we get going
here
i'm going to say one thing
once my hunger gets down just a sec just
a sec
all right and we'll jump a few more
times
there we go so it just went down uh
jumping is going to be our staple in
this episode
for measuring our hunger it just went
down
every 20 times we jump it's going to go
down half a bar
1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10 11 12 13 14
15 16 17
18 19 and here goes 20.
one two three four five six seven eight
nine 10
11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18
19 20. so
that's our easy to reproduce measurement
system
okay so the way i originally thought the
hunger worked
is if right now i'm down two and a half
bars right
eating steak recovers for
four of those so i thought there was an
overflow to it
where it'll it only shows 10 but i
thought
in this case i would have what's
two and a half 11 and a half hunger
at the moment or or food i should say 11
and a half food
i thought there would be a 1.5 overflow
there that's the way i thought it always
worked because
anybody that's played this game for a
while knows that if you were to eat a
watermelon
when you're when your food's at nine and
a half
compared to when you would eat a steak
when it's nine and a half
uh generally the steak
would keep you full a lot longer than
the watermelon that's
pretty pretty well known and
i think a lot of people figured that's
the way it works
but it turns out there's actually two
different hunger bars in this
game and most most information for this
episode
comes from the minecraft wiki uh
from the uhc comments one that comes up
quite often
is that i waste my food in it
i eat and waste food and i've always
sort of rolled my eyes at that comments
it comes up quite often some of the
other guys get it too
people that stayed are pretty much
trolls so they're doing it
i don't know why they say it's it's
never with a good attitude it's like
i can't stand watching this guy he
always wastes his food he's such an
idiot type
comment you know and turns out there's
actually some truth to it though
although the comment itself is still
very stupid for many reasons
uh anyway
well i'm going to collect my thoughts
for a second here so i don't say
anything
incorrect
yeah so i was going through my uhc
comments again today the latest episode
and once again i have gotten one of
those i hate watching this guy because
he wastes his food
comments and people kind of rang into
him about it
about how he's wrong and there's an
overflow value and
etc etc uh and it kind of had me
wondering you know had it
had me curious how does the food
actually work in this game because i've
never
actually tried to figure it out and i
decided to check out the wiki page
on hunger see if it had anything
interesting to say about it
and it turns out somebody has actually
gone and looked at the game code and
figured out
exactly the method to it and
exact data values for the food in the
game and as well as exact data values
for the different actions in the game
and how they
take away your food so
it's very interesting i or at least i
thought it was and i encourage you to
check it out i'll try uh
post the link to the page in the
description
and we're kind of gonna go over that
info today
and uh dissect it a little bit do a
little
a few tests here there's a little bit of
conflicting if
info on it there's two charts that don't
really seem to
agree with each other totally um
but overall is pretty accurate and
there's a few things i wasn't really
sure about
either which i would like to check out
um so first of all like i said there's
two different food bars in this game
there's this one here that we can see
and there's also a separate one an
invisible one
called the saturation bar which we can't
see
both of them have 20 points
maximum that we can have so each of
these food
bars each of these chicken legs counts
as two points
so we have three five seven seven and a
half here
which times that by twos 15 points
is our food value here out of a total of
20.
if we were to eat this steak it's good
for eight points
and uh there's only room for five points
here
so three points would actually go to
waste because there is no
overflow on this bar so you can actually
waste food in this game and most people
do
um from ignorance
and convenience and other reasons as
well i'm sure
um like i said i had no idea how this
worked until
i read the wiki page today
but anyway there's two different food
bars and every food item in this game
also has
two different food values and i have
them arranged from least to greatest
here
cookies as you know are garbage
but if you look at spider-eyes and
watermelon for example
both of them recover one or two points
on this bar here
but they have two completely different
values
this one's 5.2 and this one's 3.2
so
top the the number two at the top here
is the one we know
that's goes two points to this food bar
and then also adds 1.2
points to the saturation bar which we
can't see
so for a total of 3.2
food value if we go over to spider eyes
they
are quite a bit better actually they
have
two points plus 3.2 to the saturation
bar
for a total of 5.2 that's
over a time and a half better than
watermelon even though they seem to be
the same
according to what we can see on the main
food bar here
so you can you know when the saturation
bar
is empty if your your main food bar
is jittering uh that's the only
real visible sign of it right now my
food bar is not jittering but if i jump
around a little bit
we can use up our saturation bar
completely and you can see now
just so happened i didn't have much in
it so it
emptied pretty quick there and now the
the food bar is jumping up and down
which means
my second food bar is at zero and now
we're using up
this food bar here you only use up this
food bar here if
if your saturation one is empty and then
this starts jittering
alrighty so maybe we'll go through all
the food items here and see what their
actual food values are for the two
different bars
one at a time first of all cookies
recovers one point to the main food bar
and
0.2 to the
saturation bar or the overflow bar
basically is what it is
for a combined total of 1.2 points
and we know from our jumping experiment
before
we can jump 20 times per point so
if we were to eat a cookie and get
no food wasted from it 1.2 times
20. eating a single cookie would allow
us to jump
24 times assuming we're not doing any
other action that
takes away our food anyway moving on
that's how that works
uh raw chicken raw fish and watermelon
all have the exact same values as each
other
two points to the main food one 1.2 to
saturation
for a total of three point two robbie
for pork
rotten flesh again all have the same
values three to the main 1.8 to the
overflow for a total of 4.8
spider eyes my personal favorite and i
did notice this before i used to always
eat spider eyes then i switched to
watermelon
and i found after i would eat a spider
eye
i would get or after i would eat a
watermelon i would get hunger
hungry a lot faster than after i ate
a spider eye and that's because the
saturation value is a whopping
3.2 compared to the 1.2
of the watermelon so it is quite a
difference
for grand total of 5.2 apples are next
for 2.4 6.4 total
then there's a huge jump with bread and
cooked fish it goes
five and six for a total of eleven
cooked chicken is six seven point two
for
thirteen point two total golden apples
they have a high saturation
and compared to their their relatively
low
main food bars so again four is equal to
two
chicken legs on here and then 9.6
for the invisible food bar 13.6 total
cake is a little bit of a weird one
because you can eat it six
times and so this first number here is
per per each and this is
the second number here is the combined
total of them
uh mushroom stew is a pretty good food
item
eight for the main 9.6 oop i
put that one line too low for a total of
17.6 and then the two best food items in
the game are cooked beef and cooked pork
which is eight for the main 12.8
for the saturated and 20.8 for the total
so if you compare that to watermelon
20.8 divided by
3.2
assuming there's no waste a cooked
cooked pork chops and beef is 6.5 times
better
or more filling than a watermelon so
that's
how you can use these numbers together
as well using our jumping illustration
20.8 times 20
that would allow us to jump 416 times so
that's how many actions of jumping we
can perform
per cooked one if we don't waste any
um now let's go let's move on to the
actions these are
what i found pretty interesting
uh the way this works is pretty comp
well not super complicated but
there's an a value in this game called
the ex
exhaust exhaustion i can't see that
right now i'm
i'm exhausted uh
an exhaust exhaustion wow i really can't
say it
exhaustion value in the game
when that gets to 4.0 it takes away one
of our points from our
saturated food bar if there is any
in it otherwise it will take one away
from my regular food
bar okay
so watching or sneaking
takes or adds 0.01 to
our exhaustion value hey i think i said
it right there
so if we were to
[Music]
let's see 4 divided by 0.01
this is how i get to these numbers 0.01
is 400 that means we can walk
or sneak 400 blocks before using up
one food point so either from
the saturated bar if we have or else
from the food bar
sprinting uses up food 10 times faster
it's 0.1 per
per block or meter so sprinting
40 blocks uses up one food points
swimming is a 0.015
per block one food points
takes you 266.66
blocks jumping we've covered
is 0.2 so
again if we take 4 divide that by 0.2
we get 20 and that's how we get our
total of
20 jumps per one food point
uh sprint jump uses up food four times
faster than regular jumping that's one
of these
and we're allowed five of these per food
points
look how fast it goes down right now
because my saturation bar is empty
and what else block breaking a lot of
these i haven't tested block breaking is
one of them we can break
160 blocks before we use up the food
points
and then attacking a mob or whatever
takes
13.33 hits before we use up
like 13.3 three swings
at before we use up one
food point we're going to test this one
today probably because i'm not sure if a
miscounts as a swing or if it has to hit
the mob to use up your food
damage that's us taking damage is the
same
and then food poison that's what you get
when you eat
zombie flesh sometimes seventy percent
of the time you get food poisoning
and then this will take away our food
it should be if we divide fifteen by
four
3.75 points i think it
should take away i'm a little confused
about this one
over the duration of the entire
poisoning see it's still going down
i'm actually going to watch that back
and see if it took away 3.75
roughly
yeah it seems to be correct because
zombie flesh gives you
1.8 saturation so that gets removed and
then your food starts to go down so we
went from
seven not seven fifteen
down to twelve so that's
that's 1.5 there plus the 1.8
that is 3.3 and
since we can't see exactly what it is
that seems pretty close to 3.75
so it seems to be accurate
let's test one of these let's test
watermelon because i had
i haven't actually tested any of these
food values to make sure they're correct
and i'll show you how we can do that
let's jump
until our food just goes down
there we go we're going to eat a
watermelon
and now our food birds not jittering
that means we have food in our
saturation so
1.2 in our saturation if we jump
what was it 20 times 1.2
i think it was 24 times
yes once we jump 24 times
uh our food bar should start jittering
so let's try that out
1 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 9 10
11 12 13 14 15
16 17 18 19 20 21 22
23 still not jittering
next time we jump it should start
oh
25 did i count wrong
oh boy 26
something's not right here 27
30 31 32
33 34 35 36
37 38 39 40 what is going on there
finally started jittering
40. so these values were last updated
1.1 i think the wiki said
so um
yeah this might have got changed that's
weird
now the next 20 times to jump the food
bar should actually go down
one two three four five
6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 14 15
16 17 18 19
still hasn't gone down next jump will do
it
there we go so 40 so this
value should actually be
2 not 1.2 and this should be
4 total interesting so we
may have to test all these to figure it
out exactly what it is now
yes indeed so i just checked the the
wiki page
and it doesn't actually say what version
these ch
this chart was made in so
or taken from i should say wasn't made
from it
it was found out by looking at the game
code
um we're gonna put star next to here
so we know it's been updated but
apparently in the new version that we're
using right now
it's a little bit different from what
the wiki says
um i don't have time to check all these
today
especially these bigger numbers would be
hard to check in the game
using that method i showed
um
but overall it's pretty good information
there
uh let's see what did i want to talk
about
oh yeah also i said 70 percent chance of
getting poisoned from zombie flesh it's
actually
80 according to the wiki
and chicken is a 30 chance
and if you get poisoned gives you 15
exhaustion you divide that by four
and that gets you the total number of
points you lose which is 3.75
um what are we going to do now
yeah so basically the tip to not wasting
food
is make sure your your food bar here is
jittering
before you eat and that you have enough
space
for the first food value so
if i'm gonna eat steak i would want to
[Music]
use it up until it's at that point and
then
eat to get the full full effect if i'm
being
uh very concerned about not using up
food
for convenience it's obviously easier
just to eat whenever you
want nobody should tell you right
um but yeah you can
not have a full food bar there and eat
and have the jittering stop
which means your saturation bar is full
i'm getting tired here and rambling a
little bit
quite a bit sorry uh
what let's see something else i wanted
to try here that
the wiki says your saturation food bar
cannot exceed your current
food bar so if i'm at 3 4
5 6 12 13 points right now
my saturation bar can't be more than 13.
13 is the limit which tells me that it's
additive so if watermelons give you 2 to
the saturation
if i was to use up a bunch of my food
here
let's try this out just something i want
to figure out
okay so i think we just used up the food
i shouldn't be moving around
moving uses up your
ah again i didn't time that very well
okay let's make sure we get it at the
right jump here
it was that jump so if we were to eat
two watermelons in a row now
that should give us a total of four
saturation because
we're allowed to have that we have more
than 4
points in our main food bar so that
would allow us to jump
what is it 4 would be
times 20 80 times
and believe it or not i'm going to test
this so i'll be right back
yeah so there's still some hidden pieces
to this puzzle
um i've tried this twice now eating two
watermelons in a row will allow you to
jump
60 times before you use up the
saturation so that would be
three total from two
so somehow one point gets lost there
if you eat two in a row i've tried many
times
just being a single one it's always 40
jumps
which is two so
yeah there's a bit to this that we don't
know yet
uh but regardless it's pretty
interesting stuff requires more testing
more figuring out some other time
and i'm not necessarily the guy that's
going to do it
i'm going to try i want to confirm
sprinting
so maybe we'll head to the surface and
do a f3
point a to point b test and i also
wanted to try
getting or attacking uh
actually we can do that pretty simple
right now to figure out if missing
counts for anything
saturation is used up if we swing wildly
in the air
let's see if it uses up any food
we've swung more than 13.33 times now so
does not appear to
and then we will go actually try hit a
mob and see if that does it
okay so this is our sprinting test we
are going to run 40 blocks
we are at negative 340 right now we are
going to run to i think negative
380 and stop and see if it uses up a
food bar
or a food point i should say i just used
up one so
by jumping so here we go
i'm gonna run straight as i can
and bingo
so that looked pretty right to me um
that's sprinting let's try taking damage
take this stuff off so 13.33 hits
cactus will do we will have to do a
little bit of walking which drains
hunger but it's very
very small so i don't think it will
influence our rough test here
okay one
two three four
5 6 7 8
9 10
11 12 13.
yeah so that seems about right it just
went down
again that was a rough test i'm gonna
try attacking now
yes our victims are going to be
our cows they don't fight back so it
should be
good test subjects turn that down
because they're annoying let's just use
up our one
haunch here one point so we know where
we're at
okay so it should be 13.33 hits roughly
one two three four five
six
seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve let's do it
yes so that's the same two so it seems
to be pretty accurate
um it's probably all we'll do today
with this there's a few more things i
wanted to try but
it's getting late here and the episode
is getting long
so if you're gonna need zombie flesh one
of the best ways you can do it
is eat it all at once
unless you don't get poisoned first time
that way because this thing resets every
time
but anyway i'm gonna go to bed thanks
for watching i hope you enjoyed this
taki
the game crashed bye
[Music]