[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series guess what guys I am
I'm very happy right now you know I just
finished recording that snapshot video
and I went back on into my day mare to
try to do some other stuff goof around
with some of the new features and it
updated
there was a update right after I
finished that cuz I was worried it's
like how many weeks am I gonna have to
wait before I actually get to play with
these new features cuz that you know
some people they like checking out the
new stuff and creative for me to really
enjoy it I love like playing in my world
here and like exploring in the world
here and cuz that terrain I find is
permanence you know the stuff I get from
the woodland mansion is gonna be
permanent you know this means a lot more
to me that way you know if you die it it
hurts a lot more if it's real then if
you're flying around and creative so
yeah I have updated guys 16w 39b this
latest snapshot seems to have fixed the
crashing problems I was having as mostly
to do with the furnace and I had some
like ticking hopper thing that was
happening that seems to be gone now and
I've looked around here haven't found
too many issues there's one weird thing
where arrows have particle effects
sation it alright and they don't seem to
be spawning that's kind of normal though
the other big thing I have noticed is
not all my flower pots but some of my
flower pots have lost their flowers what
wait a second oh it's there it's just
not showing it oh okay maybe I don't
even need to replace these maybe I'll
just wait and see if they come back to
later but anyways guys I think what I
would like to do in today's episode is
mostly focus on some of the features
the snapshot I skipped over in my in my
video there and especially today I want
to go try find one of those woodland
mansion's because I haven't seen those
yet I was kind of waiting to do it and
my let's play so let's do that I've
already been to our village here today a
little while ago I've been trying to get
them to I killed all the all the old
crummy villagers trying to get some new
population growing here I did a bunch of
trading with them fed them some bread
now they're making hearts and stuff
again I saw there was a baby white coat
wait was it you he might not have grown
up yet but there's a good chance it's
gonna be a photographer and then we can
get the map from him I hear him there he
is okay he hasn't grown up yet what is
that that a husk I don't know what that
is it's got to be a husk all right how
close are we to the surface not too
close what is that oh it's a zombie
villager do they have new sounds I did
not know that I've got TNT on my tape oh
he grew he grew finally been waiting for
like five minutes here alright dude so I
think it's gonna be a 50% chance right
cuz it's these there's gonna be a
librarian or a photographer I think here
we go ah alright oh that's not bad
actually sharpness 5 426 that's a good
book that's a book I want actually cuz
it's really hard to get sharpness by
enchanting okay here we go here we go
so it's 17 to 71 and that was 20 26 so
that's 9 over the map
Suton minimums that's a good price
that's not bad alright guys so changes
strategy here there was actually a lot
riding on that one villager there cuz
now if I want to try to get another
katara fer I'm gonna have to wait a very
long time and then have a risk of
failing again so we're we're actually
gonna go out and explore try to find a
new village probably do it in no time in
comparison so the off this way is kind
of like uncharted territory in my world
pretty sure anyways let's see I'm
expecting it's gonna turn from flat to
crazy here in no time cuz I never go out
this way oh actually maybe I do know ere
we go here we go alright and if we if we
do this there's a good chance we'll find
the llamas as well which would be
awesome cuz what is this this is a
forest oh and we have Plains this is
perfect
oh snap or even a donkey man I haven't
been able to find a donkey and I've
looked so many times for one so we could
find a donkey that would be great Jay
here we go oh look at this this is cool
alright alright it comes out over here
darn I couldn't flew through that that
would have been amazing
hmmm finding lots of cows sheep and pigs
not even horses or anything
oh the cliff
oh we got a swamp over here
Oh Darko forest dark oak forest holy
smokes only 2,000 blocks away the only
one of these I have found in my world is
like 10,000 blocks away so that is
awesome there might even be a mansion
here oh we don't even need the cat dog
refer I'm the I'm the master Explorer
all right let's check this out I'm gonna
sleep real quick here all right oh it
looks like it's a fair-sized - that's
good
I'm not seeing a mansion though even
even just having this near my place
though is awesome because this is one of
my favorite biomes in the game I love
the grass color here it's my favorite
thing about the biome if you didn't know
and if I ever want to use it this is
where we're gonna be building probably
snap all right this is a problem with
flying by the way if you're exploring
new terrain the game starts lagging
pretty bad and then you can't shoot your
bow so gonna be going on foot here a
little bit let's see how cool would it
be if it was like right at the very top
of that island there the mansion
probably not I don't think we're gonna
get one here over here do you eat
yeah no mansion I don't think it's not
looking like it actually keeps going
here a little bit there's still a chance
still a chance I want to check out these
planes first oh yeah then something
change with the trees too like I
remember seeing something in the patch
notes set like these big trees weren't
generating for some reason and now they
made them more common maybe I'm not sure
this is the planes biome right and we
have a tree here yeah we got a big giant
tree great in the plains that's cool
llama village village yes okay we found
a village that's something yes all right
now I did bring the stuff to do trading
it and hopefully we'll find a Kotaku fur
I haven't gotten a blacksmith chest in a
long time let's see what we get gold
horse armor nice and a saddle I'll take
that cool all right and here we go is
this it no what's your unbreaking 3 for
13 not bad actually oh it's a green coat
we got a nitwit they actually are
spawning oh that's awesome they don't
have a trade though I don't know if
they're ever gonna get one or if they're
just kind of like a random random dude
hello thorns too okay
alright guys so I think I've been
exploring for about an hour my wings
need a repair here pretty soon
I remembered though there's a dark oak
forest by our desert outpost ovios where
I get my sand so we're gonna check this
out
yay we need a mansion to show up here
very soon or we're probably not gonna
get one here either
oh snap not a lot of luck with the
villages I found I think one or two more
villages and they all had librarians
here we go
here we go this is it
where is he where is either our there
really no librarians here not even one
oh we got beetroots oh there's a whole
bunch of houses down here too let's
check this out
that bunny died here's the house way up
there already fell no oh there's still
one guy in there though
I see the door moving wait a second is
this our librarian it is I thought I saw
the door opening and closing did I not
oh that's weird okay here's our cut
right over here
yeah I'm pretty convinced these mansions
are rare now like I originally was
expecting like one per mushroom forest
biome here and this is our third or
fourth one we've checked out now no
mansion so they're probably like you
know 10,000 blocks apart from each other
at least cut some random trees up there
it's awesome I've been trying to check
low as well cuz I'm not sure how they're
gonna generate in our amplified terrain
here they might do something weird and
be like underground or something I say
something a lot don't I all right good
news though I did find one more village
up here I haven't checked it out yet
this could be the one I'm going to have
to probably rely on these cartographers
for the treasure map I don't think I'll
find it without it
all right where was that up over here I
think this is a new village although
we're kind of on the edge of stuff we've
been to I think so we'll see got bunnies
purple dudes oh snap I'm gonna have to
cut most of the exploring out of this
video though because like we would be on
Episode eight or nine already I have
gone a long distance my world's gonna be
huge after this here we go okay come on
man be a cartographer do something with
your life yes oh yes finally okay you
stay inside be safe it's times like this
it's I wonder why haven't I made a
villager breeder yet like that's the one
build I'm like I don't know if I really
need it and then times like this really
wish I had one no exploring is fun no to
but you know you do it for two hours or
three hours it's like kind of want to
find the guy already
okay so we got him very happy
oh no no you're gonna take all my
emeralds I don't have many emeralds I
got to keep the compass oh you jerk okay
like I I left all my emeralds over at
the the witch firm I think that cost of
ten that was pretty bad oh and it
unlocked it awesome okay so 27 I can
afford it just barely here nice okay we
got it woodland Explorer map let's check
it out oh it's at the bottom so that's
gonna be south I'm pretty sure right if
we're facing the north the top is north
I think and then it would be this
direction okay
all right guys check this out on the way
here I think I found another dark oak
forest doesn't have a mansion but look
at this
that is that's a big tunnel alright guys
so some good news here I flew or I was
flying southeast sort of and you can see
the cursor is on the left there kind of
in the middle of the map now Oh big hill
so that now I'm just flying straight
east and we should hit it in no time
here I think I'm about 6,000 blocks out
though so it is pretty far from my spawn
should be there soon though just got an
achievement adventuring time is this the
biomes one oh no how do I look at it
achievement discover all biomes oh snap
I did it is trying to figure out what
biome I discovered and I mean it's this
over here savanna plateau Mountain I
think was the one I was missing look at
this the sheep just generated in and
they were all three of them facing
perfectly straight in the line
exploration has hit a bit of a snag here
I keep running into this mega taiga
forest stuff which at first I was like
oh cool a mega taiga and it's been mega
taiga like for thousands and thousands
of blocks now problem is it's like the
latest of all the terrain generation so
I kind of have to sit and wait for it to
finish before I can get out of here
uh-huh
so on the way I've been like collecting
coal and stuff for X because my wings
are gonna break and you remember and I
said we're close we're soon gonna be
there I'm like 9,000 blocks out now so
it seems like you have to travel the
furthest this direction ah yes we have
done it we have arrived to our
destination so you can see that my
player on the map here he's got the big
dot now it's the little little dot that
means we're close I see dark oak trees
and we are ninety seven by 65 ninety
seven hundred by
6500 blocks away so I think this is the
closest one right they did be the
closest one I'm pretty sure so these are
spread out quite a bit in the world it
seems and take your guesses is it gonna
be underground or is it gonna be
above-ground I'm gonna say underground
I think the amplified might mess with it
a little bit we'll see or it might just
be this big giant cobblestone column up
in there
one or the other I'm guessing I'm gonna
say underground just just because okay
where are we get a little bit of lag mmm
so I still gotta go east north I went
too far south I got him to go to
Northeast this way No
llamas no way
Stream Hills oh man I thought I thought
it was in the force they generate not
one of them died I've been checking all
the forests every or not forest plains
I've been checking every single Plains
biome
why are they in extreme Hills I thought
they were alright interesting we found
llamas that's cool
haven't found any donkeys this whole
trip oh we got the Mesa over there too
weird yeah it should be like right up
over this mountain here which means it's
not part of that dark oak forest we
found there must be another one up this
way there's so many llamas here
llamas everywhere that's awesome hmm
yeah dark oak forest up there okay got
to be close
still don't see it though ah man this
area is very nice so I liked having the
Mesa next to this got all kinds of cool
arches oh man can barely fly uh it's got
to be up here right oh we're showing up
on the map this truly is the the
exploration update or whatever I have
not explored this much of my world like
ever this is the most not because we're
going to some new biome or something
we're going through biomes you know
we've had in the game forever but just
to find something that's 10,000 blocks
away is crazy I'm like right at it oh
it's up there it's up there oh I see it
well this is it we're going inside
does it have an entrance I haven't seen
one yet
ah does it look like it has an entrance
does it
it's kind of weird oh no over here over
here kyoool
and it's I would start inside these
things kind of there's some torches oh
man I really don't know what to expect
because I haven't like tried fighting
the villagers or anything like that yet
I did bring some decent armor just not a
chest piece so we'll see how this goes
and surprisingly haven't seen any of
them yet it's all normal mobs I thought
it would be like loaded with those guys
but maybe just in special rooms there's
there's a lot of mobs in here though for
sure oh there's one up there I see it so
many mobs oh I hear no that's that's
these guys I'm not used to that new
sound for them I keep thinking cylinders
whenever I hear it okay first room we
have some mold here nothing too fancy go
down the hallway here oh we got a like a
weird mushroom room with a chest okay
really
I got all excited nothing's gonna fall
in my head here nope which is alright
very cool can we go upstairs here no
it's like a little little thing nothing
more to it I think that's one of them
right yeah here we go okay how bad are
you gonna eat first
okay he only does that what was that
hurt and a half with my arm oh that's
not bad
and he drops emeralds haha it seemed
like I got more than one emerald there
awesome
oh that is cool I like that that
actually looks pretty good and you know
I've never seen anything like that done
before where people just put a bunch of
saplings on the wall it looks pretty
cool and you pick them up too
that's that's nice dark oak saplings are
actually pretty hard to get normally so
I'll take those what is this I thought
this was gonna be a staircase we have a
banner okay little random Oh a chest is
it a troll chest it's a real chest Oh
baby chain chain chest plate I'm gonna
take that yeah I'll leave the rest of
that stuff okay it's like a pumpkin in a
room kind of weirdo I guess that's
Mojang for you though okay this is like
these rooms are very random oh this is
like a blacksmith sort of room you got
an anvil oh and it's like a broken
handle already darn it
Mojang cheeping out on us can't even get
a real anvil very damaged ouch
okay here we go another guy you know I
don't oh it's gonna say I don't really
want to kill all of them just in case I
want to bring some of them home 33 to 35
yeah I got two there is this like pixel
art what's going on in here oh it is
pixel arts that's awesome that must be
the invoker right he's got like a wand
or something you see the top of his
shoulder there cool I better start
collecting this iron cuz we might get a
bunch and I do like iron
is there anything inside of this guy Oh
nope no brains by the looks of it no
this is where we blast it through okay I
got cool so we went through about half
of the first floor here this hallway is
shorter hmm so it must be a room in
there then let's see what do we have
here little gathering room maybe like an
office here you got your big computer
desk with flowers on no computer and
this is like for the boss of the office
he sits on the high chair awesome so
there's a garden room with wheats very
random again oh and it's Gilliam's blown
up darn it Oh an actual tree room oh
here he comes
okay can we trap one of these guys
they're actually really fast aren't they
you sir you are gonna live in the office
if I can make it happen oh no I feel
you've got to be really careful I don't
Dyer I'm gonna be so mad there's a long
trip home okay oh come on I really got
to eat something
all right he's so fast it's crazy there
we go we got him did we go in here no we
didn't really we got a tree and like a
reservoir I wonder if they like thought
this is what this room is gonna be
before they built it or if they just
start placing blocks
yeah that is definitely the invoker
right oh storage room
hello these are all gonna be empty
though I'm almost certain yeah of course
I gotta checked every one though I don't
think there's actually something here
got like a flower up there okay yeah all
empty if you want it to like take over
one of these mansions and then live in
it that's kind of cool because when you
got your storage room pre-built for you
whoa
I got prison with redstone and a table
we got a cauldron also pretty random no
no prisoners inside though this this
room here that I hear the guy in doesn't
have a door alright let's go inside then
or am i hearing a zombie villager again
could just be like a
no there is something in here okay no
door on this phone
no one Volker either that was a zombie
villager okay Oh
iron axe efficiency one all right uh I
think I'll leave that for the next guy
to come by just I'll use this one
instead yeah I think we got the first
floor cleared here now we're gonna go to
the second things are gonna get crazy
maybe maybe not
I do like the staircase they did here is
pretty cool
I've always been a sucker for these ones
that split though and go left and right
and then you got the the railing and
stuff pretty cool nice viewing windows I
heard a lot of like zombies and stuff
when I was on the first floor so I don't
know kind of quiet now that I'm up here
okay it looks like a library this is a
bedroom with the old classic bed this is
what people did before bed for like
actually in the game destroyed oh it's
only one thick - okay very thin
floorboards here this is yeah it's a
library okay so they're like little
sitting areas you can read your books
for a second I was like oh this looks
like a restaurant syns like no people
sit down in libraries - okay lots of
books here I might go through after this
and take what I want like those books
look pretty appealing to me oh here's
our way up to the next floor okay is
that
oh okay it's one of the dudes
why was he pink they don't chase you
oh really I thought they would like be
all over you in your face oh when they
turn red they charge you I see oh that's
cool like yeah we'll charge that whole
okay that was pretty cool oh so they
totally ignore blocks don't they
if I kill them all
are they gone for good oh okay that's
about a heart damage
they give XP oh that's so cool I don't
want to kill him just in case he's the
only one so we'll see if we can trap
them I like those guys all right we're
going in or going in here for realsies
oh it's like a little conquer room it's
got the map on the table so what does he
all dude Oh No there's creepers in here
did he summon these guys or were they in
there one actually hurt foot bad I
didn't kill that one he just died on his
own
that was weird oh okay I want to get rid
of these creepers cuz they're gonna
wreck everything otherwise oh I didn't
see that one
kill the creeper there's another one
right behind it just want to watch him
for a bit and see what he all does so he
spawns these guys and they kind of float
around they charge you he's got this
crazy snake snake attack whoa okay if
you get close to him
that's cool strain the detriment of boat
year these little guys went inside yeah
look at that okay so they're taking
damage they must have a limited lifespan
then it is died over time interesting
you could probably make a fridge crazy
XP farm with this if you had a few of
these guys right because you saw summons
a lot of these little dudes and they
drop XP all right we got you can catch
on this done oh right away he goes what
I'm up to another one took the spot darn
it
okay I don't think he's gonna leave this
room I'm just gonna block it off
eventually he'll teach himself
all right let's keep going here if
there's more of them I'll kill one I
think they drop the totem when you kill
them wouldn't mind having at least one
of those all right so a giant [ __ ] get
in here interesting any eggs inside
definitely if I'm doing this right now
this is weird
no nothing inside is this a secret room
others like a dead end
oh wait yes and the number of zombies in
this mansion they find you from
everywhere hello ninja ninja skeleton no
ninja creepers that's good so we got
another library there was no chests in
here before and I don't know if there's
oh oh oh snappers that it was almost
really bad there was a creeper up there
this is nice a pretty nice room little
conference room or waiting room might be
my imagination it sure feels like
there's more zombie villagers now and
another bedroom dual beds computer desk
okay Oh dad look at them no whoa whoa
was it you something got me from behind
there no never think on this one are the
conference rooms on this floor it seems
what do you think this is I'm sure like
it looks like a table but there's no
chair
kind of interesting oh maybe it's like a
banquet table like this is where they
put the food you go up your food and
then you go sit down I could see that
that makes sense yeah we'll call this a
banquet room trying to think of names
for each of these rooms it's kind of
hard for some of them Oh another bedroom
and I think this is the last room on
this floor it is the wedding room the
bride and the groom's stand over here
and I don't know what is this it's like
an arch still in here he's still there
Oh any use in the boat right I think we
got him in the boat nice all right we'll
leave them be well he'll be he's had a
hard day
I think I might've missed one room in
the corner here double check for two
rooms yeah oh man big banquet room right
oh and another another one of the dudes
in here okay I'm gonna block I wanted me
to keep you inside too
we'll try to get this guy inside and
then we'll block it off very cool
it could get pretty rough if you had
like five of these guys inside but I saw
someone say it was like they were as
strong as ribbons or something and I
haven't seen that myself these accidents
are probably even more dangerous
Volkers as long as I stay like healed up
here perfed fed up I don't think I'll
die at all
alright we'll try getting back inside
then we'll go upstairs here Aaron oh so
we got two guys in there let's go to the
third floor where all the sound is
coming from that are eat up here first
okay so there's a zombie trap of some
sort over here they all are falling into
there I think if anyone's getting stuck
that would probably kill me if I jump
down a lot of them
a lot of them we get them we got has a
lot of zombies oh it's just like
supports for the staircase alright let's
get out of here still hearing a lot of
zombies upstairs here so many zombies
not another weird
you're missing a block or so so alright
no house is perfect so this is like the
master bedroom
with a broken desk because I blew it up
I think this is master bedroom you got
the big bed very nice
[ __ ] oh it's like got some banners up
there too like a name what do you call
that an emblem or crest of the family
sort of thing maybe and oh you sneaky
guy I don't want to kill him
there's a thing if you guys didn't know
there's an Easter egg with them you can
name them Johnny here's Johnny and then
I believe they attack hostile mobs so
you could use them for farms and stuff
so I'm trying to keep a few of them
around don't really want to go looking
for like tons of these mansions that
they're pretty hard to find so I don't
want to waste these guys you know ok
another one of those ones we saw that
one just block them off in there yet we
saw one of these we've got another
invoker duel Oh carpet carpet block that
works you know I was expecting like a
little more treasure to be honest this
is mostly not that there's anything
wrong with this but mostly just like
checking out the rooms which are
starting to duplicate themselves
bedroom I haven't seen that this is a
new one cool
I'd even notice that there's a pixel art
of the guy at the top of the stairs
there that we saw this one we got a
banquet room and that's the end the
hallway right oh no here we go another
banquet room side-by-side guys love to
feast where are you coming from
master bedroom are we at the top is that
it I don't see another huh I don't see
another staircase to go up uh yeah I
came out of the window there cool well I
think we checked it all out guys I think
that's it it's a cool little thing not
super excited about the dungeon stuff
here but you know I like getting new
mobs in the game them the new mobs are
cool then Volker and vent Gators that
kind of stuff it'd be nice if they would
spawn other places uh-huh anyways I
think I'm ready for the long journey
home now I'm not sure how to do it cows
on the roof probably got to go through
the nether honestly I don't really want
to fly back my wings have almost totally
repaired themselves though
ah so it's just enough to make a portal
here and I'll have one left over to make
a flint and steel do I do it I don't
know about this one this is like do or
die
I'm gonna start with a bit of a ramp up
here I think get some speed going if I
mess this up I'm gonna go over into the
lava or if I hit my head on it that
could be bad too okay we made it
pew all right
oh where do we go yeah this way this is
bad
almost home already wide open spaces I
like it oh I'll show them there we are
we're back alright guys well I made it
back home here safe and sound a little
bit of an oddball episode today I hope
you enjoyed it I don't do the whole
exploring thing too often and that
before next episode I'm gonna try to
raid like 10n cities at least for the
shelter shells so probably do that off
camera though unless for some reason you
guys really want to see it but I'll try
to keep track of all the loot I get and
then I can show you that at least at the
very least we'll see ah ah yeah anyways
let's wrap it up here it says ethos lab
I found a glitch it works great with
wings you put a slime block one block
into the ground put lava on it and then
slabs around it to keep the lava in and
it shoots you so far into the air there
air I forgot to underline it oops okay
well it sounds like a troll but I'm up
for testing things I brought a fire
resistant potion just in case but we
might need to do it without it it might
be the damage tick okay actually
my armors pretty good okay you have to
hop on it
he wasn't super clear on how to do it
no I missed um okay fire resistance time
like I'm I kind of like hover on it
right but it's not launching me I am
also in a different version than he was
so maybe it doesn't work anymore all
right well I tried it unless I'm doing
it wrong I don't know anyways hope you
guys enjoyed I'm off to go do some more
exploring I also want to expand my ice
road so I can get those llamas back nice
and easy and maybe the the illah Jers we
found today but until next time guys
thanks for watching take care bye bye
[Music]