[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode
of the let's play series aha yeah so
we're trying to expand our ender porter
network every episode here so we built
this one last time and now it goes to
sandy city and we can go back as well
uh it's a little bit we're gonna we're
gonna fix up the interface
trust me this is the getting the
connection set up first
and figuring out how we want to do it
first oh
oh so we don't want the trapdoor
triggering twice either
because then bad things happen like that
uh but yeah let's uh let's go see how
far away that is so that teleports us
all the way
to over right around
here so it's quite quite a distance and
the man cave is pretty much below this
now so
yeah we're going to be able to teleport
from our man cave to the stronghold
very soon so between this episode and
last episode i went and i did some more
netherright mining guys
so we can finally finish up our tools uh
netherride tools are actually pretty
good
i like the extra durability you get from
it um and i really do like
if you die in lava or something your
stuff will float on on top it doesn't
get burnt
that's actually a pretty big deal uh so
i think it's worth upgrading it's just
it's not a high priority for me either
though
all right our first netherride block i
think we're gonna store those over here
yeah check it out
finally went through this area and
removed all the torches that were around
the fishing shack so it's all hidden
lighting under bushes
and uh no mobs can spawn here oh i know
high priority thing right
every episode etho when are you gonna
get rid of the torches around the
fishing shack when are you getting rid
of those torches
i don't think anyone's ever said that
actually it's those little things though
that i know
that are bothering me about my world
here um
i don't know if you guys care about them
but uh i thought i'd show you that
anyways
uh today we're gonna be doing a lot of
uh like smaller to medium-sized projects
i kind of feel like we've been doing
massive projects lately and i kind of
want to
a little break from that we'll get a bit
more variety in the episode that way as
well
okay so i want to try to get a few
stacks of weather roses today
and i don't have a wither rose farm so i
thought it might be fun to spawn a bunch
of snow golems on an end island yeah i
don't see what could go wrong with this
idea this is a perfect idea not a dump
land at all
it's the typical canadian winter all
right that's probably enough of them
let's get this show on the road
boop boop boop
this is a fountain that snowballs up at
them that's great
oh he took out the thing right in front
of me action shot
all right i think i'm safe am i safe
probably not safe i'm as safe as i'm
gonna be here
let's run around now and pick up the
wither roses there should be a ton of
them on the ground oh
lots of snowballs too redstone somebody
hit me
let's make sure i'm not falling into the
void yeah we're good okay i'm just gonna
scatter them in my inventory like that
so we can pick up more
and it's working like a champ this is
great i'm just getting chased by a few
endermen but other than that
seems like a a success to me okay
well i think that's our cue to leave he
pretty much killed all the snow golems
uh he'll keep fighting the enderman
though and we'll get with the roses off
of them too
but it's much slower
yeah he can have the island though i
think we're we're gonna
just surrender it to him we got plenty
of islands we don't need to keep that
one
and yeah let's head back home here so uh
all in all we got
a bunch of weather roses we reclaimed
some of our snow and
it's also a good way of getting endstone
just setting up a wither in the
end like this he'll he'll farm it for
you he's gotta go pick it up
we don't go here too often but this is
where we get our wither skeleton skulls
from
we're gonna make a wither skeleton farm
today uh it's pretty close to our nether
hub we're only like 600 blocks away and
the goon farm is up above above the
bedrock ceiling
and a long time ago we slabbed over most
of this place and lately i've been
working
on uh slapping it even better there's
still a couple spots missing
but it's kind of at the point where we
could probably make a pretty good farm
um it's all slabbed over here we did
this
many years ago actually like when wither
skeletons first came out and i've just
been like running around the fortress
killing them
i kind of want something a bit more
automatic now yeah so the plan is to
build our wither skeleton farm at this
intersection here
um you want to build them in the
intersections generally because they're
the biggest piece of the fortress
19 by 19 area and you get up to three
layers vertically squeezed in
which is a lot of spawning area we also
have another intersection over there
so it's they're pretty close together
there's one more up ahead there that
we'll probably slap over
and i think just for today we're going
to keep this pretty simple i just want
to get something up and running
and then later we'll come back to this
most likely and try and prove it a bit
so we want a 3x3 area in the middle
where the
we'll put a piglet for the wither
skeletons to chase and then all around
that
we're gonna put grass with wither roses
on top of it
that's where the withered skeletons will
spawn and i think i might need to go get
more weather roses
actually i did the math it's like oh we
don't even have like
close to what we need here so from that
three by three in the middle we're gonna
go seven
grass blocks out all around it
okay here we go i brought that guy from
our nether hub hopefully
we don't waste this opportunity this is
always the hardest part about making
these farms
just trying to get them into position
yeah yeah
yeah oh one more step oh you did it good
boy
nice okay we put that there i think
we can break that one we're gonna name
them
what are you guys doing down here
oh yeah okay so this is about where we
want to go
oh they're falling down oh i see that
explains it
awesome so we got something up and
running here now i would like to add
another layer above and below this one
we'll just leave a three air block space
for the wither skeletons to spawn
uh but we didn't have enough weather
roses to do it today we'll have to do it
another day
um and uh it turns out
i probably got a lot more slabbing to do
after all
because i got it up and running and it's
like okay
we'll get maybe one wave of wither
skeletons and then i just stop
spotting them completely let's see if
there's anybody there
oh yeah here comes the first wave there
they go to the piglen they fall down and
then
there's like gonna be very little after
that so that means there's zombie pigmen
spawning nearby and they take up the mob
cap and then
no more wither skeletons spawn there but
i did add a thing down below here like a
chamber to
drop them down i'll get a couple more
falling down
so i can come here and and get them like
this now it's a little bit easier than
what i was doing before
but it definitely needs some improvement
oh we got a skull another one another
two
have i ever mentioned to you guys just
how much i love this tree farm
because i really love this tree farm i
use it all the time it's great it's
wonderful
you can break the leaf super fast now
with the efficiency hose and it's just
really cool
tnt falls down get rid of more of it if
you want there's hoppers underneath the
carpet to pick up the drops
piston pushes the logs up so you can
just plant your saplings below you don't
have to break these
and uh all in all i love this thing
but you know it's not perfect it's not
perfect right now all the drops just go
right into this double chest
and uh that's it doesn't get organized
or anything so today i would love to add
maybe a bunch of chests over here for
storage
um and like some kind of sorting system
so what do we all get from this we're
gonna get sticks
and i think we're gonna be farming three
types of trees here the spruce
jungle and dark oak all the two by twos
right so from each of those we'll get
saplings we'll get the leaf
blocks possibly and the logs
so we need at least nine chests plus one
for the sticks
oh and by the way i feel like there's
been a major change with the way trees
grow
like it's some kind of bug or something
since uh 1.16
okay so those two grow grew fine now
this one's not gonna grow for like 30
seconds to a minute
i can spam bone meal all day is not
going to grow
it just won't grow watch look look i
don't know it is not going to grow
you sleeping you forgot to set the alarm
there's got to be a reason for this like
we've gone through
just stacks and stacks of oatmeal it
will not grow
guys let's try grow this one actually
okay that one grew now this one will
grow watch look at that
amazing what is up with that
so it was this one then this one
okay i think i cracked the code now guys
i think i got it figured out i just
can't grow this tree
no matter what right now doesn't matter
how much bone meal i spam on
it's never gonna grow i gotta grow this
one first and
then this one okay i got it now
anyways i think we're gonna go for 11
double chests one for
overflow as well anything that doesn't
get sorted
i'm gonna put pumpkin lighting for the
floor and then we're gonna put the
chests above that
probably four blocks tall or so i'm kind
of regretting this now i feel like it's
too close to the trees i think we're
gonna move it like three blocks more
this way
yeah so it looks like 1.17 is coming out
summer next year guys
and the big question on the last episode
is what do i think about it
what's my opinion of the cave update
what's your guys's opinion
i think it's gonna be the best update
to the game so far i was really
impressed with what i saw
i think they did a great job covering
all the main areas of the game like
updates in the past used to be really
focused and i like how they do a lot of
different things now
you got stuff for the builders there's a
whole bunch of new building blocks by
the looks of it
candles you got the new foliage blocks
lots of new plants and stuff which i
think is
desperately needed in the game i think
that adds so much to like landscaping
and stuff
um the carpet moss is gonna be huge
uh i was also really impressed that like
they didn't just add plants they added
plants with
functionality like the parkour plants or
the one that
hangs from the ceiling and drops the
particles on you or whatever
that's really cool i think that's a
great idea you got stuff for redstoners
the new skulk sensor
they got new mobs new biomes for
adventures
so yeah overall i would say i am pretty
hyped about it
i could talk about it for hours actually
but we don't have that kind of time
maybe uh
for the comment of the day i'll talk
more about the skulk sensor though
because i think that's
the main thing you guys asked me about i
have some some thoughts about it
uh but yeah this is where we're at with
this i think it's done
so you you might have saw there we had
it like all orange and as
i started second guessing it was like
man this just isn't working right so i
went for more earth tone colors we went
for browns and greens
got rid of most the orange here and i
think it looks a lot better now it's a
lot easier on the eyes we got the loom
ceiling
gotta love the looms best block 20 20.
uh in their chest and that's and yeah so
there's a
item sorters in the back here for
the three different types of trees we're
going to be farming here and
there's this hoppers that run over top
there we got an item elevator over there
that brings stuff up from the hoppers
oh i'm trapped yeah all the hoppers
underneath here
and anything that doesn't get sorted
gets put in this chest over here
and i accidentally made this 13 wide
instead of 11 like i
originally planned so we have an empty
spot and
another one there that i just put for
boat meal uh-huh
okay so i'm gonna try to test myself
here i did not look at the recipe on the
wiki page i'm seeing if i can figure it
out
uh or does it tell me over here actually
does it say
i don't see it listed how do we do it
guys is it
two string is it one string
it's gotta be two string right
i'm gonna have to look it up i think or
is it a fishing rod do we need a fishing
rod
and then one of these that would make
more sense to me
oh yeah okay that's what it is yeah so
1.16 has been out for
ages it feels like and i still have not
rode a strider once yet also boats are
still broken in this update
in case you didn't know i know because
it
affects me every time i take my boat
road um
yeah i've never rode a strider i think
they're hilarious though i just haven't
got around to it
now here's the thing though i'm actually
pretty excited about this because
the striders in my world are a little
bit special
uh they're a little bit strange like
extra strange
so let's go check these guys out uh i
noticed this uh
a while ago they kind of
well they float in my world you see that
guy he's not he's not on the lava no no
he's out of the lava he's shivering
he's he's in the middle of nowhere so
let's see what happens when we put a
saddle on this guy and like try to ride
them
or do i have to tame them i don't have
to tame them right
all right do i have like a hover board
now
uh he's probably not gonna move anywhere
if i was yes let's get our thing though
oh my goodness i i got a hoverboard
dude check it out
okay what's the what's the trick here
you gotta right click
oh he's gonna be slow though because
he's out of the lava right even if i use
the fishing rod
oh what are you doing boy
see ya
just floated away i don't quite
understand this but i think my world is
a little bit messed up
uh it still rains underground even in
the update here
i've tried optimizing my world like you
guys suggested to fix that
but it didn't so i think this might be
related to it it's like my height
coordinates are messed up
and it's affecting these guys maybe i
don't know or it might just be a glitch
with them that
everybody's experiencing but i i think
this is
pretty weird pretty weird pretty amazing
uh let's let's hop up here
i wonder i wonder what we could do with
this i guess let's try to hit one of
these lava columns because i think these
guys might
float up it oh maybe not okay maybe not
oh wait wait here we go
yeah okay we got we got a hoverboard
elevator now
oh yes oh this is great okay that could
be useful
this is just so amazing i know it's a
bug but i never want it to get
fixed it's so so good
what about ladders oh yeah ladders do it
too okay that's great
let's see if he'll drop me off here oh
yeah he just straight drop off
here we go
okay so i think we put it in our off pan
we right click
and then with our fireworks
we can then yank them up yeah okay that
works
there he goes launch the balloon
we got his friend hooked okay let's pull
him up oh there he goes
let's try pull him down oh i'm sorry
didn't mean it okay now that he's
touched the ground oh no he still floats
i'm gonna try to pull him over and then
like hop on
oh okay that's a mistake i regret it oh
we're fine uh he bumped into him
up we go to the bedrock ceiling
that's the goon farm up there so let me
know if you guys have any cool ideas for
what we could use this for but
i think we'll try one more here i'm just
curious if we can get him in a boat
and if like the boat will start hovering
or something kinda doubt it
got him yeah just fly in my kite
that's so good well we still got a few
minutes left here so i thought we would
get started on another project a simple
one here
but a massive one and i'll try to get it
done between episodes
uh you might remember a while ago we
worked on the guardian farm we put a
mural in the wall here
a lot of you wanted me to make four of
them in total i don't think we're gonna
do that we're just gonna do
two maybe i think chocolate island was
suggested
for this side of the wall and then these
other two sides we'll just put
a giant kelp farm in i think yeah
i think that'll look pretty cool it'll
kind of suit the water we have in the
area so that's what we're going to get
started on
and trying out here so this is our
center point
right around here it's even based even
numbers
which can sometimes make things a bit
tricky but we will see so
around the edges we have the sandstone
border i think we're gonna want that to
stick out at least one block just so we
have a bit of depth
and then we'll probably put the glass
i think we're gonna go for cyan glass
instead of the light blue just uh
because i think it's a little easier to
see through
hopefully it won't look out of place
though i don't know yet
uh so sandstone at this block glass
the kelp will go here and then we'll
need a backdrop so
i'm thinking we'll go for the warped
wart block
i think it's uh pretty good for a
background for water stuff
it's got a bit of a texture to it so it
looks a bit interesting as well through
the water
so we got to mine out quite a bit of
blocks here
uh all this four blocks deep this big
giant wall both sides needs to be mined
out
oh that etho guy you gotta check him out
he's been playing the same world for
almost 10 years now
he's done all the things crazy gadgets
all the gizmos you could imagine to my
utmost shame
i've never made a kelp farm in
any series i've never ever made a kelp
farm so i might making some mistakes
with this i don't know
just kind of winging it here i think the
kelp plants going to go here
we're going to put blocks in front of
the sticky pistons so you can't see them
and then it's going to extend out and
break the kelp and it's going to float
up and we're gonna collect it at the top
i think that's all there is to it right
okay well we got it mined out i beefed
up the sandstone we got the backdrop
in uh i put sand and sandstone for the
floor
that we're gonna plant the kelp on and
this is what it's looking like i'm a
little worried
it's going to be too plain just like
that we might need to add some details
but we'll try it we'll see how it looks
i guess so the last thing i'm going to
do here is put well not the last thing
but
the next thing is uh put the cyan glass
in front and then we gotta start
flooding it and putting the tail plants
in now the question is if you guys are
building a giant wall like this
how do you place your blocks i like to
go horizontally like this some people
though they like to stack up in
maybe three blocks or so and then they
kind of crouch and go over like this
i've never really liked that method i
don't know why it just feels slower to
me somehow
aha so we got all the glass in now we
might need to add lighting in there as
well
we'll see how it looks but now we got to
start
putting the water and the kelp in my
question is
there's a certain trick in this game
that like everybody seems to love and
i've never used it
the water and kelp thing can we use that
here like can we grow that
into this downward yeah you can okay
that is probably what we want to do then
we'll place water at the top
and then the kelp will grow into it and
we don't have to
place every single source block oh man
this is actually pretty cool i didn't
know this
so you don't even need to place it at
the top
if you just left it like this i think
eventually this would fill up totally
with water source blocks
because this plant will grow up and as
it does the water
oh maybe not did i get it wrong
i might have got it wrong okay maybe
it's this one that needs to grow
that one grows that one will reach the
top and then this one can start growing
right
yeah this one grows and then the water
moves over one block
and then this one can grow the water
moves over another block
and eventually it'll make it its way all
the way down to the end it would take a
long time but it's possible
well anyways we got the whole thing
flooded and the kelp has grown to the
maximum this is what it's going to look
like when that happens
uh we'll probably harvest it before that
does ever happen though it'll be
shorter um yeah what do you guys think i
think it's better than the gray wall we
had there but it might need to add a bit
more to it i'm not sure
it's pretty plain uh but yeah i think we
gotta wrap it up for today i didn't get
the redstone hooked up to it or the
collection system or any of that
i'll do that between episodes probably
but the comment of the day says hey etho
what are you gonna do about the new 1.17
update
coming next year the cave updates i'd
love to see you
start anew instead of going off tens of
thousands of blocks to get to the
new terrain again either way suits me
however i'd love to hear your opinion
uh yeah it's probably a little bit too
early to know exactly what i'm gonna do
we gotta figure out how they're gonna
implement things and all that
uh before we can make calls uh i had a
lot of people
asking me about that though uh most
likely we'll just go
to a new area and uh play around in the
new
new features like we usually do um i
don't need to go
very far like not tens of thousands
if i go 2 000 blocks that way over the
mountains it's new terrain
i don't explore much in the world here
actually i try not to
because it makes the world bigger and i
gotta go farther right so
there is stuff nearby where we haven't
explored for sure
lots of it now before we wrap up the
episode i do want to talk about how i
think they should implement the skulk
sensor
because that's the thing i'm most
excited about in the next update
the redstone thing obviously um so if
you don't know it's basically going to
be a sensor that can
sense sounds or vibrations so if you
look at the bottom right i turn the
sound
text on to give you an idea what's going
on here
so every sound in the game has its own
unique uh
text to its like sheep bars water flows
as you walk footsteps play so having a
sensor that can detect sounds is going
to be really
cool uh especially because it does other
things it's got the wireless redstone
feature
uh something i i noticed that i don't
think a lot of people mentioned is it
seemed like you could use it as a timer
as well like
the time to send from one skulk sensor
to the other
seem to be based on how far apart they
were from each other so that i could see
that being quite useful
um and just on its own if it's a
general sound sensor that's gonna be
great but the thing that will make it
amazing
is if they make it so you can filter
specific sounds
uh they're gonna have directional
filtering with the wool blocks
but specific sounds like footsteps you
walk along and a door opens only if it
hears footsteps
um that would be amazing the problem is
if it's like all
sounds you could have a bat spawn and
then it's gonna cause your redstone
device to trigger
and you're gonna get mad and frustrated
so i think they kind of need to add
filters
how do they do its next question i would
like to see them add filters in two
different ways so let's pretend this is
our skulk sensor
over here um firstly
for newer players or people that don't
really understand how it works i would
love it
if you could right click it and then
maybe a light turns on
or you get some kind of visual
indication that it's in
listening mode maybe some particles are
spawning off of it who knows
when it's in listening mode it listens
to all sounds around it and the last one
it
hears is what the filter gets set to and
then when you shut it off
it saves it basically and i would like
it if like
you when you hover over it if it says
what it is or maybe there's some way to
even play the sound
from it and so when you look at it maybe
it says what the sound
is the other way i would like to see it
is for more experienced minecraft
players like
hey maybe you know what the sounds are
in the game and you could name
pretend i'm naming the skull sensor
right now footsteps
you name it and then the filter gets set
to that and then
if it's like an mbt data stuff it it'll
save it
even after you pick it up and put it
down again it'll still
keep that filter so you could do like
full stacks of them at a time
even and i think if they could only pick
one of those options i would want them
to pick the first one because it
wouldn't require any game knowledge
and anybody could do it and i like the
idea like
if you wanted to react to pig sounds
you'd have to bring a pig next to the
sensor like it would involve interacting
with the world more so i think that's
better
although it would be more tedious
anyways those are a couple of my ideas
let me know what you think of it we're
gonna wrap up for today though thank you
for watching guys
hope you enjoyed it until the next one
take care have a good day bye