[Music]
hey
everybody how you doing i have some good
news for you and what are my settings at
so wait
oh i clicked something what did i click
pant legs my legs are on
oh i accidentally quit the game let's
try this again
hey how's it going everybody welcome
back to another episode of our let's
play
series uh so i have some good news for
you guys today
and i have some bad news for you i'm
gonna tell you the good news first okay
here we go so you remember the door
uh last time we tried to go through the
door it jammed
right and it took like 30 seconds to
open but when we
when we tried to open it there was
nothing there it was terrible
remember that oh so so many of you guys
felt left down
i know i i feel bad about that but today
i have fixed the door it is working
properly
but uh
[Music]
the bad news is there's nothing here
i think there was an explosion in the
facility and
left this giant crater in the mountain
and
yeah it's almost unrecognizable anymore
[Music]
no other explanation for it i know i
feel bad
i guess we're gonna have to rebuild
all right everybody so what are we doing
here today what is our plan
uh i thought this might help you to
understand a little bit better
like check this out over here this is a
device
that shoots items it's kind of like
wireless item transfer although the
timing seems to have been messed up
it used to vary consistently though
shoot items about 20 or 30 blocks into
this hopper over here
it's a cool little device and as far as
i know
i might have built its at the amplified
base i can't remember but this is like
my only reference copy of this
in existence doesn't exist on the wiki
or anywhere else i don't think so if i
tear this down it's gone forever or if a
creeper blows it up
it's gone um yeah
so it's kind of a cool little thing and
i've got lots of little redstone devices
like this in memory or
or i've built in the past and i don't
really remember it would be cool if we
had a spot in our world where we could
keep these and i can reference them
later if i need to
and if you guys ever download the world
you can check it out nice and easily as
well
um so i kind of want to build like a
redstone museum
it's been an idea of mine for a little
while and we're gonna build it in that
spot over
over there i think uh for the longest
time
we used to do our redstone right over
here we would come up to the spot
and uh start designing you know then the
horses moved in here there's water
all around mobs come out of the forest
constantly and attack me
oh i see an invisible mob it's a spider
so it's not exactly an ideal spot to do
redstone and also the ground's only like
two blocks thick
in places which poses a problem um
yeah so like this has been here for
at least a year i'm sure um and if we go
over here
oh i messed that up i haven't heard
taking a hard time taking off here with
the elijah wings because there's so many
trees around
it's actually a bit of an issue because
if i do take off i just crash right into
one of them
yeah like right there i would have
gotten off the ground but nope
um and you remember the other day we did
that minecart stuff this was like the
only other open field i had
where i could do redstone and now it's
filled up and i'm not quite ready to
tear that down yet
because i might want to reference it for
a future episode here
but something that was suggested
uh a lot over time and especially on the
last episode
i'm not gonna be able to take off not
gonna happen
there we go is that we build some sort
of redstone
room and that's what we're gonna start
off here uh with this redstone museum or
the facility 2.0 whatever we're going to
call it
uh there's a nice open area here it's
not a super exciting build i basically
just want to build a big square room
where we can do redstone
and have a nice flat surface you know
that kind of thing
so the explosion did a lot of work here
oh my aim sucks
it's not gonna happen really
oh man through the magic of editing
maybe maybe i didn't set that up right
here let's do this this is a good idea
i shot it right oh i should move
clear out a little bit more space i
brought some tnt here too so
yeah basically i want a big square room
here to do redstone maybe a
25 or so 25 by 25 area
oh i just figured it out i used the
stone button because i wanted it to be
hidden you know to be like a little
secret oh
what's he doing he's shooting the
terrain for some reason
i just remembered you can't actually
activate a stone button you have to use
a wooden button
duh
i wanted to try i don't know if i've
ever done this
oh gotta use a fire bow right
it doesn't give it the highlight i
thought it would have interesting
so i'm using spectral arrows on the tnt
but it doesn't
mark it
i don't think no it doesn't
i think i finally realized the trick
with the new skeletons
i can pretty much dodge him 100 if i
just hold left or right
unless he's walking forward a lot then
he might hit me
like right now he's walking backwards
now he's walking forward he could
possibly hit me if i don't back up as
well
but otherwise yeah see he was moving
forward there so he's able to hit me
he's moving backwards he'll never hit me
but if he's moving forward and i move
backwards he'll never hit me either
aha very interesting
anyways we have a 25 by 25 room
dugout here i think this is going to be
good i think it's going to be great for
for doing redstone i'm gonna keep the
ground just as grass
because i find working on dirt is
wonderful
when doing redstone because if you ever
have to dig it's nice and easy
yeah like 100 he'll never hit you very
interesting
until you move in like once you close
that distance then then he can hit you
so you have to like run in right after
he shoots
um oh it's nighttime here let's go sleep
for a second
also check this out if you are engaged
in combat they will sometimes walk into
the sun
and if they're on fire then they shoot
flaming arrows
which is a pretty cool thing so now
he'll shoot a flaming arrow at me
all right so over here i don't know how
important the looks are going to be with
this whole redstone museum but just so
we're not looking at a stone wall here
forever
i'm going to do a pretty simple pattern
so i got bone blocks then red clay bump
back one block so it has a shadow on it
otherwise it looks pretty plain that
this kind of gives it a cool
look when it has a shadow and then you
go forward with the bone block and i
might do the same thing repeated
up here because i kind of need a tall
wall for this room probably
so i'm going to do maybe rgb red green
blue
so do green then boom block then blue
and see what that looks like for a
pattern nice and simple shouldn't take
too long to do
okay so check it out guys we got it
pretty much all done here we got the red
green blue going on
and this might not be one of my better
builds
i'll see what you guys say about it
though uh might need to do some
adjustments here
but i find it's a little crazy on the
eyes and i'm not exactly sure
why uh so then i tried to tone it down a
bit so i tried some other patterns i got
red
green red get rid of one of the colors
and then i tried red red red
but honestly i almost find this is
easier to look at and i think the reason
is because there's more to focus on
there's more colors
uh the problem is it's too uniform this
whole build i'm pretty sure like
these are all perfectly evenly spaced to
parts i just added these pillars in
mainly to hide more lighting so i got
torches behind each of these
which helps to light up the wall and the
floor a little bit i also added some sea
lanterns
so this will stop mobs from spawning
probably going to add a glass ceiling on
this as well
but uh yeah
you know we will be adding doors onto
this room though like there might be a
door here or something to go to another
part of the redstone museum and probably
another one on that side
uh go further into the mountain here uh
so it might not look all
super uniform after after i do that and
also
i think i'm gonna add some chests with
redstone supplies maybe a bed
infinite water source that kind of stuff
would be nice as well because you use
that
quite often when doing redstone uh yep
so we're definitely going to want to get
a ceiling in here otherwise it will rain
inside and that will get annoying i made
a little compartment
area here for the the chests and for my
bed and that kind of stuff
just a little work area so probably
do something like this with the chest so
i i want to always have some redstone on
hand here so i don't have to run around
looking for it's like
i do currently um usually i keep it in
my
my ender chest here but not always and
maybe like a little bit of every type of
block
like one stack of each of the types of
clay and that might be nice for this as
well
for when we're designing stuff um
yeah i brought my bed with me so cool
can go ahead and sleep here whenever
it's nighttime and i brought some water
but it's maybe we will
hide those actually let's put it behind
the ender chest here
if we can let's see
if we put water down here is that going
to be hidden
and then we'll put the red clay no i
can't put the red clay back
ooh could do something like that though
and then
put that back here and then if we want
to get water ever
you can still do it but it's not like in
your face right
yeah so i might do that as well
all right cool guys so we pretty much
got the redstone room all set up here
got the ceiling on now i used white
glass might need to do some terraforming
up there to make it look nicer later
but let's go ahead and give this a test
run now let's design
a redstone project together so i got a
couple supplies over here not quite
everything i want but oh i forgot
hoppers
there's no hoppers darn it
all right we're missing hoppers but
otherwise i think we're pretty much
stocked here
um yeah let's let's design something
here this is an idea i've had for a
little while for
possibly if i can get it to work here
one of the simplest
counting devices you can possibly make
in minecraft
uh so what we're going to want to do is
set up nine lights
and if if we can figure this out it'll
be pretty cool i think let's see let's
get our stone brick see this is nice
it's almost like being in creative
because you have everything you need
right on hand normally i
waste a lot of time looking for stuff
i'm even grabbing a redstone
what am i doing here that's kind of
important
uh did i grab the comparators yeah i got
the comparators good
okay so there is a trick i found out a
long
long time ago like back when the
redstone update first came out
and i forgot about it for the longest
time up until
i made that armor stand game with doc on
the hermitcraft server i remembered the
trick again
which is again a reason why the redstone
museum would be nice here because
a lot of times i forget about stuff and
i don't remember how to rebuild it later
i think this was the pattern though
there's a cool thing you can do
for displaying numbers in minecraft
let's see here we're gonna need uh items
that don't stack so i'm gonna make a
bunch of swords here
to fill up the dropper all right that
should work
put those in here so every time there's
one sword added we want one more light
to turn on is the idea and if you
position the redstone just right you can
make that happen
so we got two on that's good three
um actually if i have that just over
there you see
it two it goes three we don't want that
we need it to go
um this might need to be moved see
this is why we need references because
now i gotta re-figure this out
okay so i managed to figure it out here
again
uh this is the redstone pattern it's
pretty simple so it kind of does a
zigzag
back and forth uh over the redstone
lamps here
and in one of these droppers we have
nine swords the other one's empty and
basically they're facing each other
and this is a really cool really simple
way of doing a counting system so
whenever we press this button it adds
one to the display
and whenever we press this one it
subtracts and the really cool thing
about doing it this way
is it's also super fast like you can you
make a counting system as quick as you
want really
aha so today what i want to try to do is
take this idea and take it one step
further
can we that make it so that when we get
to the very end here
up to nine the next time we
press a button it goes down to zero and
adds one
to a display above that so it represents
the number 10 you know
is that possible how difficult would
that be to do
let's figure it out
okay so yeah basically what we want to
happen here is when this gets to the
number
nine and this has no items left in the
dropper when all the swords are into
this one and we add one more
uh obviously nothing's going to happen
here because it's empty but we want to
then add one to the display above
and then reset this back down to zero
which
uh it's actually a little bit tricky
because it's going to be slow
like let's say for example we set up
a comparator clock to do it right i'll
show you the issue that
that'll come up with that this c lantern
might not be the best choice actually
because i can't put redstone on it
i just realized um yeah let's set up a
comparator clock here though
so basically
um like for example seven segment
displays i think the quickest ones of
those are usually about
you can update them twice a second or so
um
with this we would have an issue for
sure
like we could only update it once every
two seconds or so
because watch how long it takes for this
to count down again
you know it's fast but we need it to
happen pretty much instantly so that's
our first challenge
second challenge is we gotta figure out
when to add one to this so
how does it know we're at the number
nine well this is going to be empty
so if this comparator is off
and we detect a button press we should
be able to do it with just an
and gate somehow here no
darn you know i thought this would be
super simple if we could do something
like this but it doesn't quite work
uh in order for this redstone lamp to
turn to turn on
and this torch to turn on this wire has
to turn off so two things need to happen
this
redstone torch needs to go off and the
comparator needs to go off which happens
when this runs out of swords right
uh the problem is this activates on the
number eight to nine
and we want it to happen on nine to ten
so we're at number eight now so next
time we press it it's not supposed to
turn this on but it does
yeah because right away this sword goes
out of the dropper here
uh we could probably get around that if
we add in some delay here
so basically it's only going to work if
this comparator was on
when we first pressed the button
so yeah something like this add a little
a repeater after the comparator
[Music]
and i guess
i don't know what i'm doing instead of
sending this a button press it has to be
a very quick pulse
in order to get away with this okay so
check this out i got a monostable
circuit set up here so notice how quick
this
repeater turns on and off
it's like on off real quick uh you'll
notice though this redstone torch is not
changing when we do that
and that is because redstone torches
need a delay of at least
two in order to activate
so now you'll see it switches so that's
a very minimum
pulse we can send this and still have it
functioning
so now we want this to to
turn the lamp on from nine to ten but
not eight to nine so let's see what
happens right now
with the way we have it all right we're
at
eight to nine right now it didn't switch
on that's good
possibly nine to ten now we want it to
turn on
and i guess it works first time here i
thought i would have to adjust this
wait a second maybe it just works with
because i have the monostable let's get
rid of that
uh let's try this again maybe we don't
need any more delay because the
comparator has a little bit of delay
itself okay
okay it's not turning on good so now it
didn't turn on okay
oh yeah so we don't even need a repeater
there this is the
this will work we just have to send it a
quick pulse cool
that's one problem figured out now how
do we reset this quickly
okay so i thought of possibly three
methods we could use to reset this
quickly
uh like if we want to get the swords out
of here into this dropper there's no
real way of doing that quickly using
redstone like
there's 10 redstone updates per second
if the game's running smoothly so
pulse on pulse off you can do that five
times five items per second
can be moved so the only other physical
way of moving items
is using minecarts
or is using hoppers right if you just
use a hopper though you can only put one
underneath here
you have to use minecart hoppers if you
want to move it quickly
so you would have to set up nine of
these
and then like push it underneath there
when you want it to to reset
it's not really what i would consider an
ideal method but it would work
very well actually yeah basically you
drop that when you want to reset it
and get the swords out of there you
would then send a piston
a pulse that moves it under there those
would go out of there super quick like
right away and then if timing was really
important you would do the same above
here to put them into this dropper again
so you need 18 mine carts in total
if you want it super fast not very
practical
another method we could use is mirror
this so we have another set of droppers
connected to the same display and
when we need this thunderstorm
when we need this to reset basically we
switch over to this one that's already
reset
and that way the display updates
instantly instead of having to wait
and the third method here the one we're
actually going to use here because it's
probably going to be a lot
simpler than the other two and more
compact uh is not
as ideal function wise because we're
gonna have to disable the display here
for two seconds when it resets but
everything should uh
still add up properly so we're gonna do
the comparator method like i said we
shouldn't do
originally i realized it's going to work
here because
like let's say we send this exactly nine
pulses when we want it to reset
if we add one during that it'll still
work out properly like there'll be eight
in in here and one in this one
so it's going to count properly but
we don't want that weird display thing
where it counts down after it resets we
we don't want to be able to see that so
what we're going to do is while it's
resetting
we're going to turn this to subtraction
mode
and give this a redstone a strong
redstone signal so that'll turn off the
display and make it look like it's at 0.
this will still function properly if
it's in subtract mode that doesn't
change anything
so basically we're sacrificing the
display for two seconds
uh whenever we reset here awesome so i
spent some time here putting this
together guys
and it seems to be working uh this is
what it looks like over here which
i know looks like looks like a lot but
really for what this is doing this is
not too bad it's fairly compact
uh could probably be improved a little
bit more here if i spend some more time
on it but
basically uh it seems to be working here
i'm still debugging it though and
figuring out what the speed limit is
i can see here's the problem with
redstone torches by the way like if i
do this as quick as possible the
redstone torch is going to burn out so
whenever you build a redstone circuit
with redstone torches in
you can't you can't like go
on a pulse off a pulse that's too fast
for it
even at a delay of two it'll still burn
out
so yeah uh the very quickest this
could possibly run because there's
redstone torches in the
circuitry is at three here at this speed
it won't burn out
and i'm not sure if it runs that fast
let's just
let's just check it here um
how do we check this let's see if we can
count
quick enough i got this hooked up to a
light so maybe it'll make it clearer
right now we're at 49 right four
plus nine um let's count the pulses here
and i'll shut it off
so one two three four five
six seven eight nine okay so we added
nine
and now we're at 54.
so no that did not work properly so it's
running a little bit faster than it can
handle we're gonna try slow it down here
we'll turn it on again so we're at fifth
or no right
wait what happened we're at 64 now
i think that was too fast one two 3 4
5 6 7 8
9 10 11 12. so we should be
at 64 plus 12 is
76 okay so at four ticks
that seems to be the fastest we can run
this right now and that worked out
pretty good
so that actually added properly uh there
is
one issue when it does the reset
you see how it turns off and then turns
on there so it's not super smooth
that's that's the two second delay that
the
display gets shut off that i was talking
about also when
we we go over here it's not quite
perfect either you saw it went to one
and then zero so
it's still showing the the reset a
little bit
uh let's try to get rid of the display
shut off i just got to break the
repeater here
kind of curious what that looks like
and so it'll actually show the countdown
now
i think yeah and it yeah that
might not look that bad actually
so maybe it's not a big deal
anyways so what we got going on here is
this is running two
amount of stable circuits this this wire
on the side here is not important really
uh this is the monostable circuit here
this little two by three thing we got
i use that instead of the pistons
because it's quieter oh yeah and then
the redstone torch
over here so the actual input to this
is right over here it goes to that and
gate thing we set up before
to this torch this turns on when we go
from nine to ten
and then runs up here sends a a pulse to
this dropper
which adds one to the tens and it also
goes off this way
uh this is just a pulse lengthener this
comparator thing we got here i can show
you example that right here so when we
send this a signal it takes a while for
it to bleed out
um so it just creates a long long pulse
kind of like a hopper clock
and that goes down to a comparator clock
here which sends
exactly nine pulses to
the reset and also it sends a signal to
this if we want to shut the display off
during that
so yeah anyways if it wasn't clear
already you can take this
and we have ones and tens shown here but
you can go hundreds thousands ten
thousands
it represents a really big number with
this just by tiling it
more more and more times i tried to
build it in a way here that is tileable
i tried to keep it a low profile so most
of the redstone is only two blocks tall
here
uh at the back it goes three blocks tall
but uh
you know you could you could move this
up higher or i got it forward to and up
to
each level here but you can arrange it
however you want
i tried to keep the redstone fairly
loose to connect to that next level here
and if you really worked on this i'm
sure you could get to work on
subtraction as well so not only
addition but subtraction uh just by
like doing what we did but doing it in
reverse as well
um yeah anyways
we did some building today guys we made
an amazing square room
that makes your eyes bleed if you have
ideas for that let me know
this wasn't really a building episode it
was more of a redstone episode we
kind of worked out something that i
think is cool here anyway i like doing
this kind of stuff
hopefully you enjoyed it as well those
of you that like redstone
and let's do the comment of the day it
says hey etho
this is a question about wilson you made
it possible to make him overweight
but i don't think you ever mentioned how
he can get in shape
is there something you can do to make
him more fit i don't know if he already
did something for this or not
if not maybe you can make it so if he
starves himself
he slowly loses weight you are awesome
yeah with rhett with uh wilson uh the
only way
for him to lose weight like
right now is for him to starve which is
not great because he also loses health
if he's starving so it's
we need to add some way of exercising
him
in the future if we can or some other
mechanic to keep him from
getting overweight because that's what's
killing him every time i i run a test
with him he gets to the five bars of
weight
and i can't really keep his health up
then because that deducts two points
from
his overall health gain and then i can
only
afford to lose two more and then he
starts uh losing his health
anyways hope you enjoyed today's episode
guys thank you for watching
and until next time take care
bye bye
[Music]