[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys
to another episode of our let's play
series
so guys i was brainstorming ideas for
our episode today
and i had a really interesting idea here
it occurred to me we can make a color
monitor
in minecraft we could use shulker boxes
as as sort of pixels right because you
can place them in the world
using dispensers you can break them and
you can also dye them
16 different colors so we could have a
colored monitor in minecraft
i know pretty cool that was my first
idea for today's episode
but then i had an even better idea
probably my best idea to date actually i
am of course talking about
solar freaking roadways what are they
they're solar freaking
roadways seriously though their
technology
they're gonna replace like a whole bunch
of stuff pyramid schemes
weight loss pills nigerian princess
emails
and they have microprocessors inside so
they're they're basically
science i've done the science for you so
you don't even have to think about it
don't even question it
now if you're like me people you're
worried about
our environments do you see the green
grass
where has all the green grass gone in
our worlds
energy breeds pollution i tell you but
not
solar freaking roadways because we're
gonna put
at least some recycled glass in them
that's my word to you they're gonna be
green
they're gonna be greener than grass
people at least one percent
recycled glass or one percent of one
percent there'll be some percentage in
there though
for sure that's my word to you and i
know you're probably throwing your money
at the monitor right now but don't
don't do that you don't need to because
they pay for themselves
they produce energy and pay for
themselves
so all i ask from you a few hundred
dollars each
that should get us going in conclusion
i'm gonna leave you with this okay
how amazing would it be are you tired
of having to plug your horse in at
nights to charge
paying ridiculous energy bills every
month
how amazing would it be if you could
charge your horse
while riding a solar freaking
roadway you can't do that there's no
proof they produce energy
but wouldn't that be amazing think of
that hope
as you invest in your future through me
through solar freaking roadways
thank you
okay uh let's move on
so something i keep forgetting to show
you guys is the new game rule that was
added
in the snapshots here for 1.11 the max
entity cramming rule which you can see
happening at our enderman farm so
basically by default
they decide to make it so if you have 24
mobs crammed together it will start
causing suffocation damage
and since these guys only have half a
heart they basically just die
automatically like constantly
so how does this affect my world my mob
farms it's a
little bit of an annoying thing i don't
like it
but like the enderman farm still works i
just have to
like regularly kill those guys otherwise
they'll die on their own and i don't get
xp from them
um something i read though is apparently
it also affects players
so i wanted to try that out here so if
we go in there with them it should cause
suffocation damage
oh we might not be able to go in there
with them
bump me away oh yeah
i can't do it oh darn
yeah let's try to ender pearl down here
if we can
they really push you around though it's
hard okay there we go
and oh yeah yeah
okay i want out oh darn it
oh i thought i'd be able to slice them
and then get out but it wasn't killing
them for some reason
there was an opening there
i didn't kill him because i didn't let
the sword charge
but i also couldn't like move out of
there either
oh man
is my stuff here
oh yeah it is there darn it uh
okay i can't get my stuff
gonna have to like get it this way i
think
and i can't go in there to pick up the
items it keeps pushing me there we go
we're getting them
all right guys so kind of recovered here
i got my stuff back
i think that enderman killed me because
i looked at it though not because of the
new game rule
to test that i would probably have to
kill myself again which i don't feel
like doing
uh so we've moved on to the blaze farm
here
because i thought this might be one
thing affected by the max
entity cramming and it definitely is so
before i would hold a certain number of
blazes here this would have to get up to
five lamps
um and that was exactly enough blazes to
go from
like level 27 to 30 to do an enchantment
and now it seems like they're gonna die
before
they get to the five five lamps
yeah because we probably gotta keep like
30 or 40 in there to do it
darn don't know what to do about that
kind of designed the whole system around
that and now
mojing have added a new game rule
so i either got to modify this or just
wait and see what happens if they leave
that on
by default which i don't want them to
but we'll see
so i noticed something happened here
today guys that doesn't happen very
often in our world
like only once every few months i would
say
we're actually running low on potions i
checked this chest
it's just about empty uh so it's time to
brew up another batch
usually i just do this off camera but
i know i realize like even when we do
the world tours
uh we don't have enough time to see this
running
so if any of you guys are new you
probably have no idea how this works
so i thought i'd just do a little quick
thing here to show you uh
we have like 40 brewing stands in this
lab
that all can run at the same time so
it's like an
overpowered crazy uh potion brewing
system
and that's why i very rarely have to
turn it on it has tons of storage
but it's split into two systems so over
here we have five brewing stands that
brew
up the awkward potions uh when we flip
up this lever
and then we have another lever over
there
that activates the rest of the brewing
stands um
so up over here we got a ladder this is
where i can
refill the empty bottles
i guess we got some here already yeah
basically just right click
shoots the water bottles into a big
hopper chain here
and those get funneled down into the
system uh
has a big reservoir of water bottles
that go into here and then up above
i wonder where we could get up i think
you can get up over here actually
there's a system for distributing those
those uh water bottles
or the awkward potions after they're
brewed um
where's the rail oh here it comes so
yeah this has
says awkward potions inside kind of
makes its way to each of these stations
and i found out a way to
make it sit and wait until it's it's
done unloading
all right there we go so this one's
unloading there was space for them there
so yeah it does its job and once it's
out of stuff it makes its way back picks
up more
and kind of fills up all the chests
okay okay they leave
giant waiting time oh man i just
realized i sucked at redstone when i
built this
it should let in a new batch right away
but i didn't know how to do that
apparently at the time uh-huh
all right so this potion lab also has a
built-in netherwort farm
which is uh mostly for decoration but
it's
also very useful to have nearby so you
get some netherwart nice and easy
nice and close put that in there refill
those
if any of these things run out of
ingredients it really messes things up
so i got to watch it carefully
uh these lights turn off if it runs out
of awkward potions i believe
aha so over here is our main switch
let's flip it
and that gets that gets the game lagging
very nicely uh but it activates all
these brewing stands over here for the
the main brewing um so all the awkward
potions get converted into
to their steps here it does it in a
chain so for
instant healing for example we have the
glycerin melon added first
then the glowstone and gunpowder and
each step
of the brewing process you can access uh
reservoir of potions here
uh instant health 2 without the
gunpowder without the
glowstone over here and just awkward
potions there
so it's a pretty cool little system and
i think i added something here too
for sending potions to the nether but i
don't know if it really works
let's try that out i'm curious so you
could
let's go get some fire resistant potions
those
i think the only time i really use
potions is in the nether actually
i i usually will use uh fire resistance
and uh speed potions
when i'm building something um fire
resistance
just in case i hit a pocket of lava and
speed
uh allows you to build stuff a lot
faster actually it's something i highly
recommend
people do if they got a repetitive
project
such as building a tunnel oops how does
this work
am i supposed to jump
i don't think it works i think i used to
be able to jump and bump it but that
doesn't seem to work now
anyways let's move on here last episode
we
or i showed you a a new system i built
here i think we're going to call it the
pixel
seem to be the the common thing but it's
a
shulker box storage system and i
tried to explain it as but i didn't do a
very good job
so there was a bunch of questions about
it that uh
maybe you could answer a few of them
here okay so i think one
question that came up was what happens
if you put an item in
that doesn't stack like
armor or enchanted books or that sort of
thing
i don't know if i actually tested that
so let's let's go ahead and give it a
try here
hopefully it doesn't wreck everything i
think it'll be okay though
what would probably mess it up is if you
had something that's stacked to 16 like
ender pearls
or eggs or that sort of thing probably
mess up the item filter
oh wait um let's search for gravel
you cannot search for items that that
don't stack though
that's a limitation of the system so i
can't search for armor for example
we got gravel we searched for gravel
in here it's still searching
oh
that was a long search
i'm wondering if it did it twice
uh good question no i think
it's just long because we had so many
choker boxes right
uh it didn't seem to mess it up let's
just double check there's no items on
the ground anywhere
yeah i think we're okay we did get the
gravel we searched for so i think that's
not an issue
actually i should probably clarify i
think we can have
ender pearls in our shulker boxes we
just can't do a search for them
because if we do a search for them it's
going to put an ender pearl in the item
filter
like if we if we have an ender pearl
here and throw it in because it stacks
the 16 it'll mess up the item filter if
it's allowed to enter it
uh but if it's just like an item in the
chest we're not looking for
it won't go into the item filter so
that's not a problem um
the other question is if we add more
shulker boxes does the search take
longer and yes
as we saw it can take longer also
a big question was what prevents it from
going into an infinite loop
because like
this shulker box gets searched first and
then it can re-enter here before it's
done
going through all all these other ones
right
uh no there's actually a system here to
prevent that that
redstone block there is a lock and
there's another one down there to hold
the items into
the chest over here and they alternate
from each other so basically
this is six chests tall over here right
six chests of shocker
box storage and then there's another six
chests above that so
uh double the storage above that
or not double but you know like copy
i'm great at explaining things aren't i
um there's an equal amount of storage
above that as a reserve it waits until
it
finishes searching through all the
shulker boxes and then it allows them to
re-enter
this bottom half uh we'll try to see
that happening here
um but i've recorded this a few times
and failed
so yeah you see that that redstone block
is over there so it's blocking this
chest here i think anything in here
oh not that chest
some hopper oh darn
yeah i'm great at explaining things
part of the problem is i can't actually
see anything
wait a second what does this redstone
block do guys it locks this hopper so
it's
oh so it prevents items from this chest
going down not this one
uh maybe we'll try that again
there's my steak let's try it again
also uh question was can i do a research
so can we search
uh stone blocks again i added this
button here to do that but i
think it's not working
i think we would have to activate it
over here
nope oh yeah yeah it's going i think
that's searching for stone blocks again
we'll see no
no it didn't work nothing showed up here
it was like an empty search wait a
minute actually it was in there
it just didn't shoot it from the
dispenser
okay so it kind of worked this thing has
a bunch of flaws though i'm gonna have
to
fix up and i'm like picking up shulker
boxes that are shooting out of it
because that's still an issue right now
but my plan with the system guys after
looking at your feedback
and like after building one of these and
seeing ways of improving it kind of want
to redesign it
and see if i can make it better because
at the moment it's like
on the verge of being practical and good
but i don't know it could be improved
because like if we look through these
shulker boxes just manually
it's about the same speed as the system
can run there's a speed limit to it
which is the speed of hoppers
at the absolute fastest you can search
is two and a half shocker boxes a
second which we can manually do
way faster than that so that's kind of
an issue
it is pulse possible to combine more
than one search engine
together the problem with that though is
once you take the boxes you've searched
and
re-entered them into the system like
let's say they have to go through the
chest
and hopper chain we have over there
again you're limited by the speed of the
hoppers so if you have
10 items entering a hopper you still got
to wait for them to go through that
hopper
so there's this kind of limitations in
minecraft
other thing i would do different if i
redesign this is get rid of these manual
item
elevators or these the ones that rely on
physics i would actually put in a
dropper
elevator here instead because you could
do that much faster
that would cut down on the startup and
ending times of the search
and another big thing you guys mentioned
is we need to set up some sort of deep
fragger
so this is kind of like a hard drive um
in our example here we have a lot of
chests with empty space in
let's let's take a look at these over
here we have
only one third of the chest is full
right over here this
we only got three stacks of items in
here there's a lot of wasted space and
that slows down the search time
significantly so if we wanted to make a
good
practical fast system we would want some
way of combining
these shulker boxes together the
contents together so
we could easily fit these three into one
and that would make the search
like three times faster for this case
here i tell you what guys we're going to
actually try to design that together we
want to make a device
to combine shocker boxes together
somehow
sounds like a fun little project so
probably start off with a chest of
shocker boxes right that are
not not totally full there'll be some
empty space in them or they might be
full
um and then we got to sort through them
and try to combine their content somehow
so
oh let's keep this locked for right now
so they'll kind of just wait in here
until we unlock it
all right and this is an empty shulker
box right yeah
oh there's the other one i was like man
i thought i brought five boxes
okay so these are probably gonna go into
a dispenser to place them in the world
and then we have to shift the contents
from the semi-full boxes or the full
boxes
into the
the totally full boxes we're trying to
fill up
does that make sense so we're probably
gonna need another
dispenser mechanism down here for
placing an empty shulker box
so like this one over here that'll place
it in the world
and then we'll have our semi-full ones
or full ones up here
oh yeah that's empty right now that will
get placed and then we need to
like shift the contents from the one
above down below now if we just use a
hopper that'll work
but it'd be pretty slow okay so the
trick to getting around
the slow nature of hoppers is to use
hopper mine carts because you can
combine a bunch of them together
in like no space at all the problem
here though is i don't think you can
place a track
on a shulker box no you can't so we
can't just put it right above this
we're gonna have to offset it like half
a block
so we'll put a fence there that way we
can
align it somehow and then we can have
like a piston here
put our track here and then we can
combine as many
hopper mine carts as we want here the
more we put the faster it'll transfer
the items between the two boxes
yeah that seems to be working good okay
and then we gotta like break the chest
or the
track yeah there we go that works and
then with the piston we can
hopefully just push him over
was that not a button i'm confused i
thought i placed the button down
i'm losing my mind i thought i just made
one button
oh piston translocation
i love piston translocation but it's
really been uh
it's getting me lately okay i got those
set up again let's try this again
i'm gonna use a lever this time though
so when we pull that
kind of offsets it half a block and then
we break the piston
so now any
you know i shouldn't have placed it
there
because it's going to pull items out of
the dispenser too not just the shulker
box
oh it's not even placing them in there
ew
[Music]
why would that be i'm not really sure
okay okay i moved it to the other side
here but it's still not doing what i
want to do it's not placing the items in
the shulker box here
and honestly i'm not really sure why
so we're going to try maybe a trapdoor
instead
of a fence gate
and let's try this one more time
oh i did it again so stupid
okay let's just let's leave the one
minecart there at least
okay so now if we put items in here
still don't go into the shulker box oh
because it can't open now right
let's break that still doesn't go in
does it need to be on a rail
even on a rail it's not working i'm so
confused
this is one we won't put the items in
so admittedly my memory in this game is
not the best but i thought
at one point you could transfer items
from a hopper mine carts
into like a chest or something by
putting it on top
could be wrong on that could be wrong
it does work if you do it to a hopper
though
uh problem is we're trying to do this to
avoid the speed limit of a hopper
so we may as well just use a normal
hopper then
we can't really get around this the slow
nature of it then
unfortunately so
wait where did uh oh i got it on me
again
okay so basically shulker box will get
placed there
contents will start draining down into
here very slowly
and then what do we need to do i guess
we gotta detect when this empties
and when it empties then we
break it and change it out with another
one
from the q here right
likewise when this one is is full
or when items stop transferring into it
then we need to switch it out with a new
empty
shocker box right so we could do that by
detecting
if items are flowing through this hopper
maybe
so once there's no items flowing through
here then
it switches this box with the new one so
this shut off now
so then this would break and it would
maybe place a new one
it's actually a little bit of a
complicated thing we also need to know
when we're done
like when there's no more boxes here so
we would need another
detector here when there's no more items
flowing through here
then we know we're done
okay so i might have uh figured out one
part of this anyway
it's actually a little bit of a tricky
puzzle uh so
let's do a little test run here we'll
put a couple items in here
a couple items in here a few in there
so we're going to take these three boxes
we'll put them in the dispenser
and then it should automatically
put them into our shulker box down here
so let's give it a try
so that turns this comparator on over
here
and then when it runs out of items it
does that so that put the
chalker box into this hopper on the side
here
these are all empty yeah that's good
okay yeah so those items went down into
the shulker box down here
this is what the redstone looks like
currently so what we
could do then is detect
when this hopper goes from no items to
items passing through
i suppose so we put a block here
and just run it to the dropper or the
dispenser here right
oh i don't know why that scared me
i can't get used to that sound that's a
zombie villager it's just
it's like the most scary sound in the
game right now to me
i don't know why okay we only need this
to activate once
all right and then it does its own loop
thing so let's try this again we've got
some boxes
let's put them in the chest this time
uh this is locked i think okay so when
we unpower this
should do it all on its own now
nope oh we need a delay here
a little bit of a delay
okay because it activates the dispenser
before the shocker boxes actually get to
it i think
try one more time
there we go place the first one it's
draining
items are going into here
good
aha okay so here's the problem whenever
you make something with redstone you
always got to think of what is the worst
case what could possibly break the thing
you've made
and because this by default is off
if we put an empty shulker box in here
nothing changes so this gets placed
and then that's it it breaks it
not really sure what to do about that so
in our storage room if we had any empty
shulker boxes it would break this
this thing we would have to add
something else
for that also i realized if we
uh just detect if items are flowing
through here
that's not gonna work either i'm not
sure how to tell when this box is full
because it might be like we have three
birch fences in
and that doesn't count as a full stack
so it's not going to output a full
like 15 length signal from here
a little bit of a tricky thing to uh
figure out isn't it
if you guys have any ideas let me know
i'm kind of out of ideas for today
though
um i think we will wrap up our episode
all right guys so our comment of the day
here it says the main issue
that this system may have that's the
pixel
search engine system we were just
talking about
is if there's a substantial amount of
boxes in the system
say 200 and the box that has the torches
is at the topmost stack then it will
take a long time to be sorted out
yeah that is definitely an issue with
the system and the reason why it might
not be practical currently
so with the thing we just made there the
defragger
would help out a lot it would speed
things up a lot but another idea would
be
to somehow introduce categories
into our system so for example if we
have 200 shulker boxes
if we could divide that into let's say
10 categories like a stone block
category that would have cobblestone
stone stone bricks you know all that
sort of thing
then it would be 20 shocker boxes per
category
maybe and you could search through 20
chunker boxes pretty quickly so that
would be another
major way of increasing the speed and
actually making it a practical system
to do that i'm not really sure how
that's another thing i've been thinking
about
but hopefully we can figure it out all
right
anyways guys hopefully you enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
as always
and until next time take care
have a good day bye