[Music]
good day everybody this is etho
and welcome back to the messy cave here
uh our plan for today is to continue
working on the silverfish farm to
complete it
and get it working
one thing i will be doing is getting rid
of this water because
uh mobs jumping around in water
causes a lot of lag
so it should still work without the
water but
we'll keep an eye on that change
actually no we can move this up one more
yet
we'll just see how that goes
um i have added a little bit of a room
under still doing parkour around here
fun stuff yeah so last time we kind of
worked
on this killing chamber and we messed
around with
with them as well i added this room here
kind of like underneath underneath the
floorboards
uh it's just these levers here control
the lamps above they power them
somebody said they're like rumored that
uh and then that in the 1.3 patch
they're gonna add upside down levers
which is something i just briefly talked
about the other day
so that's that's cool that that's
getting added if they do i can just
rip these blocks out and put them
directly under
the lamps and it'll look a lot better
but the point of that room if there's
silver fish
roaming around in there if i walk in
here
they will all start targeting me and
when i walk out they will all
follow me and fall down here
so that's an easy way of getting to them
without having to go
inside the danger room um
while i was working on this
i was i ran into some lava pretty close
to all this wood so i decided i'd move
it back and i got
careless i'm missing the axe i
went for a swim in the lava and i got
out
just not quick enough i i
burnt really close to it and apparently
my axe
and my one of my picks felon
which was pretty sad
yeah about the upside down levers it
seems like a lot of the things i see
in my lp actually get added to the game
or changed in the game so
i don't think i'm directly responsible
for it but
it must get people talking or something
i don't know
one of the advantages of having a lot of
publicity
but if somehow the words i am saying now
can reach mojang
it would be really cool if they added an
option to hide
ip addresses
so that you know if people are streaming
or
recording youtube they don't have to
worry about
not showing ip addresses that would be
an excellent feature to add to the game
i know there's a mod that does it but it
would be cool if it was built in as well
and i'm just rummaging around here
roaming around
doing nothing okay so what we're going
to do is we're going to work on the
tunnel
it's going to go that way for ways and
then it will start to go
up i will
possibly make it out of sandstone
i might change this to sandstone too
yeah uh people were wondering why i used
the half slabs
because we're down at lava level and
stuff could each easily catch on fire if
i use something that burns
so that that's one reason why i might
want to use sandstone for this too
so i'll go get some i might go to the
end and enchant a new
axe as well and i will see you guys back
yeah i got a bunch of sandstone ready
for the tunnel and we are going to
enchant the axe now
43. it will have to do
not quite like the one we had before um
a lot of people have been wondering
what's the deal with this island am i
going to
finish it am i going to make more when i
built it i didn't realize how enderman
teleports
and it's
if i remember yeah i'm pretty sure i'm
right about this they can teleport 32
blocks
in any direction and they kind of do it
randomly
so this is too close to
the farm and there's no way of
preventing it really
they like you can't just like put
torches and they won't teleport there or
put half slabs and they won't teleport
there
even if you have water down they'll
teleport to it but
at least they'll try to teleport again
so that's that's really the only way of
preventing them from
going somewhere is putting down water
and then they'll they'll still go there
but they'll teleport away
which is not something i want to put on
the island anyway so
we might still do the the floating
island idea but we'll just have to build
them
farther away if we do and that one i'll
have to tear down
and that's that's the story with that
project but we're gonna go back to the
silverfish farm and i will see you there
uh we're gonna do a pick too because i
gotta do a lot of digging for this
project
yeah that'll do
and here we are again so i have replaced
the wooden planks with sandstone in this
peeling chamber
and in my opinion it looks a lot better
but i am known to be partial and biased
when it comes to sandstone but we'll
we're going to keep it like that and
with the
the turtle the tunnel we will
probably do sandstone walls at least
maybe the floor too
we might change the floor here with
sandstone yet
i don't know you can't go wrong with
sandstone
you really can't uh but we'll do just
the walls first
and maybe figure out afterwards
uh this here is the gate control to let
them out
to let them into the tunnel if we're
going to transport them
and what we got to do is we got to build
a horizontal
ish tunnel first just to get it
a little ways away because the storage
room is only
10 or 15 bucks above and it's going to
be fairly big we don't want
this to go like straight up to the
surface because then the two will
will get in each other's ways so we want
it to go a little ways out first and
then go up
so that they don't interfere
let us try some sandstone walls and i
might
whip out the new sandstone textures too
afterwards and
and change it up a bit with that too
let's see so this tunnel it should be
two or three blocks wide at least
because uh we need to
escort the silver fish out of here we
can't have them go on their own because
just like the other hostile mobs if they
get
uh more than 32 blocks away from us they
have a chance of despawning over time so
uh we'll have to be right next to them
we're gonna have
the tunnel for them and then there's
also going to be a small tunnel for me
with water streams in that will slowly
push me to the surface
so that they can keep up and i don't
have to
to walk it myself you know that's that's
what i'm
planning with this and to separate
us to we'll either do iron bars or
glass panes probably that would make it
roughly two and a half blocks or so
of space for them um
because they're going to be fighting
each other for space they'll be in each
other's way and if we make
their tunnel too too narrow they'll
elongate
elongate elongate and
become too far away from us that they'll
stop tracking us and
then they'll just randomly
wander off and despawn
yeah i'll get i'll get the stuff here
okay i got some materials together here
and we can begin building this
tunnel let's let's see how this looks
and again you guys are going to have to
forgive me for
being a little late on the episode
release again i know i
i said i want to get more active with lp
but just the way things turned out the
last few days i've been
involved in a lot of minecraft
activities it's not because i was lazy i
just
had a lot i was doing
i think what i'll or what i plan to do
is get into the habit of making a point
of recording these a day in advance
because normally what i'd end up doing
is
releasing the lp
as soon as it's done you know assume the
day i
i record is the day i upload it is my
habit
uh and what i should really do is just
try to record in a day
in advance so that if i can't finish it
or something comes up i can have another
day to do it
and i think that'll work out better in
the future but yeah
just had a lot going on this week
on thursday uh kurtz
had invited me to join in on his 30
charity event which was a race for wool
i played with good
paz zisto
on one team and
versus the kgbs kurt and his team
we did a race for wool together on
thursday and that's
that took a bit of time it was a lot of
fun though
although the map
we did it blind and it ended up being a
type of race for wall map that you
should look at beforehand
how's this going to look if we use
paints instead
i don't really like using paints too
much or glass anymore i prefer the iron
bars
because the white is just so intense on
on the panes or on glass
yeah i'm gonna do bars
yeah so with that map uh the match ended
up dragging on
very long and it was pretty frustrating
especially towards the end
because we just didn't know how we were
supposed to do it actually let's see how
sandstone will look
instead of the wooden planks so i
probably won't be uploading
that match uh but it was fun to play
regardless
to to an extent i think
we you now unanimous unanimously
we're frustrated with it both teams we
should have looked at it beforehand
fortune pick yes
um then on friday
uh document had his fifty five thousand
fifty five five five five five sub
special i don't like how he does that
to be honest but the the
the five five five five instead of just
doing a fifty thousand subscriber or
something
whatever anyway uh
just because it's harder to say uh but
yeah we did
this is going to get in the way isn't it
of course okay i'll have to clear this
uh yeah i think i prefer the full
sandstone over the wooden plank floor
so we'll go with that
but yeah doc got a bunch of youtubers
together for his special
to play some hunger games that was
pretty cool
thanks for hosting that event doc
and for inviting me along
he also held a contest to pick
five viewers to play along with us and
that was cool i gotta play with one of
the contest winners
uh shout outs to no mercy thank you for
for playing with me we made a great duo
good team
and sorry i didn't get to say goodbye
but i
i had to get going there and you were in
the middle of a game when i left
uh but yeah we played some hunger games
i'll probably upload footage of that
sometime soon it was a lot of fun
then later i also
some of you might have might have saw or
heard this but
the redstoners uh
we were involved in this big event where
the red storms played the whiskey
brigade
oh i hope i said that right whiskey
brigade i think that's what their name
was
and they were the the season two
champions of the race
for wool reddit tournament and i and the
redstoners
that's myself seth bling fvdisco and
kraft dynasty or tree as we like to call
them
we were the season one winners of
the race for wool tourney the reddit
race for will attorney
i guess over here we'll start to make
this go up
so we'll start we'll start with an
incline
about
see uh we need the water to push us
up so we're going to use half slabs
and probably go up at it
like a 2 1 right here or 1 2 rate
whatever it is
like that but yeah that's
uh that took up a lot of time that's the
main reason why the lp got delayed
because
we had to practice our race for wool on
friday we also played a scrimmage game
on friday to to practice more for it and
then on saturday we played the official
match
which i um
which i did record but it's extremely
long it's an hour and a half
close game i may upload it
i'm not sure yet it's an hour and a half
and i kind of hate breaking it into
parts
but yeah that might come out too
that was uh that was really intense i
thought it was just going to be the
simple thing but then
a pretty big deal was made about it like
there was a post on the minecraft forums
about it
they made a specific map just for us and
it's like the most crazy
race for wool map ever
you know i'm gonna dig out some more of
this
and then we'll continue
all right so jump forward 30 minutes
into the future and this is what we have
of the tunnel
so far making progress
got it going all the way up to the
surface this is the path
i will be taking the player and the
silver
fish will be to the right of me here
once it's done
running low on sandstone though so i'll
have to go harvest some more
from the sandstone mines
and this is where we come out nice place
all right so i will continue
we might need to get another pick too
i'm not sure
and another update here this is about an
hour
ahead of the last update i just showed
you i've been
working on the silverfish stairs oh
forgot to put the half slabs in and
these go
all the way up now um
then we just got to put the walls in the
ceiling
and iron bars in between and the water
and the signs
oh boy don't know it's getting late here
if we can finish or not i hope we do um
oh is that it yeah okay we caught up
uh i found a bunch of these iron picks
at the other base there i decide we'll
use them up today instead of going
enchanting again
so we got some i just used an efficiency
three one up
we got a bunch of efficiency twos though
so
just to clean up some of the tool
storage
i'm gonna use these up and also grab
some sandstone from the other base
but big project big project even though
it looks so simple there's
a lot of digging a lot of block placing
and everything involved
as is placing some iron bars here and
there may be a flaw with this
i'm not sure yet we'll we'll see when we
test it
but this is a full block increase
and silverfish are going to be pressed
against this iron bar trying to get us
so they're going to hit this and they
might get slowed down from it i'm
guessing they'll just jump up
and hopefully keep up because
if they linger behind us then they
will stop tracking us and
get far away and despawn which we don't
want so we'll have to see when
we get to testing but we'll we'll keep
it like this for now
and change it later if it's a problem
time for another update this is another
hour hour and a half ahead uh
getting really late here gonna go to bed
soon
unfortunately we won't be able to test
it today
but i got it all dug out now we're down
to our last
two mediocre picks
and all we have to do now is place the
sandstone the iron bars
and the signs in the water
and test it so
looking pretty cool in honor of good i'm
going to call this project the
eternal that's its official name the
turtle
for transporting silverfish to the
overworld
uh i also made
a pitiful attempt at collecting enough
sandstone to finish it
which i don't think is enough
i'm almost certain it's not enough but
we will try
actually we'll do we'll do the
underneath first
so i remembered something else that i
did
the last few days that also took up some
time and that was
pretty fun as well uh related to
minecraft that is
i was involved in three pranks in a very
short
amount of time so first
uh one day pause came by while i was
working on that slime
tower and
we were goofing around and i asked if
you wanted to do something
and pranking came up and we
ended up pranking mcgamer
by well he asked me what i wanted to do
and i said fill his place up with boats
and i asked him what he wanted to do and
he said fill
his water pellets that he just drained
of water
back up with water so we combined the
two and that's how that prank came to be
it was a spur of the moment thing but we
did it pretty quick late at night
then ander andersell pranked me with the
redstone thing
that was pretty good quick cleanup
um and then there's also another prank
mcgamer got back at me along with two
other people and video of that will come
out soon
gotta edit it and and just
figure out when i'm going to release it
and that took a little while as well so
three pranks i'm out of half slabs no
okay we'll stop that there
oh maybe i'm not done mining i thought i
was
oh but he will get his trust me he will
get his
uh something else i noticed
uh in the uhc
as many of you know i did not perform
very well in
some of the battles and
i was a little bit shocked by those but
or by that i should say but after
playing
the race for wool with against the kgbs
on
thursday i kind of figured out what was
up i am
apparently pretty rusty it's at pvp
and my my shots were way off
when we first started because
like i've tarnished my reputation a
little bit but i used to be pretty good
with the bow
and in general
not to brag or anything but that was
kind of the
the consent what's the word consensus
among people that i was pretty good with
the bow
from the old race for wolf videos and
whatever but after playing on thursday i
realized i've gotten pretty rusty
but like as the match progressed i could
tell i was getting a lot better pretty
quick then
on our friday
practice scrimmage against the seabees
they by the way are one of the best
bow fighters i've ever seen that team
the four of them
i was pretty impressed with their
performance
during that match i shot a total of
probably over a thousand arrows at them
and that's definitely helped to get me
back into the groove i'm i feel i've
i've recovered from being rusty now
and then the the match on saturday
against the
whiskey brigade that is their name i
checked uh
definitely has got me back again
so looking forward to the next uhc i
think i'll do a lot better
now that i've practiced up again and
i've
i also noticed a few bad habits i had
like holding shift
always while shooting was something i
was doing and
kind of shaking that habit now
which is a good thing to do when you're
using the bow if people don't know where
you are but it's not something you
should do
all the time especially if you're in a
confined area
because it slows down your movements
uh yeah we're not we are not even close
to enough sandstone
so i don't know how much more we're
gonna do with this today
unfortunately
um i also think i ran out of things to
talk about
hmm
oh well i'm going to stop recording for
a bit here and
i will get back to you
and this is the final update so i kept
going here about another hour or so
collected more sandstone and we got it
finished
we got the bars we got all the sandstone
placed
we're starting to put some signs down to
hold the water in place
once we get that in and there's a few
other
things i forgot about like the lighting
we'll have to put in the ceiling and
and uh yeah but
overall it's about done now
and we're just gonna do a dry run and
call it an end
and call it an end for the day
and obviously i'll i want to have
something a little fancier at the top
here
oh boy
but yeah that's that's it so far so
let's go
to the silverfish where'd he go there
you are
let's go get some silver fish and try it
out
all right so there are a few leftover
silverfish blocks here which we'll just
manually break to try this out
there these are in an awkward place uh
i'll
probably have to manually break all of
them to get them out of here
let's just break a few in case we need
to do a few more tests
and
okay so i will ender pearl out of here
go underneath
yeah oh did i leave i left the gate open
didn't i
yep
oh well uh that should have been closed
walk to the center so it'll track us
hopefully
that seems to work
um any more in there that we missed
i just want to see how effective that
was
okay there's one
still one roaming around in there
we'll leave them be okay so if we go
over here they should all
trickle through yeah
and they're all following us nicely
let's see
so they're they're quite a bit slower
than us we don't want to move too quick
that's why we're using the water streams
to get a
consistent speed what happens here
yeah we got a bit of a bottleneck now
okay so what i could do
like they're running into the full block
whoa
they launch you like crazy uh what i
could do is probably replace that with
the half slab
it might look a little weird but they
shouldn't be able to fit through the
half slab and iron bar
yeah they don't want to come at all
uh the iron bars also mess up their
pathfinding i'm pretty sure
if they're in them like that which might
be why
they stay there even after i leave
all right well that's about as far as
this test is going to go
i will catch you guys next time thank
you for watching
and i'll have a good night or day or
whatever it is
[Music]
you