greetings again all my wonderful viewers
this is etho here's my plan okay I've
been looking at the silverfish farm
again I'm still not using it like I
originally intended to and I've been
trying to figure out what I need to do
to change it so I've been looking around
and I think the main problem I'm having
or the main reason why I don't just come
and knock the silverfish out it's
because I have it set up with six layers
and if I'm hitting silverfish down here
the top two layers they'll never come
out of there too far away so I have to
sort of manually remove them which is a
problem the other issue is like when I
originally made this I made it the size
it is so that's if I was to kill all the
silverfish I would get to level 50 which
was the maximum or what you needed to
enchant stuff back in the day that's
changed and there was also another
problem like if I was to have all those
silverfish released it would cause
tremendous legs so I never was able to
do that anyway so I think this is what
I'm going to do this bottom room here is
not really useful to me the snow golems
they're cool but really they don't they
don't work like I intended
well they do make the silverfish come
out but they're way too slow and now I
can make the silverfish come out using
poison potions or or other means so
novelty effect of these guys is gone so
you're fired you're fired you're fired
you're fired you're fired and that's it
okay
so what I'm going to do let's see I
think what I should do is raise the
floor up to this level here then I'll
remove two more blocks so I can walk
underneath that will leave three layers
of silverfish blocks and that seems
pretty ideal actually I'll be able to
get them all out really easily it'll
still look pretty much the same we'll
just not have these little rooms for the
snow golems I'm going to raise this
floor up it'll look exactly the same
might have to why I will have to change
some stuff with the tunnel but all in
all I think it'll work a lot better that
way
so that is what we're going to do to
start out with today renovations begin
kyoool so I got most of that changed
over
so yeah this room still looks the same
like it's not going to look different
still looks the same down here only
difference is we got rid of that bottom
layer which we didn't really need and
yeah instead of going just three layers
I kept it at four because I don't want
the life I went one higher the
silverfish would start jumping up into
these places and ya don't want that
happening and four still works so that's
pretty cool
where was the center that's the center
how do we want to do this try try maybe
doing that and then finish it cool I'm
also going to try hug up the sensor here
to detect when this thing is full so
it'll shut down on its own I never did
end up doing that and we removed two
rows of Pistons yeah all right maybe
I'll just do salt glass
so we're going to take a little
enchantment break here we're at level 33
I was doing a whole bunch of repairing
another day on the minecraft server and
I kind of learnt or like I figured out
what I'm how I'm going to use anvils
specifically what I'm going to use it on
so for armor it's almost always a good
idea to use the repair on it because you
can get any diamond piece from
completely broken to fully repaired
basically with 4 diamonds so that is a
good deal plus you get to keep the
enchantment you got so protection for is
a very good enchantment and if you only
got that on a piece of armor it's pretty
cheap XP level wise - to repair it it
does not seem worth it to me to ever
repair a shovel because the shovel costs
only one diamond to make and you will
probably spend 4 diamonds to repair it
Plus XP so you may as well just take a
chance and try to get another good
shovel just by enchanting it properly so
that's is what I'm going to do with this
it might be worth repairing picks but I
don't know it's almost worth just
enchanting a new one always although
like efficiency for unbreaking 3 picks
now you might want to spend the diamonds
on it because you'll spend 4 diamonds on
a pick that you could get with 3 plus
it'll cost you a few extra levels with
XP like three more levels to fully
repair it but it might be worth it
stuff with three enchantments like I
don't think I would ever try repairing
that or stuff like this I don't think
it's worth it because you have to repair
it like 4 times get it all the way
repaired and it costs so if you
like 120 levels so it's not really worth
it for anything with three enchantments
with swords again it's not really worth
enchanting just any old sword I would
probably use it with a looting three
sword though but that's about it
and yeah axes they take three diamonds
so you might want to repair those same
as picks not that I ever use axes
anymore shovels work just the same
except they're cheaper or at least they
seem to work just the same anyway let's
head back to the silverfish farm I've
just about got ready just about got it
ready to try outs with the new
renovations alright here we are it is
still a big mess on the outside but
we're on our way here to getting it's
nice and functioning so I move this room
up higher - this room is so I can
attract them to me if I need to this is
the killing room I do want to try
something here before we we unleash
havoc I wanted to see just to make sure
so with my whole silverfish problem oh
you broke me broke me pants man with the
silverfish problem I still don't think
it's working where I can get them
through this portal so we'll just
double-check that
oh okay maybe it is working that is the
very first time I've had a silverfish go
through and stay let's try let's try
with a few more I say it's a glitch like
that it wasn't working few people said
it was because I was using old
silverfish I need to use new ones then
you through yeah they're doing it still
and that might be although it doesn't
really make sense to me okay okay now um
we'll kill these guys will kill all of
them
that's right we're gonna unleash the
silverfish apocalypse people have been
wanting to see it for a long time just
inside the machine no not quite the full
deal in the outside world so just seal
this back up I think I got all the seals
taken care of we will go up our stairs
here OOP
okay so yeah I should be able to Oh all
right the ladders are very glitchy so
I'm going to remove some of these and we
will just do it like like this I guess
alright we're going to unleash havoc to
all they climbed out through the ladders
that's crazy this is not expecting that
they all get out what the heck all right
break break around the ladders okay we
just want a few out here okay that
should do we will unleash poison and you
know what's going to happen this is
going to see how can I do this where I
won't get hurt that is the question
alright here goes
what is crazy oh my goodness set the
limit
oh come on guys there's a lot more than
that let's see them all we came here for
the show I'm just going to hurt me Oh Oh
what one got me i leg no don't fall down
the hole ah I'm getting hit
I'm legging through her I can't stop him
whoo oh there's another one
oh my goodness
yay so it's still maybe a little bit
leggy with with four rows let's just
shrink this down see if that helps us oh
I know particles particles videos
particles minimal turn that back up
still 10 frames per second not ideal
okay so we're going to go down to our
room
how how are they getting through are
they actually getting through the bear
not be getting through I'm going to be
mad if they wreck this place again what
are you guys doing okay now they're just
pushing each other they're not actually
getting through the blocks that's good
pletely and damage me no okay so they
should all start tracking me still ten
frames per second it wouldn't be bad if
I wasn't recording yeah we will try
changes to video settings will go shorts
traffic's fast okay now I'm getting five
frames per second it's actually worse
wonder why that is
that's weird
Oh No
mmm okay I'm going to stop recording a
bit and try get them into place all
right these guys are settled down a
little bit better getting five frames
per second not good because they're I
think they're bumping into each other
and it's leaving them extreme velocity
in the game maps it calculates if
they're colliding with blocks and it's
just a big high performance issue
because right now we're looking at about
600 silver fish roughly so let's get rid
of them there's poison Oh No
why are they breaking free I think there
was some blocks left in there still
sounds like they're getting triggered in
my cave Oh oh man it's so bad so I'm
going to have to do like two layers at a
time can't do all four all right please
die who did they get free I'm getting
hurt I have no idea what's going on here
um very bad frame rates and getting
attacked now
okay and stop recording yeah basically
the XP balls are legging the game really
really bad but that should go away soon
level 25 so far 1500 entities man oh
that's crazy
there goes 900 900 is like the magic
number then it starts working fine I
think they're going to where are they
all 700 I don't know where they are are
they all there yeah they might all be
there oh man
as crazy well I guess we'll see what we
end up with yeah it took us to level 48
that's that's really excessive we only
need level 30 so when we when we harvest
them we'll have to do it's when it's
only partially full and there's still
like a row there that never got taken
out so check that they're actually
silverfish yeah there but you that's a
solid one yeah cool Oh
skelton I heard a Skelton I'm hearing a
skeleton I don't see you skeleton that's
weird
see up above come on
hitting the ladders battle see him okay
so next thing I'm going to try to
produce a new silverfish and see if
he'll go through the portals okay we got
new silverfish blocks in production here
we're going to try this out the rumor is
at the old or the blocks of silverfish I
made the for certain patch would not go
through the portal for some reason but
new ones will so that's what we're going
to check out I've tried this already and
something weird happens where they fell
through the ground and I could not find
them so we'll try this again get an
extreme lag from them jumping up in the
water big problem in Minecraft make
those vitamin old ones okay we want to
try a big group of them though because
yeah they're falling through the world
or something because I only see one
right now and this game I don't know
what's going on today ah so much strange
stuff happening ah where the other ones
go I don't get it okay they fell through
several layers of blocks somehow
there's another one it will try it a
group of them go in here they're going
to make a mess think three is all we can
get okay we'll try it's free going
through a portal one two you can jump up
oh that for all right we got four oh man
and that's where the skeleton is by the
way I found them all right what are you
guys are gonna do they're doing it again
I think dude yeah they still do it I
don't guess something weird about my
world portal just does not work for some
reason any new world I make it does work
but not here I think one went through
there's only three left now and all
right well the good news is I can repair
the silverfish damage on my boots for
pretty good price that maze will do all
four awesome
all right well I think we're going to
move on to comment reading well I've
picked out two comments for today the
first one mind if I use the eats Road on
my server if so thanks if you can get it
to work go for it man have fun with it
each road has always had a bad history
with working on servers but now that
single-player and multiplayer are pretty
much the same it it actually might work
I haven't tried it yet but it might and
as with anything on my channel actually
one of my original goals and still is my
goal with my YouTube channel to create
cool things in Minecraft that people
will have fun making themselves so if I
make something feel free to make it
yourself that's that's what I'm trying
to do
keep Minecraft fun for myself and for
other people as well so yeah thanks for
the comments next one heyy so you spend
a lot of time playing Minecraft as do we
all
oh yes I do but I was wondering how you
used to fill your time in the days
before minecraft well hmm I do like
playing video games so one of the things
I would do is play video games other
games besides Minecraft I'm a little
strange with the way I play video games
or which games I choose to play I'm nuts
a lot of people they'll play new games
they'll keep their eye out for new games
and they'll pick one they like I do that
too but to a lesser extent I usually
just play older games that I've liked I
have a list of games that are among my
favorites that I keep playing over and
over and throughout the years and I
might go a few years since I last played
one of my favorite games and I'll play
it again type thing that's that's how I
choose my games so more recently FTL has
been added to that list terraria
it's another one on that list which I
try to play every now and then on my
spare time but also another big thing is
programming I used to spend about an
hour a day programming just for the fun
of it I was big into programming with
XNA before minecraft now as getting to
the point where I was making some pretty
complicated and cool stuff XNA is mostly
used for video game programming by the
way so yeah thank you for your comments
as well and thank you everybody for your
comments just as a reminder you know
this is a family channel I try to keep
things as clean as again so I appreciate
it if you keep your comments as clean as
you can as well but I'm not going to try
to control you the main thing is that
you don't be rude to other people that's
the main thing that gets me upset and I
do block people for that sometimes but
yeah thank you for watching everybody I
hope you have a wonderful day and I will
see you again next time