hey what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back to our let's play series
once again and oh man we got we got a
project planned for today so last
episode we we caught this guest we're
trying to make a tree farm write an
automatic tree farm we set up a system
here to automatically collect the wood
and it seems like it's going to work out
pretty good I would say it might might
be a little bit slow but we'll see once
we get it up and running like I'm
worried the gas might take a little
little while to harvest the wood but
we'll see might not be an issue but
today what we're going to try to do is
finish up the second half of this and
actually build the tree farm it's kind
of important so yeah the idea is we're
gonna have to stand here I tried to turn
the sounds down it's still very loud
isn't it down we go okay I'm gonna get
creeper so many times today I know it so
I got my hostile mob sounds at at one
which is never a good idea yeah we're
going to be standing here and idea is we
want to start harvesting trees or
growing trees
so I guess we need like a dispenser this
that shooting bone meal at saplings we
plant so we were just told right-click
right tree would automatically grow
automatically get moved and and stuff
and then when it's gone we automatically
plant another one that's we're holding
right click that's going to get annoying
but yeah this seems like the spot we
want the dirt to do that
honestly I don't really know what I'm
doing here we're going to try to figure
it out as we go once again today I've
never built a tree farm like this before
so yeah it's a little out of my
experienced range but we're going to try
and make it work with the five single
tree type so no dark oak because that's
a double 2x2 but I think we can do the
other five maybe not acacia because they
grow kind of funny but we'll see we'll
see I guess the first thing we got to
figure out though is how tall do we
actually want these trees to grow
because you can stop trees from growing
certain height by how how tall your
ceiling is let's see what this does
this is gonna be the biggest trouble
tree right here acacia likes to give
people trouble oh look at that that is
terrible yeah ideally we want it to grow
straight up like a proper tree but I
don't know if that's going to happen I
do know quite a bit about tree rules
like how they can and can't grow but we
will have to figure out a few things
here this one grew all over the place
what happens if we block it if we force
it to stay a certain size or in a
certain area actually I think you can
just do it with one column right so is
this going to grow now
mmm doesn't seem to like that very much
oh no no no yeah I won't grow at all now
okay so we just learnt a new tree rule
what about if we space it one block away
one block away and let's see what
happens now
alright there's going to be a lot of
this trial and error to figure out the
ideal okay that was not bad it did still
branch though maybe let's do that all
around now let's put some blocks there
so four blocks tall all around one block
away from it's still grew crooked come
on trees okay so check this out
something weird has happened now I built
this up even taller it was four blocks
tall before now it's six blocks tall so
basically goes all the way up now right
it was able to grow before when it was
four blocks tall but not now that it's
six even though it still has the same
3x3 footprint do you know why it's not
growing now I think it's because it
requires like a five by five area for
the foliage for the leaves you know and
we took that away let's see if it'll
grow at five I don't think it's going to
grow at five so I think it wants maybe
that's two blocks from the ceiling I
think it needs three three blocks tall
and a five by five so now it might grow
again now that it's four by four again
or four tall yeah there we go that's
like the minimum so it needs a three
block tall spacing for the foilage by
the looks of it okay let's do another
test so we have 1 2 3 4 5 6 tall
blockers here and 3 blocks of free space
above that for the leaves and it's a 5
by 5 area so if my theory is correct it
should be able to grow
in this area let's try it again but uh
but it's still corrected Oh No
yeah I don't know if we're going to be
able to grow these acacia ones okay so
I've been doing a bunch of testing here
I'm trying to find the ideal height and
like setup for this so I got 5 tall
blockers now and three block space above
that which seems pretty good see if you
make it too tall then the oak trees
start branching I think we're safe at
this height with them far as I can tell
oh if you go too short though you have a
problem where the bonemeal doesn't want
to work and you waste a lot of bone meal
and also you don't get very much per
harvest which is not not a good thing
either
yeah this bone eels struggling a little
bit but it's not too bad
1 2 3 4 5 6 6 tall again this seems to
work with the jungle trees with the
birch trees the oak trees I was having a
little trouble with the spruce ones and
I've decided we're not doing acacia this
is going to be too much hassle from what
I can tell I can't stop it from
branching I can't figure out how to if
there even is a way there probably isn't
alright yeah that's $6 see the birch
tree grew beautifully there spruce tree
though I don't know maybe I was just
getting unlucky but I can't get it to do
its thing yeah Bert the spruce tree tis
not like that maybe we'll try expand the
top here or not maybe not maybe it still
doesn't like that mmm okay I got to
figure it out here and we have a very
interesting design choice to make with
our tree farm here so out of the six
different types of trees oak trees will
grow in a one by one it's the only one
that does it and it's amazing like if we
wanted to do oh it branched ohh
that would be fine though I think if we
want the ultimate simplistic tree farm
oak trees are the way to go is all we
would need to do is like put a regular
Pistons over there push it aside and
that's it no double extend there is no
triple extenders or anything crazy like
that to move the wood out of the out of
the way light doesn't get any better
than that
but it's only oak wood if we want to go
up a step to a three by three footprints
then we can grow acacia jungle and birch
all right
Taoiseach though they do that branching
thing so we would don't actually want to
grow them so that has other problems but
if we want to grow spruce trees we need
a five by five footprint and that
complicates things a lot so I'm still
thinking what do we want to do here like
that's why the spruce wasn't growing it
needs a five by five we only had a three
by three when we were testing it
previously actually I just had an idea
let's do one or two more tests here see
if I understand my tree rules like I
think I do let's let's grow this yeah
okay so if I understand this right like
we're blocking the trees from growing
using these stone blocks I'm pretty sure
wood and leaves get ignored though so if
if I'm not mistaken we can still grow
another tree here even though it's being
blocked by this wood and the leaves
above still check yeah so that grew no
problem
so maybe maybe let's grab our pistons
all right so I'll tell you what my idea
is sticky ones regular ones if we just
do oak trees like this the very simple
way to do it is just to have regular
Pistons that push the wood aside right
push it this way that's all you got to
do if we want to upgrade to handle both
the jungle and the birch trees though
the three by three footprints then we
need double extenders and all that kind
of stuff which makes things a lot more
messy
and less and less we can do a trick
which I'm hoping we can what if we just
use wood blocks for our building so if
we go sticky pistons with wood over here
it might still be able to grow and then
we can still push the the wood aside
with a single single piston you know we
don't need double extenders we'll give
it a try okay so that means all this has
to go away now if we plant a jungle tree
here if it ignores this wood it should
grow oh this has to go to make sure we
do it right it's going to grow grow oh
come on it's not growing oh it did grow
it grew yes
Oh baby okay we might be able to Oh the
gastrous sauce for sight it's fine it's
fine
yeah we might be able to simplify this
quite a bit then because basically
that's going to push that tree over and
then when it retracts its back into
position it's going or the wood on the
right and the left here this will be
wood as well I think we're good with
that
so we might still upgrade this to handle
spruce trees as well with the five by
five footprints we would have to switch
this over to double extenders but we we
wouldn't need triple extenders like I
thought originally so that's quite the
improvement but let's see if we can get
this working first it's coming along
here I think maybe what we'll try next
is figure out how to detect when the
tree grows so let's just make sure that
still is a thing in the game oh sure to
plant it that first
all right so Oh what oh because it I'm
an idiot yeah okay now we place now we
place this okay now when this grows
let's see if that piston extends it does
good
so can detect when trees grow let's see
if we have a repeater or comparator
facing this way and that is powered can
we detect that below this dirt block I
wonder let's put a put let's put a
piston here let's try this out I'm not
sure if the sash you're going to work
yeah okay no all right I didn't think so
it is powered though but we would need
to we would need to like constantly
update it to check if the tree actually
grew and then it would react
you know honestly this seems like a dumb
idea to me at first but it's actually
pretty good because we're constantly
spamming this bonemeal thing anyways
amazed we'll take advantage of that so
we don't actually want to send a
redstone signal to this we just want it
to update so it can tell when it's but
powered so if we have a repeater or even
redstone running sideways not into the
piston just beside it it will check if
there's a piece of wood there or not
because we're very limited on space with
this we can't just put like redstone on
this other side because we have the
dropper here and there's going to be
wood here and wood here we need power
here we need like five sides this is one
way of sneaking it in and if it's gone
should retracts yeah I just sucked up a
little mechanism here now so basically
when that piston extends it pushes a
redstone block now which goes to a
monostable circuits shortens lengths to
the pulse to two ticks
very important to set the Sun to goes up
to all the Pistons here that push the
tree out of the way and since it only
works when it's a full block that
transmits redstone
this does not cause it to happen when
you place the sapling it's only when
actually grows automatically pushes it
away and retracts the other other thing
so it's very nice
really happy with that yeah then just
double check in here that might series
correct it does keep going it's really
important so we're going to want to hook
this up to our leaf crusher as well so
we get saplings back that way we don't
run out okay so here's the deal guys
I know what you're thinking right now
you're like oh man II so he's got to
figure it out he knows what he's doing
it's home stretch right now right this
is a tree so we know and love but no we
got a couple problems to figure out here
and I really have no clue because it's
something I've never dealt with in all
my time working with pistons and and
that kind of stuff we got to convert
from this wall of tree stuff into a
single line now and we also kind of want
to have a buffer which I'll explain so
basically we need to convert from that
wall to a line how do we do that it's
easy to go from a line to a wall and
then to a tube but to go in reverse I
have no clue I have no clue and if we
don't move the wood out of the way we
can't grow another tree so yeah I'm
gonna have to just goof around with this
for a bit I'm not sure well I guess one
thing is clear to me with this now we
can't use smart pistons like we have
here because what will happen if the
ghast hasn't removed the wood here and
it tries to push another piece of wood
there when there's no space for it you
know the block goes here can't it can't
push it there because it's blocked this
will never ever move again if we use a
smart distance so we have to use a clock
instead but if there's a block here make
a clock run
well I ended up making a pretty weird
little piston contraption here but it
should do the trick
one of the most important things about
it is I wanted to have a furnace or
obsidian or something that doesn't get
moved by the piston over there that if
it did it would wreck the redstone and
you know it'd make a big line of logs
over here that we don't want that kind
of thing so to make it work since we
don't really have enough sides to do it
I went above so if there's a block above
this redstone torch it powers this
piston makes this come out which unlocks
this clock allows it to run which makes
this piston extend alright it's a little
bit weird so right now there is a piston
or a block in front of this piston you
can see this clock is running so it's
waiting for its opportunity to extend
right now so if the gas blows up one of
these blocks it'll automatically fill in
that space and now this is ready to go
it stops running the clock until another
block goes into place and I think that's
the way to do it still haven't figured
out this wall issue though all right so
I thought about it for a little bit here
I've came up with a method I don't know
if this is exactly a great method
there's probably something even more
clever that could be done but I call it
the sandwich machine this is what it
does so basically we got a double
extender on the top one on the bottom
and then the sideways one to push it
sideways because we're dealing with
exactly five blocks of wood here or less
this should work out pretty good um
let's try it out so put this here put
this here put this here do
oh wait yeah that's right we're gonna
have to move all this stuff down one
block though everything we built over
here ah lame I hate when that happens
down and I think in one this is where
the new dirt block should go it was over
it was over here before so we got to
move down and and to the right here
otherwise I don't think we're going to
be able to reach it from this pressure
plate like where we have to stand yeah
so that's the new plan yeah let's try
this out though okay so this is going to
be hat this is going to have to be
activated five times before we're ready
for the next three is the thing but as
you can see seems to do the trick all
right the good thing about it is we do
have furnace protection so that the wood
isn't going to move any further this
direction this these furnaces stop it
from being pushed the downside is we
have no way of detecting when it's done
like when it's in the state where
there's no more wood left in in the
sandwich machine when we're ready for
the next tree so I don't really know how
to handle that just yet either oh yeah I
should probably show you the Redstone
for this too just in case some of you
guys are trying to copy this tree farm
for some reason you might have a little
trouble on this so this is a sticky
piston regular piston we've got to tick
delay down here going to the bottom one
goes up we got one ticker over there and
it goes up here we activate the power
from down down below here this is the
button we pressed okay so it goes across
and that's a one tick the leg goes up
and then down to the sideways one with a
4 tick delay and up to the top there
this will stack up real quick I think
this is on one yeah it just climbs up
here one tick delay to the top piston
and I got furnaces on the top and bottom
here so these don't move either aha
alright so I moved everything guys and
rebuilt it all that that sucked but I
got it done I kept like rebuilding it
incorrectly and then I had to redo it
and redo it and oh my goodness I did
ended up tearing everything down like I
tried to like just shift everything over
and somehow I messed up so I just tore
it all down redid it and I think you
know we got the heart of this thing done
right only thing that's missing is the
the leaf cutter the leaf chopper thing
that crushes the leaves so we get
saplings and we need some way of
delivering one sapling to us every time
we grow a tree so that we don't run out
when we're afk probably just need a
dropper to do that honestly pretty
simple thing that the leaf crusher is
going to be the toughest thing to do on
this yet and I'm happy with this like
like this for what its gonna do it
really doesn't take up a lot of space
right I think that's pretty cool but
talk is cheap let's try it out see if it
actually works
oh yeah and I connected this clock we're
going to try this I connected this clock
thing to this sandwich maker all right
with a little bit of a delay so every
time this tries to advance a block
forward it's going to try to move that
one forward as well and it's it's like
vacuuming the the tree towards the gas
shooter thinger anyways I connected this
repeater to the pressure plate we stand
on and also oh that's not going to work
darn this redstone is facing the wrong
way let's take this out then put that in
there okay that opens the trapdoor off
this way then it goes to this to our
bone meal dispenser and the detector
thing down there yeah let's try it let's
just try it we'll see what happens grab
some saplings let's go for oak trees the
good old oak first off here okay
hey we're safe I hope and can we reach
we can reach oh no we got leaves in our
face uh-oh
that might be a problem well I could
just put like a sign or something that
would block it yeah cuz if that happens
then we can't replay kind of an issue so
where's it at right now has it reached
the thing here not yet okay oh we have
branch branches are bad I plant one more
see what happens it's still good
actually uh yeah it's gonna jam I don't
actually have a way of making this go oh
oh I guess fire is still an issue need
more trapdoors so I think that failed
because I forgot to connect the tree
growth detector thingamajig over here to
the sandwich maker part of this they
kick off the chain reaction I think that
has to happen so we have to connect it
to over here somewhere so I'm going to
run a wire between the two yeah perfect
Rapids if we delay this Oh
is that good that might be bad I'm not
sure if that's a good or bad it might
have locked my whole thing yeah well
here's the here's the test if we take
one of these out okay it did retract
everything retracted right oh we still
have a block here though okay let's go
again here guys I just tried one tree
and it worked in it it was amazing
let's see if we can keep it going so we
have eight logs in there right now I put
a trapdoor there I really want to put a
trapdoor here so it stops the leaves
from spawning in our face but it gets
triggered by this pressure plate I don't
know if I like that let's try it without
it right now okay let's do the thing
here okay here's our big moments steel
tree look we'll just do one tree nothing
crazy
yeah it still grew in our face can't see
anything but you see that is activating
and get activated all the way like we
want let's try it again yep see ya it is
gone it is going oh man okay we just
gotta get these leaves out of our face
that's the only flaw at the moment it's
not jamming I'm amazed I did not think
it was going to work the first tried it
didn't work the first try but like I
thought it was gonna take a lot more
fiddling around with this 23 alright how
do we stop delete these leaves guys
they're so annoying um I try to assign
the thing is the sign really gets in our
face as well like if we put one there
nah we have to have like a sideways
thing so even if the trap door opens
sideways like this I think it's fine
probably want to go in the other way
though so we can we and look over that
direction at stop the leaves from going
in our face
but we still have the spotting in our
path here
I wonder if oh we got to be careful it
might not keep up as well
if that happens another tree will grow
might not be fast enough at the moment
or we have to add some way of making it
wait because we're going to be afk we
can't like choose one can place the
sapling here oh oh oh no alright alright
so we we got it kind of working kind of
works needs some work yet though well
anyways guys we're gonna have to call
the episode here for today cuz we're
kind of running running long and I'm
supposed to be sleeping I was hoping to
get that working a bit better today but
you know honestly we did pretty good
with it I'm happy with that sorry for
only working on the one project - by the
way I know a lot of you guys prefer when
I I do more than one thing but I was
having fun with it and you know we got a
lot to do on it now that's closer to
done though we might be able to uh split
split up the work on it a bit more
anyways here is the comment for today it
says etho there's a problem with the
Nexus item filters you were on the right
track with your wooden mock-up but it's
the item next to the one that gets too
filled up that messes up that is rolls
off the tongue doesn't it because the
redstone is next to each other a too
strong signal will jump over to the
items item filters next to it and
activate them empting the filler blocks
you have placed there right so we set
this up last time I thought the item
filters were okay but it's I kind of had
a brain fart about it it is the ones
next to it that was the issue thankfully
you guys told me
there's a lot of comments on it impulse
he even showed me a video he he made on
the matter about a year ago um and I
took his design here and basically all I
had to do there was a block here I took
that out now the redstone runs three
blocks instead of just two
um and now it holds 41 items in here
instead of I think was 18 before if this
fills up to 64 it it will not send the
signal for blocks which is the key to
this so no matter how full we fill it
it's never going to mess up the fill the
item filter next to it I'm tired I'm
sorry I'm just like scrambling for words
here it's perfect now basically there's
no way of messing it up no matter what
items we throw into the Nexus if we
overfill the chest it's not going to
mess up and also today I added in an
overflow thing here it looks really
nasty at the moment but yeah if
something can't get filtered into the
system it will end up in that chest so
those will eventually end up here after
they make their way through the whole
thing because there's no spot for them
and also I did a little bit of building
inside there nothing too crazy just
finished up the look in a few places
apparently like the second half of this
this tunnel wasn't done for some reason
I thought it was all done but it wasn't
I'm rambling thank you for watching guys
hope you enjoyed today's episode if you
have any feedback please leave it for me
and I'll see you again in the next one
take care have a good day bye bye
you