hello everybody this is etho and once
again we are in this nether fortress so
after last episode I got a lot of
comments saying that wither skeletons
would be able to spawn in this older
fortress so I came back here ran around
it for a long time looking for him
didn't find any then I started tearing
down the walls in between the corridors
and increasing the spawn area also
making it easier to see if they spawn
and after a long long time I saw
hundreds of these guys spawn the zombie
pigmen and I even saw some magma cubes
spawn in here but no wither skeletons
and no blazes none so I went back to the
fortress we found last time the newly
generated one in the snapshot and
nothing to be found there either so did
some more research a lot of people
linked me to a video by I think cobble
is his name which I'll put in the
description hopefully I remember and he
basically I think he made like a mod for
the game that shows what spawns in the
nether depending on where he's standing
and when he newly generates a fortress
blazes and wither skeletons can spawn
but once he unloads it like if he leaves
the game and comes back it's like the
extra data for the fortress doesn't save
like the bounding box information and
that doesn't save so the fortress
becomes kind of dead for spawning blaze
and wither skeletons so that is a big
bug and until it's fixed there's not
really any good way of getting the
wither skulls and I would recommend you
don't
go exploring in the nether too far just
in case if when they do fix it they
don't fix or they don't some aren't able
to fix the fortresses you've already
found they might be able to but just in
case they don't you might not want to go
too far because there's a chance I
wrecked that fortress I found last time
something else I found wallet in the
nether here for a long time
mob counts have changed quite a bit I
don't know when that happened but if you
look up here at the e the first number
is how many your are within view in the
direction you're facing the second
number is total and that is down to
about 41 it stays around the 40s
sometimes even in the 30s in the in the
other world the real world the mob count
is 79 it can go over that but 79 sort of
where it's they stop spawning and in
here it seems to be about half that so I
don't know when that change but mob
count is much lower in the nether than
it used to be oh and just to clarify I
should have said this but the the e up
there isn't just for mobs it's it's
total entities so mobs count as entity
so do a lot of other things like like
these if I throw one of these it goes up
by one every time but in my nether I'm
going to gonna do this just to show you
mine either I don't really have any
entities it's to two entities total if
mobs are off so they're on it goes up to
about 40 or so that's that's about what
the mob count is I would say okay
everybody we are at the stronghold right
now and I want to spend some time on
these projects today because they've
been sort of neglected lately and
they're not getting done this silverfish
farm it still works really really well
does exactly what I want it to my
problem is though I have it off most
time because it's been full keeps
filling up and I have no real proper way
of dealing with the guys yet which I
really should because I've had this
thing built for so long like we've tried
we've tried things we've built the
ternal over here to get them to the
surface and then we can move them where
we want but as you've seen there's
problems with that they attack me like
crazy and on the way I lose them
whenever I have to cross water or they
run into cactus or if I go uphill and
stuff is when I lose a lot of guys so
I've concluded that moving them on the
surface is not going to work the longer
or the further I move them on the
surface some more I lose and by the time
I get to my destination they're usually
all gone so my new plan is to set up
tunnels wherever I want to take them
underground on flat land like this and
I'm digging this at y12 so on the way I
get lots of redstone and other goodies
I've started lining this with soil at
the bottom I just because it's it's a
cheap resource and it doesn't burn
because I'm passing really close to lava
so I can't really use wood or leaves or
anything so I may um ooh kind of lost my
voice there I may do the whole tunnel
soil all around or at the very least I
need to go up to here because if they
jump they can get into these blocks
still and I don't want them chewing up
my tunnel after I've built it
ooh this is a belt where I left off so
I'm taking them to that desert
which is quite ways so I'm going to keep
working at this and I may plant grass in
the soil to make it look better if I had
mycelium I would probably use that
instead but I don't still haven't found
a mushroom biome actually you know what
it just occurred to me what I should
really be using is these or some other
type of slab because I don't want slime
spawning in that tunnel I'll lower my
mob rates if I if they are and I really
won't be able to control that unless I
use these ah too little too late now I
gotta rip this all out but yeah and the
nice thing is there they're bright
they're white yeah that'll be much
better in fact I just I also thought of
this I might want to do something like
this to where I have stairs here for the
walls I do this and then that even
though it might not look the greatest
that will sort of widen this by an extra
block without having to do any more work
because I get half a block on this side
half a block on that side so bad yet is
bad and get the lighting glitch mmm it
might be worth it though
yeah I think that's what I'm going to do
um how can I fix that again I'd have to
dig a lot more to fix that
yeah mm I think I'm going to keep the
lighting glitch in I finished taps
lapping up this tunnel and as uh as
getting rid the torches and it was all
dark in here and I thought hey you know
what maybe I should try something like
this have lighting go through the stairs
and just get the visual lighting the
ambience GD lighting like this that
could be pretty cool but maybe like I
tried to check our pattern here maybe we
should do something different though
like maybe just make it solid that would
be easier actually to kind of like that
maybe change that to see what it looks
like if the stairs are all all lit up
but this is really cheap for me because
I got lots of cobble and I don't mind
using it while dirt is a little bit more
rare for me and obviously I don't want
to use things like sand stone or
anything like that because this is a
pretty grunt project and even this is
probably more time than I should be
spending on it but yeah that could be
cool have that on both sides and maybe
some lighting in the top to the top
corners this is pretty wild too if I do
it like this whoo that's cool
quite a bit of extra work though and I
think to do it properly would make it
even more work if I can't just do it
like this
if I do it like this I think we'll get
slime spawning in here so to do it
properly I would either have to put
torches underneath like that and then
like half slabs
over here prevent the slimes from
spawning and then I could have torches
up higher oh no it doesn't work if the
torches underneath so I think the only
way to properly do it is either to have
torches all the way along I think that
will prevent slimes from spawning or
have lava at the bottom of this which
would be a bit of work hmm is pretty
cool I think what I'll do first is just
get it up and working with the lighting
glitch and then if people like liked it
like this I'll go through here spend a
little more time and just make it nice
like this - check it out man I found a
zombie with a shovel there's one with
gold armor there - I don't know if you
can get the items they have them now I
didn't get it I'm not sure if it's like
a rare drop or if you just can't get it
at all but from the guys I found with
stuff on or with special items I've
never gotten anything from him yet he's
pretty tough yeah nothing got my dog -
he hasn't whoa he doesn't have his a
collar on anymore I know you can dye
them but I guess by default they might
not have a collar anymore or something
I'm not sure got a bubble and it's
damaged huh weird
mm what if you know what let's try this
I got flour here we're going to give him
oh I guess we're going to give them a
yellow collar no maybe not
right click doesn't do it that doesn't
do it huh not really sure how to dye the
collar jump there you
ah I feel kind of like an idiot right
now I just realized really late into
this that I should just be using nether
portals to move them ah dang it why did
I think of that before I'm still not
used to all the new features and I like
just just about finished
holy smokes oh my goodness
go go go go oh man this is like some
crazy stuff that was awesome um guys
should really just be using nether
portals and then I can move them up and
down vertically really easy - so after
after we finish cool I'm just going to
finish pulling the cell since it's
already anyway
but after after I do this I'm going to
try set up another portal for them
and just see what happens when I tried
to get them through it so I will be
right back alright so we're just going
to do a rough test to this instead of
having the tunnel here we're going to
have them go straight into a portal
which we can't rip that which we can
control with this lever so that's open
they'll go right through here then we'll
put blocks behind it so they can't get
through I'm not sure if they can or not
if we go through I just want to see
where it'll take us it takes us to this
one so I'm going to make a second portal
in here and see if we can separate them
let's go figure out the coordinates and
stuff whoa
okay we're here well I tried making a
portal in the ceiling but I forgot that
won't work because I always get sent to
this one it's closer then then that one
because it's way up high so my second
portal or my silverfish portal is going
to go here right here I've got to figure
it out and I might have to use this as
my main portal for a while also or
forever perhaps even because it's tough
to have two portals together like this
if I go through here I'll probably get
sent back through the other one there
anyhow okay took us out here like we
want if we go through this so where is
it going to take us okay it sent us here
now let's try goes through the other
portal we have in the stronghold it's
about eight blocks way in the nether
portal stuff confuses me sometimes such
a nightmare working it out okay so if we
go through the portal up here let's just
see where this is going to take us
I built a new second portal down at Y 65
yeah it took us here that's okay
this is alright oh actually you know
what I'm going to do now for the
silverfish I'm going to have a one block
drop like this like a little catch or
cage for them see how that works out I'm
gonna get a ladder in here for me though
or something
I'll actually I'll just use ender pearls
for the test okay so how how's this
going to work
never transported mobs through the
nether before so let's head on up here
OOP
get some silverfish going actually I'm
just going to go inside the room I don't
want too many just want to try this out
eh that's probably enough snowmen are
gonna make them keep spawning though
okay come on
good let's put the blocks behind just in
case we need them now when I open this
they should go through should go through
do they only go one at a time oh yeah
that's gonna take a while
what the heck I don't know what's
happening here
ah dude what is going on single players
so buggy thinking about transport mobs
what is that was my impression how many
are left
there's still a ton left um oh nothing
is going right today are they coming
back they shouldn't be able to come back
I don't know what the heck what you guys
doing
do I need to use water or something whoa
um okay I'm going through if I chance I
want to see what happens
are there any here there's a few here
there's one here two here um
right so I think I have to use water
somehow to make this work properly man
that's weird so glitchy all right you
guys die now I shed bear I better kill
them a long ways away I'm gonna go to
creative mode and just fiddle with this
a bit yeah it definitely works a lot
better if you have water like even under
a heavy load they'll go through like
they're supposed to
I don't know what was going on before
it's like they were coming back or
something weird they do glitch really
strange but they do go one by one and if
we go through
there they are
they freeze for a bit for some reason I
don't know what that's about
46 and then there they go so the next
thing I got to figure out is how to get
them from the nether to the overworld
because we can't use water here so I'm
going to mess with that next I'm not
really sure what why mine didn't work it
seems to work here
glitchy but it works like I'm I'm in
survival right now they're not coming
through the other side like they did in
mind um still going one by one yet just
about all through and they're all
through I go through myself it seems to
be safe yep I made a little ketchup down
below so I don't know what the deal is
with my survival world or my LP world I
should say if this one works
mine should work too yeah this is weird
stuff I heard a bunch of silverfish and
I found them trapped in this block like
in where the redstone is there how they
got into that I have no idea I think
maybe what it is as I have to make the
opening to the portal too wide instead
of one wide that could be it and we move
on to round 2 so I'm just gonna try this
a few more times
Oh get out of here boy
just a few more guys this time I've made
it too wide and if this works we'll
we'll fix it up nicer yeah that might be
the problem
Oh nope no glitch in through they did it
what the heck man what why is it
different here this is the third and
final round I say that because I'm 90%
sure I got figured out this time yeah do
let's go guys let's go
don't knock me in thank you okay
silverfish it down and they go through
go through not to me what are you doing
stop stops nope what the heck
I had it I'm sure I had it I don't
understand it oh oh I meant they're
gonna kill me aren't they what are they
doing to me what is going on oh and I
never made a safe place umm right so I
thought the problem was is I had blocks
on the other side of the portal I
removed those and it still doesn't work
so I am really stumped I don't get it
why can't they go through they go
through in the other world
we were just in they don't go through in
this one for some reason ah silverfish
for our man nothing but trouble always
nothing goes my way look at them leave
them they're going into my blocks you're
gonna make a mess of things
I know they're in there mmm well it's a
bit frustrating I wanted to get a lot
done today and I just wasted a lot of my
time with these guys and it didn't even
work in the end so hopefully we can
figure out why for next time if you know
the answer please let me know in the
comments
but don't just don't just venture just
as I have lots of guesses - I want
actual answers why does this not work I
looked on the wiki I didn't see much
information on it so hopefully somebody
knows and if not I'll have to try figure
it out for myself
but it's really weird it's like that
it's like the portals just not
registering even if I go far away and
they're not angry at me anymore
they won't go through it just can't go
through for some reason we did have like
one or two go through which is a really
strange thing so I don't know what's the
dealio here's the comment I picked out
for today
hey etho I would just like to point out
that your mediafire world download link
is broken
dun dun
I would love to check out the world and
it's a shame that it doesn't work anyway
love the videos thank you very much I am
going to try put up another download in
the description a newer one I was
supposed to do that last episode but I
forgot so the download is actually from
just before I switched this snapshot um
so I hope you guys enjoy that mediafire
keeps removing it for some reason I
don't know why or when that's going to
happen again
but please please be patient with the
world downloads they are getting quite
big close to 100 Meg's so I don't do
them as often anymore but yeah I hope
you enjoy it and thank you for watching
today's episode I'll see you guys again
next time