hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode of our let's play series
get on land Oh today's gonna be a lot of
fun guys we're gonna be making a farm
for these guys you stay on the land you
are not going back in the water
note um oh ah you did it they always
seem to get back I don't I don't know I
can't keep them on the land
yeah today we are going to be making a
water Guardian farm and I'm starting to
set things up here we're going to have a
hey speakin right here let's get this
going to do to do because we got to do a
lot of digging today a lot of digging we
are going to be making a hole from that
pillar
that pillar that one over there and that
one everything within within there that
we're standing in right now we got to
dig out it's like a 57 by 57 square and
we got to dig it down to why 40 and
we're at why 63 at the moment so yes
it's quite a bit of digging to do I
don't have a real super duper plan for
the farm just yet I figure we will dig
the hole and and like flood it and stuff
and then we'll take it from there we'll
have to experiment a little bit I'm not
sure how I want to do the firm exactly
yet um mmm
these guys are so cool though
I think I want to make it so that I
didn't have the option of of not killing
them too though because I would love to
keep these guys as pets and move them
around the world a little bit too but
we'll see we'll see what we do so I got
a little camp here for storing some
blocks under they need a lot more chests
and enderchest
we got the sponge last time from the
elder Guardian I just want to see what
it does you have to dry it out in the
furnace and then you can place it again
and it'll soak up water I am in the
snapshot where stuff doesn't really
update what I'm recording did that not
do anything oh it did do something the
waters gone it did pick up a whole lot
of water though did it yeah I had a
feeling one sponge wasn't gonna be quite
enough we might go back to that water
temple today just to get some more
because otherwise I'm going to be
running back and forth to the furnace I
need to be able to spam drop them down I
think otherwise they have trouble
picking up the water give it time to
update hopefully the next snapshot comes
out soon so that I didn't actually
record what I'm doing um MOG the miner
just put out a screenshot actually of
him getting over a thousand frames per
second on whatever they've done with the
next snapshot which I'm very excited
about if that actually translates to oh
the working and I believe he was even
using the same graphics card I I use on
my computer so that might be good news
let me show you this as well there's a
lot of dark caves around here we're
gonna have to light these up I'm pretty
sure because these Guardian guys I'm
guessing take up a hostile mob spawning
space right which you can have like up
to I forget the exact number 79 or
something um not counting like extra
from back spawning and and whatnot so ya
might have to do do a bit of caving here
well and all of this is for making the
prismarine blocks let me show you we can
make a lamp right now I think we got
five of these these crystals are the
rare drop you don't get them too often
you get these shards a lot more but with
the crystals you can make the sea
lantern and with this can do that and I
think there's also dark prismarine and
maybe one other one I have to look at
the recipes I'm not too familiar with
them oh there's another one okay
I just guessed that that's the bricks
there is a dark one too I know for sure
which I believe uses the crystals which
I'm all out of so yeah pretty cool new
block types I really like that there's a
new type of light that's that's in a
block form not and not a torch I don't
like torches too much oh and by the way
I'm making a mycelium farm over here
from the mycelium we got at the mushroom
biome last episode I figured instead of
destroying that biome we would just grow
some here and since I'm here for a long
time we can probably grow a lot of it
and yeah I guess it's time I get to
digging I can't really do it on camera
it looks like because when I'm not
recording everything is fine the blocks
disappear like they should but when I am
recording we get this
which is a bit of an issue although it
is kind of cool so so weird isn't it but
yeah I'm going to do some digging
and I'll be back in a little bit maybe
I'll give you a little updates as we go
here so just got a little chunk out
right now and my shovel needs to be
repaired let's go do that I'm going to
go through a lot of tool repairs
probably so we should just have an anvil
here now that I think of it
ouch it's up to 17 levels getting more
and more expensive we just about got all
the dirt in the sand out now I put a
perimeter around the water that we need
to dig out as well so we will probably
have to go get some more sponges in just
a moment here and my tools are about to
break again and I have no experience
levels to repair them so yeah
mm yeah okay we're doing it guys we're
doing it our mission is to kill the
remaining two elder Guardians in the
temple here loot the sponge room and
then get home before dinner because we
got a lot of building to do today we
can't waste too much time here
all right so this first parts the rough
part getting inside the temple if we can
do that we're fine
oh I started right next to one of them
there's an entrance right there oh man
these guys hurt so bad
I got I got to use these pillars as
blockage unfortunately I still do not
have the depth Strider enchantment why
are things so dark am I missing
something
I didn't bring night vision no all right
we're not gonna be here long anyway and
there's there's some lamps we got to go
up here this is where I saw one of the
bosses I think on the second floor let's
get some blocks ready - oh-ho-ho gets me
every time maybe he was on the very top
floor because I don't see him here
those guys are zapping everything yeah
he's got to be up here oh there he is
right there
ouch ouch ouch ouch dead all right we
got him that's one down drop the sponge
very good I was hoping that the second
one was up here too I'm gonna have to
look around for my Jes cuz I don't see
him yeah okay let me do some exploring
off-camera here so that we can get out
of here pretty quick
oh man I finally found them I've been
yeah been wandering for at least six
minutes in this temple totally lost so
let's get a region water breathing
strength should be able to kill pretty
quick here and some blocks this thing is
such a maze it's crazy how easy it is to
get lost in here
this is a bad room oh man
it's like all empty down below here and
that's where he is and all his little
minions are just waiting for me
look at that me is hiding over there how
am I supposed to get to him without
these guys hurting me um okay I can't
block myself in or I'm I'm in trouble
here
oh oh I'm in trouble here wait a sec
yeah if I blocked myself totally in I
will not be able to get out of that that
block is there been a couple pillars
going it's pretty dark here I'm sorry
for that oh he's gonna zap me oh that
hurts oh now his minions found me going
in for the kill oh that knock that did
not help he is he's out of there now
and a let's let's hide and then enter
pearl again that were pretty good oh
right in his face and got him yes oh man
this is like the very basement of the of
the thing I think or I don't know
totally lost where are we in relation to
the structure I wonder anyway all three
of them are dead that means we can loot
the sponge room and maple just take a
little look around here - pretty sure
the sponge room was here yeah it's right
there can we steal one of these lights
now yeah all right we can have some
light up here as we steal the sponges
mining fatigue has worn off now that
those guys are dead oh oh it's trying to
cheat and see the layout of this place a
little bit it's it's really confusing is
there a special tool for sponges I
wonder is it I doubt it's a pick no it's
not the sword let's try the axe no
shovel nope it might be shears but there
might not be a special tool for it
yeah there's one more room here we
should try loot this is like the most
open room in the whole place it's a
giant tube in the middle of it
snap there's so many these guys in it
too
we're okay others they're coming they're
coming here I'm not trying to steal your
gold it is gold right oh it is gold yes
let's take the gold I don't really need
gold but it is the prize of the dungeon
right we got to take it and I've heard
rumors that if you take the gold then
the elder Guardians can respawn I either
want to prove or disprove that I don't I
don't have a clue personally I haven't
looked into it I kind of doubt it but we
will find out I guess Oh
as far as I know they can't respawn all
right very good everybody we got 36
sponge blocks now and three of those
came from the elder Guardians themselves
the other 33 are from the one sponge
room in the temple I'm pretty sure I
went through the whole things so I think
I only had one sponge room I believe you
can get random like the rooms in the
temple I believe a random so you might
be able to get more than one or you
might get zero I'm not sure how it
spawns exactly but we got one sponge
room and 36 bunches and if you were
wondering you can instant mine this type
of block with if you have a stew it's
pretty cool if you don't have hey stew
these let's see is it going to go away
not that we can see it anyway
let's just lay them down lay them out
see if it gives us trouble breaking them
yeah so it's definitely not instant mine
normally that's kind of cool
umm I'm guessing these have the same
breaking speed as stone let's put these
back where they belong
oh it's so weird oh yeah to make these
dark ones you need ink sacs I look I
looked it up you do ink sacs in the
middle prismarine around it get one each
oh that's expensive that is pretty
pricey and the crystals are only used
for making these lamps so far I think
it'd be really cool if sponges could be
bought from fish fishermen villagers I'm
not a big fan of blocks that you can't
get like that are not renewable so I
kind of hope they implement some way of
getting them
I don't different people have different
opinions on that though some people like
stuff to be rare but when it comes to
building blocks I'm not a big fan of it
personally all right we're gonna sponge
urn not sponge it's fab we're going to
spam these but you're supposed to start
from the top and work your way down with
the water
let's give it time yeah it's working I
think very good pink yeah I think we got
rid of a lot of water there actually
those ones at the bottom did not work
though because the top wasn't cleared
first let's try again so I'll be able to
go through here and get rid of the water
pretty quick hopefully otherwise I would
have to fill this all in and then and
then remove all the blocks and yeah it's
a big area of water to get rid of so I'm
glad we went to the temple today ah
let's see get back to the water now
suckers oh oh he might actually get
don't you get down there those guys man
they can move even on land they they're
all over the place uh-huh look at this a
lot of the wheat fields are grown right
now earlier today when I was here they
were all pretty much mowed down like
there was no
so I'm guessing since I've been working
in the area this area was loaded the
village and the farmer villagers the old
school ones must now actually pick up
the the wheat and the seeds and regrow
the crops because it was only the the
new villagers not the old ones like the
ones with the old trades but there's
nothing but the old farmer villagers
here so they are definitely the ones
doing it right pretty sure that's a
that's a new change I guess for a new
fix depending on how you looked at it
anyway let's go over to the digging site
pull those sponge blocks they they
helped a lot I wish I had more of them
they were very very handy that's a lot
of water to get rid of I didn't realize
this till later I was like trying to
figure out the best way of using them
but I think you should really section
off the water as you're removing it
otherwise you will you'll just have the
water refill all the time and you might
get a couple blocks here and there but
like a water of water source blocks but
it's a bit tricky so once I started
sectioning it off like this it made a
lot easier I think I should make the
area a little bit more narrow and have
like long strips for whatever water I'm
I'm trying to get rid of I think is the
best way of doing it and you can see
these guys are actually spawning outside
of our perimeter there's one over there
so they must spawn outside of the temple
region and not just in packs ponds so I
might want to extend this just a little
bit like like two to four blocks uh-huh
anyway I'm going to do some more digging
I'll be back in a little bit okay little
updates again I've been digging it I've
been digging and I've been digging and
man I thought it's like it's got to dig
a hole today flood it and
we can start adjusting it and making it
the way we want no this is a project oh
my goodness
this whole what we've done so far has
taken many hours already
and we're only at y55 so we go down 15
more blocks over half half the ways yet
although there's a lot of teams on the
ground which is actually good that'll
save a lot of time so I think we are
four more layers down now and it took a
long time they did not go quickly and I
got to thinking what kind of etho
episode would this be if we did not have
some TNT action this is like the biggest
hole I've dug it in my single-player
world here we we got to do at least some
TNT right so this is a 5x5 to high thing
of TNT hopefully this works well and
then we'll do one in each corner or in
each quarter please don't hit the beacon
please don't hit the beacon oh did that
hit the beach in that might hit the
beach in it ah what did it do please
show me what you did I think that hit
the beach in did it not
I really wish things would update I'm
gonna do f3a that's how you refresh your
graphics by the way which takes a while
sometimes that is a pretty small hole I
thought we would get something a little
more substantial the beacon looks fine
though at least oh I'll stay on the
ground at least that's good oh never
mind we look at this this is a good view
Oh deep spider spawner right there
unexplored there is a lot of dark caves
around here
oh man it's gonna take some time to
light up that one flew all right this
guy is not getting back to the water oh
man it's done the hole has been dug now
we have to actually build the thing
which I think we'll save for next
episode because this this has taken so
long um somebody said in the comments
last time that I shouldn't dig the hole
here and I should do it out in the water
and like a real water temple that I was
kind of cheating doing it this way that
it was it was easier no this is much
harder than just going to a water temple
because basically all I've done here is
I've dug a hole which has taken many
hours and now I have to fill it with
water and I could have just went to a
water temple and leveled the water
temple and I would have had the same
thing basically and I could've did that
in less than an hour so if you're making
one of these don't do it this way the
only reason I'm doing it this way is
because I want it close to my home base
the other life I want an actual water
temple I have to go like a couple
thousand blocks away from here which I
don't really like so that's the only
reason why I'm doing it like this and
while doing this I came up with some
plans for how we how we should actually
build the farm some pretty good ideas
maybe one more thing we'll do this
episode though is I'm going
to be putting a glass-bottom on the
whole thing invisible one as you would
expect so from what I observed they
spawn at y40 and up light up to the
surface of the water so they spawn at
this level they don't spawn at Y 39
which is where our heads at right now so
this will be the like everything above
here will be spawning space see I'm
going to place the glass floor next
episode will flood it and then we'll
start building the actual thing oh man
that was a lot of glass that was crazy
it's really hard to understand the scale
of this thing until you start actually
doing something oh we did get one
spawning there's a guy right there I was
trying to see that's what this water is
for is trying to see if anything would
spawn oh you got stuck underneath let's
go down sucker these is zipping around
down there that's awesome I
so with this farm this is what I figured
out to buy though it's like 54 stacks of
glass just to do one layer the bottom of
the farm here with this farm our goal is
not super efficiency I decided we are
going to try have fun with it to test
things out and and instead of trying to
kill the mobs as quickly as possible we
are going to try move the mobs to the
center of the farm instead of trying to
move the items that they drop to the
center of the farm and you'll see why
later
it's it's kind of so that I can move
them through portals and stuff and have
fun with them that way but we'll get
more into that next step next time so
here is our comment for today it says
etho you should replace the cows in your
wheat and Cal farm with mushrooms from
the mushroom island that is a really
good idea I think we will do that
actually because at at the tail farm I
have in the
man cave there's even the fence that
divides two sides so we could have
mushrooms on one in and normal cows on
the other that would be pretty cool he's
gone alright guys that's it for today I
hope you enjoyed the episode and we will
continue on this next time take care bye
bye