hello welcome back to everyone this is
etho and we're finally finally getting
around to making another episode here um
forgive me I apologize guys it's been
this episodes like two or three days
later than I would have liked and I so
sorry but here's the thing it's not
because I've been lazy about doing stuff
in my world here it's because I'll tell
you what's going on it's because I've
been obsessed absolutely obsessed with
completing Wilson I've been working on
Wilson's this in here by the way the
Tamagotchi Pet remake thing we're trying
to do here in Minecraft I've been
working on this for hours and hours and
it's like every time I come into my
world here it's like I just want to work
on a little bit more get a little more
done to show and hopefully you guys will
find it interesting when I finally get
to recording it because this project
like I know you guys really like the
idea and you want to see it up and
running but the actual building of it is
you know very slow redstone work
involved um actually you know what I'm
going to do while I talked here I'm
going to start it up so we can watch
what it does
I've been I've been working at it adding
lots I got lots of different complicated
components attitudes since last time I
show this and one of those the one we're
about to start up here is Wilson's heart
this handles all the updates and all the
crazy stuff you see back here this this
is what drives it all his heart once we
boot this up he's actually going to
start running so all I got to do is
connect this and we'll probably get
quite a bit of lag because it's running
faster than I wanted to when it's
actually when we actually enter beta
testing for Wilson when his first
official life begins
oh man this is the first time I stirred
it up let's go on outside first and just
see what it's doing yeah so I think what
we'll do this episode I'll give you guys
like a status report of where we're at
with this project and we'll go down the
back and see some of the wiring working
and then I'll get you involved with some
of the planning and and research for
some of the other components we got to
add to this yet
and then hopefully later we'll go do
something else too
something a little less time-consuming
and different so first of all actually
the goal the kind of goal or game behind
Wilson here is I want to try to keep
them a lot alive long enough for his age
up there to fill out all the way to the
end so all 15 lights turn on and if I do
that it I'll feel like I won the game
basically because Tamagotchi was like it
was considered like a game you want to
try to keep your pets alive and healthy
and that's that's what I want to do with
this - so the age let's go on up here
real quick I've showed this before you
know those variable things well he has
an age variable really where let's be
down below somewhere hopefully there's
no creepers okay so you saw that every
time the heart beats it sends a pulse to
this wire and that goes to this dropper
here and then it sends one item from
here into this and it this is basically
how old Wilson is right now he's 20 out
of 576 that's all this will hold and
he's running a lot faster than he will
when he's officially done because I just
I'm just testing it right now
if we take that number 576 and we if we
were to make his heart beat once every
minute or for him to update every minute
576 minutes divided by 60 that's like
nine point six hours it would take for
his age to get all the way up
and even that I think might be a little
too quick so we'll probably make that
move only every two or three minutes so
he'll live about 20 30 hours or so if we
can keep them alive that long so this as
as more and more items get added I'm
going to watch my popcorn here more and
more items get added to here they'll go
out further and further Oh or this
further and further these lights will
turn on alright that's how the ADA is
being handled at the moments health is
working pretty much entirely health this
top left one this is what determines
whether or not he dies if this goes all
the way down to zero he will die and his
heart will actually stop beating so then
we'll see what at what age he was when
he died and all that the health takes
into account his weights his happiness
and his hunger if all three of those are
good is his health will increase if
they're bad they'll go down if they're
average it'll just kind of stay the same
so we this is the main thing we got a
watch make sure it doesn't go down and
it changes very slowly to happiness I
have not really set up to work yet oh we
can actually I think the hunger has gone
down quite a bit since we started it up
I haven't really oh there goes he's
starving to death no so if he was at
this state right now he would be losing
lots of health every update in fact I
kind of thought it would have gone down
by now let's go check that out
all right I think I figured out why the
health wasn't going down it's because I
overfilled this there's only supposed to
be 200 items in something this quick
okay so that should be full health right
there and every update should happen any
second here we can probably see the
wires do crazy things if we look this is
empty
all right oh why is that pulsing Dayton
I got a lot of bug fixing and stuff so
we lost for health that update let's see
if it does it again this is not supposed
to be doing that that pissed in there
come on come on what I wonder it's mean
power from zip from above huh
so yeah you saw all the pulses in this
one is decreasing the health all the
pulses in this one is increasing it per
update and it bounces out to being a
loss of for every update at the moment
with the current health and weights and
happiness stats so if we left them like
this eventually he would die I think we
have to do something to improve is is
stat point so we can we can feed them
and that will that will help them out a
lot um
and feed them steak and then you gain
some health or some hunger quite a bit
we can also feed them cookies these give
them food and they also give them
happiness 6 points of happiness but they
also increase his weight a lot oh he's
looking better now as his happiness
increases his face changes wait it this
wait here this weights that it's like a
reflection of its hunger over time huh
if you overfeed him like if you give
them too much food at a time he'll gain
weight quicker if you if you don't feed
them like it'd be starving for long
periods of time his health or his weight
will slowly go down as well this changes
pretty slowly ideally you want it to be
at level 3 here but yeah the manage is
wait it's going to be pretty interesting
I think like every update it decreases
by a little bit like you just saw it go
down what by 1 there if he over eats
it increases quite a bit if he's
starving then it's really going to
decrease so there's there's a bit of a
control method to it poor poor Wilson
let's give him a cookie there you go his
weight went back up cool all right let
me try this again you can see the stats
have changed since my last time because
I keep messing up my recordings I don't
know why I'll try this again though I
just want to take you on a quick tour
through some of the new wiring stuff I'm
not going to explain it in too much
detail but just try to go through it
real quick this is the food detection
system you've seen that before this goes
to these hopper timers I replaced all
the repeaters we had here with these and
we can control how long this wire stays
on based on how many items we have in
this hopper so this one is for steak
when Wilson eats steak there's seven
items this one is for when he has
cookies I don't remember exactly how
many pulses that works out too but we
can try fake a feeding here this turns
on and this was pulsing as that was on
this adds food to his hunger um up here
it branches off a bunch of different
directions that's to is hunger variable
over there it also goes to this this is
what determines if he's over eaten or
not there's a small buffer here that
replenishes overtime so I think a steak
takes a weight around 20 or so cobbles
so if you give them two steaks in a row
he will gain the double weight penalty
for like four ten of those points or so
right I don't know something like that
this is the bladder system I showed this
in a video not too recently and sort of
explained it
I have to make some adjustments with it
it's not set up properly yet um leave us
alone
there's wiring going all over the place
around here every every component seems
to attach to two or three other things
so it's really hard to follow what
everything does the other really
important thing I've added though
there's a timer here to reduce his
health by six every update and then it
gets riad 'add based on his other stats
this is a thing I've added for
determining whether or not he's sick
if this redstone block is to the left
he's sick if it's the right he's not and
that is determined by his immune system
as crazy as it sounds up here so this is
a randomizer based on how healthy is he
as a is a lower chance of getting city
bees healthy and a higher one if he's
unhealthy on this is just a bunch of
hopper randomizers every updates it goes
to this one if that goes through it goes
to here and it will send a pulse into
those blocks if he's unhealthy we can
fake it let's take away some of his
health right so two of these Pistons
went out right now he's probably it to
health maybe OOP so hard to show you
guys stuff here the disaster yeah so
he's at two health right now now every
updates um
this receives a pulse the sing here and
if it happens to work out that the sword
goes into the hopper it will send the
signal all the way to here and all the
ones that have a block in front it will
send to these other randomizers and the
more of these that get activated a
higher chance he will get sick and that
goes to here and to this piston which
then sends this out as an RS nor latch
crazy all right let's see let's let's
force this will make them get sick my
force here again so one a nine chance of
this gain triggered come on no we are
just messing them up there we go so that
got triggered and I don't know if this
randomizer now so he didn't get sick
this time because out of these out of
these two hoppers the sword didn't go up
when it received a power pulse so it's
very rare that he's actually going to
get sick um if he does get sick though
this extends will just really forcefully
make them get sick now okay that makes
this piston go out as well this line of
wire here is what increases his health
so when he's sick it's not possible for
his health to to increase it will only
decrease until we cure him
so if he's sick he's going to die really
quick if we don't cure them and the way
we cure them is with a Golden Apple
which will you can see if if this wire
is powered it will make the piston
extend and that will go back to this
this place here so if we follow this
wire
it will connect to our food detection
system all the way over here at the
start you can do lots to this guy's
absolutely crazy amount of work this
thing here so this is where that wire
connects to this is this is what the
text if we gave a medicine or not so if
we if we give them an Apple that
redstone block will go back to the not
sick position let's do that I don't
think we can get there quick enough to
see it happen
oh that we missed it it happens pretty
quick so it's back into that spot so
he's not sick now that we cured him oh
no I just that's it for Wilson for today
I've been running around here getting
ready for our next project neglecting
him and when I came to check on him he's
he's gone he's dead he ran out of health
and that that was actually a pretty good
test cell because I can see he made it
to level five for his age before he died
that's with me neglecting him I think he
was at like age level two or three where
we were still here and kind of feeding
him and he wasn't totally suffering at
that point so if he's at good house and
we leave him alone it looks it looks
like he'll only make it like two bars on
his age before he dies so that's that's
about a good setting and if we go check
it out we can go see his heart stopped
doo-doo-doo-doo down here just real
quick I've spent longer on this today
then I wanted to already I had some
other things planned but we'll do it
another time but yes this is his heart
it's not moving basically what happens
is this it sends out a power signal to
this block and that prevents the hopper
timer from running anymore until this
becomes unpowered and that's just
connected to his health stat
but yeah let's move on let's move on
we're going to go on over to the new
village we're making the underground
village wait a second
feeling lost yeah down here down this
way I always I always forget which cave
I have to go to to get here so I saw
this post on reddit a little while ago
that I really liked now somebody made
like this medical station out of a
zombie spawner to create villagers like
it's it's like the villager purifier
thing I think we're going to build
another one over at our village here
just because there's a zombie spawner
pretty close to here and it would be a
lot more convenient than trying to
transport them from our other one
through the nether and all the way over
here so let's give that a shot I think
it'll be fun so the zombie spawner is
just down here it's about 50 blocks away
or so up these stairs all right here
alright so let's get it going here I
brought a bunch of sandstone I should
have brought some other stuff I think
maybe we didn't use dirt and yes I
figure what we'll do is we'll make a
layer level with the spawner nice 7x7 at
least let's go on up there actually the
idea behind the medical like purifier
thing I saw is instead of like spawning
zombies and then dropping them in water
and moving them and separating them
getting the villager zombies out from
the regular zombies I got the post I saw
you just spawn them into a one by one by
two high area and separate them that way
right from the spa
here so I think I'm going to try build a
sandstone I think so they'll spawn
within an 8x8 area of this zombie
spawner so that would be this would be
pretty close to the limit here let's do
it like this each of these slots here is
going to be where a zombie can spawn we
got to make sure we make it dark though
so that they'll actually spawn in that
spot and we'll try to keep the rest of
the area like over here light so they're
not spawning next to us or anything like
that
let's make maybe seven spots this is
within range yeah yeah okay yeah let's
do it like that
okay so we'll put a wall over here all
right cool
let's okay okay let's get back up there
I'm going to make a staircase here just
so I have a feeling I'm going to fall a
lot of times span this out a little bit
so the idea I have
let's put half slabs like this I want to
be able to see the zombies but still
make it dark so that they can spawn
within these one by one areas so we need
to block out all the lights we can if we
did that and then we had a cover over
top it would be dark enough within that
area here for them to spawn I think
even though it looks like light can pass
through from here to here it can't like
even if it torches right next to this I
think that's still a dark spot believe
we'll leave that and see if any zombies
spawn there what I want to do is put
lamps underneath each of these spots oh
look at that okay so he did spawn in
there even though it's bright outside
here no zombies will spawn outside but
they'll spawn within each of these
little compartments we're making just
good then what I want to do on top of
each of these lamps put a pressure plate
so that when they do spawn they will
turn the light on and place it yeah I
can turn the light on and also maybe
activate some redstone stuff here what I
would like when they spawn if we could
move this half slab up so that we could
see their their face because even if
this is missing they won't be able to
get out but we need it there before they
spawn to keep it dark so Pistons will go
up above then something like that okay I
think we're going to go with this setup
here what I want to do is hook up these
pressure plates to these Pistons now if
we can so let's
let's see how do we do this we will put
that's their something-something so they
can't get out what I want actually is to
let them out here so have Pistons down
below like that that will make these
slabs retract and that so that they can
just walk out when it when they're down
we will
although the back here a little bit just
to try this okay so where is that little
stone it's right there let's how I did
bring something good we're going to put
some of that down right stone so if
that's pressed down this will turn on
make that goes there to torch and
hopefully this won't interfere with
anything see do we need to invert it one
more time or is that good let's try that
out so if we do that
that's whoops and bring it all the way
up good cool so that made that go down
which will block the light from entering
and if they spawn here it'll go up and
we'll be able to see their face alright
so we still have the dark spot good nope
we got one that spawned sweet that's
that's working exactly like I want it to
okay well this seems to be working
pretty good so what we're doing is we're
trying to separate them and get a zombie
villager to spawn and one of these in
when they do then we give them the
weakness potions and the apples convert
them into real villagers they drop it
now they never drop it and when they're
dark like that it's really easy for them
to spawn so it seems to work pretty good
now the only thing is we want to make it
look a little bit better if we can
whoops whoops what did I just break yeah
let's try this again we'll put stairs at
the top here it might make things to
cost phobic we'll see I want to tight in
here that would cover up the Pistons
and then this would probably be slabs
hey we got a villager so what you do is
either the weakness potion on them and
give them an apple and that will give us
the villager then we got to move the
villager out through our tunnel here and
we should probably fix these lighting
errors yeah it's working guys very well
very nice
I want to polish it up some more yet but
let's do this I don't have enough
potions
I guess we'll lose that guy I've got a
blacksmith here from the one in the
middle one of these times I'm gonna get
chainmail trust me it's gonna happen
yeah that's pretty cool let's get on
with the comment reading for today and
we'll call it an end okay guys here's
the comment for today
hey etho I have a little suggestion I
don't want to sound mean but I think you
should upload once a day instead of
twice a day I've noticed that you upload
UHC and something else and then the next
day you don't upload anything and a lot
of people would like it better if you
upload once a day instead I hope you
take this into consideration so this
week I was really bad with that I would
like to have nothing one day and then
two episodes the next day instead of
spacing it out like one per day that's
sort of YouTube let 101 if you have
episodes spread them out as much as you
can so that's it's easier for people
watch them that way basically and you
get more views on your episodes if you
do it that way the problem is if I don't
have all my episodes done in in advance
usually
I'll record something and upload it the
next day like this this episode I'm
working on right now is going to be
uploaded overnight for the next day and
just the way it works out sometimes
sometimes you don't get an episode done
when you would like one too sometimes
you do collabs with other people and
they want to upload a certain time and
you kind of just go with that so I try
to spread it out but it's not always
that easy unless it's like all
pre-recorded and and done and ready to
be uploaded it's not always going to be
perfect anyway I'll try my best that's
it guys thanks for watching I'll see you
next time