[Music]
hello again
thanks for joining me i was doing some
caving and i found a dungeon here
spider dungeon so thought we would take
it on together
probably won't be that tough because
they just keep falling in lava
but maybe i will too
yep doing some tv trying to get some
more iron i'll probably work on the
enderman farm today
so got lots of stuff for that
there's no chest here no oh that's
that's my favorite part of a dungeon
besides making a mob system out of it i
like to get a chest though
or two
oh well yeah so just kind of a starter
project for today's episode i'm going to
work on the enderman farm
and hook up that second ring so that'll
add 128 spawning spaces which will
cost uh
128 irons so two stacks of that for the
pistons
and it will cost me six stacks of
redstone
and two stacks of those goes to the
pistons as well
so i'm gonna make two stacks of pistons
and then i'll need four stacks of
redstone for the torches
and uh yeah got a whole bunch of yellow
wool
black wool i farmed a bunch of black
wool and
i'm about to head off here so i will see
you there
this is where the black wool is coming
from by the way
i decided to break down and just make a
low-tech sheep farm until
just to withhold me until i can actually
get around to making a fully automatic
one that
works really well so
good way of getting blackwell quickly
i love how many people got scared last
time we came here from the end
falling whoa they're pretty loud when
they fall next to you
okay so i'm going to add a second ring
to this thing today
and there will be a one block air space
between the two rings
and yes they stole the watermelon
i might have to do something about that
it'll be annoying if it keeps happening
um the other thing a lot of people
commented on
is that these ender pearls and xp will
be useless here
because i can't get back no that's not
true all i have to do is kill
the dragon and then the portal will be
created and i can get back no problem
i just haven't done it yet uh i can
pretty much do it anytime i choose to so
it's not a big problem
okay so i'm gonna get started here and
i'll probably skip
building it because uh you've seen it
you know how it works finally finished
the second ring
took a lot longer than i thought it was
going to took me a good
i think like an hour and a half two
hours to do it
which is uh pretty surprising because i
had everything here i needed
and i knew how to build it i just had to
place the blocks but there's just so
many
blocks to place that it took that long
but it's done
pretty cool when you're up here you can
see them spawning in the back there the
lights will turn on
like there and they fall down i still
have to extend the platform below
because they're just falling into the
void these ones on the outer edge
uh it's actually more than 120 blocks
too
i forgot to count the air space that i
leave between the rings so it's
an extra what is it 4
4 8 16 128 plus 16
144. okay so
down we go
all right we're down below here and uh
getting lots of girls now
so many that inventory fold them i've
been watching this for a while
this is the from below view
slowly but surely they're stealing the
watermelon so i have to use something
else
i'll probably try maybe green wool or
something
they're just for looks really uh
but yeah there's a lot to see now
yep so i really want to kill the dragon
now just so i can get these uh
pearls out because they're awesome for
transportation
like i would just love to have
i plan on setting up like stations in my
world
every every like 100 blocks apart from
each
other that will have ender pearls in and
speed potions and food and everything so
that uh if i run out of pearls i can
just go up to one of the stations get
refilled and
take off again but uh
that'll be something for another day
i've been thinking
uh i'm gonna try raise the floor up
below
this first air space in the ring
so that they won't die and just see how
that works out how they fill up the
floor and stuff
some people have suggested i should make
the floor retractable
with pistons so i can control whether or
not it's an xp
farm or just a pearl
it's a good idea but it's going to cost
a lot so i'll do that
towards the end of this project
what's my volume at that's okay
all right so i'll try to raise the floor
and we'll see how they fill up the place
here
okay yeah it's pretty scary having them
wandering around for you like this uh
so that's one thing i might do i might
try to make the pistons push
the ground up like that another option
would be to do uh
fence gates in the rings like that
and i could probably easily just open
and close them all with redstone
be a lot cheaper than using pistons i
think
so i think i got no armor on right now
we'll see how this goes let's see if
they kill me
it's me just casually hunting them
yeah this is dangerous
so i'll have to think of something
better
i might set up like a tower like
in the middle or something just look at
them all have them teleport to me but
they won't be able to
uh hurt me and that way i won't have to
run around the place either
we'll see how that goes
here's like a side view of the thing
i'm gonna go over there get my stuff and
we'll try a tower approach to this
see how it goes uh it would probably be
a lot quicker if i just get them a row
at me
we'll see
okay so i should probably get rid of
this so they have nothing to stand on
and we will put ladders there i found
out something interesting about this too
if uh if you have ladders on them
like on a soil block they can take the
soil block and the ladder will pop off
so even if you have a block they can
take covered with something they can
still take
pick the block away okay
let's try this out
okay he can't get me up here this is
three blocks up
i wonder if there's a trick to make them
get mad at you because sometimes
oh okay you gotta look uh kind of the
crotch
i guess that's the that's the sweet spot
weird
yeah if you look at their head
they don't seem to get mad this is
really scary oh dang it
so if i do it that way i need a safety
on it too so that i can't fall down like
that
yeah it really starts to fill up down
here after a few minutes
the rates slow down though as they uh
populated at the bottom here
uh another idea we could try out
something
that always gets suggested to me when i
go to the end is the pumpkin approach
and now i can look look at them with no
problems
and we could probably casually hunt them
this way
yeah that works pretty good you can get
xp
this way uh if we have a looting sword
we could get tons of pearls
not that i think we would need them
these guys very rarely drop pearl so
even though there's tons on the ground
here
a whole lot more endermen have been
killed
yeah that works pretty good too that's
one idea
um something else i want to try is uh
with messing around with water
i hope i have some i only got one bucket
there
uh i'm gonna kill myself and grab
another one i guess
and we'll try something here
okay so this is what i've done with the
water i'm just curious
to see what happens when i get the mad
at me when i'm up here now
i don't know if the water will kill them
should be pretty close to them yeah as
soon as they touch it
they try to teleport away the last
interesting that's another idea of
something i could do
to get the pearls like all grouped
together in the center here instead of
uh
all over the place but then i would have
to get the mad at me
which i guess doesn't uh take too long
there's pearls cool
all right well i think we're done here
for today
and uh let's head back to
the real world which isn't really the
real world but the real world in
minecraft
and uh
do some other stuff i guess
all right we made it back here safe and
sound
all was good and i figured out
what i want to build today i got a big
project in mind
redstone project related to the timer i
talked about for
these guys although
i'm going to go really overboard with
this it's going to be a big timer
so it probably won't be for the team
spiders actually but
maybe for the blaze farm uh
we'll get into that in a sec the thing i
want to talk about
as well is the crash that happened to my
world
uh two days ago i got a lot of comments
people telling me what i should have
done
or or what caused it
and i'll i'll tell you what happened so
a lot of people thought when i threw the
splash potion that the entities being
created all the string and spider eyes
is what crashed it
because if you have 100 or 200 spiders
and you throw a splash potion that
all at once creates hundreds of new
entities which
really lags the game out but that's not
what uh
that's not what caused the crashed i
picked those up stopped recording
waited around a while for my frame rate
to go up
and it was everything was going good i
think my frame rate was up to about
10 or 15 and i decided i wanted to start
recording again so i could
capture the xp orbs going into my guy
because that
looks and sounds cool but the thing was
i had no game sounds for whatever reason
that happens to me
quite often in minecraft so i wanted to
restart my game to get the sounds
so you get the noise you know
when xp orbs going to you
but when i logged out and logged back
into my world that is what messed
it up that's what corrupted the world
so if you if you have a lot of entities
in your world don't log out and log
in because i think that's what it can't
handle that's what crashed it
okay uh some people suggested you know
just using mcedit to remove the entities
yeah i thought about that i figured it
would just be better to load the backup
i had because it wasn't that old and so
far this world
has not been touched by mcedit so i'd
like to keep it that way for
as long as possible even when uh
the jungle biomes come out i don't think
i'm going to cheat to get them
because that'll mess up the other biomes
and stuff too
uh also i did try logging in on peaceful
and
setting my my view distance to tiny and
all that
didn't help the world was corrupted so
yeah
that's the background so moving on our
project for today is the delay timer
that we talked about let's go up i'm
going to build a prototype of it because
we have a lot of things to figure out
for it we'll probably be working just
outside the cave
and i'll get set up set up here
all right so we got a nice work area
here just outside our
cave a nice flat spot let's get started
so the goal is to make a long
timer like many minutes maybe maybe like
an hour so it'd probably be good
and the idea is after that hour goes by
it'll shut off the cave spider spawner
or any uh
any mob system i have i want to be able
to
control how long it's on for if in case
i go
afk near it i don't want them to keep
spawning
to the point where it might crash my
game or
you know it just gets annoying when it's
the game slows down you
pretty much can't even kill them it gets
so leggy sometimes so
that's what we're trying to create here
something to prevent that
and i'm guessing a lot of you had this
idea this is the first thing that came
to my mind because i
i've messed with this before in the past
just use dispensers for the timer
and have them shoot out a junk cut a
junk item like spider eyes
i have lots and lots of spider eyes to
throw away
and the idea is you would have like a
button
over here this is what you would press
to start the timer
cause the spencer to shoot out an item
onto a pressure plate and maybe i think
it'll work if we do it like this if we
have
torch over here right below the
dispenser you got to be careful with
dispensers they have an annoying thing
where if they're being powered pretty
much any
redstone update next to them will cause
them to
shoot out items
like when i destroyed that shot on item
so
if you place it right next to it it
shoots on an item so you just got to be
careful that when dealing with them
but i think this method works if the
torch is down low like this
it's out of range yeah so you'd have a
a chain of dispensers like this maybe
we'll do
we'll do four so just to visualize it
something like this we're at three
yeah i better go to sleep here it's mobs
are gonna start spawning
so we have a row of dispensers like that
everyone will add five minutes because
it'll shoot on an item
items despawn in five minutes and the
idea is when it despawns
like if this one shoots an item onto the
pressure plate
after five minutes uh
this torch will turn on which will power
this dispenser will cause it to shoot
here
after five minutes this one shoots and
five minutes more
and when it gets the end that's what
will
cause the cave spider spawners to
shut off or whatever so let's place
torches
and yeah we'll end it here
okay and maybe we'll use glass on the
sides just so we can see
items
okay so i just went ahead and finished
it here so
our prototype is a 20 minute timer
because we have four dispensers
each one is five minutes or so slightly
longer
because it there's also the time it
takes the item to shoot out and
land on the pressure plate and the
pressure plate to activate and
deactivate and all that stuff so it's
just slightly longer than five minutes
keep that in mind if you're trying to
use make a clock or something accurate
it's
just a little bit longer than five
minutes uh this is a very good way of
making a timer very compact very
efficient
i like it some people don't like doing
it this way because you have to refill
the dispensers
but i just figured it out on the
calculator
it will last for about 48 hours of
constant use so
before you have to refill them so it's
pretty
pretty good i wouldn't complain about
that
uh yeah so let's do a dry run of it here
so i have a lever hooked up to the cave
spider system i would replace that
probably with a button like i have here
and ideas when you would hit it it would
activate the first dispenser
items falls down lands on the pressure
plate
turns the torch off now after five
minutes when it despawns
the torch will come back on and the next
one gets activated
and down the chain it goes until it gets
the last one
and that now all the torches are on so
that is what we want the thing is
we wouldn't just simply hook the wire up
to
our lighting system from from this last
torch
you could do that it doesn't really work
though
actually no that wouldn't work at all uh
you could try run a wire
between them all and then hook that up
the lighting system but the thing is
this is going to be powered the whole
time
so even if one of these turns off it's
still
being powered so what we actually need
to do is invert
all these torches
so i think the easiest way of doing that
would probably just be
putting a torch here
oh that one's active that's why it's on
something like that
that will invert all the torches and
then
you could set up like a a wire line all
along
here
uh right now there's no items on on the
pressure plates
there so this wire is off right now if
at any time
there is this timer is running this
wire will turn on now so
first one on stays on
oh accidentally grab that
thing is it will flicker though so i
might have to add something else to this
to prevent that
uh not that it's a huge issue just might
be
annoying to hear the pistons switch and
then switch back really quick
okay now let's say it's at this point i
come back to my computer i decide to
kill all the spiders
will the timer work again like can we
get it to run again while this is
already running and yes we can
if we press the button again even though
we already have an item further down the
line
we can restart it and it will last the
20 minutes again
so it's a pretty good way of doing a
timer
and that's what i'm going to hook up for
the spiders
i might play around with trying to
prevent that flicker
between switches so i'll see if i can
figure something out
okay so i finally finally figured it out
here
um you know people some people think i'm
good at redstone
uh i got bad news for you guys it's not
really true
i struggle with even the simple things
sometimes
i i was messing around with an and gate
and a delay at first
and i realized that's not going to work
then i tried an rs nor latch
and a delay and that didn't work
and i was kind of shocked and worried
that that didn't work
and then i realized all you have to do
is have
have your long delay and have a just a
repeater here
and that will that will take care of any
flicker things
so because what happens is
uh it takes a while for the repeaters to
go off the long chain
so this wire stays powered for however
long that takes
and if you turn the power back on
it doesn't take long for it to go
through the short repeater
and then it will it will get ahead of
the
of the delay here so
let's just see it it's easier to realize
so
and that's that's it power stays on
constantly
so yeah like watch this wire here it
doesn't go off
but if you keep this off for
however long your delay is here
then it will go off
okay and you need to have like a
repeater or a torch or something here
something that prevents the power from
flowing back
because if you do this
like we don't need a delay at all but we
need to prevent the power from flowing
back so that's all that was there for
if you do this so you can't shut the
power off
because what's happening is
oh i don't know if i can explain this
this is constantly sending power out
from this repeater
like if you if you break this here this
one goes off first and then
this one then this one this one right
but the thing is if this one's not going
off when you shut the power off
it's sending power back to the beginning
here of
of the chain and it's just a constant
infinite loop where you
can't shut it off so that's why
repeaters sometimes do that where you
can't shut them off
even though you're not powering them
okay so this will work uh what we got to
do next is figure out exactly what kind
of delay we need for
our setup here so i'm going to sleep and
we'll
try to see what that is
oh i got some bad news guys very very
bad news very sad news
tragic terrible the
the amazing pick the incredible pick is
just about
gone just about but it had a good life
long life full of good times good
memories
i might keep it around just for just
so i can say i have one but no you can't
you can't repair enchanted tools so no
way to get the life back
uh oh well anyway
we got this set up i added glass on top
just so
this is consistent and correct
so all we have to do to figure out the
timing is just
see if that light turns off no
see if it turns on
okay let's try shorten our delay here
quite a bit just want to figure out how
many repeaters i need
it doesn't have to be an exact delay or
anything
okay i think it stayed off yeah
so we can shorten this a little bit more
we'll try that
let's restart it
and so yeah this is the simple timer
this is the
the basic one we're doing for the cave
spiders but for the
for the blaze farm i'm going to be
making something
different which we'll probably get into
maybe next episode
oh it flashed on okay so we need to
extend this a little bit
and we'll restart it yeah i
i got a pretty cool idea for the timer
it's going to be really over till though
totally unnecessary not still flashing
but a few months ago i made this block
swapper thing
that i thought was pretty cool i was
pretty proud of it but i never used it
for anything
so the other day i happened to see it in
my creative world
and got the idea of making a timer out
of it
so that's what i'm going to do just so i
can use it in something
i think we got it here oh
maybe not yeah it's still flashed okay
so
that's about the delay we need 1 or 4
8 9 10.
so it's really nine but since this is
this is delayed one so that
we need ten okay so
three repeaters
good to know okay so
i think i will end the episode here i
hope you didn't mind a little redstone
uh this reminds me of like i think it
was
i think i can remember that the actual
episode
it was episode 17 when i was working on
the delay timer for that other mob
system
good times anyway
i'll see you guys next time thanks for
watching