[Music]
so you thought i was working on
something for you
you're watching
[Music]
i love it what do you think
creepy coming
this
i'm telling you guys you're gonna see b
double o on american idol one day
that guy's got a beautiful voice
anyway hello how's it going
uh i had a lot of fun last episode
building around here so i kind of
continued
afterwards and i've done a few more
things vines are growing
i kind of like how that looks so we
might do something
sort of like that when this is all done
make it
make the vines spread out wider
the tree i replaced the ground around it
with slow sand to kind of highlight it
make it look like the grass is dead
underneath
might keep it i'm not sure this bridge
here
i tried adding suspension cable
types well not cables but a ceiling
suspension system
does that make sense you know what i
mean something to hold the bridge up
from the ceiling
and i don't know if i'm going to keep it
or not i just wanted to show it before i
made my decision
see what you guys thought of it
this glowstone here though it lights up
the bridge very nicely
uh not that this bridge needs to be lit
up like
we won't have mobs spawning on it
because this is upside down half slabs
here
and this is fences so those are all
blocks that they can't spawn on so it
doesn't matter if it's dark but just for
visual looks
we want it lit up so
that works good if i do keep this
obviously the idea is we will have to do
more with the ceiling it's not just
going to be
this to a stone ceiling like this
we'll have to make it match in somehow
then over here i don't know if this was
here last time but
i added rails i
might move them out one more block yet
though
i think you would look a little bit
better if they were one block out
so but anyway
it seems to be going good then i started
a second bridge here
just because i really like this one so i
wanted another one
and uh i think it looks pretty good
uh right now it goes to nothing but we
will probably
be building us the storage room here
today and maybe a
furnace room it'll
i'm not quite sure what shape we're
going to go with but they'll probably be
the storage room and then to the left
like behind behind here is
maybe going to be the furnace room and i
would like to have a three by three
window here somewhere i know that for
sure
and this will probably have to be moved
back at least three or four blocks
um what else
what else this this bridge it goes over
top
there's a drop down here this is a
natural this was here naturally
i was thinking it would be cool if we
were to expand it
make it wider like move it out that way
at least five to ten blocks
and the sides a little bit too then put
a water pool at the bottom here
for a water drop and also
have a waterfall at the top there going
down to the pool of water
below and we could use that to get down
here
quickly and also have vines growing
around the sides i think that would look
pretty cool
so that's kind of what i'm thinking with
that
and what else these i have
leaves in with the glowing pumpkins
below that's to light up the grass here
and it does a good job
but i feel it looks a little bit
strange so i don't know if i'm going to
keep that i might just put glowstone
on the ground here and see if that looks
better
but uh i don't i tried having the leaves
too high and it looked
worse in my opinion so now they're one
high
and i don't know
don't know i was looking at some of my
older episodes
the other day apparently when i started
this game
it was in version 1.2.6
believe it or not and now we're in 1.2.5
so maybe in a few weeks or so we'll
actually
get to where i was when i started that
would be pretty exciting
if there's another version after 1.2.5
um like i mean not 1.3
anyway i also put or i continued the
half slab look there
and it connects with the bridge and
underneath that i now have half slabs as
well
and i just going to put them under there
but i might move it yet
so i haven't done it yet
and maybe behind the creeper face
we will sneak in a secret uh portal room
or something so that we could throw an
ender pearl
and get into our portal room but i want
it to be
a little ways away from here so we don't
have the portal noise constantly
but i think that would be pretty cool
and yeah so i think i'm going to get to
work here
and expanding this out and trying to
figure out a shape i like
and then i will be back in in a few
minutes
all right everybody i figured it was
time to do a little bit of an update
here
i got some space cleared out here not
much
and then i started playing around with
the different ways of laying out the
chests for the storage room
and i came up with this it's very you've
seen it before
i have three chests together stacked on
top of each other like that
last episode i said we need 18 double
chests
for this storage room to organize
everything nicely into them
and that would mean we would need six
columns like this
this is a really practical way of doing
it because the middle chest
is at your eye height so it's very easy
to
look down slightly to get to the bottom
one and
very easy to look up slightly for the
top one
and it's space space efficient too
however after looking at it for a little
while i realized it was um
really lame it's uh it would be a lame
way to do a storage room
so i started to think of other ways of
maybe making a
cooler and i got one so
the idea was now or the idea now is
to make it so when you walk into the
storage room uh the chests kind of pop
out at you they come alive
but the thing is you can't move them
with pistons
can't move chests with pistons so it's
kind of hard to do it
and if you were to sink these in one
more block and have
like shutters on the sides where the
chests are here
uh it works but they're so
deep in that it doesn't look very good
anymore
so came up with something else
the only problem is i can only have two
chests together so we're gonna need
9 columns it's a little less practical
but it's going to be
really cool i think i think you guys
will like it
and it's going to be a lot of wiring
it's going to take a lot of time to do
but it's going to be a real treat every
time we go into this storage room
it's going to have a cool effect to it
so
i am going to get working on that
um i'm going to have to clear out some
space i think i need a 10 by 10
room for the storage room now
and actually you know what we're gonna
do i think we're gonna have a path here
so we'll
maybe do that and then
like we have the other paths over there
where we have the wood
outline this way we'll go to the furnace
room
and then this way this will be gone
obviously
this way we'll go probably to
um up over there and connect with this
path up here
so up up up here somewhere probably
although we'll have to adjust the golden
door if we do that
so i think it'll be pretty good and then
in front here will be the storage room
the 10 by 10 room
so i'm gonna get to work on it gotta
clear out a bunch of space here
and i will be back
all right so i got that room cleared out
over here now
it's a square it's ten by ten
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten yep and
uh it's probably gonna take a while to
do this so i don't think we'll finish it
today but hopefully we can get it
set up at least and you'll just have to
imagine the redstone we'll probably have
to do the redstone another day
but i think we're just going to half
slab the floor
and we'll probably incorporate some
design in the floor but for now
uh for today we're just gonna do solid
wooden
half slabs on the on the floor and on
the sides
on the corners i think we want full
blocks
like that yeah
and then on the sides we'll do stairs
on all all four sides
there's gonna be a lot of planks in here
but we might adjust things up a little
bit once it's all done and get a
some some
i'm really stuttering today some
texture and stuff using different colors
of blocks
different types of half slabs and stuff
all right so i'm going to try to put my
world up for download again
for this episode so check the video
description if you want it hopefully i
remember to
and have time to but
that's the plan anyway it's been
close to 15 episodes since i last did
that so it would be good to
it's good to do it again i think
all right so that's the basic floor and
like i said we'll we'll have a pattern
or something i hope
and then there's gonna be chests all
along here
here and here
i think the way it's gonna go
something like this
yeah like that
and then over here we played uh
the next season of ultra hardcore
i think that's going to be coming out on
monday
and it's going to be awesome you guys
are going to like it i'm sure
i had a lot of fun doing it again
and what else is new i don't know
okay so in each of these is
where the chests are gonna go
and i'm not quite sure how we're going
to do the lighting i'm guessing ceiling
lighting maybe
or floor lighting i don't know we'll
just put that there for now
basically the way it's going to look is
like this
not like that
like that on all these
yeah looks a little strange right now
don't worry it gets better
um on the tops
actually we'll put that all along here
on the tops it's going to be like this
and half slabs like that
um probably another full block here
yeah yeah i think it's gonna be really
cool
okay and then again it continues over
here
maybe we'll just do these
see how the corner looks
and so basically behind each of these is
going to be the chess
and it's going to be piston controlled
okay
so let's get rid of these
there will be a piston
up here i guess it would have to go
right here i think
and that stairs will go like that
that'll come down and then one on the
ground here
will come up so we'll have
two more pistons down here
uh stairs like that that'll come up
that'll come down over here is where the
chests are going to be
i think we'll put lamps below here that
will control later
over here we will have to use
stairs so we can open the chest
so we'll do that
and then these sides we will do out of
the regular planks as well
and maybe for the back here we'll use
the dark wood i think that would look
good
i have to change this
yeah okay and with
these fences they're going to connect
um like that don't know if i'm going to
keep the leaves
for right now we are and there
they let up the place very well too
so even if we don't use leads we will
probably put lighting there
like in those spots so we'll keep it
like that
fences will go
along there and along here
and eventually connect to a wall
probably
um let's go get
well actually i should probably stop
recording here um
i'm gonna get the chests and do all the
sides here and we'll see how it looks
okay
all right there we go that's the basic
look behind the storage room here
but like i said we're going to try to
break up the the constant wood look with
some other type of blocks on the floor
and
probably the ceiling
do something fancy with the ceiling
hopefully might put some lighting in
there
now the next next part of this is to
have
lamps and we'll put those over
here and then
this is going to be the back wall and i
want to try
two different types of blocks here we'll
try the dark wood first
and get our chests down and see how this
looks
not bad
okay let's try the other type of block i
brought
the light wood
see if that looks better
you can't really see much of it because
the chests are in the way but
hmm
almost think i prefer the light wood
oh i did light wood again i meant to do
darkwood
to compare them it's getting late here
so we're going to have to call this
an end soon as you can probably tell
dark light dark light um
i think we'll go with light
not that it matters much
okay so
just go there and we'll see if we can
do this so that's
that's the idea behind it that's what it
looks like when it's closed
that's what it looks like when it's open
except the lamps aren't on we're going
to do something fancy with those yet
and this will all be triggered by
i think we'll use wooden pressure plates
here
and when we walk in these will trigger a
t flip flop
which will cause all of these to open
and then when we leave it'll trigger it
again and they will all close
and we're going to do it with a cool
timing hopefully so maybe
the one in the middle opens first and
then it expands to the left and right
each one with a longer delay
and let's see a really cool thing
about this is i think these stairs here
are gonna light up from
the lamps behind even though
it's completely shut off that the light
can visually leak through but it has no
effect on actual lighting but you can
see the light behind it
so we will probably keep this room
fairly dark to get that effect
so i doubt we'll have these torches here
when this is all said and done
i might have some lighting in the
ceiling though so it's not pitch black
in here
but we'll see
okay so this is all good to go now uh we
got it all
all laid out and and framed and
everything uh the pistons are in place
for these uh shutters and we got the
lamps down
so all we have to do is a redstone on
this they'll be quite a bit
involved with that but
i'll probably do that off camera and
then
run you through it afterwards maybe next
episode
but i think you can get an idea of how
it's going to work from this
and i just want to comment that this is
not to be confused with the other
storage room we're going to do this is
this is a small one here we still have
to do our big storage room
at our new base location at the
stronghold there
and that's going to be more warehouse
like
reminiscent of the storage room i had
on chocolate island probably and
there'll be a mob system in the middle
and you know how it goes
um i just want to try one more thing
here just to see how this looks
and again we may not necessarily be
using
wooden planks for this i just want to
see how the stairs
shape out here
yeah yeah it's kind of cool
okay so i think i'm gonna go for today
thanks for watching everybody
oh i had one more important thing to say
and i can't remember now
i really gotta start making notes
um okay well i'll remember it later
take care thanks for watching