[Music]
hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome to another episode of our
let's play series
uh what what is this what do we have
before us here today
it looks like some kind of secret
message
oh man what could it be i have no idea
no actually i made it of course so i
just wanted to demonstrate this to you
guys it may be a cool
way you can hide messages in minecraft
see if you can figure it out it's kind
of like a puzzle
personally myself i don't like puzzles
very much i
find them a waste of time they're
frustrating to me because i can never
never figure them out but i know some of
you really like puzzles
so i made one here for you actually
there's a whole genre of games
based around puzzles solving puzzles
they're called puzzle games
i know it's crazy alright so i will say
one thing though i messed up here on uh
i didn't mess up but there's certain
limitations in minecraft that prevent me
from doing the letter u
so this over here is a u and this over
here is a u
alright i could make it work if i made
the
the key to solving the puzzle more
complicated but i thought i'd keep it
pretty simple for you guys
so guys uh last episode i got called out
in the comments on something and i
i kind of knew it was coming i felt it
uh
i brought it out myself but basically a
few people were like
etho can you do something besides
redstone
for just one episode please like do one
episode not entirely based on redstone
uh because lately i i've been pretty bad
on that i've been doing nothing but
redstone
we did a little bit of exploring
recently too but we haven't really done
any building and today is that day guys
we're gonna do some building just for
the sake of building
try to make things look nicer
i gotta say this though guys like i've
been loving this update this has been
one of the greatest updates in a long
time
i was thinking about it today like what
have we got as redstoners in this game
since the redstone update 1.5 i checked
it was over three years ago
what have we got uh we got slime blocks
that was a big one
but besides that we got like weighted
pressure plates nobody uses those
we got uh activator rails those aren't
super useful
moonlight detectors not super useful
really we haven't gotten too too many
new redstone things in the game
unless i'm missing something so this
update i've just been like
loving it so much because there's we got
the shulker box and the observer two new
things to play with
and i got so many ideas uh
redstone though a lot of you know i'm a
redstoner at heart uh
i always have a redstone project i want
to do building is more of an artistic
thing
there's a lot of ways you could do
something and i
i struggle with that because i want to
know the right way
or know exactly what i'm doing um
so i i ho-hum a lot when i'm building it
i try something
don't like it redo it try it maybe
that's better maybe it's not
try another thing a lot of trial and
error instead of actually knowing what
i'm doing
i find oh i don't like this we're too
close to this fence
should we fill this in we have a hole
here should we make this a lake or
a mine or something i'm not sure
okay so we got a little bit of a path
started here
uh i just used gravel and i mixed in
some cobble and some andesite to give it
a bit of variation
uh it's a bit of a weird spot we have
the village on this side and then the
farmer field on the left here and
for some reason i left a bit of a space
between the two
so it's like what do you do what do you
do with this area just put a path
through it
i guess okay something that might look
cool is if we had trees on both the left
and the right
here so i'm gonna try cheese it to begin
with see if we can get oak trees to look
good
like that and that's gonna force it to
be a tall oak tree
uh you want the the stone on the right
side because i think it's gonna
go lopsided to the left here because of
this we'll see let's see what happens
to see if we can get the tree to grow oh
maybe not
uh yeah it's it kind of looks heavier to
the left doesn't it than the right side
there's more leaves on the left side
so i'm going to grow a few of these all
the way down here
all right guys so check it out here so
far this has been pretty low effort i
just put in a path
and grew some trees and that's it right
and already in my opinion it makes this
area look way
better than the grassland we had here
before was way more interesting right
uh but now that we got this the question
is how can we make it better
that's the question you always want to
ask yourself when you're building how
can you make it better
um not so sure i like how low the leaves
are here
uh or am i being too picky i don't know
uh one thing we could do or try to do is
start making some droopy leaves
kind of make it look like that it's
hanging a bit more
could could make it a little bit better
also we could mix
in some other types of blocks here so we
have just green
green grass oak and we have the leaves
right let's mix in some coarse dirt too
see if that helps it any any bit so i
got some coarse dirt here i brought some
soul sand as well but i don't know if
we're gonna use that
okay very cool guys so check it out i've
mixed in the coarse dirt around the
trees here
i started around the trees and then it
looked a little weird
to be honest so i decided to like mix
coarse dirt throughout this whole area a
little bit as well
and that helped it out a lot
then i added the droopy leaves a little
bit not in the middle
of the path but on the right and the
left of it so on the edges of the trees
here
kind of makes it feel like the leaves
are hugging you you know and closes
closes you in a bit more and uh it was
pretty dark at night so i added some
hanging lamps here
staggered them of course so uh we got
one on the right
then one on the left one on the right
one on the left uh halfway through so
it it lights up a bigger area that way
with fewer lamps
and now i'm not sure what should we do
should we move on
i wanted to try we might want to add
more to the bottom of these
i don't know that's not something i
typical
typically do but i've i've seen b double
o do that and it looks pretty good
oh man you guys are gonna have to
forgive me i just watched back like some
of the video
and i'm all over the place my camera's
moving all over
it's a building episode you guys need to
be able to see things and i'm running
around like a fool here
i'm gonna try hold shift from now on as
i as i look at things
but yeah basically uh added the bottom
on the trees here i really like that i
think that's
that helps it out a lot it makes it feel
way more organic now
and just added a couple logs at the
bottom not not a crazy amount
and it's nighttime so you can see the
lighting i'm really happy with the
lighting
it looked a little weird hanging the
lighting from leaves so i added some
logs above
each of these fake ropes you know
and the last last little bit of detail
we might do here is
add just some some leaves at the bottom
mix these in
very cool so i think we got this area
taken care of
i put some flowers in as well and some
mushrooms i'm hoping they don't spread
too much but we will see
uh so i think we got this taking care of
we're going to move on now to a new spot
we're going to go from over here to over
here
i was looking at this the whole time
it's like man i really put
put forth the effort on this fence
didn't i just a big plane fence all
around this village
uh we should do something about that
a couple options we could do like a
what do you call it a pike fence or
whatever like i did in the bandit camp
in my modded series so
put put logs down ranging from two to
five blocks tall probably
kind of stagger them as as well and on
top of these
probably going to put some slabs either
that color or
this color that way we don't get any
zombies spawning on top and killing the
villagers
hmm actually you know what
uh if we just do a fence like this
the whole way it's gonna be a big pile
of brown
uh definitely like the spruce more by
the way
so i i'm thinking we should also include
fences every now and then between them
so you can see
into the village get a little bit of
green and whatever other colors are back
there
let's see how cool is this uh yes
it's kind of cool right still simple
problem is we got a big area to cover
here so i don't want this too
complicated either
awesome so check it out guys we got our
brand new fence around the village here
villagers are safe once again uh this is
a good example though like we had a
fence here i didn't need to build a new
fence
but compared to that stupid little oak
fence i think this is way better right
that'll help the look of the area quite
a bit it looks good on the inside too
it's it's basically the same thing
uh and it's a simple pattern didn't take
too long to do
so what i decided to do is just two or
three blocks tall for the wood parts
there's always a slab over top
and either one or two blocks wide for
the the fence parts
and it kind of staggers back and forth
as we go here
uh-huh very cool and you know how
the the path was too close to the fence
before i decided to move the fence
inward so didn't even have to move the
path here
uh-huh added a couple leaves on the side
i didn't do the whole thing though only
about half the village
building takes a long time i'm running
out of time already so we're gonna have
to keep moving here
try to do some other stuff as well today
should we should we keep going with this
i've decided let's build a lake here
let's go ahead and do it
one problem is that dude over here he
is making making things a little tough
at this distance he's not
he's not getting me but i think if i
move closer
like up to here he's gonna start getting
me
maybe maybe not i hear a lava pool
what is that from oh right over here
really
did not know that was there careful
careful oh looks like i might have
actually gone into here before
redstone okay there is redstone
everywhere in this world isn't there
so i put some coarse dirt on the bottom
here just so there'll be a little bit
more texture once all this grass
turns to dirt so it'll be a mix of the
two i don't know if it's really going to
be obvious
you can't really see through water
anyway but just in case
aha so you can kind of see the coarse
dirts maybe a little bit
kind of possibly when you're in the
water at least not not from above
yeah that was kind of pointless anyways
we got our little
uh dugout over here and we have the path
running right next to it
which is a big no-no uh in order to make
it look maybe a little bit more
realistic we want to fortify the path
with something maybe would
we'll try some wood here kind of run
that along
see what that looks like in just a
second but also i want to show you this
so those mushrooms are spreading quite a
bit a little bit more than i would like
like we don't want them on the path this
doesn't look very good right
so here's what we're going to do this is
a little trick for you guys in case
you've ever had this problem too
mushrooms check a nine by nine by three
area
if there's any more of the same type of
mushroom in that
if there's less than five then it will
spread
okay so basically it takes four blocks
away from itself
one block above one block below so we
can hide some
some red mushrooms here probably get
them underneath
here for example we can hide two there
pretty easily maybe some under the tree
and if we do that it's going to stop it
from spreading and it won't go on the
path like it was there
yeah put a couple more over here
although wait a second
so this one's going to check if there's
if there's five within the area it'll go
one two three
four yeah that's still within range
secondly i think that'll work
we have a crisis situation here people
it's a step up step down typical problem
we all face
how do we deal with it i don't know
now uh this is uh just a couple examples
of how i usually do step up step downs
i always use slabs i don't like using
stairs for these
slabs are a little bit more gradual i
find
young etho probably would have done
something like this or you just put the
slabs like that
i've kind of learned though i don't like
it when the edges
are next to op to air blocks like
i always want a block on the left and
right of those if possible
another rule i usually follow is i don't
like to make a u-shape
when doing a step up step down if i can
help it
so in this case what would i do that's a
question for you
i think i would
go in another block here at least and
like then you can do that you also don't
want it to be straight
straight is boring you want it to look
uh organic so probably
probably go like this switch this over
to gravel
there step up step down we got it
all right so this is another interesting
thing i did not expect to happen
uh so i put some slabs along the side
here this doesn't look right
right you know why it doesn't look right
it's because our eyes like to detect
patterns and we have an offset pattern
here we have grass on the right side
none on the left side um so it looks
weird
right i need to get at least one block
of grass on this
left side here for it to look okay um
also if we look over here i don't
like the oak wood at all we should use
the dark oak
hmm
still doesn't look quite right does it
something is off
it looks better i would say it looks
better i tried it with the slabs that
doesn't look very good i tried it with
fences here
looks better with the fences but again
it still doesn't look quite
quite good uh possibly we need to
mirror what we did on this side to this
side
also i think the path is just wrong
yeah yeah let's uh let's shave off the
gravel over here
a little bit add it to over here we want
it to look like it's winding and it's
just a little bit crazy looking at the
moment no it's still no good
um let's try a little bit more
push it over here oh and we got some
other problems
okay fill us in
again a lot of trial and error just
seeing if things work or not
i think it's getting better problem is
it's only two blocks wide there now
ah no it's not working
and there we go so a little bit of trial
and error i think that looks a lot
better now though
hopefully please agree with me
uh yeah so i had a zig and then we had a
zag
and then we had a zig and then we had a
zag i got rid of the
zigzag zigzag and now we just have one
big zig
and a little zag that's the plan and
after i did that it went a lot better
so we'll take this out uh-huh
also to add the bounce to the pattern
like we talked about before we also have
to add
leaves and we have to add coarse dirt to
this other side
in order for it to to really feel right
so i want to put that over here maybe
get some leaves and yeah you get the
idea
all right let's take a look from over
here
how's it looking now all right that's
not
terrible i can live with not terrible
right
uh yeah i think what i'll do
yeah let's let's do this uh we're gonna
build up the terrain a little bit here
all the way around and then make it
connect to
over here ah darn it
ah i still have a button of milk though
we're good
well there we go guys so we bounced out
our pattern here we got all this garbage
on the left side as well
the leaves the grass coarse dirt and by
doing that it just
it looks a lot more pleasing right or at
least i think it does anyway
you can share your own opinion in the
comments uh i've also uh
finished mixing in the cobblestone and
andesite over here
you'll notice when i do this i start
with the gravel first like the soft
material
or if i'm working with dirt and like
clay i'll start with the dirt
first you don't want to do cobblestone
and then add gravel because it takes
longer to break cobblestone
and it just goes quicker if you use the
soft material as your base instead
here's another really simple little
trick
i'll share with you guys it's a pretty
common one
if you have a plain plain jane old fence
like this
one way you can add more interest to it
is by
like every second block get rid of the
fence and put in the fence gates
and what that does is it has a slightly
different texture
and it doesn't connect at the bottom so
it looks like this fence here is
supporting it
and this is raised it's also nice
because you can
exit out wherever you want that way too
and you can see it pretty clearly here
too like it's a simple thing but it does
change the look of the fence quite a bit
i would say uh-huh added some lily pads
in our water here
um one sugar chain i would add more but
i don't want to go near the
the fishy up there elder guardian keeps
getting me
um so i'm going to keep my distance for
for today
uh but yeah i'm really liking this guys
it's feeling pretty good
it uh has one problem
as some of you might be thinking did
etho really spend the whole episode
building this path
that has no start or finish and yeah
i did it's true so it's not super useful
at the moment
what we got to do is bring it down oh
that's curse
not curse course dirt that's the word
i'm looking for
now we want to bring this down kind of
a gentle slope down to here and then
connect to this i don't like this trot
and dirt i don't know what i was
thinking when i put it here
i don't know but this is supposed to be
a path as well we'll probably have to
change that
and my plan originally was to dig a
tunnel through this hill
so we'll have a path going through a
tunnel which should look pretty cool i
love tunnels
go through the to the other side here
and
eventually we might get around to
building a path through this area too
which will hopefully connect to a
village we build over here
we got one building made already
kind of need like 10 more or so though
to make it feel good
but this is our blacksmith building and
we have the purper
smelting in the basement here i
i'm very bad at interior design i don't
do it very often
and like a lot of these buildings still
need it
so that's another project to do
but uh that is gonna have to wait until
another time guys because
i am out of time for today and i just
got a leg spike and i realized i haven't
shut off the
potion brewing system since last time
that's been running this whole time
oh snap all right so here's our comment
of the day it says to those commenting
that ethos should just change the game
rule to fix his farm
you're not exactly wrong but i don't
think etho is wanting to do
that at all not just because it might be
temporary either
want to say first that i do do think the
cram limit is incredibly stupid and
mojang should definitely
not keep it so last episode i talked a
lot about
the cramming limit rule you can change
it
you definitely can change it um oops
oh did i overshoot uh but as a general
rule i try not to change
any of our game rules or any of the
vanilla settings of our world here
the only time i've really gone against
that is when i switched the world to
amplified
a long time ago and also one time i
tried
or i thought about moving the spawn in
my world but i never did end up doing
that for some reason
so yeah it's pretty much a straight up
vanilla
series here now i did get a lot of
support though a lot of people told me
i should change this game rule because i
don't like it either myself
the max climbing rule seems a little
stupid so i
might go ahead and just get rid of it
i'm not sure
we will see i'll see what you guys say
again if you have any uh
if any of you have any strong feelings
that i shouldn't do that let me know in
the comments
also something i've been thinking would
be fun is if we tried
a texture pack in our world here just to
see how it's different
not to use regularly but just as a
you know what does our world like look
like with the texture pack that might be
a fun thing to do
um we will see all right guys so
until next time thank you for watching
hope you enjoyed it hope you have a
wonderful day
and i'll see you in the next episode
take care
bye
[Music]
you