hey guys welcome back I've just been
doing a little bit of cave exploring
here the abandoned mineshaft near my
base trying to extend my territory you
could say I found a pretty dangerous
part of it there's like all these mobs
around I saw a cave spider spawner as
it's gonna be crazy
yes it is you know like it might shove
you dude ah
Oh Dan oh good it's all good he was just
having a bad day pushed him over the
edge we're still friends
um yeah messed me up okay there is the
cave spider spawner I want to take on
don't have any milk or anything so we'll
just have to do it I could get it I'm
just too lazy all these mushrooms
oh well that's going to complicate
things a little bit I don't see them
these things are so dangerous that looks
like I did it without any spawning
really though except through the wall I
think one did
so yeah mission complete let's Skelton
hey whoa ravine low dangerous ravine
creepers gone whoa scared me
all you little cheater shot through the
fence
come on I love those two ways there must
be another spawner can't be this many
left Oh what the heck
where is it above right there holy
that was insane fall fall fall I dare
you I dare you come on that you
that they're you now he falls I do not
want to get knocked off here yeah oh
shoot what's this no no no no no no I'm
sorry you yeah what are you doing over
there you got enough problems without
you oh yeah there's a spawner there too
and they are everywhere
okay guys so the other spawner is over
here I did find another one
don't dare let's disable it if we can
it's a lot of zombies they all I don't
have another sword I'm getting out of
here
maybe we'll mess around with these cheap
spider spawners again but I'm having a
lot of difficulty with them I've been
trying to find a way where I can attack
them easily without them attacking me
and I thought I thought glass panes
would work but they're not working you
can hit them through the corners of
blocks but then they're out of position
so you can't hit them again easily tried
stairs stairs don't really work maybe
I'll try try to show you
yeah block mechanic seem to have changed
a little bit from what I remember
basically you can attack through the gap
in stairs anymore least I'm pretty sure
you can't but maybe I could use a
minecart to hold them and then I could
easily attack them safely but I think
they're too small and you hit the
minecart instead of them yeah so I don't
know if there is any safe way besides
through what are the block like that
cuz they're just so dang small can't
really control ha yeah I don't know I
can't think of any good way of doing it
with your sword
you could easily set up an auto killing
thing but then you won't get any XP
maybe if you attack from the bottom it's
different I'll have to try hmm yeah
running on a deep running out of ideas
here Oh what are they gonna do why did
they choose to climb nope doesn't work
doesn't work well it kind of works thank
you if you have a block and then a half
slab above with water below them they
have a very difficult time getting out
and you can safely kind of safely not
perfectly safely attack them through the
half slab stuff the other items but you
will get the XP just rare occasions like
you just saw they'll actually climb
hmmm I don't know these guys are tough
to deal with I tell ya okay so I think
I'm going to try and make a system for
these two spawners now basically what I
need to do is connect them together with
the water stream and then have them
branch off to a killing system I still
don't know how I'm going to safely kill
them with my sword and really I think
that's basically all I want to do is
just to be able to kill them with my
sword because if you do an auto killing
system you don't get XP and you don't
get spider eyes from these guys so
there's not much benefit to it all you
did is string which is not hard to come
by so yeah I'm going to do that there is
a bit of positioning I need to take into
consideration though basically if
there's more than six cave spiders
within as seventeen by seventeen by nine
area around the spawner so imagine eight
blocks this way eight blocks this way
eight blocks this way eight blocks this
way and then four blocks above and four
blocks below if there's six or more cave
spiders in that area no more will spawn
so I need to carry the spiders out of
that area for both of these so I'm going
to count one two three four five six
seven eight
that would be eight away from that
spawner which is far enough or one two
three four five six seven eight
oh yeah that's why I have this line here
so this would be nine blocks away from
the spawner so if I move the spiders
that far away from that spawner they'll
spawn infinitely excuse me and then if I
move four blocks below this spawner so
this would be 1 this would be 2 3 this
layer here before I need to go one lower
have the spiders in that area or so for
this one and then I'll Thierry them this
way kind of I'll have to mess around
with it see how it works I also have to
stand within 16 blocks of both spawners
for them to work so there's it's going
to be tough making it work
nice try hey stupid nose
Hey
the heck
oh isn't that the worst sound ever just
cutting my ears I've been listening to
it for so long I'm in the middle of
developing this thing still thought I'd
give you a little progress updates when
it's all done I'll give you a
run-through of how it works but as you
can see it's there's not really any
limit to the number of spiders that can
collect so the longer I stand here the
more that will come unlike a real mob
system that is bound by the mob cap with
spawners though they obey different
rules so there's no limit as far as I
know and my game is actually starting to
slow down because I have so many
collected here and at the moment I only
have one of the spawners being utilized
right now I'm trying to get the second
one to join up with this stream here
having a little trouble with it but once
I do that when I do that it'll be twice
as fast as it is right now and spider
spawning same stuff slowed down a little
bit too I think that's because there's
so many moms here if you'd like to
entities it says 126 so there's probably
probably about that many spiders in
front of me and I can hit them easily
through the glass
and it it's pretty cool so two hits with
an iron sword
I believe this works really really well
better than I was expecting
you can see the XP orbs just falling
down below
I believe cave spiders give quite a bit
of XP to like every mob has a certain
amount of XP they drop in and pretty
sure cave spiders are high on the list I
don't know the exact number though like
for example creepers drop more than cows
do when they die I'm guessing cave
spiders are pretty high anyway I'll
finish killing these guys it takes a
while and then little collect our XP
okay I got most of them my game is
lighting really hard right now
it's a six hundred and fifty seven
entities on screen all the XP orbs and
stuff
I've got no spider string on me or eyes
and now let's go collect what we killed
it's probably about 20 spiders or so I
didn't kill them and pretty pretty
awesome so I'll have to polish this up a
bit I'll probably do that another day
though I mean I spent quite a bit of
time on this today already pretty pretty
awesome though
don't know what to call it
we got 41 spider eyes and about a
hundred string from that and they gather
pretty quick like it's it's awesome so
if you want XP in your world I would
definitely recommend building one of
these things find the tape spider
spawner or if you want it to go quicker
find two or three together it's actually
pretty common to find that many like
over there I found three together right
within range of each other so definitely
doable
I might work on this a bit more yet
today and then I'll run through the
water and the lighting system and all
that yeah I really need to be more
careful when I'm working on this thing
this is not the first time these guys
have killed me it probably won't be the
last
oh crap oh never getting back in it
there's like 50 cave spiders free right
now because when I was fighting them I
broke the glass and they all just shot
out the top of that thing at me oh no
dang they're so hard to hit I'm hoping
they spawn if I'm far enough away
yeah
so I got that I got to change a few
things too I want to make them a one-hit
kill so I might try to incorporate some
cat cacti or something in the water
streams to damage them before they get
to the holding chamber I don't know if
they'll do enough damage though so I
might have to play around with fire or
something instead gravity would work
best but I don't want to have to go down
low to harvest the spiders and yeah
having a little bit of trouble
connecting the two streams together all
my stuff's down there too and it's going
to probably have two or three minutes
left to get it didn't help okay where
did I die I forgot I just could go for
it hey there is
let's cover top now let's cover it with
something Oh what happened to them all
that's a bad thing I mean attacked by
spiders for hours now probably because
they're all running around somewhere
okay well I got my stuff back okay so
big improvement right now put an iron oh
are they called iron fences check iron
bars I put an iron bar above instead
with glass block so that's a huge
improvement it's much easier to hit them
now I can get close to them without them
poisoning me the only place they can
poison me is in the corners here so I
have to be careful that still isn't
finished I probably won't finish it this
episode because it's getting long I only
plan on like spending 3 or 4 minutes on
this today and I just got into it and
made the whole episode about it so sorry
about that if you didn't find it
interesting but I did and that's why I
continued with it so I'll show you
quickly how it works well you probably
saw it when I was building it it's a
little hard to see it's very dangerous
to go in it now but there's basically an
8 by 8 by 3 high room plus an extra
block for water so 8 by 8 by 4 the water
stream is 8 blocks long carries them to
another water stream which is also 8
blocks long then I do the stair and sign
trick
for moving the spiders uphill works
really well with them and then they get
pushed out and this area here is nine
blocks away from the spawner so it's
just out of range so that they will
continue to spawn until your game can't
handle it anymore basically now the
other thing we've got another room here
which is it coffee I try to link the two
together I know how to do it now but I'm
going to have to redo this I've played
around with the using stairs half slabs
fences and fence gates kind of find a
good combo but you'll see you see they
get stuck here I got it figured out now
though there's a stair underneath this
water screen here and when they go up
they don't go up all the way so they get
stuck on the glass block so they need
another spider to push them sometimes
they'll go on their own the trick of it
is to not the water screen needs to go
around the bend so we have to go like
oops my mouse is getting on my nerves
pretend this is water if we wanted to go
around a bend it would have to do this
has to be three blocks long and there
would be
I stare over here pretend that's a stare
and then the same thing if we wanted to
go up again we have to make it go around
the bend if we wanted to go around a bit
I should say and then there'd be a stare
here with this I was only going my water
streams are only two blocks long because
I was trying to get them up as quick as
possible because that spawner is lower
than in the southern one I also played
around with using a water elevator they
don't seem to work with these cave
spiders they don't behave like normal
mobs in water they don't swim or at
least they weren't for me so they were
just drowned in water instead of
swimming up and the guys in the stream
above are actually able to come down
through water blocks like three or four
water blocks to attack me so I'm curious
to see what would happen if you had one
of these guys chasing you in the ocean I
don't know if they would be able to go
underwater or not but it seems like they
could from what I saw
seventy yeah I'll work on finishing this
it's really really cool I liked it
I want to hook up cacti though so that
they get damaged ideally I want one hit
with a stone sword to kill them would be
a huge improvement if I could get that
working and I'll try to redo this so
that it joins up with other spawner so
that this works place is quick what
would be really cool is if I had a like
a cobweb here I could jump in it and
then as I fall down I could do critical
hits every time because you slowly sink
down and you do a lot extra damage that
way but unfortunately you can't place
them legitimately
the rooms for these spawner things are I
think I covered that they're 8 by 8 by 4
I went I decide to go with bigger rooms
because there is a an advantage to it at
first I wanted to use smaller rooms but
bigger rooms when spiders spawn there's
a chance more than one will spawn if
there's more spawning space and this
maximizes it so every single possible
spawning block is available for the
spiders to spawn in and it's completely
dark so if light affects it it's perfect
basically and I also have a lighting
system here to disable it but there is a
flaw in it in one of the corners it's
too dark and a few spiders are able to
spawn still so I'll have to change this
around yet but yeah I think I'm going to
call it an end guys and
thank you for watching next time we'll
probably do something else
but this is fun for today I enjoyed this
and now I'll have plenty of XP I'm sure
enchanting tools and stuff so it'll be
great okay I'll see you guys next time