hi everyone this is etho it's time for
some more minecraft look at my inventory
you see redstone pistons you know I have
something planned already we're going to
get right into building today I've
wanted to make a pumpkin farm for a few
episodes now didn't have slimes before
then I didn't have redstone all that
kind of stuff we got it now let's do it
get it done with I'm going to build it
right over here there are many different
designs for pumpkin farms I'm going to
make my own here might not be the best
but it'll be my own and I want to do it
kind of like the mushroom farm I want it
so when you walk in it Auto harvests of
course you'll have to till the soil
again because I'm not doing the bud
switch style or it's automatic just
because it takes up a lot of space and
causes a lot of leg stuff like that so
I'm gonna put it right here yeah yeah
stone breaks pressure plate this is
where the pressure plate is going to go
I better turn this down that'll be the
entrance let's make it official
okay
just like that and now I'm thinking I
wanted to go down half a block so I'm
going to use half slabs this I want it
kind of like a greenhouse looking if
that's possible for no reason no real
reason Oh wonder if this is going to be
a problem getting close to our tape
spider thing there um yes we'll have
half slabs that I'm thinking we'll have
the soil on both sides for our pumpkins
and that this will probably be a melon
forearm too so we'll need we'll need one
for the plant one for the pumpkin or
whatever we'll do it on both sides like
this this is kind of why I want it to be
half slabs so if if these two blocks are
missing and I got my pumpkins in that
here I won't be able to walk off and
trample them which will be nice nice
safety feature okay
yeah so I'm just going to go all along
putting soil here both sides and
hollowing this place out a little bit
more hollowed out now but I forgot
something before I can place the soil
down I need to place our pistons and the
way that it's going to work by the way
I'd like it to work so we'll just run
our wire underneath the pressure plate
over there that's right over here it
will be hidden underneath our half slabs
there you okay we'll have our redstone
underneath so when you walk in that
needs to power our Pistons gonna have
the Pistons one block lower right there
so that wire should power the no problem
let's check it just to make sure yeah so
then we'll have our tilled farmland over
here this is that what the pumpkins and
melons will grow on so if there's any
grown above will get pushed up and then
they'll get Auto harvested and then
you'll just have to retail any oops any
soil that's untilled after that
ooh I'm not doing too well with my words
anyway and the plants go here so the
plants will grow this way see
yeah so I'll do that both sides and I'll
try figure out how long I want it I'm
guessing around 10 blocks would be nice
and blocks long maybe 10 pumpkins and
Penn melons 1 2 3 4 5
just in its 10 long yeah so this is
going pretty quick it's not done yet but
it's going real fast just going to put
fences below the actual plants so they
can't be trampled hopefully if that
trick stays in the game I don't know if
it will be for long
we'll find out we'll cover that with
soil that's where the plants will be
this is what this is what it looks like
I brought pumpkins with me to try this
out to make sure it works
yeah harvests no problem but you know
what I kind of messed up here I want it
to be so that when I walk in the soil is
up and then when I walk out I want to go
back down the easiest way would be to
use a lever I suppose maybe I'll try
hook up an RS nor latch or a t flip-flop
or something to our pressure plate maybe
if if I got enough space here wish I
thought of that sooner we'll make it
work okay what do we have to do yet I
got to replace this side and I'm going
to change the roof the ceiling sorry and
it replaced the ceiling the walls with
our stone bricks to make it look nice
and oh yeah we got to put a back wall on
so it is ten blocks long it's a good
number good enough for me
don't want to get too crazy you'll
notice I'm pretty much this building
simplest things in our cheap system so
far this is like our starting out area
so want to keep it simple okay I'm
liking it I'm liking it a lot looks good
should work good hopefully we are
missing something important though we
need water so that our crops will be
hydrated so I'm just going to stick some
hidden down over here probably that I do
want that back if I can I can't get it
back not that sad we'll do it over here
we're here yet maybe I'll talk about
something a lot of people and I mean a
lot of people seem to want me to play
skyblock survival what do you guys think
of that it looks like fun
but a lot of people are doing it so I
don't know I wouldn't mind playing it
that's for sure but if I do I'll
probably cut out a lot of the grinding
parts of it and just give you like
progress updates not not straight
playing it that's for sure because uh it
it progresses pretty slow
from what I've seen but it could be fun
maybe okay so that we're going to have
to rig up some lighting in here too ah I
can't get it I don't know don't feel
like moving blocks around yeah so I have
to take care of the water for lighting
I'm going to use lava because at some
point I would like to get rid of all the
torches in my cave area so we'll have to
design this with lava probably yeah
that's what I'll do I'm going to I
brought glass with me I'm gonna put
glass all along here above where the
plants will be and then oops what did I
hit
and then in the wall there I can put
lava and it'll be held in place and if I
put glass here like I originally was
planning I won't be able to walk and
trample the crops
it'll be nice as a nice look to it -
yeah
I'm happy with it ah stop wasting lass
still don't have silk touch would like
to get it but it's pretty rare yeah okay
so I'll add the lava and then we'll
plant our crops and I should figure out
what I'm going to do about the redstone
I'll probably have just if I can make it
work out maybe have two stone pressure
plates this one here will set an RS nor
latch so that these stay up and the
second one over here will make them go
down all right so when I walk into the
farm they'll be down normally so if I
walk on the one that makes it go down
nothing will change but when I walk on
this one they'll go up and then when I
leave the farm these will still be up if
I walk on the one that makes them go up
nothing changes but then when I walk on
the make it go down one they'll go down
so that'll maybe work I'll try it it's
very close to being done now I went with
the pressure plate after all and I did a
T flip-flop so what happens you hit the
button
block moves over which empowers this
wire but if the block is above the
redstone torch
then it powers the wire the wire goes to
redstone torch here which powers the
line redstone wire above that's pretty
cool just have to put a floor here cover
it up like that
and so when I walk in boom all the
pumpkins and melons get harvested not
the other nice thing about these glass
blocks here is they should prevent like
the melons and that from landing on the
plant area probably a few still will but
it'll help prevent that from happening
and then when I leave it goes down so
that's what I wanted we got pretty cool
lighting here got lava
then I moved the water up just for looks
kind of have a red blue red blue red
thing in here and this water hydrates
the land so the only thing left now is
to actually plant our well there's a few
things left but main thing left is plant
our melons and our pumpkins here
I got the seeds from the abandoned
mineshaft for the for the watermelons
here and I wonder if I have a side
preference or should i mix and match
them I'll probably just do water Mel on
this side and then pumpkins on this side
ten and ten in beta 1.93 for release
I don't know how do you say it the pre
for the beta pre-release four there we
go
melons still only drop one it's fixed in
the pre-release five but like I said I'm
trying to avoid using that I'll wait for
six I'm sure they'll be a six all right
very nice so even when the pumpkins and
melons yeah if if they don't grow and I
enter here like if a few have grown
that's fine even if I if I step on
pressure plate the tilled soil doesn't
get untilled when it goes up like that
so that's okay and I wanted to add a
dispenser here too for the hole and I
brought one with me maybe
so maybe I'll try get the redstone wire
to connect to that underneath there got
the dispenser hooked up but that is not
all I also spent some time polishing it
up making it look nice because I know
you guys like it when I do that so just
for you this is what it looks like
pretty nice got some chests in front
here where we can store our melons and
pumpkins haven't tried it yet should
work fine open there we go we lost one
melon there it's okay that's fine and
our our hole got shot at us from our
dispenser so if we had an empty
inventory at our front here it would
just be neatly in our inventory and then
you would just retail everything put it
back and leave since the sense is that T
flip-flop it doesn't get shot out again
so that's fine and yeah that's all there
is to it it's it's nice I'll show you
the wiring for the dispenser ow all I
did spencer's over there on the back
there's there's a repeater there the
wire connects to repeater repeater sends
power to this block and then there's a
redstone wire on top the redstone wire
on top sends power to this block and
since this block is adjacent to the
dispenser it sends power to the
dispenser and it shoots out the hole so
that was not hard to do at all
one more project on McCool I am going to
check the time and we may do some more
stuff I don't know this is good because
it's given me a feel of how I want the
chief to turn out to when I when I
polish up projects like this I can tell
already that I want this area wider I
want this to be at least four or five
blocks wide because right now it feels
like I'm too close it's just way too
close so that gives me an idea of how to
shape the team yeah so I finished
editing the video we had for today and
we're about 19 minutes in right now so I
thought it'd be cool to do something
quick and we're going to go explore in
the nether haven't been there yet
excited to see it
very curious what kind of nether it's
going to be I'm hoping for a big lava
pool but I doubt I'll get it because
other generation has changed since 1.8
and I did I do have some arrows I don't
have a whole lot but I'm going to bring
some with me for the guests and here we
go we are on hard
same deal as last LP or last LP world's
not going off hard ever in the nether I
never did before proud of myself for
that right off the bat we got the ass
and we got that flicker deal going on
let me know how the brightness is guys
we're at 80 percent right now maybe I'll
do the brightness test for future
episodes let's get away from the portal
first yeah so we have absolutely no lava
yeah you see it or you got a fortress
right off the bat that's nice okay let's
see the brightness thing
I'm guessing Moody's going to be way too
Moody let's go up to 25 this is just for
a future reference tell me which which
looks best to you 50 is generally I
don't place down torches in another so
whatever you're looking at right now is
probably the brightness it's going to be
normally 75 and let's go up 200 right on
okay I'll go back to 80 tell me what you
liked the most
let's go let's go check this place out
seeing absolutely no mobs yet oh there
we go hey that's a nice sword you have
there you know what did I ever tell you
I hate you guys gold nugget first one
I've ever gotten awesome
okay we got a lot slow sand over there
glowstone supplies decent it's going to
be easy to get as long as there's not a
million gasps portal don't want to lose
our portal get some mushrooms down there
all right let's roll and yeah we're
going to head over here
okay now the the Pigman are spawning
first gasps oh boy the joys of the
nether my shots there now two shots I
like that's a huge improvement with the
bow well I guess easiest way of getting
in here it's probably just through here
put up a torch wow that takes a long
time that mine only ever mined it in
creative mode and another efficiency
pick there we go I do really like these
nether bricks they are one of my
favorite blocks looks like we're all
alone Oh blaze spawner that's good we
need blaze rods
yeah oh dang oh saw that coming
come on okay I should get away from here
actually stay 16 blocks away from the
spawner snipe them out they won't be
able to see me at this distance actually
like it oh dang damn probably too close
still start to see those fireballs
sometimes should we torch it get rid of
the last guy come on no there's another
one up there arrow supply is not going
to hold it very long excellent ok we're
going to run in try to get as many up as
we can
blazer out awesome you need so many
torches to stop them from spawning Oh
thing I thought I fell down a hole no
retreat Oh can't see where I'm going
did they a nerf tore something I'm
taking no damage here or is that my
armor taken what
okay I think we need more torches
excellent no not enough where maybe I
think they're spawning on the fences
let's do it this guy okay it's pretty
close one more come on come on
oh my mouse got stuck there oh yeah like
no depth perception when the fireballs
are coming to you stinking fences there
we go ah all right so we got ourselves a
blaze spawner no they're still spawning
we didn't do the side all right well we
almost got one all right cool yeah so
when we get around to setting up a base
in the nether here I'm going to build it
in this fortress area probably near that
spawner or somewhere around here I'm
going to get back home
whoa that freaked me out
can't remember how oh there it is
got to blaze rods oh I want to kill
these guys you think I could take them
all on
I'm very tempted to try I do have my
awesome sword right now can be they have
a lot of hit points and that systems to
the ghast whoa I forgot they run cool
all right you get a biscuit these hands
are coming pretty close least always
wait they still dropped a still drop
gunpowder huh
I just said just don't have enough space
to get away from me now because this is
such an enclosed area otherwise it would
be flying away all the time okay we got
it
oh yeah I saw you never-ending battle
now okay
so close to home how did we get across
must've came from up there another one
that glowstone is freaking me out by the
way ten looks like a skull it's weird
awesome okay let's get out of here
yeah make it oh my god boy there's a few
more my bullet oh we missed the gold
nugget hey sweet okay let's get up and
successful mission is successful awesome
oh dang we're quit
I got a ways to go back probably to 300
bucks away from home
alright guys I'm going to end the
episode here thank you for watching I'll
see you again next time