oh man first world problems guys man I
got it so bad here let me let me tell
you a little bit about my anguish just
took a shower and dried off as you do
right but you can never get all the
water it always hides in your pores or
wherever it can hide it takes a good 20
to 30 minutes to fully evaporates after
a shower right well I i sat down too
soon here and in my leather chair my
back is just damp still damp from the
shower and it's the worst sticky nasty
feeling ever now I can't lean forward
because then I'll be in the wrong
position for the microphone so I just
have to have to deal with it guys my
life is so hard but anyways that's where
we're at today to start off with here
but thank you for joining me again for
another let's play episode we're over
here at our ice cream sandwich that we
built last episode there was a villager
fortress here which we bulldozed and now
we're trying to make a farm out of these
guys a raid farm ideally the plan was to
do something like this is just gonna
experiment with it here we set up like a
a tube loop here where we're gonna put a
villager in this just one and he was
gonna go around and around and pass by
the different layers of the farm and
then the pillagers were supposed to see
him as he passed by and then start
chasing him but not be able to shoot him
because he passes by so quickly right
that was the plan
unfortunately I can't really test it I
cannot get a villager guys it's so bad
am I missing something or do zombies
illah Jers not spawn anymore in this
version at one point 14.4 um I don't
know I feel like I missed I missed
something in the patch notes or
something because I have spawned a good
150 zombies in it's supposed to be a one
in 20 chance
like I've flown around at night the
whole time I was building this farm I
was looking out for him and I never was
able to find a zombie villager to
convert so I feel like they're not in
the game but i might just beginning
unlucky i'm not sure if i'm getting kind
of frustrated with it
and I can't get them from zombie spawner
anymore either that would have been
another good choice but like I think it
was back in 1.11 where they removed that
from the game where they no longer spawn
spawn from the spawners so I gotta get a
villager from a village and transport it
here which is gonna be a little bit
annoying so instead of doing that I
think we're gonna come up with a new
plan here we're gonna use iron golems
instead of villagers because iron golems
also attract villagers but we can just
craft them in place where we want them
which is way more convenient then trying
to get villagers somehow yeah so for
each of our layers here of the farm
we're gonna have an iron golem in the
very center and I want a pillager spawns
like over here on the outside they'll
see them we're gonna keep it open on
that layer but we can see it happening
right now actually
although he's he was targeting me
unfortunately you can see if they are
close enough they will shoot the iron
golem right I worked it out and creative
if we have a five block gap here that's
the range they need to be in to shoot at
the golem if they can't get within that
range they will just try to get closer
to them so the way we're gonna do this
is on all four directions we will set up
a fall spot where they'll fall down here
they'll try to walk on trapdoors even
though they can't like this down here as
well then we can remove this glass and
then kind of dark down here let's get
some torches down then we will set up
just one piece of glass here and then
we'll have like a five block spacing all
around the goal so it's gonna be like a
doughnut shape platform basically good
stuff alright so just took a step back
here we're kind of watching what happens
so far it's looking like it's working
now they're not spawning oh here we go
we got one we got two
so you see they walk to those trap doors
and then they fall down you can get a
couple more spawning there's another one
spawned right in line with the golem and
he can't see him because the trapdoors
are in the way so I think we have to
here let's go up there I'll show you
what I mean so he spawned like right
here
and the trapdoor is totally block out
the view so we got to probably have a
couple blocks here removed like probably
all this otherwise they won't be able to
see him at all
uh-oh looks like we might need to remove
a few more blocks that guy's shooting
the golem right now which is not good
all right whoa okay let's go down oh
stop shooting the golem okay maybe let's
get rid of this this business yeah so
the idea is we want like where the
trapdoor is here to be the closest point
to the go home so that they try to go
there to shoot them but it looks like
they are like going to here to shoot
them sometimes if we get rid of those
blocks then this should be the closest
point all right everybody well we made
about four more trips to our Brown
mushroom farm and smelt it a few
thousand blocks at our super smelter but
we have now put together pretty much the
whole farm I think we got five layers to
this super Donuts hopefully that'll be
enough I think we're just gonna finish
these five layers and see how it
performs before we decide if we want to
add more onto it or not while building
this I actually discovered that might be
a problem if we spawn too many of these
guys rooms so I might have overdone it
already I don't know like potentially if
there's too many guys around I think
afraid won't start
understand right but we'll find out when
we try it out I guess basically the way
I've been doing these layers as I do the
outline and brow mushroom blocks and
then I just fill in the center here
pretty good and you can see we've made a
few design changes as well with this
thing so I've expanded the size of the
donuts I think there were about 12
blocks before now cheater 15 3 6 9 12 15
yeah and in these dead zones where they
spawn in front of the trapdoors I just
filled in earth blocks we don't really
want to leave these open because what
they'll do they'll spawn like here and
then that's the closest point so they'll
run up to here and as soon as they see
it's open they'll start shooting at the
Golem when they get there but if this is
a blocks they'll just just wander down
and fall away so at the very tippy top
of the farm here I decided to slab the
final layer so that hopefully none of
the pillagers will actually spawn up
here and get stuck there's not gonna be
an iron golem at the top layer um we we
need to get the iron golems and now we
have to currently this is kind of the
method I think we have to do up in here
and a fall-off so most of them are doing
that good good all right so what I like
to do is just building a little bit of a
place we can stand here oh they found me
see sometimes they go to a farther one
I'm not quite sure why that is like that
would have been the closest group but
they went all the way over there which
is a little weird
Oh didn't get shot again
this is kind of like the never ending
thing to building this thing it just
never stops they never leave you alone
okay met Jemaine quickly but typically
you know it's not gonna happen oh oh
they're gonna shoot him now okay that
was a failure let's go back see if I can
save them I've been throwing regen
potions at these guys every so often
just that keep them alive oh man I did
it again okay we got him in there what
we got to do then is get some slabs
above them like this and this is kind of
the tricky part we get some upside down
Pistons we got to push this layer down
so that they'll be able to fit within
three layers okay do it like this we'll
fill the space in-between with some
blocks and then activate these so I
pushes a slab down one block kind of
into his hitbox be the way one more here
okay so all those got pushed down and
then this that's gonna serve as the
floor for the next school over at this
level here you see just the top of his
head's kind of smooshed into that
alright so we pretty much got most of
the farm built here but we might want to
make a couple more changes to it if
we're down here the rates aren't that
great to be honest just the odd guy
every so often as far as I can tell
though they're not getting stuck
anywhere with their pathfinding which is
great
I think our design actually works pretty
good I've noticed though like when I'm
actually on the farm it works a lot
better like they spawn a lot quicker we
got our five golems in there in the
middle five Golden's for five layers
yeah you see how much quicker it is now
that we're up here we fully slabbed at
the top I think what we're gonna do is
maybe slab over the donut hole here
as well I kind of feel like darkness
makes them spawn faster so I kind of
went test that out to see if this helps
if we cover over everything here uh-huh
yeah yep so we filled in the doughnut
hole and I filled in the sides here as
well so it's completely dark on all five
layers now in the farm it doesn't look
the best honestly though I might change
that to a different block like if we
decide to keep it like this but we're
kind of just testing it right now it's
really hard to say whether or not that
improved the rates like the rates are
good ish now I would say I'm not sure if
the darkness actually helped because it
seems to matter a lot where I'm standing
and stuff and I might not have this I
might be standing in a wrong spot or
something I find like if I go up here
though or at least last time I did this
I went up and I went back down to look
at it it like got really fast for a
moment yeah
oh yeah it's way faster now right so I
think what we got to do is position
ourselves on top of the farm when we're
using it not off up this side like this
not underneath or anything like that
seems to get the best rates when we're
on top okay so we're doing something a
little crazy a little dangerous here
they fall down here right we got it so
they're gonna land in some water that's
moving this way yeah there's some fences
below here so it's it's like a half
block so they can actually step up onto
the souls hands you don't have to jump
on it they'll just they'll get moved on
to it we're using two signs on each side
here to hold the water in place that
we're gonna put over here and there's
also a little compartment here for the
water flow this way some more when these
blocks break and basically we're gonna
make a water elevator that goes to the
top of the farm now when we get to this
level here I don't really want to block
out the view that they have to the iron
golem which got destroyed but I'm
working on the farm here it kind of
messes up their their path finding a bit
so if they are targeting me and I leave
they can sometimes this switch to the
iron golem without moving to get them
you know they'll just switch to shooting
him and that's how he got killed it's
now gonna put a replacement there
somehow
so I'm putting trapdoors here so it'll
still be an open space but we need to
hold the water back so the trapdoors
work pretty good for that nope
yeah so he lost view of me and then he
switched an iron golem and shot him
okay like this so I really shouldn't be
working inside the farm I should have
put the iron golems in the last I guess
okay go up and basically we got to get
all the way to the top here alright and
then when we get to the top here I break
the ice I slab over top and then we make
our way down the tower here filling this
up with a water source box so that we
get a bubble screen alright and then
they're all free to flow here and then
we escaped with the ender pearl
alright so still kind of just making it
up as we go here how we're gonna build
the farm
apparently pillagers have 12 hearts of
health which is quite a bit like zombies
or ten which means I think we got to
drop them 27 blocks to get them down to
a one hit kill so we're gonna make these
elevators go up about 30 blocks above
the top of the farm and then we're gonna
drop them down to a one hit kill
hopefully so extend this this is I
shouldn't scared of this out there this
is one two three four five six seven
maybe we'll just make this eight blocks
long length of the water stream take
this come around
we'll put water at the end here alright
alright and then I guess let's we need
this to be at least two blocks tall for
their height just come up all around and
I guess we'll slab the top is we don't
want anything spawning up here either is
really important okay so water for the
elevator is full of water if we're gonna
break out now
I guess let's just open this up and see
what happens they go oh yeah we're gonna
have we're gonna have to have water
there so the bubble screens can go to
the top as well let's fill this the
missing ones oh and I accidentally
placed the block there oh no and I broke
the back oh now there's water on the
ground they're landing
alright everybody well we got the first
part of our farm done here the tricky
part I hope this is quite the project
but man I am really happy with how it
turned out here this is pretty cool so
they go up the elevator from all the
layers and then they fall down here we
have a little bit of leeway here where
we can find the sweet spot where they
died was one hit right now we're just
dropping them to their debt so let's go
up a bit try fine that is if we put a
slab there they died still dying you
want a little bit of space underneath
here in case we got to run some redstone
or hoppers and stuff maybe I'm dropping
them way too far
one more there it is
now the diet one hit at this level so we
got quite a bit of space underneath more
than I probably need okay so yeah this
this part of the farm is done so let's
talk about a few things here where do we
go from this point I think maybe I
overdid this first part of the farm it
might be too good like or unnecessarily
good I'm not sure as it is right now
these guys aren't really that beneficial
all we get from them the main reason we
have this farm is to get the bad omen
effect that's like the main purpose how
do we see that over here we want to be
able to farm bad omen from these guys by
killing the banner ones if we do kill
them we get a few things XP is always
nice
they'll drop crossbows some of them
enchanted we can disenchant those for
morale even if we wanted to get crazy
and they also drop banners other than
that these guys are kind of useless so
what I'm thinking I don't know how the
game mechanics actually work for this
yet we'll figure that out as we build
more onto this but if possible we want
to try have multiple raids going on at
the same time that was possible
previously I don't know if it is
currently in one point 14.4 they might
have patched that out of it if you can't
do multiple grades you might be able to
do it if we set up multiple villages
like we can have one village in this
side one over here one over here one
over there and then activate four
different raids at the same time maybe
if that works I'm not sure that's kind
of what I'm thinking at the moment but
the next step to this farm is we
actually happy at some villagers here to
test out triggering the raids and stuff
now we don't want to like when we
trigger the raids we don't want the raid
guys drops to mix with these ones
because these are like garbage drops
which will probably end up trashing when
we start getting emeralds and stuff
though we want those separate so that we
get the good stuff separate from the
garbage you know so have a separate kill
chamber for the guys we spawn in I think
what we'll do is remove this portal up
to the top there and what we're gonna
have to transport some villagers through
our nether to build the second part of
this farm probably since we can't get
zombie villagers I still haven't seen
one alright so this is actually a great
project for me cuz it's gonna teach me a
lot of game mechanics I'm a little bit
hazy on mainly villages I I know a
decent amount of villages but not all
the superfine details this is what the
wiki page says upon creation a village
center is defined as a bad claim by the
first villager or the gathering site
block a bell
and the villages size is the greater of
32 blocks or the distance the furthest
bed from the center so I don't know if
that means diameter 32 blocks
that's what we're gonna test out here so
my plan is like from here this portal is
over 16 blocks and we're gonna get a
villager on this side of it give them a
bed and like a workstation and
[Music]
what that means is whenever I did a bad
omen effect if I move like from from
like so here it should trigger a raid
right but if I'm standing here it should
be too far away assuming that's like
radius I don't know we'll find out I'm
gonna learn some stuff here but in order
to get a villager here guess what that
means I have to build another tunnel
because probably the easiest way is
gonna be by boats so check this out we
got ourselves a brand new extension to
our massive nether tunnel Network this
is probably about it
thousand blocks no it's not a thousand
the 300 or 400 something about there
yeah so this is this links up to the
part we had built before so I did see a
green villager running around our nether
tunnels we might snag that guy or we
might go to our underground village and
spawn some guys in there and send them
through the nether so I did find the
green coke guy but he's like way off the
path here and he's not he's not
accepting my nudges at all actually I
didn't just lock them in with a minecart
track and I that'll make it so those
pathfinding won't go out of that now can
we get him in a minecart have to like
push him onto the track a bit maybe go
in that way no oh he's gone don't go
through the portal no not allowed man
what a disaster okay what if we like
lock them right here he'll just go out
of it that's that's what will happen um
you're trapped there I feel like this
should pick them up as it goes around
the corner yeah it does okay so now that
we got them in there we can drop them on
the track
hopefully maybe let's take out on
another carpet okay we gotta make sure
we push him the right way to you there
we go
whoo so that'll make him go a couple
hundred blocks I don't know if I'm gonna
be able to get them in the boat though
is the problem break this we got them
barred off please go in oh he walked
over top I bet oh that's not good okay
let's snag this we gotta get him in the
boat I think I don't know how to do that
oh there we go okay that worked cool so
that can that'll allow us to make them
travel through the hub unfortunately
there's a little bit of a hill here
which I don't think we can get above
right awesome okay so I will get them
down this tunnel block this off so he
can't go that way
get him out of the boat goes through the
bar oh good job oh he's actually kind of
broken
it's like I can't nudge him at all
oh wait wait did he go through and then
back now he's moving again
[Music]
sometimes I wonder does the game know
does it know how long I've spent on this
hours building this farm not being able
to find a zombie villager to save my
life and now I finally have a pretty
good idea to get a villager to our place
here and he won't go through the nether
portal it's been a good 10 minutes it's
not the timer for some reason can't go
through now I don't I don't understand
why like you tried to go and then he
couldn't
can you not move entities through
portals anymore or something
my crazy like if I throw a stake through
I did go through you go through two
[Music]
now go alright so I went through the
whole thing again
we got another villager here I put my
bed down for him this guy came from our
underground village it was kind of a
pain to get him here but we got him here
he slept in the bed so now I'm hoping
that created a village in the spots we
will be able to test that out so I think
I'm gonna go ahead and skip the night
though I didn't give him a workstation I
don't know if we need one
yes we'll find out we only need one
villager for the village oh I'm pretty
sure so let's go up here I drink some
milk to get rid of our bad omen effect
as well so let's get it again here a
brand new there's no bannermen in there
oh come on no bannermen really if
they're pretty rare okay we got one oh
and the raid triggered instantly
unfortunately that guy might be in
danger where he is should probably cover
this I don't know if they're gonna see
him over here I'm gonna cover it though
just in case um we have a little bit of
a problem here
I can't find this raid anywhere I have
no idea where it's gone and like their
health went down I think that's a glitch
I don't think I've killed any of them
actually so
not too sure what to do about this I
kind of figured they would have spawned
on this hill somewhere but I don't see
them so yeah we're kind of stuck with a
raid right now here's what I found out
though it seems like if a raid is in
progress and we kill more bannermen we
don't get the bad omen effect at least
not while we're within range of the raid
Baro there may be if the raid happened
somewhere farther away we would be able
to go it again during the raid but kind
of in trouble here I can't really do
anything until I figure out how to get
rid of this raid so I think what's
happening it's counting these guys as
part of the raid even though they're not
and I think the raid wave won't end
unless all these guys die which is
impossible because as soon as we kill it
more will spawn so that could be what's
happening I'm kind of curious what
happens if we destroy the the bed the
village here let's let's give that a
shot will that end the raid
[Music]
oh it might have the bar is gone okay so
that definitely ended the raid hey guy
look there's a bed at the end there oh
it looks so cozy
you know it's nighttime it's raining you
should probably go to bed he's scared
okay I'll tell you what I'm gonna mend
edgy there Jess this is what I gotta
have to do I think he still sees the
village actually cuz he's like trying to
go there even though it's gone it's gone
man you gotta accept it he doesn't want
to be pushed away from the spot okay now
he's going now he's going it's like when
he got within like 16 blocks of that bed
he just beelined for it that's good so
that's gonna set a new village there I
think hopefully the old one is gone and
they're not like overlapping or
something crazy and now that bed is
definitely like 32 bucks or more away
from the center of our farm here let me
sleep myself that means it shouldn't
activate the raid as soon as we kill a
Bannerman we'll have to walk towards the
village over there I think oh we're at
the ender pearls but Old Spaghetti
Holmes I keep I keep some in here I
think yeah there we go it's like by
potion chest okay go back up here and
then I broke the Bell I don't know if I
need to do that
so we got bad omen again you can see it
up there right got the bad omen and the
raid did not activate this time so let's
see how close we have to get for it to
actually activate and go slow here once
we know the range we might be able to
put four villages around the center of
this thing still not activated still not
activated that should be a village now I
think I didn't think we'd have to get
this close though I'm a little confused
still not activated Oh what's going on
is that a village or not oh there it
goes okay so around here mark that he's
freaking out where are they gonna end up
is the question they actually spawn this
time I feel like that mountains the only
place they could spawn because there's
no land nearby here it must be those two
guys there so let's do an experiment
here my question is if we get outside of
the range of a raid so like if we go
over here the raid bar shows up so we're
like just on the border of it right what
happens if we kill a Bannerman from up
here is that gonna give us the
Battlement again during the raid like
while one's going on might be like
really hard to tell if we even kill one
though unfortunately
they can't see that far I'm just gonna
keep checking this thing for a while and
see if anything happens so I'm pretty
sure I've killed the bannermen by now
and we're outside the range of the raid
but I haven't been able to get the bad
omen affecting again so it might not be
possible to trigger more than one raid
at a time
which is what I'm trying to go for here
yeah all right rates still going on
right let's go over here yeah it's still
happening so good to know also getting
an incredible amount a leg for some
reason now something's happening down
there that's not good let's break the
bed
something is not running right I have
activated some glitch I don't know
actually let's let's keep it broken for
right now
oh my goodness oh I don't know if you
saw that but there's like a million guys
going up the tower right now and that is
what it's causing all the leg okay okay
I think we figured it out
[Applause]
I'm not sure how that happened that's
interesting
well anyways guys our episode is getting
a little bit long here at this point so
we should probably wrap up but man I had
a lot of fun building that today I like
doing stuff with mobs especially when
you don't know what's gonna happen right
that's the cool thing about new things
so I guess with that in mind though some
of you guys probably do know the
mechanics better than me with that so if
if you know a way that I can make a
multiple raids happen at the same time
please let me know in the comments cuz
that's kind of what we're going for we
don't want to waste all those bannermen
we're spawning in it kind of looks like
you can't spawn more than one raid at a
time but I'm gonna play around with it a
bit more but let's get to the comment of
the day it says so question do you still
play hearthstone if so are you going to
make a random hearthstone video anytime
soon so I've posted a couple videos on
hearthstone in the past just kind of
random one offs I have actually pretty
much quit playing trading card games at
this point I like them a lot but they
take a lot of time and I was finding
with hearthstone I kind of got to the
point where
I was playing it because I felt
compelled to not cuz I really wanted to
because they keeper they released like a
new expansion every three months and if
you don't play constantly you can't get
the cards you need in time for the next
expansion right so you're kind of forced
to keep playing or else you got to pay a
lot of money to play that game because
their card packs are not cheap so I kind
of got to the point where it's like man
I keep doing this where like I have fun
for a while but then I feel compelled to
keep playing even when I don't really
feel like it's just because I'm not in
an off phase you know where I don't feel
like playing the game and I just kind of
said dad you know what I'm done with the
game so kind of out of trading card
games at the moment pixelmon is actually
kind of my replacement for that I find
it's very similar to trading card games
but with a couple nice variations you
know so it's kind of like a new thing
for me so that's why I've been playing
instead but thank you for the question
anyways that's gonna do it for today's
episode guys thank you for watching
again hope you enjoyed it and until next
time have yourselves a wonderful day
take care bye bye
[Music]