hey how's it going everyone this is a
though and welcome back guys to our
let's play series how you doing if
you're in a good mood I'm about to wreck
it that's right I have something very
serious to talk to you about please
please keep an open mind about this all
right it's a topic near and dear to my
heart and I'm entitled to my own my own
opinion as all of us are even though I'm
in the minority here please be
respectful okay I'm of course talking
about pig power okay pig power is one of
those taboos in society you know we have
these pigs in our world they just roam
around free all day not a care in the
world not doing anything for society
just I mean look at them oh I mean yes
so what we're gonna do like we have
horsepower right we put horses to work
nobody's got a problem with that but
then we just let the pigs roam free we
should put them to work - yeah so
basically what we're going to do here
we're going to look at a couple ideas on
how we might use the pig AI in this game
the first thing I wanted to show you
here is a pretty good example like
you'll notice he follows me pretty even
when I'm pretty far away here as long as
I have the carrot selected I unselect it
he loses interest right so you can use
them for tracking your player as like an
invisible switch as well in redstone
like he's he just kind of stays put
otherwise but then if he sees you he
stays right on you like you will not
break that focus and let's get too far
away and then and then he loses it it
takes a little bit of time for him to
regain it it's random but it usually
doesn't take too long this time a little
bit more so
actually it's taking a really long time
okay there we go
sometimes it's like instant sometimes it
takes a bit of time oh I thought it was
faster for some reason hello mr. pig so
lazy we should just remove them from
society honestly oh hey you found me
quickly now the other thing I stumbled
across which I didn't know before like
you know how you can use dirts for piano
with a note block wood for a guitar
stone is I think drums it turns out you
can can do this with pressure plates
directly like if you have a stone
pressure plate it does drums if you have
wood its guitar and I think iron and
gold are piano that's kind of a cool way
of doing this and then since the pig is
only one tall he can inactivate three
different instruments without really
using any redstone so here's what I'm
considering though guys you know how I
always have steak in my hotbar like it
usually fourth or fifth slot here is
where I like to keep it I might switch
over to eating carrots which isn't as
good of a food it's true but if I do
that I can activate redstone wirelessly
if we set up pig switches and stuff so
I'm I think that might be a cool thing
we'll have to do some experiments here
though let's first see what we can do
with this if we can make a reliable pick
switch first all right so we're going to
take this guy over to here let's get an
idea of how far this works as well come
on alright so we're going to send this
guy down here okay and can you see me
from up from up here still let's see if
you'll track us
I think you should mr. pig yeah he can
see us okay let's go up a little bit
let's see how far until he loses focus
oh but I unselected it darn it okay
let's build like a staircase go up step
by step so we don't have to keep getting
his attention all right mr. pig there we
go okay so I'm going to go up one step
still sees us good go up another one
still sees us now now we lost them okay
so this is the absolute limit over here
which is one two three I'm guessing it's
eight four five six seven eight ish I'll
call it eight so up to eight blocks away
ninth nine if you count the pig itself
we can get his attention and that works
through walls and stuff like ant path
find towards us it still works is what
I'm trying to say all right double check
that yeah so he'll follow us no matter
where we put them as long as we're
within eight blocks of us he can do
stuff okay so if we were to do this
let's let's set up an example here let's
pretend there's a wall here the pig is
hidden inside the wall
and when we come up this hallway we want
a door to open or something so little
we'll just use a light to represent the
door all right
how reliably do you think we could get
this to work I have no idea because we
don't want the pig opening the door just
randomly on its own for one thing we
only want it to happen when we have the
carrot selected and ideally as quickly
as possible too so we would probably
want the pig just like resting in a 1x1
block area or something I was to guess
build this up so you can't jump over all
right so you're very cooperative I like
you getting shoved around you're not
biting me or anything that's great okay
and then maybe water let's let's see if
he can fight the currents first off ok
and he's only one tall so maybe we can
do this even we'll see if I have the
carrot no he cannot escape that oh ok
what if we get rid of the blocks above
how about now no really
okay oh I was hoping that would work ok
so if I select the carrot will you go
through the water oh it does okay good
the other thing I want to see though is
if actually this is dangerous right
because if I unselect it he's gonna die
umm big you better get out of there
quickly see me no no no oh darn it's um
well we got one left there I actually
don't have any pigs in my world I think
we have one at the coarse fruit farm
here too I buried some more before I
kill the last two yes yes I know you're
very excited this is your big day oh and
that's oh he jumped he actually made it
across
aha I think I have a good idea now I
this might actually work what we're
gonna do is get the pig into position
into the water there we go very good and
yeah I think I think we can do this he's
jumping though what we want to do is
Finn's Finn's let me place the fence you
stupid thing Oh
here let's do that so he stops jumping
alright this is a bit tricky but it
should work and then if we activate this
this piston it'll push the fence down
into the pig then we can put a pressure
plate on top and as long
as we seal this off the pig should never
path find out of here right no reason to
go anywhere get rid of our piston up
here all right I think that's good so
the pig is this going to stay there I'm
pretty sure I don't think he'll go to
the water but we'll watch it for a
second just to be sure but if I have the
carrot then he's gonna activate the
pressure plates AHA and that's kind of
the key as soon as we unselect it he
should stop activating it right hasn't
seen us yet it's thinking about us it's
taken him a long time this time oh there
we go okay so soon to be let go
he stops okay so what we would have to
do then is get the signal out of here I
wonder if we use the repeater he might
be able to escape then that wouldn't be
good let's try it though don't don't get
out nope nope you can't come here the
repeater has a little bit of a hitbox so
I don't know if you'll try to get out of
that on his own there's lots of nice
grass out here do you want to come see
it how he is trying to get out okay um
we can't do it this way then they won't
believe me if you don't do it Pig come
on just go in the water let's pretend
I'm not recording you did it before
there there he just did it he did it
proof I got proof on camera aha I
tricked you he thought I wasn't
recording but I really was so that took
a long time but you can see even though
I put a stair in there and these two
blocks are water he still tries to path
find into these two water blocks which
is a problem because in order to make a
reliable switch we don't want it
activating randomly on its own we only
want it to happen when we
a carrot selected right so we have a
slight problem with this design I did
figure out a way we could get the
redstone signal out of here though if we
wanted to use this this method basically
we can't get it out of the sides without
opening up the walls so we would have to
like dropper into a hopper it's not a
pretty method but it would work and then
like have a comparator detect when
something goes in there alright so we
have an item in here and then when the
pig activates its air let's put a light
down to there this is how we could
detect it but yeah that is an issue I
really don't know what to do about that
because the beautiful thing about this
is it was self resetting as soon as the
pig would go into the water he would get
pushed back if we get rid of it he's not
gonna move at all okay I got a new idea
guys let's try something here we might
be able to do it with minecarts I
remember something odd about mobs in
mine carts now okay one of you I don't
care who age before beauty
haha no oh wait no that means I'm old oh
darn it I got them I got them mixed up
somebody go in the stupid minecart
come on it's not supposed to be this
difficult all they have to do is touch
it I think it oh there we go we got one
ha ha got the baby so now that we got
him trapped oh that doesn't look good he
already moved um this might not work
actually I think it has the same problem
where even though he's in a minecart
he's randomly seeing these two blocks
but we'll try it let's make sure
I'm going to totally seal it up all
corners and everything alright so if we
select a carrot you can move right
that's good
they path fine towards you or track you
which is what I was hoping for I'm gonna
watch it for a second
why are you doing that stop moving mm
let me just watch him for a second I
think he's gonna move on his own though
yeah there we go
darn it's um okay I'll have to think of
another idea then okay there we go you
see that ah really I tell you what guys
I'm a little sad now I thought I had a
perfect method figured out here I
thought it was perfect
IAF Kate here for ten minutes without
any problems yeah because you see what
he does he usually only gets the second
one and then it fails it's only I think
if it fails and then he tries again it
like right after before the minecart
rolls down can he get higher than that
so it's extremely rare I have F cave
here ten minutes left 60 for dirt in
here and when I came back it was all
there then I started recording and it
failed the first time uh-huh but this is
good enough I think I'll use it so I
figured something out with the carrots
too it seems when you select them they
the pig instantly follows you so check
this out always it always works but
after you deselect it there's a cool
down timer so the pig is going to ignore
me for you know I never did time it but
I'm guessing it's about 15 seconds or so
um but this is good enough that I think
we can use it and I don't know if it's
close enough I kind of built it a little
far away here but we'll try yeah you
hear that you rolled up the hill so I
think I think it's pretty pretty much
good unless you guys can think of a way
of making it even better I'm going to
say this is the best you can do
and actually now that I think of it
after saying that you know if we just go
up one more to a fourth one I want this
as compact as possible to of course but
if we go one more block make it a little
bit bigger I don't think the big will
reach this or extremely extremely rarely
yeah this is how I'm gonna build it
awesome so now we know how to make a big
switch that seems fairly reliable I'm
gonna set some up in the man cave or at
least one so we can try it on something
like a door or something just to try it
out before we do that though just to get
some variety in this episode as much as
I love pig power
maybe I'll just show you this so I went
through this path finally and mixed in
some cobblestone because it was all
gravel before and I didn't like to have
that look so I mixed in some cobblestone
and man I tell you that makes a big
difference I like it a lot more all
right you know just a little bit of
cobblestone a little bit of variety
makes a big difference I also went
through this area again added some more
flowers and bushes
instead of having torches all over the
place I tried putting torches on little
fences here like tiki torches I don't
know if that's a good look or nuts
haven't quite got used to it yet myself
but it just goes along the path and it
it does a pretty good job at nighttime
too
what else did I do
added a random root here from the tree
over there and some some coarse dirts in
a few places just to mix it up a bit as
well we got a beet garden over here
three beets and some vines on this tree
or I think I did that last time but they
finally grew course dirt around it a
mushroom log pile this is a couple more
details and I think this area looks
pretty good now right some people some
of you guys said I shouldn't have built
this here because it blocks the view of
you've been ethought over there but I
think it's fine we can still see it over
here
very well
alright guys I'm gonna try hook up some
big power to this door over here in the
lab it's a perfect candidate for it
because there's no button or pressure
plate on this side of the door I can't
close it once I'm on this side I have to
go back and then close it with this
button so it's not a very good door as
it is to get a button on this side or
pressure plates I would have to like put
redstone somewhere where we can see it
like the buttons here I need redstone
here but if we do Pig power since it's
hidden in the wall we won't see it and
it should work I hope if there's enough
space back here okay so here we go
everyone we have pig power installed on
that door so now if we walk up to it
with a sword or whatever in our hand
nothing happens
alright that's what you would expect if
we do it with a keratin in hand our key
card then big power activates pretty
cool you've got to hang around it'll
close and then we can go on with our day
and the doors closed rights there's a 15
second or 20 second whatever it is time
before we can activate it again though
but by now enough time is probably
passed so if we walk up with the carrots
big power uh-huh that's that's the kind
of idea - it's I think it's cool
it isn't perfect though I have to say
sometimes he activates it when I don't
have a carrot in hand just on his own
and I don't know why or if there's any
way to make it better
um oh he did it already man I don't know
what what the deal is why does he want
to go there I have no idea
most of the time like in that other area
he didn't seem to do it as much so
something with this path finding in this
area makes them more likely to go to the
top there I guess there's more
more places he can go I don't know I'm
watching you Pig I know you're gonna do
it again okay he's not doing it again
it's pretty rare but I would like it to
be perfect I just don't know how to do
it Oh Oh Oh baby
aah I want to get the mending and frost
walking enchantments so bad but I just
don't like fishing very much I have to
force myself to do it
Oh a name tag hello oh man I love
fishing so cool hey your name tags for
free I've never got a name tag I don't
think I think that was my first time I
don't do a lot of fishing though it's
true we're not gonna fish for well yeah
we are going to fish arrest this episode
because it's the end of the episode guys
we're gonna call it here for today oh oh
oh this is it's mending three nope okay
not bad though not bad yeah I did more
of a Discovery episode today because I
didn't have as much time to record hope
you enjoyed it regardless I just wanted
to get one out for you for the weekend
here is the comment for today though ah
fish was coming I should have stopped
first one says etho you should start
using a shield I might have talked about
this already I'm not sure but you know I
want to use the shields
I like the concept of shields it just
takes up too much of the screen I'm like
the only way I would ever use it in my
let's play here is if I edited it edited
its to be like transparent and maybe
just see the border around it like you
know the wood part there I want that gun
so I can see through it but that means
not being entirely entirely vanilla
which we've always been so I don't know
well I say that I say that I have a
confession to make
I have oh never mind
I thought this was selected I do have a
resource pack that I made myself that
adds one sound file to the game but I
don't have it equipped apparently
anyways um oh there we go
but yeah that's my my gripe with the
shield the other comment says it says I
don't want to be rude
but people who don't like redstone can
go to another channel it's very sad that
you're adjusting to that audience so bad
and aren't true to yourself anymore
you are the redstone genius of Minecraft
why would you let the mainstream
viewership change the way you do these
videos i love redstone projects most out
of all content on this channel and every
time you do something with it and i
actually enjoy it every time you say
that many people don't like it you are
basically bashing own content minecraft
untechnical stay yourself keep up the
great work
mm-hmm so I see what I see what you're
saying and yeah I know what you mean um
but we you know we do redstone like
every episode still I don't think I
veered off too much from what I do or
did in the past right this is still I
feel like we do a lot of technical stuff
still I do glanced over some redstone I
know but some of it isn't particularly
interesting or you know like the Simon
game I glanced over a little bit last
episode because we already spent 10
minutes on it and the other part of it
was not too exciting to be honest um
basically just making a lot of
connections and stuff and not really
something easy to record and some of it
I plan on changing because I'm not happy
with it so I you know I show it then I'd
have to tear it down and redo it anyway
so yeah I don't know like we do a lot of
redstone and I whenever I discover
something new or find anything
interesting I for sure tell you guys so
that's that's my thoughts on that and I
mean come on this content is great look
at
oh we got another one alright guys I
hope you enjoyed today's episode oh yeah
I do have a couple other things to tell
you first off I I got the pigs in here
now this is the rabbit farm but I
brought over a couple pigs so if we want
to do more pig power we now have a way
of getting them all so I have playlists
added I updated the playlist on my
youtube channel if I missed any series
please let me know and I'll try add them
as well and they should be auto-updating
now so for etho plays minecraft every
time i put up a new episode it should
automatically find it and add it to the
playlist which is cool and what else I
think we'll call it here for today I
think I had one or two other things to
say but yeah can't think of it off top
my head now so thank you for watching
guys I hope you enjoyed have a wonderful
day and I'll see you in the next one
take care bye bye