[Music]
we're gonna start this one out right
our diamond swords getting a little
brittle we need a new one
so it's gonna be the best sword
ever period
i can't believe that worked i don't know
if that's technically the best it could
have been sharpness five but man that's
uh and i guess i could have got the
flame thing but man that is a good sword
that is a good sword awesome
all right everybody so since last
episode i've been doing more cleanup
more polishing trying to make the place
look better
uh got a lot done again
it's taking a long time though lots of
lots of
uh little tweaking and taking a few
steps back looking at things and then
changing it again
this area of the cave i really haven't
done much with it's pretty much
been untouched since the beginning
although that was a recent addition
i think in this area i will probably
have
like a bedroom sleeping quarters type
thing and i might set up a
furnace room and possibly
like a mini storage room here that other
location i showed you last episode will
be where my main storage room is i think
but it would be good to have like some
supplies over here too since it's
a few hundred blocks away that other
place
i still haven't moved the mushroom farm
but i do have the path figured out here
now
and what else i added trapdoors on the
clothes stone for our spider
staircase here i have
added this thing this is an infinite
water spring
so there's water on the left and the
right and when they join in the middle
they create water blocks
which is good it's good it's good to
always have a few infinite water springs
around
crafting benches are nice to have around
chests
and stuff are nice to have around this
one will be moved
uh i'll probably change
the block type with this thing though i
think i should have went with wooden
planks
uh it has a nice low profile to it
because i used half slabs on top and
stairs in places so
that's kind of cool but
yeah i'll probably do a wooden texture
to it just to make it a little warmer
i have also re-added the fences a lot of
people seem to like them
and of all the things i tried it was my
favorite as well
so they connect nicely to our stairs
as well and we now have two sets of
stairs so
exact copies of each other i have stuck
with the lighter wood
again it was like a 50 50 thing with
people
um choosing between the dark wood and
the light wood here
i really i don't know what type which
one i prefer
i'm so bad at deciding things like that
let's see
i don't know the lighter wood blends in
better
and the darker wood has a high contrast
i don't know which is
uh which is better though
they both look pretty good in my opinion
anyway i'll fix that
up again
go up the stairs here and you come up to
this
section which i've sort of shaped a
little bit better now
um slime area just
goes and ends here and then it goes down
to here
i have to do something about these holes
in the ground though i don't know
exactly what i'm going to do but i'll
figure something out
and that's pretty much all the changes
i've made
started putting sandstone in here but i
ran out
i wish there was some way you could
convert cobblestone to sandstone
it would just be the best thing ever
[Music]
okay and uh the cal frame a lot of
people are complaining it's not
centered it's uh because it's two blocks
on that side and one block on that side
if you know what to do
to make it better tell me please because
i have no idea how to fix that
it's like set in stone this whole area
i can't exactly make the farm shorter
now
without changing everything so
if you got a good idea on an easy fix
for it let me know and i will definitely
do it but
i think we might have just have to live
with it
off-center like that i don't know
um what else what else what else the ufo
thing
people commented about this last episode
the dripping is gone
it's not because of my particle setting
so you can see it's dripping here
we have all particles on it's not
dripping
still don't know the exact cause hadn't
really investigated it
it could be due to fence gates
or it could just be because it's old and
my world got corrupted and
some block updates got messed up or
something i don't know
okay it seems that was removed i guess
uh this is a brand new fence gate just
placed it just placed this water
everything's been updated
and it's not dripping so i guess water
doesn't drip through fence gates anymore
uh it's too bad let's try
i want to try out a sign
it doesn't drip through signs either
darn
why not oh that would have been nice
does it drip through wood
doesn't drip through wood what is going
on here
oh there we go okay maybe i didn't give
signs long enough
yeah i guess it's just certain blocks it
drops through now it's not all them like
before
we should probably try ladders too
does take a long time to get going there
we go
one more to try
nope it would look kind of funny if
water drops just start appearing in
midair
i guess that's probably why i wonder how
they did it before then
i don't know it doesn't seem like i'm
going to have water drops anymore though
which is too bad
oh yeah something else i changed that i
forgot to point out is i got rid of the
wood striping around the top
it's back to stone stairs again
a lot of people did not like them that's
not the only reason i changed it i
really did like it i thought everyone
was crazy
but after a while i really didn't like
it either
i don't know why it's like i think it's
like wood paneling or something you you
like it at first it's the greatest thing
but after you see it for a while it
really uh
you start to hate it and i i started to
hate it after a while so
back to the stone stairs and i
another reason i wanted to change it
because over here
everything the important stuff becomes
four blocks tall
while over here the wood panel
or the wooden stripe kind of worked
because everything important was only
three blocks tall
so we had one extra block to do
something with
um so it's this uh better this way i
think
and i started putting some of this
trimming around the top but i didn't do
over the door yet because i
might try uh raise this up one block
when i
do some adjustments here yet um
i added these trap doors and glowstone
here
for the door i think that has a nice
look to it
need to get it more lighting around
that's why i have this here
that little stone
doing pretty good with the no torch
thing we still have a few around i have
to figure
something some other alternate
way i can sneak lighting in over on this
side yet
but overall we pretty much have no
torches
for this finished up area which is cool
that's what i was aiming for i do have
one problem
yet with this with these trap doors
uh they open when i open this door so i
have to move some wiring around so that
doesn't uh
mess up and i'm not exactly sure why
it's working because i
kind of thought glowstone doesn't uh
transmits uh redstone signals i should
try that
yes glowstone stuff's really confusing
me because
you still can't put redstone on it
it's like you couldn't do stuff to it
then you could and then you couldn't and
then
just keep switching back and forth so we
still have that update glitch with the
trapdoor
yeah doesn't transmit power i guess this
is the update glitch that's making it
open
when i open my potion door so maybe i
don't have to worry about it and it'll
be fixed
next patch perhaps i don't know
so i had someone in the comments asking
that i do an inventory update to show
you the tools i have
and stuff like that so i thought haven't
done in a while we'll do it today
i pretty much always skip my resource
gathering in my lp so
just to keep you informed of what's
going on here this is my
goodies chest oh yeah pretty good
running along glowstone again uh-huh
um got a lot of lapis and
my iron supply is pretty good but it's
been dwindling away
used to have 64 blocks and it just keeps
going away
haven't gone caving in a long long time
um then we have a gravel chance that's
all my redstone
cobble cobble cobble
coal i've switched to using coal again
instead of blaze rods because
what else do you use it for you know
like i could use for torches but i don't
need that many torches
uh cobble this is like my sand and glass
one but
it's been messed up uh this is my wool
colored wall dies
cobble empty okay these are my tools
um so the one i'm using right now is a
pretty good one fortune 3 unbreaking 3
efficiency 4 pick got an unbreaking
three shovel which
is pretty much garbage bane of
arthropods five
sword at the moment uh unbreaking three
efficient
efficiency five diamond axe this is a
winner
i love this axe and i got a efficiency
four silk touch
one pick i got another one in the nether
i believe
which is pretty much full health uh this
is my
amazing pick the best pit you can get
which i got i think last episode um
got another unbreaking three pick here i
hate these like i really do
um dating on breaking three is like
getting
no skill in my opinion
because i got lots of diamonds so it
doesn't really i don't really mind
breaking diamond picks
but the waist 50 levels on that is
disappointing
to say the least my swords this is a
sword we got today
which is awesome we also have this uh
one here which is great for zombie
pigmen getting gold
as i've demonstrated before like
unbreaking is great if you have it like
on with other good skills like this
obviously but on its own it's garbage uh
fortune three and breaking three
efficiency four fortune three shovel
uh breaking three fortune three fortune
three fortune three
got lots of fortune stuff so i don't
mind wasting it on
just random digging like i had a few
efficiency 4 fortune 3 picks and i just
used it for digging
i didn't mind wasting the fortune skill
netherrack netherrack cobble
random good blocks
cobble lots of random stuff in there
whole chest full of wool
gobble random
random minecart stuff i got all these
tracks
from abandoned mine shafts so that's all
my supplies guys that's where we stand
at the moment
and i got some stuff in the nether but
not a whole lot
and my statistics are all messed up
unfortunately because i keep switching
my version number like when we were
doing race for wall i had to switch to
1.0
when i play legendary i switched to 1.73
and the way i do that my statistics
always get messed up when i
when i switch so
that's everything guys that's the
updates
i'm thinking for today's project we're
going to build a piston elevator
right here to go to the surface
because uh something i wanted for a long
time if i ever have to go
up to the surface i need to uh
like go over here and parkour my way
around this garbage
climb up my broken ladders and it's just
it takes a good minute every time it's a
real pain
so i want to quicker way up
it's easy to make a way down but getting
up is the tough part
another one coming so
yeah we'll build it right at the end
here it's only
it's only gonna be like 15 to 20 blocks
to the surface i think
medium all right
and i think i'll build it out of uh
wood blocks probably so it's been a
while
since i last made one of these but i
think what you do is you go in one block
and we'll set up a temporary frame here
yes door frame just to help us visualize
it
[Applause]
go in one block and then dig four
then on both sides dig out the four
this side too
that gives us a 4x3 area we need a 4x4
to build the elevator
wow they're just pouring in i shut off
the old slime farm now
so this is this one's getting faster
got another one coming and oh man
you guys are interrupting my video
okay there we go last one
yeah so if i wanted to go clockwise i
need to go
one block to the right yet if i want it
counterclockwise i go one block to the
left
and i prefer clockwise
but since we might do something with the
big slimes here i'm gonna
try save an extra block space here so
we'll go
counter-clockwise on this one so we've
got a four by four area here and i'm
going to dig it all the way up to the
surface
and then makes it really easy to build
the elevator
[Applause]
okay we're just about done here uh it's
going
going pretty good it works i was worried
about that
a lot of people told me it doesn't work
in the recent patches but
you just got to make sure you go all the
way in otherwise you will get clipped
against the block and stop
so that's all there is to it and of
course set your first repeater to 4 or
so just give you extra time to get into
position
and the wire comes down and
goes next to the pressure plate there
so it's pretty easy took about an hour
to do so far
and only thing left really is
to
just jump there to stop let's just align
it
with wood
um well we'll start here
gotta make sure when you do this you
don't cut your wires
so no
wait oh
um i guess i can't put one there
all right not a big deal um
getting close to 100k subscribers it's
amazing
never thought that would ever happen uh
have not
uh i'm not sure if there's going to be a
special or not
it would be cool if there was but time
is the issue
got a got an idea but it'll take a while
to do so
i don't know last last special
was kind of an issue because i went a
few days without really posting any
videos and a lot of people are upset
about that so
if i can do it i will do it but i'm not
going to let it interfere with my
regular schedule this time so there may
or may not be
a cool special this time around
we'll see what happens whoops
no good glowstone
there we go yeah that should do it now
got the all the empty spaces filled in
this is going to be so convenient i got
a quick drop here which
i'll probably uh clean up to yet
sometime
for a real ride here
only one slight issue i'm having with
this
this very last one doesn't push me quite
up
it doesn't push me on to the top of this
stair
so if i walk forward
i tanked it up i kind of have to walk a
little bit to the right i'm not sure why
it's doing that
oh well anyway i should have like some
little hut here too so maybe
we'll try rig that up before we end this
episode
put some leaves around it
um can i put one more
no has to
has to go there okay
i love using leaves for decoration i
don't know why
it's just i know why i know why green's
my favorite color
it's not that complicated okay
make a derpy little hut here
um
i don't know
try hide it
oh you know why it's not working i have
that set at one that last one i kept
forgetting to change it
let's give this another ride
i was wondering why that was doing that
there we go perfect that
is the problem so all the repeaters have
to be set at
two i i've heard if you
you can set them at one if you hold
shift as you ride it but
that seems like a pain but i think you
can get a faster elevator if you hold
shift as you ride it
or at least that's the way it used to be
um but yeah i'm gonna
finish this up i'll call the episode and
end
for today thanks for watching
little by little we're getting more and
more done here so it's cool
okay see ya