[Music]
hey hey
how's it going everybody this is etho
welcome back
thank you for joining me again today
guys i hope you're having a wonderful
day
and i i need you to do something for me
right now
go get your snacks you're gonna want
them
you'll regret it if you don't because
today oh
today's a very special episode it is of
course
what were we doing today the four it's
the 400th right
yeah the 400th episode haven't i become
such a great actor guys over
over these years of of doing this i am
yep yep i don't even see people saying
i'm a bad actor anymore we have all just
accepted it
oh snap so i i want to have some fun
with you guys today
i'm hoping we can do some cool stuff
here
we uh we're going to try to do this rube
goldberg machine i think it's a fun idea
and we started it last episode we got a
little bit done here
we got like our villager in the house
here and he goes out to get the
newspaper
and we have it rigged so it blows up and
then he gets washed away and he has a
very bad day
gets sent down here onto the track
and then he gets stuck on the gravel
pile and it blows up and
that's about as far as we got
unfortunately
i was kind of hoping we'd have a really
cool show to watch today with all this
but that's all we got so far
maybe should have started it earlier but
we'll try work a little bit more on that
today and hopefully get a bit done
and there is something though i realize
no matter how much we get done on this
at best at best like seeing a gravel
pile explode
i might get uh oh that was nice type of
reaction out of you guys
that's not what i want that would be
nice
but i want uh oh that was cool
type of reaction from you guys if
possible so i
decided i should try to build like a
final piece
to this rube goldberg machine so no
matter what happens today even if we
don't build anything exceptional
we have something cool at the end here
to look forward to
so i have spent like 15 hours
on this final piece and i wish i could
tell you it's super amazing and i got so
much done
but this is minecraft survival minecraft
and
uh it seems stuff takes forever i don't
know what it is
i am happy with what we got here though
it might not be as impressive as i hope
though
but we will go check it out before we
look at it though
i want you to think what would the final
piece of the rube goldberg
machine be what do you think i built
what would you expect
it's something weird actually it's not
really something you might think of
so this is it basically no matter what
we do even if we add on to this later
at the very end of it we want to try
connect the villager up to this track
here and that will activate this final
piece
as soon as he goes through and basically
i decided let's build
a village the final piece of the rube
goldberg machine
is a village believe it or not and this
is it
i call it drearyville it's like an
abandoned
coal mining camp of some sort and we got
like a crane here
moving some logs this is like a oh
oh intruder get out of here
this is like a tnt shack of some sorts
got coal on the ground all over the
place these little mines set up
minecart tracks um and i was about
i was able to build like three buildings
again it doesn't seem like much it's a
pretty small village but
uh i was building like a a madman here
guys
i tell you like i was placing blocks
quick it's just
it takes time it seems um
and like any special i make i had
technical difficulties too
because apparently i lucked out and
found something that crashed the game
while building this
and uh had a lot of fun trying to fix
that
apparently i gotta update though so
before we see the final piece here
or activate it we gotta update to 1.8.3
because i'm still on the pre-release
but anyway we got like a back belly here
not back belly back ellie and
that's that's about it uh just a little
mining village nothing super duper
special
i died like 10 times building this thing
because
because of this spot right here it's
dark and i kept having creepers come
over
in fact one of the main reasons i built
this minecart track thing is just so i
would have like a fence
to keep the guys out because they kept
killing me
anyway so how does this tie into
our rube goldberg
theme you might wonder and i tried to
come up with a story
for this as i was building it and i
decided
[Music]
um our villager is having a bad day
right that's our theme
this place you might not know this but
the hopes and dreams of every villager
is to one day
own their very own village he was a
villager chief this was his village
and one day something tragic happened
something terrible
this horse is an evil horse
he wanted apples he was greedy all he
had was hay and he wanted apples so he
made a deal with the zombies for for
some apples and he
he let the zombies kill all the
villagers it's terrible
it's terrible and he's still here and
yeah that's about it uh
so this is like the worst place in the
world for our villager to come visit and
this this is where he's gonna be
end up at the end of our roof goldsberg
machine because he'll be
reminded of the memories of his fallen
brethren
his friends memories of his dream being
taken away from him and the one that did
it
is still here that horse
i'm very bad at telling stories anyway
this is the final piece
uh we'll check this out again at the end
of the rube goldberg
berg machine let's go ahead and head
back and we're going to start
adding on to we didn't blow up
i'm actually surprised we'll add on a
little bit more to it here
and uh maybe we can talk a little bit as
i do that
all right everybody so we are growing
some flowers here
it turns out the other day when i tried
to do that floaty sand thing or floaty
gravel
i did not do it correctly or i must have
missed the bottom block
why is it not working
you know what it is i bet i have to
update
yes okay i'm updating my minecraft right
now
and i'll be right back okay
here we go moment of truth
yes it finally works we got floaty
gravel
yes so we tried this other day i thought
i was doing it wrong maybe because i
just could not get it to work but i
guess it was the version number so
we are in 1.8.3 now um
i need to use this version for today
because of that final part
it was crashing in the other version we
were just on
but unfortunately this newer version is
not nearly as optimized
for for my computer anyway so it runs a
lot
slower but we'll have to live with it
for today
so the next part of this rube goldberg
machine
that we're gonna do is like a floaty
gravel section
and we're gonna do like carpet bombing
yes carpet bombing i just cannot get
away
from the tnt it's so much fun uh so what
we'll do we'll set up like little
platforms every so often
with these like gravel hairs connecting
to them when the gravel gets up to here
it's going to make the whole platform
fall
and basically
we'll just try d1 here
we gotta put flowers up on here actually
we should shape it maybe too
let's make the edges a little bit taller
and yeah so then we just put down our
flowers
oh i was like is that four blocks wide
because the the flower is
really close to that one and really far
away from that one but it's just
the randomness of it all right
and how tough is this going to be to do
then we gotta put the gravel down
i have a feeling it's gonna be very
tough because
because it's really hard to place things
now
i guess i'll have to go on top here
like so do this
and afterwards i'm going to go
underneath and just remove all the
flowers and everything should stay
floating
yeah we'll just do something like this
and then put a track in the middle
and if tnt minecarts fall three or more
blocks they explode
so then we just need that like like
there and when this whole thing comes
crashing down it's going to explode and
when it hits the ground
so we'll set up a few of those and
hopefully that's a cool
cool little thing to our track here
okay so we are pretty much done with
this here look at this
doesn't this look crazy uh it's
definitely one of the stranger things
i've done
um now we got to remove all the flowers
i'm not going to make this any bigger i
realized as i was making this
it has a critical flaw and
if we make it any bigger it's probably
going to be a bad idea
do you know what's wrong with it do you
know what the oversight is
uh enderman can pick up gravel
yeah that's a little bit tricky
to avoid i'd lit up as best as i can up
here just so hopefully it doesn't happen
but they can pick up gravelly and pick
up sand
i would have had to build this out of
either anvils or dragon eggs
which i can't get either of those very
easily so
we'll have to leave it at this now to
remove the flowers
this is going to be tough i guess we
have to do the outside ones first like
before the
interior ones because when we break
these it's going to update
the lower block
did i just break two oh man
this is gonna be so tough isn't it
hopefully we can get into a groove
um so far so good
and maybe as we do this we can we can
talk a little bit hopefully i can focus
enough
oh man i am like
this is a little scary one false click
and the whole thing comes down and it
doesn't just come down it comes down
exploding
yikes okay it's got to be the bottom one
too i think
so 400 episodes guys i can't believe
we have made it this far like it's been
what it what has it been is it been like
four years now since i started this
series
and we have had some good times together
really been enjoying uh what i do here
and
from what i can tell you guys have been
enjoying it too you guys are still very
supportive
and i appreciate that um
always getting nice comments in the
videos and i love to read them
it's my favorite part of of what i do
here is just seeing your guys's
reactions
and uh you know quite often i'll see
comments and people will be like
i could hardly wait to get home from
school or home from work just
to watch your video it makes my day
better and i just love to
to be a part of your lives in that way
to to
bring you entertainment to make your
days better
those of you that enjoy what i do here
um
just the other day i was i was talking
to somebody
they spend an hour and a half
every day going to work an hour and a
half going home
they leave bright and early in the
morning and they get home
at like nine o'clock and they're
basically done for the day and it's like
man that sucks so bad
for me i can just like sleep in
i can i can just roll up
roll over get out of bed and i'm ready
to go for work and
oh it's just it's been wonderful doing
what i do here and i
i greatly appreciate you guys supporting
me because you're the ones that allow me
to do this
and uh have allowed allowed me to get
this far
and it's just been wonderful uh doing
this
and i hope to continue to do it for as
long as i can here as long as you guys
are
are enjoying it okay here we go guys
home
stretch last little piece i just made a
backup because i don't trust myself
i don't want it to all end
on this last little piece um so
i just had to make a backup we're going
to test this out too
so i want to make sure it works i think
at the staircase
i have to start at the top and work my
way down
i'm sort of building this in reverse
order like it's got to be activated in
the right order otherwise
it all comes crashing down yeah this is
good okay good
remove these and
then when we have the villager on the
track down below i'm gonna have to try
make it look like he's dodging the tnt
falling even though i haven't planned
uh what or how it's actually falling so
that
he'll avoid it you know um
okay this is
this good oh we're almost there
and
no wait wait wrong one do that one first
if i need to add on to this i can always
just put the flowers back
at a spot and start building off of that
again
like i just did there
woohoo that's it
look at that that's crazy i hope they
don't
fix this honestly i think this is a cool
glitch uh where you can actually do
floating sand and floating gravel again
uh i will activate this though now just
because i want to make sure it works and
the backups not from too long ago
actually i got one on me
okay and
no darn it's the tnt blast doesn't even
reach his gravel here
okay that's a slight oversight
oh whoa
no i didn't expect that
the explosions actually uh carry up
through the air and the
a whole bunch of them activate it once
in midair that's interesting
uh-huh all right well i think that's
kind of cool i gotta try fix this though
um we gotta hurry up here like it's it's
almost 12 o'clock here and i want this
up at two
which is uh i'm really pushing my time
this episode has taken so long to make
but uh
maybe we'll just do a final setup here
and watch
this thing activate all the way through
and hopefully i can think of something
quick to fix that
um slight setback
dang it i can't respond
okay this is why i need to finish the
tunnels guys
is it down here or is it the next one
it's this one the minecart stopped okay
so basically i just shot out my track
right and it was unpowered i hopped out
of my mine cart
to put a lever down and i fell all the
way down
apparently that was not a good spot to
get out over there
where did i land is it down here
uh yeah it must be right down here
somewhere no maybe i thought so
oh is it further ahead
oh no
my stuff this has been happening way too
often lately
this is not the right spot darn it okay
i gotta die then
hmm um
not looking good no
i brought blocks this time but i thought
this was a spot right here where i fell
i guess that doesn't make sense does it
like up over here i thought
somehow no that doesn't make sense
either huh
i'm in the wrong location i gotta be
wait a second okay so that's the tunnel
up there
no at best i'm only gonna recover my
sword as the thing so it's
i'm not grasping too much here but i did
want to get that at least
yeah the minecart's over there that's
where i fell
right down there somewhere
hmm darn it
um
no all right well i gotta
break my bed because i can't get through
my my portal without ender pearls and
then i gotta die
again and now i'm back okay
i gotta try to get re-equipped quickly
here so we can finish up the episode
all right guys well this is it we are
going to activate the rube goldberg
machine now
i did not really have much time
to finish this like i wanted the
villager to weave in and out of the
the following tnt here but wasn't able
to do that i just made the track go
straight to the final
because we are really pushing our time
here
i wish i had a week to make an episode
but uh probably the biggest complaint i
get is i don't make enough videos so
we'll just have to push through for
today and i decide to do this just as
the sun is setting
so here he goes
the villager is about to have his bad
day
i think he can get away from that tnt in
time
i hope oh here it goes here it goes
bam and he's getting
washed away oh he's trying to jump out
don't jump out guy
all right let's use the paths i built
here
can watch him go down he's getting all
wet
oh poor guy okay
no he found a spot
you stupid villager are you kidding
he found a spot where he can get stuck
not today good sir not today
oh oh i missed the path okay well he
should fall down
i'll have to fix that i guess there he
goes he's in the mine carts
there goes the tnt minecarts
what
oh no oh no oh no okay okay
um
how did that go so wrong we've tested
this before
let's try that one more time shall we i
gotta see why he bounced over there that
didn't make any sense
okay let's go again here uh i
checked out the gravel pile i don't know
how he bounced off of it
there was a track in that block right
there
that i just removed and hopefully it
doesn't happen this time
but yeah it also looks like my path down
there isn't very safe because the whole
thing
blew up um so we're gonna have to get
out of there when this
sky starts falling
is he going to get stuck in that spot
again he's he's hugging that wall
he really wants to he doesn't want want
to wait for me to fix it
yeah look at that oh my goodness you
this is ethos bad day now
and he won't even go forward come on
cut me a little slack here all right
i'm on the path this time let's uh
get ready to run okay that's good
please don't bounce please don't bounce
okay that time he stayed and he's still
going good uh let's go over here
uh we'll have to try beat this guy here
because i have nothing to slow him down
we'll have to add stuff
later he's not going to just be lined to
the end we're going to have stuff in
between hopefully
but uh yeah there he goes into the final
let's get into position here
this is it
oh burn it down baby burn it down
oh my goodness
i wanted to try to do this at night time
for the fire effect
oh my goodness
kill that horse kill the evil horse
who killed all your friends yes
oh oh
creeper oh that was not planned
uh there's also tnt hidden throughout
this place by the way
i'm stuck in that cobweb
oh no oh no okay i'm not really supposed
to be down here let's go off to the side
a little bit before i die
um so yeah basically the final he blows
up the whole village
and torches it down
oh so glorious
oh what hit me oh he hit me
i'm so close to dead i don't want to die
whoa come on i just need to survive a
little bit longer
there we go
oh snap that was pretty cool
so yeah i built this place entirely out
of flammable material
for this for this purpose um
so even the coal blocks burn the hay
all the cobwebs and stuff they burn the
whole place
burned to the ground
and he's got this cool little like
machine gun thing oh i think it's out of
ammo now
let's go check them out
oh we gotta go through here
and i'll just break this to keep it
quiet oh no i gotta break this one
so yeah he's got his little gunner up
here and he gets dropped in from above
over there and he's
he looks all cool in his uh machine gun
as he lays waste to the world
uh-huh anyway that's the final guys
we'll probably see this a few more times
as we activate the rube goldberg machine
i wanted to do a big uh like hollywood
editing with lots of different angles
and stuff with this but maybe we'll do
that next
time just as another
cool way we can show this but uh
i think that was pretty fun
look at the town though this is gone
everything is gone pretty much
left the giant crater so that building
in the back was full of tnt as you
probably guessed
uh-huh
but anyways guys i think this is it we
should probably
wrap up our episode with the glorious
fireworks show
um i got three comments picked out for
today
first one says hey etho i was wondering
why aren't you doing
speed challenges anymore like in the old
days
anyway love your videos especially now
that my leg is broken
oh that's terrible i'm sorry
keep up with the great work you're
awesome
ah speed challenges so i think
i kind of mad
bomber challenge was kind of the last
one i did i didn't call it a speed
challenge but that it was sort of uh
meant to be like one um but if you guys
want to see more speed challenges
please suggest ideas because that's
that's the most important part of it if
i have a good idea for a speed challenge
i'll do it for sure
um so don't be don't be afraid if you
want to see them
second comment says hey etho i really
like your videos but one thing is making
me
sad why aren't you working on the nexus
it is my favorite project that you're
doing but you aren't doing it anymore
for the 401 episode can you please work
on it yes we are going to get back to
that
really soon i just have had
so much off camera stuff i've had to do
with it like it takes so much time that
project
it's the biggest it's by far the biggest
survival project i've ever done in this
game
um but we're just about at the point
where we can work on it again
so i'll try push through just a little
bit more
and we can get started on uh the next
step to it
third comment it says hey etho i really
like your videos
no that's the second one hey
etho what was your favorite pro protest
project you ever did including real life
and other series
that you have done oh also congrats on
reaching 400 episodes you are awesome
etho
thank you very much i'm going to answer
in minecraft my favorite project
not the nexus nexus is fun and cool and
all that stuff
but i would have to say my 50k
subscriber special if you guys weren't
satisfied with today's episode i hope
you enjoyed it
but if you wanted a little bit more
maybe you haven't seen
the 50k special so i'm going to link it
in the description that's the canon run
video i did a long time ago
and uh maybe you'll enjoy that
anyway i had a lot of fun today guys i
hope you did too
there's one last thing i've been waiting
to do
for so long and i finally get to do it
today
you've all wanted to see what's behind
the door
i better make the daytime for this too
make sure you can see it so today let's
let's check it out
no more games no more tricks
here's another door what's behind this
door well
it is uh what you might expect