[Music]
Hey how's it going everybody this is Sol
and welcome back once again to the let's
play series mini mushroom farm
oh man still works kind of maybe so I
thought of an interesting thing maybe to
bring up your little conversation piece
for a long time in my life I had this
idea this perspective that's there were
people with just natural talent in
certain areas like naturally born
artists and naturally born musicians and
I wasn't one of them so I kind of had
this impression for a long long time
that I could never be good at music I
could never be good at arts and I'm
still not to this day but I've realized
more recently that it's it's not that I
can't be good at these things it's that
I haven't put forth the effort to learn
them I I think anybody can learn them to
a certain degree anyway just by putting
effort until actually learning them and
I think the the time that actually
started changing with me is when I start
playing minecraft because a lot of what
you do in Minecraft is like building
things and then looking at them and
deciding if you like them or not and
then comparing them with other things I
used to see like stuff people built in
Minecraft and I would hide you like oh I
like that but I didn't know why and now
most of the time I can answer why I like
that or why something is better than
than something else so I feel to a
certain extent I've learned arts may be
the bare basics right but it's learn
about right even like colors before I
start playing minecraft I could not put
colors together at all and now I have
some idea of how to do it right with
music you know I thought there were
people that were just naturally gifted
it they have perfect pitch you know I've
heard things that if you don't learn
perfect pitch before you're 8 years old
that you'll you'll never be able to
learn it but I've seen things now that
it's like people with perfect pitch it's
not actually something that necessarily
makes them better at music it's just an
ability they have and it all comes down
to effort basically that's my
perspective now you guys can disagree
with me in the comments maybe there is
some natural affinity or talents
associated with becoming among the best
in the world I think in general anybody
can learn something right uh-huh
anyways there is actually a point to all
this there's a reason I'm bringing it up
it's not very profound though but
basically I've been trying to learn
music theory lately putting forth an
effort into that with very little effort
I feel I've learned like a lot of the
basics which I'm happy about like you
know if all the notes and C's sound good
together why don't we play everything
and see stuff like that like I've learnt
that learnt a little bit about reading
notes like I knew how to play tabs on a
guitar for a long time I can memorize
music right but I can't actually I
didn't actually know how the notes were
laid out on the guitar stuff like that
so I've been trying to learn all that
and while looking at like how to compose
music I was looking at some cave story
music to see why I like it and we're
trying to figure that out I ended up
adding a cave story song to the
Minecraft here that's that's the reason
for this long explanation anyways here
it is aha so if you're wondering what
that is that's moon song from cave story
just the like part of the melody I
didn't do the full song or anything like
that ah let's get to some of the
mechanics here so to play the song we
just opened the trapdoor activates an
observer here and then stop it we close
it
it'll keep playing on a loop as long as
that trap door is open like endlessly
and the range is actually pretty good I
didn't hear it all the way over here
which is cool once you get like out here
though it goes quiet like when we
transition from the rooms so that worked
out pretty good I would say yeah it just
start over here listen to this part
that's coming up I'll tell you when
right here you see it went like
high-pitched and then it drops an octave
that's a problem I don't really know how
to deal with
let's let's let this finish you see the
redstone turns on here and then I move a
piston out of the way to stop it this
isn't the mechanism for starting
starting and stopping it
the observers up over there uh-huh but
yeah in I find like a lot of the songs I
try to put into Minecraft the melody
alone usually goes over three octaves
and minecraft only allows you to do two
octaves like that's the range of pitches
just twenty-four different notes we need
like 36 piano has seven octaves in total
so if you want like full control of
music that's kind of what I'm hoping
they might change it to eventually now
that there's options for more blocks in
Minecraft maybe more data kind of hoping
they'd redo note blocks and give them a
better interface and stuff so that we
can have more range more instruments and
one thing I've seen done in texture
packs that I think is a really good idea
like you see the note here then the
music note but it doesn't say like is it
an a a B a C or D that's something they
could have done really easily that's
some texture packs do I'm kind of hoping
they change that because it's really
hard to actually encode a song in
Minecraft without knowing what letter
the the note is you have to go by pitch
or by Counting which is really annoying
anyways let's move on here we're gonna
work on the mastermind game some more
today and call me crazy you know that
ethos thing I start a project I leave it
I come back I leave its I come back
something about this one though I really
am determined to finish it like all in
one shot here I don't know why I guess I
want to see it working right so we've
built a lot of the components to our
mastermind game here now we're kind of
at the point where we got most of the
important stuff built but we got to
start linking it together to finalize it
to actually get all the pieces working
together like a big puzzle that's
intertwined bad analogy do that that
makes sense okay anyways so one thing
I've done now is that added these water
streams
on both sides here these connect the
code randomizer to the part of the of
the game here that handles the logic so
you know that ice stream thing so
basically let's just show that we got
our random code thing here purple blue
orange red right we hit this button it
randomizes the new code so we'll do that
at the start of the game it'll make a
random code that we can't see that we
have to guess inside here I put some
concrete powder now and basically when
we press this button over here at the
start of the game this is gonna happen
as well we eject some concrete powder
out of those shell core boxes and they
go into the water streams on both sides
here and then they end up at the ice
stream below up over here so this is our
code green green yellow orange I just
wondered did I mirror that by accidents
so it was I gotta make sure
so it's green green yellow orange what
does that thing say here green green
orange yellow oh so I got the yellow and
orange mixed up how did I do that the
green and the green might be mixed up to
you then because they're both the same I
can't tell ya I'll have to fix that
because they should line up with each
other according to what we see on the
code there but that'll get them down
there right so that's all good I had to
do something here with upside down
stairs we're using these to align the
blocks because I realized something I
had like an item on one side of the
block here and I was realizing when I
was sending another item down the other
side they don't actually join together
they don't stack which is what we use in
our logic part of the game so in order
to make sure the item ends up like in
the middle we use some some stairs here
so when it's going this way the stair
stops it like instead of going all the
way to over here it stops it like that
over here and then again this way it
stops it this way so instead of going
all the way over to here
all the way over to here so it ends up
like right in the middle of this block
when it falls down and it falls straight
down it doesn't slide on the ice so
that's that's the way we're doing that
um you know I might just do this lazy
way I don't want to redo the whole
stream so we'll do it like this we'll
just instead of this stream going up and
around this way we'll make it go through
here and connect over here and then this
one we will run a nice stream across
this way and down okay
okay that'll work so every one of these
it's different color so we got green
orange red blue green orange red blue
okay so let's send this down I think I
got it switched now properly but I
realize there's one more thing that
needs to line up okay so we got red
going down there I'm blue going down
there so it's blue red orange green if
we look down here we got blue red orange
green so that's the right order but we
also got to make sure so our switcheroo
was good there good stuff good stuff so
we also got to make sure our input lines
up too so if we enter blue red orange
green it needs to line up with the
answer there but also the input down
below there or our logic right so oh
yeah I got a jump here we jump that'll
break it and send it down so now ideally
we should see them stacked together yeah
we got two blue to red to orange and two
green so everything stacked together
like it was supposed to yeah so that
should be good they're all lining up
like they're supposed to now there is
something else we got to add to this
though like those items if we leave them
for five minutes they're gonna despawn
right so what we got to do is refresh it
and that's why we built it this way so
every time we press this we can refresh
it right well not quite we got to add
one more
mechanism because these are gonna stack
together with what we have down there
already the problem is like they'll keep
ending up in the same spot problem is
though if we have an item here and let's
say it's on the ground for 4 minutes and
50 seconds items de-spawn in 5 minutes
in 10 seconds it's gonna despawn if we
add another orange to this it doesn't
reset it to 5 minutes it's still gonna
despawn in 10 seconds so just by adding
more items to the stack here isn't
refreshing the code we actually have to
like remove these and then put new ones
there okay so I just added a mechanism
for this to remove these so that we can
drop new ones down and have the timer
reset so I was gonna do something with
pistons and I realized oh yeah just a
hopper minecart can pull items through
blocks that's probably the easiest thing
to do so if we make your round cross
here it'll pick up all the items above
and now we can drop down the new ones
mm-hmm all right so we got we got some
more stuff done here there were a bunch
of wires like in the middle of this
platform and I've moved them over I had
to redo a bunch of the redstone but like
those wires are over there before we got
it moved over so now I was able to
extend this a bit more and it feels like
we actually have a nice polished
starting area without a bunch of wires
in our face you know so that's all good
I've added a mechanism on the side here
for our our white and black peg displays
so there's a dropper up there somewhere
storing a bunch of items yeah up over
there which funnel into those hoppers
and they all kind of funneled down to
about there but then we need some way of
getting the items back up to the top
there to make it a complete cycle and I
was gonna do it manually but I decided
to add an automatic system for it here
so basically what we're gonna do is have
a storage minecarts it gets held in
place there by this block that can be
retracted with a piston and basically I
think I fill this up yeah
oh it's gonna be hard to do it though
with my inventory so full yard some more
items so basically the items in this
hopper will funnel into the storage
minecarts yeah they're going in there
good and then when this storage minecart
gets filled up of stone or whatever junk
item we want to use then we send it off
to unload at the top there oh I'm
stuttering what's going on let's put the
rest of that in okay and it fully filled
up so this comparator turns on with a
power of 15 and this one since this
lever is on right it has a power of 15
and it since to subtract mode so 15
minus 15 from this one is zero which
causes the piston to retract and then it
goes up here and it starts unloading the
storage minecarts this turns on which
holds it in place a ton powers a power
rail over here and as long as there's
items flowing through this hopper it
stays there until this kind of all fills
up in this empties uh-huh all right so
some of this stuff is actually getting a
little bit tricky for me I'm gonna try
my best to explain the problems here so
I'm working on the logic part of this
right now like how many black pegs
should be awarded and how do how do we
do it
so let's say our guess here is blue it
lines up with that so we're supposed to
get a black peg awarded for that right
how do we actually detect that is a
problem I thought we could use the
pressure plate in the back here to do
that like if it goes over top but we're
awarding the black page if it's stacks
not if it gets to here like if it
doesn't stack it'll get to the pressure
plate so basically we're not detecting
if it hits the pressure plate we're
detecting if it doesn't hit the pressure
plates how do you do that it's a lot
harder because if it doesn't statue
don't hit the pressure plate right
that so I think what we gotta do is
maybe have another set of pressure
plates I think we need like another one
here and if this one gets activated but
this one doesn't then we award the black
peg I think is the idea that's what I'm
gonna try to do so I was gonna do
something with pistons here and I'm
realizing this is just nasty so I'm
gonna redo it let's see we don't have a
lot of space to work with either here's
the problem because I've added in this
rail here and it's gonna get in the way
I think I kind of have an idea of what
we need to do what we need to do though
so right above here is that pressure
plate we just put down I think we need
like a redstone torch this doesn't
matter and we got to like run it under
the rail now because it's in the way
so you're on it under here and we'll
need some kind of delay because we got
to wait for it to hit the other pressure
plates let's just put that there and yet
another one of these and somehow run it
up to here I guess we could use a slab
and then change this to a slab I
sometimes use notebooks for testing like
if I can't see what's happening I have
to go by sound so I think we're gonna
have to have a redstone torch here we
kind of we're making like a NAND gate I
guess ok so we run the signal up here so
if this redstone torch turns on that
means we award a black peg I think let's
try this out I'm stuck down here
oh okay so let's test this before those
despawn if we can so we're gonna throw a
blue in here which should line up right
and quickly quickly before they do spawn
so let's see if that happens oh we heard
the note okay that's good okay so this
time we're gonna do it again but we're
not using blue we're gonna use a
different color so it won't stack and no
no block plate okay so that's good cuz
we're not supposed to get a black peg if
they don't stack so that does exactly
what we want
basically yeah if this gets powered
again from that second pressure plate it
prevents this torch from switching
alright I might be losing my voice a
little bit now fast forward a couple
hours in time here I've been working on
it non-stop red stone projects you know
they they tend to drag on a little bit
they make it a little bit tricky that
when you're trying to finish them but
here's what I've been working on now
basically I'll show you how I've been
testing this it's actually pretty pretty
annoying but basically I've been
matching the color code here alright and
then I activate this and run down here
as quickly as I can and make sure this
wire pulse is 4 times because all four
of those lined up so we should get four
black pegs and this wire runs over to
here so we got the black peg logic
figured out now I think it's I think
it's all good this goes up to the
dropper which shoots those garbage items
into our display yeah I think that's
good let's try this again
let's let's watch this actually ok blue
purple orange
man I'm really tired I said this was
blue din and I okay let's watch the
display so this should all move forward
by one - I think yeah and it added four
again because we match for like we like
we're supposed to there what happens if
we just like match - so only green and
purple are gonna match up yeah testing
stuff takes a long time because you
gotta make sure everything works so why
did we get 300 that wasn't supposed to
happen okay wait a minute wait a minute
make sure it wasn't a fluke
so again we should only get one one two
three four one two don't oh wait a
minute wait a minute
so this is what determines when to move
the display and I realized it's
activating before the items flow into
the display aha
so let's try this one more time and buy
one more time I mean for the hundredth
time okay one two three four and that
happened before this switched taste that
turns oh come on
oh snap okay I think I got to figure it
out kind of it's this has been driving
me crazy and it's a weird game mechanic
I have never seen so I'll try show it to
you here I got four green down so only
one of them should stack watch the green
watch a green in the back there it
didn't happen okay it's inconsistent as
well so that's that's making this even
more fun let's reset this we'll try it
one more time if we get lucky it'll
happen this time
okay so it resets get the items down
again
and we'll drop another four green man I
don't know what to do about this one two
three four
quickly quickly hey let's watch it again
watch the green yeah you see that it
stole it
oh man that's what's been causing all
the confusion of course I'm up there so
I can't see it happening right mm-hmm
okay so I have a theory here correct me
if I'm wrong yes I think the rule is the
stack with more items absorbs the one
with less so if this has one and this
stack has two this stack will absorb the
one with one and since the one with two
has a momentum it's gonna keep moving
right yeah so that's kind of what we
expected now if this has two and this
has one it'll stay put because the
stationary one absorbs the moving one
okay so it's got three in there right
now if we go for four absorbs three so
the moving one should keep moving
not quite sure what happens when they're
equal it seems to stay put most of the
time anyways guys I hate to do it to you
but I think we're gonna have to wrap up
episode 4 today we're kinda out of time
here and honestly I wasted a lot of time
off-camera like trying to get that to
work today lots of bug fixing and lots
of things went wrong there I wanted to
get that finish but looks like we're
gonna have to spend some more time or
off-camera time on it I can't get it
done today after all but yeah anyways
we're gonna get into some deep lore some
background information you might not
know etho subjects von sway here we go
so the other day engineer Xtreme generic
be stream I complimented his base by
saying your face looks very once way
generic be very exalted responded this
is not von sway ethos stole it from me I
was intrigued so I kept pushing the
button for days
until finally he said one day peccary he
thought came to me we invented it and
the next day he called it von sway it's
not von sway oh by the way a generic
being and me we always tease each other
so don't get the wrong idea on the tone
here he's probably just teasing is von
sway a lie
please etho me and a small portion want
to hear your side of the story
hashtag von sway is real so I'm gonna
tell you my side of the story as I know
it's I'm gonna start off by saying it's
definitely true it would not be called
von sway without too generic be now when
you guys watched the old mindcrack
videos you probably watched like one or
two three or four of us right you didn't
watch the whole server like everybody on
the server probably but a lot of our
videos were really intertwined it's like
we often referenced each other in some
way so I think the very first time I
used the term von sway was during the
goood house prank writes but the reason
I referenced it to begin with was
because a few weeks before that I think
generic B did a video on the topic of
fun I can't even say it
feng shui Fung Shui I think that's right
right so it's a Chinese decorating term
or something anyways in his video he was
talking about how his wife was getting
into the Feng Shui and like decorating
their house and stuff and I watched that
video so it was it was on my mind so
when we were doing the house prank and
we were like stupidly trying to describe
all our fancy stuff like the Persian
rugs and whatever in the house I thought
of the term that that generic be thought
or that generic piece and I thought it
sounded really fancy right Fung Shui
right so I was like okay I'll say that
to describe the house and I ended up
saying von sway because I didn't know
how to pronounce it
that's her von sway came from and since
I used the
incorrectly like I pronounced it wrong
von sway and it ended up referring to
that weird building style that we did in
the the good prank right kind of the
idea of a crazy building style and since
then I think after that we did it again
when we pranked generic B and we did von
sway again where we just like put down
random blocks or whatever and then later
I kind of changed it again like with the
fool craft series and that that sort of
thing uh-huh
I think I got that right anyways that's
my side of the story on on von sway how
it kind of came to be and I think we're
gonna wrap up here so thank you for
watching hope you enjoyed it and until
next time take care have a wonderful day
bye bye
[Music]