all right so what do we got here what is
this dear etho hey that's me now that
you finally got the Nexus operational
what projects will you be doing instead
to fill that void Oh
oh that's a good question I bet you a
lot of people are wondering that but
don't worry guys I have I big I have big
plans in mind big ideas I have something
very exciting planned for this episode
a lot of people wonder etho what is the
secret to fishing I'll tell you what the
secret is it's patience a lot of
patience apparently come on where's my
fish finally oh my goodness can you
believe it that was a leader three
fishing rod on top of it I'm sorry if
you wanted to see me fish I just can't
handle it guys
it's not going to happen I'm only human
that's not what we're doing today
instead I decided to try updating to the
latest snapshot again so we're rocking
the 15 W 35 B and I've just been going
around my world here a little bit
playing around with some of the new
features again like the shield's let's
see I wanted to make a yellow one here
I've also been testing to see how stable
this snapshot is and so far it seems
pretty good actually my frame rates
decent haven't encountered any bugs or
things acting differently than I'm used
to so pretty happy about that I'm
planning on keeping this version from
now on unless I encounter some really
serious error I do have a backup just in
case I need to fix something but yeah I
was trying to copy over my shield to a
banner which you can apparently do but
it's got to be the same color of shield
as the banner so this says yellow banner
at the top that's the base color so if
you do it on lime or on white or
anything else doesn't work you got to
use a yellow shield and bam there it is
alright so let's check this out put
there or alternatively you don't have to
do that you can just press F yeah there
we go got to get used to it I'm not used
to this whole double dual wielding thing
yet okay so this is our banner how does
this compare Oh
I hold right-click does it show oh yeah
there we go aha
so they're they're actually pretty
similar but the shield doesn't seem to
be as detailed does it what do you think
ciao you're cross-eyed you don't know
all right all right well I was just
checking out a few more things here and
something really caught my attention
they rebalanced
although the tools and the weapons and
when you hover over it with your mouse
now it actually tells you the attack
speed as well as the damage I think it
just told you the damage before so if we
look let's look at the wood tools here
first so one point two and two for the
pick one and two point five for the
shovel 0.9 and seven for the the axe you
know the axe actually looks pretty
decent as a as a combat weapon like
compare the axe to the sword this is
only for tech damage compared to seven
but the sword has better speed so that's
kind of the big thing there but the the
hoe is really interesting it's won and
won all the gold tools have the same
stats as the wood tool so it's basically
the same if you hop over to the stone
now look at what the hoe does it goes 1
and 1 and then 2 and 1 3 and 1 4 and 1
so it goes up by one for each for the
speed all these other things they'll go
up by attack damage not by speed so that
the the wood tier is one point two and
two then it goes three attack damage for
five so it goes up by one for each and
then these again it goes up by one on
attack damage 8 9 10 4 5 6 7
so the hoes only one that goes up by
attack speed so if you could apply a
sharpness effect to a hoe it would
probably be the best weapon just because
it's got that speed boost as well but as
far as I know you still can't put
enchantments on
oh right yeah it's just exit out right
away does this tell you the change oh it
does tell you the change after or in the
anvil itself so it goes from seven to
ten point seven five with sharpness
three think each level of sharpness
increases it by one point two five is
that right
yeah uh-huh but the tack speed stays the
same
oops I noticed like with enchanted picks
and and regular picks the attack speed
stays the same efficiency doesn't make
it faster anything like that one thing I
was wondering you know the gold tools
always had that a special ability of
being faster miners than than other
tools I wonder if that's all the same
good I think that the speed the tack
speed only applies to combat not
actually harvesting right that's wood
oh yeah it's still fast ah very good
very good okay so I was curious about
something guys I got out my calculator
here I was trying to figure out in like
straight DPS damage per second how the
sword and the axe actually compare and
in general like if you don't factor in
shields swords basically win except for
the wood and gold tier they don't do as
much damage as the axe in DPS but then
at stone and plus the sword is better
and here's why this is what's
interesting about it so if you compare
the tack damage at the wood level sword
is for the X is seven seven divided by
four you'll find the axes 1.75 times
stronger than the sword but as you go
down the line as they get stronger um if
you look at the diamond tier 10 divided
by seven that's no longer 1.75 the ratio
becomes closer and closer together and
if you look at the max possible like
that the diamond axe for example it does
ten attack damage so that's our base ten
damage plus annoying music
6.25 you can get from sharpness 5 every
level adds 1.25 and then in addition you
can also get 6 damage from a strength to
potion now they rebounce rebounce those
so that equals do I fail math I think
that's 20 2.25 for the axe now the sword
is 19.2 5 because it does 3 damage less
and that ratio is much closer together
that works out to I figured it out my
calculator already about 1.15 times
stronger than the sword compared to the
1.75 we started with so as you get a
better weapon the sword gets better and
better in comparison to the to the axe
umm but that doesn't factor in the
attack speed either if you look at DPS
it's 0.9 compared to 1.45 so assuming
that means 1.45 divided by 0.9 is how
much you have to adjust it which is 1.6
1 1 I like this kind of stuff guys I'm
sorry the sword gets a 1.6 1 1 x boost
over the ax so yeah at the max the 19.2
5 yet you times it by the 1.6 one one
was its yeah and that's higher than the
22 points to 5 or whatever anyway so
interesting when you factor in the
attack speed at the would tear the DPS
of the ax is actually better than the
sword so it's like just in general
better at the stone tier if you factor
in the tack speed it's eight point zero
five attack damage so they're basically
the same except you know obviously it's
better to only have to attack a guy once
instead of twice like you might need to
with a sword so I would still pick a
stone axe over a stone sword beyond that
you know it's the ax still has a pretty
strongly
I would say but it gets less and less as
the damage goes up the thing about the
AK so apparently they made it so if you
hit a guy and he has a shield out it
will stun the shield for five seconds so
they can't use it to block your attack
so what you would want to do like if you
have a high damage axe and high damage
sword is just tap them once with axe and
switch over to your sword and finish
them off with that if they're like in
the same same league as each other that
would be the ideal but another really
interesting thing I thought is they
buffed weakness potions as well so it's
- for attack damage now instead of the
zero point or I think it was one one
attack damage they reduced before so if
you hit someone with a weakness potion
they're using a wood sword for example
they'll do no damage to you compared to
the three damage he would do with an X
and then one two four two two five three
two six you know um income oh wait I got
that messed up anyway
in comparison the weakness potions have
a much bigger effect on someone using a
sword than an axe and just one more
thing I wanted to show you guys and
we'll do something else is I was curious
about the attack speed what this number
actually means and if you if you attack
with a weapon like let's take the axe
for example when I left click it takes
it a little bit of time you see that for
it to get fully charged up back in its
normal position like so you can still
spam click though if you want but it
does very little damage if you don't
wait for it to fully charge up and every
weapon has a different speed like if you
look at the hole for example look how
fast that that gets ready between
attacks it's like almost instant
compared to the the axe here right
so I actually figured out the numbers
for a single attack with the pick these
are the diamond tools I checked is zero
point six six seven seconds the shovel
is 0.833
x zero point nine three three swords
zero
point six zero zero and the ho is zero
point two three three
well anyways guys the main thing I
wanted to play around with today is
actually those course fruits so we have
to go get some and to get them we have
to kill the Ender Dragon again and
before I do that I'm getting rid of this
beacon because if you remember that last
fight she totally destroyed it all my
precious emerald blocks I want to get
these out of the way before that she
didn't spawn when I entered the end this
time so I think I actually have to
manually do it now
okay here we go we're going to summon
the ender dragon and I want to see what
happens with these towers I believe they
made it so they respawn now and in a
uniform way so right now they're kind of
chaotically placed around the end
there's all different heights and stuff
different sizes let's see what happens
does this work even did they change it
can I not summon the ender dragon Oh hmm
and here we go oh it does work okay I
was not actually expecting it to J so
she is spawning in towers yeah look at
this oh do I have to break the beacons
on top Oh some of them are shorter than
others okay it's not all the same yeah
the crystals are back I suck with the
bow um all right we gotta get rid of all
the heals
oh I got her with that even Oh who's hit
who's hitting I didn't even see what hit
me there
was it the dragon breath did she get me
with that I was going to try to get some
of this stuff to by Jan I have to stand
in it
no I don't and very good
it disappears kind of as I picked it up
here - okay okay we got to focus on her
a little bit that one has a cage on it
that's gonna be tricky
why can I not hit it there we go Oh Oh
is it every time I break a crystal that
it spawns the dragon breath oh no it's
those those fireballs there I see oh no
no I didn't mean it I didn't mean it
don't kill me please don't kill me oh
you're doing funny teleports please just
stop oh I'm spam clicking that's why
it's not working
oh and quick you'll okay I forgot I
can't spam quick Diddy more gotta like
oh I did it wrong again you got a light
hit them and then you gotta wait before
attacking again that's why the sword is
is good actually I guess because if you
miss your attack you're in big trouble
oh oh oh please just leave me alone a
second I'm really hurting the fight is
significantly more difficult now all
right Dragon's Breath okay I'm starting
to spot them a little easier there's a
lot of dragon's breath got it okay
got that one I think the only ones I
have left are in the cage maybe there is
a delay on enderpearls now oh that was a
bad throw you cannot reach that high
apparently or you have to stand maybe
you guys stand like right at it you
might have to be do like an absolutely
perfect throw to get up top no I can't
reach it
huh I'm fine everything's good it's got
a way to set in here dragon's breath
if I I go up like five blocks or so I
should be able to enderpearl though and
try one more time oh yes
but how do I break these without dying
you know what I mean oh ah she knocked
me off of it well I opened up the cage I
guess if you open up the kg and shoot it
then right tough oh I did do it I got it
okay so if you break the bar open you
can shoot it from the ground might take
a few shots that's possible
alright I'm going to try this don't
knock me off to buck me off don't let me
off okay I made it up break it I'm not
going to destroy it
I'm gonna enter pearl down try shoot it
from the ground I think that's the best
way of doing it if you break those up
close I think they'll kill you a little
bit higher seems about right
gotta get lucky oh I got it sweets got
it
she she intercepted it she's like now
bodyguard move oh come on
there we go that one was a little bit
tricky
Oh Dragons Marez is that all the cages
did I get everything watching her for a
second she doesn't like to oh wait a
second and denied so when she goes above
the portal you can't shoot her I think
that's a really good it gets really loud
too I think that's a really good change
you can do melee damage he'll it looks
like
she is mad she's really mad and then she
tries to do the dragon's breath on you
and yes but she's aiming the wrong way
she's staying longer this time that I'm
attacking her it's like she knows she'd
be getting hit
I mean year by day now she took out yet
she's not gonna turn around it's alright
I'll do it this way
woohoo okay that was actually a lot more
fun than any other ender dragon fight
I've done it's way better now still
could use a few more tweaks which I'm
sure they'll do like when she hovers
over the middle they're really easy to
do damage cuz she doesn't like spin and
try to attack you once you're here but
if they added that in I think it would
be pretty much perfect now so the portal
spawned in the middle do I still have my
other portal over here she didn't wreck
this right yeah she seems to like still
stay near the middle so even though I
got stuff built over here she didn't
really go in and wreck it
my old portal is gone though this is
where it was which kind of sucks
because I had a few things set up like I
had my ender pearl mover set up with
this and the musical portal will have to
be moved this rail line I don't really
use anymore so I don't I don't care so
much about it okay so from that fight we
did get some dragon's breath we got 19
of it you need that to make lingering
potions now so I wanted to get some of
that there was no dragon egg this time I
just realized like usually it spawns
right on top there nothing there this
time we do have one from the original
fight though so I'm not too worried
about that and it looks like our our
teleporter is over here
I'm gonna go through that I'm gonna go
get some chorus fruits we're not going
to go to the dungeon this time though
hey weren't the first time right I had
trouble with that last time no I'm stuck
in uh-oh oh I might need to real aughh
I'm going to try reloading hopefully
that fixes it otherwise I'm stuck in
void space right now
yup that did the trick everything is
good
so our teleporter is right here let's
set up a torch trail so I don't get lost
like I like I tend to do and I'm just
going to go through here and collect as
much of this as I can carry
whoa and I'll try get some of the
flowers to so we can actually plant some
in the overworld well I tell you what
everybody I gotta say I'm really
impressed with the snapshot like even
more than I was expecting
cuz I tried that one a couple weeks ago
and that had me worried it had crashes
it had bugs it had many issues this one
you know I haven't seen a problem yet so
far and I'm finding I am even getting
better frame rates now than I was in 1.8
like I went to the nether you know my
another helper I got the blinking lights
was getting a much smoother frame rate -
there even with the sand cannon thing
jumping around this used to just it used
to just stutter like crazy right now
it's it's pretty smooth I gotta say and
even the rendering seems smoother like
the animation of that flying through the
air I don't think it was that good
before pretty happy but anyways dragon
fight was cool - I thought that was much
better but I wanted to try something
with the chorus fruits like they let you
teleport like an Enderman right that's
the thing with them I'm wondering how
impossible is it if we just have a
single block we can teleport to
Enderman they teleport 32 blocks on all
three axes right so right now I believe
the only places we can go is right there
so let's try this out okay nom nom nom
I'll put us on the floor really huh okay
that's not what I was expecting because
that is over 32 blocks high maybe it
fail-safes to the ground then the fish
it doesn't find a spot what happens if
you do it in the water I wonder because
Enderman they don't like water rights oh
I put me in a cave hey it failed that
time I've never seen it fail before put
me right by the water but not in it down
in a cave again Oh in the wheat field
and I didn't trampled the crop either I
don't think that's that's interesting
uh-huh this is a this is a pretty fun
mechanic oh hey okay down in the cave
with the zombie villager you know this
is all supposed to be lit up and
apparently we found a spot that isn't
uh-huh
back up here oh we're in the the long
tunnel now okay back up by the tree it's
like you never know what you're gonna
get
that's pretty cool I was thinking maybe
you could make a way of transporting
with these like if you could isolate it
so you only have one spot to teleport to
and then you close off the spot where
you started so you can't teleport back
you could actually make a road but I
don't know how to make it so you don't
teleport to the ground like that
okay well I decided let's try this one
more time I went even higher in the sky
now so we're 175 at the y-coordinate and
since I was up here I decided to try out
the 32 chunk render distance you know
what it's not bad actually before when I
would use the 32 chunk my game which is
like all the time right now it takes a
really long time for the chunks to load
it seems to do it as it can but it my
framerate doesn't drop terribly as it's
loading them it still really smooth the
whole time so I kind of like that
actually I think once everything is
loaded then it's fine but I shall don't
see any more chunks loading it might be
done anyways let's see if we can get to
that block or if we get back to the
floor back to the floor really all right
so well not much we can do then oh no no
no he's gonna blow he didn't blow up yes
excellent so I made some of this pop
course free
gives you XP when you when you take it
out of the furnace to make bricks out of
it oh yeah wait what did it wow it
actually gave me two stacks of bricks
okay I wasn't expecting that I'll have
to remember how to make the other blocks
but yeah I want to build the Nexus out
of these most likely I think is like
this yeah that makes the pillars very
cool so I want to farm up a bunch of
that stuff we will probably play around
with that more another day though
mmm-hmm very cool slabs I think there's
stairs and stuff as well I did want to
check out the lingering potions so I did
make some healing ones I I just had an
idea though we should try make some
weakness ones in hard mode zombies these
fools placed I couldn't wait a second
you're the perfect
peste candidate here and now he's gonna
die isn't he come on come attack me they
do four attack damage in hard mode I
believe so they should be perfectly
nullified with these weakness potions so
II shouldn't people attack me yeah look
at this does no damage now that's so
cool is this like spazzing out all right
let's make some lingering weakness
potions so that's what the dragon's
breath is all about where is my potions
over here yeah okay I should be some
here we'll oh oh man this is all
automatic I forgot okay let's take this
over here just do it like that just get
three of them anyway and put the
redstone back inside I looked at my lab
here umm I was reading some recipes
might have changed with brewing but like
these aren't messed up now
last time I I did the snapshot all my
potions got messed up now they seem to
be working so we didn't lose our
existing batch they all converted
properly and that oh it turned it down
to one minutes so it was four before now
it's only one minute interesting this
doesn't have a time the health potion
okay well that's as let's go outside I
think you should be nighttime by now the
idea is if there's an undead monster if
you throw a health potion I think it'll
just kill it right if they walk into it
we will see I want to check that out
I still have weakness from when I threw
it at the zombie okay
oh don't want creepers leave us alone
creepers that's all I'm seeing there's
always a ton of monsters in my desert
here okay skeleton let's try to find a
few more guys though
mmm have they not spawned yet places
generally just crawling with them okay
they should be showing up now yeah here
they come
okay so I'm gonna throw except there's a
zombie in there okay so I can actually
one shot
creepers with my axe here this is a 15
attack damage if I do a crit it will one
shot on my found oh did I mess that up
there we go so that was the one I didn't
hit okay here we go here we go lingering
healing potion get rekt
let me get healed zombies they'll track
you they'll walk right into it okay not
as effective as I thought I thought it
would just like instantly kill lemon and
keep me alive but I guess not
weakness potions don't work on skeletons
right you know I should probably heal up
alright get some food in me if we do a
weakness potion let's say we have a ton
of zombies chasing us if we just do it
in front they'll walk into it and they
won't be able to get us any that are
tracking us okay and I really got to get
used to using the shield I haven't
really played around with it but
apparently you can block a skeleton shot
with it hey you
oh if you're good
Oh am i doing it wrong I must be doing
it wrong
oh there we go okay it's a little more
tricky to do than I was expecting but
there's gonna be method to it right oh
I'm very bad I've locked one I don't
know how I did that
oh you just got to hold it out really I
thought you had to time it yeah you just
hold it out The Thorn still takes effect
even through the shield even though I
took all the damage in the shield there
yeah it's kind of interesting all right
let's try weakness this fool yeah
doesn't apply to arrows mm-hmm second
one shot pretty much everything with
this axe if I do a crit
ah-ha very cool and if you spam click
obviously nothing really happens it's
gonna take a lot of hits to kill
something you still can kill them but it
takes a lot all right everybody's so we
should probably wrap things up here for
today's episode last episode we worked
on the Nexus I was squashing bugs fixing
the mistakes I made and in the process I
actually created a few new bugs that I
had to find and squish and yeah this
comment though kind of gave me a good
laugh as a result it says 47 bugs in the
code take one out patch it around 278
bugs in the code so true so very true
uh-huh
anyways guys thanks you thank you for
watching hope you enjoyed it I'll see
you in the next one
take care bye bye
you