[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho holy smokes that
was some lag
uh today
we're gonna do a bit of testing with
things uh first of all i put the
water stream back there i i know i
removed it last time but
without it they just weren't entering
the blocks like they
were before so put it back
um and i'll have to just deal with the
leg they create when they're jumping up
and down
and hopefully that gets patched sometime
soon where it doesn't
cause crazy amounts of lag
um yeah we're going to go
do something with the turtle first of
all
had it very close to complete last
episode but we never did
get the silverfish out
so what what i need to do first is
replace these blocks
with either half slabs or stairs a lot
of people said to wait
until the sandstone stairs come out
which is probably what i'll use
when this is all done but i want it up
and working already so i'm just going to
use
stone brick or something that does not
match at all just to get the function
there
because i want to see if this works or
not
let's test it out i sort of suspect i
messed up there
but we will see um
yeah silverfish farms running again so
we're we're getting new ones in here
this whole we got almost two rows now
okay
uh let's head down
get them into the tunnel
okay so go to the middle let them track
you you can hear they're right above
move around a bit to get in the corner
they should come to
[Music]
here
yeah the thing about using stairs
i i realize this afterwards it's going
to leave
an extra gap that they'll probably be
able to fit through
because it no longer this bottom no
longer connects to the block
so they can probably yep dang
all right well you know what i'll do i'm
just gonna
i'm gonna replace all the iron bars with
glass i think that's
that will be a full block no
complications
yeah lose a little bit of space but
hopefully it's okay
we'll try it again here uh the glass
actually looks
not too bad i thought it would be worse
but it that is going to lower the amount
of space they have
okay
i'm almost positive it'll work this time
though that's that's the important thing
come on guys let's go for a little
journey
and the point of all this is we're gonna
use these guys as digging machines they
or attempt to anyway they
you can dig blocks very quickly if you
have an army of silverfish
yes
here we go oh yeah this is the
glass tunnel it doesn't look bad hey i
don't think it's that bad
how do they keep up they seem to want to
jump when they go over the half slabs
that's weird
they're following us though so uh
after last episode i did a bunch of
grunt work around here i
uh what i all do i
harvested trees for about an hour or so
did a bunch of caving i harvested some
sand
and i also started working on that
tunnel
from the man cave to here
um which we'll probably check out today
and maybe
finish the rest of the blasting on it
and there's something else i want to try
out today too we're going to do some
experiments with the bed
i'm assuming we are you know i always
lose track of time when i'm making these
especially
like i should cut recording here because
this is taking a long time to do these
guys are a lot slower than i would like
them to be
and i say that now but in a vex map
they're they're way too fast
sweet so this is the first group of
silver fish
up to the surface and for the most part
everything above ground is you know it's
either covered in sand or covered in
dirt or or whatever grass
so we don't have to worry about them
getting in places we don't want them
for the most part you guys have trouble
swimming
looks like one guy went down
did he yeah they're not very good at
swimming
are they okay so i'm gonna take these
guys all the way to
actually you know what this is a small
batch it's pretty cool
i'm gonna get a bunch of these guys and
take them to
uh where i harvest my sand which is just
a little bit further that way
we got a bunch of stone exposed and
we're gonna let them
do their thing and see what happens
okay so this is going to be the main
test of all this
uh let's let's not mess this up
uh so i'm gonna make a ton of these guys
spawn
i hope
and then we'll transport them i got the
water in that
turtle now
[Music]
okay i don't wanna fall down there
don't want them to either dang
[Music]
yeah uh let's get the rest of these
gotta make sure they don't kill me or
anything like that too
okay that's probably enough that's
that's a lot of silverfish
so i'm gonna get out of here
and then go back down
i left the gate open oh
where'd they come from
oh man there was one more i saw there
okay let's not get too far away
uh get all these guys together
we'll see how they do in the tu in the
tunnel see if they have enough space
so when you get a larger load like this
they're going to spread out a lot more
and they might not want to follow us
there you are
how are they getting out
don't tell me i have a leak
dude if there's a leak again i'm gonna
lose it
seems like a water missing doesn't it
dang it
sounds like they're above why does it
sound like they're above
i'm sure i filled every every hole
unless they came from these i don't know
see i should really encase the this
strip with glass as well
as a oh safety now i
covered up my hole okay
uh the room is basically empty
get this last guy come on you're missing
the party
we'll open the gate just about punch
the glass that would have sucked
okay
so that is about close to a hundred
it's a fair bit
and i just want to see if the water
moves me too quick here
that they can't keep up or or what
oh i'm moving okay i'm going to slow
down a little bit here
give them a chance to catch up okay now
hands off the keyboard
i think it's too quick
yeah it's way too quick darn okay what i
could do
is put down slow sand as well
every every full block and that will
make it so i don't move so quick
but anyway you know how this goes i'm
going to bring them to the surface
and take them to that pit i'll do that
off camera
and then we'll continue on
okay we got a little problem we got a
big problem
oh okay um
help uh this
is uh when i got to the top
there were issues
dang it man
ah what do you do you know you can't
teleport out of that
ah damn
my armor like broke too i don't think
i'm getting that
i don't think i'm gonna get them out of
there
this is not going well at all
yeah they're gonna all despawn by the
time i get there
the only thing i can think of is trying
to make a mob evader for him
this long tunnel is not really that
great
like hmm because we lost about half of
them on the way
which isn't good either
if i try to go out there they'll just
kill me
yeah i don't know what to do
okay kill me tell me quick quick quick
quick
quick do it do it
i'm gonna run through their tunnel this
water is
a big problem
oh man this is uh
it's not going well
okay we'll go through here sprints
it's such a it doesn't seem like it'd be
such
a tough thing to get them to get them to
the surface but
there's a little bit complicated
okay get off ah come on
they're pushing me back i can't get up
at all
there we go come on
regen regen quick quick quick
yeah we lost like all of them from that
that sucks
oh boy
yeah the rest despawned
so we only got like 10
out of 70 or so wow
all right well i'm going to take them
there anyway
better than nothing
okay we're here so from our
our 80 silverfish that we started with
we got a total of six
all the way over here that's not a good
rate
um and we might lose a few here
yep no oh they knocked me off
great so we got four four here
i wanted to get like 200. um
dang
all right well i'll let them disperse
so i'll have to streamline that thing i
guess
i don't know rethink it so that did not
work
very good at all it was
not easy like i had hoped
but we got four here let's try to get a
few hundred
more and
yeah it'll be cool if i can get it
figured out
and working good but like it is right
now that's
not very useful for anything so
i'll think about it for a while and
most likely change my setup there but
we'll go
do something else today
we'll mess with the bed yeah let's head
back to that
that area there and do a few tests
well i've been thinking about it and
really the way i lost mostly silver fish
was from this top
part here not being very good
as i was making my way up it they
reached the end of their tunnel and
at about this point here a bunch of
silver fish started
just pouring down on my head and started
pushing me down the water
now i ender pearled i managed to get out
uh but then i ran back so that they
wouldn't despawn
and then they pushed me down this tunnel
and yeah you saw the rest so
what i should do is just build a little
room up here which keeps them separate
and have a date control on it so i can
let them out when i want
and that should solve the problem really
because that's how i lost at least half
of them i'm sure
and then the rest i lost had a creeper
explosion on the way and stuff like that
so maybe i'll put a bed up
top here too and i should widen this
like if it was three blocks i could
make a lot more fit through here at a
time
and i'll do the slow sand thing so i
will eat so i'll go up slower and
they'll be able to follow me better
but yeah that's that's the plan with
that
yeah so i got a little trick i want to
try out today with the beds i think
it'll work
um basically i usually keep my spawn
sent
my spawn set here
um so when i go through
the end portal and return i end up here
so you
there's this will work two ways if you
if you got your spawn set at a bed
you'll return at your bed
if if you don't have your spawn set at a
bed or your bed is obstructed
intent you will get sent back to
your the original spawn of the world
which it so happens is right
next to the man cave which is
a nice 800 block teleport or so from
here
um that would be pretty convenient to
take advantage of
so that's what we're going to try to do
we got to figure out
how to obstruct the bed i looked at the
wiki and there wasn't really a lot of
information about
how how the bed gets obstructed so we'll
have to do some tests ourselves
so we'll put a bed down here we'll set
our spawn and then we'll just keep
placing blocks around it until
it says our bed is obstructed and it's
it
spawns it spawns us at the original
spawn point in the world
so i'm gonna have to wait till night and
then i'll begin
yeah so i set my spawn down here that
other spot
did not work i was too close to the
silver fish and i wasn't able to sleep
so we're going to do it down here and
we'll this is gonna take a bit of trial
and error we'll just keep putting blocks
around it until
we get obstructed and we'll try that
first
uh i'm guessing it's gonna be like a
five by five area around it'll check but
who knows and
we'll just keep going through the end
portal and back again
over and over
so this is cool because what i could do
is set up like a lever right next to
our portal here that will
say either send spawn us back at our bed
or spawn us
back to the original spawn um because a
lot of times i'll be
the man cave and i'll
need to enchant a tool or something did
i look at him no
and i run i run here which is like 800
blocks
and then i gotta run back which
takes a takes a long time when you have
to do that a few times
an episode or whatever i have no pearls
holy smokes
i gotta do something with this portal
too i don't like to
just have it floating in the air like
this
every so often there'll be like an epic
battle between these snowmen
and these endermen because as soon as
they hit throw a snowball at the
enderman that the enderman teleports
and get de-egg road so they're just
a never-ending battle between them
okay
that was enough so this is where it
sends us
right by the the mine shaft
so i'm going to try to remove one block
and do it again
and see see what happens sadly i have to
run back
800 blocks now
so now my new guess is that if any of
these blocks get
removed the spawning will work
around the bed so let's try let's just
try to remove this one first
do it again um
and in case i wasn't clear i would move
the blocks
towards the bed using pistons to
obstruct it
or remove them type thing and just hook
that to a lever or button
i'm curious like if you hooked it to a
button if
when you return like when you load the
chunk again if the piston will retract
on its own or if it will get stuck like
that
yeah we want to go in
okay test number two on my way
and once again i forgot to get under
pearls not that i
really need them
hello chicken what happens if you go
through the portal
okay then
and no still obstructed dang
okay let's let's keep going
i came at the same spot right yeah
um this time let's do this let's
get rid of all the corners
and we'll get rid of this one
and i suppose this one whoops
and just leave the sides blocked
and
there's a chance that might work i don't
know
what i should have probably done is just
set up a bed near
the original spawn point and just kept
killing myself that would have been a
lot quicker
okay here we are again
look mad so i'm guessing this
won't work let's see
yeah won't work so now
that leaves it down to four blocks i'm
well i'll head back again
let's take out this one this one
and this one and
that should work i'm pretty sure that's
gonna work
and if it does we will put one block
next to it and i think that'll obstruct
it again so
we'll know for sure then
let's go let's go let's go episodes
getting long so we'll probably end it
soon
don't go up there
so we meet again
yeah be cool to have um
a quick way of going from that obsidian
platform here to the portal
like a conveyor belt or something
or a minecart or something something
quick
seriously
huh i did sleep in that bed i promise
you
well i hope it works otherwise i don't
know what to say
i have no idea what to say
why doesn't that bed work
okay if it doesn't work this time i'm
going to assume i need to sleep in it
again
because this is a lot of space
not the best team
okay come on please work please work
please work please work
i don't want to walk that again
yeah i have to sleep in it that has to
be it
sun's rising sleep sleep sleep
okay now it's gonna work
that was the problem but
sadly that means this idea doesn't
really work because i'll have to
sleep in it if i ever obstruct it which
isn't exactly convenient like i was
hoping
that's the whole point of this to make
it make moving around more convenient
but that's
that's not really good
so we'll just try it out to make sure
that was the problem
yep okay so if you ever obstruct your
bed you have to sleep in it again
[Music]
idea is a bust oh well
so we'll do one more thing and then
we'll call it an end i'm going to take
you to the tunnel that i was working on
uh it's not much to see but
it's something i actually gotta obstruct
my
i do have a way like i i do have a
sort of a way of saving time i go
through the nether portal here
and that's because we're at like
negative 400
800 go through here
and go through again and that will get
us
a fair bit closer
now we're at negative 400 and zed like
three
three hundred or so so that saved us
like 400 blocks of walking
but i was hoping i was i could have
reversed that
and used the end portal will go one way
and then the nether port will go back
the other way but i guess not
okay so the new tunnel is over
down here
oh i heard a slime
there he goes hasn't jammed up yet so
that thing's working great
yeah over here is our new tunnel it's
much like the mine shaft we're gonna run
a track
all the way down here or two
um missed the spots i use the dark wood
this time and i like that
a lot especially up ahead here where the
grass changes
got the pumpkin pumpkin lighting yeah i
really like these two colors together
this dark brown and
the green that looks pretty sweet
um and it keeps going
keeps going
and there's the end so we'll have to
continue the tunnel sometime
it's got to go another 400 blocks or so
man i am hearing some weird noises
outside so
i'm gonna go check this out i'll say
goodbye
for today and uh thanks for watching
guys
see you again next time
you