[Music]
hello everybody this is Beto and we are
back at it again with another let's play
episode today and to begin with here
we're just gonna check out something I
saw in the comments on last one someone
corrected me that I said that the
beehives
you can't generate them by growing
saplings you have to go to new chunks to
find them and someone was like no no no
you though you can just grow the trees
you just have to make sure you're in a
Plains biome or sunflower Plains or
flower force you have you still have a
5% chance so we're just gonna test that
out here to begin with
I've set up a bunch of trees here so it
should be a one in 20 chance we'll get a
beehive on one of these if it works the
wiki page says it doesn't work but I
didn't I didn't properly test it so just
want to double-check you know see which
is right the wiki page says you have to
generate new chunks to get them so
that's what I assumed was correct
hey I kind of hate doing this because I
have to chop down every single one of
these trees after I haven't seen one yet
alright I got a couple extra here just
to try a few more I'll do a few more
off-camera just the candy kind of make
sure cuz it's a one in 20 chance but you
only grow thirty trees there's a chance
you know you might not get it still okay
so I grew eighty oak saplings in the
planes biome here and not one of them
spawned a beehive when it grew so I'm
gonna call that busted I do feel like
that's a great idea though to be honest
like maybe in Flour forests if you grow
a tree you have a 5% chance of spawning
in a bee hive that way they would be
farmable in some way and like if you
didn't want to go exploring to get them
or if you couldn't you would have an
option like another way of doing it
right like in my world I would have
preferred to just generate it I didn't
want to go exploring for it but I had to
because it's an older world and I don't
want my world size to get bigger or
stuff like that right yeah so I think
that would be cool but I don't think
they should do it for
every biome because then you run into
issues where like maybe it'll break some
tree farm designs and stuff I don't
think that'd be good so maybe just pick
a biome where that happens it would be
best in my opinion add a little bit more
interest to the game that way too but
anyways something we got to do here I
actually need carrots so this is my old
mini farm design I've built like four or
five different mini farms in my world
and most of them are broken or they keep
breaking all right this doesn't work
anymore because it requires darkness to
cause the crop to pop off and now half
slabs let light through them right so
that doesn't work you need a full block
to block of all the light so now when it
would do that it would be done right so
I has this mess around with another
design here because we need carrots for
a project today very simple just like
this right we're gonna load this up with
bone meal okay so we got these loaded up
with bone meal now I also put water
nearby here you got to keep the cropland
hydrated right if this is not enough
storage if you want more like all the
bone meal in the world you know that
some hoppers onto the side here and if
you really want to go crazy
throw some chess as many as you want on
top as well something else I didn't
mention is to automatically pick up the
crops you want to put a hopper
underneath the farmland so that'll pick
it up through the farmland block
actually and we'll put it into the chest
here what I like to do is put a slab
here as well so most of crop for most
the plants don't land where I'm standing
the land on the farm line a few will
land where I'm standing and I can pick
those up to keep my inventory full but
like not enough that those start be
spawning on us have some ladders here to
escape
[Music]
oh I'm missing something
I think I ran this up to the piston like
that hmm okay I just double-checked my
creative world like where I built this
originally and didn't do it like that
as it is right now it's pretty bad it
like breaks every second one or so and
it wasn't doing that in the creative
world but I also put this differently
when I built in the creative world was
the piston on this side so these this
redstone here activates it I don't know
if that would make much of a difference
so I guess let's figure it out
it still glitches out so something I
think cuz my world laggy it doesn't work
as well maybe yeah so the layout is
exactly the same I'm pretty sure but I'm
going to show you the creative world
version here just to show you I'm not
crazy see it works so I think by a let's
play world's just kinda laggy and it
doesn't work as well so maybe I need to
try to fix it okay so I decide to come
up with another design here cuz that
light-based one was giving me a bit of
trouble actually sometimes it would work
and sometimes it wouldn't I think it
works always if you build it underground
but if it's above ground it can be a
little bit tricky so I came up with
something a little weird here I'm just
gonna run some hoppers to a chest the
idea with this one is we're gonna have
some sticky pistons one over here one
over here to bounce the farmland back
and forth that's gonna be our farmland
block and yes we can cover that and that
then we run some blocks over here break
this redstone torch here and repeater
set at two so the idea is Pistons like
instantly retract but it takes two ticks
to extend so we want this to retract as
soon as possible like one once we grow
the crop on it we want it to move as
soon as possible so on the retraction
it's like instant
yeah and then that other piston-like
brings it back as soon as it can too so
it's like a double tree track so it pops
up popped off the crop doesn't rely on a
light hoppers pick up the crop
underneath put it in the chest we got
double hoppers and it should be good I
think so then we can like build it up
however we want here it's a little slow
though let me yeah there's that problem
to you sometimes I look in the hopper
this is the rate of it it's not great
but if the shirt grows them every time
and it'll work all right well how we're
doing here we've got a few all right
good stuff so next up here we're gonna
add a little feature on to the ethos lab
an auto bottle filler was highly
suggested on last episode's comments so
let's go ahead and do it it's very
simple very easy to do so the way we
used to do this the way we would fill it
up
we would fill up our inventory with
something right and then we would just
go on the water shift right click and
the bottles would pop out of our
inventory landed in the hopper here but
now in Minecraft 1.15 they added a cool
little feature here if we put water in
front of a dispenser so we're gonna
we're gonna do that water right in front
of this dispenser or hopper underneath
if we put empty bottles in that
dispenser it will be able to
automatically fill them with water so
that's pretty cool pretty cool so what
we got to do is check if there is any
bottles in here and we do that with the
comparator right and then we run that
into a redstone torch over here back up
to the dispenser and then we just got to
fill this up with bottles if there's an
empty space the water bottle will go in
the dispenser but if it's full we got to
keep this thing full that way it'll
shoot out the water bottle into the
hopper here and then all we gonna do is
tick start this to get it going
yeah so it's gonna keep going until it
this is totally filled up and there's
like one left in here right and then if
that ever disappears it'll do another
one and another one and another one so
it'll always keep this full of bottles
which is really cool as long as we got
empty ones above here so it's probably
good to run like a hopper and a chest
full of bottles here as well put a chest
here oh I always do that I'm never gonna
get used to that
you gotta click on the chest see our our
empty bottles
should go up in here our big storage
room and then it'll always be full
uh-huh all right so that brings us now
to our next project the thing we needed
the carrots for do you got you got ideas
what it could be mmm-hmm what could it
be what could it be
well if any of you watch the pixelmon
series you might have noticed I got a
little bit addicted to having night
vision like given my let's play series
I'll just like try to right click with
my shovel on the ground that's how you
get night vision and in the pixelmon eye
i just do it out of habit now but it
doesn't work obviously
so with the new brewing stuff I decided
to challenge myself I kind of wanted to
create a new brewing system and I've
wanted some way of like having night
vision auto brewing in our world so I
created a new brewing system I call it
the indie brewer which is running right
now basically we can come up to here at
any time step on the pressure plate and
get a lovely dose of the night vision I
think I'm gonna show you this during the
daytime though because those mobs are
pretty brutal at night they were making
it a little too difficult but yeah this
thing's pretty neat it fits in a 5x5
area like all the redstone and stuff
like I managed to get a pretty compact
I'm pretty proud of that and we can load
it up with glass bottles it'll auto fill
them with water as it needs them we can
load our ingredients at the top here I
got guns
I got gunpowder redstone and carrots in
their nether warts this is a system that
doesn't rely on a timer it's like
intelligent it uses that trailing nether
word
I figured out a while ago that I used in
my other systems and it's set up in such
a way like it's gonna keep going and
keep going until it either runs out of
empty bottles or it runs out of space
for the night vision potions to go or if
it runs out of blaze powder yep this
runs out it'll shut off or it also has
like a manual shutoff if we flip that
down it'll stop running at whatever
stage it lasts left off at so now it'll
shut off as soon as we undertake sit
shut off so that's pretty cool
so I had a little trouble deciding here
if I want to make a separate like
tutorial video for this brewing thing or
if I should just show it in the let's
play series and I think we can build it
pretty quickly so I'm just gonna do it
in the let's play series here a lot
easier for me
so I would say figure out where you want
to start with your dispenser first off
and you put a block over top and the
pressure plates make sure it's a
dispenser not a dropper and then we go
three hoppers into the side let me go to
hoppers up and then this is where our
brewing stand is gonna go right over
here then into that we have one hopper
for the water bottles one on the the
right side if you're looking this way
for the blaze powder and then on top of
that is our hopper for the ingredients
and we go up to here it's been a while
since old tutorial etho came out and
made it appearance how should we do this
that's let's actually just wrap grab
some blocks around this hopper here like
that
well actually we got a got a punch these
out then and this is where our droppers
are gonna go for our ingredients so we
go boop boop boop and boop all facing
into the hopper here it's probably a
good idea to build our water bottle
filler as soon as possible here so we'll
do that next that way we don't like do
it later and spill water all over our
redstone so dispenser make sure you use
a dispenser for this and then we're
gonna close in this area with glass
we don't accidentally break a block and
have it spill everywhere and then we
need to come out like this break those
two comparator into this hopper check if
there's any water bottles in there and
then up to redstone torch like we did
before and then we can just put a hopper
on top of here with some storage for the
glass bottles okay so next up here we're
gonna add our locking line to the thing
so any reason to shut down the brewing
this is how we're gonna do it just
redstone on top of that hopper there so
that's our manual shut down that'll lock
it we're gonna add a way of locking it
if we run out of the the blaze powder
and the stopper here so we do that with
a comparator we run that into a block
and then a redstone torch on the other
side and then we're gonna add some
blocks over here to there and we got a
check if this gets filled up of night
vision potions or whatever we're brewing
we want it to shut down otherwise it's
gonna mess up the brewing process so we
checked it with a comparator run that
into a repeater we do a staircase up
here that'll run underneath this torch
which will lock it you'll see this
comparator can power the wire through
the block here so we got to put a
repeater here say at 1 and then we run
it up to this hopper to the locking area
so that's good and then we also want to
add a way of locking it if we run out of
empty bottles like if this hopper is out
of empty bottles so we'll do that with
another comparator over here run that
into a block and to a redstone torch on
this side so that'll power it over here
cool alright so now we're gonna get into
the final part of this the controls for
the brewing so this hopper above the
brewing stands pretty important we need
to fill it with some items some junk
items like cobblestones fine we're gonna
want 19 items in that second slot and
leave the first one open then we're
gonna set up a block in front of it
they're probably the easiest way to
place this comparators is mined out
those to place it that way so it's going
to detect what's in this hopper
we put those back and then we're gonna
go
yeah and thinking about is like wait a
second that doesn't seem right I guess
we gotta bust out the corner of this
brick here and then we run a repeater
into this block so that locks this
hopper underneath the brewer and then we
run redstone above here and then this is
very important we need a redstone torch
on the other side here which will lock
this hopper and then we go up a block
and this is why we carry our ladders and
then we use a redstone torch go up block
on top and then we're gonna make these
blocks come out redstone dust on this
side so that's that redstone torch is
powering over here we need three
repeaters set these at four this is the
give time for the brewing stand to clear
out the the finished brew before it
sends in new bottles and then we add
some redstone in the corners here and a
repeater set at one another one set at
one very good very good so now with that
I think we're done building it we just
need to stock it with ingredients and
get it running get the first few brews
happening which actually I find a little
bit difficult I haven't quite figured it
out but we'll see if we can here
so we'll stock it with ingredients let's
do that so underneath here we have this
one hopper for the blaze powder throw
that in in the chest tears for our empty
bottles we'll throw those in and then
let me grab a dropper real quick here
yeah so one thing I didn't mention like
this brewing we're doing right now is
for night vision potions splash night
vision extended potions that's four
steps to brewing but some potions like
invisibility potions would be maybe be
five steps and that's impossible
with our current setup here if we want
to do a five step brew we need to add
another dropper here run that on top and
then might have a hopper or a barrel or
something over here okay and if you do
that make sure you put the nether work
in this dropper but since we're only
doing
or stepper I'm gonna remove that and the
nether wart goes into that one the order
you put these in does matter quite a bit
you want the nether work to shoot out
last this is the one that activates last
because it has to go through all this
delay set in to last is over here which
I will probably use for a redstone I
don't have a lot of redstone we're gonna
have to go mine some more after this and
then if you have gunpowder put it in one
of these all right and then your main
ingredient should probably be the first
thing that gets put in alright so that's
all loaded up ready to go we have to
kick-start the autofilter because it
doesn't like to do that so to do it I
think we can just put like one object in
here and take it out yeah so that's
going to go
this is ready for the ingredients okay
now this is the part that scares me the
most because I don't quite know how to
do it properly I guess let's just flip
it up and see what happens here the
blaze powder is going in that's good I
don't think it activated ingredients
though okay I see what happened here I
have the barrel I broke stuck in there I
think if we just replaced that with
another word it might be fine I just
grabbed another word out of it I think
it'll be okay if we do that so it starts
with another word they'll end with
another work because that comes out last
will have a couple junk potions in there
we're gonna just take out they never got
brewed but otherwise I think it's going
to be okay now
yeah here comes the carrot so awkward
potion with a garrote that'll make a
night vision many of us decorate this
too so you can see we got the repeater
right there so that's why I like to put
the stairs in front here awesome so
that's all there is to it it's working
now and I let it run for a while it
seems to be fine we got our night vision
here I decorated it a bit more so again
when you're starting this like the very
first time you only have to do this the
one time just put another word in this
hopper to get it going
a couple other things to comment on like
obviously you don't need to run it into
a dispenser you can run into storage if
you want to store them or whatever
that's fine I'm not checking if we run
out of these ingredients up here you
could if you wanted to just hook some
comparators up to these droppers and
send it to this locking line and then if
you run out it won't keep brewing but
that'll bulk up the design a little bit
alright so that's why I didn't do it but
otherwise I think it should be pretty
good here this is so weird
so I just walked over here and like that
looks like a villager is that the
traveling merchant or why does he look
so weird
it's a villager - cleric a master rank
one he was just wandering he was
wandering around here I think he's from
my underground village I don't know how
he got above-ground though oh wait I
might have an idea he's not supposed to
be on the surface though very very weird
that he's up on the surface let's just
lock him in make sure nobody can get him
keep him nice and safe did he get out
through the school I wonder that's the
only thing I can think of let's go down
the llamas unfortunately died that we're
in the llama Vader hmm I think the only
way they could possibly get to the
surface is over here
oh it is open so maybe he went up here
so it might have been a baby Ben that
grew up but it no it's a mastering guy
like I don't know that's that's strange
but yeah anyways we were supposed to
work on the B stuff today but I don't
think we're gonna have time to get to it
here and I also like I got I got
distracted with the burning stuff but
also kind of wanted to get more
honeycomb saved up here so I've just
been laying this run so that we can is
make several stacks of the beehives like
right away when we're building it but I
also ran into a little bit of a problem
here
like I've been trying to perfect the
design a little bit I noticed one thing
for example like as I was testing it
when I had the glass at this level
sometimes the stuff would shoot out side
the glass
I need the two high area here I also
kind of prefer this because I can easily
walk in here and and breed the bees or
whatever when I'm setting it up so I
think that's good like that with the two
high area but I had an issue here you
can see one of these honey combs is full
for some reason like there was a shear
in there but it didn't activate which is
very strange I feel like it may be
glitches out like if the chunk is lazy
loaded or something maybe it doesn't
work the same and if it gets stuck like
that where the honey combs full it'll
never clear itself so I think I'm gonna
have to avoid using the observers in the
design here actually I think you can
glitch out I'm not sure why though like
I can I can manually fix it if I want
I'd like that but that's gonna keep
happening with this design
so I think I might switch over to like a
timer based system instead like set up a
hopper clock that just activates it
every every so often like the time it
takes them to collect the flowers and
produce the honey so if you're ever
wondering like where does ether get his
redstone from like really I never see
him getting redstone it's it's from down
here I do have a witch firm set up kind
of in the world but I never set it up
very well yet so I don't use that I
don't really like AF King at mob farms
either to be honest like even if I did
set that up I don't know if I would use
it very much there is a way now though
with villagers we could get a villager
to sell redstone for cheap and I could
probably do that now I think that would
be a good idea but so far this is where
most of its been coming from I've just
been doing speed mining down here and
it's getting to be a bigger and bigger
area over time uh-huh and I need to get
some more now so I thought it's about
time we wrap up our episode for today so
let's check out the comment it says heyy
so what do you tell people in real life
when they ask you what you do for a
living
aha so usually I'll just say I'm a
youtuber right and they'll be like oh
really well how does that work usually
they'll kind of light up about it you
know I find most people are pretty
curious and interested in it so then
I'll explain like well I make videos on
YouTube Google sells ads on the videos
like when people watch ads then I make
money from that and Google takes 30% I
guess 70% and like most people know what
YouTube is right so it's not super
foreign to explain it but usually they
don't know the finer details so I'll
have to explain a lot of that they'll
ask me like what kind of videos do you
make and I'll tell them I record video
games and then go into what video games
and they'll be like so do you set up a
camera in your room or how do you do
that and then I'll have to explain you
can just record your computer and stuff
they'll usually ask me like how can I
find you on YouTube and I'll tell them
that
and that kind of stuff right so it's
usually nuts not too tricky to explain
it is a weird career like most people
when they hear it they're like very
confused and interested there's still
kind of a new career right so most
people have never met anybody that's a
youtuber like that does it
professionally so yeah they're usually
pretty interested I find I think we're
gonna have to wrap up the episode for
today guys so hopefully you enjoyed it
thank you for watching as always and
I'll see you again in the next one take
care have a good day bye bye
[Music]