[Music]
uh-huh I don't know about you guys but I
am getting pretty excited about the next
minecraft updates I'm just patiently
waiting for it to come out when's it
gonna come out I don't know no clue but
if you're not excited about it I mean
look at this like you can do some crazy
stuff and poof so how's it going
everybody this is etho and welcome back
once again to another episode of the
let's play series so of course last time
was the 500th video guys I looked at the
comments I saw the kind words and and
nice supporting stuff so thank you very
much for that it made me feel good and
moving on here I had to I have to ask
myself you know what do we do we're kind
of sitting on the fence right now
because there was a lot of calm and so
once again is like etho are we gonna
start a new world it's time to start a
new world and it's like oh no not this
again what do I do I don't know so I
thought about it for a little bit here
pondered it and what I decided is we
need to add some variety in the series
here if we're gonna continue with this
world and I have a plan so I checked out
the aqua update today just to see like
maybe we can start doing some snapshots
with it but no it is not ready
whatsoever
it was super laggy like down to 15
frames per second in the man cave lag
spike and lots of glitches like oh my
goodness and you would think oh it's
it's the water update the water is gonna
be all glitched outs and it is a little
bit but especially it's just random
stuff not working like hoppers weren't
working and like just just a lot of
weird stuff I was broken that I tried
out so we're gonna have to wait with
that but the
and is to get into base building in the
next few episodes here we spent a lot of
time finishing up some old projects and
I think we're ready to start some new
stuff now and maybe I'll just clarify
what I mean by base building - like when
I say base building I don't mean
something like sandy city there that's
more of a decorative build I don't
really consider it a base and I thought
about this today like even something
like the amplified base even though we
call it that it's not really a base
either it's mostly decorative and we
have a few contraptions there but not
enough so when I say base building I
mean let's actually make a base like a
standalone base because like when I work
at the amplified base I have to run back
and forth to the man cave and there to
pick up resources and and stuff we want
to have all the farms all the
contraptions and stuff in our new base
so that we can just stay there if we
choose to which is not something we've
done in the world here before this is
our only real base in the world so
that's what I mean by base building and
we're gonna start a water like an
underwater base once that update comes
out but before that since it'll probably
be a couple months or so we're gonna
start a new base today with another one
of my ideas here all right guys very
good very good so I just spent some time
here gathering together some materials
for our base building and figured out
the location and I think we're good to
go now before we take off though I do
want to show you a couple things around
the worlds since the world tour I think
I spent like 10 or 15 hours just doing
random random stuff collecting resources
worked on the nether tunnels a bunch and
a couple little builds like I finished
up the wall here
so this is our snowy side and it's just
like a collection of random garbage
I guess this kind of represents the eye
spike biomes over here we have the mega
taiga you know with the mossy cobble
this could be like ice Plains here maybe
with a big frozen lake and just regular
taiga and then like the extreme Hills
over here we
opening here so I had to like cover or
do something over top of it and I want
to change out the glass here with the
blue stained glass and kind of finish up
this part of it too but I didn't get
around to that just yet and then if we
go outside did one other pretty pretty
big scene here and I think we'll fly to
the new base location just so we can get
an idea of where it is in relation to
the man cave it's only like 2,000 blocks
away where we plan on building and I
don't know exactly what we're building
with and that kind of stuff we'll figure
it out here together today yeah but this
is the other thing I did the bottom of
the gold firm here was not finished for
the longest time we had random
scaffolding just sitting around forever
here too so I finally just was like okay
how long is this actually gonna take the
finish and I just I just did it here so
it's this random pattern or a simple
pattern I should say for the bottom hey
you leave us alone that's cool that's a
finish build now I'm happy about that
but we are gonna be going off I think
this direction actually we have nothing
built up this way is that the right way
we want to go to 170 and minus 1800 we
got nothing built up this way so this
should be interesting I never fly this
way either so we can check out some
stuff here I guess one go slightly this
direction to it and we'll just fly there
and just see what's on the way because
I'm kind of curious oh we have another
jungle here too
is this one better I want to build in
the jungle just for the green grass this
one's pretty big actually huh why are we
going so far away I don't know now how
did I miss this this is a huge jungle
okay interesting yeah okay so I checked
out the other jungle that I had in mind
I think this first one we found is
better it's bigger and also it's closer
to the man cave so at the very beginning
of Base building here we're not gonna
have our firm setup and I will have to
run back and forth so having it closer
is gonna be more convenient for me but
here's here comes the big reveal guys I
just spent the last half an hour to an
hour chopping down trees here and you
can see a lot more of the grass now
which is nice there's still some more
leaves I could get rid of and I would
like to chop down more trees but check
out the axe I pretty much ran it right
down here
so I'll do it another time the reason
for that by the way if you look over
here if you just look at a raw untouched
jungle it's really hard for your eyes to
focus on anything it's just a bunch of
green leaves right well if you look over
here there's a little bit more character
to it it'll be even more once we build
something but also like this is bad for
YouTube videos it causes them to
pixelate really badly well if it's
smoother it's it's a lot easier so
that's why I did it
and I actually chopped down the trees I
didn't burn them down and this is what
we got at the end of things here on our
first run so quite a bit of logs and
stuff it's it's worth it I think a lot
of people they'll just burn it down cuz
it's a bit quicker to do it that way but
you don't get the materials a lot of
times when you burn down trees that
leaves chunks of leaves and wood in the
air too and you've gotta climb up and
chop those down the only thing that
might be worth burning is this like the
bushes on the ground because it's
usually just one log or something it's
not really you're not gonna get a lot
out of it if you chop it down and
they're really annoying to get it cuz
you got to like break the leaves and
then you got to find the log too
usually pretty hidden and stuff so yeah
chop down the trees maybe burn the lower
stuff is what I'm trying to say here
anyways let's get to the base building I
think we're gonna start in this area
here cuz there's not a lot of water
nearby you see how the water changes the
biome and the grass color so we're
trying to avoid those spots if we can so
to get us started here guys we are gonna
press f3 and G to bring up our chunk
borders and I'll try to explain the idea
or the theme behind the space for all
the bases I build I like to have it a
theme like a building theme or general
set of rules we have to follow with the
building so we're gonna be using grass
and stone bricks as sort of our basic
theme materials and the rules set for
this base is we have to build it out of
slabs we're gonna call this slab City
and the slabs are gonna be 8 by 8 by 4
so 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 this is the size of
one of our slabs went too far ok and
then 1 2 3 4 and we will have to play
around with this lot to like figure out
what actually is gonna look good and how
we're gonna do it here and that's sort
of the goal of today just to get an idea
of how to make this theme work this base
idea but I don't know if you guys have
ever seen like the chunky renders and
that on Reddit and stuff there's a 16 by
16 area while we're doing an 8 by 8 cuz
I think that'll be a little bit easier
for a survival minecraft to make a
make-work for us and like to build the
base all the crane is gonna be these
slabs so the next one if we want to put
one next to it is gonna go over here and
it's gonna follow the same 8 by 8 feet
and if we do buildings we're gonna want
to try align them either in an 8 by 8 or
8 by 16 area and try to make everything
look kind of square and chunky with the
build is the plan anyways awesome okay
so let's use
this starting example here we're gonna
build an intersection to begin with
and we'll use this to figure out what
rules we're gonna follow with the build
here so for one thing I think like these
four slabs are kind of connected
together right they're all at the same
height and everything I think when we do
that we're gonna remove the borders
between the tiles that are connected
together so we'll get rid of that bridge
the gap here with grass or whatever
material we're using and the key to
making basis interesting usually is to
have a lot of variation with like the
flatness and and stuff you don't want
things to be flat but that's sort of the
defining quality of this base I feel
like we want it to look chunky but in
order to like even though it's gonna be
flat to make it not look flat if that
makes sense
is we're gonna want to still have height
variations and stuff but the rule I
think will be like let's say we want to
put a staircase to go up here right and
we'll start a new slab next to this one
what I don't think we'll do is like we
don't want to like make a hill or
something like the okay just start out
one blocks and two blocks and then three
blocks but I think what we're gonna have
to do is follow the rule so every slab
is eight by eight by four so we'll go up
four blocks straight up here and we'll
use stone brick as our border in general
here and there and then any like in
between material that we fill in we want
to use stone I think
and these height variations are gonna be
the key to making the build look the
interesting actually let's not put it at
the bottom let's let's just have it at
the top there yeah I think that would be
better so if we want to if we want to do
this then we would put a staircase here
and when we do staircases maybe we'll
put like two blocks in this chunk and
then we'll remove two here okay so check
this out I did a little bit more here
just to get an idea of what it might
look like and
this is gonna work the cool thing about
this base is how we connect the tiles
together right we have a lot of options
with height variations and and stuff but
it's gonna be easy to do because it's
like either it connects next to the tile
or it's gonna be down or up or whatever
right it's not gonna be hard for me to
expand the base it's gonna be simple
you guys might remember a while ago on
the minecraft server I tried something
similar I made like a hexagon house out
of hexagon tiles that was like I thought
it was kind of cool but it was hard to
build the hexagons and since stuff is
square in Minecraft it didn't really
work out super great but this is gonna
be good I think
I hope so we'll fill this in with grass
and you can see like when we're up here
and we look down it looks kind of cool
right because we got the height
variation I thought for the middle here
we would try to do a triple slab so it's
it's 12 blocks tall right and then we're
gonna have to fill this all in with
stone and that's gonna make it look
really plain and flat and that's one of
our challenges we're gonna have to work
out here how do we take these big flat
surfaces and make them look interesting
right and in general I think we will be
allowed to like maybe cross over into
this chunk a little bit with decorations
but we shouldn't do it too much we
should try to make it look like the bulk
of the mass is in the proper slab or
chunk area right you know what I mean
yeah anyways let's sleep here oh yeah I
think I had a good idea here guys
there's a trick in Minecraft if you want
a flat surface to look not flat you use
textures that sort of devil out from
each other so if you look at like the
stone and the stone brick here it kind
of looks like the stone brick is
sticking out further than the stone even
though it's not right
so one thing we can do and this is a
trick I've seen people do that looks
really cool is you break out every
second block here and just make it cross
over like that do and that'll
that'll kind of give it some
characteristics and some depth here even
though it's still gonna be a flat wall
and look really chunky all right do that
that's and we'll take a look at that as
I slowly build it here okay here we go
this is good now if we take a step back
I think that looks a lot better already
right and now we can do that with other
blocks too I did bring some andesite I
think yes we got Han to say how do you
polish it is it just like yeah I always
think you have to put in the furnace for
some reason I don't know why but these
really stick out from stone so if we mix
some of that into and maybe some
cobblestone and stuff it's gonna look
pretty good I think for these big flat
spots sure we'll put one there put that
they're kind of just random pattern like
we usually do and I don't know how about
there okay so another rule with this I
think we're gonna be allowed to go
inside slabs right so we could possibly
have a tunnel here to go inside the
solid chunk of land right and maybe
that's how we do our buildings like
instead of building something on this
big flat spot and like building a roof
and everything maybe we just dig into a
slab and then kind of do it like we do
with the man cave and just I had a
little bit of a brain fart there what I
meant to say is we only have to build
the interior of the building that way
while if we were to build structures on
like flat pieces of land like this you
have to do the inside of the building
and the outside which is a lot harder to
do especially if you're working at a
small scale so I think I like that idea
and it's also easier to hide redstone if
you're working with void space so yeah I
think a lot of our buildings will be
like that and another thing is like we
should be allowed to go inside chunks or
slabs like this but I think we can also
stack slabs within a slab
right not just have like like if we're
in this this slab here it's not like
this is the only height variation
allowed within that slab we could for
example stack one on top of this well
stack it as close as possible so we'll
have a one slab spacing and then we'll
build a slab over top here and just see
what that looks like - I think that's
eight so there we go that is our
floating slab idea I think that looks
kind of cool right that'll work out it
looks interesting from a distance but
also a big thing when you're over here
it feels pretty cool - I liked in
Minecraft when you have things over your
head or when you're walking and you have
something up high to your left and right
like this feels like you're being
sandwiched in or whatever I think it's
like a good idea so that's kind of the
basic rules to shaping our build here we
still got to figure out the decorative
side of things like how do we add
variation and make stuff look cool so
like with this for example it looks
weird on the skinny legs like that so
maybe this gives us an excuse to
possibly do arches and stuff you know I
like my arches
maybe we beefed up the legs like this
and like it looks weird when you look at
the corner here we got it going this way
and then it kind of goes this way all
right we need to blend that in some
house so we could do just a simple thing
like like so so I think we're allowed to
like step into the next tile or next
chunk to the one we're in like if we
look at f3g this is the line here and we
kind of like make this build go into
this one by doing that but I think
that's okay as long as the bulk of the
materials in the other chunk if we don't
do that at all everything's gonna look
really flattened and boring in the end
of things here so we we should do it a
little bit I think just one or two
blocks not more than that though or
it'll it'll be too much probably uh-huh
so that's one idea we also have to add
more color to the bill that it's just
green
great right now that's not gonna fly
long-term we need other stuff so
possibly we will start building with
brick I did bring some brick here
I like brick a lot now like brick Casas
history if you don't know in Minecraft a
lot of people don't like it in building
because it didn't really go with many
blocks but I think it does more so now
it looks a little bit better with stuff
especially with like clays and stuff
like that so maybe we'll include those
too
I'm gonna move this staircase over I
don't think we need to Center everything
either well yeah actually let's hey you
that's twice I got I got burnt today
maybe we won't keep it centered on
second thought here so we'll build a
little bit out of brick I really like
dark dark oak with brick so let's mix in
some of that stuff will do the border
thing like I usually do there's gonna be
some similarities to the man cave I
think with this build because this is
something I do at the man cave but I use
oak when I do it and then I put fences
on top and I will be filling in all the
void spaces b-double oh you trust me on
that
I don't skip out what not when things
are finished but we're still in the
building process right now okay so let's
maybe get some fences in here too do we
have we probably don't have any made
I'll do it off camera okay let's
experiment with this - this will add
more color it's got like a nice yellow
color goes well with brick and it'll add
a little bit of depth in the bill cuz it
sinks down a little bit if you go
straight - yeah I'll be pretty simple
all right oh yeah and by the way because
we didn't connect the two slabs or
chunks here to these four that means we
either have to go up or down with them
and we're probably gonna go down with
them it's gonna feel like we're like up
in the air here as we're walking I think
that'll be neat be pretty cool so I got
some fences made
I think we will also in places have
fences so we don't like fall down
maybe not everywhere it might be too
much if we do a lot of them but in
places will have some fences and stuff
and maybe along the top here I'm not
sure exactly how we'll connect that and
also I was thinking about it let's add
water to the base as well get that nice
blue color mixed in although it's not
really a nice blue color I wish they
would change to the water color before
the aqua updates finished making a nice
aqua color you know it's water it should
be an light blue not deep blue that's
the one thing they need to change to
make the update like perfect for me but
I kind of doubt they're going to I think
they would have done it already if they
were that I don't know too many people
in Minecraft that like the defaults blue
water color everybody use texture packs
get the nice color instead yeah when we
walk here now that feels a lot cooler
all right I like it I like it let's mix
in leaves and stuff with the build to
like maybe we will sneak some in here
somehow
on this side and maybe a hang down area
over here I don't know how that's gonna
make sense logically but could be cool
oh this will come down like this I
always looks neat when you see hanging
leaves like that let's test that for
right now Oh take that hang down a
little bit more I just want to see what
it looks like from the other side I know
it looks terrible from this side well
yeah let's go over here
yeah that's a little bit cooler right
maybe it goes even more uh-huh I liked
it I liked it but anyways guys I think
it's about time we wrap up the episode
here for today we got a good start on
that bass I'm happy with it so far I
know it's not looking like super great
or anything but we just started it as we
add more details and as it gets bigger
it's gonna look a lot cooler and as we
build the firms and contraptions we will
spend more and more time there I think
or it'll be easier to spend time there
as you can see I have to come back here
to do the comment of the day so that is
just one thing we can't do it the new
base there until we get set up for it
anyways let's get to it here so it says
hey etho I'm a longtime sub but I'll be
honest I haven't watched a video in a
long long time I just got tired of the
game and lost interest in it and what
and watching videos of it but I think
it's absolutely amazing that you've kept
the series going for this long I
remember it was like my daily ritual
when I got home from school was to get a
snack hop on youtube and watch you dock
and B dubs videos aha you know I I like
this comment because I've seen a lot of
comments like it and it's totally
understandable by the way I get it you
know interestingly the majority of the
people that watch my videos now aren't
aren't teenagers or kids or anything
like that it's actually you guys in your
20s in that because you started watching
like when you're 15 or whatever and I've
been doing it for seven years or
whatever so now you're in your 20s and
you're busy with life you got stuff to
do I totally get it and even for myself
like I find it's hard to watch somebody
even if I really like them I very rarely
will watch someone for more than a year
or two on YouTube I don't know you just
kind of get to get used to their style
or whatever and it's it gets repetitive
I think and you move on to the next
thing that interests you and that's
totally fine right I think it's cool
same with games like you play a game for
a long time even though it might be your
favorite game ever you
you get tired of it too it's just the
way it is with Minecraft here it's a
little bit different for me
because I'm doing the YouTube thing so
it adds an extra challenge to it and I'm
always trying to push myself to do
something different in the game I think
it's like that with a lot of things like
a lot of people like music for example
if you only played the same song over
and over again you would get bored of it
I think but a lot of people that like
music will try new songs try to please
different songs whatever and that's what
keeps it interesting as long as you're
not bored with something you will enjoy
it right same with videos I try to do
something different so that you guys
don't get bored but eventually stuff
does get repetitive no matter how much
you try because the game doesn't change
that much right uh-huh
anyways I'm rambling hopefully you guys
enjoyed today's episode we'll try to
build the base some more next time and
if you have ideas for like how we should
design it and stuff let me know in the
comments and I might include your ideas
with the build okay so hope you have a
wonderful day today and I will see you
again in the next one take care bye bye
[Music]