[Music]
look
at this how profound is this intro
you're looking at me
as i look off into my future
my hard work the harvest that is yet to
come
as i stand on my porch but yet you're
looking at me and i'm looking at myself
as well because
wait what yeah
that's right so profound i am staring at
the back of my head too
uh-huh so welcome back guys to another
episode
today we're gonna do probably a bunch of
random stuff
feels like a random things episode got
lots of plans and all that stuff as
usual
and we will get to that but first but
first
pay attention pay heed to what i'm about
to show you guys
i have been working on a little bit of a
secret project
lately and i've been very careful not to
show it you see it there don't you
that's right you guys this is gonna blow
your mind
alright here it is
behind this door this door
all that once was and all that will be
control space and time and love and hate
no
behind the door is the secret project
are you ready for it
i hope you're excited i hope you're
you're all riled up and hyped and
yeah hyped that's the word here we go
actually on second thought forget about
pretend i never said anything
all right anyways guys to start off with
today i have an idea i want to try out
has it has potential to be really fun
and might be really cool but it also
might not work out so well
we'll see but we gotta recruit uh a
horse here
pretty fast horse if possible
and if i remember right some of these
early guys were pretty quick
let's try this guy oh
guy with a saddle he's got 13 hearts
that's good
um he's not bad let me try this guy
okay this guy's a little bit quicker
we'll take him um i'm gonna get some of
this wheat
as well now if you let's try this out if
you injure a horse
can you feed him to heal him while
you're
riding him i wonder let's see
let's get a little bit more farmer come
here farmer
you got some replanting to do
where is he
where all the farmers hate you get to
work there
go replant okay um
yeah we're gonna we're gonna head off to
the wither skeleton farm
the big parts or the big slow down there
is i gotta run around
a lot to kill the wither skeletons and i
wanna see
if bringing a horse is gonna speed
things up like considerably
and i uh i outfitted the wither skeleton
farm with all these slime block
launchers today so
it it's potentially going to be really
fun
okay can i feed you while i'm on you no
i think i have to get off
defeat him yeah hmm
you're doing a fine job
okay so we are on our way to the wither
skeleton farm here
uh today i widened the tunnel so we
could fit the horse through
that gas better not give us trouble here
oh there's one in front too
okay this is like the tough part oh and
we got that lava thing in front there
this might be a bit tricky we're gonna
give them a fire resistance
maybe we can jump over this
nope this horse can't jump um
how ow horse is fine
we just gotta get past this and we're
we're home free
there we go perfect so the skeleton farm
is just up here it's double checked in
no i can't feed them
well i'm on them so i'll have to get off
to do that
don't go in the mine carts uh gotta get
up on
the ramp here or the railing
and we are here awesome so i got a speed
potion in them
and fire resistance i'm gonna take a
night vision just for youtube here so we
can see
i really see a little too well so the
blazes shouldn't be able to get them
we should be able to get around pretty
quick
hopefully no he won't get withered right
i'll get withered oh i forgot to get a
new
chest plate though before i came here
um that might be an issue
all right so let's whoa
chest place chest plate must be broken
yes
look at all those buffs
all right i get it guys you're annoying
stop
shooting me okay so i just made
a diamond chest plate so that we can
survive here it's unenchanted though
unfortunately
um it seems to be holding out pretty
decently
so let's try this out basically
we give swiftness potion fire resistance
to the horse and myself here
and hopefully we can get around really
quickly
so that we can kill mobs oh of course
took damage here
so we can kill mobs quickly and get lots
of wither skeletons to spawn
so far it seems pretty decent and uh
yeah that's one of the jump pads i
installed
today
it's actually pretty fun so fast
all right um let's try out the jump pads
see if they work
okay my health is okay horse health is
okay
i don't have diamond armor for this guy
though
let's just kill this guy
all right still doing okay so that's one
of the jump pads there
on a horse these are really easy to use
and we seem to be able to get around
pretty decently actually
oh oh he came up too
all right get out of here the magma
tubes are the biggest problem with this
farm i have to like go far away
to get them to despawn
um but yeah this is not bad we're
cycling through the mobs
fairly quickly okay we gotta get over
there
falling might be an issue for the horse
though because i can't give them feather
falling
and to get down in a lot of these spaces
in a lot of these places we need to fall
quite a distance
okay we're fine wasn't sure
uh i'm gonna do this for a bit off
camera though and just get a feel for it
this is pretty fun hey over here
no wither skeleton heads yet
oh we got one we just got one well i've
been at it for a little while here guys
and this is
really fun and it's it's much faster
with the horse definitely like i'm
getting around pretty good here
getting a little bit better at hitting
the mobs too as i go by
without you know wasting a lot of time
missing
um has no problem going up and down like
this
for the most part odd time it's a little
tricky
and the horse doesn't take as much
damage as i thought he would
um i've only had to heal him a few times
and just out of
out of safety not really because he
needed it he does okay with the
the falls and the jumps for the most
parts like he didn't
he didn't stop when he fell there so i
didn't waste time from that
and yeah just overall it's going going
good
so in less than 30 minutes i have gotten
oh i'm up to 11 now 11 skulls
and yeah oh
they're mad but i think we're gonna go
head back we'll go do something else
i'll show you this too
maybe before we leave over here
is a reset line i have so every now and
then
the magma cubes like they just keep
building up and building up i think you
have to go 128 blocks away from them for
them to
despawn so if if there starts to get too
many of them there i'll just go here
or if the wither still skeletons aren't
spawning for some reason
i'll just uh go reset them like that
it's pretty easy
these guys are mad
i don't like it when they're mad oh i'm
at half heart
am i not healing see i got to get more
beacons here because i go out of range
sometimes
and when that happens every hit does
tremendous
damage
okay so i thought we would stop by the
village and do a little bit of trading
with our long-nosed friends here
look at that nose so prominent so proud
you could be the chief um
but yeah we got lots of these
weaponsmiths and i think there's some
toolsmiths running around
and i haven't unlocked their trades um
so these ones are kind of fun to to
unlock because they're
there's an enchantment involved level
five to 19 enchantments so you can get
like efficiency three unbreaking three
on some stuff okay that's kind of bad
that's also kind of bad
you are bad yeah he was a dud
um any other ones there was like four or
five of them at least
new to our village is there any farmers
you know we might want to test this i
could be crazy but i can't get a farmer
to save my life for some reason
like they're so rare i almost think
they're more rare
than any other villager or i'm very
unlucky
at finding them okay
what about you what are you gonna give
me
and let's see what is the price
so you can get that the diamond axe for
9 to 12 emeralds diamond sword 12 to 15.
let's see what he gives us oh he didn't
unlock
let's try one more time actually let's
do two
unlock your trades oh you just greedy
little guy
are you a farmer no same guy
come on man i hate when they do this
there we go okay so this should be the
the trade unlocked
so he's got a sword for 15. oh that's
really bad
oh he's even worse yikes
okay i'm gonna trade with a few of the
other guys and see if we get anything
good here
all right i decided let's do a little
bit of myth busting here so we're in a
creative world a super flat
and we're gonna just see if any of these
villagers seem more rare than others
are you a farmer you are fletcher okay
cleric armor
from what i could tell the three the
armor the weaponsmith and the toolsmith
those three different ones seem to be
pretty even like forgetting them
lots of clerics okay librarian
weaponsmith librarian okay
shepard fletcher
um so between the classes i think it's
probably equal probability
but then when you have like this the
brown coat class there's four different
ones in that
so it's probably really rare
to get one one specifically in that but
also
i think it's favored more
towards the other three than farmer
let's just get a bunch in
fletcher see i'm not getting any farmers
[Applause]
what is up with that fletcher fisherman
okay we got a fisherman
i also tend to get a lot of butchers for
some reason
um okay we got a couple more fletcher
shepherd
see we're not getting farmers
and i'm wondering why shepherd
fletcher so i might not be crazy
there might be something to this
[Applause]
fletcher fisherman shepard
fisherman yeah i think there's something
to that
i did some more testing off camera i
started keeping a telly
and these are the numbers i got i got 26
fletchers
20 shepherds and 20 fishermen
and how many farmers 15 so it's not as
bad as i thought
but still there seems to be some
favoritism there especially towards
fletcher's
it was kind of interesting did some
trading with the two old smiths here
not really anything good unfortunately
and not really any librarians in the
village trade with
we got one little guy there um
but can't trade with them yet
oh i just couldn't resist guys i i was
trying to go
through the whole episode without doing
any building
we gotta do a little bit of building
right i don't like it when we don't make
any progress on things but we've been
doing a lot of buildings i wanted to
just do some other random stuff today
but uh
maybe just a little bit let's
let's see i gotta mirror this onto this
side obviously
but i also wanted to try
mirror this to the left side of this
um not not identically but sort of the
same thing
let's make more of these compartments
down here perhaps
oh yeah and i brought some flower pots
let's let's set these up just gonna put
these just in the corners
like that uh i looked at the comments on
last episode
i asked for suggestions on the windows
here and uh somebody said
bricks like normal uh
the red bricks you know yeah i think
that might be cool
i'll try that out i don't have any uh
right now though i'll have to go make
some
um maybe another another episode
actually because uh
i'll have to go farm some clay and stuff
but maybe
we will start it here
no no this has to go in one
let's see those are four wide if i
if i remember correctly yeah four wide
so this will be oak
and i'm just going to try to figure this
out and then i will do it off
camera but maybe like this
and it goes three high right
is that gonna work out so the beam i
guess would be down here
that might not be good
ah oh and this is raised here too so how
would that work out
because this would come over and then it
goes down that
actually might be cool
if it's like this we could put carpet
here
give it some more color
ah this might be okay so here it is
with all those changes in place this is
what the library is looking like
now i think that's pretty good right
we got some walls going on it's like
enclosed
enclosing us trapping us inside
like a proper building should i think
that's i think that's pretty good
so i need to decide what to do with this
section here yeah i was originally
planning on putting a window there
like you come up the stairs and there's
a window that's not really going to work
now i don't think cause
for one thing we we got these
bookshelves here
um which we can't really cover
if this is a window um the
other thing is we probably need to put a
staircase back here somewhere
because like look at the shape this is
making um
oh man we gotta get a better view so
yeah this section here is lower than
that one so there'll probably be a
staircase
um over there to bring you up upstairs a
little bit higher
that area back there is most likely
going to be for the librarians that's
where i'm going to stash them on both
sides because there's
there's a lot of space running all along
the wall there and we need a lot of
space
for the librarians because there's gonna
be a lot of them
um but yeah anyway just a little bit of
building for today
uh there was one other thing i was gonna
say but now i can't remember
oh yeah i was gonna try join these
together actually
let's just do that real quick so maybe
maybe like here
we'll start making a beam come across
and connect on this side
and we'll just take a look at what
that's like
and maybe uh put some half slabs up here
too so that
no mobs will spawn and just to give it
more color a slightly different color
than
the wood bark oops
okay
yeah let's just take a look is that a
good height for that
i think so yeah
yeah i'm good with that might add some
some stuff
in those corners there too
all right so anyways guys i'm gonna have
to go in pretty quick here so let's
wrap up the episode i got two comments
picked out
first one says etho what is your
favorite snack
aside from mandarins ah
lately i've been eating mozza sticks a
lot
those are so good so they're frozen
right
um toss them in the toaster oven
a couple minutes later you got like nice
crispy
gooey gooey delicious mozza sticks have
them with barbecue sauce
so good so good i find i like barbecue
sauce a lot more than ketchup
now i used to always eat eat stuff with
ketchup now i love barbecue sauce
um yeah that's my preferred snack right
now
another food question sort of says etho
is either super obese or just normal and
has a good metabolism and he works out
i'm actually really thin
and i cannot gain weight i have a crazy
metabolism
there was a period of time even where i
was getting these cheesecakes
from the grocery store they were 500
gram cheesecakes i was getting like two
a week
did not gain a single pound i have never
gained weight
i have no idea if i could um
at least not with the way my body works
right now
because doesn't matter it doesn't seem
to matter what i eat i just can't gain
weight but i do avoid a lot of sugar
in my diet i guess not really
intentionally
it's just i don't really like super
highly processed food
usually except for lots of sticks
um you know i was thinking about it that
was kind of a jerk move what i did
earlier today wasn't it i was like
i got you guys all hyped up to to look
behind this door and then
you got you got your curiosity up and
then i took it away
i don't know what i was thinking how
could i do something like that
what is wrong with me all right now we
are going to officially look behind the
door
and uh we are going to see things that
will amaze you
and shock you and i'm not just stalling
to
build anticipation so that i can shut
you down again
or am i i don't know okay
behind the door is
anticipation huh another door
oh man look at it
it glows it's animated this is the
door how amazing is this door
i like it very cool
um let's take it asleep really quick
oh that crazy dream dimension i think
it's seeping into our world
i blame you for this
but uh anyway thank you for watching
everybody i will see you again
in the next episode take care have a
good day
bye bye