[Music]
hello everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode
so today i think what we should do
is work on the nether hub some more
it's been really helpful having these
paths in the nether
in these portals and everything and
i would really like to get it hooked up
where i could actually use the mine
carts
uh for most of the stuff so far it's
been pretty close
like the stronghold is not that far i
don't mind walking
this um but hey if there was mine carts
that would be even better
yeah strongholds just over here
through this portal uh but you can see i
started going further
this this track now goes all the way to
my nether fortress where i've been
hunting wither skeletons
and that is at about i think it goes up
to like
380 zed or something
so it is a it's a little bit of a
distance
so minecarts we want minecarts
oh oh no those are those are blank i'm
like
man the text isn't loading again but no
i never put any text for them because
it's not set up
but yeah we have our selector panel here
little thing to select our destination
so the way this is supposed to work
you pick your destination sends you down
this main tunnel here
and then like at 10 different places
along this tunnel there's going to be a
a t junction
with the minecart tracks that will
send you off to your x test x
destination yeah
when you get to it so
the thing about that though
um it's not as easy as it sounds like
in order to send information to those
t-junctions
i would have to run a redstone line
from this main selector panel all the
way
to as far as it goes you know so if we
have a junction a thousand blocks away
we have to run a redstone line a
thousand blocks away
um and one for each of these
which is like oh no what have i done
i can't do that so
yeah we're gonna experiment with
something today uh there is
ways i've seen like where people can
send multiple signals
with a single uh redstone
line um
using different lengths of pulses and
stuff
we're going to do something similar to
that with minecart tracks
and this is an idea i played around with
over a year ago now i was going to use
it on eats road
and it's it seemed like it was working
but it's kind of complicated too i don't
know
if it'll be successful or not
but like for these close junctions like
i would put a junction
here to go to the stronghold that's not
that far that's only
like 40 or 50 blocks i don't mind
running redstone that far
but it gets to the point where you get
hundreds and hundreds of blocks away
we need a better way of triggering the
junctions
for this to work the way out what i
hoped it too
so i'm gonna get some minecart stuff
together
we're gonna go do it up in a nice grass
area
nice flat grass area and just experiment
with an idea
and i'll see you there
all right so here's the idea let's
pretend this is our main
track the main line we wanted to branch
off 10 different places
down the way some of these might be
hundreds or thousands of blocks away
right and we'll branch them off using a
t-junction like this so if it's
if it's going like this it'll keep going
straight
if it's like this it will go this way
to the destination otherwise you'll just
keep going down the main track
okay now the problem is telling this
junction to switch
when we want it to we got to make it
ignore
but like we might have to make it ignore
nine of the junctions on the way and
then on the tenth one
have it switch and uh
that's kind of challenging so usually
the way people do this
and we might end up doing this also if
this doesn't work out too well
is you'll you'll have your selector pad
so we got 10 choices then we'll have
all our junction stuff all in one area
and it'll split into 10 different tracks
that's one way of doing it another way
is to have 10 separate
redstone wires running all the way down
or we could try to be fancy and get
one redstone wire with different length
pulses
going all the way down but what i really
want to do is make like a
self-intelligent track
that just knows this is where we want to
go
and we can actually do that if we use
two mine carts
so how should we set this up i guess
this is going to be really rough this
this test set up here
uh when once we actually do set up we
have to be
pretty specific about our timings and
everything
okay so we'll have two mine carts
right and we're gonna use the time
between
one mine cart and the other one to to
send information
down the track to tell it when we want
to get off
that's the goal with this now the one
problem with this
an empty minecart does not move at the
same speed as one
that a player is riding in uh
so we'll have to put a mob in the second
minecart i'm thinking
i'm gonna use chickens for this just
because they're like the most portable
mob
they're easy to replace if they
disappear just throw a few eggs
you can get chicken
all right
so today i finally set up a proper
chicken farm in my world here
uh this whole time since i started my
let's play world i have not had
a chicken farm of any kind like i kinda
did by the channel farm
there's like there's been like one
chicken in the water for
forever um finally
decided to set up a temporary one by the
purple sheep i don't know if you know
that pen
today and it's just getting going but i
did get five eggs i'm really hoping we
get a chicken out of this
yes awesome quick
quick capture yes okay
we got our helper
um
[Music]
right okay so the way i originally did
this
i only used one detector rail i'm
talking like a year ago
the way i did it originally i only used
one detector rail
basically i had to put it before the
t-junction
so and let's get out our redstone i
basically made a switch
with different delays
or kind of like a redstone fork
i should say so on one
one path the delay was
like actually no the first thing i had
to do
is set up a monostable circuit that's
the very first
thing um just
so that it's easier to create unique ids
with the delays
this will all make sense once we get it
going don't worry
i hope um
so yeah monostable circuits we'll put it
over here
do think that's i think that's right
let's just i just want to see if it
flashes properly
i think i need to set it three yeah
set it to three
there we go that's a monostable circuit
just creates a quick
quick pulse only one tick
in delay okay
so you get the monostable circuit and
then you have to have a fork
of two different delays one of them
will be like instance another one will
be
the delay between our two mine carts so
just do this for now
and then these go into an and gate
and it basically compares
if the timings are equal a current will
pass through
if they are not it will not pass through
and then this would connect to the
junction
so we'll just we'll just do this for now
see how it lights up
and i do not know what delay we need
um well let's see wait a sec
we'll just set it to a very short delay
then we can control the the release time
of the second minecart from here by
a delay from this button
this is how we give each button a unique
id
um again i'm putting this together very
rough
so it's not going to work the first time
i'll have to play with the timings
let's just give it a play like this and
see how it works
and that will send power to the track
and send off the second minecarts
power power one goes to those
okay so i'm gonna fool around with this
a bit and try to get the timings right
so it'll make sense
i've made a few refinements to it to now
and i think i can demonstrate how it's
supposed to work
so i got a lever hooked up here to
do the same thing that the pressure or
that the detector rail does
so when you go over the detector rail
that's what happens
you see that torch goes off first and
then that one
as it goes through the delay
now another important thing about this
monostable circuit is it's
like even if you keep this powered it
still only sends a pulse it doesn't stay
powered here
if it was to stay power it would always
trigger
and these noteboxes tell us when it
triggers properly
that it would trigger the junction up
there
um so if i time it right though
if i send two pulses with the right
timing this one will trigger
which has no no effects then this one
will go then on the second
second time it goes over the rail this
one will trigger again
and if it matches up with this torch if
they both match at the same time then
it'll go through
and then also this will get triggered
again this side but that doesn't matter
so let's see if i can't time it right
nope almost had it
there we go you see what's happening
there
not too late so
the timing has to be very very precise
and that's how we can control this
at several different spots just by
having different timings
uh there is one thing though you see i
have this set at four now so it's
actually a two tick
pulse instead of a one tick ideally we
want a one tick
but the problem we're having
if we set this to this this torch won't
go off it's too quick
see that it just quickly flashes on and
on off the torch didn't change
sort of a limitation of a redstone torch
but there is a way to trick it
if you have a repeater
at one tick it won't work still didn't
change it he said it's the two though
then it does and it's still only a one
tick pulse
it's kind of a trick so we can put that
at the start of this
like that connect it to both of these
oh oh i didn't change it there we go
there we go so it changed so we want
the smallest possible number so we can
we don't have to use as much delay to
make it unique our code or our delay
but anyway now there's also another
limitation here
these detector rails they stay powered
for about a second
so our second minecart has to trail at
least eight blocks behind
i don't know the exact number but
minecarts move 8 blocks per second
at max speed so that's the distance
we need i'm just going to change this
back to how it was
because i had it all synced here i'll
show you how it works so
our little helpers here we lost our
other chicken i had to make a new one
um so i would go first
chicken will follow behind
note that distance
and it triggered
if we change this timing just a little
bit it's not going to work so if we add
in another
repeater let's see if it works with this
just with one more tick
it might i'm not sure oh it still did
that's because this pulse is two ticks
so if we were to add one more i
don't think it'll work
that's why we want that as small as
possible
so it shouldn't trigger i'm pretty sure
oh okay
i know when i tried it before like a
year ago i figured it out
to being a three to four tick
minimum difference between the ids
let's see if this one works
still triggered wow maybe i'm doing
something wrong here
if it doesn't if it does it again i know
i've done something wrong
so we've added a four extra ticks
okay that time it to go so yeah it's
about a four tick
buffer we need uh three ticks if we can
shorten this one more
and that's our minimum between ids so
for each button i need to add three
ticks to
the repeater so the first one would be
like
three for the id next one would be six
then the next button would be nine
and so forth all the way up to our tenth
button to code it
code the signal between the mine curts
yeah so the tough thing about this
though is gonna be
controlling the chickens um
making sure we distribute them through
the stations properly
or i might just try to set up set up a
big chicken farm get tons of eggs
and
always get a chicken that way by
shooting
eggs out of dispenser into a mine carts
or something i don't know
we'll have to figure it out but maybe
we'll do something else now
oh yeah i forgot to say another idea i
had
was to use two detector rails instead of
just one
and have a monostable circuit for each
one
and an and gate still but i think that
would eliminate the need for
all this repeater business this initial
repeater business like we could get rid
of four repeaters doing that possibly
i'm not sure all right
let's try find something else to do
oh just a little correction here with
what i said uh you know that trick
of tricking the torch here it does not
work actually
uh this is at one it's going to be too
quick
to trigger it oh i actually did that
time
oh i actually timed it right that's
amazing
i saw it flicker that once yeah did that
time too
but yeah anyway it's actually extending
the pulse if i do it to two
it'll work but it's actually a longer
pulse and you can really see it if you
extend it to four
yeah so i'll have to just set that at
four
it'll be a two tick pulse that's the
minimum i can do
and make this work i'll have to have a
but
a difference of four ticks per button
so one repeater which isn't too bad
and yeah all right
i guess the next part of trying to
finish this hub is
figuring out how we're going to do the
tunnels
uh we need something that's fairly easy
to reproduce
so i brought some blocks with us uh i
want it to be gas
proof definitely there's some areas are
gonna be like in the ground like this
and some areas are gonna be out in the
open
so i would like that to look good i'd
like to be able to see outside into the
nether
as i travel um
and i like three by three tunnels for
mine carts like this
it's a good size so
i think i'm gonna do iron bars for
looking out of although i am kind of
tempted about
these although i don't think you can see
much through these can you
yeah it's just a little crack
now that won't work okay we're gonna use
iron bars for the sides
i also want it to be relatively zombie
pigmen proof
so need to try to prevent them from
spawning i would like them to be
lit up to the tunnels if possible so
let's just play around with this idea a
bit
so if the tunnel is three by three we
need the
or if it's a three by three airspace we
need a five by five tunnel
like this
okay iron bars on the sides maybe
those would have to go three high
it's gonna take a long time to build
this i can tell already
oh boy
okay
see iron bars here
oh yeah so uh we played our second game
of race for the wool
spoilers spoilers cover your ears if you
want to watch it
i'm sure a lot of you have already
either from my perspective or someone
else that posted
uh but we lost so we're out of the
tournament
but we had a good time and i'm glad uh
we played it was a lot of fun
very very difficult to beat those guys
though man
we had our strategy all figured out but
uh
you know as kind of realized it after
the game but it was
really unlike us to go for a rush
strategy usually we're the guys
trying to lock down resources and
just muscle the team down but that's
exactly what happened to us
and we lost because of it very very
close though so congrats to those guys i
hope they do well in the tournament
[Music]
and when i say those guys i mean team
pme
professional minecraft engineers
yeah the tracks we're going to do like
this our power boosts we're going to
have it detect a rail
[Music]
power rail protector rail so it'll work
both ways
and we don't need any levers or redstone
to power it
um
[Music]
yeah to prevent zombie pigmen from
spawning we should have a block here
so maybe we'll use these if we do that
we don't really need iron bars that low
bring these up
and no i'm not going to waste those iron
bars i'm going to pick them up
not that rich
oh boy that gas sees us
if we put a light here we'll have to put
half slabs above
this we could shape better so it looks
better from the outside using
stairs maybe
actually we could put them there too
and here
and these stone stone bricks i have
plenty of cobbles so that they're not
hard for me to get
yeah maybe something like this
all right anyway it's going to be
something similar to this i might change
it a bit yet
i do want to check out the anvils yet so
let's go do that and then we'll probably
call it an end for today
okay so this is the first anvil i've
created i don't know a whole lot about
them i'm going to try
figure it out after this episode
probably
um
[Music]
they look cool i know that um
i think i can pick it up with a pick
yep cool i know they can be damaged by
dropping them
and that they can hurt things by
dropping them on them
uh you can launch them with tnt a lot of
thought really went into these things
i'm impressed like
they look cool they have many different
purposes you can
name stuff with them they found a way to
incorporate that feature in
to vanilla which is cool um
okay you can repair items with them
i think like i said i don't know too
much about them i think i
read that you can actually upgrade
levels if you combine two at the same
levels
um not quite sure how that works
i'm just gonna bring a few tools we'll
see what happens
efficiency 4 do i have another
efficiency 4. i want to see if like if i
do efficiency 4
if it be if they become efficiency 5 or
something because that would be
awesome
does it say what i get
no it doesn't say darn i was hoping it
would tell me what i could get
five levels to fix it
do i have to name it oh that's just to
name it
how do i repair it
i probably don't have enough levels
this is really cool because like stuff
like looting swords man you could just
repair them
um keep them forever i still have this
pick
i'm really hoping i can fix it
that would be awesome
29 levels to repair it
or no that's to name it man i don't know
what's going on i should just
i should just go read a little bit right
now
yeah i'm gonna read a little bit on this
okay i think i get it a little bit
better now i'm still gonna have to
mess around with it a bit but yeah you
can get a higher level like you can get
efficiency 5
which is awesome i love that
um i was kind of wondering if you can
get like
level 6 stuff but it almost looks like
you can't
like if you do two power five bows
it's still power five which is too bad
that would be really cool let's see
efficiency 5
26 levels before too expensive
i think you want the damaged one in the
second slot
yeah i'm gonna i'm gonna try to figure
out all the formulas and stuff and
figure out the numbers and
that's that's what i have to do when a
new thing comes out
i don't know i find it fun
all right let's read the comments or a
comment for today and we'll call it an
end
this is the comment i picked for today
it's a good one
etho what is your upload schedule
it would be very helpful to know as
knowing it would help me stop wasting
time checking for new videos
please respond
well do you guys know do you know what
my upload schedule is
um i don't have one
that's right i don't have an upload
schedule i've thought about it like
before like setting in stone exactly
what i'm going to upload and when i'm
going to upload it
uh but the problem with doing that is if
i
missed an episode or if i start falling
behind which happens
quite a lot actually people would freak
out
they would get mad at me and i don't
want that i don't want people thinking
they deserve an episode or that i have
to
make an episode i make an episode if i
can i try to please people
sometimes i fall behind though so it's
not something i want to do
you might notice patterns though with my
videos like with my let's plays i try to
upload them
every two three or four days apart
it all depends on how much free time i
have to make them know
because they are the most time consuming
thing i upload on my channel
i put the most effort into them which is
why people tend to prefer them out of
all my videos
um with the ctm map i'm playing
right now as long as i can keep up with
that i release that
every second day at
at 6 p.m eastern eastern standard time i
think
my let's play episodes i usually upload
in the morning
actually most of my videos i upload in
the morning except for the ctm map
and yeah if you're having trouble
or if you don't want to keep checking my
channel i also have my
twitter account linked to my youtube
channel and it will
post a message automatically whenever i
upload a video
so that's another way you can keep in
touch and thank you for
the question all right guys i hope you
enjoyed today's episode
and i will see you again next time
[Music]
you