[Music]
hello everyone glad you could make it
great to be here i'm going to start out
today by giving a shout out to neon
fighter thanks for solving the
netherworts
uh riddle or glitch or whatever you want
to call it that was confusing me last
episode
he figured out that if he got glowstone
above
that's the netherwarts below the
glowstone will
break off so this one broke off here
directly above is glowstone
but one next to it one one block this
way is this one
if you place one next to it it doesn't
break off so
i guess that's it he also said lava
natural lava will do it i haven't tried
that and i probably won't
um he also said the glowstone has to be
naturally there like the game generation
code has to have it there
but we're going to try to play some and
see what happens too
enchantment time here we go
yeah i'll take it
all right so we got some natural
glowstone up there that was generated
with the map
and we will try to do this test before a
whole bunch of gas get here
but uh so again like right above here
there's no glowstone
so it doesn't pop out of the ground
would you get out of here if we go
one block over it does pop out of the
ground
so that still seems to be true uh now
what we'll do is we'll
i brought some glowstone with me
as much as i hate placing it here we are
going to
we're going to try overlap a section
that already has glowstone and then put
some
where there is none as well so let's do
it
i guess right over here
well we'll maybe only place nine or so
okay so we'll put it over here has to be
far enough away for this
test because if it's if it's close
uh the light from it will prevent it
from popping out anyway
so there let's try that out ouch
get rid of this dirt if we can
we got some mushrooms growing on the
glowstone up there too that's kind of
cool
okay gotta go higher
higher
there we go
all right so where does it overlap right
right above us here's an overlapping
area
so that's natural and self-placed
glowstone oh it just disappeared
on its own that's never happened before
maybe it grew it probably grew that's
why it disappeared
okay so it is popping out
and then let's above our own glowstone
um no glowstone there so that shouldn't
pop out
but right here
doesn't pop out and that's glowstone we
placed ourselves so it
has to be generated with
map for it to do that for whatever
reason i have no idea why
all right everybody so the new plan is
to move our nether base to this area
here to this
new fortress we found because we have
the two blaze spawners
we got that one over there and this one
over here so we're going to have an
excellent
xp farm very shortly i'm going to
start building that today
um i'll do most of it off camera because
you've
you guys have seen how to build it
already i have a tutorial on it too if
you want to check it out
as do other people they have there's
lots of blaze farm tutorials out there
uh what i'm gonna do
the good thing is i have these fire
resistant potions this time
but what we'll do is uh
i like there's two options i could try
to get both
try connect both of them together so the
blades end up in one holding area in the
middle or something
or i could have two separate holding
areas
having one is better obviously but
i think i'm gonna do two separate ones
because they're so far apart
would just be a lot simpler that way
and otherwise you got to make the blaze
travel like
10 blocks to the center which uh would
take a lot of pistons
to do quickly or it'll take them a long
time to find their way on their own
um so i'll have two separate holding
areas but i'm only going to use
one i'm going to connect them both
together with the same redstone
circuitry
okay so i'm going to get started here
hopefully all goes well i'll see you in
a little bit i might do
i might show you a few clips of me
building it too
all right everybody i'm going to give
you a little update here what's going on
we got them disabled i managed to do it
without dying
it wasn't wasn't all that difficult
i ran out of potions so i should have
brought more but
i was i was able to deal with them still
they are at the same height these
spawners and they are the same x
coordinate so they're perfectly aligned
it'll be uh really easy to
connect them together because of that
and
never did count the block distance one
two three four
five six seven eight nine 10
11 12 13 14
15 16 17 18 19 blocks apart
it's not bad
so i've just been clearing out area
around them and
between them to do myself some working
area here
doing the fast mining trick with iron
picks
i guess they're quick enough to do it
otherwise it's uh
it's a lot slower mining
it's really easy to do it with
with iron picks here it's nice uh i was
also looking at the comments
for last episode and it seems the reason
i'm having that issue with
the netherwart is because this is uh
this area here is all generated in 1.9
pre-release
there was a heights mapping glitch
in that pre-release that makes it so i
have that problem
uh if i go to new areas that are
generated in 1.0
i shouldn't have that problem but
there's no way of me fixing it without
using mcedit which i
probably won't do that would
i'd be cheating and we don't want to
cheat
right um got a new idea for the
netherwort farm we'll try it out shortly
here
and i want to say thank you to everybody
that's helped solve the problem
a lot of people contributed their input
so thank you everybody it's much much
appreciated
probably wouldn't figure it out without
you so
awesome
here's a quick update of the build it's
going really well
clearing out a lot of space just uh
got the frames around the spawning areas
set up here
we're doing in sandstone that's right
sandstone i love it
miss it oh that nether video man it just
brought my love
back for it it's my it's my favorite
block again
look at this is beautiful how can you
can't go wrong with it really
um i'll have to be careful though with
gas
because they can blow sandstone up with
their fireballs so i'll have to
gas proof this area but i think as long
as i put a half slab or something every
five by five area on the ground they
shouldn't be able to spawn
even if i have a big open area here
i think it's five by five pretty sure
[Music]
okay moving on
the only issue with sandstone of course
is it's a little bit more work to gather
it
but yeah even that's fun
i want to try this run by thing see if
we can do it oh
uh interrupts darn
it gets in the way of the pitch as you
run by i was hoping that would work
oh well i can still do it from a
distance like this too
i think there we go
too far away
yeah so this should keep me set for a
long time again
and here's another update of the build
it's going really well
uh area is getting huge it's a big open
room now still got to go down a few more
blocks
to finish this up uh but really it's not
taking that long to mine out using the
quick mining trick another rack breaks
very quickly
so it's got a little ways to go here
and then we can start doing something
else i probably won't set these up
fully today i just want the frame done
and then we will start doing something
with the netherworts
and there we go
all right i'll see you in a bit
all right so we got the frames pretty
much done here
they're looking pretty epic in my
opinion they're going to be nice when
they're all polished up and finished
i like them really really large though
that's quite a height took a long time
to set this up a few hours
but now what i want to do
is kind of hook them together at the
ground here
so the blades will be up here thinking
i'll put glowstone
right here these two blocks for sure
or maybe here maybe these four blocks i
don't know
uh i'll have it four wide here
instead of just too wide the buttons and
the levers aren't going to go down here
though
like in the other one we will have them
in the middle somewhere the controls for
these two farms because they're going to
be linked together
so that's what we'll do to me it feels
like this is a good viewing distance of
the blaze
to get a nice look so we'll start making
this go
up here i guess try half slabs first
and then
do it like that maybe we'll try wooden
stairs
here so i'm going to be using
wood in this build a little bit and
hopefully everything will be fine there
won't catch fire or something stupid
uh thinking like having a circle or
something in the center here
again on this side uh one
two three blocks and then we go up
is it three or is it four it's four okay
one two three over here
we'll just see how they meet together if
we do that
yeah no that's not going to work
stairs need to be steeper
because i want to go down a hole here to
get to the blaze that way we're just a
little bit closer to the spawner
if we're like at this level here instead
of
two or three blocks lower it'll be
better
yeah this might seem a little random but
i went mining i took a
building break to go mining because i'm
looking for
redstone ore the actual blocks i got
silk touch with me that's how i'm
getting them and i keep finding diamonds
so i thought i'd share
got so many like seriously i'm never i'm
not going to use them
probably have 150 now
and i keep getting more so yeah you can
get
the actual ore with silk touch
which is awesome i'm going to try to do
a bud switch thing at the blaze farm
uh will be pretty cool if i can get it
working well
well i'll see you there just about done
mining
here
i just want to make sure that this
actually works because i had one person
tell me
that these redstone ores don't light up
after you pick them up with silk touch
but that is not true they do still light
up so
you can use these for bud switches and
if i flip this up
if i unpower the piston this will
retract when this stops glowing
so i'm going to try and make some stairs
using this i don't know how it's going
to turn out or if
it's a good idea but we'll see
yes i was just trying to think of a cool
way of doing these little pits here
like instead of using stairs i thought
it might be neat to have
redstone ore blocks here and
here and instead of stairs this will be
a wall a steep wall
doing this more for the challenge
and then when you walk on these
they will glow a piston below will push
them up one block
and then they'll be
i don't know they'll be a stair or
something over here
and you'll be able to walk up it
i don't know uh this we will change a
little bit
try find something that looks good here
too so we need at least some lighting
near here so i'm going to put down some
glowstone
uh i don't like to put the glowstone on
like where this pad is because when the
pistons move around it changes the
lighting
and that kind of causes leg
um maybe maybe
we'll do a two by two there and
try some sandstone around it half slabs
this whole bottom area maybe
okay probably won't use half slabs we'll
do full blocks
it's just a little bit too strange
and you can't use pressure plates for
this either because if a piston pushes
the block up with the pressure plate on
it the pressure plate's gonna
just pop off so
redstone ore has a few tricks you can do
with it that you can't do with
any other way
okay so
something like that i suppose
you'll be able to see the blaze pretty
easy at this height i think if you go
one higher
it gets challenging the piston kind of
blocks your view a little bit more
yeah it's not bad either
alright so this is the challenging part
now uh we're gonna have to
figure out
how to hook up the pistons to make it do
that
this could take me a while so obviously
take this out if you pick these up when
they're glowing
they still show up in your inventory as
regular
redstone ore not like glowing redstone
or anything like that
so definitely have a sticky piston below
um
obviously a simple thing you could do to
make the lift
is just have this
powered oops not like that
the one one block above that if this was
if this block here is powered this will
just pop
up when you walk on it
but it won't ever retract unless you
unpower this
all right give me a minute to play
around with this and we'll see what
happens i might just ditch the whole
idea i don't know yet
yeah so i thought about it some more and
i decided i'm not going to use these
after all
these redstone ore blocks because it's
just it's just
too much work for such a simple effect
you would
i think you would need to use a t flip
flop for them
that's a lot of wiring and stuff for
such a
such a small effect and then you'd have
to try
make the blocks match the stone look of
the redstone war
and there's probably better ways of
doing this
one thing i tried here that i thought
would be so cool if it worked is i
i have half slabs over top the redstone
ore i was hoping like if you walked over
these half slabs it would still trigger
the redstone ore below and make it glow
but it doesn't work because if that
worked
you could completely
completely hide your trigger which would
be awesome
because i know in the past if you had
half slabs over ice or something you
would still get the slippery
effect walking on the half slab so i was
hoping
it would work with the redstone or two
that you could
you would somehow be touching the block
as you walk over it but
it doesn't seem to work too bad
um yeah
so the reason i want like a steep
staircase or steep r rise here is
because i want
at least a seven wide walkway in the
middle here just
just for a good feel to this thing and
when i
ran the stairs before there was like a
three or five block wide
walkway which just would look really
silly
so i could run the stairs this way or
something
instead of this way
or just make them really steep i don't
know
we'll figure it out but um we should
mess around with some netherward stuff
again
because i wanted to
get into making that farm sometime soon
so i'm gonna get set up here and we'll
do some
more experiments and try to figure out a
farm design that will
be pretty cool
so the first idea i had this is probably
the one i'm most likely to use
you'll have these rows of slow sand with
pistons on each end
you could make these up to 12 blocks
wide
and then we'll put some more over here i
think
i think we got 10 blocks wide right now
let's make it 11.
because that's a nice weird odd number
okay and then you would have your
netherwork
all along i don't know if this is going
to work or not
i'm worried that the drops will fall
through the blocks
as they get pushed the idea is
you would have a row of redstone wire
on both ends as well
like so and then
we'll just put levers there for now but
the idea is
uh when the pistons extend
all these blocks will get moved and all
the
nether wart on them will get uprooted
let's try it
[Music]
okay first of all i had that in the
wrong place
and second of all they didn't get
uprooted
darn it darn it darn it darn it
uh that was unexpected
so what you could probably do is if you
had
a strip in between of something
that isn't slow sand
like so then it would probably
cause them to break maybe hopefully
yeah there we go um so every
every second block you'd have to do that
it's one possibility i was hoping that
would work better
let's try it one more time make sure
these pop off
forgot to release that
oh yeah and we'll want to make sure
oh okay now they popped off
i'm gonna have to rewatch that video see
what happened there
aha i got it figured out this is kind of
cool if you have
them in rows like this you're able to
move the slow sand beneath them
it can shift and they'll be in the same
spot
at i thinking maybe it was uh
maybe i had glowstone above or something
but no
so what you need to do oh now they broke
why are netherworts so confusing
i wonder why they broke that time
the idea is you would you'd hit a button
and the pistons would extend then a few
seconds or
a few moments later that set of pistons
would extend and
put the soil back into place the slow
sand and then you could replant
everything
i wonder why they popped off
okay but here's the thing uh you can
make them break
if you have a block next to them
and that block can be nether warts so if
this is solid
when you shift it to the left for
example so this
let's say if this netherward here gets
shifted to the left
it's going to get it's going to hit this
block here this netherwart and that will
tell it to uproot
but if this is an airspace that won't
happen
which is kind of strange so if you want
to use this method which is a good
chance we will
uh we'll have to make sure we plant the
whole area it has to be solid filled
you can't just plant one here one there
type thing
has to be solid
so that's one idea for design let's see
we might
consider a few more
here's another another wart farm i
thought was pretty cool i saw this in a
video by uh
jl2579 today uh
so he had this is just a terrible
looking prototype of his
but he had the slow sand with the
fence gates in between so you plant the
netherwart on the
slow sand of course
you need these two high walls of
whatever block
you want
[Music]
like that and then when you're ready to
harvest you
you shift them over and what happens is
uh
this this is pretty cool
so
it they get uprooted and then they fall
through the
nether gate or the fence gates here
excuse me
brain leg there and then you're free to
pick them up underneath that's what i
like about this one you can
they drop underneath and it's easy to
pick them up
otherwise you've got to walk around on
soul sand which you probably have to do
anyway with any farms
when you're replanting it but i don't
know this is something different
and it's ready to go again
all right guys so i guess i'm going to
end the episode here today uh
it's going to be awesome when these are
done and when we polish this area up
some more we'll definitely
build our netherwort farm which
shouldn't take too long i wouldn't
i wouldn't think i like that first one
where they
when you got a big flat area it shifts
over
i think that's the one i'm gonna do
unless you guys have some better
suggestions
i do like this one too but i think i'll
do the first one
okay if you have better suggestions just
let me know or other ideas
i got open ears
and i will see you again next time thank
you for watching
[Music]
uh
is
room
um
you