[Music]
hello hello how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode of the let's play series so
what's going on here I've just been
standing here just dreading this
terrified so nervous what's gonna happen
I don't know we'll find out so if you
don't know what's what the deal is here
I'm still using an old snapshot from a
few months ago I have not wanted to
upgrade I've been putting it off because
I'm hoping Mojang will revert their
redstone changes with the 1.16 update
but the 1.16 update is out now they did
not revert them so I just gotta suck it
up and take it basically so here's the
deal they made a very subtle change with
redstone to try make it a little easier
for new players to understand um
basically when redstone is pointing in a
block now it's gonna power that block so
in the updates this redstone is pointing
at the boom block so this boom block
gets powered which means this light
turns on this comparator on the other
side gets powered and basically it just
changes redstone that's fine right for
the average player most people they only
have a world around for a few months
baby they usually don't do a lot of
redstone but for me oh man this is gonna
be horrible
I got an old world years old here with
full of redstone contraptions a lot of
weird stuff as well and I know this is
gonna break a lot of things but let's
update it and let's see what happens
here
okay this is it everybody I've upgraded
to the latest snapshot 20w 27a this is
the one that introduces brutes into the
game as well as all the 1.16 stuff and
you can see our thing here looks exactly
the same right but now that when we
update it oh that light turned on what
the comparator turned on oh no
everything's changed alright so
basically I gotta go around my world now
and like test out my redstone
contraptions and just see what's broken
and what's not
door works super smelters smelting three
firmly
bamboozler is working just fine so far
so good but let's try a trickier one now
let's check out the Nexus here I've seen
some people say in the comments the
hexadecimal decoder here doesn't work in
the updates which has me worried
because I don't know how to fix that if
it doesn't work it's gonna be tricky
let's give it a test run there let's
maybe try it some netherrack so ii 5 e
and then 5 over here
pull the lever we should get some
netherrack delivered here and yeah it's
looking okay actually that's great
yeah it might not be as bad as I thought
it was gonna be actually so pumped in
farm is still working ok let's check out
the Brown mushroom farm like on hermit
craft half of my stuff broke there which
might have just been a bad coincidence I
guess I kind of expected something
similar here mushroom stocks got pushed
up as well that's what they're supposed
to do
yeah the potion lab is all good here all
right well I've checked a lot of this
stuff now and I haven't found anything
broken yet so I'm very happy about that
but uh Wilson is a big one as well let's
check this out so give them an apple see
if that still works yeah okay okay
that's good super happy Wilson neutral
Wilson sad Wilson very sad Wilson and
dead Wilson so all the phases are
working still try the food bar if that
still works
I should go up by about two I think yeah
that looks good let's test out the blue
fire here this was a really weird
contraption well it looks like I might
have been worried about nothing cuz I
can't find anything broken actually so
that's that's great actually I was
really worried about that um there might
be some broken stuff I just haven't
discovered it yet I don't know but it's
nothing major like I expected so that's
good now that I've updated we have
access to a brand new redstone
contraption is it target block let's try
the tried and out oh it does work so the
closer you hit to the center but further
the signal goes I believe let's stretch
it out a bit more alright let's check
this out yes so it doesn't go all the
way closer to center than it reaches
further that's the intended purpose of
the target block but what it's actually
gonna use for most the time is the new
functionality it has in redstone so
check this out
when you put it next to the redstone
line you see the Redstone actually
connects to the target block well with
other types of blocks it doesn't do that
so this is a special functionality of it
and I'm gonna be using that probably a
lot because it's really cool so you can
see the repeater turns out here the
torch goes off that makes it great for
compacting redstone but it's also pretty
useful when working with comparators
where the signal strength matters so
let's say for example we add redstone
dust here this has a strength of 1 over
here but if I add a target block we go
up to 2 so I have a little bit more
control over what I'm
want to happen here alright so I've been
trying to build up my shelter box
collection lately so I did another hour
of n city rating the other day and this
is what we got
look at this bunch of stuff in a bunch
more stuff and 48 more shelter shells to
add to the pile alright everybody so
let's get to it here we're gonna head
over to that crimson keep to work on our
pig line bartering station today now I'm
gonna try to do something a little bit
challenging here oh there's a random
Ashoka box here with random stuff in
let's take the random stuff ah that's
gonna be a new glitch whoa Kay hello
that probably happened because I was
recording while riding the ice road and
those two don't go together very well my
team can't keep up at all and it does
some funny stuff afterwards got to be
careful here there's gonna be the brutes
spawning now I think all right don't see
any though what's the plan what's going
on here guys well let me tell you all
about it so mind out a bunch of black
stone here kind of got an area s started
we're gonna be putting a giant higgling
bar during trading hall here the way I
want this to work is we'll probably have
a double chest somewhere we put the gold
in it's gonna split that gold up to
probably I'm guessing at least two dozen
big lens but we'll know when we start
testing this out but a whole bunch of
big ones right they're gonna give us
their items and then we want to auto
sort those into a bunch of chest before
we get started though we're gonna do a
little redstone lesson with e so this is
valuable stuff guys are you ready for
this okay so most of you are familiar
with the idea of hopper chains right you
put items in they funnel down and then
they end up over here takes a little bit
of time not too bad um and then we can
hook other hoppers underneath these to
pull the items out and set up item
filters and all kinds of stuff right so
one of the major bottlenecks when making
massive systems and
minecraft is the speed of hoppers they
can transfer items at 2.5 items per
second or the speed here which is great
in most circumstances but like with
piglet bartering where we're getting
tons and tons of items this is gonna get
backed up really quickly and in the
nether we don't have the option of using
water streams or anything either so this
is this is it unless we cheat the system
somehow and one of the ways we're gonna
do that is by using a dropper chain
instead of a hopper chain what here's
the thing so dropper chains are actually
better than opera chains in a lot of
ways but people don't really use them in
the game for a few reasons one of them
is they tend to be harder to set up and
they make Etana noise which isn't ideal
in most cases and usually they're just
overkill and hoppers do the job right
here's the thing though like hoppers
they transfer items at one item every 4
redstone ticks in the game and what
happens in 4 redstone ticks on on off
that means two items can pass through in
the same amount of time so this is twice
as quick as hoppers but the way we got
this set up here isn't a good good way
of doing it so if we just run redstone
over top and we do this guess what
they're coming out the end there they're
not getting sucked up by our potential
item filters running along underneath
here that is because all the Redstone is
activating at the exact same time and
we're not controlling it so depending on
what order the game decides to update
these it's going to like instantly snip
across some of these droppers and the
hoppers won't be able to pick it up so a
better way of doing it is to have
another chain of observers over top of
the chain of droppers and then you can
set up an observer clock on one of the
ends here if by making the observers
face each other and here's that horrible
noise I'm talking about
yeah yeah but we can load this up with
items over here and they'll make their
way down clock is running back and forth
here shooting up the end there you can
see this is the raid over here so that's
twice the speed of hoppers and each of
these is given time to potentially put
their items into a hopper below like an
item filter like a so but as you can see
they're still shooting out of the end
here because it's twice the speed of
hoppers so we actually need to to keep
up with that rate and they'll go into
both of these aha
so that is the basic idea to what we're
doing so let's get started now with what
I got in mind we're gonna need to space
our chests three blocks apart from each
other so this is our Center gonna line
up with the chest here and I'm thinking
we're gonna have like seven chests along
this side four along here and four along
here that adds up to 15 okay so we got
our room expanded a little bit more here
and our chess positions figured out
hopefully again this is not something
I've built in creative already so we're
gonna kind of figure it out as we go
here but I believe we're gonna want to
store fifteen different items there's 13
stackable items you get from piglet
bartering and then there's the fire
resistant potions there is the Iron
Boots with soul speed on and then
there's the soul speed enchanted books
that adds up to 16 but we're gonna void
the iron boots probably I don't want to
save those so 15 total um what we're
gonna be doing is trying to do four
times hopper speed with the system so we
got a point for hoppers into each of
these double chests and I very quickly
ran out of supplies there so he had to
come back here and we're gonna make a
bunch of chests bunch of hoppers and
stuff yeah Jess and how much iron do I
have I might need to need to go get some
more iron actually we have like over
eight stacks of iron box just one or two
episodes ago and somehow they're all
gone now
I don't know where they all went so you
guys spent some time at the the new goon
farm here get some iron get some gold
oh yeah still working okay so check it
out we are back you're working on the
project here and as you can see it is
actually a pretty big project a very
expensive one as well all these hoppers
man that's the has a lot of iron in
there um so I actually had to move the
chests again I expanded the room a
little bit more I realized I need more
space between these two so yeah this
room got a little bit bigger I'm about
to set up the dropper chains here I just
kind of want to show you guys how that's
that's gonna be done also while digging
this out I found out there is a giant
lava pool above us and you can see the
lava droplets coming down yeah so we're
gonna be doing a double dropper chain
which means four times hopper speed and
I want to show you how to do the corners
here so it is possible to take corners
with this we got to go like yeah one
more this way and then we gotta go this
way and then to actually make sure all
these droppers activate we gotta add two
more here and then for this row we can
just go like normal back here a little
bit like this and bam corner taken very
good very good so our next big step here
is we gotta install a bunch of item
filters for item filters per item to
keep up with the four times hopper speed
so yeah we're going overkill at this
project just for the fun of it
but it should be really cool and it's
all done so what we're gonna have to do
is add and hoppers one more hopper
underneath here and then this will be
where we put our item filter and then
all along here we got to do that
comparators going all along and probably
gonna have to make several trips back
home to get more stuff here cuz this is
using up a lot of resources all right
and then there's gonna be item filters
on this side as well so we got to do the
exact same thing mirrored we won't be
able to see the side from the room
uh-huh very good very good so we got
those item filters installed but it
occurred to me some of the items we get
from the piglet bartering can't actually
be sorted with an item filter that way
the non stackable items we get Iron
Boots with soul speed on from the pig
lens as well as fire resistant potion
splash fire resistant potions and
enchanted books and these are all mixed
in with the other goodies you get from
them and these four items are non
stackable right so it would be nice if
we could separate them in some way and
there actually is a way of doing it but
it's gonna be tricky
okay so step one is this special item
filter here so this is a way of
separating stackable items from non
stackable items like if we put grass in
there that's gonna end up in this chest
but if we put this other stuff in that
doesn't stack it's gonna end up down
here and one will get stuck in the
hopper there so basically these will
emit a signal strength of two while the
non stackable is only a signal strength
of one if it's two then it unpowered
this hopper over here and it pulls the
items down instead of it going in here
that's the way we do that so that's step
one and I'm kind of imagining the pig
ones are gonna be standing right on top
of this hopper here throwing their
goodies in there and then we got to work
on separating these two different
branches aha so this branch with the
stackable items that's these items here
this is what we've been working on most
episode four we have a home for those
now and that's kind of all set up with
the dropper chains and stuff but now we
also want to work on this the non
stackable items so I've done step two
here this is for separating potions from
the other non stackable items so if we
again do this little test here throw in
our goodies chanted books and all that
kind of stuff it's gonna run those into
a brewing stand and enchanted books and
the boots can't go into the brewing
stand so they get stuck here and then
after a certain amount of time if
they're still in there
this special filter unpowered the hopper
below and it pulls items out and puts
them
why are the fire those in there wait a
second
Wade have tested this before start
recording what did I do wrong it did
something wrong guys
oh maybe I I don't know okay I think it
was just getting overwhelmed like it
always worked if I just put one potion
in but I think sometimes too were going
into the hopper at the same time so I've
tried to speed this up now I replace the
hopper with a dropper and now we also
have a redstone dust here powers this
bone block and then we power the power
rail to update the dropper so that it
knows it's getting powered diagonally
here and then I also set this the one
down here instead of two just to try get
this working a little bit quicker
and now let's try a test here so we're
gonna put a bunch of stuff in here let's
put the stone in let's put some more
potions and chanted book and hopefully
everything ends up where it's supposed
to go alright first potion in oh it
worked through the stone I think yet
stones in there potions in here
oh one guy in there okay I think we got
it here now
same kind of issue I think two items
were going in the dropper at the same
time and that was messing it up so now
replace the block there with a target
block so that this will point out it
still and then we branched off here we
got a two tick delay to lock this hopper
so it'll give this time to get the item
out before another one goes in and as
far as I can tell I've tested it a few
times now it seems to be okay a bunch of
stuff in here unlock that so it starts
sorting you see they're going into the
brewing stand some stuff should be going
down here yeah potions in there grass
blocks in there so that will leave us
with books and boots in one of the
chests and then the tune-up and fire
resistant potions in the other one now
we might want to refine this further I
haven't decided yet
we might void the splash ones just so
it's all the same type of potion because
we're gonna be getting a lot of potions
and it might just be a good idea I don't
know so like one way we can do that is
to get them all going into the dispenser
the non splash ones should just shoot
into the hopper and other ones will get
destroyed that's how we can clean that
up if you wanted all uniform and finally
we got everything sorted except for the
boot
from the books here and how are we gonna
do that this is probably the most tricky
one um I thought about it for a bit the
best method I could think of is didn't
use armorstands like maybe there's a way
of doing it with mobs like where they
could pick it up and try to put it on
but I don't know how to do it reliably
so my plan with this is the books and
the boots will go into this dispenser
and then it's gonna shoot across here if
it's a book
it won't go onto the armor stand and
it'll shoot across into these hoppers
here if it's boots it'll go onto the
armor stand and then we push that armor
stand into lava or something down here
to get rid of it the only downside of
doing it this way is it's gonna consume
our stands every time we try to separate
the two but armor stands are cheap so it
might be okay oh and I can't stand here
because I'm gonna grab it alright
alright so you see they got the the pair
of boots on there but if it's if it's
books goes into the hoppers here in good
step so I think we got every single
piece figured out the system now we just
gotta put it all together which is gonna
take a little bit of finishing and
playing around with it I'm sure now we
are running low on time in this episode
so I think we're gonna have to split it
into another one but before we wrap up
here I just want to show you where we're
at here so you can see we got the item
filters running all around here now and
we did do both sides so again we got
item filters on this side as well out of
view so that we can get four per item so
we got to fill these all so this is
where like obsidian is gonna go I'm
gonna use basalt as my junk item I
believe and then Citian basalt we got to
do around the back here again for per
item a little bit wasteful it's a little
bit crazy I know we're gonna need like
41 items in there before it starts going
down into the chest but that will flow
in on
zone here I'll put the rest of the
meirin's fine then we move over to the
next item which I believe is crying
obsidian yep so I got to go all along
here and and put those in so crying
obsidian basalts cue also we got all the
item filters set up now except for the
final two here these are special case
ones the fire resistant potions and the
enchanted books with soul speed on are
going to go in the final two there and
we don't run those items through these
regular style item filters we're going
to tear these out on the final two rows
and set up our other item filters we
designed today for the non stackable
items but then all the stackable items
we have to send into these droppers at
the end here and ideally we want to be
able to split those evenly so half the
piggelin trades will go into one and
half into the other and when the item
goes into these droppers we want the
clock to activate so we'll just do it
manually for now to show you the speed
of this so we put four stacks of soul
sand in and that should make its way
down to here and it did so it's filling
up at a very nice speed and we're
getting attacked you know I haven't seen
a single one of the boots yet I don't
know if they're not spawning here or
what you see nothing shooting out of the
end here so they're all going into the
filters they're keeping up the problem
they're mad sorry alright having that
beacon here is helps so much though whoa
I'm an idiot Rockets quickly oh well
anyways guys I'm out of time for today's
episode so we should wrap up here with
the comments of the day which says hey
etho have you ever considered going back
to the ender Porter I recall there was
an issue with the loading of chunks but
with how nether portal chunk loaders
work now would it be more possible now
I'm not quite sure I know exactly what
he means by nether portal chunk loaders
I'm assuming something that shoots items
through constantly I don't think that
really will work in a single-player
world maybe on a server for keeping the
chunks loaded because as soon as I close
my game and come back I think it's gonna
reload them no matter what all right I
don't like the idea of keeping chunks
loaded either because that's gonna like
my world as I'm playing constantly and I
don't think it's really worth it
now let's let's just talk about the end
reporter real quick cuz a lot of people
get confused about this the issue isn't
that we can't keep the ender pearl
suspended that's actually fairly easy to
do still I say that in the tails then I
fall through yeah I never did perfect
the setting of this oh come on there we
go so it's bouncing on the slime block
and as as long as it does that it should
be fine but the issue is if I die and I
leave the area or if I go through the
nether or if I just fly a few hundred
blocks away and come back the chunks
unload and then when we reload them we
teleport that's why it's broken I have
not found a way to fix that see it
activated unintentionally there that's
the big issue with it but I have thought
of another teleportation system that's a
lot easier to do I think we're gonna do
that as a project pretty soon yeah I
think I think it's gonna be cool so look
forward to that maybe in a few episodes
here maybe the next episode although we
should finish the bartering system but
yeah that's gonna do it for today's
episode everyone so hopefully you
enjoyed it thank you for watching as
always I appreciate it have yourselves a
wonderful day take care alright
you