[Music]
hey what's going on everyone this is
etho and welcome back I decided to stop
by the village here do a little bit of
shopping and I love my shopping that guy
looks like you he was a levitating curve
bit there
I guess he's on the fence it's kind of
floating there yeah we're gonna do some
shopping I brought over some more stuff
hopefully we can do some more trades
yeah so there's one guy selling gold or
buying gold one of the blacksmith's I
saw see if we can hunt him down these
guys oh here we go this is what I wanted
eight come on what was that he leaves I
go to click and then I punch somebody
oh he wants oh now he's gone you guys
you all need names you know that you
should be born with names because I
cannot tell you apart nope
there he is I found him yet don't run
away he's gonna make me punch the Golem
I just know it alright give me new trade
diamond leggings mmm can't afford it so
we only got seven see oh he wants wool
he's trapped in there alright we'll do
this one just to see what else we get
librarians are the best though these are
the guys we want the most of all right
come on
you know that's not bad now that I have
all this gold kinda cool have an easy
way of getting apples because apples can
be a painted yet if you're trying to get
them from trees ah man alright so there
was one of these priests guys had an
awesome pic enchantments let's see if we
can find him oh oh wait I thought he
unlocked something new here we go this
is the guys looking for those efficiency
two and silk touch one oh yeah come on
give me something good guy
OS sword ah oh yeah we definitely need
to get a way of killing these guys soon
not necessarily killing them we just go
get them out of the village okay this
was kind of a bust alright I'll buy you
a cookie from you I have three emeralds
left make it worth my while oh my
goodness uh darn it
Jay let's there's a few librarians
buying books steel here we go so I wrote
up a bunch of books
let's give him toaster face thank you
unlock paper trade no oh that's less my
emeralds you better give me something
good oh my goodness
yep just randomly trading with these
guys is like the worst thing you can do
because you'll just go broke in no time
guys there's so many good houses here
you should go check them out
don't don't all focus on the red house
wait wait wait where are you oh there's
one more guy who wants a book I know it
these guys are trapped oh he's being
hunted right now that's why he's running
so fast wait wait no we saw you darn it
I found him he's one of the good guys
too he's one of the few not living in
the red house he's actually in the blue
one I will give you I traded the rest of
the books that one yeah I got five more
emeralds give you a fat momma joke
alright what will you give me in return
to be of equal or greater value than a
fat mama joke 11 books for an emerald we
can do that you know what the one who
spent too long here just really quickly
let's give them a bunch of books get get
our emeralds count back up because we
aren't pretty poor all right here you go
we'll just do it once
cuz that one time I traded with that guy
a lot and then I had no trades available
ok I'll do that
I don't really like collecting sand
well actually quit any sounds kind of
fun I just don't do it enough ah
[Applause]
alright well he is no longer valuable to
us so let's get what we can out of him
ok that's it's we wore outs that trade
oh that trade we could still do yet and
then he's he's a goner
okay so we got 13 emeralds back in our
collection
not terrible not great I think we should
head back to the man cave I'm not
exactly sure what we're gonna do today I
kind of feel like doing a bunch of
random stuff maybe repair some stuff at
the cave maybe expand out or build a
farm or something you know what I wanted
to do is figure out how to connect my
teeth to this village a little better
actually so we are- 350z 300 y23 about
because i think my lab yeah my lab you
can see it right here if we could
somehow make a tunnel go from my ethos
lab to the village that would be cool
let's see can we get inside I don't
think we can get inside we can from the
roof shortcut yeah cuz we got this we
got this like tunnel that we can start
here and this might go to the village
let me let me figure this out okay so I
checked it out here I just dug straight
from the lab and it is surprisingly
pretty good if we go straight
just a random cave here it comes out to
here which is really close to the
village and I'm guessing eventually I'll
put houses in this part too and this
will be all grass and stuff whoops so if
we just make like a staircase going down
here we can have a nice straight shot at
it pretty much I will do that also this
is a good like path to take because
there's a skeleton firm right over here
I've been wanting to set up like just
over here so we could have that in the
hallway to the rights like over here
somewhere I've also been considering
making a mob farm to the left here but
I'm not sure if I want to do that or not
but I'm going to
clearing out some space here maybe put
some grass down yeah yeah yellow grass
yellow grass why does there have to be
desert here that's no good guys we can't
do this I don't like yellow grass like
this we need a new plan new plan I've
been considering actually wait a minute
here's the thing I have yellow grass
here as well which I do not like at all
I've been considering changing this out
with mycelium which would go pretty nice
because it's bluish and we have a
blueish floor here as well so I think it
would transition really well
a problem is I don't have any much you
know I haven't found it yet in my world
here I haven't really looked well I've
looked a little bit not I never checked
the oceans and that's where you got to
find it as a problem change this out
with my ceiling maybe even glass make a
cool glass bridge I haven't really built
anything here I might even like trying
to get an epic hallway here like nice
and spacious
because I have the space to do it maybe
oh boy what could we do here guys what
should we do I'm thinking I might want
to like somewhat copy what never stood
in his old base on the minecraft server
that he had this one like hallway room I
particularly liked where he has like
water down below and the roof was kind
of angled in the corners he had these
like angled beams it looked really neat
I might try to do like a miniature
version of that maybe bringing this up
two blocks maybe three
that might be too big maybe two blocks
up and then like dig down five blocks or
so below the path and have water
underneath and then like water on the
sides I'm pretty much gonna copy what he
did maybe changed a few blocks around
but it might look pretty cool so I just
I'm gonna do a lot of digging here and
I'll be right back
yeah I think this is gonna be pretty
cool guys nice and spacious they need to
go up one more block at least and it
needs to be wider of course so let's
make it wider I got tired of digging
pretty quickly all right oh it failed
[Music]
that happens every so often and we got
to get down here to excellence look at
this guy man he came from like down the
stairs there where I think he's going
all the way to the villagers here hey
are you lost buddy oh don't step on
those pressure plates where is he going
so you're gonna go up these stairs yeah
yeah Wow it's like it's like you live
here you know your way around I don't
you know help yourself to anything in
the fridge if you want you stuck on the
fence isn't he
or does he see the villagers over there
now guy oh yeah he was stuck on the
fence okay
now he's going back up he's gonna get
stuck again and he's going back down
he's going back up Stairmaster okay guys
work out somehow maybe he had a hard day
at work and he's like stressed out and
he's pacing and what am I supposed to do
alright anyway let's do some more
explosions I don't know what's up with
that zombie
dudettes
I gotta get some oh hey there you want
to help out you want to help out wait do
it in the right spot ah oh you did do it
I just fell hopping down there oh that
would have been bad
all right go close to the path it's fine
it's fine I got to rebuild it anyway do
ya we got to get some more beacons guys
because digging this out without phase
two is pretty bad TNT is fun and all but
it's not a whole lot faster all right
cool
well I'm gonna keep diggin here so I've
been hovering at 30 levels here for a
while so let's go ahead and just do in
Chapman's wing and there - oh that's
pretty bad that's a bad book even though
it got three on them it's like three of
my least favorite enchantments on
everything alright we're gonna head back
down here that zombie I didn't even
realize this but he has an item in his
hand right so he's not gonna despawn and
let's say accidentally Laden on peaceful
so he might be with us for a while I'm
tempted to remove that block there or
the fence or something just so he can
keep going
oh you almost ran in front oh he found a
way to not to mess it up still alright
so I'll take out one more last one I'll
put them back later no he's still messed
up all right I'm putting them back never
mind I think that fence might be
partially messing him up like his
pathfinding period anyway we'll leave
him be so let's head on over here get
ready for this this is the reveal kind
of the feeling we're going for so wait a
minute let me just wreck that reveal so
I'm trying to get myself in the right
frame of mind to but you'll be walked in
through this room it's kind of enclosed
go through the door and then WHAM nice
and open there's probably gonna be a
cross path going this way to the spawner
and maybe one on this side as well yeah
it feels very open very epic so now
let's see what should we do I wanted to
try replace the grass with this blue
glass and just see what that's like I
don't know if we're gonna do it this way
I haven't decided what to make the path
out of like we could do mycelium too but
I don't know the cool thing about using
glass is you'll be able to see the water
below which it I think would help out
the look a bit although mmm it's gonna
be dark without torches or anything near
it
I'm not sure hey should we do glass or
not and if so what colors or color and
kind of like that I guess all right so
the other thing I got to do I brought a
bunch of stone here the corners I'm
going to measure bring this down a
little more I think like that all the
way along and I can just barely reach it
here and sort of make a hexagon ish sort
tunnel here I guess I don't know how to
describe it yeah do that do that on the
other side and then at the bottom as
well
do it like this uh-huh all right and
then in the middle here I'm gonna have
water so this is coming along got
another one of these crazy zombies I
wanna I wanna follow make sure he can't
get into my villagers over here and
these guys they're so smart the way they
figure out this path from a mile away is
just mind boggling and they like watch
them the whole time you better look
where you're going guy oh that's what
happens oh no I don't want to get in his
way
all right you figure it out oh look at
this
and up and man that was that crazy loop
around like he went down then up OH oh
my goodness I think this is one of the
stray guys that shouldn't be here I
don't really want him over here come get
him
this is outside the greenhouse he wants
12 fish it's ridiculous
feel free to kill him come on please
please yeah
useless all right everybody so I got the
bulk of the digging done here and it's
all shaped pretty much so here we have
it lots of digging lots and lots of
digging but it's all done so now we got
to decide how we're gonna dress it up
because it looks pretty plain just like
this it's also kind of dark too so I'm
not entirely sure how I want to do it I
don't never see used I think use stone
brick a lot for the like the decorative
features I want to keep the walls stone
I think to match the cave feel I got
going on so ideally I would like a
different color of something for like
the beams and pillars and stuff
I mean cobble I don't know I know if I
want to use a cobble I did bring some
some mossy here I'm not sure he's got
green in it but yeah I don't know I
think we might go with a courts theme or
some kind of wood acacia would have the
most color if we use planks but the
shape never stood when he did is
originally it was like he had these
beams going like this and then every
three blocks do it again and then in
between have water flowing down and
it'll flow down to a big pool of water
here I think I'm gonna have the water
start at this level here this I was just
messing with see what the leaves look
like in in the desert biome see if we
want to use leaves when we're when we're
dressing this up and this is I think oak
leaves
far2 yellow this is dark oak leaves I
was curious maybe they wouldn't be
affected by the biome but they are
unfortunately and surprisingly birch
leaves are more green than oak leaves in
deserts which it's usually vice versa
normally a spruce looks pretty good
jungle kind of yellow so I don't know if
we're gonna use leaves in here I'm also
not sure if I want to keep this blue
glass I think I think I might work on
this some more another day though let's
see that's pretty good I might move
these over one more block so we'd have
two beams this path is centered in the
middle so there would be two more of
those over there and basically have it
go like this have I think stairs like
that going all the way to the water and
then do that for the top as well so all
this would become stairs let's see I
guess maybe like this
maybe I'm not sure well not the not the
last one that would be a straight beam
like this I know that might be might
need to make that
yeah that's not that's not enough the
other material it'd have to be like a
block and then stairs if we wanna do it
like that I think yeah I think that
would look better anyway I'm gonna mess
that with this some more another day I
think we should try to do something else
today
have a little more variety with what
we're doing here uh-oh I guess I've been
recording for a while here so we don't
have a lot of time left today but maybe
just really quick we'll be able to dish
something out
I said last I think was last episode I
wanted to make a vine farm so we could
attempt to make a really tiny one here
it doesn't we don't need a big vine farm
or anything like that
oh wait what's with this stone brick is
that wiring well that might be wiring
see I don't that's how I know I've done
wiring if there's stone brick I don't
really want to break it yeah that's from
the horse stable okay maybe we can't
make a vine farm here darn we got to
find a new place guys real quick
maybe there's this other spot I've been
wanting to expand out to over over the
river here you know this river doesn't
huh the water doesn't come from anywhere
I should add like a waterfall here now
that I think of it or somewhere around
here but this spots this is new new wish
I think it's double check the furnace
room ends about here so everything to
the left should be fine so maybe we can
dig something out here yeah I don't know
so vine firm not too tough I don't think
it just basically maybe we'll use Moss
stone firm is that what they call it
Moss stone mossy cobblestone Moss stone
I wonder why they call it must own hmm
like that's the official name not mossy
cobblestone that's just what everybody's
called it I guess all right I'll
probably make adjustments this once I'm
done recording too but basically get the
vines oops
go up one more block here like that okay
do I have vines how do I not have vines
and I didn't prepare too well here I
guess I think they wanted to puts
hoppers down here go this way the vines
will fall down and get collected in
these and then I just want to put water
over top to sort of hide them and to add
the natural feel to the cave do dis this
is a pretty pathetic vine farm I'm
rushing here though guys just so we can
do one more project before we end it let
me go get some vines okay so I got
thirteen vines I think I used them all
last episode so that's like the last of
what I have just put them over at the
top here they'll grow down
I'll shear them they'll fall in the
hoppers get a chest down here somewhere
let's change this out I put some wood on
this
and I might mix up a few blocks here so
it's not solid mossy cobblestone either
see going down there and we'll change
this out with planks hopefully I don't
open up to achieve anywhere here good I
hate when that happens because it washes
all the torches out changes to that and
let's maybe put a beam across the top
here to make this oops there you go
I gotta make a treat those Chapa in my
single-player here okay well it's
something so yeah basically let's let's
see how well this works I'm guessing a
few of them won't fall in the water
they'll land on the side but then I can
just throw them in the water although
I'll probably want to keep them if I'm
looking for vines I may fell in 3 mm
about 50%
I couldn't make it 2 blocks wide but I
don't think it's really worth it
so there we go very simple vine farm
well I think it's that time again guys
we should end our episode here but as
always before we do let's read our
comment for today and I thought it'd be
fitting if we read it by the gold
farming here because it's about the gold
farm
it says etho the reason you are not
killing the baby zombie pigman is
because they are only one block tall and
the blocks from the crusher are at the
heads of the two block tall zombie
pigman hopefully you can fix that issue
indeed that is definitely what's going
on I was wondering why they weren't
dying and then it's like oh yeah I'm not
suffocating them at all cuz they're too
short same with these chickens they get
stuck in here
and I messed around with it today I I
set this up so that I can have Pistons
below as well down here but I totally
forgot that doesn't work because if if
the top blocks these two blocks and then
the two below all push at the same time
any zombie pigman that are in the middle
of a jump when the blocks come out they
will jump on the Block below them and
then jump up once again and they will be
able to avoid getting suffocated which
is pretty annoying so that doesn't work
I think what I might do is I just well
you know I think it's fine like this to
be honest I think it works yeah I think
we'll keep it like this it's not it's
not a big deal will despawn the only
thing really annoying is the chickens
but I can I can kill them or this can
double as a chicken firm if I want I
have as working on it today actually and
I I set up an item sorter here so Gold's
wait what happened all my gold Oh does
this item sorter have issues with chunks
unloading or something they're supposed
to be like gold there there there there
and 18 in that slot it looks like they
fell down for some reason alright this
is why I didn't show this this episode
because it's not ready yet
that's like these these stayed got some
eggs in there all these flow go to huh
why do they do that well I'll have to
look into it more later yes and then
this is like junk that didn't get sorted
but yeah just a basic item sorting
system you've probably seen lots of
times although I'm not sure why it's
letting stuff through sometimes yeah
anyway that's gonna be it for today guys
I hope you enjoyed today's
episode and I will see you again next
time take care bye bye
[Music]