hey everyone this is Ethan welcome back
we are at the blaze farm here I got to
get a bunch of tools today I have used
mine all up and I left this thing
running while I was away for a while and
I didn't turn it on and this is what
happened so just filled up a whole
caterpillar here I'm curious to see how
quick it sorts itself out once I start
it if it does at all even okay ooh bunch
of them saw me through the piston said
yes mmm oh yeah look at all of them
going up now yeah so it is working it's
just going to take a while to sort them
all out
okay I put some signs on here because I
always mix these up I don't know why I
never marked them fresh sure I love this
mob farm okay
the only problem with this is getting
away from necks Pete and I didn't bring
enough ender pearls I don't think all
right first up I wanted to put silk
touch on this Oh 34 what I must have
checked it with a different shovel
before
doot-doot-doot there we go and I'm going
to repair this 25 levels got another one
of those 423 levels
yeah are we going for round 2 here
there's like 250 to 300 and this baby
and this Bart's Oh to fix up the sword
with this one and I always mix them up I
always do
Arial 33 levels Boing Boing Boing Boing
Boing ooh robbed mm-hmm let's see what
we get this time much better much much
better and dead whoa we fired what me
his dying wish was for me to die all
right well we're going to fix up my
boots here my lovely boots we will do
that for 32 levels and chant another
pick Oh the worst one you can get ouch
I want a couple of shovels too so let's
enchant one of these and ooh I got so
many silk touch shovels that's insane
was manually kill them this time all
right level 30 last enchantment then
we're going to go do some other stuff
I'm breaking fortune dude hey not the
best uh-huh you you thought we were
still at the blaze farm but i
transitioned to wilson now and i used
the fire to trick your hearing yeah no
people are saying I'm having too much
fun with transitions and it might be
true okay so we're at Wilson now I'll
tell you what the plan was for today I
was going to do a bunch of work on
Wilson off camera and then show him
fully working on camera and that did not
go so well so what I was doing
nothing's really changed back here what
I was doing actually is I opened up a
word document and I started figuring
things out exactly how I need to program
this guy like exact numbers exact
amounts of stuff I want to flow between
our hopper variables and stuff and how
long the redstone needs to be on for and
all that kind of stuff and I got a lot
figured out I know exactly how I want to
do the weights the hunger attention I
know how to do it I don't know exactly
what ways we're going to interact with
this guy yet to give them my attention
but I know how to do it redstone wise
and the age I know how to do that's the
trouble that I'm coming up with now this
is a I don't know if I if I'm going to
be able to figure this out this is a big
problem is how to do the happiness and
the health because there's a lot to this
basically happiness is going to be a
reflection of Wilson's hunger level is
health level and he is
attention level those three things right
and I have to do I have to figure out
how to determine how long to keep the
redstone on and off for and if it's
adding or subtracting to the stat every
update so words or words it's hard to
understand what I'm saying I'm going to
try lay it out and explain the problem a
little more clearly okay guys I set up a
prop here to try explain the problem and
also this is probably going to help me
out because it makes it a lot clearer to
see what I want to do so I think it's
going to help me - but I've shown this
before behind Wilson we have all these
hopper variable things and I control the
flow of items between two hoppers and I
do that using two wires this isn't this
isn't set up by the way but I basically
have a subtraction wire if I power that
it subtracts or or takes items away and
then I have a addition one where if I
power it it adds items and depending on
what I do I'm doing I power the wires
for different lengths of times longer I
power to the more items that will flow
okay so that's our happiness stats this
thing here will pretend and happiness
equals our health stat plus our hunger
stat plus attention stats based on these
numbers here which I'm probably going to
use to figure things out so if health is
at one I want one or if it's at one I
want negative three items in my
happiness stats so I want three items to
go out of the hopper but I have to take
into account all three variables hunger
and attention so with this set up here
if this is what Wilson looked like his
three stat bars 1/4 for hunger and three
for attention I would want
we have to calculate this so you have to
do negative 3 plus plus 1 that's
negative 2 and then at 3 I want no
change so it would be negative two items
flow per updates unhappiness um that's
the general idea behind it question is
how do we calculate that how do we make
these interacts so that the right number
is found I don't know
so yeah I'm going to think on this for a
bit if you guys have ideas let me know
but hopefully that made sense
anyways we're going to give Wilson a
rest for today we can't really advance
any further with that project until I I
get this figured out this is a it's a
challenge I thought we were done all the
tough parts of Wilson but I just say I
didn't even didn't even think about how
tough that was going to be to figure out
anyway
over this way I was experimenting with
some trees here you know that big flat
brown patch of grass we made the other
day when we covered up the hole I was
trying to make it look a little better
so I grew a bunch of tall grass and
flowers and tried jungle trees I don't
know if they're really working though I
wish there was a way to change biomes in
this game like some corruption or
something you could implant to change a
biome to another type I'm a big fan of
deserts to be honest Oh
maybe we'll just let these naturally
grow but anyway I can cut these down if
I get sick of them just try it out for a
while see how it looks when they all get
groaned when they all grow that was
pretty bad grammar wasn't it ah alright
so just what my silverfish farm has been
full for a long time I want to move
these guys and you always know how fun
that is so here we go let's try to get
these guys out of here
this is always a nightmare sometimes it
works out okay I can't reach them
a few more than will throw poison
potion wonder if I can handle all these
guys or not with the new updates it's
not looking good on its 24 frames per
second now let's turn this down and here
we go
oh my goodness that is so much fun
couple blocks there we're not silverfish
it looks like I wonder why that is
alright so fall through here games keep
it up not bad it's still 25 frames
I forget how this all works it's been so
long
I think this drops them yeah okay so we
got to go underneath here so it'll track
us 20 frames I could turn particles off
but I think the poison wore off already
it's over here more just follow as a
terrible noise alright I think it's this
button
yeah let's push it whoo and then they oh
why did they not all go through the
portal okay now do I can't remember if I
die when I go through or if they're all
on the ground I don't know I die Oh what
no why aren't they down in their hole oh
that's terrible that is not good move
there's supposed to be underneath why
are they all on top I do not like this
go through guys
they're not even going through mmm that
is strange how many are up here still
there's a few let's let's just kill the
top one oh they don't kill me first
oh they do a lot of damage Oh silver
Fisher's so much fun
Oh I'm not healing that's a problem a
soulish you follow me I think I got most
empowering you know they're actually
having trouble tracking me it looks like
it's like they're wandering into the
wall
and go through all of you all of you is
it doing that thing again where they lag
spike I hope not
thought that was fixed sure looks like
it though getting through through
getting through okay let's go click the
rest here actually you know what I'm
going to go through the portal first and
then collect the rest these guys because
I'm probably going to die here or
something stupid oh they can't get me
when I'm transporting that's cool
alright are these guys all over the
place it's not a lot of them around is
there I wonder what happened they either
went into the stone already or they got
teleported back somehow go up hmm very
strange
alright removing another batch here
there's going through the portal
it does lag when they go through but I
think because because it's doing so much
stuff like they're walking around
outside on the other end as they go
through and it speeds up when there's
only a few left - looks like let's go
check this out let's what what do they
do exactly
so you would think there would be a ton
out here oh there's quite a few now hmm
quite a few so that is we go up high and
then they all go on the stone and then
one day once we get enough of them we
throw a poison potion and they will dig
a big hole for us or let out some snow
bones hmm
I gotta admit I am really curious how
big our silver fish army is now I can't
remember how many were here before and
we just moved a bunch so I'm guessing
it's quite a few I think we're going to
try it out we're gonna hit we're going
to call our army get them to work just
out of curiosity so let's get a few of
them and then we'll poison potion
actually let's get let's go over here
see they should be able to jump yeah
we'll go over here call a bunch of them
come on my warriors get it together
there's a few around yeah should be
enough oh I hit myself oh stuff is
happening let's get up high oh man
they're there all the way over here - ah
these guys I hate silverfish hate them
in love them I can't get up they do this
to me every time
oh it made passed on it all right well
there's a few around I think we need
more still so we're going to wait before
we do the big excavation maybe another
one or two loads and they'll be a lot I
think oh no it's happening again the
world doesn't know who I am
pressure plates works with items I got a
real aughh to fix it
yep REE lodging fixed it's
recognize me world I am Alive okay
everyone I think we're going to wrap up
today's episode but first got two
comments to read together here at our
wonderful library worked in progress
time to be complete to be determined but
yes I did do a little on it today I
added the top of the window there and I
duplicated the window on the other side
and some other minor minor stuff I don't
know if you can tell but it's coming
along I'm hoping to do a bit more
off-camera before we record here next
time because it's a big project and it's
going to take a long time if I don't do
some off-camera and try to get the ball
rolling on it but yeah here are our
comments for today number one do the
leaves it gives more vegetation to the
build where without them it is a little
too dull that's with regards to the
library at I asked if I should keep
these leaves here and the general
overall opinion of people is I should
and yeah I do like them pretty good and
I can hide lighting behind it so they're
going to be useful to just have to work
out how to join it with the corners here
but yeah we'll try do some trees in
front here or some other stuff too but
thank you for your opinion everyone
number two ESO 1.5 came out this morning
world map Go Go Go Go no no Go Go Go
it's not as urgent as I thought it was
only three goes not four hmm he must not
really want it yeah 1.5 came out it's
awesome
I was looking at the change log for
today and you know playing the snapshots
to get a little bit here and there but
when you see it all together like all
the changes it's actually a really
impressive patch
Lots has changed to the game since 1.47
yeah 1.47
I use the snapshots most the time I
haven't used 1.47 a long time but
exciting
lots of great changes lots of good
redstone stuff and also stuff to help
mapmakers and look forward to see what
they do next for 1.6 I think it's going
to be good as far as the worlds download
for my LP here I'll try to get another
one out soon I know the one I had up got
taken down it's a problem that keeps
happening with my world downloads they
get too reported for copyright
infringement and they just get taken
down that's the way it works not much I
can do about it but anyway thanks for
watching everyone have a great day I'll
see you again next time bye bye