hello hello everybody this is Ito
welcome back guys I just saw falling
swig make a wish
oh man welcome back to everybody to
another episode
go get your cough drops oh if I sound
happy today it's a lie oh I got to stop
doing that I am I'm sick today guys I
bet you could never tell so apologies in
advance if I sound terrible which I
probably do okay so I gotta try not to
laugh today breathing it oh I just did
it again started breathing and suddenly
is is killing me so I learnt that now I
haven't talked much since I got sick so
this is this is all an experience for me
anyway happy thoughts
but no laughing how many of you guys
remember this safe we built this this
farm at the end of one episode and I
used it a little bit after that got tons
of blue flowers and did you just hear an
explosion what I can't even think of
what would have done that uh-huh found
it oh yeah something like that happened
iron golem spawned swam down must have
attacked a creeper somehow and that that
blew up over here alright so I finished
up that firework builder thing we
started last episode and now I'm just
trying to fill up all the the droppers
with dyes so just trying to figure out
how to get all the colors we need 9
stacks of each color which is quite a
bit and then I remembered oh yeah we
have this light blue flower farm over
here which which makes that pretty
simple we got the other flower farms
which will get us like the Reds and you
and oranges and purples and then there's
the mini farm we can get brown from we
have the the Guardian farm we can get
sweating sacks from and get this farm
for the greens so I think we're pretty
much all covered here for all the colors
assuming of course that this still works
I haven't tried growing cocoa beans in
so long alright they work yeah still
good alright it's very good I got these
all pretty much filled up with
ingredients now it took so long to get
all the colors but there is enough here
to make a few thousand fireworks I'm
pretty sure before we have to refill it
which is awesome and yeah this dropper
here this was a suggestion in the
comments that I add one dropper that
gets activated every time we fire this
because there was a problem where we
sometimes weren't getting a color and
you need a color to make the firework
star so now this gets activated 100% of
the time so we're guaranteed to get at
least one color and then there's a
random chance we might get more than one
from these other droppers I just
installed this thing here and try it out
we stand in the spot when we craft the
fireworks star we then throw it into the
hopper and that makes it send out a
signal to up here and it tells it to
send us the stuff to make another star
so it keeps the cycle going for as long
as we want these two droppers they get
activated every single time because you
need at least one die and at least one
gunpowder we're actually only one
gunpowder not at least one to make a
star and then the rest this stuff is all
random alright so let's try it out and
I'll try to tell you guys a little story
as we do this I I was very excited when
fireworks came out in this game because
in real life I like fireworks a lot well
people do but I really like fireworks
they're kind of hard to get your hands
on though in Canada I think they're
illegal the story I heard is some kids
blew their hands off playing with
firecrackers or something so always
always a little bit tricky to get your
hands on fireworks I think they might be
illegal to sell or something but I don't
know if they're actually illegal
themselves I've always been confused
about that but anyway a long time ago my
family went to the States and we stopped
in at a fireworks store we weren't sure
if we were going to be able to get them
across the border because it was sort of
a great issue um pretty much the most
fun I've ever had shopping though it
like these the fireworks stores in the
States some of them are the size of
Walmart like just endless supply all
types of cool fireworks had so much fun
we stopped in at like three of them and
oh it was great but then unfortunately
when we went to the border they took
them away from us and I was very sad my
heart was broken so yeah they're kind of
illegal in Canada because they're
dangerous but because of that I started
making my own fireworks which is even
more dangerous
um somehow I got my hands on like a
pound of gunpowder and a bag of
potassium nitrate and yeah had a lot of
fun with that had like a secret forts my
fireworks lab where I would make them
and and then I test them out sometimes
they would work sometimes they wouldn't
made bottle rockets I made like
explosive stuff I had lots of fun with
it for a while I was like when I was 13
or so so I thought I thought I knew what
I was doing I thought I was doing stuff
pretty safe and then one time when I was
mixing up a batch of
balint it must have overheated and
caught fire and then I freaked out and
sort of dropped it on on oh we sometimes
oops
sometimes we can get to colors here
that's a bit of an issue actually oh I
gotta stop doing that
I'm putting stuff in the hopper drop the
batch of the propellant I was making and
luckily I didn't get burnt or anything I
was I was safe but it freaked me out
because you think an oil burn is bad
this stuff it's ate through that my 2x4
table within a couple seconds if that
landed on my skin oh man
so after that I'm kind of quit making
fireworks but I had fun with it for a
while but very very dangerous anyway
that's my firework story for today this
seems like it's working pretty good
except for the Boop except for this
sometimes two color thing Oh what am I
doing here now when when you're done you
just drop off the Stars in here and get
all sorts of random colors so now what
we got to do is make some way of getting
these stars to another station where we
get a piece of paper and either one two
three pieces of gunpowder and then we
combine them to make the actual firework
okay so next thing we're going to do
we're going to clean up this mess here
somebody asked me to kill these guys on
camera so we can see the enchantments
that they drop I'm pretty sure they all
have feather falling for but this will
be interesting to see if that's true or
not maybe they can survive with feather
falling three even not sure
oh snap look at them all oh now they
kicked it out one guy held up the line
all right yeah this thing is totally
backed up all the chests are full with
with mob drops and stuff all these
hoppers are filled up to feather falling
for and anymore these are all full or
that over here yeah they're all pretty
much full except for the very end one
here and and these last two that we'll
need the glass back we actually get many
drops considering so oh yeah feather
falling three and four feather falling
four and four okay so they can survive
with the three it's a pretty far drop
anyway so we got that let me show you
also today I added something in the man
tape here just a little minor adjustment
in the main room here I just added two
things I added a light over there
because there was a bunch of stone I
wanted to add some some more detail and
then also over here added another lights
but this is a special special light got
some droppers up there what you do you
hit the button and that gives us a lead
from that one and the other one has
something important like we have the
horse stalls here and there wasn't
really any way of giving them speed
potions before but now that M gives a
speed potion we can use it whenever we
want whoa actually that's not very quick
and to refill it I made a hole over here
where we can drop them in uh anyway I
think today maybe we will go caving for
a change I have to take it kinda easy
today
I want to talk to you about the series
on the channel there's been a lot of
questions about that so maybe we'll just
do a quick recap on on the plans and
what's going to be happening soon oh I
hear that
I found a cave here looks like it goes
through a little ways hopefully it
doesn't end and this works out very good
because we got to light this up or by
the Guardian farm so if we light this up
we'll get better rates there and that's
something nice and chill to do today
when I'm sick not too not too difficult
and I've been meaning to talk to you
guys about the series on my channel and
it's really hard to do so in a normal
episode so hopefully in today's wacky
episode hopefully you guys don't mind it
too much this gives us a good chance to
talk so the series on the channel I've
kind of been also hesitant to talk about
this because some of the things I'm
going to say you're probably going to
upset certain people and you know
there's that choice don't talk about it
and then nothing bad happens or talk
about it and risk getting backlash from
people so hopefully you guys don't mind
too too much hopefully you accept what I
say so the first thing we got talking
about is mine crack that's what most
people are oh wow look at all the mobs
are upset about because I haven't
uploaded it in a month now you know we
got to turn this up
which is very unusual but these focus
there's not a lot of dark spots around
here so all the mobs are all in one spot
basically with Minecraft not too much
has been happening on the server is the
thing I'm a statue people aren't playing
on it too much nothing's really getting
built and I kind of losing inspiration
on it now that doesn't necessarily mean
it's ending but just at the time being I
don't really have much plans um a lot of
ways it's become a single-player series
to me and we already have this for that
so it's kind of hard to continue it and
also very I haven't really been asked to
do anything online crack in a long long
time by the other guys so so yeah if
things pick up on the server I'm sure
I'll play it again but for now we'll
just leave it as it is might try to
finish finish the horse track it is
pretty much done and maybe the tree as
well I'm getting really distracted here
I'm not talking as fluently as I had
hoped
there's too much action going on in this
cave alright the other thing though like
the last few episodes I've recorded on
mine crack it's like I log in don't
really have a plan for the episode so I
just kind of wander around do random
caving or whatever I try think of a plan
and then nothing comes to me and I log
off and then try again a little later
and I just I've been struggling to come
up with ideas of what to do on there
I've talked about this before but like
in my single-player I need to have lots
of stuff going on all the time I need
lots of open-ended projects by doing
that I don't get bored if I just have
one or two main projects
I find it really hard to keep wanting to
play you know on mine crack I don't
really have the option to start a lot of
projects so because you know there's the
map resets and also I don't want to like
get take over the map you know have a
million projects going on all over the
base because then it's like how do you
things I guess I don't know it just
doesn't really work online crack so
anyway I've talked about that enough I
think ever since I stopped doing it
though I have really enjoyed my
single-player series a lot more like
it's kind of tough to to keep coming up
with ideas all the time like when you
have two vanilla series going on it's
easy to watch episodes but to actually
make them sometimes can be tricky to
think of what you're gonna do when every
you know you got single player than mine
crack I got to come up with two ideas
every time now I just need like one idea
every time and it's just a lot easier
I've been finding anyway I've been
enjoying it a lot more this way the
other thing we got to talk about is UHC
again another possible source spots I
haven't played the last few seasons and
there's multiple reasons for that first
one is they are no longer recording on
Fridays they record it on Saturdays and
I've talked about my sleep schedule I
have a really hard time doing stuff on
the weekends because I get up early on
the weekends and then like to record UHC
when I've only had four hours asleep is
tricky
um there's that I've also become a
little less interested in the series
because it's been going on for so long
nothing really changes with it lately I
found I don't watch other people's
episodes even like I don't really care
it says I don't know I've kind of had
enough of it I think
I used to watch every single episode
everybody put up and look forward to it
and somehow that just changed over time
and I think this something similar has
happened because my views have dropped
also on that series like they have been
down a third or half of what they used
to be in the last few seasons so I think
either you guys are getting sick of it
or there's this more people playing or
more people to watch now but also
another big thing is I get a lot of
backlash in UHC whenever I do poorly and
that can be a little bit discouraging
especially the last season was probably
the worst so far there's a there was a
few people that were like well nice try
etho better luck next season but there
was a lot of people that weren't quite
so friendly some of them are band some
some of the comments were removed but
yeah people say you have to have a thick
skin when you do YouTube it is true it
is definitely true but I never want to
get to the points because this is both a
hobby and a job for me I'd never want to
get to the point where that hobby part
is gone and I think if a youtuber
doesn't want to read his comments
anymore I think the hobby part is gone
for them in my opinion like when you no
longer care what people think about what
you do when you're not when you no
longer look forward to it I don't think
you're you're having fun with YouTube
anymore
and with UHC that's kind of how I feel I
don't want to look at the comments and
the thing is even if I choose not to it
doesn't matter because people comment on
my other videos with their UHC comments
and get me down on my other videos and
then I don't want to look at those
comments either so it's kind of a
rippling effect
ah please don't be mad guys so doesn't
mean I won't play UHC anymore but
currently kind of like mine crack I just
don't feel it's alright one more
negative thing to talk about the
material energy I tried that out I was
kind of looking forward to it but that
was probably my least well-received
series I've ever done a lot of people
weren't too excited about I think a lot
of people were confused about it so I
don't think I'm going to continue it it
was I just did one episode and it sort
of failed the trial I guess so will will
use that time for other things I think
all right so the good news I am very
close to starting my modded series not
like this any modded series this is
going to be the modded series on my
channel is going to be very similar to
my single-player here where we just kind
of do whatever I feel like um like a
sandbox experience um I am so excited
for it a lot yesterday I was like
putting together mods lots of stuff I've
never played with before
lots of mods that look like there's so
much content I don't think I'm ever
going to get bored with it and I've also
chosen a lot of mods that will allow me
to be very creative and like have fun
doing unique things three of the mods in
fact I there's pneumatic craft it has
the drones computer craft and also the
custom NPC mod I'm going to be using all
three of those allow programming within
the mod so I'll I'll be able to do some
really cool stuff with that um my thing
I'm a lot I just noticed I said um I
don't usually talk for long periods of
time like this so I'm not very good at
it oh I almost said on there I caught
myself though alright
so that's gonna be starting soon I'm
super excited for it I hope you guys uh
well I didn't ah there
hope you guys are looking forward to it
too I think it's going to turn into
something really cool I have a plan for
some like meta games and unique stuff
that's probably never really been done
before in a modded series if all works
out well but anyway I think that's all
the talk for today was there anything I
missed
I don't know how did I miss that
cape spider I don't even know it was a
sitting there I swung at him and I
missed um
still thinking just in another um I
think that's I think that's it oh wait
no no I forgot to mention
so crash landing is ending very soon I
talked about that in crash landing and
the new modded series is going to take
its place so that's that's what's
happening with that I've had some people
say I've been doing too much modded
stuff lately so hopefully that's not too
much because we lose a series and then
we regain one oh baby give me that
redstone oh yeah okay maybe one more
last little thing to talk about here
real quick
Terra Firma graphed a lot of you have
been missing it we did a pretty long
series on Terra Firma craft and it was
pretty well received I really enjoyed
that mod um and lately like b-dubs and
jenni have been playing it and I've been
watching that and it makes me really
want to play it again but currently
there's no definite plans to play it
again but probably sometime in the near
future we will do that so oh spotter so
yeah we'll get we'll get to that too one
day again
I'm almost definite and oh don't I keep
thinking of things don't start with GM
that's been going pretty good it's
received pretty well some people aren't
happy with how how new be we are at that
but hopefully hopefully it's not too bad
my plan is like what when I'm done with
her when doc and I finish up there will
probably do 15 to 20 episodes I think is
sort of the plan if if I still feel like
playing and people still feel like
watching I might try to get good at the
game and then like do a single-player
Challenge series on it but we'll see
when the time comes that's not definite
yet like where I try to make it as hard
as possible and and struggle to survive
type of thing um what else I think
that's it I think we're good now so
anyways I hope that clears up a few
questions people have been having I want
to thank you guys for all your continued
support I often get people saying like
how nice people are in my comments since
how like supportive you guys are it's
definitely very apparent when you
compare like the comments I get to some
other larger channels you guys are very
good and I appreciate it you give
valuable feedback and you're friendly
you're nice and in general you you're
very supportive and loyal um anyway so
hopefully you guys are okay with those
changes and you're still pretty happy
with the way I do things I try to try to
please you guys as much as I can but I
also try to do things that I enjoy as
well I think that's important baby
anyway that will oh man there's still so
much Cape to explore I thought we were
like done and now I see a whole bunch of
dark spots anyway I think we'll we'll
call it there alright so let's do the
comment for today it's like I never
stopped talking today it says with trees
and other vegetation on all this that on
all the steps the pyramid would look
like the Hanging Gardens could be NEETs
and I actually like the mix of the two
sandstone colors
I think he means the orange in the
yellow which along with the various
sandstone textures could work well
enough as base blocks I did either line
it again are you seriously you know and
I would I do it it's good and then when
I sign it it changes I swear I don't
know why it keeps doing that never used
to be a problem um yeah I think that
might be cool I like the Hanging Gardens
idea a few a few you guys suggested it
so we'll try add more leaf blocks in
with this and since we got the forest
over here that the leaves will actually
be green the problem is like over here
it's deserts so it doesn't look so good
when you do vegetation so I was thinking
maybe we'll have like a bit of a walkway
here and then like walls on both sides
of us with leaves hanging down and other
plants and stuff could be a cool like
entrance to get to the sink but a lot of
use also suggested I keep it simple like
more simple like this not not too crazy
with all the the patterns and stuff
because pyramids are usually pretty
simple looking still not sure about the
wood some of you like that some of you
didn't anyway that's going to do it for
today guys I hope you've enjoyed the
episode it's a little bit of a strange
one
it will be back to normal next time
assume again I'm not sick anymore but
thank you for watching have a wonderful
day bye bye
you