hello hello everybody this is Ethel hey
how are we all doing today hopefully
you're doing okay
yeah I've been doing some more work here
at the storage room and I'll show you
around
some of the changes so I've got this
like overhead walkway thing going on now
and I do like to it like I really like
it but I don't know there's it's really
flat for one thing which isn't
necessarily bad like it looks flat out
the other thing there's a lot of wood we
might have gotten carrier carried away
with the wood here I'm not sure but it
does look pretty cool very tempted to
whip out the little sandstone though and
just start changing everything up here
but yeah it's kind of cool so we got
still working on the stairs a little bit
we got a staircase that goes up here a
little bit of a thick rail this is a
stair it's all half slabs in that so I
don't have to worry about slimes
spawning up here and then it's going to
be a replica on the other side here will
you'll have the staircase going down and
yeah I don't know don't really want to
do any more with this until I get you
guys its feedback on it because I would
have to I'd have to do one of these over
there and one over there but I'll take
you into the storage area this is how I
decide to do it it's not quite done
either yeah instead of doing like a Cove
with just three walls one here one here
one here I decide to make it go in a
little further and have like a cove here
cove here and then an extra wall here so
instead of just having three walls we
have seven just kind of cool and then
probably what I'll do like over here
I'll have a well actually maybe we can't
do that
somehow I'm going to try incorporate a
ladder that goes down and we'll have
additional storage down below for like
overflow like all my cobble and that's
will stick down below here I think
that'll work out pretty good but yeah
let me know what you guys think of that
oh it's raining I don't really know what
I want to do today I think this might be
just a goof around episode or maybe
we'll just do small projects alright you
know what I thought is something I want
to do today for sure let's work on the
mob system a bit the the water tubes and
stuff so let's head on up here still
working great yeah you know what like I
talked about before I wanted to do like
a mob separator here I'm sort of having
second thoughts on that now still like a
mob separator but maybe do it
differently because there's I don't know
there's not really any point to
separating skeletons into their own
tuber or anything like that
one thing that is beneficial Oh is
getting creepers into their own tubes so
that they can stockpile so don't mind
the sounds they're going to get fixed
I'm sure they will yeah I think they
they match the wrong sounds to the wrong
actions but I think that's going to be
fixed for sure yeah so this tube here
will dedicate the creepers and I'm
choosing this ones for a good reason
let's see let's get some light up here
so we can actually see all the other
tubes are under the snow I think oh
maybe not I can't tell I'm too high up I
can't see but this one I know definitely
isn't the center of it is right there so
we can get sunlight down to here
and burn up the other mobs that are not
creepers and make a cook outside of this
one so that's what we're going to do so
something else I was thinking though
like we might still do a mob separator
but just different types like I might
want to separate the mobs that spawn
with special things like armor or tools
and try to get them to go to a separate
tube that might be possible by throwing
items on the ground for mobs to pick up
I don't know I haven't really looked too
much into it I kind of doubt that will
work but maybe but anyway we need to
make a switch that will instead of
dropping the mobs straight down here
we'll have them go this way into a water
stream okay so I got a platform set up
here the very first thing we need to
sort of figure out is if this is even
going to work if we stick a vine here so
we need them to come to a gradual fall
here okay yeah they're still dying from
fall damage that's good zombies - yep
all right so that'll that'll work nice
because if we have if we have a ground
below here the ones from the very high
levels of the mob system all dang that's
what I was afraid of yeah we may need to
remove one layer of this thing because
he kind of got stuck there he was from
the lower layers didn't have the speed
to fall through and yes another idea
maybe let's try lower this one more
block see if we can sort of dealt that
way it allowed to but maybe hear that
and let's hope they still die from fall
damage
and then we can just lower everything
one block come on where the mobs let's
go down
I think it's nighttime nope you know
what it is they're just completely stuck
up there
it wasn't night Wow alright see me fall
when we Wow they died I think they died
yeah so the vines weren't working that
great so we're going to try and do a
water water break instead of a vine
break thing is if we do it too low
they're not going to fall to their death
and we don't have a lot of space to work
with here so I'm just watching right now
if this is enough to prevent them from
dying the ones that fall from the very
very top so I'm going to watch it for a
while and see if any mobs die by hitting
this glass block I placed right there
nope very first mob that dropped and he
died so we need at least one more water
block to stop them which shat out
there's a problem actually because we
and his lower this all one doesn't
matter
definitely no he's seeing a difference
with the game's audio engine no because
before if you had a whole ton of mobs
like this together it would be
SuperDuper loud now it's like they're
interrupting each other you can only
hear one and he keeps getting cut off at
a time anyway let's I can do this real
quick nope darn
hey we got a record um we got a problem
here we've got a problem okay how about
now three blocks I want that record man
my record ah okay let's just watch it
now make sure we picked up all the drops
dude can't do that hmm some things have
changed in this game I guess we're not
going to be able to tell Adana I
mumbling I'm sorry just trying to watch
if they're dying on impact with the
glass block it's a little hard to tell
with all these guys drowning in front of
me now seems to be okay so what we got
to do is have a piston out lets water
flow from here then down three blocks
and then left and it'll push them to
that tube so we got to lower this by one
actually in order I don't think it's the
audio engine that's the change I think
it's just because there's so many noises
it's doing that thing like what happens
with the blaze when you get a lot of
them there's so many noises because of
the water being the water noise is being
glitched at the moment okay we'll do
like this
oh that sounds so weird okay mmm
might need to shut the mob system off to
do this let's see I got to move these
pistons we need one sticky piston here
to extend make that a platform for them
to land on there and then we need one
for controlling the water
dang no oh that sucks
oh no no that's not too bad
I've been messing with the switch system
for a little bit and I haven't tried it
yet we're about to I'm a little scared
too but let's see what happens here so
yeah when this piston retracts it'll
allow the water to flow will come down
then when it passes by this piston it
will cause an update you see it's being
powered diagonally but it's not extended
yet so once the water goes in front of
that it should extend and create a
ground for them to to hit when they fall
down and then go this way hopefully
we'll see it we'll see what happens here
who knows what the whole thing might
blow up when I remove this block oh it's
scary stuff yeah I don't know the piston
might cause some problems it's just a
regular piston head yep
dang so we have to use a full block I'm
pretty sure it did extend though that's
good then when it it should retract
properly - I would think again I'm
scared to try though yep because when
the water disappears it causes another
update which causes it to retract but
it's not perfect
it's letting mobs through on that side
still which we don't want and they're
getting stuck on the piston head so I'm
going to redo this
I've been messing with the switch system
for a little bit and I haven't tried it
yet we're about to I'm a little scared
too but let's see what happens here so
yeah when this piston retracts it'll
allow the water to flow will come down
then when it passes by this piston it
will cause an update you see it's being
powered diagonally but it's not extended
yet so once the water goes in front of
that it should extend and create a
ground for them to to hit when they fall
down and then go this way and hopefully
we'll see it we'll see what happens here
who knows what the whole thing might
blow up when I remove this block oh it's
scary stuff yeah I don't know the piston
might cause some problems this is just a
regular piston head yep dang so we have
to use a full block I'm pretty sure it
did extend though that's good then when
it it should retract properly - I would
think again I'm scared to try though yep
because when the water disappears it
causes another update which causes it to
retract but it's not perfect it's
letting mobs through on that side still
which we don't want and they're getting
stuck on the piston head so I'm going to
redo this it should be good now I'm
going to do one thing here though I'm
going to just for now put a vine here so
that they don't fall to their death
because when I tried it before a lot of
them were dying on on this fall here
okay and redid the piston switch
pretty happy with how it turned out so
you would powered from this block here
and goes up to that and then this way it
was kind of tough to do it where when it
caused block to update issues with the
Pistons but this seems to work okay
and we are ready to go see as oh no no
no no no no oh dang it okay we got to
leave this area oh man I wonder if I can
get up there no there's no way I'm
getting up there that's didn't realize I
forgot to seal that
okay um I'm not really sure what to do
now
see if I try to go up there I'm going to
get creeped 'red hey they're going
through ah come on
well maybe if I ender pearl I can do it
nope nope no oh boy that's right I know
this place is full of creepers right now
can we try this again oh it's bathroom
Oh oh no all those creepers there no
this is not going well how did I fall
through there come on oh dang no I know
there's at least one more here where'd
he go
there you are
oh man Oh another one's coming down no
okay this time this is the time that was
bad throw oh I have it
um isinglass whoo
oh no the Skelton's gonna shoot me off
just fall down man ah okay we got it we
got it
check this out yeah there's definitely a
clog here we could fix it by moving this
I mean how many records do we get from
that one um of that not fix it what the
heck
close this up well no
get out of here hmm okay well we left
the area and we came back now having
some issues with that vine up there
they're getting stuck on it so I think
we have to lower it but otherwise the
cook us is doing what we wanted to the
creepers are alive down here the ones
that did make it everything else burnt
up let's go up there and just check for
jamming I think it's okay
yeah no jamming here that's good sweet
oh there's some items there oh that's
from before our records still there I'm
not able to get it where it is that's a
second record we didn't get today still
there it's still there I think my kill
me I get it
I was full right there I think I picked
up an arrow hair come on just want one
record today oh now addy spawned dang
hmm so let's fix this okay switch this
back to glass and for now we'll just
lower the vine to here or something
until we get the EMP unit setup that is
yeah we'll put one over here should work
now whoa-whoa-whoa
all we have to do it again we shouldn't
do it but we have to do it again
is it directional is it the the
northeast glitch or whatever again the
eye thing is back in the game oh that's
scary
I'm so tempted to see how far I can push
it but I don't want this place blown up
well it seems they were getting stuck on
that vine we just placed also so we'll
have to do something else maybe either
lower that thing down so they won't die
on the fall or we'll just have to
control a water break system but if
there's water above them the zombies and
the skeletons won't burn but the idea
behind this is now we can use a looting
sword on them the bat doesn't have
sharpness and get tons and tons of
gunpowder we had 47 at the start of this
not sure how many are here
and I want to try out also that the idea
of getting the guys with this with tools
and with armor to go separately and
stockpile because that would be pretty
cool too
all right what do we get here oh-ho-ho
oh man that's awesome
count think there was that many there
even yeah so let's let's head out at
night here and try figure that out I'm
going to see the what I'm wondering
about is if all zombies like all unarmed
zombies and skeletons if they'll pick up
items I throw if it's only some of them
if it's all of them we should be able to
separate them okay we're out at night
here just trying to figure out like will
these guys pick up my items do they all
do it do they only do it when they're
not aggravated you don't sleep too want
my items maybe they don't see them yeah
it's probably a select few
okay
I left them he's right by them he's not
picking them up No Oh nope yeah so it's
only a few or a rare chance that they'll
actually pick up the items too bad
otherwise it would have been pretty easy
to make a separator what still might be
able to do it just by inflicting various
damages like if they have armor on but
take it all not pick them up anyway it's
something I'll think about well it's
that time again guys let's go over to
comments I picked up from last episode
number one do you want some thumbnails
mm-hmm this is something I've been
wondering about for a while do you guys
think I need some nails for my different
series um is it worth the bother do you
think it's uh is it worth doing because
so far I haven't been convinced that it
is but maybe maybe I don't know I'm
pretty lazy when it comes to YouTube
stuff like I'm there's a lot of
playlists I need to make and stuff and I
just haven't done it and thumbnails I
never make thumbnails and yeah do you
think I should or not first one second
one guys stop feeding the troll
please yes I don't know somebody left
the troll comments this is what he's
referring to was quite clearly a troll
comment and there's like a whole big
chain on it and instead of just
downloading it so would you Martha's and
negative comments people reply to it
over and over
and over again so guys stop feeding the
trolls if it's obviously a stupid
comment just download it
it'll get hidden away and I can delete
it if people reply to it if hundreds of
people reply to something I have to
either just let it fly which makes the
comments full spam or delete every one
of those which takes oh so long like
easily like to go through a hundred
comments it probably takes me 10 15
minutes and that's time I could spend
making more Let's Plays so don't feed
the trolls