ah these patches guys they just keep
getting better and better don't they oh
so beautiful wait for it wait for it oh
here we go
you think it's done it's not done it
just keeps going and going
oh one less does that fence over kaboom
oh here we go we got this don't worry
we're gonna get to that be pretty soon
we just have to play with TNT for a
little bit longer
deemo Oh time sets I sure got myself a
sword oh well too late dude
so I wonder what it would be like
running into something like this on a
map doesn't it's not very random though
is it always feels the same spot it
sounds like that is void down there
yep
oh it blew up it actually blew up all
right whoo that's major height on there
okay guys we're not going to get too
crazy here just 14 T there 16 in each of
these and this is set at 16 and a half
ticks is it going to implode on itself
is it going to be amazing let's find out
what's it gonna do woo oh okay okay so
imploded it was a few too many T for
that delay but it did shoot it
oh that's right it's back baby you knew
I had to make one of these it's been so
long
doo doo doo well let's do five and oh
yeah hit a tree check that out
oh man so cool I think I should make a
series let myself just derping around
and create about one day it's so much
fun whoa that would have killed me for
sure though
all right everyone welcome welcome we
are in the LP worlds and now sorry for
the delay it was heaven
so our plan for today is the pet project
plan so we looked into this last episode
we we plan things out I think we have a
good grasp on what we want to do so
today we are going to actually start
building it our pets in the comments I
think the number one suggestion I got is
I should try to include a night cycle in
with our pets so at nights he goes to
sleep and then I can't interact with
them I can't feed them or or play games
with them or anything like that he goes
to sleep or maybe if I maybe I can wake
them up but at some penalty to happiness
or something like that so that's that's
a good idea we'll try to do that but of
course we got to play with some more T&T
here so let's get this going don't know
how successful this will be whoopee
moves up them
why I almost think that was perfect it's
really hard to do multiple layers like
that like the chain reactions hey always
gonna chant oh boy look at this
craziness man five hearts granted I only
have shoes on but still whoops
give it so this is the spot we're going
to put our pets I I don't like that
noise it's uh oh nots what did we get
there oh this is the storage room we
just just barely nicked it it looks like
that's good oh oh oh let's try it out
I might've wrecked it oh boy how do I
get out of here I don't know yet I just
want to double-check this is working
after that explosion I did make a backup
before the explosion in case of any
problems
I did not realize this so close to other
stuff all right come on open
whoo okay I think everything's okay we
just broke into the casing a little
bit's that's why we put these things
around things because you never know
when you're going to blow something up
there's a mom on top there all right so
we got the space cleared out I'm going
to clean it up a little bit more and we
will start laying things out these guys
man there's snipers now like
unbelievable range it's insane
lay this he's shooting me from all the
way down there or trying to you can't
even shoot this high barely and he's
shooting at me well actually he does
pretty good for himself doesn't he
Oh oh there's a lot down there careful
careful to get in a spot where they
can't follow you
oh gee I don't have a jet pack gonna
play for real here oh yeah that's
Skelton there he's uh he's stuck at the
lava let's see if he'll let's see what
kind of range we get from him or is he
going to go around
I hope probably around where'd he go
even oh he's around here somewhere there
he is
okay excellent so we have a good start
going on here I'll show you where we're
at I've been working on the interface of
our pets and this is what we got this is
where we're at and it's it's pretty good
I'm happy with us this looks pretty good
I would say so we have our our emotion
our face over there of our pets which is
blanked at the moment we have our stat
bars three on the left and two on the
right I think we're going to put buttons
or maybe other ways of interacting at
the bottom slot there because there's
only what was it five stats plus age so
age happiness on your health wait
attention that we were going to do so
that's the age bar is going to be over
top there that that big bar there so I
do this a free spot where we can have
buttons or something else that we might
need and in the item frames I think I'll
use a visual indicator for what the stat
bar is and then we'll also have signs on
the right of each of the stat bars like
over here my bad guys accidentally
stopped recording their press the wrong
button yeah we'll have step four signs
on the right and left of our bars so
actually let's figure out what we want
where so if we we know where age is
going happiness on your health wait
attention health is probably the top
priority bar because one South goes down
to zero our pet dies so top priority may
be let's put that at the top left here
go health the reason why I want the item
frames in addition to the signs is
because I there's no way just by looking
from a distance we could tell what that
bar does the only way we could get that
effect like I can't read that can you
read that I can't read that so the only
way we can actually see what the bars
are from a distance is with item frames
I I figure but then you know it might
not be
clear what the item frame represents so
that's what we have the signs also to go
along with it even though I'll memorize
it pretty quick I'm sure
so do health the top left then happiness
is going to be really important for the
overwhelm well-being of our pets so
let's put that next happiness and I
guess let's do weights below that the
weight of our pets so ideally weight is
kind of a special stat we like for
mostly stats we want them to maxed out
we want health to be maxed at 5 we want
happiness to be at 5 but with weights we
want it at 3 ideally because at 5 is
overweight at 1 is under weights and
both of those will affect the health of
our pet so that's going to be a little
bit more tricky to deal with then on
this side what else do we have we have
hunger actually hunger is kind of
important mm-hmm maybe I should put
hunger little health
yeah those those all go together pretty
well don't they health hunger weights
those are all fairly related so we'll
move happiness will put hunger here and
I'm going to use I think a cook stick to
represent that in the item frame which I
have on me so let's put that in already
perfect on this side I guess let's do
happiness at the top right happiness oh
that actually works out perfect because
well I'm going to say for this
interactive spot here I think it's going
to affect our attention level but I
guess it's also going to fit hunger and
other things so never mind never mind ok
so that's what we're going to put sup I
might add one more block to the right of
signs like we have here two blocks so
just the one
probably look better but we're not going
to worry too much about looks for just
the moments um yeah that would be better
I think okay what's next what's next
let's do let's do the face let's
consider the face so we've we've been
over this before our different emotions
we know what we want with that oops
so I'll just outline the happy face
again a happy face is like that
ah it's gonna be so cool when it's all
done yeah I like the courts for the for
the emotion thing it's it's pretty good
people suggest that I should use colored
wool and quartz and maybe we'll do that
instead of sandstone but we'll just do
this for now and the reason I picked
this positioning for everything by the
way this works out really nice because
this this height of this walkway right
here and the the left and right of it
the horizontal positioning when we walk
up to it standing right here we're
perfectly Center with our face here
which is nice from a distance we can see
what how our pet is feeling even that
will work out really well this is
actually at two four blocks wide area
four block wide area and I might remove
one more block over here so we can get
it centered you know five watt five wide
area here so that'll work out pretty
good um so yeah our face our emotions um
we'll need Pistons behind this and I
just to represent all the the mouse
aspects of it we'll need an area like
this with pistons behind so let's get
those down we'll use sticky pistons
and we're going to have to this is going
to be kind of tough to do whoa that was
weird that was a glitch that could be a
face - ah
that will be our mouth controls the top
two blocks on the eyes we decide we were
not going to change ever but the bottom
two might change so we'll need pistons
behind those as well
certain faces will make use of it and
other ones won't I'm saying faces I
should be saying emotions certain
emotions so we'll have two Pistons per
eye and we'll do the same over here I
should go get some work quartz morning
song I love that so much sweets so those
are all our pistons the hard part now is
we got a wire that to express six
different emotions on the face so that's
going to be kind of tough to do actually
let's take a look at the ravine is by
behind here so we have lots of lots of
space to work you know I should actually
get rid of that lab because I'm going to
fall on that at some point while we're
on this if I don't
sorry leva bye bye okay cool
so I feel what we should work on now is
maybe figuring out how we're going to do
the mouse on our pet here how are we
going to wire it because it's kind of a
complicated thing would be good to get
that out of the way pretty early on this
by the way pet names do you guys have
pet names the the one I'm kind of
feeling right now is maybe we'll call
our pet hop drop so one idea or maybe
every time it dies it should maybe give
it a different name but hop drop is what
I'm thinking at the moment unless you
guys have better ideas
but yeah the mouse is kind of
complicated I don't know how I'm going
to wire it to be honest at the moment
but I do know the method I'm going to
take for figuring it out so maybe I'll
share that with you and give you an idea
how how to figure these kinds of things
out so we're just going to build a
second Mouse here that we can work with
easily whoops so it's a five wide two
tall thing we're working with here and
we have there's six emotions on our face
that we're going to do but I think the
mouse only changes for four different
ways so we have our happy oops get our
happy face we have our neutral face meet
that's what it was
yeah neutral face and then we have our
sad face and then we also have a dead
face so for pet dies they look like that
so how do we go about figure out how to
wire this well you'll notice one of the
one of the tricks to it is we got to
figure out like if we were to there's
ten different Pistons here 14 total
counting eyes if we were to connect our
like six different wires to all 14 of
those Pistons individually the wiring
would be crazy that's not going to work
so what we got to do is look for
patterns or ways of simplifying the
wiring so with all these different faces
one pattern unnoticed
thing is ah Stilton the it's always
inverted like if this piston is is out
this one is not this one's out this one
is not it's that way for all these
different phases like neutral phase this
whole top row would not be extended
while this bottom one is so with that in
mind we might be able to do something
like this and just have a redstone torch
nope if you got to go up one more block
for that to work
well no work either it would kind of
work this is being powered at the moment
oh wait no it's not it's not won't work
so now we play around with it to figure
out how to make that work that's not
going to work which is a bit challenging
mmm see it's kind of hard because the
redstone torch will actually power so
many blocks below it like even a torch
here I'll power both if we can figure
this out though that'll reduce the
number of separate ways we have to run
the wire from ten ten different
connections to just five if we can do
that so I'll see if I can figure
something out here okay so I got rid of
the stake from oh there it is I want
that back from our item frames here and
instead I've been thinking about it
maybe for hunger let's use an apple it's
easier to see the steak was really hard
to see a little bit brighter for weight
I was thinking we could use an anvil for
health maybe a bone you know
take care of your bones and happiness a
flower we can change these these are
just ideas flower for happiness and this
kind of looks like a toy like a ball
maybe use that for attention like we got
to play with our pets if that gets slow
what does that look like good for now
okay so I did figure this out we got to
do something like this and so this is
going to add three three wide three tall
to our wiring but this allows me to
invert it perfectly without the Pistons
interfering with each other so we can
use that that takes our connections from
ten down to five which is a lot simpler
that halves it basically it's just I got
to connect to this block here that goes
to a torch which inverts it and then
goes to repeater to the left here and
also repeater down below so those
alternates so now can we simplify it
even more are there any other patterns
we can see in the mouth here there's one
I noticed as well this this column here
and this one is always the same with all
the faces and same with this and this
column they're always the same so if
this one's extended this one is extended
with all the faces or or vice versa like
if we go to a happy face just the
reverse of that this one is extended
this one's extended so this one's
extended this was extended so that
simplifies it a little bit as well we
can connect those together just see
creeper no um so maybe I'll try connect
those and see how that goes
I'm not really done with the redstone
here but I'll just show you this to give
you an idea of what we've done we went
from needing 10 different connections to
control our mouth all the way down to 3
control all 4 emotions we need or all 4
different mouths setups we need just by
using these 3 Pistons in different ways
so happy face we can make a neutral face
by flipping this all right we can make a
sad face by flipping these 2 then and
then we can make our dead face by
flipped in the middle one so there might
be more patterns to this yet I'm going
to look into it and if we find more
it'll get even simpler hopefully
assuming the redstone doesn't get super
complicated
if the Redstone is really complicated
you're not really simplifying things you
know what I mean
but our our emotions are going to need
the rect reflection of our happiness
level of the pet so there's going to be
5 different levels of thats only one
happiness will be I hate you face which
is let's let's get it here which will we
need this for a level 2 will be sad face
which again we need this for the same
thing so there's no change there so
that's simple we can connect those two
together but then when we get to level 3
here it's going to be neutral face so
then flip that that's neutral face level
4 and 5 is going to be happy face the
only thing different between the two is
the eyes so we have to take that into
account to wait what are we doing here
happy face happy face there we go
cool so it's not that tough to do really
just just a little bit of redstone um
but yeah I think that'll work out really
nice so I'm going to put that in behind
our our backing there and that should be
good to go whoa well that's going to be
it for today you guys but I did pick out
a comment for us to consider this guy
says a etho I was just wondering why did
you slow down on producing a lot of
videos a day like a few months ago you
had like like two or three videos a day
and now you only have one and sometimes
none at all
question mark I'm not mad but I'm just
wondering why you slowed down um well to
me I don't want to force videos for one
thing uh I I want I try to make my video
as good like that
I aim for quality over quantity that's
always my goal I do try to get one out a
day that's that's also another one my
goals but I don't want to force them I
otherwise I feel like I'm wasting
people's time if I'm not putting effort
into a video they're watching something
that I don't feel is as good as it could
be and you know they're not gonna like
it as much and it's just not it's gonna
be a downhill you know downhill going
going that's not the word I want
I tend think of the word I want so
quality over quantity but the other main
reason why there's been less videos is
because I don't have any filler videos
going on at the moment like uncharted
territories is ended don't starve as
ended those are videos that were very
easy for me to record and those series
have ended so they're easy for me to
record because I'm not really the guy
making the content with those videos
someone else
Amla made uncharted territories so he
put all the work into making the map and
then I just get to play through it and
have fun so typically a video only takes
me you know maybe twice as long to
record as it does
is playtime you know while with my LP
here takes me a lot longer to record the
natural play time of the video like
several hours have gone into this video
already even though it's only going to
be like 2530 minutes total and that's
that's kind of the issue because I have
three main series now I have my LP I
have mine crack and I also have feed the
beast all of those take quite a bit of
time because you know I put a lot of
time into it then also like the map
making series that's another time sink
if I ever do that so just my videos take
a long time to produce I might get some
more villa filler videos out soon people
complain about the filter videos though
is one thing I don't like and but
whatever you know I enjoy doing them as
well so every once in a while I'm going
to have filler videos but that's that's
the reason also January as far as like
money and YouTube goes it's not a good
month either so if I'm going to take a
break this is a good good time for me to
you know take it easy a little bit so
that's another reason there too but yeah
I think that's going to be it for today
guys thank you for watching and I will
see you again next time
you