[Music]
wow
all right guys this is exciting mo jang
have added a new block to the game
another one for the 1.16 update you know
i thought they were done with the update
i thought that was it
um yeah there's a new block called
cracked nether bricks
now technically it's been in the game
for quite a while but i just discovered
it today
somehow i missed this one uh i knew
about the chiseled one
but i didn't know they added this so you
just take uh
you pick the regular nether brick and
you smelt it
can't craft it that's probably why i
didn't see it
oh look at this the cracks are in the
exact same place on every block
now if you guys are worried about the
end reporters that i had forgotten about
them
no no no no i want to get ender porters
all around our world
trust me it just takes a lot of time to
set these up so i'm trying to do like
maybe one an episode
uh but i gotta like dig the tunnels run
the redstone hundreds of blocks that's
actually
surprisingly uh time consuming but we
got one over here now we gotta build a
building for this as well uh and
probably add a lot more to make it cool
but
for now we hit the button takes us to
our guardian farm so we can go to our
guardian farm and back now
look how fast that is too that's insane
yeah so to give you an idea of what's
happening here we're just
suspending our ender pearl in the bubble
column and then whenever we want to
activate it we'll teleport
and we've run redstone hundreds of
blocks to different locations in our
world
so that we can teleport hundreds of
blocks at the press of a button
basically
so that one takes us all the way to over
here we also had another one that we set
up previously this takes us to our
stronghold
which is a few hundred blocks away as
well
and basically you just load the pearl
hit the button and then go back
so this one it takes a couple seconds to
activate
um we tried to make like an instant wire
using
trip wires but i'm no i thought it was a
little bit slow because the chunks were
loading and there was a delay
but now i'm realizing it's probably got
a little bit of delay in the wire itself
it wasn't instant
after all because this one seems a lot
faster to me
yeah so for this end reporter we just
went for the old school instant wire
this has been in the game for many years
and
probably won't break anytime soon aha
yeah so last episode i
introduced the big project plan to you
guys the lab
the ethos lab as many of you are calling
it
uh we gotta get building that thing
today we gotta get it up and operational
after all without our lab how are we
gonna explain all the mysteries of the
minecraft universe
oh i know what you might be thinking
etho come on minecraft's over 10 years
old there's no mystery left in this game
you would think that but then can you
explain to me
how did i make the llamas walk around
sandy city you can't no
before today you probably even know
crack nether bricks existed
there's mysteries out there guys we
gotta discover them we gotta
we gotta explain them we gotta we gotta
see all the craziness and the lab is
gonna allow us to do it
i mean look at that guys can you explain
that
i could probably explain it to you but
i'm not going to tell you i believe that
as a little puzzle for you guys
now before we get to building our lab we
got to clear out a
massive area in that mountain hollow it
out
which got me wondering about the respawn
anchor now
speed mining has been the fastest way of
mining in this game
for the longest time technically tnt is
faster if you have the tnt
generally for tnt to be faster you need
to either dupe the sand or dupe the tnt
which is not something we do in our
let's play here so we need
to try respawn anchors so these emit a
massive explosion and they
should be faster than speed mining if
you can survive it
so we got blast protection pretty much
maxed out here
i want to see how much damage this
actually does
and we're gonna try have our shield
equipped to
take the blast as we right click this
thing
you ready for it i don't know if we can
do that
well it's survivable just barely though
oh snappers we might be on to something
here actually i wasn't sure at first but
i've done a bit more testing
and this might be a game changer idea
so the cool thing about respawn anchors
is they're kind of farmable right you
get the crying obsidian from the piglen
bartering and the
glowstone from villager trading so you
can acquire them
fairly easily and you need glowstone to
activate them
uh we got to clear out this room this is
where we're going to be putting our
block breaking lab we got to go about 15
to 20 blocks up in this area
which is a fair bit of land to clear
right so
here is what i've kind of figured out
still refining the idea a bit
but i think your respawn anchor
dirt respawn anchor dirt respawn anchor
all the way up to as high as you want to
go
so here's the secret sauce to it we're
going to put an anchor on the top this
will block the explosion from really
hitting us
and the cool thing is as we go down the
anvil falls with us
so i think this is all we got to do so
we right click the glowstone then we
right click the anchor
and we took like no damage
i got a fire resist on i got resistance
beacon and all that stuff at the moment
uh but they're not really necessary i'm
just trying to play it safe because i
don't want to lose my stuff
but yeah you just right click go down
right click down
right click go down all the way down
here now here
we could get hurt because i'm not above
it
and uh yeah it clears out a decent
amount of area
uh we might need to put it every block
though because it's leaving a bit more
junk than i expected
yeah let's go again here but we're going
to place it every block this time i
think it'll work a lot better actually
so just solid anchors all the way up
here
oh i don't have my shovel on me because
i'm afraid i'm going to die here
another thing you can do with this as
well if you don't mind wasting some
glowstone is you can just hold right
click if you want to fill it up all the
way
and then it pops but
that way you don't have to switch
between items
still a little nervous
[Music]
oh it's so cool though
isn't it i think that's so awesome
anvil still okay you got to keep an eye
on it oh i'm stuck on something here
i got to figure out how to center better
because the main thing i waste time on
is
trying to get back on the anvil here
kind of pushes you away
as you go down maybe i gotta jump
every time oh i'm out of ghost stone but
yeah look how much bigger this hole is
you gotta do it every block i guess
even though that seems to work
unfortunately i'm gonna have to mine
most this out manually still
because uh we don't have a good gold
farm and that was my only stack of
respawn anchors so
we're out very much mining later and
check it out we got a massive room
cleared out
oh look at all this space think of all
the things we could do with all this
space
this is perfect i just got a whole bunch
of stone and we have a place to put it
now
with that i think we're ready to get
started building the very first room
of our new lab project oh this is
exciting yeah so i tried to jot down a
couple notes here to help organize
what we're going to be putting in this
block breaking room so if it's related
to block breaking ideally we'll want to
put it in this room like haste 1 haste
two beacons
affect your mining speed so that's
related to block braking right so
somewhere in this room we wanna set up a
haste one and haste two beacon that we
can
control and turn on and off uh someone
reminded me of this last episode
actually i totally forgot conduit power
gives you like a haste one effect i
believe when you're underwater
i don't know we're gonna have to test
that out but uh we're gonna want to
conduit in this room as well
and a whole bunch of other things here
so if you missed last episode the short
version of this is we're trying to build
a lab
but rather than fill in the rooms of
that lab with
like uh machines that are purely
decorative that don't do anything
we're gonna use the game as content
for deciding what we put in our rooms
and we're going to try arrange them
in a way that looks nice and is
presentable and interactive
last episode we got started on the
mining speed timer i just added a couple
lights above it to represent seconds the
bottom row is for tenths of seconds
so for breaking obsidian something that
takes a bit longer we'll be able to
hopefully measure that still but yeah
this is gonna be the main machine of
this room the most important thing so we
want that center of the room front
front and center and a little creeper
you know i can't find any coal in this
mountain i guess it doesn't generate
this high up
so i'm all out of torches i got light up
this room it's horrible
um yeah so beacons i'm thinking we're
gonna put above the timer
to the left and the right and the
conduit up above in the middle
uh elder guardians probably gonna be up
above us in the center of the room
and because this is gonna be such a
massive room my plan is
to add four columns to it uh one over
there one
there one here one here they're going to
go up to the ceiling and look like
they're
supporting the roof so it doesn't cave
in on us right
um the plan with this is blackstone
columns we're going to get some glass
panes blue ones here for color
and i want to try something out with
this build end rods
are going to be used a lot probably
stack them like this in the middle the
panes don't connect to them
oh yeah check that out so the other
thing these columns do is they frame in
our timer
again this is our centerpiece of the
room we want our eyes to focus on that
and these kind of work as a border by
having them stick out a bit
forward and also by being a different
color
it makes our eyes attracted more to the
center here
the other thing that we should do is
lighten up that timer it's like
gray concrete black stone basalt let's
try use some of these other colors we
have in mind for the
our build palette here i think we're
gonna go for acacia it's close in color
to the lamps and i think we're gonna be
speeding through most of the building
this episode i mostly just want to show
you guys why we're doing stuff not
actually the building itself
basalt door frame i don't think so nope
we're going for red terracotta
so the formula i used to use when
building is i would pick three
maybe four blocks different colors
and then those are the only blocks i
would use in the build
and that works fine on a small scale but
if you're doing a big room like this
you want like a few different colors and
then lots of different shades within
those colors so
we're not just having red terracotta
we're having
crimson wood mixed in different oranges
and stuff
and kind of fade between the things you
know this happens to be every time i
build something it's like oh
i'm okay with it and then i start second
guessing myself a little bit like is it
too much detail
oh it might be too much detail might be
a bit
too chaotic i don't know uh we gotta
drop off a few things that the man cave
and also pick up a few things so if you
guys don't know i'm storing a lot of my
like stone and cobblestone over here now
it's just uh
plopped down a bunch of barrels and just
fill them up this guy
he's making a run for it again i cannot
get him to stay put
i think i'm gonna make him a special
little area
or something let's just put a composter
here maybe he'll go to that
oh he's going to it he's going to it
locked in
got to get our tools repaired you know
it happens to all of us you're mining
you're not paying attention
and bam you break your diamond pick it's
the worst feeling ever
nope not anymore now you can break
netherrite pics
oh i haven't done it yet but i'm gonna
be so sad when i do it
yeah so at first when i was designing
this i just did a rectangle shape for
the timer and it looked okay but it was
very plain
so i went back and i've added a whoo-hoo
at the top there
and that just makes it a bit more
interesting i think you can see we got
the most acacia in the center again
that's to help focus our eyes on the
center
and there's a little bit less on the
sides and also the center is the biggest
portion of the thing but yeah we are on
number two
of our list here block hardness stash so
we have a machine to figure out how fast
we can mine blocks
we need we need the blocks now so we're
gonna have
in these spaces here a stash of all the
blocks in the game
ideally i don't know if we're actually
gonna get to doing that but
we'd probably want a stack or at least
four blocks
of each thing in these chests and
hopefully
name them according to their hardness
level
um so we could either put chests here
barrels but i'm thinking we actually go
for
shocker boxes red ones it's a little bit
more expensive
though unfortunately but i think it's
gonna look
way better all right everybody so we're
gonna do a building montage now while i
talk about some of the feedback we got
on the last episode and over 4500
comments guys that's a lot of opinions
got some great uh feedback so thank you
for that guys um
uh it's very useful to see some of the
thoughts uh about it
so yeah is a very polarizing idea it
seems some of you are really in favor of
me doing this project and some of you
seem to be not so much in favor of it
some valid criticism got brought up that
i hadn't thought about actually
so i've taken that in and i think it
might adjust
how we do this project a little bit but
also i just want to say
we'll probably roll with it for a few
episodes and just see
if you guys like it or not because it's
hard to judge if you like it or not even
i don't know
what we're doing exactly until we
actually just get down and start
building it like we are today
so yeah i think once we make a little
bit of progress on it i'll check in with
you guys again and see if the thoughts
are the same or if they've changed it
all
and then figure out what to do from
there oh snappers
all right everybody well i've been
building like an absolute madman here
for the last few hours and
this is a big room this is a crazy room
i don't think most of the rooms we do in
this project are going to be quite so
big
and complicated this one's sort of
special i think but uh
man i have been having an absolute blast
working on this this is unlike anything
i've ever done before
and i think it's turning out pretty good
the the colors are a little
crazy and everything but i'm liking it
actually aha
anyways as you guys can see this room is
fairly busy there's a lot of stuff going
on here so i'm gonna try to give you a
tour now
and sort of point out what the stuff is
what it does and
what we need to do with this still i'll
start off by saying i ran out of time
there's supposed to be like some side
wings onto this still and i didn't get
to that
which is probably good though because if
you guys think of something i forgot
here
we'll still be able to add it pretty
easy um
also yeah we got this bridge over here
which is kind of cool
but there's an area underneath which is
also unfinished
i'm planning on putting like a glass
dome here uh with an exhibit in
somewhere around here that way we can
still look out and see the cool scenery
here
um which i think will be good but yeah
we added another column
like we had the original four and then
besides these ones i added another one
so we could put a staircase between
so you go up the staircase did you see
him
i saw him he's over here oh he can't get
to us though
so we'll probably have a door that leads
to the facility over here
we also can then go across the bridge
and get a pretty good view
good overview of the room here so you
can see the beacons nice and easy from
here
uh you'll notice i made the middle area
a little bit brighter red
and then the sides are the crimson stem
a bit darker
and it just kind of makes the center
more important i guess
uh this bridge is uh just the acacia
trap doors we've got some end rods in
here
kind of feels like we got some wiring
running under metal grating
is what i was trying to go for and then
chains is railing
um a couple lanterns and stuff again
we'll probably have another door here to
lead to the facility
now i want to clarify something here
when you guys look at this you're
probably like etho i thought you were
building a lab
i was expecting quartz and white
concrete bright colors
clean cuts uh typical lab stuff right
and i went for more of a grungy dark
themed thing here
so just to sort of explain that we're
splitting the project into two main
areas we have the wiki entries that's
what this is
these are going to be in general darker
themed more grungy looking
um but it'll depend on what we're
putting in the room like if we have
something involving
water it'll probably be aqua themed or
if we're doing something with plants
it'll probably be plants
nature themed you know but the other
part of the project
is going to be the facility the support
thing that connects all our rooms
together
and provides transportation and anything
else we might need right
that will be the typical lab super clean
bright white colors and stuff and we'll
have a clear distinction between the two
yeah so the reason we did this room
first the block breaking room
was because i figured it'd be one of the
most complicated ones to do
and if we could get through it we could
probably do any of them
because uh the challenging part about
this one is we have to combine
so many different factors together
because many different things affect
your mining speed
and be able to test them in different
combinations and see the result
so yeah we got our mining thing here we
can see what happens when we mine things
in water how it slows us down also
mining stuff floating in the air slows
us down so we got the ladder to keep us
suspended
we can test that out and when we break
the first block here
it starts the timer which i still need
to finish because it's not working
the seconds aren't doing anything at the
moment uh also i don't have the stop
working at the moment so it just keeps
going when we get to the last one but
it's supposed to stop when we mine
uh the five blocks here and then you can
see the total time
based on all the different factors
combined together so another one of the
factors
is what block you're breaking so we're
gonna have all the different blocks here
ideally in a perfect world um also what
tool we're using
really affects our mining speed so we'll
have a stash of all the different tools
here
from wood stone iron diamond netherright
to gold
slowest the fastest and we want
the unenchanted version but also
efficiency one
through five um so that'll take a little
bit to get together
we've got a few of them here um and then
there's axes swords will want to get
shears
you can put efficiency on shears and
also
we need hose in here too and i think
that'll cover all the tools if i'm
forgetting something let me know because
it's hard to keep track of all this
stuff
the other thing that affects our mining
speed though is
haste beacons right so we'll have some
controls over here
we can turn our beacons on and off we
got the numbers there to represent
if it's haste one or haste two so now if
we flick this one
we'll get haste one that's back on and
we also had to put it close enough to
this room
so that we actually get the effect like
if it was
i think if we stand over here we're too
far away so that was another challenging
thing to consider
and we can mix and match them and see
the effect but also conduit power
affects mining speed so we need to be
able to turn
that on and off so if we have the water
out here
get the water we sit in the water you
can see i think i got it off at the
moment
so we're not getting the conduit power
up here
but if we flick this on we just push a
block into the three by three by three
water there and that shuts it off
but if we retract it lights uh turn on
when the conduit power is active
and now when we go in the water here we
have conduit power
and the final thing we have in this room
is the cage in the middle
for the elder guardian so we can get his
mining fatigue effect we'll have a
switch to
drop him down we'll probably put a slime
block there so he'll
fall down and bounce around for a bit
and then give it to us
and then when we shut off the switch we
need to somehow
get him out of there and go up a bubble
elevator to the top of the mountain if
you're over 50 blocks away from him
you don't get the effect and that's why
i built this around y
180 or so so we have a bit of leeway
where we can store them up there and we
won't get the effect
but i'm not sure how we're doing all
that just yet and when we drop them down
the lights there will turn on as well
and that's the kind of plan with that
so how did we do here well let's check
out our list we kind of worked on
these six things and we're missing
just a few of them these are the a lot
easier to do than these ones though so
that's why i saved them for last ghost
blocks i don't know if we need to add
that into this room
maybe that would go into the a bug room
or something
but anyways unfortunately i did kind of
mismanage my time a little bit today and
spent too long building there
but we got a good start on the project
hopefully it gives you a better idea of
what we're doing
and like i said before we're only going
to be working on it like 20 to 40
percent of our time
i just spent a full episode on it today
because it's a new thing
uh but next episode we're probably gonna
be working on farms and we'll probably
do a little bit on it we'll see how it
goes
here's the comment of the day it says i
think this idea is really cool and has a
lot of potential
the only thing i'm a little worried
about is the scope
this project is just so huge
that being said this is not the first
time i've been skeptical of
a project idea when you propose the
nexus so many years ago it sounded
insane to me but you finished it and
it's so
impressive i think it will be fun
discovering and recording all the game
mechanics world generation
building techniques etc and i know that
if anyone could do it
it's you yeah so last episode i
laid out the ultimate goal of uh storing
all the information in this game
in that lab i want to
just clarify that's the
ultimate goal it's actually probably
impossible to do that
i'm just saying we're gonna go and work
on it as long as it we're having fun
with it
if i'm enjoying it and you guys are
enjoying it we'll keep working on it but
if it
gets boring or whatever that's it we're
done
sort of thing yeah kind of my idea with
the project is it's almost like we're
building a base
right uh except it has a purpose to it
not just like building stuff for the
sake of building it um
the thing about this game is like yeah
you can build make farms and farms serve
a purpose right well
technically they don't they just get you
resources if you don't actually use
those resources
farming in this game is kind of
pointless if you're
just building this game and the
buildings don't do anything they're kind
of pointless so i thought this would be
a good way of combining
like building with a purpose and
also the building is going to be
extremely expensive so it's going to
encourage us to build
more farms in our world and
do things that we don't normally do in
our world because the scope of the
project is
the whole game so that's kind of the
whole idea
behind the project and yeah we need to
get stuff i used our last beacons today
so we got to get a wither skeleton farm
set up and
uh yeah stuff like that right
anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
until the next one take care have a good
day
bye