well hello everybody this is Ito and
welcome back guys how you're doing
can you walk like this look at the legs
man they're just going wild so funny
backing up in Minecraft is the best
thing so if you walk forward legs go
straight if you back up they go sideways
right doesn't matter what camera angle
you look at even in this one and if you
swing your arm they just they just freak
out it's great
alright guys so here we are back in the
nether once again I just wanted to talk
about the changes here so as I predicted
you know I love looking at the comments
after an episode because I like to first
predict what I think you guys will say
and then when I actually read it I get I
get my answer as to like how you
actually react so I figured there would
be a lot of different opinions about our
our nether style here and yes because I
chose such a weird and bold design here
the opinions you guys give become very
different from each other and very
they're much stronger I should say it's
kind of a weird thing with the way we we
think if I built in a safe style you
know I wouldn't really get much of
reaction but since I built in such a
weird way here it's like some people
some of you guys are like etho I hate
the floor love the ice and then some of
you were like get rid of the ice but I
love the floor and then others like get
rid of the purple wool but keep all
these other things so it's very
interesting if you look at the comments
you'll know what I'm talking about it
was very very different from each other
anyway
since you guys can't decide on anything
it's up to me on this one so I might
make some adjustments here but for today
we'll keep it the same I did just spend
a bit of time here adding in a couple
more of these horse swapper things I'm
very happy about these are a little bit
tricky to build but I was able to build
three more here and just did a little
bit of terraforming in the nether as
well some of these tunnels are finished
now or not finished but you can actually
go through them with a horse which is
important so yeah you can see back there
how do I get three by three now ignore
that portal in the way but you can
actually fit a horse through there which
is good so what that's what we got to do
here we're gonna try get some horses in
the nether we also got to add speed
potions to these and into these droppers
here and I want to try you know I never
really played around with the saddled
pigs too much and and the carrot on the
stick so we might try that out today and
just see how fast those piggies actually
are okay so this is perfect opportunity
to try something here I don't know how
many of you saw this but on the
Minecraft reddit not too long ago
somebody posted that you can take an
enchanted fishing rod and a carrot and
make it how do you make a carrot on the
stick even I don't know if I've ever
done it like that okay
it actually makes an enchanted carrot on
a stick and it keeps enchantments which
is kind of cool
oh yeah I should probably mention that
they did fix in the newest version so
you got to be in an older 1.8 or earlier
to do the trick
okay mr. Fuji just right click yeah okay
I like never use saddle things before or
not very much I have used them before
come on guy I put a saddle on him and
suddenly he's king of the world he
doesn't want to listen to me
alright you go in here we're gonna do a
test here so I loaded up some speed
potions it might actually be faster than
a horse I'd have to modify this because
he can escape currently Oh might need to
modify it a fair bit you let me just
double-check it even works so he should
spring up yeah and then he gets stuck up
there good you could swap aru very good
or switcheroo that's what it's called
okay this one is for the speed potion
that is not a dispenser that is a
dropper that is a critical error on my
part just ignore that here let's do that
oh I all that was weird
I threw the potion and hopped on the
piggy at the same time there okay let's
go let's go this way
and I'm gonna right-click full speed
ahead
Oh his health is low that's cool you can
see his health now when you ride and you
have the speed potion okay it's very
slow compared to a horse although I
haven't used your ability on this maybe
I'm not doing it right good because it's
enchanted though okay it's getting a
little bit faster still way slower than
a horse though oh yeah now we used
irritability no okay
we're gonna stick with horses I thought
it would be a fun idea but now these is
Jesus waist lower alright guys I think
we can all agree saddled pigs need to be
made
lightning-fast like 16 blocks a second
at least because right now you would
never really want to use them they have
the the humorous effect but beyond that
horses are better in every way they can
even walk-ups blocks like that they can
jump
they have crazy mobility you don't need
to get it on the stick saddle pigs lose
out in every way so they should be made
way faster than horse
and that would make them even funnier
right I think so I think it'd be a good
change all right very good so we have a
bunch of horses in the nether here mr.
piggy still around - I don't know what
to do with him he's just happy to be
here honestly these are fully functional
which is great
horses are fairly fast as well which is
gonna be helpful I see a little bit of
netherrack when I open that gate
am I too picky should I not be bothered
by that I'm a little bit bothered by it
to be honest it's a very small thing no
let's try to forget about it okay so
what I want to do today is well we're
gonna head over to the man cave we
haven't really worked on the man cave
much lately and there's a few things
that need to be done there first off
we're gonna head over to the mushroom
the farm yeah this thing here this is
the thing we like never look in because
it's it's never used but yeah this is
supposed to be a mushroom farm it's not
really set up the main thing it's
lacking right now it needs to be made
more streamlined because I've I wanted
to use this a few times and when I go to
use it it's like well I don't have
anything here there's no bone meal
dispensers or there tools or mushrooms
to sling around so I think what we'll do
we're gonna take out this wall and we're
gonna just set up like chests and some
bonemeal dispensers that kind of stuff
just so that we can actually use this
and have everything here that we need to
operate it okay
so I've just been staring at it here for
a little while trying to figure out what
what we're actually doing with it I
guess I'm a break first ask questions
later type of guy should have planned it
first maybe I never liked how narrow
this door is even over there it feels a
little strange but it's it's acceptable
here I think cuz this path is too wide
but if we're gonna continue this like
this is not supposed to be the end of
the building there's a lot of free space
here I believe
the wall that if we want to build
something further on here we can so if
there's gonna be a door here I think I
want to make this wider just so it
doesn't feel quite so claustrophobic I
guess so we'll make this go up to the
top there yeah like that's okay move
this over a little bit I think we will
keep the yellow walls I do like the
yellow walls in here and we'll just set
up a few chests no dispensers not this
time okay so let's just lay out the wall
again why did I rip it down if I'm
putting it back we will do it
like Oh actually that might be okay to
bring it forward maybe like that and
then let's move this in one I probably
actually didn't need to tear it down
because I just rebuilt it all right and
then we'll just put a bunch of chests
here oops
like so and maybe yellow glass up here
so we can open our chests and it'll
still look pretty good against the clay
and then something like this whoa how's
that look okay I think it'll be fine and
there we go so I just set up on both
sides here it's very similar to what we
had but just a simple change now it's
actually functional we have stuff here
so for double chests in total this one's
gonna be for the red mushroom blocks
this one over the brown ones then we
have bonemeal down here so when I come
to the farm I can actually grow stuff
kind of important and then this final
chest is for the raw mushrooms and maybe
some axes we really need to get a silk
touch axe in here but I have one on me
right now
so it's fine so we basically come here
grab some bonemeal and whatever mushroom
you want to grow oh and I hit a and
just down here and some crafting tables
as well down here as well got the yellow
glass up there I think it's a nice
subtle thing now I never actually did
try growing red mushrooms here that's
not really what the farm was for for
some reason that they grow good but they
don't actually activate these detectors
but it's fine
yeah when I made this you couldn't get
these blocks before but I find they look
really good these blocks so I'm glad I
have a farm for them but I think the
main idea was just to get brown
mushrooms for fermented spider eyes when
I first made this so that's why it's
brown mushroom specific I forgot about
that I don't think I actually hooked up
the rest of the no blocks now that I
think of it do the lights change I can't
remember if I did that oh this this
light turns on that's right let's maybe
just take a look down below here I think
I have some stuff to do with the music
blocks oh snap not a good place to be
I've got some note blocks and it's
pretty much empty under all these so I
might want to add those in as well for
for the rest of them okay anyway just a
small little fix on this farm should be
operational now all right guys so next
up we're gonna head over to another part
of the man cave up at the mob farm here
I've been debating building arena for a
while here somewheres some where you
fight mobs you know it would be fairly
easy to set up because the number of
mobs we get from this thing is actually
pretty crazy I've made very little
effort to try to improve the efficiency
on it of course I say that in and under
falling right now
it was just nighttime I think ya might
take a little while to get going
here but we could for example just have
dispensers with water buckets in and a
bunch of signs running along here you
press a button the water will get
released and then we have a way of
preventing them from dying when they
fall here I also was curious about
something that I wanted to try you can
like jump off a building and right-click
on a horse and you won't take fall
damage I'm wondering if the same thing
applies to mobs like if they enter a
minecarts if the fall damage gets
ignored like if this catches and as
they're falling off that's possible
it might Oh drop them when he was dead I
didn't know it would do that that's
interesting might take a little while to
see it happen if it does happen and even
I'm not sure I'm trying to catch one and
have it not die basically oh I got it
nice very nice so it is possible I was
considering using this as a way of
catching them and like moving them off
somewhere but it doesn't seem like it
happens too often it's pretty rare that
actually catches them that's cool I was
curious about that okay so if we were to
build an arena we would collect the mobs
here you can see we get quite a few
probably wouldn't take too long to
collect a bunch of them and we would
have to build the arena nearby
accessorize they would be spawn so
probably behind this wall which has two
concerns for me basically this project
if we were to go ahead with it first one
is is there anything actually back here
that would get in the way of our
building so let's just check that out
the other thing though I'm worried if I
build an arena and spend all this time
trying to make a game out of it it's
gonna be boring
how can we make it interesting guys I
want to bring that to you how can we
make it fun to play how can we make it
difficult so that's it's actually
challenging what are your ideas I want I
want to know what you have to say it
looks like we have a lot of clear space
here for building not running into
anything so that's a good sign so you
could potentially build something fairly
large here it looks like so again if you
have ideas on how to make it cool arena
I want to hear it okay
all right everybody so next up we're
gonna do another quick experiment here
I've been considering ideas for that
rude goldberg machine that we might
build for episode number 400 we would
probably want to start it before episode
400 uh because it might take a little
while to build so probably right away
actually we need a good trigger block
though something that's visually
appealing and I think falling sand is
the winner for that everybody loves
falling sand right and I believe this
trick still works actually tell you what
let's do it like this I think this still
works but I just want to make sure this
is not a very well-known trick I don't
think but you can have two tall flowers
like so and then I think you can put
sand on top I haven't tried this in a
while so I'm very much hoping it still
works like so all right and now we're
gonna line a sand and I think you can
break the dirts
no no they fixed it just terrible
oh why why did you fix it Mojang it was
such a good trick you used to be able to
make sand floats not too long ago ah
maybe I'm doing it wrong I thought
that's how you did it though maybe just
let me try something here
can we update it with water I think any
updates gonna do that does the problem
oh that would have been so perfect if we
could make falling sand oh wait a second
okay if we do this nope
darn it
now I'm sad I was really hoping that
would work okay well it used to work
with lily pads as well let's just double
check I think they fixed that as well
it's something like this I think you
either put the block units nope
not looking good you either put the
block in it or you just broke the lily
pad I can't remember
that's nope
maybe a torch would do it now all right
so we're not totally out of Hope here
there's a couple other options they're
not quite as good though you can for
example do signs like so and signs on
signs the only downside with this is
they all break instantly and with the
falling sand it's fun to watch it sort
of cascade you know that's not quite as
good you do get the Cascade effect oops
as it breaks upward though so it's kind
of like a wick
but then when it hits that they all go
at once so that's kind of okay not as
cool though the other thing there is
there's a trick you can do with vines as
well let me see if I can figure that out
maybe not go so high here actually let's
do it like this I think if you have a
vine there you can do that
no oh somehow you can attach whoa a vine
to the bottom I thought that was it
maybe I'll try a block that's nuts and
and stick the vine on that and then the
sand on that I thought it would stay if
I break this no it kills it hmm so
either I'm doing the trick wrong or I
think a lot of the vine tricks got fixed
actually because you used to be able to
for example here let's try this out
whoa whoops not that not that if you had
a thing of vines like this right if you
placed a sand block in there it used to
float now it doesn't it just falls that
I know for sure but for some reason it's
changed
can't place that on there no okay I
place this upward in this it doesn't do
anything doesn't do anything
uh-huh we can do something like this but
it's pretty much the same as the torch
trick over here it's nothing to to cool
like that that is cool but it's not
unique right another idea for a trigger
block instead of using falling sand a
lot we might try burning leaves but I
don't know how reliable that'll be or
how fast it'll be either just gotta burn
along like it would burn along and then
it would activate something basically I
think it'll be too slow and unreliable
but might be cool have a little bit of
that it's gonna burn out snow it's still
going pretty slow though but anyways
guys that is gonna have to do it for
today's episode I'm gonna keep
brainstorming ideas for the Rube
Goldberg machine room with a B not a D I
always say rude goldberg machine buts
rube which is a few people were
wondering what is it's basically a
complicated machine that's fun to watch
it doesn't really serve a purpose it'll
activate something at the end but it's
it's just for sure
basically so lots of crazy stuff happens
in the activation a lot of unnecessary
stuff and it's fun to watch basically
but you can look it up on YouTube for
example and you can see some some really
cool examples I'm sure anyway here is
the comment for today this is in regards
to the minecart sheep farm again the
flying sheep farm says what if you took
like a big stack of sheep in mine carts
on top of each other like with the
minecart dispenser at the slime track
thing then you have a piston on a clock
to push them onto a track just an idea
not sure if it will work so those are
called Pez minecart dispensers by the
way I don't know if people still use
that term but where you have minecart
stacked on top of each other it's a
great idea it would work perfect except
one little thing the sheep need to eat
grass to regrow their wool and if
they're up in a stack of mine carts they
won't be anywhere near the grass they
have to be on top the grass to actually
eat it so they won't regrow their role
in the sheep farm so we have to keep
them on the ground
unfortunately otherwise it would be
great but thank you for the suggestion
thanks for watching everybody I'm gonna
say goodbye for today and I'll see you
again in the next episode take care
bye my