[Music]
greetings everybody
this is etho welcome back to um have my
tongue
welcome back to
another episode one sec all right i'm
fine
i'm fine don't worry don't call 9-1-1
all right wash your hair everybody today
make a point of it
the threat is real it could happen to
you next
okay so last episode we talked about our
mob system here how we're gonna
possibly redo all this snow stuff
you can probably guess that it's it's
happening i've already started tearing
it down
so yeah we're going to build a pyramid
here guys i'm kind of excited to do this
i've never built a
pyramid before i probably stink at it
but we will try we will
endeavor to endure and prevail and
and build something magnificent
i'm still thinking about the hair on my
tongue it's messing with my brain
okay so i'm gonna tear this
this sucker down uh we'll probably have
to go
collect a whole bunch of sandstone today
too to build the pyramid
now let's talk about it for a second
okay
there's there's a couple ways we could
do it
now the most common way is to do just a
straight up staircase
totally constant no change um
that's probably an easy way of doing it
i'm going to try to do
more of an aztec type of pyramid it's
going to be
aztec shape but i'm going to still build
it out of sandstone usually when people
do that they build it out of stone
so we might go like five blocks up and
then
go sideways three or four blocks
let's try for four and then go up again
for the next level so
we'll do it in levels all the way up and
i think that'll look
pretty cool maybe have a staircase
running up the middle
but we'll we'll see um let me tear this
thing down first and then we'll get to
it though
and today we say goodbye to everyone's
favorite tree of all time
the most beautiful thing we've ever seen
is gone
and there we have it everyone the deed
is done the snow
is gone quick let's build something
before i regret what i've done
oh man i always have that fear when i
tear something down
and try to replace it i'm always worried
whatever i replace it with is going to
look worse
and then it's like oh i'm such an idiot
why did i do that
so hopefully that's not the case today
um
the animals they got moved up by the ice
cube there so you can kind of see the
mammoth from here and the penguins up
over there too
everything else is gone though and i'm
starting to lay out the framework for
the building
it's not going to be very big is it
which is good we'll get it done today
most likely at least the exterior um
so i'm gonna go get some red sandstone i
want to try red sandstone just so it
stands out a little bit more in our
desert
so it's a different color and then we
will get to it here
so i've been all over the mesa biome
here looking for red sandstone i can't
find any
where does it spawn guys i don't know
i've never looked for it before
but no there is none there's barely any
sand either
because i think of the because the
amplified terrain makes it so
it's very little land that's actually at
this level here
most of it's raised and yeah it's just
very very little red sand even
but hopefully there's enough we got
quite a bit here i'm gonna head back
soon
all right so here we go we are doing the
building now
uh first step the first thing i'm gonna
do is just copy this
basic frame this shape here all the way
along the side and not going to do
anything fancy to it right away we'll
add details
step by step to it i think and then once
we get one side
totally figured out we'll copy it to the
other three
um that's probably the the easiest way
of figuring this all out
all right well major red sand shortage
unfortunately
so we're going with regular sandstone
and we got one side
kind of done here now it doesn't look
very good does it
no there's no detail to it so it just
looks like a giant
blah giant blob of nothing we need
stuff for the eye to focus on for it to
get better
so let's let's get to the detail adding
shall we
uh this is really the only good side for
for making a front i think because we
kind of got a hill here
got the reeds on that side this side
over here we have the trees
so we're going to make this side over
here the front
if i can figure out how to get there
again okay
so i want to try to put a staircase in
maybe starting at this height let's make
it
seven blocks wide
and try that out okay very good and now
we're going to put in a main entrance
to the pyramid probably the full width
of the staircase here
let's go like this and maybe
curve it a bit yeah let's do that and
then like do the staircase thing like
this
maybe some half slabs over here too
and if we want to make it more detailed
we can add like something that
sticks out a bit
yeah uh-huh okay we're having a bit of a
problem here
i can't find any blocks i really like
with sandstone
like this looks just kind of weird
doesn't it
we need more than just sandstone though
we need something with contrast
something to
to highlight stuff like for example we
have all these levels to the pyramid
we need some way of differentiating
between them because right now it just
looks like one giant flat wall
you can't see that it's 3d even so we
need like something
to highlight each of the levels like
maybe
slabs or something running across the
top
but what block do we use to do that i
don't know
spruce might be okay
okay well if we put spruce on every
level we get this kind of effect
which i kind of like but i'm not sure i
want to do it with spruce
struggling quite a bit with this this
build
i don't build a sandstone often and i'm
starting to know why
i used to use it a lot but i never like
mixed blocks with it it was this pure
sandstone always
because i don't think there's many
blocks that go with it too well to be
honest
usually people use lapis in like a
yellow block like gold or something
so i might just might just try that
we'll see
but uh here let's let's try add some
detail
so i was thinking we should have some
arches
at the front here like some
some cool design nothing too fancy
we'll just do this see the thing is
i want to mix a block with the sandstone
but if i can't just use wood because
wood isn't used as a structural support
for something like a pyramid
so it doesn't make a lot of sense i need
another type of stone block
to use instead and all i can think of is
nether brick
and nether brick i don't know
it might stand out too much
all right let's do a little bit of this
does this meet up with the staircase
over here
not quite let's just try some some wood
all right uh maybe
maybe maybe let's put a block of lapis
here just to try this
maybe maybe uh
there's other clays too which might work
i grabbed this stuff it looked
kind of decent let's see let's put some
yellow by this and just see what happens
yellows oranges browns
and blues i think is our limits
um still experimenting one two
three probably like one the most but
it's
yeah why is this so tough
no it's like a polkadot pyramid
all right everybody so i think maybe we
will just leave this as it is for today
i have tried so many different things
and i am just struggling trying to find
something i like i don't know
sandstone oh i used to love you so much
but now i just
can't work with you i don't know why
um i tried adding some palm trees up
here i thought it would be a good idea i
do kind of like the idea but
even that's not really working because
you can see the sky through it and that
that doesn't look so good so i don't
know if you guys have ideas of what
blocks i should use or what
shapes or patterns i should do here let
me know in the comments
and uh i'll try i'll try to figure it
out i've really tried today but it's
just not working
so i think either i need your input or i
need to go into creative world and just
mess around with it a whole bunch
all right all right let's go do
something else
well i got some bad news everybody i
just checked it looks like
bloopy bubbles and magikarp they're all
gone
they left us they disappeared i don't
know where they went
but they're not here so if you're trying
to keep fish in a koi pond
get rid of the water streams i saw them
swim up these a few times and they must
have like
got onto the pathway and then bounced
around and
probably bounced down here or
or maybe down here somewhere and and
died most likely
because i have not seen them i kind of
checked around a bit
oh that was a pigment okay anyway
so i was thinking about what we should
do next uh
it might be a fun challenge to build
like a firework
factory fireworks stand or some
some gizmo for putting together
fireworks basically
currently this is my fireworks setup
over here
it's not too fancy but we got some
gunpowder some glowstone
and what's left of the dyes some paper
nothing too great
do these work i can't remember if these
work these used to crash the game
oh i think they're okay now these are
the ones that don't have a fireworks
star on them
when they first came out they would
crash you but they seem okay now
okay so let's plan this out let's start
designing our firework gizmo here
so with the stars you can have i think
up to eight colors per
star is what it looks like here
and then there's also a bunch of shape
modifiers you can put on it
and then there's glowstone and diamond
also
oops so feathers make it a burst
firework gold
nuggets make it a what was it
trying to think i think they're the star
ones and then these are the big
fireworks
like the big explosion can we use
more than one of these i don't think you
can right
no the recipe goes away okay so
we can use either this one this one or
this one or none so that's four options
there's also the option of using
a head like a wither skull head
but that's going to be too expensive so
we'll never we'll never do that
i doubt so we're not going to even think
about it
um then there's also like the glowstone
and the diamond i think
one of these makes a trail i think one
it's the diamond that makes the trail
and the glowstone makes it twinkle
and you can have i'm pretty sure you can
have both of those if you want right
can you do both yeah it lets you do both
okay
and then you can have the shape modifier
too
all right so the way i think we'll do it
we'll make a
stall for putting together the stars
first
and then we'll just drop a bunch of
stars in a chest
and then we'll have another area for
putting together the firework
itself and we'll get a random number of
stars given to us
and we will put together the fireworks
that way
all right so we're trying to make it
random like
make the system give us a random number
of items to create a random firework
basically so
we will be using droppers to do that
with randomizers
and let's go start setting this up
now we just need to find a spot for it
and i think over here is
pretty good it's sort of out of the way
it's not something we would use all the
time
and we'll just make like a door to enter
it over here and then i think there's a
bit of space for us to work
i'll just hollow this out and for the
most part
most the wiring is going to go in the
roof i think or in the ceiling here
all right so let's get to the building
now
i don't know exactly what we should do
or how we should lay this out but we'll
just try
what i have in mind first so basically
i'm thinking we'll put
most ingredients in the roof here like
all the dyes all the fireworks
modifiers additions whatever they'll go
in the roof here we'll have a
water stream here let's get a bunch of
droppers going here
water stream will carry them all to a
one by one hole
and then they'll fall down on our head
so we're gonna use pack dice
i wonder is that enough head space
yeah it should be good that's four
blocks up all right
so let's get this laid out and each of
these droppers
we'll need 16 of them for the dies and
then
probably another do i don't know eight
or so
for the rest of stuff
so we got 22 in total here 16 for the
dies and then we need six more for these
other things
every fireworks there take takes a piece
of gunpowder
but then these other five are optional
all right
so the ingredients get delivered to us
in the middle here they'll fall on our
head and then they'll probably be like a
hopper or something we craft this star
then we throw it in this hopper and then
when we throw it in the hopper
it detects that and tells it to send us
more ingredients to make the next star
so
the cycle will continue as long as we
keep throwing the stars
in the hopper here is the plan all right
but now we got to randomize what we get
so what we'll do is set set up a whole
bunch of these randomizers much like how
we did the
random random music in the end there all
right so we have a whole bunch of wire
it's got to go three spaces and then we
have comparators running along here
oh and these go to a dropper hopper
combo it's actually very close
to the outside i might need to move this
further
yeah i almost definitely need to
actually this is just a little
too close to the wall all right
um that's not in the right spot
has to go down here and then we'd need
to run another wire over here
to trigger the droppers
but basically with these we'll be able
to set whatever random probability we
want for each ingredient
so certain colors we might not want as
often as others
like black for example might not want
black too often make that a rare one but
the super colorful
or the bright colors like lime and that
we might
we might want more often um
and then again some of these ingredients
like the diamonds we might not want as
often as
as the glowstone for example so yeah we
can play around with the probability
that way
but i guess we gotta move all this a
little bit further
over here very good we
just about have this thing up and
running totally we're gonna try it out
now
oh and i'm trapped in here i thought i
could teleport through there but no
i put i put a thing glass over top
because some of the items are flying out
uh of these droppers like they would
shoot over top sometimes
but yeah this is what we got a whole
bunch of randomizers here
most of them i just left as a one out of
nine
chance and then we got all the items in
these
and i think the glowstone i i left as a
one and three chance or one and four i
can't remember
and then i'm gonna split this these last
six over here
i'm gonna make them have a lower
probability i haven't decided
how to do that exactly but these are the
colors we don't
want as often like green
white uh light gray gray
black and brown these don't look very
good in fireworks so i don't want them
happening as often
the rest of the colors though are just a
one to nine chance for right now we
might have to tweak it
but let's let's do a few test runs here
and just see what we get
okay we lucked out
pretty poorly there we didn't get any
colors
which was something i was a little
worried about
uh oh
how often does that happen i did not
think that would happen very
often if it ever did all right
let's try it a couple more times i guess
um there we go let's make one more just
to use up this
all right yeah let's try it again
we got purple and red
and one gunpowder okay that's not a bad
start that's pretty good let's try it
again
just one gun pounder all right so
there's some issues
that time we got a bunch we got a fire
charge
so it looks like we'll have to lower the
probability on a few things
lower or raise make it more likely we'll
get things
that's what i'm trying to say all rights
but yeah basically just get random
colors random effects
make your stars from that this time we
just got light blue
and yeah that happens a lot actually i'm
surprised
where we don't get any colors again we
didn't get any colors
all right anyway that's the basic idea
behind the firework thing we'll have to
set up a little bit more to it and make
something nice uh
over here as well like so it's not just
a rough thing
but i want to keep this so that we can
still access the droppers if we ever
have to refill it
i'm going to keep that open i think
all right everybody it is that time
again let's wrap up this episode
so let's just check something here first
i saw one of our escape fishies
oh yeah and look at this i've never seen
that before
so many armored zombies because we were
spending all that time building the
pyramid i think
oh hey where'd you come from
[Music]
ouch okay um
yeah if they have feather falling on
their boots they don't die when they
fall down so
usually it takes a long time for for any
number to accumulate here
but today we got tons what was i going
to say oh yeah look at this
who is it it's magikarp he has found his
way over here apparently
um he should be perfectly safe in here i
don't think he can escape anywhere
he could possibly swim up one of these
i don't think he'll be able to get out
though he might die
from falling though if he does that
i'm not entirely sure but anyway
here is the comment it says you should
try connect your world a bit more
not in the way of portals but actual
roads and then names for the roads and
the areas they go through
even though it would be tedious and the
fact that you probably wouldn't use them
a lot i
still feel it's worth it because of how
it gives flesh to the skeletal structure
of your world
i recommend you start with a king's road
going straight to the amplified base
make sure to not destroy the natural
terrain too much when laying it
plant big trees when approaching the
amplified terrain to avoid seeing the
horrid
transition you know i've never even seen
that like
oh yeah maybe i have actually i can't
remember where
it switches to amplified going that
direction
but uh yeah it's a long ways to amplify
base i don't think i would ever lay a
road that far
but i do like the idea of having roads
it just
they would take a very long time
i don't like this
this guy's been here a while he's got an
egg
all right i'm gonna kill him
how did
we got two iron golems here now there
used to be one over here how did that
guy get
in there
huh that's kind of weird
because he's been up there for a long
time
all right anyway here's the fireworks we
made today
this is not a good place to do fireworks
wait a second let's go outside
yeah let's just double check that the
fireworks we made actually look good
because that's an important part too
this is a straight up blue one oh with
the after
after effect on it that's the light blue
one
[Music]
that's the purple and red
yellow and pink that one was pretty nice
straight up red with a twinkle
i like that one so i think maybe add
we got to add a couple more colors to it
like make them more frequent so that's
the fireworks usually have two or three
colors mixed in
would be good because when it's just one
color that they're a little bit plain
but anyway hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode
thank you for watching have a wonderful
day
[Music]
bye