hey everyone this is etho do you know
what's going on here do you I think you
know I am shaft mining that's right
looking for diamonds looking for
redstone I hate to admit it but that's
what I'm doing I haven't gone shaft
mining since alpha days I vowed never to
do it again because I hated it hated it
you're looking for diamonds and you
would blow through your diamond pickaxe
looking for diamonds faster than you
would actually find them it was stupid
absolutely absolutely garbage but I ran
out of redstone the other day so I
figured I'd had to do something about it
and really these days shaft mining isn't
so bad because it's actually kind of fun
I'm enjoying this I I realized if I have
an efficiency for pic or five or
something like that or or with
unbreaking on the diamond pics are going
to last a long time the mining is going
to go fast and not only that I got a
fortune pic as well so I'm getting tons
and tons of diamond doing this tons of
redstone it's great in fact I've like
I've mined a shaft like this about a
thousand blocks and in total I got about
40 diamonds from that it was crazy 40
diamonds I think about eight stacks of
redstone just from going a thousand
blocks I don't know if I was lucky or or
what's going on but again I'm having
pretty good success here found some more
diamonds found a ton of redstone here
finally have some diamonds guys
that was really bugging me before I
could not find any but now I'm I should
be good for a long time especially if I
continue shaft mining here yes that's it
so before I start mining here I decide I
should figure out what the best tide is
to define diamonds in redstone so I did
a little research on on that because I
think recently I think in the 1.0.0
patch diamond positioning has changed
it appears lower then it used to or
something so in the past I used to just
go by what somebody posts it on the
forms he had like all these graphs and
statistics on what the best height and
everything is to find all the different
ores and the concentrations and how they
all compared so the other day I created
a new test world and I used mcedit to
scan the layers one at a time to see the
concentration of diamonds gold redstone
iron all that stuff
and I found I could be incorrect about
this but this is what I found this is
the ideal height to go shaft mining when
your y-coordinate says ten point six
that's that's what I found the best for
these four layers the one before you
this one here this one and the one above
you seems to have the highest
concentration of diamond and redstone
from my tests anyway the only problem
with mining at this level though is a I
think this is two blocks below the lava
level so when you're digging there's a
good chance you're going to run to big
lava pools and if you're not careful you
could definitely hurt yourself
I think there's a dungeon over there
I'll have to check it out so this is
what I've been doing just converting it
using water budgets and then mining
through the Obsidian with my diamond
pickaxe doesn't seem to take all that
long especially if you have efficiency
also with my torch placement here I've
just been placing them every 10 blocks
apart to make it easy to figure out
where to put them so I'll I'll mine
through here then on my way back all
I'll place all the torches every every
10 blocks you really only need to place
them every 13 blocks for to prevent mob
spawning but this a lot simpler if you
do it every 10 blocks see 250-260
and I'm not just shaft mining either I
have to admit that this might be for a
transportation system in the future
you'll notice it's on it's following the
256 where this cross occurs but that's
that's something for another day I'll
talk about Lu all this stuff I got
eighty diamonds whole stack of iron
blocks plus like another half stack to
Rose the redstone here
it's a good thing spaz doesn't know
about the time machine uh that was good
I like that
admit it I had to go in there you
thought it was real for five seconds at
least you thought it was real
that's good that's what I wanted okay
yeah so we got lots of stuff here I
might start working on the trivia game
again soon if I do probably won't go
into super detail about it I'll do most
of it off camera cuz cuz you've seen it
already I do have a lot of stuff all
these blaze rods start that for my tools
bobble this is my random junk it's not
really junk there's there's little stone
and stuff in here here lots of uh lots
of spider eyes more random stuff yeah
anyway okay so today ah this is going to
be the Mythbusters episode there's a few
things in this game that I've been
wondering about and we're going to check
whether or not they're true or not
whether or not they're true or not does
that make sense
I could have worded that better yeah
because I've been doing certain things
I'm wondering if I should be doing that
or not some people say I should some
people say I shouldn't like blocking
fall damage I have no idea if that
actually does anything so we're gonna
we're going to check out some things
that have been on my mind alright so the
first thing we're going to check out
here is a what armor is actually used
against or what it's used for a lot of
you probably know the answer to this
question but I honestly don't know
exactly everything it blocks I know for
sure it blocks melee damage from mobs it
blocks explosion damage for sure but
things like fall damage poison
suffocation drowning those two really
the same but they might be handled
differently in the game and fire damage
I'm not sure if Armour blocks against
those so we're going to check that out
today and this is important to me
because ever since I lost my wheat farm
I've been eating these spider eyes as my
main food source they're not bad
actually because I have so many of them
from the spider XP farm I only eat them
when I'm up in a safe place so because
they take your hearts away but once you
fill up your hunger bar they come back
anyway so it doesn't matter but I'm
worried it's wrecking my armor by eating
these so the best way of testing this
please probably just get a fresh suit of
armor on it has no damage bar on and
then if I eat one and there's a damage
bar on the armor after then Armour is
blocking damage it's not blocking damage
from the poison okay so that's one thing
it doesn't work against let's try
suffocation this is just just some
things I've been wondering about
probably common knowledge Hill here we
go yeah okay
so ooh jarring does a lot of damage
action that's taken full hearts away
yeah so that does not affect armor you
take full damage from drowning we should
try suffocation I got scared there let's
try that again
chickened out now that's as quick as
drowning was actually okay that doesn't
affect armor now let's see what else do
we have to test fall damage and fire
damage
hey Armour is still at full don't try
this at home kids be safe ouch that was
even that far yet okay does not block
fall damage that's for sure
one last thing the test is fire damage
this is kind of two parts actually
because I think yeah when you first
touch lava you take five hearts damage
if I remember right and then you can
catch on fire which does another type of
damage possibly yeah this is dangerous
hmm all that affected it doesn't do I
thought Lapidus damage did more click
away more hearts in that so when you
first touch it
is not okay we're going to have to do
this a little differently then touching
lava does affect armor what about the
actual flame like when you catch on fire
we'll have to figure that out separately
I think we only really need to put boots
on or something okay so all I'll just
have them on the ground here touch the
lava then one on my fire I'll put the
boots on and see if it gets the damage
bar then you catch fire
aerial well I'm going to die for science
let's check out our armor a date then
take damage from the actual flame of
being on fire but touching the lava did
cause it did absorb deborah touching the
lava did touching the lava did it affect
the armor yeah okay moving on yeah okay
so the next thing we're going to check
out here is whether or not we can have
our fall damage using a sword by
blocking with it I've heard a few
different things about this some people
say you can some people say you can't
I've had some people say you have to be
looking straight down for it to work ah
that last doing that seems a little
fishy I've been doing it recently though
just because that's what people have
said is it true or not though that's
what we need to find out and judging on
the fact that the armor doesn't block
fall damage I'm almost thinking the
sword doesn't either just just through
my Jess on it so we're just going to do
a straight fall here have no armor on
right now let's see how many hearts
damage I take just from walking forward
four okay now we're going to do it with
a sword
blocking same exact spot and we will try
first of all blocking facing forward and
if that doesn't work we'll try blocking
facing down dum-dum Oh health
regenerates so slowly so this should
give us two hearts damage if it actually
works
aha
does not work if it's facing forward at
least let's try facing down I've been
blocked in like an idiot this whole for
like a few weeks now oh well so I'm
guessing it doesn't block suffocation
poison fire damage and drowning either
probably just things that Armour effects
the sword effects as well if if I was to
guess maybe we'll try a few of those ok
facing straight down now four hearts so
no does not work that maybe let's try
drown ourselves
I really don't expect it to work though
so we were taking about one hearts every
drowning hit so let's see if this makes
it half a heart nope
yeah so it doesn't block drowning damage
pretty sure it doesn't block any of
those things
it'll probably block the labid damage so
like on contact
I almost almost want to try swimming
lava doing that but the flame will get
me anyway that seems to okay well took
it too far
okay there was another thing I was going
to check out here I noticed like when I
enchant my armor it seems to wear out a
lot faster than when I don't enchant it
and I thought maybe that was a glitch
with the game like something wasn't
being calculated properly but I just
checked the wiki and I got my answer -
what's going on ah if you have armor
that has protection one on it protects
you against environmental hazards so I
think if I have this on it will protect
me from fall damage pretty sure normally
we take four hearts from this three and
a half Oh
oh that's that was unexpected it didn't
damage the armor even though it seemed
to protect me maybe it gives you the
benefit without any any sacrifice that
would be cool let's try it one more time
we were taking four hearts damage from
this fall before three hearts still no
damage okay
okay ah as I'm expected the thing is
that doesn't explain why my armor seems
to be wearing out faster I thought it's
good it was absorbing environmental
damage and taking durability for that
but if it's not taking the your ability
even though it's giving me the benefit
I'm still confused okay so that kind of
blew my mind a little bit like I said I
haven't done a whole lot of vintage
handing yet pretty much the only thing
I've enchanted is pickaxes I haven't
really played around with the armor too
much but I'm learning a lot here today
so I'm doing another test here again
kids don't do this at home this is being
done by that trained professional here I
know what I'm doing I got two pieces of
armor with blast protection on I'm
wondering if it's going to use up
durability if I blow myself up here
that's what we're testing out so I'm
going to go right to this corner here
after I detonate this and see what
happens so two hearts damage and it did
take durability I'm really confused now
because it really shouldn't have if the
protection stuff wasn't taking fall
damage
for durability huh my world is shaken
here nothing's making sense okay we're
going to do that same thing again this
time though I don't have any armor on I
just want to see how much those two
armor points helped protect me with the
with the blast protection if you see how
much it helps go to the exact same
position four hearts so it half the
damage huh Wow let's blow ourselves up
again here this time again I have no
armor on but I'm going to try block the
explosion with my sword to see if it
does anything because I kind of think it
does but I want to know for sure so we
should take two hearts damage from this
approximately same position yeah perfect
okay we're going to do a combo this time
got the the two pieces of blast
protection on so that half did before
and now we're going to also half it
again with our with our swords so we
should take I think one harder damage
same position perfect we're going to do
one final test here with the TNT says
moved on from Mythbusters episode two
etho fascinated with the new armor
system but the thing I want to check out
like normal armor or right now we have
two armor points out of ten and
according to wiki each of these reduces
damage by 8% so 10 would reduce by 80%
to here reduces damage we take by 16%
so without armor we took four hearts
damage with this blast protection stuff
we have that so I'm guessing that means
blast protection one is about three
times more effective than regular armor
if it's if it has an enchantment for for
protecting you against explosions
because that's about half two times 16
is 48 percent and that's that's the belt
what it was so right now we're going to
switch this out for regular armor and so
it will only be 16% and that means we
should take either three and a half to
three hearts damage if I if I use my
calculator properly here just wanted
wanted confirmation go to the same
position why doesn't the world make
sense sometimes yeah I really don't know
what I figured out wrong there I know I
said something wrong I said 2 times 16
is 48 I meant to say 3 times 16 is 48 48
percent anyway
we're going to end episode here today
thanks for watching but before we go
it's going to run through some of these
new trees we have here new donors I also
have corrected us some people's names I
got wrong before so that should be all
fixed hopefully I do my best but
sometimes I make mistakes so thank you
everybody new here also maybe I'll say
one thing a lot of people wonder if my
name is etho or Ethos like what is ethos
lab the the s in ethos lab is possessive
so procced raphy s except they can't use
apostrophes in your channel name so
yeah my name is Ethel without the S on
but I really don't care if people call
me ethos and so normally I just ignore
it but in my channel comments a lot of
people have been getting into arguments
about you know is it ether or ethos its
etho but really I don't care if they get
it wrong thing that does bother me
though is when I see people people
arguing in my channel comments and then
I have to go through it to remove all
the spam so if someone calls me ethos
just let it slide it's fine I don't I
don't mind okay
and I think that's where we're going to
end it here so I'll see you guys again
next time I hope you learn something new
here I know I did and maybe it'll show a
few clips of some multiplayer before we
end this the same time everything opens
with pistons and then shoot the creeper
pretty much chooses who he goes for
don't work yeah you could have it like
revolving on a minecart
and then the member dhadges doing
arresting people in the bed just stop
and fools cool only thing you can do is
place blocks right and vanish do
everything out so you can't place blocks
or use doors and stuff yes but you can
see each other if you vanished as well
Dobin punch pause balls in the face
about four times and left oh great
Superman moment there it just needs to
be a signing my now saying this has been
either approved there you go yeah that's
how new let's introduce that you know
something's good in Minecraft
it's either approved yeah that's right
still tested etho approved