[Music]
hey hey welcome back everybody this is
etho thank you for joining me again for
another let's play episode how are you
guys doing today you're doing okay
you're doing all right you you
practicing your slow motion running like
me very importance it kind of tickles
though I should get out of here why I
figured out something else today
this is amazing right let's get up here
oh well oh no that's not it
all right okay there we go
this is my my earthquake simulation -
are you ready for this you ready
earthquake get to the doorframe
the whole place is coming down the cave
it's caving in no I think we're fine
yeah so guys I have been I've been doing
some finishing work around here for the
last hour or two and I thought it might
be nice to get you guys involved too
because well show you some of the
decisions I'm making I guess so I've
been mostly focusing on this mushroom
farm and I added like green slime walls
there which I think looks pretty cool
from this side but this side not as much
I don't like it quite as much but I
think it's okay but then I started like
realizing I don't like these reeds
behind these fences so I decided to
change those out with slime blocks and I
changed it out like the wool I had up
there with slime blocks so this whole
place is like slime blocks now I got
carried away I think I think what we
should do is get rid of some of these
and I got some other colors here to try
out I got yellow orange brown it might
look a lot better if we get another
color in here
let's try these out let's do brown first
because I think that's the least likely
one will want to use it that works
definitely works but it's I don't know
it doesn't add anything to the room it's
this brown we already have a lot of
brown in here all right so this is what
I'm really deciding up between is the
orange and the yellow
which I'm guessing yellow is gonna look
better but let's just see here good
orange and green are really good
together I definitely want to have the
slime blocks behind the fences I think
that looks so much better than the reeds
I think the recolor changed for one
thing I think that's why I don't like it
as much I don't remember being able to
see all this stone behind your before
either though orange not too bad I do
like that more than the brown but let's
go for the yellow oh you know what I
should be doing actually we gotta check
that from this side too because that's
pretty important yeah that's that's
definitely acceptable the orange I think
that's okay all right let's do yellow I
decided I'm gonna call this my musical
mushroom farm aha I want to wait a sec
and yellow I think I'm gonna go with
yellow yeah I sort of decided before I
even started yet and I think that's fine
on the side too musical mushroom farm
because what I want to do now I think
it'd be cool like I got this this thing
here set up where turns the light off up
there whenever a mushroom grows let's
see do I have I don't have any bone meal
yeah when a mushroom grows it activates
that bud switch up there and then we can
make something happen and I haven't
really decided what I want to happen but
I think playing like a note note block
sequence would be pretty cool like a
little tune between four and eight note
blocks would be a good idea
I think I want to add the yellow up on
the top there to try to get rid of some
of these slime blocks because we just
have too many now haha let's pick these
up and what else I want to do is try to
order these torches because again we're
trying to do a no torch look to the
whole cave if we can so if this is a
finished area we can't have any torches
here and I really got to get these doors
working too that this door I've built a
long time ago does this work no doesn't
work but I never really hooked up the
Redstone to it and we need another one
over here too so just kind of kind of
some stuff I've been up to here be nice
to finally get this mushroom farm done
because it started it so long ago I was
working at finishing the roof here to
see I'm gonna leave the like an opening
here in case we want to add something
later on down the road I'm not really
sure what we would put down here but I'm
sure eventually I'll think of something
this and trapdoors yeah alright anyway
I'm gonna do do some more work on this
and we'll check it out
so I just discovered like something I
should have been doing all along in my
worlds here usually when I need leaves I
go up to the surface and like I'll grow
a tree I'll chop the leaves off of it
and I'll chop the trunk down then I'll
grow another tree and chop the leaves
off growing up and the trunk and
whatever I do it one by one the trees
I've had this tree farm here forever
this is the way to do it
is so much better this is how you get
leaves oh my goodness
that is fantastic
hey I'm getting creepers and stuff in
here from somewhere I'm not quite sure
exactly I think I have yeah this might
be a dark spot just about done here I
got okay let's let's look at this so I
got lights hanging from the ceiling now
we got one one two three four of them
currently and I tried to like alternate
their heights so this one lowest and
then we got medium and then highest
pretty cool and hit a bunch of lights in
the grass here like there's one over
there on the pillar I did some of these
sneaky lights like this and we got those
in a few places I know there's one up
here to decide to put some fences along
here some vines not sure if I want to
keep those vines what else what else got
the door going so wouldn't pressure
plate here and run through there's a
button on the other side and it's pretty
easy to open it if you're going to this
way like that I don't really want to put
pressure plates on the ground here so
that's why I did a button instead
because I don't think that was looking
very good and then inside
did a bit of work here I got rid of the
fences on the top there and I put the
yellow clay behind you got the yellow
clay walls I think they're pretty good
they might not be totally perfect I
don't know if they really go with the
green but I really like the green behind
the fences I think that looks really
neat yeah
mushroom firm pretty much done I'm gonna
add some note blocks underneath here yet
make it the musical mushroom farm and
that is about it for right now all right
all right so check this out I got one of
these mushroom growing areas rigged with
note blocks now I just wanted to kind of
demonstrate you guys what this would be
like I have four note blocks down with
random ish tunings
I tried my best but I'm not very good at
making chimes in that in Minecraft so
that's I'm kind of hoping you guys will
help me out with that because I can have
up to six different tunes in our musical
mushroom firm here but I just wanted to
show you what it would be like so here
we go let's grow a mushroom oh yeah so
majestic and then all it turns on up
there for some reason doesn't really do
anything I don't know why I did that or
wait maybe this is too high no it's only
one block so mobs only spiders could
spawn up there if it was dark anyway
all right best so that is the musical
mushroom farm as it is right now let us
go you know I I wanted I wanted to sort
out my nether situations so I got all
the sandstone some purple wool we're
gonna head over there and try to do some
stuff because wait where is he because
my nether is a mess honestly it needs a
lot of work because I got I got portals
all over the place some of them I don't
even really know where they go or what
they are they're not labeled for one
thing I don't have paths to some of them
like convenient paths this place is sort
of a mess even like this is the main hub
area I never finished the roof or the
ceiling I mean and a creeper blew up my
portals the other day and I never turned
them back on because if I go through
them it takes me inside my gold farm
with the the angry zombie pigmen which
would not be a good thing I have to
climb up this ladder go all the way to
the top of my nether and then go through
the portal and then that takes me to my
gold farm still but at least not where's
the angry zombie pigman are so it's we
need to do some work is what I'm getting
at here I don't think I'm gonna be using
the rail system I don't know if I want
to tear it out I might use it I'm not
sure but I think mules is the way I want
to go because horses came out and that's
a really good way of getting around so
we might take that path but what I think
we should do I want to hook this up to
the portal network - which is gonna be
tough unless we move it mmm how could we
do this I almost want to set like a
portal up here and make stairs that wind
around and go up above here like to this
area on one of these sides instead of
making all four sides totally
symmetrical maybe we could do a
staircase to come up here
maybe and then we could like put a
piston elevator where this portal is
because I would like a quick way up to
the roof to so that might be the way to
go so let's let's see it's I'm scared to
work on this because it's that big
project and I'm scared of big projects I
just I feel bad just like randomly
picking a spot here for a portal but I
think that's what I'm gonna do so we're
gonna move this portal to here and we're
gonna try have staircases that wrap
around and go up there I think is the
way to do this and also I'll have to
have a path that goes around to here
because we still want to go off this
direction I also kind of regret making
tunnels
instead of like something more unique
like I just have a straight tunnel there
that goes on for quite a ways it's a
little bit of a boring way of doing it
to be honest like that's not even
centered mmm alright tell you what I'm
gonna skip ahead a bit as I get my
thoughts together oh man guys I don't
know what I'm doing here I I put myself
in a tough spot I gotta make all these
decisions now and I'm really bad at
making decisions I'm trying like I put
the portal there the sandstone in the
purple wool we're gonna try to keep that
for this this hub anyway I do like the
way that looks but I find it's a bit
plain on its own so I've been trying to
incorporate dark oak wood as well just
as a third block with somewhat success
not really good I I need to find places
to put it we don't have enough of it so
the thing is I do really like the way
these look these minecart selection
tract business I don't really think
we're gonna use them though but I like
the way they look so should I keep them
or not it's the question like I might
get rid of the one behind the portal
there but I I almost want to keep these
three for the other directions this
middle thing though for sure we should
tear down because it's just it doesn't
look good it's not gonna work being in
the middle is to hook it up to the
portal network I have to do all this
redstone stuff to it and there's this
not enough space if it's in the middle
I'd be too tough and yeah it's pretty
busy looking we can do better I prefer
like just a plain look like that to be
honest now maybe at the time when I made
this I didn't but yeah so we'll take
this down let me flatten this out well
that was unexpected that portal the one
I just build did not take me to the gold
farm like I thought it would it took me
underground somewhere a little ways away
and it's full of zombie pigmen so I have
a better idea though I haven't I think I
know I'm doing this now yes so this is
what we're gonna do guys this is my plan
we're gonna take this portal and we'll
move it back to the middle genius right
I know I know I do my best but we're
gonna put down lower like five blocks at
least down we might have some stairs
going downwards but what we also want to
have in this middle the reason why we
had to move the portal
besides needing room for redstone is we
also want to put an elevator to go up
here now the thing is there's no real
good piston elevator I can put here
because piston elevators are usually an
even number like they're a four by four
sort of thing and and we got like a 5 by
5 here so what I decided to do
we're gonna do a minecart elevator
because that's that's an odd number type
of elevator the only one I can think of
actually so that's what we'll do and
they're actually really good and they're
really quick so it's probably even
better than a piston elevator in this
case I'm just saying this up temporarily
just as a guide of where I want to put
it all right so this I'm not sure if I'm
gonna keep with the dark oak let me know
you guys think do you like the dark oak
here or should we just keep it the
sandstone in the purple probably needs
to go higher that's a really short
doorway oh man wait a second here let me
go up a little bit more see where was it
it was here let's go up at least one
more all right that's better so yeah
what we'll do I got any slabs I don't
have any slide to make some slabs I'll
put these away there we go let's do a
ring like this
oh no no no cuz I moved it up a block
that's not the right spot let's put it
up one more higher because I'm gonna
move these up to you at this level here
and then we will probably do I think the
spots where I have ladders I'm gonna put
the lamps like this and we'll put the
ladders on the lamp facing this way I
guess we'll do and see minecart track
and we'll build this up the goal is to
build all the way to the top there
before I have to jump down here because
I have I have no way of getting back up
really so we can't mess this up oh
actually poor little pig men's man
they're running into places in there
suffocating
that'll fall down and sits on the ladder
atlases double-check that's an okay of a
height block it in though alright so
hopefully I can I can reach I can't
reach can I reach if I jump I cannot so
it's a little bit too tall let me lower
this one block after all or wait wait
wait before I stop what if I have a half
slab here then I can get in if I jump
hmm is that good enough to I want to do
it that way oh I wanted to try something
here second I take a lot of fall damage
not too bad I could put a slime block at
the bottom to you I think we'll keep it
like this okay that's fine alright let's
go back up good we still made it and
then every there I should use this it's
every three blocks we need another
ladder so one two three ladder then one
two three next ladder will be there oh
wow look it actually matched up with the
stone there oh that's gonna make this a
lot easier I'd even think of that
alright and anyway so you get the idea
I'm gonna go ahead and do this I also
want to light up these lamps I'll
probably just put a lever on like that
that's the reason I'm putting them here
so it's not completely dark in this
tunnel
cool cool very good I got the elevator
all done here up to the gold farm anyway
so let's give it a try
show you how it is hold right click
takes us up to here I got a hold up when
I exit otherwise I fall down so drop
down very very safely the ladders catch
you it's pretty cool it's nice and quick
and oh I got stuck there I would like to
eventually make it go all the way up to
the top of the nether like up why 250 or
so but I got a punch another hole into
the bedrock like right there which I
hope that still works by the way I
haven't tried it in last few batches so
there's another thing I can do too if I
want to a quick way down I can just get
into one of these carts and a hole press
shift and they'll drop me down so it's
like a quick fall so I might put some
slime blocks or something there to this
I'll dress up later it's a bit plain at
the moment but I brought in a friend
here too so I'll have a mix of horses
and mules I believe like if I got to
carry stuff I'll grab my mule if I need
all I just want to get somewhere quickly
I'll use a horse sort of thing and we
got to make stalls for these guys so I
brought some string and some wool
probably the best like the most
convenient way I can do this is to set
up let's see where do I want to do it
set up some some of the carpets traps
for the the mules and horses see the
diagonal is right there the midpoint
would be right here okay so let's let's
use that as our midpoint I want it at
least like two mules two horses but we
might want more than that
we'll see let's you know what let's
let's just try a like a one by one for
the for the mule why should know because
they're bigger than a one by one we need
at least a two by two we should probably
do it three by three
so this and we will put we could either
make it go down or up make it go down
I'll look like this will you make it go
up let's see
you'd have string oh wait no no I need a
bigger day let's let's extend it out
like this
we'll do a 4x4 area I guess yeah we'll
put string down like this all around and
then we will put the carpet above that I
like so hopefully this is okay and then
these we will probably want to change
out with stairs mmm don't have the
stairs let's get the stairs alright how
does that look yeah it's not too bad I
like that so then what I got to do is
dig at least three maybe I think it
might be four blocks below the string oh
it broke I hit the string I must stay at
the string like so and that will make it
so the the horses and mules won't want
to cross this carpet border because
they'll think it's a drop and they won't
want to take fall damage so let me go
ahead and do that and we will try it out
okay should be good to go I got a four
block drop under the carpet here all
around it let's cover this up and we
will try it out with our buddy here so
we should be able to pretty easily just
go up hop off oh I missed it I want it
to be super convenient like I really
didn't have to try too hard to get him
oh I pushed him off okay so maybe I do
have to whoa getting a little bit of lag
see if I drop him off like that he's
kinda on the carpet is he gonna what are
you gonna do guy you're gonna stay
they're gonna be good take off and run
away in burning lava somewhere
thankfully it doesn't work did they fix
it they might have fixed it he shouldn't
have been able to do that make sure he's
not on any of the carpet and then see
what he does yeah he's still crossed oh
man they might have fixed it hmm or it
needs to be two blocks possibly mmm
because a horse can't actually fall down
a one wide hole it needs to be too wide
mmm that wouldn't look very good yeah he
can cross that no problem hmm you know
what let's just try to change out this
middle first I want to see if that works
all right so we get string I should get
out of here before I drop myself okay
get some more string and we'll cover it
up I'm curious like you feel just freeze
if I Park them on there now all right
guy I'm gonna drop you off right above
this hole don't move he wanted out of
there pretty quick whoa I must have a
ton of guys going through the portals
right now cuz I'm getting so much leg
yeah okay so that's not gonna work
either hmm ah darn that would have been
a lot nicer than having to unless I put
it like a stall in the wall here
stalling the wall that might be better
than out in the middle this would have
been more convenient though cuz I would
have to walk
as far mm-hmm that's what I needed I
need to carpet blocks wide and he
doesn't seem to cross that let's put
some blocks under here see if they'll
cross then whoops just to make sure I
think this did change a little bit
though because I know it's now on the
minecraft server the kwik-e-mart I'm
having mobs entered that building now
they weren't doing it before like since
we updated it's been happening to the
snapshots
mm-hmm that's weird I know as soon as I
break these walls you'll walk off you
should you should attempt to cross this
now I would think unless it doesn't
matter how deep the hole is doo doo doo
okay I will free you you are free
are you being stubborn now there he goes
all right so if I do it this way though
it's gonna take up a huge area
especially if we have four of them so
I'm gonna just put them in the walls
here is the best but anyways guys it is
that time again I'm out of I'm out of
recording time here - so you'd than ten
episode I got the comment picked out it
says oh yeah and I've done some little
things around the cave and other places
do you like for example I put some vines
up here now they should grow down
hopefully it looks cool cuz I like I
like how these ones look over here so I
wanted to do that and I also worked on
the bridge over here a little bit yeah
the comments here is the comment it says
hey etho I was wondering and feed the
beast you have you have to build things
quick and have to have a chance of being
robbed I don't want to change those
rules but I don't like watching you
throw junk together and build a tiny
base I personally like that when you
one big bait main base where you stored
all your resources neatly on the new
server all you do is build as fast as he
can while other people wait for the
right chance to rate you he means I
think that you and the mine crackers
have an awesome server but I was
wondering if you can do it like - how it
was before I think he means like how we
were a build building focused server so
yeah I wanted to address this because
there's almost certainly gonna be some
changes with feed the beast coming up I
don't know exactly what those are gonna
be but we found out we can't we might
not be able to keep ICBM and Flan's mod
in our mod pack which are that the two
main like fighting packs like ICBM has
those rockets I've been using a lot in
the grenades and all that cool stuff and
Flan's mod hats all those guns and that
there's airplanes and tanks and stuff
and since the whole focus of our series
is fighting and we're losing our two
main fighting packs yeah that's that's a
big deal so either we're gonna get a
different fighting pack that's more
stable that's the reason they're there
kind of unstable and the feed the beast
guys don't have the time - or the
manpower not really well time and
manpower to keep those up-to-date for us
so either we get it a new fighting pack
which there are not many of those or we
somehow get those working or we focus on
being a build server which would
possibly means we reset the map I'm not
entirely sure but for my past experience
with feed the beast like I had a lot of
trouble recording the season before this
like a lot the server was laggy it was
constantly thrashing and when it would
crash I had no control like I couldn't
do anything about it after it like
secured and hopefully he'd be around and
get it back up that modpack was a lot
more stable than the one we're currently
using so I may go and do a single-player
feed the beast thing but it it depends
on like if the other mine crackers do
feed the beast and they're they're
active with it I I can put up with lake
leg and that stuff but if if they're
only gonna play for a week and then I'm
stuck there alone
doing my thing on a lady server that
crashes I'm I'm gonna wish I did a
single-player thing so I don't know
we'll see what happens but there's
probably gonna be some changes coming up
anyway that is it for today guys I hope
you have yourselves a wonderful day
oh yeah I changed this to dark glass
hope you have a wonderful day thank you
for watching and I'll see you again in
the next one bye bye
[Music]