hello everybody this is etho welcome
back guys OMB respond get your snacks I
mean I mean yes we're here out at the
gold farm and after waiting for a while
here for these zombies to spawn on this
little platform because the iron golems
are hitting the zombie pigmen there and
when you hit a zombie pigman there's a
chance they will spawn zombie in a dark
spot which is right over here after
waiting quite a while we finally got
enough zombie villagers to spawn that we
were able to get our real villagers here
we converted them and I got the cleric
woohoo that means all the zombie flesh
I'm getting here I can actually get rid
of and convert into emeralds which is
pretty cool this guy over here he's a
what is the leather worker yes which he
sells saddles for pretty cheap eight
eight emeralds is not a bad price so
that's cool to have got two villagers
here if I wanted I could make a village
because we're above the leather ceiling
too but I don't know do we really need
another village maybe we'll do it I
don't know anyway so so far I've gotten
over fifty five blocks and what's
trading with these guys and we still
have that ones in for me that one's
energy weight now is empty that one's
empty those used to all be full of
zombie flesh in all the blank spots
let's check here I got through this
chest this one this one this one still
has a bunch in and this one I haven't
touched it yet so not too bad anyway I'm
gonna finish up trading here we'll go do
something oh the poor little bunny just
doesn't look great does it it that that
was pretty funny lifted there's this one
bunny that wasn't on a lead and he's
been following me around I kind of want
to see how long he'll live with
if I neglect them so far he's been okay
but the teleport into the hopper there
so guys last episode we made that bunny
farm grab some of these and a few of you
asked what the the rabbit's foot is for
and that is a new thing in the latest
1.8 snapshot so let's let's make one
let's see what you do put the rabbit
foot in there awkward potions it's for
brewing jumping potions which if you
jump boost I believe one jump boost one
or jump boost to a few but glowstone
with it you know when I made this lab
when I made this lab this potion lab I
thought I don't need to worry about
expanding it they'll never be any new
potions added to the game and then water
breathing potions came out and then oh
it was the other one wasn't there one
more
we got jumping potions now I thought
there was one more that's for water
breathing maybe it was only two I'm
blanking I kind of thought there was a
third one but yeah we keep getting new
ones
oh you can't extend it that's weird I
thought you could extend it for sure all
right three minutes can you make Jim oh
yeah you make jump boost to good um so I
don't know it's not a potion you would
probably use very often but you can give
it to other mobs I believe and possibly
that helps not maybe we should try on a
horse actually yeah let's try that out
on horse see what happens
jump boost ooh okay we will have to add
gunpowder then and looking around here
it looks like this thing is filled up so
I I've been very lazy about emptying the
goodies in here at
it's been backing up I emptied the
Gunpowder once just because I didn't
want to lose any of that but I got
nowhere to put all this stuff so mm not
sure what to do all right cool let's go
find our horses I've been I still have
them locked up here I've just been
breeding trying to get some good work
horses let's see this is my good guy
ouch I this will use them go outside I
don't think this elevator works anymore
oh the bunny found us I have to make
some adjustments to it so we can't get
out that way like this we'll go up here
hopefully it's daytime of course it's
not it's never daytime when I need it to
be well we got lots of torches around
all right so let's make a pillar see can
you get over this guy it's not a great
jumper yeah he just barely does it so
now if I give him jump boost oh yeah I
think that works Wow okay yeah it
definitely works on mobs how many I
place there oh it's five blocks okay
let's see we do five yeah so that's just
the limit so that's two blocks or
two-and-a-half blocks I believe to the
jumping Heights that's pretty cool I
noticed something today - I got a wither
skeleton out at the gold farm there
another one and when I put it on my mask
doesn't show anymore whoa that's not
cool all right guy don't worry calm down
let's get out of here
before you used to be able to see you
like my headband and that through the
mask and now you can't slide I don't
really like that they made the head a
little bit bigger but I just for some
people skins that have the second layer
doesn't look quite right so I guess
there's there's
benefit to it that Chad freaked me out
so bad when I saw that head just
sticking out oh man why did he teleport
silly kitty I think that's what I had
sitting down over here for some reason
he decided to come see me is that guy
gone yeah he was right there before
sitting okay guys so I've decided today
is the day we are gonna finish project
Pokemon here oh it's only been a hundred
episodes what are you talking about it
hasn't that long maybe a little bit
longer
um yeah I realized I can't actually
finish it it's impossible because the
original goal was to get all these
villagers all the different types and
they had to be naturally spawned in a
village I couldn't breed them was my
original rule to it every time I found a
priest in a blacksmith in a village they
always died the zombies though and
there's usually there used to only be
like one or two per village I think
that's still probably true though so
they were the rare two and I just never
got them but they're all the new
villagers with the new villager trading
they are no longer priests and
blacksmith they're like armorsmith tool
smith and like cleric and all that stuff
so I can't actually get the original
villagers from anywhere so let's go
ahead and just I just put in a purple
coat in the black coat villager and we
will call it good so in this village
here this is a village with all my
original villagers that had the old
trade system to them in the whole thing
we only have one blacksmith this guy is
special he has diamond helmet
let's go gold for emerald and diamond
pants unlocked which you cannot get with
the new trading system you can only get
diamond chest plates so he is actually
pretty cool I don't want him to die
that's why thrilled ear in his face how
hard is he going to be I don't think I
can get him out of here tonight
alright we got to be very careful here
this is a delicate science oh this is a
tough shot
Oh oh wow I actually got one out okay
you're free oh not the pig no that pig
has been that well forever I don't want
to let him up
come on blacksmith's I know I can get
you oh that's a cleric oh so close
get out of the way Claire I got him yes
sweet all right let's break this slow oh
that would be the worst if a zombie
spawned right at the top of the pillar
there because it's like the only dark
spot and then killed everybody all right
we're gonna take him through the nether
come on guy while we're young and
hopefully this goes okay he's gonna
resist it though he doesn't want to
leave this has been his home for quite a
while although he might be okay with it
I get to get farther away from the
village before they start fighting it
okay guy come on
and through the portal this is the tough
part I don't want him to get away from
you here I don't really have the nether
sealed off too well long as I'm close to
him he won't run off on his own though I
think let me block this way actually I
gotta be careful I don't hit a zombie
pigman I'm almost there alright so close
guy you're so close I made sure it was
day before we went to the portal
hopefully it's still day and I know what
you're thinking how am I gonna get him
through the lava ash I don't want to
drop him down the stairs no don't fall
downstairs I'm gonna be very gentle with
this guy oh all right oh man he still
took damage I tried so hard
alright so I disabled the portal and the
man tube and we have another portal
right where I'm going to drop them in
and he's gone where did he go dude
seriously it's dangerous out here you
can roam free and I'll never find you
alright alright so which one not that
one hopefully I don't push them into the
portal again moving villagers is always
so tough because there's no I wish you
could attract them with something
blacksmith you're you're over here this
is your stall right here very good
hopefully the water hasn't dried up over
the last year or whatever it's been the
res you're gonna have a rough fall whew
awesome and if I remember right I had a
lever here and that turns his torch on
there's supposed to be a door here deep
zombies from jumping down although they
break doors now so yeah
this is all old school stuff that
doesn't work anymore like supposed to
I'm going to get that other priest here
okay this guy is giving me a really
really hard time anytime I get close to
getting him down these stairs he walks
away like every time guy why don't you
like the stairs you know where you're
going
usually if I'm by a villager they think
I'm trying to trade with them and they
don't move but this guy he doesn't care
about me he just does whatever he wants
need this guy stop running away man oh
he's so annoying
blacksmith just did whatever I wanted
not this guy thinks he's special go down
the stairs no stop trying to run away
from me he sees something come on stop
he won't stop going to that spot no he
like he won't just like stay still near
the stairs so that I didn't bump him
down he just runs every time ideas close
watches watches look at that what what
is your problem with these stairs don't
do it again of course he does it again
oh man this way oh you're so close it's
the middle one right priest yes this is
you oh oh yeah yes
so that should do it except we got this
one extra spot don't we why is this door
open is that right oh yeah there's no
guy down here
originally when I made this I thought
you could get all the villagers but
there's a green coat one oh why is he
happy oh no
there's the green coat one that you
could never get just the plain old
villager so we have an extra spot here I
might put a zombie villager in it I'm
not sure so I've never really believed
in this whole herobrine thing I know
it's it's a popular thing in Minecraft
but I I always just rolled my eyes at it
but this doesn't make any sense I know
we have video proof I turned the light
on here and I closed the door and I
noticed he was gone so I went up to
check and the light was changed to off
and the door was open
and I'm pretty sure Dom bees don't open
doors they break doors I have no idea
what happened to the blacksmith somebody
tinkered with something up there and it
wasn't me I know it wasn't me and I
looked around I don't see him running
around anywhere ah well it's weird I
really don't get it
maybe these four the other four
villagers here murdered him huh we could
have a clue kiss on her hand here like
he was getting all the attention they
couldn't stand it so they conspired to
kill him and frame his death as a
mystery or something I don't know anyway
I got an armor from the other village
the one with the color of colourful
houses in the man cave
brought him over here hopefully he lives
I honestly don't get it like I don't
know the three villagers I had here
never had a problem with them then I had
these two and then they start dying
and weird things happen who knows so we
have a lot of emeralds if you hadn't
noticed like a lot of emeralds and I
would like to spend some of these so see
is it them making the noise with
friendly creatures so we got a librarian
here he is a super librarian he has the
old trades and the new traits and
because of that we have two paper trades
within one librarian which is pretty
cool although I'm having a hard time
getting that to work
let's try D let's buy a nametag we're
probably going to be buying a lot of
nametags soon I think I'm going to try
to do that charged creeper farm like B
we are doing on the minecraft server
yeah so if i unlock the trades again you
see how it refreshed that one paper
trade always stays X X tau to the old
one and then the new one is okay which
is very weird we got the old cleric and
the armor maybe we will trade with the
armor this guy will actually I hate to
do this so expensive such a waste
he will actually trade us diamond armor
I believe yeah right here cost 19 haha
ok so there's an armor Smith there's a
tool Smith and there's a weapon Smith
tool Smith I think you get picks and
axes from the weapon Smith you will get
diamond swords from and the armor you
will get diamond chestplate from and
that's about it oh you can hit the
chainmail I didn't know that hahaha
maybe we'll try by piece since we have
the emeralds why not see I want to fully
unlock their trades here ok that's it I
think that's it for his trades and these
other guys I guess we could try and lock
them
by a couple arrows even though we have
lots see what happens when we do that oh
I think it just exited out that's not
good and we have this guy here maybe
I'll try buy some steak I'm not sure if
that's going to create new trades out
did okay so see we had that we had that
we unlocked this right I think so maybe
we'll buy some more stay tuned to see
what happens here 2 2 2 2
Oh didn't refresh ok ok here's what
we're gonna do we're gonna trade with
all our librarians and just see what we
unlock with them because the truth is
the only villagers that are really
interesting is the librarians they're
the only ones that have a randomness to
them really you can pretty much predict
with all the other guys are going to
sell you but librarians they have these
book trades which are at random punch -
this guy he doesn't have very good stuff
unfortunately let's see what Tom will
unlock for us so he had projectile
protection 3 this is glitched out this
one you give them a book and he gives
you this you don't even have to pay for
it see we got to try unlock some more
trades here so let's give them some
paper and hopefully that will unlock
some new stuff and
all right that's probably plenty give us
the purple swirls nope
what else could we do let's buy a bunch
of glass I guess 2 to 5 5 glasses the
most you can get from a trade so it's
pretty good and out we unlocked a new
paper trade so that's 28 for one little
bit on the expensive side 27 was one
before oh darn it bane of arthropods -
it's not even 5 it's - so bad
ok I'm gonna buy more glass just to
knock trades
alrighty refreshed beta bar spots do we
get this next this and that mm-hmm
we do the glass one again I think that's
the most desirable one so far whew out
being lot more good Oh another glass
straight for for written book it's
confusing because there's old trades in
the new trades but we're just getting
into the new ones here so he should
unlock two more book trades and then the
nametag I think after the glass here it
o in Finity one four seven that is good
that is actually really good I like that
buy some little back glass and some of
the good glass
whoo so much class I actually need it
though because I'm all out at the moment
and we unlock something else we get
knocked back to don't and I know the
name pages after that so that's it for
Tom I'm going to trade with other guys
off-camera and we'll just take a look
afterwards what we all get okay so let
me show you the trades we got unlocked
here I guess there's only two librarians
in this village I thought we had more so
first off this guy's a paper trade for
35 which is about the worst it can be
think it goes 24 to 26 if I remember not
26 36 so it's just just the most bad B
we got protection to 420 emeralds ouch
and then we got projectile protection 3
for 16 punch 1 for 8 name take 421 Lois
you can get this 4 is 20 um then 22 24
for name peg this guy we have fire
protection 1 4 6 and blast protection
for 452 hip out and then protection for
450 - I thought it okay so I really
wanted to get a protection for book I
thought it was gonna be a lot cheaper
than this though 52 is it crazy named
egg comes after that so not the best of
trades but it's okay and I wanted I want
to tell you guys something - so if you
want emeralds if your goal is to get
emeralds how do you do it what's what's
the best way you might think I would say
go for clerics because that is what I do
these guys here because you can sell
them zombie flesh for you get as low as
zombie flesh for one emerald and then
you can buy glowstone from them to
refresh the trade or you can buy
redstone or lapis are also pretty good
but I find it's pretty annoying trading
with these guys to be honest because
there is so much clicking involved
you only get one emerald like per stack
of items you put into this so you're
constantly clicking and then you lose
about a third or a quarter of your
profits because to refresh the trade
after the zombie flesh trade wears out
you got to buy something where else you
could sell gold but that's definitely
not worth it so you lose a lot of your
profits trading with them I only do it
because I get so much zombie flesh and I
either toss it or trade it you might
think I would say librarians because
they have paper trade and you can
automatically harvest sugarcane so that
is pretty good that that takes a lot of
the effort out of it because you just
have it automatically harvest then you
just kind of craft it into paper and you
got lots of paper you can get up to 2
emeralds per stack with this trade goes
from 24 to 36 I believe um then if the
paper trade wears out you still have the
option of trading written books let's
see 2 for 1 emeralds it's not bad
actually that's a good trade if that
fails and you still want to sell them
something you can also do a book trade 8
books for one emerald those are the only
three things if those are the three
things
the librarian buys so that's pretty good
but really I think the secret to getting
tons of emeralds if that's what you want
is let's see if we can find them
nothing there Darren why did it have to
be nighttime all my guys are hiding what
are you two doing all right if we looked
at this guy already yeah so Oh I
unlocked a shepherd too by the way so he
buys wool white wool
he sells shears and then he can also buy
a wool from him at one or two emeralds
each all the different colors it's kind
of cool it's a little expensive
uh where is loud truck outside I don't
know if you heard that I just will sleep
hopefully they'll come outside and we
can look at this one guy because it's
pretty interesting to see not there he's
not in there and where were all my
villagers oh no he's not in there
where did he go I just some oh is it you
farmer yes this is the guy so these are
all old trades these ones this this this
and this these are the new ones these
are what you'll get with a normal
villager you can sell them 18 wheat for
an emerald 15 potatoes for an emerald 15
carats for an emerald you can get
cheaper prices too you can buy bread
from them you can sell them pumpkins bye
pumpkin pie you can sell melons you can
buy apples buy cookies and buy cake so
if you want emeralds this is the one
right here
pumpkin trading this can get as low as 8
which means you can have like 8 emeralds
per stack which is pretty convenient
very nice not much clicking with that
you can auto harvest these you don't
need to craft them they grow pretty
quick so I think pumpkins are the
secrets if you wear out that trade and
you need to refresh it then
also trade melons or any of the other
ones so yeah I think if I'm trying to
get emeralds I'm going to go with a
pumpkin trade it looks pretty good
anyway we're going to get to the comment
for today it says hey ESO do you have a
phone if so what one and do you play any
games on it I have a Samsung Galaxy Note
3 did I say that right I hope so I got
the note 3 it's a big phone little big
doesn't fit in your pocket too
comfortably but it's ok if you have big
pockets you don't notice it um yeah I
like the phone a lot seems really good
it's really powerful nice clear screen
too it runs Android oh wait yeah I think
so
I just thinking if it was Google's thing
or not um where is that Google thing
anyway so yeah it's pretty good phone I
don't have any games on it yet I just
got it so I haven't set up quite rights
but yeah I hope to play some games on it
but that's going to do it for today's
episode again I've had family visiting
so today was a little bit rushed again
but this was the last day they they went
back this evening we had a good time
though we went to the rocky mountains we
went on a road trip to the rocky
mountains for three days and we went to
the radium area went to the radium hot
springs did some hiking and then did a
lot of other fun stuff together which
was cool so we had a good good time
together
but starting tomorrow I should be able
to get back into putting more time into
the episode so hopefully today wasn't
too bad anyway hope you enjoyed thank
you for watching guys have yourselves a
great day and I'll see you in the next
one bye bye
you