[Music]
hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
welcome back to our let's play series
and today guys do you know what we're
doing
that's a little bit annoying we are
doing a world tour today guys that's
right
uh hopefully i put that in the title or
something to kind of clue you
in uh it's been over a year
since our last world tour and i i feel
it's time we do another one
probably a little bit past time because
you know what we probably have a lot of
people that have joined us since
our last one and they see that number
that
big 400 and whatever we're on and it's
like i don't know where to begin
i give up i'm not watching all those
episodes i don't i'm never gonna know
how everything came to be but today
no no no today's the day if you don't
want to watch all the
old episodes and you kind of just want
to know what everything does
that's that's what we're going to be
doing here so i'm going to stop
yapping on here because we have a lot of
stuff to see
and not a lot of time well
like the last world tour is over an hour
i want to try
keep this one shorter if possible so
let's get to it
uh where to begin well as a lot of you
know
the very first thing we did when we
started this world is we entered into
our man cave here
and my goal when we started was to build
some underground forest type of thing
and it has turned out wonderfully it's i
i love the man cave i think it looks
great
uh the reason we're going out here
i wanted to show you something i think
we dropped in over here somewhere
originally
and in fact our very first chest
well maybe not our first chest but our
very first pick i know for sure
at least i think i know for sure is in
this chest here so we're gonna look at
this
and i don't know what else is in here
some garbage but yeah i think that's our
very first pick so we we came and we
dropped into here
and i liked what i saw decided this is
where we're gonna settle down
and we've been trying to
sort of just build a cave a never-ending
cave here
full of all kinds of gizmos and cool
looking stuff with the goal of uh
not really altering the shape of the
cave too much unless there's
there's no cave then we sometimes need
to dig dig out areas but
we're also trying to avoid using torches
wherever possible so we have hidden
lighting throughout this whole place
the very first thing we built in the
world is the creeper face i'm pretty
sure
and then we set set up like a storage
room area over here where our horse
tolls are now
and then right after that i think we
started settling in
this area up here because it was around
the time
uh what was it it was around the
adventure update actually when like
bannon mine shafts and all that came out
so
there was some cave spider spawners here
which really caught my attention and we
built like
a cave spider exp farm for the for the
first time
and that's what this is over here this
this is a
water staircase that would bring the
spiders up
into the ceiling and they would get
dropped down over here
to this gizmo
and i think it's totally disabled now it
seems but this used to crush them and
or no i wouldn't crush them i think i
would throw damage potions at them
or something but they would all gather
to this area here
at one point i even installed a timer to
keep them from spawning hundreds and
hundreds of them
uh it's got some random chests around
here
then i think the next thing we built was
probably this
this is a mushroom farm i think i called
it the
mini mushroom farm or something i can't
remember but there's like a brown
mushroom under the stone brick there and
a red one under that one and they
it just grows a couple mushrooms every
time almost useless
this farm here though this is one we've
used quite a bit
every single pumpkin and watermelon in
our world has come from this farm
and we've got quite a few of them saved
up here
because we never use them and
i think later we probably built the
slime farm next year so
we had this design so that the small
ones would land into here
medium ones and then the large ones
there's actually uh
a separating mechanic over here
uh there was a change at that time
because before
slimes used to only spawn below
y level 16 they then they changed it so
that they could spawn up to
y40 so we made this this little farm
and the spawning pad is all the way down
here
just a single chunk at
y-39 so right at the level they spawn
and they fall into the water streams
here and they
they make their way up uh later here
we've added hoppers in that to sort of
automate things there's
a drowning sections if i start rambling
through this episode i'm sorry
i'm i'm saying lots of things i'm i'm
kind of worried i'm
i'm speaking too quickly or something i
don't know
it's not it's not our typical type of
episode here
anyway let's get out of the slime farm
we also added a way to pick the slimes
up with a minecart to the big slimes
over here
but i don't think it's working again
they they like step on a
or they fall on a pressure plate and a
minecart would come out to the corner
and pick them up
and then they would go around our tree
farm here
underneath this is the donator tree farm
uh which i transferred over from our old
world we were in our old world from
episodes
one to i think about a hundred
and then there was a small transition
period like to episode 105 which is
where we actually started into
our world here and we've been here ever
since
for over 300 episodes now wow
but i transferred over all the donators
i got in the past
and i gave everybody a sign sort of
recognize them and
remember them and there's even
more somewhere else in our world which
we'll probably check out
in just a second uh later
actually you know one of the first
things we actually we built here was
probably the cow farm as well let's go
down here
so this was one of those square rooms
you see in abandoned mine shafts i don't
know if those still spawn or not
i think they do and i just sort of
hollowed it out and made a
cow farm in this area got some pixel art
big map of our area here and there's
also some controls that we don't really
use too often anymore
but i think that releases the water to
gather all the
the drops to the middle this used to be
a wheat farm it was a dual purpose thing
it's a wheat farm and it was a cow farm
there was a trick in the game for us a
very short period of time
if you put fences underneath tilled soil
cows weren't able to trample it's
nothing was able to trample it
but that got fixed eventually
and we just got like hay and seeds yeah
we better move here
let's keep on moving let's not focus too
long on anything
got a cage here for jeff we put jeff in
here one of our
uh potion lab villagers but then he
glitched out and
i have no idea what happened to him uh
so it's an empty cage over a lava pit
all right let's go back up here uh we
got a ufo thing
up here let's see if we can get in there
which
uh i think the ladder is over here yeah
what what we used to be able to do i
don't think it works anymore
but we got like fishing rods here you go
down into the ufo
and it was positioned just right so that
you could fish the cows
and like pull them up into the water up
above here
and then they would all get funneled
into an area but it's just a little bit
short
of uh getting them up here now it seems
unfortunately but that was a fun little
thing we might try to fix that
eventually
we've got project pokemon here our
original goal was to collect one of
every type of villager
original villagers not bred ones but of
course
villages and villagers have changed
since then so we've
kind of abandoned that idea and we're
just trying to get one of each type over
here
which we will try to finish soon
over here is our original
potion lab in the world tom's not here
oh no
no we used to have another villager in
here a white coat villager named tom
i haven't looked in here in a long time
but he seems to be gone
oh man that stinks uh but yeah
we built this around the time potions
came out in the game
and like enchantments and all that stuff
came out around the time we started the
world here
so this is a fully not a fully automated
but
nearly fully automated system like we
could request certain
certain items to brew potions is there
anything left in there
no let's try these
and basically all the ingredients would
fall down here every
brewing stand here is within reach of
the center so we just go around
and throw in what we needed
this door by the way this was the very
first 3x3 door i built with a hole in
the middle
the spiral door um
for some reason i always build three by
three doors with the hole in the middle
it's sort of my trademark i guess
but this was a spiraling door and
i have it on a pulse extender and all
that kind of stuff
i was very proud of it at the time
because i wasn't very good with redstone
at that time
so i was very happy with how that turned
out
in here now i i got a lot of flack for
this build
guys this is emerald city this was
supposed to be an underground
uh villager village or as we used to
call them in the past testificates
when did that change by the way like i i
just realized the other day we don't
call them testificates anymore
even in the game i think they're
referred to as villagers like
like in text and all that there's still
a couple guys here
old school villagers hello
uh the idea with this village is i
wanted to
set it up so that we can could control
where the villagers go
i don't exactly remember the whole thing
but there's like some tripwire here
would automatically pick up the water
and somehow it would like bring them
into their house or something i i don't
exactly remember all we were trying to
do but yeah
long story shorts uh this place got
abandoned i was
uh i struggled very hard
trying to make something that looked
good here and what i didn't really
realize at the time
is you can't have such big houses in
such a small area
like these are fully built houses uh we
sort of took this project and redid it
in that other place that other
underground village except instead of
building
full full buildings for the villagers i
just did
uh like a facade for the buildings which
worked out much better
but this is where the villagers could
drop down from the
surface without dying
all right let's keep going here this is
the ugly brick thing
every man cave needs one of these
some random brick thing infinite water
source and crafting table
that's all it does there's some potion
dispensers here
secret chest behind it for extra storage
and i think we covered this area pretty
much except for this
piston elevator which does not work
anymore unfortunately
but yeah this was the area we we built
first and then we sort of started
working on this area and i gotta say
i like this area a lot more i don't know
i like the look of it way better
we got the arches over here i think
that's what it is
i really got into the groove then um
just threw in some random bridges
everywhere
got one here one over there got a
waterfall
pond type of thing there and eventually
i moved the
old storage room we had down there got
tired of it and we built this one
and i love this storage room even to
this day i think this is
pretty much perfect you only really need
like 20 double chests or so maybe 22 and
you can
you can store every single item um
nice and organized i find with like
enough of what you need usually
you know i've seen lots of people have
made tutorials on this too
afterwards and it's like you know maybe
i should have made a tutorial on this
back in the day
all it is is like pistons move the
stairs up and pistons move the stairs
down and that's it
all the way around uh-huh
we got secret anvil here ender chest
i've got a block swapper crafting table
thing here
and there's some lights up here that
turn on when it's daytime and turn off
at night time
so right now it's night time we have our
smeltery room here and just recently we
were working on that tunnel and i
put a whole ton of furnaces here because
i had to smelt
these aren't supposed to be here either
i had to smelt a ton of netherrack and
it was taking forever
let's put it back the way it's supposed
to be but these have an
automatic tune that plays
and it goes all the way around the tune
is different for each one
and when when there's stuff smelting in
here these lights turn on when
when all of these are off these lights
are off got like a little wire room back
here
for that and for the storage room
let's keep going here gotta hurry guys
gotta hurry
um over here is our sheep farm
basically this is a backup by the way so
if i
if i destroy something it's fine um
but yeah basically here go along
and water comes from the ceiling it
washes the wall down these grates
onto some pressure plates and
[Music]
this farm used to be really cool but
something's changed in the game
that doesn't work like it used to but uh
it had a double bud switch that would
detect when the sheep would eat the
grass
or when it would grow and and then when
they would eat it and then they would
get sent
up we call this the pop-up sheet farm by
the way
all right now i feel like i'm talking
too fast
oh i'm losing my voice today guys um i
was just
at a party too with like loud music and
uh
i was talking loud and now my voice kind
of hurts
anyways so you press the button water
comes from the ceiling
and wherever the wall hits the pressure
plates those sheep go down
the lights turn on turn off up here
there's also manual
manual things over here it was actually
a very complicated farm
then all the wool gets washed over here
and automatically fills up these chests
and then they're stored over here type
of thing
all right above the potion room we have
this this
room i guess with another three by three
door with a hole in the middle
this is where all the ingredients are
stored for that first potion room
uh but we don't use it too much anymore
because we got a better one
all right there's like a
item detector underneath the ground here
by the way that's how that works
and then we also have the ender pearl
dispenser thing here
you can fill it up with a button up here
just jump and
drop them off in the chest and i think
that pretty much covers this top floor
right
this entrance we still have not built
and i feel terrible about it
we will get to it as soon as i get some
inspiration
i don't know why i just can't think of
what to put in that area
it's like the last thing we got to do
here and then like
a pretty big portion of this cave is
complete
uh we got our jukebox thing over here
lights turn on when you put a record in
turn off when you take it out and
got the bridge across here we actually
built this pretty early on
as well and we built it out of sandstone
i don't know why
but i've i've become used to it i think
it looks pretty good actually now
um back when you needed 30
bookshelves for enchanting in there and
50 levels
this all kind of worked out pretty good
um
but even to this day i still use this
quite a bit
and we got books and tools and stuff up
in the ceiling here
that was a later addition across
this bridge this is like a area we don't
like to go too often
or i don't like to go too often this is
supposed to be a loot room
where we store iron and gold and
emeralds and all that kind of stuff
in block form but i found out pretty
quickly that that gets annoying
like to mine a hundred blocks of iron
just
it takes a long time when you want to
use them
so i decide not to do that but we we
haven't done anything with this room
um and then we got the river originally
we were planning on having like a boat
system running through the whole cave
here but i i added it too late
um there was actually going to be
this is a backup right we can do this
right
there was actually a way up to the
surface here yeah up over there we were
going to have like a boat elevator go up
there and
and out but that just never happened
instead we just
put a river in here for looks instead of
for riding boats
and i think it looks pretty good
uh-huh we tried to incorporate water
throughout the man cave here
um another archway here this is for
future expansion there's nothing here
really except for a vine
farm hopper's at auto collected
all to this one spot and there was a
chicken farm
thing i think this was supposed to be
for a target game wasn't it i can't
remember
but that's my chicken farm basically
that i use off camera
if i ever need to get feathers for the
comment of the day that's usually where
i get it from
uh you guys never see it anyway let's
keep going here
uh there's a tunnel that goes out to our
stronghold base here an ice tunnel
that's very long so we're not going to
take that right now
let's just double check we didn't miss
anything
yeah i think we're done here we've done
that room let's go down
further um
our portal used to be in a different
place but eventually we moved it behind
the creeper face here
and did like a sandstone sort of thing
there's controls here for turning on and
turning off
the portal that goes to our nether hub
we added in horse stables and stuff over
here
we got a lot of stuff to cover guys oh
my goodness
uh every so often randomly the creeper
will shoot arrows from his eyes flaming
arrows
and there's a way of accessing that back
here
um yeah every five minutes that item
despawns and then it shoots an
arrow is there any arrows left i guess
we can't see it
or randomly might shoot an arrow i think
oh i can't reach it anyway it's there
in this room we have wilson this is
a tamagotchi sort of project i built
in minecraft it's actually
incredibly complicated and
one of my favorite things we've built
unfortunately it's not
totally done i wonder
oh you know what happened he died
wait a second i'm not sure how to reset
this guy actually
but he's got all these different
variables like for his age and for
um his happiness level his hunger level
he's got a weight level um like five
different faces he makes depending on
his mood
he can get sick randomly and you gotta
feed him golden apples
there's like a port here where you feed
him steak and
and stuff when he gets hungry yeah i'm
not sure what what to do to restart him
at the off the top of my head actually
darn i wanted to show that anyway
uh let's keep going um maybe we'll go
over to this area first
got a mini farm thing here
so you take seeds um
seeds potatoes carrots even cocoa beans
there's like a jungle log here you can
plant
and then it automatically grows it and
harvest it
and you picked it up manually i use this
thing
quite a bit but we recently built a
better one
got a snow farm thing over here a shovel
still works right automatically picks up
the snowballs and then they get
deposited down here somewhere
we gotta go down here as you can tell i
don't use it too often it's also
put snowballs in our snowball fountain
thing
these automatically get picked up by a
storage minecart here
if it's still around
i wonder if i broke it i must have broke
it because there used to be one
huh anyway it delivers the snowballs to
a snowball fountain and
randomly shoots snowballs in there for
looks
from the pond over here
uh-huh if you've seen it you know what
i'm talking about
i didn't explain that too well these are
the cave spider farms
that we originally were we're getting xp
from we redid them so now they fall down
when they spawn
onto the creeper faces down there and
then there's some
hopper mine carts that pick up the
string uh they like
fall through some trip wires which
activates the whole thing
and we also have a fishing hut over here
if we just want to do some some fishing
all right i think we're pretty close to
done with the man cave here just a
couple more things to check out
we saw the slime farm already over there
we got the flowers on demand farm though
amazing could not make a slower
flower farm if you tried uh then
we recently built the ender porter over
here
and throw like ender pearls in it and
they
say they stay suspended until you press
a button and then they teleport you to
where you want to go
rail track out to the stronghold base
over there
and i think we can go down now let's
keep going down further a lot of this
area is just for looks but there is also
a rabbit farm we added in over here
back when rabbits first came out they
they could be tamed and they would
teleport around you had to tie them to
a fence with leads to stop that but
that's not an issue anymore so this
farm is maybe not so good anymore
we don't use it too often because
how often do you eat rabbits and if you
do why do you
got access to the snowball fountain
wiring over there
this is for future expansion over here
but there's also
an eats road we set up i don't know
i guess we can try riding i'm not sure
if it's gonna work though
or how to ride it was there not a
i gotta place this in a certain spot i
think and i'm not sure where
let's try over here nope let's try over
there
nope oh
okay that's not how it's supposed to
work
anyway boats are glitchy as it turns out
and this doesn't work so well
but maybe in the future uh that goes to
an old strip mine which we might check
out there's another way of getting to it
over here is mostly for looks we also
have a horse elevator
takes you up to the surface that works
pretty good still
we have
maybe we'll go up over here
kind of access the wilson wiring over
there crosses bridge is an area we've
been working in recently
just expanded a little bit and we have
access to our our newest
potion lab wiring and minecart stuff up
here
got our firework making room over here
for making
randomly creating fireworks another wire
access room
for the elevator here and
this goes to wilson now we're going
we're going in circles guys there is
some dispensers up here for
leads and and speed potions for when we
take the horses out
these doors automatically open and close
when you ride them
in and out type of thing all right
then over here is our mushroom farm
you grow the mushrooms oops
and then these lights turn on there's
like some bud switch stuff
happening
[Music]
and musical notebox play we recently
began working on arena build
but it needs some work yet
uh-huh future project for fighting mobs
you know i always feel like we haven't
really built a lot of stuff in our world
here but when we do these tours
oh my goodness we're like 30 minutes in
already and we're just getting started
got a netherward farm
very cool this is probably
oh it's tough this might be my favorite
build we've done
uh we called this ethos lab all you got
to do is flip the
lever here and it will automatically
brew potions for us of
every single type pretty much
well that should have another word in
this will automatically make
awkward potions
and they all kind of go through a chain
system of like of one step of the potion
to the next step to the next step to the
end of the line
and you can access the potion from each
step
basically so there's pretty much every
single potion type
you could possibly want
and it automatically restocks itself
which is pretty cool
causes a crazy amount of lag if you
leave it running though so i usually
don't
but i love how this place looks and it's
it's a very technical build
it's kind of a combination of everything
i like about minecraft all in one thing
got another 3x3 door here
pretty happy with how this area turned
out too i think it looks cool it's
something different from
from the other areas we got our mob
system over here just regular mobs
which automatically filter their items
into these
chests and
get all the goodies
this room here there's a skeleton
spawner we were supposed to make a
some some we're supposed to do something
with this spawner but
all i've done so far is turned into
storage room
from all the mob drops these are like
all loaded up
with garbage and the water down there is
just for looks
and then this goes over to our
underground village
again i really like this build um
got the school hey guys how's it going
and the goofy little houses some of them
up in the air some of them on the ground
i think this turned out way better than
emerald village
but i don't have people asking me to
finish emerald village
uh there is like a fighting room here
for the extra villagers
where they come to die basically
oh and
another three by three door i love
making three by three doors i don't know
why
in here i think this thing was for
making written books
like it dispenses a book and then you
sign it or you copy it throw it in the
hopper and then it gives you another one
i think i used to trade written books
with the villagers and
there's a tune here that plays at night
time
zelda tune shoots a firework
and daylight sensor that activates it
let's see i think i put something in the
red or the orange house here this is
where we have our other
newly made
what am i trying to think of smart
no not smarts what's the farm mini farm
except this one uses light to harvest it
lack of light instead of pistons so it's
a little bit
a little bit cleaner a little bit nicer
to use but it doesn't
grow jungle for cocoa beans
i am losing my voice guys i'm losing it
i've been talking too long here
all right i think we are done with all
the man cave stuff
pretty much it's a rail cart that moves
the villagers
throughout the village elder villager up
there
oh yeah and there is something up here
too
that we don't see too often let's go
check it out
uh there was a zombie spawner up here
and i turned it into like a medical
convert them into a villager type of
thing so they spawn in each of these
holding areas
if it's a villager zombie you can
convert them
and then set them free so that pretty
much
covers the man cave might have missed a
few things but we can't see
quite everything all all today this
would take way too long
this is my bedroom by the way you guys
always ask why don't you make a bedroom
etho
that's my bedroom right there underneath
the beacon
and i had it set up so that when i died
there's a fence post running up the
the beam there you can't really see it
too well but it goes up to that
platform and when you die you spawn up
there and then you ride a boat down
but i think that might have broke
because i couldn't get to work when i
tried the other day
uh this is for project pokemon get the
villagers down there
where they need to go uh we got a poppy
farm set up over here the snowflake
originally i made it just as like a
beacon so because i kept getting lost
around our world and
you know you can you can spot that from
quite a distance
but eventually we put a poppy farm on
top
and we can get a little bit of extra
flowers when we need them um
and what else what else
where should we go first maybe we should
head over to the library and like make
our way back
to the stronghold type of thing
so up ahead here is the first
gold farm we built and it
isn't finished that's not a good sign
when you
when you have more than one gold farm
and you still haven't finished the first
one
and you've started the second one
the second one is finished though it's
just the first one that i never finished
because it's a really awkward shape
and i didn't know how to make the
building basically
uh but maybe eventually we will finish
this
all the items from the gold farm funnel
down into this chest
like nuggets zombie flesh
they end up in this
holding area over here so from the
nether
you afk like at y250 in the nether and
then a bunch of zombie pigmen spawn
and some spawning platforms i wonder can
we check this out i'm not sure
but then they get teleported through the
portal i don't think this works anymore
oh maybe it does
oh we made it sweet
oh other one there we go
this should take us on top the nether
i'm not mistaken
nope i am definitely mistaken
okay well this is our nether hub uh if
we go up here
this is our shortcut to get up i can
hear them mad at me too
probably not a good thing this is where
all the
zombie pigmen spawn though and the
piston pushers push them down into these
giant portals
and they all teleport through there is a
control back here
one of these turns them on
must be this one one by one they all
turn on
and if i want to disable that ever i
just press the
other button
anyways that sends them through to the
gold form and then we kill them
with a crusher and instant damage
potions
the afk way at the top here there's a
special
thing i'm trying to figure out how to
use this
yeah you press the button there's a
timer after
a certain amount of time before the
world starts to get too laggy
um this piston will push you down and
then you just
you drop down and then they stop
spawning once you get low enough here
so that's all pretty cool all right
let's go
check out the library so across from the
gold farm there we have this long
bridge that takes us to the library area
here
this is a big project we've been
ignoring it lately
i've been ignoring it lately you guys
have been wanting me to work on it
uh but we're trying to get some we're
trying to get the nexus to a good spot
before we
get back into this uh but this is what
we have currently just a bunch of
bookshelves around
we have a nice little enchanting area
over here
and also the book matrix thing
all our different enchantments can be
requested by pressing a button
if this is working not sure if it is
i think some of them were working some
of them needed some testing
[Music]
is that a power book i'm not sure
what the issue was i think they weren't
organized oh it is a power book
okay but yeah it requests them from
from all these chests here
which is where we're gonna be keeping
all our books all our enchanted books in
the future
all right so let's get out of here we
have glowing trees throughout our world
all those uh swamp trees down there have
pumpkins in them which
keep them lit up at night and i think
that looks really cool
okay this way back by the man cave
we have so many things to see
when hardened when hard and clay came
out i made this path up to the library
i thought it was the coolest thing and
now yeah
not quite so happy with it got our
tactus farm here this was based off of
our very first
world and i made a replica of it
automatically harvest cactus from above
there they drop down into the water
streams
all right nighttime is not the best time
to be
fooling around out here
[Music]
that's our nighttime song if we sleep
our daytime song plays there's a bunch
of noteblocks right underneath this bed
down there
and i'm sure you guys have heard that
plenty of times
[Music]
all right we are gonna go maybe up this
way first
yeah i think this is a good way to go
all right so just outside the
man cave here again
let's go this way first this is a
man-made river for the most part
uh sort of cutting through the mountains
here there's also
a mine shaft we made this pretty early
in our world
goes down oh
gotta dodge the lily pads on the way
down uh there's a room here for smelting
and for storage
this is also where that eats road meets
up
that we saw earlier
and there's tracks running throughout
this whole place to
deposit the items you get and more
donation
stuff down here to remember all the
people that helped me in the past when i
was first getting going
and it's a pretty big area down here
we're not gonna go check it out
all out though there was a thing here
for converting
boats into planks
oak planks
don't ask me why you place the boat here
though and it would break it
automatically
i doubt it works anymore
just out of curiosity because i never
use this thing anymore
like when the different types of wood
came out i think is when i made this
because jungle was was easier to get
yeah you can't place the boat there
anymore
yeah doesn't work anymore
uh let's get out of here though there's
some ender pearls in those dispensers
this was always a challenge i got it
right away there
oh maybe that got easier
and let's see up on the mountain
i don't know if we should bother
checking this out there is the ice cube
tray thing literally
an ice cube if we hurry with our ender
pearls we might get there in time
oh yeah and i harvested it recently too
so it's not done growing
um
but yeah this is a pretty cool ice farm
it will automatically
grow ice out of the ground 10 blocks
high
10 by 10 by 10 you get what is that a
thousand
blocks of ice every harvest and there's
like a rail carts
going underneath activating all the
pistons
although it's not working right now for
some reason
i might have to look into that
uh that should be working but it's not
okay was not expecting that anyway let's
go down
over there is sandy city this is a newer
build we've been working on
part of the biome enhancement project
where we're just
basically taking empty space and putting
something there that looks
a little bit better so we're trying to
build a wall around the city
got this cool little tassel gate thing
that actually functions
you run through it automatically closes
started building some houses here
sort of random buildings i love the path
that we have running through here i
think this looks really good
not the houses the path that's that's
what catches my attention with the build
uh this pyramid is hiding a mob firm
that mob farm that we saw in the man
cave all the mobs fall down
it gets incredibly good rates actually
uh the mobs get chased off the platform
from the cats and dogs inside
strategically
placed all right
let's keep moving let's see
giant field of sugarcane here
this path keeps going on through
to our left well actually this is the
main sheep farm i use believe it or not
uh just having a bunch of white sheep i
find works best
we have the you've been ethod up over
there that is based on a
thing good and bwo started a long time
ago when we were playing
the huge maps together and people
started making some fan art of it and
i i copied one of the fan arts people
made
and it looked just like that except i
made it 3d
recently we built this fence again part
of the biome enhancement project i've
converted a whole bunch of grassland
here into a wheat field
built a windmill windmill
windmill i always say that wrong
windmill right not meal
mill uh-huh got some scarecrows
throughout here the tractor
a bunch of random hay bales and stuff i
think that looks pretty cool
um let's go to the nexus why not this is
a giant storage room project we're
building
this is the biggest project i've ever
attempted in survival minecraft
and it's getting close to working
probably spent over a hundred hours on
it already
very complicated well not very
complicated it's very tedious it's very
a very big project that we've been
working on
and then up over this way everything is
relatively close together in the world
here i've tried to
compact things as much as possible
because i don't like running around all
day
let's see we're probably skipping over a
few things too but
this is uh the original village is the
first village i found in my world i'm
pretty sure
uh back when villagers didn't trade or
anything they just existed
as testificates they didn't do anything
they just
stood there they didn't even die like
zombies wouldn't kill them or anything
um converted all the wheat farms
actually functioning ones
and killed all the villagers at some
points and then
brought them back and killed them and
brought them back probably
a few times got a little portal to get
into the nether here
and if we go out further this way
we have the guardian farm not too far
from here
which works terribly
i afk there over nights like
10 hours or something came back and
there was less than
two double chests of stuff doesn't work
the greatest
so we might need to do some improvement
here
but basically they fall down through the
lava
burn up down below we also have a
guardian
this is like the randomest thing we have
a guardian
elder guardian a horse and a sheep
in the portal here don't ask me how they
all got there
darn i think it's gonna be over an hour
again i tried i'm trying to hurry
so much and it's not gonna happen is it
uh well from the village in the guardian
farm we then get to the stronghold base
out this way
and this is pretty much a furthest thing
we've built
out this direction and i am out of ender
pearls now
uh this was gonna originally be our
second base but i sort of dragged my
feet with it
for too long and got a little bit tired
of the area
there's actually controls all the way up
here to control the mob
farm to turn it on and off
and if we go down we're not totally done
with this area though don't
don't you worry about that we just need
to
i don't know rethink what we're what our
plan is what our goal is with it
but uh we we're gonna build a storage
room
this must have been before trap chest
came out because i was like staggering
the chests
even uh-huh
kind of weird to see all that we have
the big mob farm though
pretty happy with how this looks like
this facade for it
uh there was an item sorter no a mob
sorter we were building up here
and a bomb factory
thing where skeletons would shoot at the
creepers and then they would
get combined and blow up where we wanted
them to
for some reason i was gonna convert it
into
an automatic tree farm but then people
started doing like the wither
tree farms and i lost a little bit of
inspiration after that
but might eventually try to complete
that
then we have the silverfish farm which i
i still think is pretty cool to this day
where will automatically create stone
it's like a stone generator then they
enter the block
but detector detects that moves this
whole chain
forward starts clumping them all up
together
down here in this room if i fall in
there i don't think i can get out so i'm
not going to do that
but these are all silverfish blocks in
that room
and we have enough space in here to fit
exactly enough to get 50 levels of
experience back in the day
which you needed to enchant one thing
but that is all changed as you know
there's a bunch of sandstone stuff here
this goes up to the surface
this was a way of transporting the
silverfish around
as was this i had a lot of trouble with
moving them around
eventually we settled on some portal
method
i can't get out of here can i not having
ender pearls is terrible
i guess we could probably go to the end
next
yeah why not we skipped a few things in
the nether we might
go back and check those out but let's go
to the end first
uh since we're here so this is our our
way to the end
[Music]
first thing you hear that is the musical
portal setup
thing we are randomly creating music
right now
i did look at them darn it
man these guys are so fast
[Music]
all right good thing we put the armor on
today
friends i don't think we're friends
all right anyways it's playing music uh
out this way is the original
ender ender maybe i'll just pause the
video and walk out this way to show you
so at the end of the eats road here we
come down into this glass tunnel
and down the whole way we have a rail
line running too
what you can do with this is put some
ender pearls in this
minecart chest and it would
automatically go back
and drop them off near the portal if you
wanted to
transport them easily but yeah this is
the original ender ender
and as you can see it does not stack
it's totally flat but they spawn up
there and then pistons push them down
and
and they drop down is that
yeah that is wool up there okay i wasn't
sure if i put melons
for those yellow blocks but that's
that's yellow wool
spent a lot of time here back when i
built this i didn't even realize like
this was going to be an xp farm i just
wanted ender pearls
and it kind of caught on that hey this
is a really good way of getting xp
and eventually people figured out how to
stack the layers and
yeah and now today we have even better
ones that use endermites
but i did make a second ender farm so
let's go check that out it's out
that way you can see the other path over
there in the distance
that's the old ender ender out there and
it comes back and then we come down and
we have this long
path going off from the island
this took a long time to make but
i think it looks pretty cool and then we
arrive to the ender ender 2.0
a little bit more sophisticated than the
original one over there
uh let's go into the room it's all made
out of courts
got a little enchanting area here let's
turn them down because you know how that
is
um the way this one works you you stack
up tnt
then you take a flame bow
yeah they all gather on the two sides
here
down to one hit kills they fall from all
the spawning platforms up there
and then
trying to remember what what do we do
again
oh yeah up here so up here there's a
giant column of tnt you can place
and whenever you're ready to harvest
them you just
shoot it with a flame bow
and get xp from them
because it's your tnt that blows up if
you hold a looting sword you get
extra pearls as well
and we're so so much better than the
original one
anyway we're running out of time so
let's let's keep moving here
all right we're going to check out a few
things in the nether here now uh so we
just recently built this path
out to a desert where we get our sand
from
uh it's pretty long tunnel connects up
to the nether hub here
if we go out this way are they mad at me
we're friends again awesome if we go out
this way actually let's take a horse
oops this is the horse switcheroo
you can alternate between donkey and
horse
give them potions ride them out
this goes to the mesa biome where we get
our clay
and this is also where we have our rube
goldberg
machine thing that we've been working on
and also the amplified bases out this
way too
it's a long pass maybe i should have cut
there anyway let's let's keep going
without falling off please oh
i'm stuck on oh because i'm on soul sand
i can't
walk up that apparently okay don't
go through this portal horsey i want to
want to take you back
all right so through here this is our
mining
outpost for for the mesa clay stuff
um basically you can send out a cart
storage mine cart fill it up and then it
comes back and automatically deposits
off into these chests
they automatically filter type of clay
to the one it belongs in and you can
ride it out yourself
and then up here up on the surface is
where the rube goldberg machine is
and there's not a lot to it right now
but we did build like a village
as the final part of it
oh that's a bad throw no
all the way at the bottom okay now we
have to cut
so this is the rube goldberg machine
see you um let's not stand
down over here or here
but uh yeah a little bit of a fun
setup with the tnt minecarts and stuff
and then the villager goes out this way
this is where the village thing is
which is probably the most impressive
part of the whole thing
for right now anyway and he goes into
there
this is the village up here
we did this for episode 400 the 400
special
i just wanted to see it again today
because it's cool uh but yeah this is
our village
built this all in one episode took quite
a while
um and then he burns it down and it all
explodes and it's pretty cool
and the horse dies of course all right
anyways let's go back to the nether
so yeah just a little bit further in the
nether past that mesa
outpost we have the amplified terrain
um our amplified base this is a
very much work in progress
raining and night time could it be any
worse
we have a bunch of like movement related
stuff
here though like we have a a boat road
up there that goes across
and we used to have a launcher here i
think i might have ripped that out
already i can't remember
yeah i think the boat launcher is gone
uh but we're
we're basically trying to build a base
here and we've done a little bit of work
on it but there's a lot left to do
there's a chicken farm
up there the chickens will automatically
get shot out and then they
float down down here and
don't really do anything except spam the
world
for right now and got a little bit of a
polished up area here this is for a
mobile
storage room which is incomplete at the
moment i think it all works i just have
to run some rail lines and then it'll be
done
let's see we got our our bounce pads up
here
to get around they work pretty good
actually
they're a lot of fun and there is also
a sheep farm down there that's a work in
progress
and there's a flower farm up up
somewhere too but i don't know how to
get to it
oh yeah in the oakwood farm man we
actually got a fair bit of stuff here
don't we
yeah you plant the did i say oak wood
i mean dark oak dark oak plant the
saplings here they grow and then they
automatically get clumped together in a
a big thing here and the leaves get
crushed so you get the saplings back
from them
uh-huh but that's the amplified base in
a nutshell
okay so back in the nether now from the
nether hub if we go
this way this goes out to the stronghold
base
the guardian farm stuff is over here so
just to the left
the guardians will accumulate here and
then you can kill them and get xp
and extra drops and all that kind of
stuff to the right here is the
stronghold base in this portal
i think this one takes you to
[Music]
um is it the villager purifier thing
yes it is okay this is a special build i
did
way over the top it's basically a zombie
spawner
and you can you can convert the zombie
villagers into villagers here
and there's some special logic to do it
all kind of automatically
and then send them to to the portal here
had a lot of fun making this actually
even though it's pretty much pointless
this was a really enjoyable build
and it goes up to the surface here
and there there's the tower the mob
tower
all right so let's go back into here
was there anything else um
all these portals are connected together
well there's my ride darn it
yeah he's dead i wonder
interesting something's wrong with the
timer on that one
it seems okay in the nether now
if we go a little bit further
we have one of my favorite builds as
well
that we almost never see anymore because
we don't really need xp like we did in
the past
but uh just out this way
yeah there it is right down there never
really made a fancy way of getting here
but just off from the tunnel is the dual
blaze farm
and i think it still works
let's see one of my most popular videos
actually is the blaze farm tutorial for
some reason
i don't know why
that that seems to work still so i never
did find a good way of uh
moving them around but i think
this should do the trick still there was
uh switches for turning the stuff all on
and off this is working right
that turns it off so it puts out enough
light that they won't spawn
but otherwise i think it does work
and that conveyor belt system basically
moves them up to the lava
and then they swim up into this
this holding room here and there was a
special timer i built
which was way more complicated than it
needed to be
nowadays because you just use a hopper
timer
but this was a pulse extender a very
fancy one
um that had like no delay it was it was
made in a certain way
all right everybody so probably the
final thing we have time to check out
today
is the gold farm here this is the second
gold farm we built
and this one uses iron golems to kill
the
the pigmen they will also sometimes kill
the gas
if they get in their way and
there's a hopper minecart that runs
underneath the whole thing it picks up a
few items here at the start so that it
guaranteed
will always pick up those items and not
like the junky gold swords on the
on the ground and then all the items get
dropped off here
for our enjoyment oh i almost just fell
down below is also the wither skeleton
farm
both of these are pretty big projects
that i spent a lot of time on
um i totally like redid a fortress here
though
made it have a lot of spawning space
and lots of wither skeletons spawn here
i also slabbed out
a big portion of the land nearby
like all that over there so we get
really good spawning rates here
and i think that's probably gonna have
to do it though for our tour we're gonna
skip the comment of the day today
because of the length of the video
but i hope you guys enjoyed it hopefully
you saw something you didn't see before
or maybe saw something you haven't seen
in a long time and
got got a nostalgic feeling for it or
something i don't know
hopefully you enjoyed the episode thank
you guys for watching
have a wonderful day take care bye bye
you