[Music]
hello hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
and we
are back again with another episode of
the let's play series
and i have just updated our world to
1.17 which means today
we are going out on an adventure oh i'm
actually pretty excited about this i
don't get to go
on adventures too often in our in our
old world here but
because all the new stuff is in new
chunks pretty much we have to go out on
an adventure
we get to explore we get to collect all
the new stuff
and then maybe we'll get around to
building farms and playing around and
testing things out
oh all the stuff i love to do
uh so yeah we gotta go far far away
right to get to
all the new chunks and stuff well not
too bad not too bad um
you might recall we have built
an expansive array of tunnels in our
nether here and when i was building this
and i got a carpal tunnel from building
for so long pretty much it's like was
this really worth it am i going to use
this tunnel actually and i have been
using this tunnel
so this goes out to the crimson keep but
we're also going to head out there today
and just
drop the portal and see what's on the
other side in the overworld and it's
going to be brand new chunks
don't have to build any infrastructure
it's all pre-built for us already
oh man it's dangerous here it is very
dangerous yeah i just set up a portal
over here we're gonna go through
now place your predictions do you think
anything's gonna be different
in amplified terrain with the new stuff
i don't know i kind of suspect it'll be
much the same
oh boy okay so not the best portal here
we got put underground
we are at y 28 so i think what we're
going to do is bust this and try bring
it up to the surface
because uh i've done this before where i
leave the portal down underground and i
always regret it later
uh we do have new stuff right lykan
that's the lichen so something kind of
caught me off guard with this the
the terrain generated very quickly
so that either means one of two things
either i've been here before
and i don't remember going here or
mojang have really improved the chunk
generation
times because my goodness it was fast it
was like
i've been here before normally like the
game stutters a lot when you're loading
new chunks
um so oh yeah there's copper
there is copper here okay that's good
news
uh let's go i'm gonna try and make our
way up to the surface
definitely noticing like the caves here
are crazy
as well right like they're just
splitting all over the place i don't
know if that's an amplified thing
or just the area here
haha we got the drip stone awesome okay
so that wasn't too hard to find
let's start putting together a goodie
bag here with all the new cool stuff
from the update
we'll see how much we can get today um
so i found a way up to
the surface here from the cave which is
awesome i didn't have to
dig a tunnel or anything and
brand new terrain here guys brand new
look at this
i'm gonna fly around a little bit and
just see how it does in the
in the video here if it like stutters or
for if we're good because it might be
quick now i don't know
like this is amplify terrain it's
usually really slow
so it is struggling a little bit but
honestly i think it might be a bit
faster like this is brand new terrain
it's generating
while i'm recording at 1080p and stuff
like this is a huge load on my cpu my
fan is going
crazy right now uh it's not bad though
it's honestly not too bad okay so we got
really lucky with our starting spot here
we
we came out at the swamp but there is an
ocean right by it
and we gotta get some moss from a
shipwreck
so this is perfect also i think the
easiest way to find the geos is just to
go to the ocean
because you usually see them sticking
out at the ground
oh we got coral reefs here good good
good i have to like go
and just mine a big coral reef sometime
so i got those blocks because i still
don't really have
a supply of them anywhere oh i think
that's one right
there is that no that's sand that's just
sand no it is a shipwreck
oh i did not want to do that oh we got
it on the first one look at that
okay cool now i'm just gonna get
distracted for a second here i know
we're on an important mission and
everything but uh i do want to sightsee
a little bit and this caught my
attention we got
ice spikes biome which are normally
pretty rare
and they look really cool and amplified
so i just want to see if there's
anything
any cool views here it's kind of a tiny
one
yeah not too much not too much i don't
know if we can get the powdered snow
naturally is that a naturally spawning
thing or can you only get it from
cauldrons
this is solid snow it's not powdered so
i just checked the minecraft wiki and
you can only get the powered snow if you
farm it currently but in the next update
1.18
it'll spawn naturally in a couple places
uh-huh so i think it's time we go mining
i think so let's get some copper let's
get some iron some gold all the
all the good stuff so check this out
fortune does up it does work on
the copper you actually get quite a bit
like we got six from that one i think we
got
four or three from that one two
six three yeah so it's
pretty good actually it won't take too
long to get a lot of copper i
really love what they did with the oars
i know it's a little bit of a mixed
feeling in the community some people
like it some people don't
uh i think it was a huge huge
improvement to the game
so for one thing they kept adding
more and more ways to use iron in the
game right
it's like oh we got hoppers oh we got
cauldrons we got chains we got all these
new iron
uh eating things in the game and they
never added a new way of getting iron
now you can fortune iron and you get a
lot more so caving
for iron just got way better right
you don't necessarily have to make an
iron firm anymore like for the average
minecraft player obviously someone like
me that plays the game all day
probably still got to make an iron farm
but for the average minecraft player the
game just became way more
friendly i i would say and you know kind
of similar to iron with the gold they've
added more and more ways to use your
gold in the game with the piglen
bartering and stuff you you need more of
it you want more of it
and now you can get more of it when you
go caving
so david just got way better which i
love like it
it's still probably better to make an
iron farm a gold farm in the game but it
doesn't feel like you're wasting your
time
as badly when you go caving caving is
more rewarding now
which i think is just wonderful and uh
the other cool thing about the oars is
they've added a bit of utility to the
game so if you think about it
you can compress them into a new type of
block for the copper the gold and the
iron
so that's great because like when you're
out caving takes up less space in your
inventory right
and also for building you've got a cool
looking block added to the game i love
that
uh but now that brings us to the main
thing i wanted to talk about
motion have added something in this
update that really excites me i don't
know if they did it intentionally or not
but uh they have added a reason
to go mining in minecraft
villager trading has in my opinion kind
of ruined the game a little bit
the game used to be a bit more about
like exploring
and uh gathering resources and then like
maybe you go
looking for some oars you go build a
mine shaft underground a road
a minecart track to get to your mine
shaft all that kind of stuff you
explore the world you get resources from
your world you build up your worlds
and then after everything is built
hopefully you can interact with your
world
with villager trading it's kind of like
they added a cheapo creative system into
survival minecraft
instead of like going out and exploring
your world
building stuff in it you're literally
just
opening up a village or gui and buying
stuff kind of like a creative mode
window right and i think that sucks but
in this update guess what
guess what you can't get this from
villagers uh-uh you have to go mining
for it
same with calcite can't get calcite
anywhere the deep slate you can only get
underground so there's actually a reason
to go caving now
oh we found our first little guy here
what do you guys think here do you think
it's a copper vein or just a lot of
granite
it's supposed to spawn near granite
at least it's a bunch of granite yeah
i'm trying to keep my eyes out i want i
would love to find a copper vein oh yeah
there's a few of them down here
nice
oh yeah
gotten that one a few times i don't know
what i just discovered
something in the ravine there must have
been a snowy biome i don't know or a
beach
cold uh oh i bet you it's a cold beach
snowy beach yeah
woohoo all right check it out i've been
mining for a bit we got over a stack of
the iron and copper now
and most of the other stuff we were
looking for and now we have stumbled
across
not really stumbled i've been looking
for a while we have found the mine shaft
guys
we need a mine shaft for the uh
i don't know what they're called because
i've never found one yet i think they're
called glowberries or something
they spawn in mine shaft chests in this
update
also we got the new mine shafts in this
update with the chains and there's like
logs underneath
uh they kind of burnt on that one but uh
it's cool a little bit more decoration
to it
i like it so we gotta find some chess
that's our main
hunting here okay we got cave spiders
things could get hairy here
oh cave spiders plus skeletons the
ultimate
duo the skeletons shoot you in the
cobwebs
and then the cave spiders ruin your day
that's the way it works
okay we got one we got one everybody let
me place the torch okay
first chest ah we didn't get it
okay all right we'll keep looking it's
fine
just a random chicken down here where
did that chicken come from
i wonder i think that's all there is to
it
oh wait wait i haven't been up here
that's all there is to it this is a
weird mineshaft there's a lot of these
little
dead end things yeah we just found the
one chest in here so we gotta escape we
gotta find a new mine shaft
oh it keeps going look at that so if you
get to a dead end on a cable a lot of
times there'll just be another team
behind
it although this dead ended
but maybe if we keep going i hear water
oh yes okay we found we found out that
in my shop that's perfect
that's exactly what we're looking for oh
and there's uh there's one right there
awesome okay we're safe yeah oh
none in there didn't get the globe berry
but
but there is nobody but we just didn't
get it
ah darn he's cheating he's in the he's
in the lava
oh yes okay okay okay this is it this is
the one
oh yeah we got it we got it
okay so it took a little bit of time but
we found it oh there's another one
okay this is bonus chest let's see if we
get more oh okay this is where we should
have went to begin with
now we're just finding tons of them okay
we're gonna mine
this deep slate over here so here's the
thing we're in the mountains actually
means there's a chance we can get a deep
slate emerald block that's like the
ultra rare
super cool bonus points deep slate
silver silverfish
got it then you actually get like
overrun with silverfish
like never go mining in mountains looks
like you can't get that many spawning
okay so check it out this is what we've
got so far i think we're pretty much
done with our mission here obviously
i'll be back here if i need to
get more deep slate or anything like
that but we've pretty much got
a little bit of everything now that we
needed from the update here
except for the geodes so i looked around
for geodes i did find one eventually
right over here kind of near where we
came out
um do any of you guys know how these
generate because i've been really
curious about that like from what i've
observed so far i've never seen two of
them like
really close to each other so i don't
know if there's something in the code
that
spaces them out or if i just
happen to get unlucky with it because i
would love to get like four or five of
them together right and make a big
amethyst farm
so i did look around the ocean a fair
bit and i did find more geods but again
none of them were really together
they're always like at least 100 blocks
apart from each other and that just
might be like me getting unlucky with it
i don't know
but that's just what i've observed so
far and while mining i did find another
geode over here and also when i came out
uh after i dug up to the surface i did
find some goats
uh-huh we got goats which is awesome i'm
gonna try bringing those guys back
there's another one uh wandering around
somewhere waiting to
headbutt me probably but yeah while
mining i i dug up here and there was a
geo down here
as well so like i think those two are
close enough together where i could farm
at least two together
and there's probably at least one or two
more in the area so
maybe we do that i don't know
um but i do want to get a little bit of
amethyst before we head back here
so the other question is what is the
best way of
farming these i might just set up a
bunch of pistons and then just manually
trigger it
to break the crystals and then get the
shards
all right so check it out we got the
geode pretty much mined out here that's
kind of step one to making an amethyst
farm just expose as many of these
crystal sides as possible
um and leave all the crystals behind
obviously you don't want to break these
because you can't get them back
now i mined out one of these geodes
before and it only had 18 of these
crystal seed things
this one has over 30 so this is like a
super geode actually
so not all of them are created equal we
got about 10 stacks of calcite and
amethyst from
from this geode as well from mining it
now how do we make the farm trying to
figure that out
uh so i'm pretty sure you can waterlog
these so you can't use water to break
the crystals i think we're gonna have to
go for pistons
and probably the smartest way to do it
is to work from the top and go
down and when you use the piston to
break the crystal
you need to figure out a way to make the
crystal shards
drop into a water stream and then like
combine all the water streams together
and then like the water streams from
several different geodes together
all into one central location so it's
actually like a
big crazy thing to do because you're
gonna need like hundreds of pistons for
this right there's so many sides
okay you know what normally i'm like oh
guys this is how you automate stuff
right you just
get a bunch of pistons in the redstone
in it oh it works amazing you should do
it too
i'm going to go out and say don't try to
automate this farm it's not worth it
just mind the crystals yourself i'll
probably try to automate it just because
i like the challenge but it
is a nightmare absolute nightmare it's a
giant puzzle
and this is two of the seeds this is
what just getting two of them done looks
like
so it's like 11 or 12 pistons there
i decided to go for hoppers instead of
water streams just because they're more
compact i don't have to worry about
water
spilling over the redstone as i'm
working on this
uh but yeah the crazy thing is you also
have to run redstone over atop all the
pistons you have to
uh watch out for creepers as you're
building this because if a creeper comes
along at any point
he's going to blow up your your seeds
all your hard work and you're going to
feel so bad
and guess what you got to build this
underground so you're going to have dark
caves around and stuff
okay well i worked a little bit more on
it here i think we got six or seven
hooked up now
like over 40 pistons all activating
harvest the thing and
maybe a fifth done but i'm out of it i'm
done for today on this
it's very tedious there's a llama
spawner
look at this what are you doing llama
you don't belong here oh we got horse
armor
i'll take it no way
okay well here comes the tricky part now
we got two goats in the nether
and uh when i pushed them through the
portal it spawned a new portal in my
bridge and broke my bridge
and we're just holding them in boats
right now so they don't wander around
but we're gonna use a lead
to get them around i could you know i
could build a minecart track and do it
like super safe but i am
usually kind of lazy when it comes to
that kind of stuff i try to use the mob
behavior as
much as possible like whenever i'm
moving villagers you know i set up
workstations so they move to the
workstations and i don't have to move
them around
uh if i'm moving animals i try to use
leads to do it instead of minecarts this
is so much
so much faster and easier to like remove
the track after and stuff you know
so he shouldn't wander off the edge i
don't think
i would be surprised if he did you gotta
get him up here
to the the road and then just boat him
back to
our nether hub easy peasy
got the boat yep there we go let's go
oh i'm sorry so something i realized
just recently that i probably should
have realized a long time ago is it's
actually really smart to have like two
of every animal
at your nether hub like two goats two
donkeys two chickens
two horses villagers have a few of every
animal here so that if you want to move
them anywhere else in your world you got
your nether roads all set up
it's really easy to do that you don't
have to worry about like i've had my
donkeys go extinct on me
i've almost had the llamas go extinct
because i only brought a few over right
and
uh they're only in one spot in my world
and if they accidentally die
guess what i gotta go thousands of
blocks to get more llamas
but if i had two llamas in my nether hub
here just go to netherhub
breed a couple more and uh yeah
oh oh i bet you it was a ramming attack
i didn't expect the little guys to do
the ramming attacks but i guess it makes
sense that uh
they all would do it unless he got mad
because i put the food away
i look like he said no there
so apparently you can get milk from
goats if you want
uh i don't think you can put saddles on
them and the little guys you can feed
wheat to grow faster question mark
okay no you can't settle them oh that
would have been cool because they jump
really high right
and you could use them for getting
around vertically
uh-huh so whenever a new animal comes
out in this game one of my goals with
our world now is to
try to spread them throughout our
pre-existing world so that it's not like
uh
they don't exist you know because we
never see pandas we never see any of
these things in our world
because you know i never populated them
anywhere right so i brought some goats
up to our ice farm area here i'll
probably spread them around the man cave
area and a few other places as well
just so it feels like they're part of
our world and in the game
instead of like we never see them so
over at our ice farm uh
another thing i want to do here is just
drop down a bunch of cauldrons so next
time it rains in the game i'm going to
come out here
and we'll try to collect some of that
powdered snow in the cauldrons and
we may eventually set up a farm here for
it
seems like this would be a good area
because i kind of afk here for the ice
already
so i have a bit of a question for you
guys this is one of those things i've
had a hard time deciding myself i'm just
kind of curious where you guys sit on it
like whenever a new update comes out do
you think i should try to enhance
the man cave with the new features or
should we leave it
kind of the way it is because it for the
most part like most of the areas we see
here are
are done right but whenever a new update
comes out there is potential to
enhance it like we got the stone slabs a
long time ago
you know i could smooth out the cave
with these with the stone stairs and we
could mix
andesite into the walls all that kind of
stuff i kind of chose not to
i don't know if that was the right
decision though like
and like with this update now we've
gotten more foliage and stuff we got
these
drip stone things we could hang in
places do you think that's a mistake
let me know in the comments because i
really struggle with that decision
okay so i think for the rest of this
episode i kind of just want to play
around with the new stuff and just see
how it works how it works with the game
that kind of stuff
so can we get the smooth basalt from
the nether update basalt
[Music]
it is smelting okay that's good what
happens when we smelt
deep slate iron does it just give us an
ingots um
i don't think you can smelt the full
blocks of these can you
no because i think it takes nine i
or nine uh copper ingots to make a
copper block right
i almost feel like maybe they should add
a way to smell the full block
and make it just take longer or
something i don't know i don't know
you gotta uncompress it and then smelt
it and then recompress it as the block i
guess
um so we did get some gobble deep slate
you get that if you don't use silk touch
that smelts into i think regular deep
slate which you can get with silk touch
that can't be smelted again into
anything okay so
this turns into the smooth no it does
nothing
hmm where's my grindstone where is this
thing
i need to learn can it not go in oh it
can't go in even
interesting so that's the like the cook
stuff
the silk touched one okay and then if
you put the cobbled one in that's where
you get all the options
yep yep so the basalt is getting turned
into smooth basalt this is the new block
that was added oh there goes my bed so i
could ask you guys what is your favorite
thing about this update but
uh you know i don't need to i already
know it's the moss block right
i think everybody loves the moss vlog
it's amazing oh it's so cool you get all
this neat stuff from it
it looks awesome uh i did want to check
the
lichen can you grow that with oatmeal
if i was to guess i would say no oh
i was wrong look at that okay
this kind of keeps spreading
that's actually kind of a a neat thing i
don't think anything else in the game
does that
huh i wish it was a different color i
don't like how it looks
it doesn't work with a lot of stuff in
the game um
although from a distance that's not too
bad right it's this one you're looking
right at it
just don't look right at it and it's
fine
okay okay uh these can you grow them or
do they need to be the azaleas oh no you
can go
grow them just like that and that gets
you the dirts the rooted dirts
all right and then the rooted dirt i
think we can bone meal
for cool stuff as well
yeah look at that oh wait
can we still touch it no i think we
gotta shear it then
do i got shears i do have shoes on me
there we go yeah you gotta shear it
interesting does the the lichen does it
hang at all i don't think so right
no okay i kind of have mixed feelings
about the rooted dirt like for me
personally i think i like the way it's
implemented currently because it
adds a new farm to the game like you
would want to farm the rooted dirt
and it's kind of a little bit of tricky
thing to farm not really
uh but it's just an extra thing to do in
the game right
but on the other hand i kind of feel
like they should have just made it
craftable
you know like you you get the roots you
get the dirt
you still gotta farm the roots i don't
know
what do you guys think about that one
you right-click it that turns it to
regular dirt and then
there's no way to make it or can you
wait wait can you click this onto it to
do it no
they did add something pretty cool with
the moss blocks like you know you can
craft
carpets out of them right but there's
another thing you can craft
you can make mossy cobbles so you don't
necessarily need vines anymore you can
still do it with vines but there's
another option now
and i like that i think that's cool you
can also do the mossy bricks
all right it just turned nighttime here
so the lichen the glow like in has a
light level of seven
let's check out the globe berries can
you hang them from leaves no you can't
probably hang them for moss though right
yeah so the vine itself doesn't emit any
light
it's just the berries
okay how do we make the vine grow
can we not bonemeal divine does that
does it grow naturally
oh we probably shouldn't have done that
oh i guess we had berries right
as we do it oh okay you just right click
more berries on it i'm an idiot
it doesn't feel like a plant right the
berry doesn't feel like a plant to me
i'm like really trying not to sleep here
so that it'll rain and i can get some of
that powdered snow
it's tough though it's a tough life so
you can't eat the glow berries
i just had an idea with that too how
cool would it have been if they made the
glow berries
give you the same effect as the spectral
arrows where you actually glow
right and like someone you'll be playing
with someone it's like etho where are
you you eat the glowberry and then you
get highlighted for them
i think that would have been neat
because i do feel like there's a bit of
an issue in this game where they keep
adding new foods to the game but
it's like you're only going to eat
golden carrots right maybe at the very
beginning you'll you'll eat something
else
but like if they added a special effect
to new foods
like kind of like how chorus fruit
allows you to teleport that's awesome
i i would love if glowberries made you
glow or let you have night vision or
or something like that right i think
would uh
make food even though you don't eat it
all the time it'll still have some value
in the game
but i do love this plant this plant
looks awesome i like how it gives off
light
everything about it besides like the
actual food is awesome
and speaking of awesome we also got new
leaf blocks in this update and they look
so
good oh they look so good i'm so happy
about these
many months ago one of the mojang
developers was talking to me and he's
like etho
what are you looking forward to in the
next update what do you want to see
and i was like new leaf blocks more
foliage in the game
and he's like oh i think you're gonna
like this update i can't tell you what's
in it but i think you're gonna like it
and uh yeah i like it
i really hope in future updates they
keep adding more foliage and leaf
blocks and stuff because i they have
such a wide application to building in
minecraft
and they've uh they don't have much
variety currently right there's so much
potential like if you look at mod packs
you got orange leaves you got yellow
leaves all kinds of leaves
um so this is a great step towards that
i would say
i believe these also keep their color
which is oh yeah
i can actually make my desert look nice
now
you know you don't want to do too much
of it but just a little bit here and
there
would have a big impact
what a fighter
oh he's going for another one wait a
second
now he froze he's like wait a second i
thought they'd take a break after they
killed somebody
oh he's getting he's getting attacked
back that's why he's stopping the heel
uh-huh so one thing i'm not really too
sure of just yet is
uh oh that was nice
our copper farm is going to be a thing
in this because you can get copper from
the
drowned guys right it's pretty rare
though and these guys spawn extremely
rarely
anyone drop any nope no drops
hmm oh there we go
there we go everybody so i've spent
about 15 minutes or so
farming the drown guys here um
where is he there he is uh
so yeah i've gotten three copper so far
uh foreign and a trident
so uh i checked the wiki page just to
see how low it was and it's eight
percent with looting three that you'll
get a copper and get currently in the
next update though they're gonna buff
it a bit it's going to
17 with looting three um
but yeah that's still just cocaine
i don't think it's gonna be very
effective to make a farm for these guys
all right everybody well i think it's
about time we think about wrapping up
our episode for today i do have a couple
things to show you real quick over here
uh this cobble wall so you remember you
may
actually probably didn't even notice but
the cobble wall used to end over there
always kind of bugged me i was supposed
to finish it and uh now i finally
finished it
it extends all the way out uh up to
there so
it doesn't feel like it ends randomly
anymore
and also i did remove the mountain over
top the nexus i do
want to do more with that though like we
just have these big straight walls
i'll either uh curve them out and make
them look more natural or we'll build
something
around the nexus up there is my current
plan but i haven't figured it out just
yet
more work to do uh this is what the map
looks like after
after we've done that it looks way way
cooler i think i like it i like
it anyways let's get to the comment of
the day
and uh yeah it's a it's a fitting one it
says etho
why haven't you uploaded in a while so
for those of you that don't know i've
pretty much just been uploading third
life lately
and just been taking it easy haven't
really uploaded any let's plays
or had a lot a big gap without hermit
craft as well
uh no like specific reason
it pretty much came down to like ever
since hermitcraft season seven
started back i think in march last year
to like january february of this year
i've been playing a lot of minecraft
like a lot of minecraft and it was
getting to the point where i felt like i
needed a break so i
i've just been playing other games in my
steam library taking a break from
minecraft
um i was worried if i didn't take a
break like when 117 came out here
and i just kept pushing and pushing and
pushing that i would just
burn out like when it came out and that
would be the worst time
at the start of a new season of hermit
craft and a new update and all that
stuff so
i'm feeling good now like i got plenty
of energy right
update just came out is the perfect time
to be refreshed
um i do try to keep my uh
youtube channel here as a hobby which
means i don't really set a schedule i
upload stuff when i want to
uh i upload what i want to as well i'm
not just like trying to chase views
uh the downside of that is you know it's
not a
not a great way to grow a successful
youtube channel
you should be uploading regularly but
i've been doing this so long i'm kind of
the point where uh you know i don't care
i just
i just do what i want to do at this
point you know i would rather be happy
than
like growing my numbers and stuff if
that makes sense there's more important
things
in life right and that's kind of where
i'm at at this point
so i'm happy to be back though i hope
you guys enjoyed this episode i'm going
to try to keep uploading more regularly
again
uh now that the update's out and i hope
you enjoy it so thanks for watching
take care have a good day bye