Hey
hey what are you doing stop that that's
disgusting don't pick your nose stop
picking your nose how's it going guys
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play series
I guarantee you guys statistically at
least a few dozen people were probably
picking their nose when they started
this episode and I bet you I just gave
them the scare of their lifetime with
that oh man they got caught they got
caught and they were confused anyway so
guys I've been working on the next this
year I decided I would try to tackle the
beast again there was a comment on it
last episode that some some people want
me to return to this project
so I had a lot of tedious stuff to do
with it but we should be able to move
forward pretty soon have you ever wanted
to try collect one of everything in
Minecraft have you ever done that
challenge that's kind of what I had to
do here so I I went around my world
collecting things and I'm trying to
organize them in our chests here as
neatly as I could and try to keep
everything together in groups as best as
I could so we got like our ores here
slabs and stairs and then got our stone
category up here dirt wood sandstone
stuff then we have redstone I got plant
materials we got this is like wool and
random blocks in this chest and then
rails um miss items we got the glass and
dyes and then finally food and clay were
the categories I kept in mind and I just
I've been following our list here that
we made a long time ago pretty much got
everything on the list I decided to axe
off a few items though that seemed like
unnecessary to store like anything I
would craft like in place I wouldn't
really need or earth
things I wouldn't use very often I
decide not to include like daylight
sensor I've made maybe two of those or
three of those in my world since since I
started it so I don't think I need three
double chests full of daylight sensors
sort of things so I decided to axe those
off the list for example and now what we
got to do maybe we will grab our dyes
and maybe glass let's do the dyes first
you got to take all these items and
start adding them to the item filters in
our nexus storage room here so I decided
to put all these colored things like the
colored clay and the colored wool on the
top floor of this because they're least
likely to cause me problems down the
line like the random blocks I might need
to add or remove them in the future and
Oh
or I'm more likely to make a mistake
with them too so wait this isn't the top
floor I want the top floor up here let's
make sure I do this right so yeah it
makes most sense to put the colored
stuff on the top floor and then like the
random stuff on the bottom all right so
we should also try to keep this as
organized as we can because the easier
it is to remember where stuff is the
better so maybe we'll try to follow a
color pattern like will do the
monochrome stuff first we'll go white to
the dark gray black we have 32 items per
row that we can enter here and that
works out pretty good because there's 16
different colors in the game I mean
Google Brown next and maybe switch over
to like the red colors try to do like a
rainbow
I guess uh-huh but anyway I'm going to
spend a little bit of time on this
off-camera just trying to enter all 256
items into our item filters here and
I'll be back in a little bit cow break
whoa check it out guys we are locked and
loaded here all 256 item filters have
been filled it is amazing it is glorious
took a long time to collect all this
stuff and put it in but I'm very happy
this step is done so was one of the more
challenging things um I count bad though
I don't count so good
turns out I thought we would have a few
extra spots after it was all said and
done no in fact we went over by like 16
items so I removed the dyes from the
system just so that there would be
enough room for everything and in the
future like I know you guys you're like
etho what it what if there's an update
factors one coming out soon I think
what if there's an update that adds more
blocks and stuff well I think if that
happens I'm going to remove anything
that I'm not using very much like that's
a low priority and I'll replace it with
the new item if I think I'll use it I
think that's the best way of handling
this the next step of this we we are
very close to a fully functioning like
item pickup system where we can we can
store stuff automatically we got to add
in some water streams though to carry
the items to these hoppers now started
no is it that torch this torch doing it
I see you over there
you stupid torch okay so I made a backup
before I started this because I'm I'm
terrified of this step if this water
leaks can I break this without crying I
think I can okay I'm gonna try remove
that torch um if there's water leaks
it's gonna wash away my redstone and
then it's GG basically and I got a load
of back up and try again
no I'm not very happy about this it's a
sea lantern I think that's melting it so
I have to
shut off the water break this lock
replace it with a solid block and then
put the sign back break these knees and
then put the water back okay and there
were a few steps to that and I gotta do
it all the way down like so many times
but I think that'll fix it you know I
was so worried about this ice here and
then I ended up breaking the pact ice by
accident we got a leak we got a leak I
gotta load the back up and try again
this isn't so bad actually I realized I
can just put packed ice here and I only
need the regular ice over the chest so
that's just four spots there's no way
for this to leak out if it melts so it's
perfect and I'm stuck in a hopper no I
hate when that happens
so guys if you haven't seen it yet
Mojang have revealed what the theme of
the 1.9 update is going to be it's a
combat update they revealed it in the
April 1st like joke snapshot and I am
pretty excited for it it sounds like I
saw a tweet recently that they asked if
we were ready for updates so I think the
snapshots are going to be coming out
soon and we're gonna actually see what
content they have made and I am pretty
hyped about it it's been a few months
since the last update and we desperately
need a new one
so the combat update has me pretty
interested I don't know if that means
they have like focused on redoing game
mechanics like combat mechanics to the
game if they have I kind of hope they
make it more reactionary like where you
you can like prayer parry attacks and
block attacks and like counter
counter what people do and sort of do
that but I don't know how well that
would work I think no matter what they
do if they rebounce the combat mechanics
they're going to upset quite a few
people yeah it's one of those hard
things to change because no matter what
they do they still have to deal with leg
and I don't think they can ever perfect
it really but I think maybe it's not so
much like combat mechanics of change but
maybe they've just added more combat
things to the game like I'm pretty sure
they've redone the Enderdragon fight and
it sounded like they even changed
terrain generation in the end and and a
whole bunch other stuff with it so I'm
excited to see that and I don't know
what else they've been doing but they've
been working on it for quite a while so
I'm sure there's a lot of things they
haven't shown us so yeah it's going to
be pretty cool um this is done with that
I think we finished it so I got water
streams running between all the rows now
all the water streams are in so this
should fully automatically pick up items
and store them now we're gonna have to
try this out okay guys so at the very
top left of the Nexus here this is where
the water stream begins for the
automatic storage and I'm just going to
add in one more alignment thing here
alright so when you throw in an item it
should hit the ender chest and then it
physicians item between the hopper and
the ice so it can still move very
quickly through the water streams but
the hoppers are able to pick them up
still the very last item this is going
to reach is the oak oak wood so I'm
going to throw a couple of these in and
see if they make it all the way and
maybe just a few oak planks too and
we'll kind of get an idea of how long it
takes it to pass through all this so it
just does it oh let's not break that it
does as IG's I hear
so it's going to come back you see it
whizzing by now and then it goes down
there and it goes around the band comes
back and then it falls down to the the
bottom level because there's two levels
to this whole thing they should start
falling down here yeah looking good and
we got to make sure these items can get
through all this before they despawn so
if it takes longer than five minutes
that's not going to be so good we'll
have to like add something to refresh
the items if that happens but if we go
all the way down here this is the end of
it up there
yeah up there is the very end so this is
the Oakwood and I think this is the oak
planks here so if we give it just a
little bit of time it should finally
make it here might be able to see it
whiz by here even doo-doo-doo I think it
would be a belt now come on I hope it
doesn't get stuck anywhere this is gonna
be so cool when it's all done guys I'm
excited for it this was a big step if we
can get this to work they still haven't
made it though maybe I missed them maybe
they went by and I didn't see it let's
check nope hmm out there they are whoops
okay I forgot some enderchest here that
makes sense
aha good thing I checked so what we got
to do is put two ender chests here you
have to use two otherwise it doesn't
align it properly from what I could tell
okay now they should be able to make it
the rest of the way nope here they come
I so I tried it again here guys with
spruce wood and just want to make sure
can do the whole loop so those should
end up in the third spot if I remember
right goes oak birch spruce jungle yeah
look at that
oh it's so cool very cool so yeah
automatic sorting and storage is working
what we're going to have to start
getting into next is probably building
our command room over here because what
we got to do is attach to the water
stream at the top left there will want
like a chest in the command room where
we can basically just drop off stuff and
then it's going to put it into a dropper
and it's going to shoot it out at a
certain speed he'll go up an item
elevator and then to the water stream
there and it'll do the loop and then
anything that doesn't get sorted by the
system is going to shoot out the end of
there so we'll have to bring it back to
the command room here and store it in a
chest and that will be the junk that
that can't get sorted or that there's no
space left for and that way it doesn't
just go to waste you know uhm so yeah I
think that'll be pretty cool for the
command room here I'm a little bit
inspired to buy what I built in my
modded series that little command room
so I think we might go for like a grey
floor with white walls like same style
but difference like vanilla blocks
instead of modded blocks so we might use
courts for the walls and then cyan clay
for like the black parts and do
something sort of similar like really
high-tech looking build ooh and what
else did we have light blue so we might
use light blue as like a high light
thing to kind of those colors you hear
that
is that in the building I'm pretty sure
I put torches in all these very weird
it's like down oh I'm gonna get you oh
there goes all the sand aha look at this
what is this super tiny crack really
that's that's all there was
oh no oh it's terrible okay I'm making a
mess now
I gotta fill that in uh but anyways guys
we got a ton done a ton done a ton done
on the Nexus today I think we'll change
it up now and do work on a few other
things I don't have any said yes I do
good I was thinking let's do some work
on our sandy city here haven't worked on
in a little while yeah we're missing a
piece of carpet now over there oh well
so I was looking at this I thought it
would be cool if we maybe added a wall
around it because look at this we got
the sharp transition from sand to grass
I think that's always going to look bad
it's going to be really hard to smooth
that out but if we have a wall we could
have sand on one side and grass on the
other and it'll kind of create a
separation of the two and I think it is
so cool just have a wall around the city
so let's do it
let's see what we can do here I'm gonna
try build it out a sandstone primarily
gravity we need more we need more stairs
let's make a few more oh I have the
carpet on me I don't even see that cool
let's put that back okay so maybe where
should we start this let's start
yeah maybe let's plan to put a wall down
this line here okay
so doesn't necessarily need to be very
tall I like to work with odd numbers all
the time I could do pattern like this
and then three ah it's amazing let's
build it up one more and then maybe
we'll do the arch thing like we were
kind of planning on doing on the pyramid
so let's do like stairs that kind of
curve is that going to be might need to
go a little bit taller and we could do
like the castle wall thing like where
it's jagged kind of like that might be
cool yeah I like that
okay so let's fill this in and I would
like to make it so we can actually go on
the wall to not just like a one wide
thing that's kind of cool here I don't
like this sharp thing let's put a slab
between like that yeah so maybe let's
make it three wide so will will kind of
copy that on this side and then in
between we could here let's grab some
birch slabs because that's kind of what
I've been using here um and that's not
very materials were my materials I've
been building like all over our world
here so I got stuff like in so many
different locations I'll split up and
it's it's gone for good basically got to
do a bunch of farming again to get more
yeah this might be nice though do that
maybe in places we could set up like an
overhang above us and have some lighting
too but yeah maybe we'll just do this
first off I'll go around our city here
and then we could add points of interest
on the wall to like to have certain
sections that are a little bit different
just so it's not so so boring like all
this
same how's that aha so check it out guys
I've been working on this for a little
bit and I am pretty happy with what we
got here so far I think that looks
pretty cool right now I haven't put the
blocks in between like the filler I
don't know what to use um yeah I just
got it going up and around the village
here try to keep the shape of it as best
as I could did a little bit of
terraforming on the way we'll have to
clean it up a bit
like this should be sand we want sand on
this side of the wall and grass on the
other side where it's possible so I'm
trying to go down like the biome line
here so that we don't have brown grass
anywhere this is very close to the man
cave as well so we'll have to try
incorporate this into maybe this path
over here we could blend those two
together somehow would be amazing like
we could put a gate on the wall maybe
over here and then like redo this area a
little bit could be cool and I like the
view from up here you can sort of run
around the top of the wall you get a
little raised view of the whole area I
think is pretty cool and we'll probably
add like towers in the corners and a few
places to like with a floor above us
type of thing and you can have like a
watchtower I thought that was on fire
it's like I thought I saw a fire
underneath the leaf there that was the
sunset or the lava in the back there
that's what it was messing with my mind
but I'm probably done with this for
today I don't want to do it all in one
shot Earl I'll kill myself it's it's
pretty tedious to do it over and over
but pretty happy with what we got so far
alright everybody so this feels like a
good place to wrap up the episode I hope
you guys enjoyed it but as usual I did
pick out a comment for today this one
it's a little bit of a tough one I might
need your feedback on it I don't know
exactly what to do
so it says why is ESO uploading barely
any videos mm-hmm I know a lot of you
have probably noticed it I used to do
like five or six a week and now it's
more like four it's not good it's very
very bad um it's not because I'm on the
couch watching TV or anything like that
it's because I have a lot of series that
are huge time sinks and this is one of
them I know I can't just end this series
oh I that would not be a good idea I
don't think I need to maybe come up with
ways of spending less time per episode
though like today I've spent over twelve
hours on this episode and same with the
last one I spent over twelve hours on it
it's not it's not good turnover time um
and it doesn't necessarily make the
video more entertaining spending that
much time on it like most of that was
just collecting the items together to
put into the Nexus and and yeah spent
like four or five hours on that then I
built it a lot off camera and lots of
off camera stuff which isn't necessarily
good so currently I have four series I
have this one I have my modded series I
got hermit craft and Flyboys all four of
those are building series that take
quite a bit of time per episode to make
ah so what do I do I don't know like if
I just upload them less than people
aren't happy if I can them people aren't
happy it's a tough situation I'm not
sure the best course of action um yeah
but that's basically what's going on
I'll have to try figure something out
and maybe if you have ideas leave it in
the in the comments and hopefully
somehow I can get more episodes out I
think regardless I'm going to try to do
some more like custom map stuff maybe
maybe start another game and just see if
that helps because I can record that
stuff really quickly compared to what I
got currently and it might just help get
more videos out but yeah
it's an issue I know I'm trying to think
of what to do but anyways thank you guys
so much for your feedback on the last
episode the 420 even though it took a
long time to make it seems like a lot
you guys enjoyed it which made me happy
and you left a lot of nice support on it
and I appreciate it made me feel good
and I just will see you guys in the next
one here if you have any feedback on
anything else on any build decisions or
the Nexus plans please let me know as
well but until next time have a
wonderful day bye bye