hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series how're you doing I'm
doing great I'm doing wonderful
uh last episode guys we did the world
tour and my voice has recovered since
then it was an hour and a half long it
was really really challenging I'm not
used to making long episodes like that
we discovered some things have issues in
our world maybe this happened cause it
chunk unloaded is he gonna go nope
hello let's pretend that didn't happen
um he has an hour and a half long as a
little worried it was going to have that
too long didn't read mentality to it
like a lot of guys would just skip it
cuz you know it's way way too long of an
episode but mostly you guys seem to
enjoy it I didn't see any complaints
about the length so that's good I did
we're going to do a little bit of a
follow-up on that episode some of the
stuff I wanted to do but we just didn't
have time for and also got some stuff to
try here so one of the issues we had a
lot in our world tour
with our past projects is with these
hopper minecarts not picking up items
right and I do my very best guys to try
to keep up to date with this game
whenever a new patch comes out I go on
the reddit I look at the changelog
change log usually doesn't tell you
everything okay so you guys said the
reason these are not working is because
they added a tag to hopper minecarts
that say whether it's enabled or
disabled I'm guessing that has to do
with activator rails because when these
hopper minecarts are on activate the
rails you can enable or disable them
this is a feature not a lot of people
know about um so you said all I got to
do is break and replace it and that
fixes it but uh yes oh that's so awesome
because my tape spider farm was broken
that Golden Door was broken this was
broken couple other things that had
issues so I all I gotta do is replace
these pretty simple loop you see that
you see that empty minecart going around
the track that actually has the slime in
its this not drying him or rendering him
inside the minecart he's stuck here you
see how he's not moving this is that
glitch like when I moved to elder
Guardian how he went invisible in the
minecart so this isn't actually broken
it's just a rendering issue in the game
game thinks the slime is somewhere he
isn't but it should fix itself
once he D spawns kind of weird
nice wee awesome guys so we got those my
cards fixed now what I want to do is
update our world map here I notice
during the world tour I haven't done it
in quite some time it seems there's a
lot of things missing let's uh hmm where
should we start
where should we start okay so like sandy
city isn't on here at all this ice
mountain is gone
um break there we go
so now when we look at it it should
render in right all right well that's
one of them done right yeah you see how
that changed over here now we got the
pyramid instead of the Ice Mountain
thing yeah I think I actually have to go
go to the area to update it oh man I
might do a few of them but not not all
of them because that would take forever
that one updated pretty quick see the
mushrooms on the map that's the swamp
right there oh here goes here goes new
library showing up on the map
alright alright so admittedly that was
not quite as amazing as I had thought I
thought we could like break the map and
watch it update in real time and see it
change and it would be so cool but no I
forgot you actually have to go to the
area to God caused it to update and
usually you miss it when that happens so
anyways I did do a few of them like what
you got the pass over here now that's
the blacksmith house the little house by
the lake we got our pyramid Sandy City
is not as amazing as I had hoped like
you can barely even see the wall going
around it and the gates like these are
the gates here um those are the houses
they're brown apparently and the swamp
area looks kind of cool though and the
new gold farm we got the new library up
there so we can see a few changes but
like the village in the Nexus and all
that stuff is down lower the course
fruit farm all that stuff's down outside
of the range here for some reason when I
made this map stupid etho thought this
stuff up here was important I should
have like shifted it up to map places
and we could see a lot more of our world
ok so another thing I really wanted to
do during the world tour but we just
didn't have time for and I saw in the
comments as well you guys are like II
thought you should have done this is
look at our statistics it's been a while
since we've done this actually let's
look at achievements first the other day
I got an achievement I was like what
that when I made the snack o matic
machine because I had to make I take for
it and I got the the lie it's like whoa
there's still things I haven't done in
the achievement list here overpowered
eat a notch Apple that one's gonna be a
lot harder to do now umm so any that I
haven't done question marker was a lie
the last one have I done on a rail
travel by a minecart at least one
kilometer from where you started no it
does
and say taken so I haven't done that yet
apparently take and take and take and
I've done the beacon stuff
discover all biomes I haven't done that
oh man ah man trade diamonds with
another player can you do that in single
player is there any way to do that in
single player I don't know
oh snap or duals missing yeah there's
actually quite a few there I haven't
done all right now let's check out our
statistics guys see if there's anything
interesting here I'll try to go through
them pretty quick this page is usually
pretty interesting though it says games
quit 1100 minutes played 43 days what
does our date counter say let's check
that out
we're on day 7117 now guys that's like
oh man that's almost that's almost 20
years in Minecraft you yours right
that's that's quite a bit of time
alright ah statistics
yeah let's go back here distance walk
5300 I don't know if that's a lot seems
like I spend about half my or no third
of my time sprinting mm distance by mine
Kurtz don't use mine Kurtz all that much
anymore by boat that's going up quick
now that we got the ice roads actually
quite a bit of a horse travel 392
distance fallen there is one for Elijah
wings to one 178 that's going to
skyrocket soon guys
distance fallen 144 almost half a
million jumps 11,000 items dropped
almost half a million
yeah half a million there's a decimal
there it's like man as a huge number
half a million damaged delts two hundred
and sixteen thousand taken a hundred and
eighteen deaths that's a decent amount
right that's nothing too crazy though
mob kills 75,000 animals bred four
thousand zero player kills as you would
expect I don't do a lot of fishing and I
have gotten four treasures from fishing
so far
pretty pathetic talk to villagers three
and a half thousand times traded about
five thousand zero cake eaten one
cauldron filled interesting armor pieces
clean I guess that's when you remove the
die from leather with a cauldron same
with banners 400 interactions with
brewing stands I look in droppers and
hoppers quite a bit it seems three
thousand on just about both of them and
it's not much of a DJ with the note
blocks under chests open 1,100 items
enchanted only 59 that seems pretty low
doesn't it pretty low 1,400 crafting
table interactions that also seems low
to me I guess it probably doesn't count
when you look in your inventory though
right uh-huh
alright and we'll try to go through the
blocks you're pretty quick 345,000 stone
broken 106,000 dirts 70 mm sand I and
that's a lot of sand or is it all going
I don't even know
sandstone 20,000 wait what oh Sh rubs
that doesn't seem right
oh maybe that counts like just regular
grass has the wrong icon for it maybe
oh man 1800 obsidian how have I done
that much that's pretty brutal that's a
lot of time mining alright to anything
else do they have redstone on here just
the redstone dust I haven't seen it yet
kind of curious they got the blocks mmm
yeah I didn't see it there Oh purr purr
man 10,000 I've done a lot with purr
purr all right items just go through
here pretty quickly again I don't want
to spend forever on this 218,000 things
broken with my shovel 570 4000 with my
pick I think is what that was
yeah you guys in pause the video if you
want to look closer at this though what
what is this times used yeah and mobs
I've been blown up by seventeen creepers
lot Enderman Oh shocker I've killed four
of them never been killed by a shocker
two and a half thousand Guardians lots
of cows this is where my food comes from
uh huh well anyways those are statistics
guys I hope you found them interesting
and if not so well thank you for not
leaving the video let's let's move on
now let's get to the the main part of
our episode as you guys know my favorite
thing to do in this game is to come up
with ideas and then just see if I can
make those ideas happen
I love the whole design aspect of this
game I love coming up with new redstone
contraptions that sort of thing so today
that's exactly what we're doing we're
gonna try make a new redstone device
it's a technical challenge might not
necessarily be super practical for me
because I have two brewing systems
already but I really want to build this
thing so I'm going to you can't stop me
if you're playing on a server though
guys you might find this useful for your
nether hubs is where I think would be
most useful and I'll probably put in my
another up here too I am of course
talking about another brewing system
what do you guys think if I asked you to
build a brewing system that works in
another do you think you could do it do
you know how you would do it I've been
thinking about this for a little while
if it's really possible and I think I
have a pretty good idea of how to do it
now so here's the challenge of course if
you're in the nether and you place a
water buckets
it's gone so how do you fill up your
water bottles this has played everybody
that's tried to make another brewing
system it's impossible no it's not of
course as a lot of you know if you have
cauldrons in the nether you can fill
them with water
ah right so now if you have glass
bottles you can fill these from the
cauldron that's that's really cool right
seems pretty impractical etho why don't
you just build it in the overworld well
we're trying to a challenge right how do
you do it in the nether what's the best
way well there is one game mechanic
that's not super well known that we're
going to use as our main feature of this
brewing system all right so if you cart
water into the nether you can do it one
bucket at a time which we'll try to make
work with the system as well but you
also have another option a more
complicated option you could bring wet
sponges you those stack up to 64 so a
stack is wet sponges is like 64 water
budgets right did you know a lot of
people don't know this but if you if you
cook a sponge it dries it out but if you
also put an empty empty budget in the
bottom here watch what happens
dah dah
it fills it with water so we can get
water budgets in the nether now let's
build an automated system of doing this
okay guys so we're going to try to
figure this out together I haven't like
pre-designed this in creative or
anything I'm figuring this out with you
as we go and hopefully this is going to
work in the end of things I decided
let's build it in the overworld though
so we don't have to listen to the gas
the whole episode and because we got
better lighting more space figured it'd
be nicer so we have three main parts to
the project we got to figure out how to
get the water out of the sponges in a
nice way we got to figure out how to
fill up the water bottles and then we
got to make a brewing system which could
be anything you know there's lots of
different designs for those so we'll
focus on the first two parts mainly um
so fuel goes in from the side right yeah
so that goes there
can we put water can't put full water
buckets and we put empty ones yes that's
what I've thought okay good so those
instantly got pulled out
that's interesting because the planks
didn't do that right the fuel stays
inside but the budgets don't hmm what
happens we should test this actually
what happens when it fills up with water
can we can we make that happen we're
gonna have to power this hopper down
here and then let's just put that in for
right now when we unpowered this is it
going to pull the water bucket out
because it's not pulling the fuel out
okay it does take the water backed it
out that's really important otherwise
this ideas is busted right okay so we're
gonna have to keep this locked while the
empty bucket is in there but then pull
the full one out so unlock the hopper
once it fills it up ah-ha so check it
out guys I got an idea for a trick here
ah a furnace has three inventory spots
right so if one of them is full this
comparator outputs a redstone signal of
five distance right so up to five blocks
away if this one was full it would be
ten blocks if all three were full it
would be fifteen that this would output
a signal so there's a cool little trick
here if we if we if we do that and we
put our empty bucket in right now this
hopper is locked by the redstone here
right look what the comparator does goes
way out when it turns into a water
bucket which unlocks the hopper and
allows it to pass through so because
empty buckets only they stack up to
sixteen per stack water buckets only
stack up to one so they output a signal
way farther than empty buckets so that's
how we know when to pull the bucket
through oh man I think this is gonna be
a really cool machine
when it's all done guys so I got a
little carried away I started watching
some YouTube videos and I should include
you sooner but I'll just run you through
what we got here now so this is our wet
sponge to water bucket machine and it's
like fully automatic fits in a four by
four area I'm
really happy with it actually I'm really
happy with how this turned out so the
way this would work
you'd probably drop off a stack of wet
sponges in here let's just do four to
begin with though once you do that you
press a button and then it does its
thing here so what happens is this is a
dropper facing down into the furnace
that puts the wet sponge just one of
them in the inventory there and you see
what happened it put two sticks in and
then the empty bucket comes after that
once it turns into water but yet the
hopper has to unlock below to allow it
to pass through there's a lot going on
in such a little space honestly it's
pretty cool but yeah the the dry sponges
and the water budgets passed through
this hopper we got like a little item
filter thing here so wet budgets can't
go in this hopper only dry sponges and
then the wet yeah I say wet budgets I
guess they are wet but yeah the water
budgets they keep on going they fill up
this chest right so that's that's the
general concept of it on the side here
we have three three more droppers facing
into these hoppers so the ordering is
really important we can't just fill up
this furnace with fuel because if we do
that then we can't put the empty buckets
inside we need to just have exactly
enough fuel to do one operation and it
just so happens two sticks does that if
we were to use planks what would happen
is each plank can do one one-and-a-half
operations so eventually they'll get to
the point where it doesn't need to burn
a plank and then a plank will get stuck
in here and then the whole thing freezes
but with two sticks it's perfect so what
we do we have sticks in this one sticks
in that one since they're first in line
they go into the furnace first and then
at the back here is the empty buckets
alright so it does two sticks than an
empty bucket every time pretty simple
let's let's get this going again so you
just put that in pretty pretty cool
though it
stops once it's done with all the wet
sponges on its own there's no like
clocks or anything so here's the other
big thing when the what what I was going
to say wet budget again when the water
budget passes by this hopper
we got a comparator over here to detect
it so that lights up every time we get a
water budget passing through and that's
what activates these droppers over and
over and also the wet sponges up here
sends power to this block to this
dropper so it activates all four
droppers each operation and that's like
all there is to it uh-huh all right so
first part done second part now we got
to figure out how to fill up the water
bottles in a cool way
okay so I've been thinking about it here
I currently have two ideas of how to
fill up the water bottles we want this
to be as easy to use as possible as
quick and simple as possible but also we
do want the machine to be as simple to
build as possible to so of my two ideas
one of them is simple just the single
cauldron the other one is more
complicated involving a piston type
thing of cauldron so five at the minimum
and you would probably want more though
like maybe even up to 64 you could fit a
full stack of sponge water into your
cauldrons that way enough to do 192
potions without having to refill them
okay but here is the thing I just set up
like the spiral thing here so we press
the button here and see the cauldrons
switch places they're also got a
comparator detecting when we fill it up
a water so it should do it automatically
so let's let's try this out okay so you
would probably fill up all the cultures
with water at a time so you would fill
one what happened no wait oh I see it
sent power to this but I also sent power
back here we don't want that ah-ha I
think
power didn't go through to the other
side that's kind of weird right wait a
minute something very strange is
happening here let's do this and let's
change this to a repeater now what now
it works okay okay so every time we feel
a thing of water kind of switches places
so you could fill them all this way
every time you do it have it eject a
water bucket at you maybe the problem is
you do still get stuck with the empty
buckets right
they don't stack together it seems so
you would still have an inventory
nightmare you couldn't just hold right
click in any way that would be the dream
hmm and then you'd have to do the
reverse to so when you empty the
cauldrons you'd make it cycle then - oh
actually I just have another idea and
this would be the way to go if it works
but Mojang I don't know did you do it
did you make it work with dispensers I
would be very happy if you did water
about get in dispenser who doesn't
automatically fill a cauldron of course
not Mojang ah I I don't know man seems
like it should right should maybe it
matters which way you do it oh hello
there's nothing nothing below us
I was also recently disappointed like I
tried you know how you can light a
creeper on fire or ignite a creeper with
a flint and steel where they'll
automatically blow up I tried doing that
recently with a dispenser and it didn't
work like a flint and steel in a
dispenser and then you make it hit hit a
creeper it doesn't make the creeper blow
up like like you would think all right
yeah I think it just ejected it yeah
okay so you can't fill them okay so I'm
experimenting with two more ideas here
which are poo
this one got away from me a little bit
but the main concept I'll show you here
grab a water bucket let's get these out
of here too I want to try make a system
where you just hold right click and
press Q every time you get a new item so
watch what happens when you hold right
click on this cauldron trapdoor Goes
Down that stops you from pulling the
water back out of it all right because
you can do that if you hold right click
normally this is what happens - the
trapdoor so the idea is you can hold
right click doesn't pick the water up
again then you press Q throws item in
the hopper here it detects that it's an
empty bucket so the trapdoor goes back
up and then you would have it dispense
one empty bottle at you let's say
there's there's bottles in here hold
right you'd still be holding right click
now before you would drink the water you
would press Q to throw it that would
give you another bottle q Q and then you
would get a water budget but I got a
bottle there so it's not perfectly set
up yet you told right click oh it's
broken I don't know then you would have
to know it's broken right I don't know
oh now it's working hold right click
throw that it's not quite perfect at the
moment hold right click q q Q and then
ideally get a water budget here my big
concern with this idea though guys is it
might be a little bit slow like it took
a little while to fill up the water
bottles there and that's just because of
the redstone delay that I don't know if
I can make any shorter really it's also
going to be complicated to design and
build so difficult for me to design and
difficult for you guys to build so yeah
this is the other idea I had the second
idea which is a lot simpler it would
work something like this let's try it
out so you would get a water bottle
or a water budget from here to begin
with so from our sponge machine all the
water buckets will collect here and then
you would right click on the the
cauldron you can hold right clicked or
anything then you would right click
right click right click with a full
inventory those are going in here
they're getting sorted there's an item
filter here that collects empty buckets
so the empty buckets don't go in here
they go down and when it detects an
empty bucket going through it also sends
a redstone signal up here to the dropper
to give us another water bucket if there
is one so it repeats the process so
basically throw this in get water do
that right click right click right click
throw a bucket right click right click
right click throw budgets yeah it's not
quite as a user friendly like you got to
actually think a little bit right click
right click right-click right-click uh
at least didn't go down below yes I
don't know I don't know I got to think
about this so I decided I don't like
this one here guys honestly it's too
much for old details it's too
complicated even though it's simpler to
build you got to like right click
sometimes sometimes you got to press Q
sometimes you get to switch your
inventory spots there's a lot going on
just to fill up some water bottles right
it's too much too much ideally we want
to try to get as close as we can to how
you fill them in the overworld we just
hold right click at water fills them up
and if your inventory fills up they
start spraying out and you can pick them
up with a hopper that's like the dream
for our nether system I think I've
gotten about as close to that dream as
possible here though I decide to refine
this one makes it faster make it better
not quite as scary looking so here let's
go for a little test run okay so we got
our water in there empty bottles there
so what we would do to start off with
get our water our sponge water all right
and all we got to do is hold right click
and press Q every time we get a new item
in our inventory Kaew Kaew Kaew Kaew
Kaew Kaew Kaew so it's quite a bit
faster now right it's not too bad it's
not too bad it's not as fast as
overworld filling and I'm using that
empty water bucket at the N or empty
water bottle at the end there to tell it
to give me a water budget otherwise I
would have to count to three with the
water bottles here and that would
require much more complicated redstone
so I'm kind of doing a trick with it
yeah it's not too bad right and we got
water so it keep going until you either
stop or this runs out of water ball or
water buckets all right guys so I think
we pretty much got this designed we're
also very very much out of time for
today
so what we're going to do like we got
part one done I'm really happy with part
one part two might be able to improve it
a little bit more yet but what we would
do I should have mirrored this so that
the water the water buckets were on this
side then we could just connect it
directly to this chess pretty much and
build them side by side that's what I'm
going to do most likely the other thing
we got to do though is I'm using item
filters down here to detect when we the
change that needs to happen when we
switch from you know filling it with the
bucket and and when we're done with the
water bottles I signify we're done
filling with water bottles by throwing a
glass bottle in here so this detects
when we throw the glass bottle in this
is the text when we throw the empty
bucket in the problem is these just kind
of get stuck here at the moment so
ideally I would like these glass bottles
to go back up to our our dropper here
right get
back in there and then these empty
buckets we need to connect up to our
part one here they need to go back into
here and that kind of completes the
cycle and then the water bottles just
have to go into our brewing system okay
so here's the plan guys let me know if
this is a good plan or not I'm going to
try to refine that get it built for next
episode so we can check it out right
away
what I will do if you're interested I
might make a tutorial for it it's kind
of like I don't know though
like most people don't even want to
attempt to build a normal brewing system
and this is like another brewing system
all that part 1 and part 2 stuff is
extra complication so I don't know how
much interested they're actually how
much interest there actually is in this
build you'll have to let me know if you
found it if you think you would ever
build something like this in your world
or if you this thing is a stupid idea
either way I had a lot of fun making it
today I hope you enjoyed watching the
design process and that kind of stuff
anyways zip comment of the day says
should finish the villagers houses get
loads of them running around like an
army bot so good yes you know what
happens guys every time every time I get
like 20 or 30 villagers running around
here zombie siege zombie sieges happen
so often when you play on hard mode and
you see my local difficulty is that 6.38
if I stay here for like 30 minutes or
less probably all the villagers will die
I have to like constantly keep an eye
out for it and just recently I lost like
20 villagers so be very careful if
you're playing on hard and you have
villages as they happen pretty often
anyways guys thank you so much for your
comments on last episode and your
supporting everything again
very very good support from you guys
really appreciate it and hope you enjoy
today's episode as well until next time
thanks for watching bye bye