[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho
why am i talking like this
do you know the reason i know you're
thinking of the reason
you're thinking this because i have
implanted that thought
into your mind inception
yes so it seems
i think when this episode goes up i'm
going to be past
another major landmark with my youtube
channel which is incredible the 250 000
subscriber
landmark it's amazing it's awesome thank
you everybody who has supported me for
so long
i'll talk more about that though at the
end of the episode
the weird intro just kind of segues
to something i was going to talk about
usually
when i hit one of these landmarks i will
sort of devote an episode to talking
about
maybe like the behind the scenes stuff
towards my youtube channel
maybe a little less specific about the
game and more
more about the channel and
i thought you guys might find this
interesting but
back i think it's like between episode
10 or 20. i made a very specific
decision
um that i was not going to
develop a catchphrase intro
i don't know if you guys ever noticed
that but a lot of youtubers
they have a catchphrase something they
say every time
they make a video which is
i'm curious to see like i want your
response on this
i'm curious if you guys prefer that more
or not because
i decided i wasn't going to do that
right off
early in my series because i thought it
would limit
the creativity or limit what i could do
at the beginning of my episode so i
always
try to avoid that even and even when
um like a lot of people want me to do
the
get your snacks intro like and when i
wouldn't do it people
seemed almost upset but i really didn't
want that to develop into
my regular intro so i avoided it
what do you guys think is it better to
have
a specific intro or not in case you
couldn't tell we're going with the
winter theme
that was the popular choice with
industrial being a close
second i also saw on the
reddit the minecraft reddit somebody
made a jungle theme
and took a picture of it it looked
really cool but the thing about that
is i really don't like the texture for
jungle wood it's got that
do i have any here maybe i can show it
it looks like puke in my opinion
um which is too bad because i
always thought like mossy wood would
look awesome in this game
yeah here it is it's i don't know the
brown
in it is really gross looking and then
you got the pukey green
lines in it it's just
it's not my favorite block that's for
sure
it can look good if it's set up right
but even still i don't think i'd want to
look at it
all the time so
not doing the jungle theme um not doing
the industrial theme it's
it's a good idea what i have planned to
build on the s
on the minecraft is going to be sort of
industrial so
we will do we will use it to an extent
there
anyway so may as well do the snow theme
here
and people said i've used the wood theme
enough i should try something different
for the challenge
and even though i'm scared to i think
that's what we should do as well so
we're doing the snow
theme i got this
uh octagon highlighted with this circle
now
we're going to try that instead see how
it looks
and i thought i would tell
the story of how i got into this game
today it's some
it's something i've said before i think
a long time ago but i'm sure
most people haven't heard the story um
i was trying to figure out exactly when
it was i was looking at some of the
patch notes today and when
other famous minecrafters started their
let's plays in that and i think it was
either the middle of july or beginning
of august that i started
as far as i can tell i don't remember
the exact date
basically i was watching youtube and
a minecraft video was suggested
and i was watching it was of these three
guys going around
creative servers
like the old creative not the creative
we have now
and just exploring the things people
made and
i don't know it looked interesting to me
so i thought i would check it out myself
and i played creative for a while
um i had some fun with it
i like checking out what other people
built in that
then i started to try build things
myself and everything i built
quickly got griefed that was very
common back then actually one of the
first things i saw
is you know that video of
the earth someone made the earth in
minecraft a long long time ago
the video has like over 8 million views
now that that was one of the first
things i saw in minecraft i
was just joining random servers and i
came across that
so that was cool to see kind of got me
even more interested in the game that
you could do things like that
um but yeah people kept briefing my
stuff
got bored of the whole building aspect
of the game and was about to move on
then i heard about the survival mode
that just came out
or that was new and that sounded really
interesting to me i especially like that
you could play it in single player
because
before that everything was multiplayer
pretty much
but you had to pay for the game so
what i did is i looked for a bunch of
videos
or tried to find videos on youtube
showing
this new survival mode how it works and
all that
and i came across oh what's going on
here did i do this wrong
i came across this lp this guy just
started and it was the worst
video like the worst thing i could have
found to explain the game
um i always wondered why i didn't like
see
nanners first or x's adventures or
paul source or one of those guys and uh
i checked it out today and apparently
they didn't start their s
or x and who else did i check today
cnners x and c niners they didn't start
till about august
their series so i guess it wasn't out
when i started
um but so instead i
i saw a very terrible let's play
couldn't figure out anything from it the
guy spent the whole
video inside a cave he wouldn't go
outside he wouldn't
look at anything and
i figured the only way i was going to
learn about the game is if i
got it for myself so i i broke down and
i thought hey i'll just
spend the 10 bucks whatever um probably
the best decision best game i've ever
bought in
for the money that's for sure um
had a lot of fun with it played it for
months
and then did we do this all
that's it people are suggesting i should
try birch instead of the dark wood for
the stairs
again with this winter theme a lot of
stuff is going to have to
wait until 1.3 um
but yeah i played it for for a few
months i got into playing snp
just going on public servers um
had fun with that got to the point where
i was getting bored of the game though
um then
i started getting into the technical
stuff in minecraft like
used redstone for my first time um the
way i actually got into youtube
i was i had this idea that i wanted to
make a boat dispenser
in my world because my boats kept
washing out into the ocean in the game
and i wanted something to hold them
in place until i used them so i did a
long
search on youtube for a video or
tutorial showing how i could make
something like that
and after like three or four hours of
looking i just
couldn't find anything so i thought i
would try
just make it myself use redstone for the
first time and
and stuff like that and it turns out
i was on to something good there because
i posted
my final version of it on the minecraft
forms and i
got an amazing response from people like
i wasn't expecting anything
but like thousands of people viewed the
video
and left great comments on on the topic
i made
and yeah that's that's that was my start
and then i kept making videos beyond
that like people
suggested ways i could improve it and i
thought of a few different ways so i
made
version two and some people
on the forum topic wanted to see
my world so i posted a video of that
and then when i was watching my boat
dispenser video i
noticed there was like when i rode my
boat into lava
there was this glitch where it
duplicated
the amount of wood i got back and from
that i made the wood dispenser videos um
and yeah i just made a bunch of little
videos
and kept doing that with any idea i
could come up with
then got to the point where i had about
a thousand
subscribers already and i really wanted
to
get into making let's plays because i
was watching people like co-star
and uh even before minecraft i was
watching azeroth blade and other people
i liked the idea of a let's play and i
thought it would be cool if i could get
into making one
myself and went and bought a mic
and recorded my first episode
yeah there's going to be a lot of
tweaking and playing around with
different types of blocks until i get my
style figured out here
we got to choose between a
b
c
or
d or e none of the above
and also the plan with this part was to
make it ice when we can
we can't do that though until 1.3 comes
out
when we can pick up ice with silk touch
again
so i think in the meantime what i'll do
is just change it to grass so it looks
better
until we actually make the change um
and who knows we might become attached
to the grass or
we will switch it to ice when we can
um with changing this to a circle
instead of the octagon
it seems to be okay up here like the
only place it really got narrower
is at these parts here and
it it still seems wide enough as i go by
here
the thing i was worried about is these
fronts being too
too narrow if we made a circle but it's
it's about the same
even with it so that's good
um so i'll switch this out and then we
will
work on our main project for the day
all right guys so we got the grass
spreading here um
we're going to move on to the main
project i wanted to do today
the thing i missed the most about the
old world was that five minute
timer thing i had that would play the
zelda tune
if you guys aren't familiar with it
basically it's
it was a timer that would tell me when
uh the item drops would start despawning
and it would play an audio tune
zelda tune that would tell me it's time
to pick them up
otherwise they're i'm going to start
losing them type thing
the way i did it before we're going to
have to figure this out
i had two pressure plates and a
dispenser
like we'll just set it up like this
basically
when the mobs would land on the pressure
plates or when their loot would it would
go down
that would trigger this telling it to
shoot out one so
it would also be on and then when i
would go pick up
the stuff i would grab it off of both of
them
and that would reset the thing
it would cause this to shoot again and
also
it would play the tune when i did that
or
the other thing that would happen if
there was loot on this one
and this one despawned after the five
minute timer
that was on and that was off then it
would also play the tune
and tell me it's time to pick this up so
that's what we're going to try mimic the
thing i
don't want though like with this setup
uh we only got one block here right so
we can't do it
like we had before because before we had
two pressure plates side by side
and when you grab it you would get both
i want to try hook this up so it works
on one
and we got to figure out how to do that
so basically one
visible one we'll have we'll still need
the two but one of them will be hidden
underground
out of sight out of mind um
so i'm going to play with the redstone a
little bit and see if we can figure this
out
so before we do the redstone we should
really figure out
the logic behind this thing what we want
it to do exactly
and then we'll figure out the and gates
and how that all needs to be set up
so i got a indicator light here when
there's something on this pressure plate
turned on we can pick it up from over
here
while we test it uh
i think what we want for sure if
if a mob drop falls on
the pressure plate that would be the one
we're going to put over here
uh the pressure plate over here is going
to be hidden underground
this one but this is the one the stuff
will fall on
i think when that goes down we always
want it to shoot
the five minute timer and get that going
if an item another item falls like if
another mob falls down
while this is on here doesn't matter it
doesn't press it again
if we pick up the items before the five
minutes are
up
that goes up and we can
like mobs can fall on it again and that
will
shoot out another item and it resets the
five minute timer anyway
so it keeps working
let's see i think this is simpler than i
thought it was going to be
if yeah so
if there's items on that if that
pressure plate is down and this one
go it was down but goes up i think
that's what we want to trigger the tune
uh
like the way i had it before i think i
also had to play the tune when i picked
up the items
the question is if we wanted to do that
or not if we do we need to do something
else as well
otherwise it's really simple
okay here's what we'll do we'll just
make a very
simple and gate here to see what happens
if we
have that there um
oh wait actually no run that over to
here
there i made a note block put that next
to it
so right now it's off
so this is going to check if if one is
doing something another is doing
something
if if it's going to let power through
okay so it played once an item landed on
there that's not good
um if we pick it up
it doesn't play we don't want it to when
we pick it up
well we might i'm not sure if we should
okay that's shooting those if we pick
this up
then it plays that's what we want when
we pick that up
and if there's nothing on both right
so this is pretty much all we need
actually
we just need to figure out how to get
rid of that initial
play and i think it's because we have a
delay that it's doing that
let us
just change this real quick
um we'll put the torch
above here i guess
we'll have to move that this is really
sloppy i know
it's okay as long as it does what it's
supposed to so now
now they have the same delay let's see
if it'll play it
on the startup
it does hmm
did i change something here
oh
wait a minute i think it's because this
is inverted now
okay well if we do this
this is falling apart now
do that
this is why we do redstone off camera
okay
pick this up it shouldn't play
good and if we pick this up
it should now right so we're just going
to figure out how to get rid of the
startup tune
and oh that's what it is it's the delay
from this shooting out and landing on
the pressure plates
that's causing it so if we delay this
one
that should fix it
yep so all i did is i added a delay
before
the and gate here and that seems to do
the trick
it gives the five minute timer enough
time for the item to fall down to the
pressure plates
so let's check it out mob loot falls on
there
didn't hear this go off like we did
before
and if we pick this up
we hear the sound so after the five
minutes and
loot starts despawning it gives us our
warning signal
through the note block to come pick
stuff up
um
and it won't play sound if we pick that
up and
let's see what other conditions would
there be
yeah well i guess that's it so if we
wanted it to play sound
when we picked up the items like every
time we do all we would need to do
is also connect this pressure plate
directly to
our noteblock sequence that way
inverted uh connect it inverted so that
when the pressure plate goes up
it will go through the note blocks um
so i'm not sure if i want to play it
every time i think i'll just keep it to
uh the five minute d spawn that it would
play
all right very good very good so we know
how to build it now
this is going to be hidden underneath
these emp units out of sight
i guess where stuff drops i'm going to
put a lamp
and the pressure plate above that so
it'll light up when there's
loot on it
yeah i think i'll wait though maybe a
little bit we got to wire up the emp
units is what we got to do first
uh how do i get down
over here because there's not a lot of
space around
underneath them i'll have to be pretty
compact the way i do it so i may either
have to
um i'll know when i do the emp units but
i i suspect i'm going to have to put
the dispenser in that a little ways away
from
from where they are and i'm only going
to hook it up to
the general mob dropper not the
the ones i plan on sorting so just this
main one
this main tube over here
and also what i would like to do because
in my old one i had
lights that would blink when it was time
to harvest the stuff
it would be cool to maybe have lamps
around my place here every
like maybe just a few around the area so
if i miss the
audio chime the zelda tune i can
have a visual indicator as well that i
need to pick up the stuff
like if i'm out of the area out of the
range of the noteblocks
that's that could be useful um
that guy's been there this whole episode
i think
but anyway let's go take a trip
uh yeah 250
000 subscribers that is awesome um
thank you everybody very much i love
what i'm doing here
why can't i find my way down ever i was
right there
no over there
yeah thank you very much everybody for
your support i really enjoy what i do
with this minecraft stuff and that i
started doing this back
in november 12th was my first video i
checked that today
so it's just a little over a year and a
half i've been doing this
and i still find it very very fun this
is
the ideal job
i guess you could call it uh
i kind of view it as almost like playing
like having fun uh so it's awesome i get
paid doing this and
and enjoy it very much and i love the
social interaction that comes with it
through like talking to the mind
crackers and also
through the viewers like last episode
for example
i was blown away at guts
just about eight thousand comments on it
that's that's a lot of feedback
so that's really cool
and like five thousand likes or so
dang it
so yeah it's cool getting feedback from
people and and reading what they have to
say i really enjoy that
and i do make an effort of reading as
many comments as
i can cannot reply to very many
unfortunately
i miss youtube used to have this feature
where
uh the person that uploaded the video
they had like a special
area in the comments where their most
recent
the uploader's most recent comment was
always displayed no matter
whoever like there wasn't i don't think
there was up voting back then
but the uploader was guaranteed one slot
in the comments and i liked that because
when i said something people could
actually see it now
if i reply to somebody it just gets
washed away
and most people don't see it
but i do i do read the comments and i
i'll reply every so often
uh regardless um
what else is it gonna say i looked at
socialblade today and i was
pretty pretty impressed with the stats
as well
for the channel i'm averaging over a
thousand subs now
per day and about 250 000 views which is
incredible considering i only upload
like one video a day
and maybe even a little less this look
at this
this is blowing my mind
there's two
there's two of them he cloned himself
i don't know how he did it how did you
do it
can someone explain this i cannot
explain it the only thing i can think of
is he cloned himself
because there was no way for any other
villagers to get in here
and even if they could somehow walk
through the walls
there's no doors anywhere in this world
like around here so they
there's no way they could breed
it's very weird um
but not just myself uh good somebody
pointed this out good hit 90
000 subscribers today so congratulations
to him
and also kurt j mack hit 75k
uh around the same time as us
and even more importantly he reached his
100 percent
goal for his child's play
uh charity fundraiser so
congratulations to him and props to what
he's doing and
especially to everybody that contributed
and helped him out with that as well
now here's something i wanted to talk
about
today's itaki it really is i'm sorry
um just been wandering around here uh
but something else i wanted to talk
about
is some of you noticed the 250
000 subscriber special world
i have in my my folder
um i still haven't put him in
he's fine he's just wandering around
there uh i have been working on a
special
but i'm not forcing it like
i the last major special i did was a 75k
and the one before that was the 50k
do you think i can remember the buttons
i do awesome
really need ice to fix this but
um
yeah what happened with the 75k is i
ended up spending
hello uh
ended up spending like four or five days
straight where i wasn't uploading
anything and just working straight on
that because i wanted to be the next
video i uploaded and uh
it had mixed success like people not
everybody liked it and they were like
they were unhappy with the video to an
extent they would have preferred i just
tipped my regular upload schedule so
that's what i'm trying to do
with this one i'll work it on it as i
have time
and hopefully get it done sometime soon
but i do have something kinda special
planned today
uh there is believe it or not
a lost episode in my
in my series that you guys have never
seen
and i'm going to show it to you today
and it's very relevant to what we've
been doing
[Music]
yeah um
i think it's around the episode 10 or 12
or between 10 and 20 as well where i did
this
i recorded about a 10 minute clip and
well 30 minute clip and i fast forwarded
three times the speed
and i was going to do voiceover
commentary on it but i never
i was still new to editing and that and
i didn't know how to make it work
so you guys never saw this footage
i've kept it ever since like it's over a
year old
and uh i thought i'd show it today
as is so if it's something that
interests you feel free to watch it
it's there's not going to be any voice
in it it's just
showing me build the old storage room so
it should bring up feelings of nostalgia
especially if you
if you watched my original videos
so that's it for today guys thank you
for watching
i'll see you again next time and thank
you for your continued supports
yep
ah
[Music]
[Applause]
ah
church
[Applause]
um
[Music]
uh
yes
[Music]
um
[Applause]
bye
foreign
[Music]
[Applause]
um
[Music]
[Applause]
foreign
[Music]
um