oh dang I did look however fine um hello
everybody this is etho you're once again
in the end here do you go back nothing
you went back you got bored yeah we're
in the end I'm still working on the
renovations to this as Enderman farm the
ender ender oh man come on I'll be
Rebecca I'm so sorry about that guys if
but it was important it was very urgent
I had to get that call it seems I am a
preferred WestJet customer and I am
entitled to a special gift that's right
today is a good day
but anyway I'm up high here because I'm
planning things out I have to build oh I
don't have to I want to build I can do
anything I want this is my game I want
to build an enchantment station I want
to build some kind of food farm we need
a road to get to our ender ender here
something better than this obsidian path
and also place for a handle and
enchantment or not not champion what we
do need a chairman but I meant to say
ender chest so we're going to have to
have a station somewhere I'm trying to
decide if I want it down low there or up
high here because up high at this height
is where the portal to leave the end is
that so we could make a road that goes
all the way from the portal to some kind
of platform up here or another option is
to make a road from the entry point in
the end all the way to a platform
somewhere down there I don't know what
I'm going to do something else I got to
do yet is set up a killing area
over there probably what whatever we
build though we got to build it 32
blocks away from their platform there
because otherwise we'll be able to
teleport to me and we'll have that
problem again grab some of these just
want to try something here real quick I
did mess around with each road a little
bit after our last episode and I think I
got a very very basic but very practical
Oh what the heck was that
ah okay I'll be right back oh I got some
bad news some really bad news I've
updated I am using the 42 B snapshot
this is my first time hearing it the
bats they make this most annoying noise
constantly are you kidding me I can't
live like this
I have bats down here constantly like at
all that's going to be so annoying
they're everywhere
and okay actually know what there's
something else I've wanted to try - lets
go - you can send items through nether
portals now I can you send them through
end portals this is one thing I wasn't
really sure about so I'm going to throw
a slime ball down here oh I guess we'll
have to look really close that we don't
pick it up as we drop down here which
could happen hmm hmm not the best test
yeah you know what I should do fill up
my inventory so I can't pick something
up as I jump down into the portal I
think you did go through but I'm going
to try that again later okay so I I just
want to try set something up with the
fences here and see if they will kill me
or not build out just a little bit's
yeah we'll do this that's then we'll put
oh you're not allowed here I told you
try this out now do you think they'll
teleport in with me they probably will
yeah they definitely will but we'll try
it anyway
as also curiously if I'd be able
sorry
oh that doesn't go down when you turn
down either you have to do it at the
start I'm also curious if just a sec for
safety of my items I'm going to while
that might affect things I may return
attracts I'm just going to be ready
wait how'd you get me
how did you hit me man um oh oh yeah
they can definitely reach Jay so we'll
have to make this go out at least one
more and we might set up like or just
put water floating water above us so
they can't teleports into the box with
us seems I can't pick up the XP through
it though which is good oh maybe not
well what we could do is just put in
another or a regular fence in here and I
should be able to fit through the crack
when I pick too many
ah it's so scary I should make it back
up before it I don't want to lose my
items so far seems okay it's gotta be
really careful not to get close to him
yeah I'm going to make a backup and I'm
going to experiment with the food
experiment with it a little bit and see
if they ever teleport in with me or if
I'm too close to allow them to do that
well it seems yes they were able to
teleport in with me and give me lots of
hugs so some sort of ceiling was needed
and I came up with this started making a
tunnel which will go up to this killing
area it's two-and-a-half high so they
can't teleport in with me as I stand
here and it works pretty good
the fence isn't there anymore I didn't
like the fence because xb going to get
to you and you can't just walk out
whenever you choose so yeah this tunnel
goes 32 blocks just out a teleport range
so it's two and a half blocks high in
here it's all made of glass so they
can't spawn well they won't have enough
space to anyway can't come in here
they tend to on top we have to put water
above prevent that I tried making this
with ice I thought it would look cool it
looked okay but it was way too blue you
couldn't really see through it like you
can with a glass so I switch to glass
looks really white which I don't really
like either I'm kind of hoping Mojang
will eventually update the the glass Tex
texture to make it more visible get rid
of the streaks maybe or introduce alpha
transparency somehow um yeah we got to
put water on top let's do an enchantment
before we die I don't get
so I brought a whole bunch of ice here
let's get to it
okay well I'm on top of the tunnel here
I'm trying to set it up in such a way
that there won't be any flowing water if
possible which might not be possible
I'm not sure for some reason I think it
can be done but I'm probably really
wrong on next all right so I filled in
all this stuff with there was a error
where the soil is so I have to remove
that eventually but I think the first
step is to go along the top fill it in
solid because we want water everywhere
the goal is to make it so that won't be
flowing over the sides which is a tough
part Oh you's a real guy oh oh he's real
- this is all the real guys up here man
well good I think we're good okay
oh that's all for the ice I don't like
to have a need he just fell through the
block don't like having these guys all
around me I think I brought some more
yeah
okay we'll probably need more of this oh
you jerk I hate when they do that ah
I've a fk'd before come back and then
you have this Enderman just mad at you
step standing in front because they
happen to walk right in front of where
you were you had your cursor pointing
and then when they do that they just
freeze and are angry okay it's a look oh
yeah so there's going to be a two man
going to be a tube that goes up to the
platform above I think over there inside
I'm going to build the platform up a
higher
where the eats roads going to be okay so
this is all solid um maybe we'll put
some more over there so first up I got
to break everything above its soil I
think oops just dripped out like that
for now okay have to do this in the
right order or it won't work
okay and then I got to remove the soil
and place I swear it is so I'll do that
off camera then I'll break it all
okay maybe before we do the whole thing
out I'm just going to try it out see if
it works or not so I put dirt all along
here this will probably prevent the
water from flowing to the left it will
flow to the right because there is a the
drop one block drop here which is closer
so nope that didn't work
that's what if we make it wider
nope can't be done because the water is
there okay let's try this set we'll get
rid of this water we just placed we will
have the flowing water sound
unfortunately okay I never did place any
at the bottom I don't think I need to
add a fill to the rights and then we can
remove this okay well I guess that's
what we'll do
it's going to get so far but I have come
across a little bit of a challenge up
ahead here I'm always worried I'm going
to look at one of these guys I'm not
really like they'll does knocked me off
I'm not in a good spot Wow
yeah so the challenge is this corner
right here if I try to break or even if
like even if I extend this out
the water is still going to flow over
this way because like we saw before we
have water blocks here so I don't know
if how I can fix this I definitely have
to get rid of those so now the water has
to travel two blocks to get down so we
need to make this go out more than two
blocks so it doesn't flow this way it's
like a little puzzle man
so it'll feel like that hi I think
though when I break this one it's going
to create a source block here and then
it's going to flow this way oh good it
didn't that simplifies it a lot oh why
to do it on that one and not the other
one
dang it
I'll have to watch it I wonder what was
different about that yeah basically it's
it's creating a water block here so this
this water won't flow that way and it's
it goes over here it's now I'm going to
try melt it so that doesn't cause an
update and see if if that'll work
yep that works so we were able to cover
the whole roof with water without it
spilling over which is pretty cool ah
had a few drops I had to redo a few
things but I did get it to work and
pretty cool so next up oh dang this
shovel oh good we got four I love it
when you get four when you accidentally
break it although you know what I should
probably change this up so it looks a
little different - oh well some other
time
so I would like to know that's a real
guy these guys got some pretty good
reach to them so yeah maybe we'll start
working on the platform above and the
eat throat I kind of like I really want
to work on the eats Road today so I'm
gonna pick up the pace here yeah you
know what I decided just to go ahead and
start working on eats roads so that's
what I'm going to do I'm not going to be
able to get it centered with this I
don't think because this is an even
number and I need an odd number for the
road design I'm using and like stuff
like the enchantments room will probably
end up being an odd number too
because that's just the way it is so our
platform up here is probably going to be
odd number based but I think this is
where I'm going to Center it so we're at
Y 65 that's the height of my portal to
get out of the end and I have it all
written down I'm looking for my notes
here yeah the portals at Zed negative 9
and X 73 so it's about 200 blocks away
from here the entry is at Z 0 so right
here so yeah I think right here will be
the middle of the etes road so we'll go
I'm going to use glass for the bottom of
it and it's going to be three wide oh
man I was using my pinky like a fool you
got to use your ring finger just about
let go there yeah I'm going to run glass
three wide all the way up to our portal
and we'll probably have to go get some
more glass very very soon here oh man we
got we got glass going all the way down
now it's a long road the next part of
this is going to be putting on our walls
so we're going to have wall in the
middle wall on the sides and another one
on this side okay I decide these fences
they work pretty good I was going to use
cobblestone walls but they aren't quite
as visible so they're pretty much solid
so fences work pretty good see I got to
run all three of these all the way down
and then I'll be back again
ah very good very very good the next
thing is the cap in the middle we need
that hold the boat down I'm going to use
I think I'm going to use the light wood
half slabs and then we'll use the
regular ones and let's see where I want
to start this that's the middle of the
portal should really get rid of this I
guess we'll start here so I think I'm
going to do it like this I'm going to
have one layer then three then another
one then three and do that all the way
down just so that there's a little bit
of variation as you're going down here
otherwise you can't really see how quick
you're going if you don't have some sort
of marking that you can follow with your
eyes so that's why I want it just a
little bit different but yeah we should
be just about done here so I'll go all
the way down alright so I got that done
now I'm going all along here and placing
signs at all these the darker ones and
these are just to hold the water in
place so that's it will flow correctly
you can use pressure plates or anything
else you can if you're if you've got a
thicker road like if it's too deep you
can just dig a hole and the water will
flow that way you don't even need to use
a block to hold it then um yeah I'm
gonna use signs and you know I really
haven't messed with eats Road in a long
long time
not even like off-camera or anything
just haven't touched it I do really like
eats road I always have but it's always
always gets broken it seems by the
patches or and then you got to fix it
and tamper with it
but it is really cool to have still
minecarts are better in my opinion a lot
of people always wonder which is quicker
they're actually the same speed I'm
pretty sure still eight blocks per
second is max speed for mine carts and
for each road but you know it's cool to
have variety in your worlds in Minecraft
so that's why when I have an eats Road
here just to change things up a little
bit and a big question a lot of people
have is what does tes stand for what is
eats Road it's it's a a boat road system
I came up with a long time ago
it stands for ethos advanced
transportation system even before I
started my let's play I think is when I
came up with it and is it's basically
just a trick with boats that if it's
being held down by a block when it's in
water and it's trying to float up it
will move quicker for some reason and
they'll move on its own so you can
actually make tracks for the boat which
is pretty cool and then you can set up
loading stations and and departures and
boat collection systems and all the
other fun stuff you might do with the
minecart station so man that's one short
that sucks that one one short I don't
have any more wood Oh
but anyway enough rambling now the next
step mmm I'm really nervous around here
being out in the open with Enderman
around I'm going to look the wrong way
it's happened a few times already next
step will be the water probably don't
need that much um of course where I live
actually eats Road first was inspired by
modern roads and the way I had it set up
you drive on the right side of the road
so that's how I'm going to set this up
so when this is broken it will go this
way and the other one will go the
opposite way so I'm going to put ice all
the way down and I'll get back to you
whoo-hoo excellent so there's still one
more thing I want to do with it but I
need to get back so let's go for our
first test drive qu yes I'm Steve the
skin servers are down faster we move in
I want to check this I'm going to check
this to make sure it's still a blocks
per second to I'll use as a reference
but yeah eats Road very cool all right
I'm going to do that one last thing and
then we will check it out one more time
the last thing I did with it is I put
these glowstone down every every section
so just to give it some more color
because the end is very dark and very
bland so we want as much color as we can
get whoo-hoo I did check it out it's
seven blocks per second exactly which
might be what mine carts are I would
have to check I'm not sure the a seven
blocks exactly just cool and I think I
found out trickier
well not found out it's an old trick but
I didn't know you could double jump
doing this or at least I think I'm
double jumping we'll see if we can
replicate it here so if I hold forward I
automatically jump on my own this is
something out there real this is
something I've done before but I've
never
we'll jump before going in yeah it is a
double jump check it out
that is awesome I can't get up on top
though I've tried but it is definitely a
double jump only in Minecraft and a lot
of other games okay cool
one last thing to do before we read the
comments that entity's going through the
end portal I want to do that properly
proper test so I'm going to fill up my
inventory oh the way I'm going to do it
this time I'm going to throw a blazer
out in okay and I'm going to fill my
inventory all the slots I won't pick it
up and if it went through we should see
it's on the city and pad okay it does
work cool so you can send items through
the end as well all right all right I
got two comments for today first one is
oh hey etho I was wondering regarding
the new 1.4 anvils are you going to make
a special room dedicate to all the
things you can do with anvils or will
you hide them in random places like you
did with your work benches I personally
think you should make a room and
whenever an anvil was destroyed because
of overuse you could make a piston belt
that replaces it or something I just
thought that would be really cool
addition to your world and it will give
you something to do with your redstone
yeah you know what I'll probably have a
few animals around the world some of
them might just be on their own but I
might also make anvil dispensers at some
point too but I haven't really used
anvils yet because and I think they're
still working on them quite a bit so
maybe 11.4 comes out all you some more
second comment it bugs me so
so much that the beacon is off-center oh
it bugs me so much when people say that
because I've said many times that I need
three more beacons and then they will be
centered perfectly fine this wait I'll
get three more they'll be centered look
fine okay thanks for watching