[Music]
hello everybody this is ESO and welcome
back to the let's play series alright so
the goal here is to get through that
yeats that one right over there without
really looking at us going through it
you know what I mean we got to be in
this camera view where we can't see
anything really I missed and we got to
fly through that thing that's my life's
ambition right now don't ask me why it's
just something I want to do come on I
hit the top of it
how's our health oh we're almost dead
uh-huh
no one said it would be easy one last
try come on yeah I kind of wanted to
keep flying but I'm going to count that
as a win okay I think we're good so
today we're going to answer one of
life's greatest questions guys how did I
make the llamas walk around Sandy City
like that no actually that's a secret
what we're going to do instead a little
experiment here I want to see what
happens if how do we position this I
think we wanted to dispenser and
observer facing the other way like that
right and then observer this way and the
dispenser two dispensers two buckets of
water two observers so what happens if
we activate the observer is it going to
just activate them once I think it's
going to add it like create a clock like
they'll they'll pulse constantly all
right let's find out I'm just curious
that's pretty cool yeah so it seems
water streams with observer blocks are a
little bit weird
they don't work quite like I expected so
you see it triggers twice
it always triggers twice that time I
triggered three times I think
but yeah so when the water stream gets
updated like when this water flows to
like where this observers it updates
once and then when it flows down it
updates again at this block so you can
see check this out light if I open the
chest next to the water stream that
causes the observer to update because it
updates the water which and updates
observer I think open and close yeah huh
okay this is unrelated to what we were
just doing but I have a question
maybe maybe somebody out there knows
what's going on when you load up the
game in the minecraft Launcher it says
loaded like 488 advancements and then
later it keeps saying loaded for 344
does anyone know what that's that's
talking about because if you look at the
advancements there's like only 50 listed
here right so where are the other 300
coming from or what's it loading
constantly curious just wondering we're
going to do something here I got a
stupid little project in mind it's going
to require 40 dispensers so what better
opportunity to try out the new crafting
system here then making dispensers
dispensers if you don't know are the
absolute worst thing to craft in the
game so we want to try this out so we
still gotta like throw them that's fine
I expected that all right throw that I
think we still got to do it one by one
all right
I'm going to grab some cobblestone
boo-boo-boo-boo then we'll start picking
up the bows so I think we can go on here
like I've actually contemplated making a
machine to make crafting dispensers
easier because they're just such a pain
there's a worst oh we need redstone
that's what's missing so what's going on
okay let's try this notes dispensers so
yeah you got to do it one by one it
looks like oh no I messed up normally
the way I would do it is I would press Q
then the number key Q number key and I
think that's actually faster still all
right very cool very cool so we're also
going to need a few blaze rods for our
build here and you might be thinking
etho what could possibly require blaze
rods why would you need blaze rods for a
bill I'm gonna give you one guess all
right make your guess what's your guess
you said brewing stands you're wrong we
do not need them for brew these desks we
need them for something else you ready
for this we're making fire charges aha
new recipes unlocks and it is gunpowder
oh it makes three stacks I thought it
was two for some reason
okay that's very good we want to try to
get as many as we can and then those are
going to get loaded into the dispensers
okay so here we go guys we're about
ready with this thing now I did warn you
I did say it was a stupid little project
and I meant it so I wanted to see if I
could spell out a word with fire right
so I want to see how tricky it actually
was so it's like what we're do I spell
out so we're going to spell out my name
is Oh out of fire and it's going to be
amazing
so turns out it was a little bit tricky
not too bad this is our ethos circuit
over here
and we want to try and make it look cool
right so we don't want them to all
activate at the same time kind of wanted
to like spell it out like as it goes
down you know so got the button set up
here we'll do it once before we cover it
just to make sure it works I got it on
Adelaide uh-huh so I think that's gonna
be pretty cool the whole thing activated
that's a good sign that means we didn't
miss a piece of redstone anywhere and
now all we got to do is cover it up so I
put slabs in places where the redstone
goes uphill like that so it shouldn't
get cut off and I think it should be
good all right hopefully we'll find out
cool so here we go guys I think we're
ready now so the idea is you could hide
like a secret message or an arrow or
something something completely hidden
underground then you tell somebody hit a
button and then they'll be like oh my
goodness
so amazing okay that's pretty cool I
couldn't quite get that the timings
perfect at the end there just because
the way it worked out there was enough
space to do it
like where it was perfectly smooth but
that wasn't too bad that was pretty good
I thought let's try it one more time and
then the fire will disappear over time
here I put the border around it because
I was worried I wouldn't know where to
look her might lose it eventually
because like outside creepers kind of
carelessly sometimes when I'm on the
sand and I wanted to make sure I
wouldn't do it over top of this right in
the future if there's ever a creeper
here I know oh gotta be careful because
we got the border there one more time
all right here we go
aiyee yes I just trying to decide what
are we going to be doing here what comes
next and tell you the truth I'm in a
little bit of a Dueling mood right now
so we're going to do some building will
try to refinement if we can like I was
just here as like man I never finished
this path and this place like we got the
important stuff done like we got most of
it triggered out but there's still some
stuff here that should get finished the
floors not done down there that's not
done all this netherrack shouldn't be
there the roof isn't done here so yeah
I'm going to spend some time here and
see what we can do I think for the roof
oh because this is another fortress and
please respond in nether fortresses now
sometimes I get surprises oh and if I
kill one of them then everybody freaks
out like all the guys behind the glass
start freaking out not going to leave
the area joke how will be fine we'll be
fine
okay so yeah I think for the roof here
what we're going to do is Doolin with
cyan and I did bring a bunch of stuff
with me here yeah around the little
stone it looks like it kind of got a
sheet figured out here before I do like
this oh I actually saw a fireball go by
oh he snuck up there okay he's going to
get me I just left the area they were
giving me a lot of trouble so had to
leave came back gave me trouble again
had to leave came back and now we're
doing some building okay so this purple
border I think we'll run along there on
both sides along there too and then
we're going to fill in that middle part
with glass kind of like we did over here
just to create some more depth okay well
I think that's an improvement right a
little bit better than what we had what
I'm having trouble with now is I got to
connect like this was all open before
and now
I connected to the roof right instead of
keeping it open like we did make it feel
like the room is finished problem is
there is redstone behind those sandstone
stairs there so somehow got to make this
look better maybe I don't like how like
as you're watching here that windows
kind of block so maybe we will try get
rid of some of this a couple blocks here
make it a bigger better arch right it's
always a good thing see if we go up here
that might be that might be good
actually and then it might be easier to
make this look good over here
because then this is like it's on top
that's good maybe we'll throw in some
slabs here get rid of that then what's
what's over here
oh it's open but then I think yeah red
stones right here so we got to put
something here - hmm it's a little bit
square a little bit chunky over there I
couldn't quite get it perfect because
the redstone was in the way oh actually
a really hard jump area we got it but we
almost never see up there anyway because
it's on the back side right so next
thing we're going to do we're going to
run maybe some purpose stairs along the
top here on both sides we'll see if
anything comes with that
and I think we'll make it stick out like
this all along good stuff all right next
we're going to bring the perper down
next to the spawner there on the right
spring it down and then mere that on the
other side of this opening here like
over here
yeah so basically our goal with this
guy's is just to think of things to add
to the room that we can fill in the
space and get it finished looking you
know not really thinking too too much
about it we're going to do another skunk
line thing like we have over there we're
going to mirror that on the top of the
roof here so we'll put sandstone between
and that's hopefully look cool too
what is this what is this stone brick
over here is that red stone I hope
that's not red stone now it looks like
it's just a bunch of blocks for some
reason
what about above no there is on that
stone I know okay you know what I'm
actually really happy with that skunk
line I think that's really good
because it creates like a continuation
effect it goes whoop and then whoop and
it's almost like they connect together
up over there from this angle but when
you're up over here you can see that
they don't actually I think that's good
mixes in some sandstone up there as well
now take a guess how do you figure it
out my secret sauce the building what's
going to go over here question got to
balance it out you've got to get some
perper on this side too
piece of cake alright keep it in line
yeah over here is good oh I just killed
it yeah so purpur pillar here is going
to happen what else so on the other side
of the skunk line here again we're going
to do the mirror thing I'm going to pick
some cyan and try to add that over here
okay well it's coming together here guys
we're getting close getting very close
here I don't know if I'm going to keep
it like that that's a little weird maybe
but I am about to do something I don't
know if you guys can handle this though
your mind we're gonna do horizontal
skunk lines horizontal I know crazy
revolutionary
it's gonna happen let's change out this
so there's not quite as much sandstone
we'll get some gray mixed in here to
that way let's make this gray then we're
going to try blue blue blue blue
horizontal skunk line okay it's gonna go
over here we might try to get two of
them in oh I'm sure it's done okay so
yeah we're gonna try to get sandstone
running along here we'll break that and
then continue it on so it connects to
over there are you ready are you
prepared to witness the horizontal skunk
lines okay here we go here we go guys
boo absolutely astonishing right we just
unlocked a new recipe looking at these
things they're so amazing mm-hmm mm-hmm
so they fill up the spot pretty good
there and then over there I decided to
add in a door remember it was all grey
here before it added in a door so we can
still go back here if we want to and
look at like how the gizmo works where
for some reason they get stuck we might
be able to reach it from here too
didn't want to cut off that access like
you had before up over there I just
filled in with glass you can see that
netherrack back there through the glass
but I think I'm okay with that because
but you can see it through this glass
over here too and I don't really want to
change all that out it makes it feel
like we're still in the nether if you
see a little bit of nether act right so
I think that's okay then up over there I
put in a pot light because it was kind
of dark and got some lighting behind the
door there too what else what else
connected the arch across like that and
I think the top part of this room is all
finished now oh yeah and there's like
some weird things here like where this
wasn't stairs this was solid blocks I
got that all fixed changed a little bit
with the door here and I'm just going to
block them off with glass until they
actually put something there
made like a little support stair thing
here for pathway and yeah we got the
bottom part of this to do which I think
we'll say for another day because that's
probably gonna take me a little bit of
time too
won't be as difficult as this top part
but still um and maybe we will try to
work on the tunnel here before we finish
op because this is what's really bud
buttering buttering me bothering me
because this tunnel because I got to
walk it right we should really change
this out with some some ice so that I
can ride the boat here oh he wants me he
wants me so bad he's like how can I get
him and he looks at me and he's gonna
think about it for a little bit then
he's gonna be like can I get them if I
go up over here no no I can't get him
I'm going to come back can't let him out
of my sight okay let me think let me
think
if I wait long enough he's gonna have to
come down to pick up his ice because
it's gonna despawn I'm gonna hit him
down there miss all right we got it we
got them 360 ie
mmm
decisions decisions do we go with option
number one with the sign right next to
the perper or we do or do we recess it
one block and makes it look darker and
like there's something back there hard
to decide option three we do this but we
also fill it with glass what does that
look like
I think that's better all right very
cool guys so check it out our tunnels
pretty much all done here I would say
ended up going with option three I think
it looks the best out of them or it's
the most interesting anyway so if in
doubt always go with the most
interesting one now what I would like to
do one final thing here is we got to
make a connection to the tunnel up here
the way I get up here normally is to
enderpearl or I use my fireworks it'd be
cool if we could actually ride the boat
up here and connect to this tunnel and
then like drop down to so I'm going to
try set up a slime launcher and I'm not
sure I just will try and keep it in line
here and see if this is the right spot
it's going to be a trial and error thing
I don't know the exact distance they
launch you so we want slime launcher
right here this is going to have to be
like noteblocks or something that
doesn't move with the slime and I got
one do we got more doodoo oh no I don't
think we have more no okay I'll make
another one unless I'm blind I didn't
see it do we still have redstone yeah
we're running low on redstone again
sometime we really need to finish up
that witch farm I kind of left it in
heaven haven't fixed it right and I'm
running low on redstone again so it
might be a good time to get that done
okay so we do that then we're going to
have a pressure plate over here I think
you want it on the backside so if we're
approaching from this side towards it
then I think the pressure plate goes
here if I remember right and then we
just need to run that down to the piston
don't have a block something okay let's
just use the ice I guess and that should
be good hopefully so we're going to take
a running charge at this launcher and
see if it'll take us up to the tunnel so
height and distance is the big concern
here is it going to make it oh I hit my
head
well okay we had some pretty good speed
going there though so maybe it'll work
we got a maybe take out some of the
stuff let's take this away a couple
blocks okay here we go again
whoo what okay so we're going a little
bit higher than we want to um looks like
we also can't go too quickly because if
we go too quickly it seems like we shoot
over the launcher let's try this one
more time mmm Oh hit my head again
alright everybody well I tell you what I
just noticed the time on the episode and
it's about time we wrap up for today
we'll save that launcher thing for
another time and I was watching through
here just tell me something here I
noticed all the vines today for some
reason like where these always here and
I just never noticed them or did they
just start growing recently like they're
all over the place surely they grew
recently right for some reason because I
find it hard to believe they were here
all the time
I don't know anyways here is the comment
I picked out for today guys this is a
question that kind of comes up or a
suggestion that comes up quite often so
I thought I'd mention it it says hey ESO
I know you've been doing a ton of large
projects lately and I really like them
but it takes away from the uploading
schedule as you've said from the last
term a craft episode instead of not
doing any more large projects have you
thought about streaming them you could
stream the building of the project for
the two or three days it takes to make
it and afterwards upload the regular
video of the entire process okay so
here's the thing about that because it
is something I've thought about doing
maybe but you gotta like really be some
special person to do both YouTube and
streaming I think it doesn't work out
for a lot of people you either do one or
you do the other and the reason for that
is pretty simple it's because they both
take efforts they both take time they
both take efforts like you got to set up
your streaming
you got a like when you're streaming you
got to put a lot of effort into what
you're saying and you know be
interesting for people to watch and and
all that kind of stuff so if I do both
it's just going to be one more thing I
got to do is the problem and from my
experience I prefer YouTube over
screaming so that's why this is what
I've been doing
like streaming's fun but I would find it
hard to do everyday I think uh-huh and
actually to be honest with you like the
part of making these videos that I enjoy
the most is when I'm not recording
that's like my my fun time when I was in
just chill and like build something like
I did today but he's also pretty much
that's that's my like joy time when I'm
actually recording it it takes effort
like I got to think about what I'm gonna
say how I'm going to say it so I mess up
when I'm saying it I got to redo it and
that's not fun and like it is it does
take effort is the thing well it would
really be good this is why I need I need
to find some way of doing small projects
that people enjoy watching right and
I'll give you an example here of how
things have changed for me a little bit
like when we first started in this world
I'm just going to give this as an
example I spent a whole episode I'm
pretty sure building this mushroom farm
here a whole episode if I did that
nowadays like people would be like that
was lame right or is that just in my
head because that's that's what I think
people would be like or I spent a whole
episode building this for example
honestly I could do that so easily now
if I was to do something like this but I
don't think people would have be happy
watching me do something like this
nowadays they expect more in my mind
whether or not that's true I don't know
but that's just the feeling I get
because there's so much like other
youtubers doing minecraft and we kind of
shot ourselves in the foot kind of by
doing more and more every episode to
like attract people
we've entered a slippery slope where
well we got to keep doing more and keep
doing more and it's I find it
overwhelming to some extent at this
point alright but it might all be in my
head maybe it's all just in my head and
you know people would be happy with
simple things like I would love to just
spend an episode caving that would be
super simple for me but I don't think
videos of this gamer at this point
anything at that point anymore right
correct me if I'm wrong I'm curious what
you guys would say mm-hmm anyways that's
going to do it for today guys thank you
for watching hope you enjoyed it and
I'll see you again in the next one take
care bye bye
[Music]