[Music]
hey hey
what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys to
another episode of our our minecraft
series here
you ever heard of minecraft
uh i've been working on the the course
fruit farm here
trying to finish this up today if we can
and and hopefully we can
blend it into this area a little bit
because it sort of sticks out at the
moment
which i i don't really like we want to
try polish up the area make it look
nicer
so let me show you this first off okay
so i uh
i just built like a lane out here a lane
um scaffolding that we can walk across
and then i planted the coarse fruit down
there and this is how it grew around it
and i think this is going to work out
perfect for getting the seeds
so the plant look at the plants they
still grow pretty tall
right so we'll still get a lot of the
purpur blocks off of them
but it's really easy to harvest the
seeds from up here
look at this they're like they're like
right there
bam piece of cake so just go along on
the top here
if i ever run a low on seeds i just have
to do a little seed harvest like this
if i got lots of seeds i i can just skip
it too
because each plant's probably going to
give me about two or three at least by
the looks of it
some of them like those down there i
can't reach but for the most part
it's pretty easy to reach everything
here
okay just about done with the harvest
looks good okay so then after i harvest
the seeds then we're gonna have this
thing here i just set up some pistons
running along the the back of the farm
we're gonna fill these up with water and
the pistons will hold the water
in place until we release it
okay this is going to start harvesting
the plants
oh oops
uh yeah i guess that's eight blocks
isn't it so the water's not actually
going down like it's supposed to here
whoops
okay i'll have to deal with that um
man it would be a pain to move all the
all the pistons here maybe i'll just
get rid of the stairs here then
yeah okay so that's what i ended up
doing here i just moved the stairs one
block over to the right here
so they're in line with the end stone
they used to be down this row here
if i had moved the pistons over to the
left they would have been
uh in this area here and then the
the chorus fruit we plant right here is
going to get blocked by this so that
would have worked
really so this is probably the best way
of doing it
anyways we are gonna do our first
harvest here we're gonna try this out
make sure it works are you ready
and
we got to make sure all the the fruit
flows down it doesn't get stuck anywhere
that was pretty cool oh yeah look at
that they they bounce out of the water
when they go over the stairs that's cool
i like that all right looks like things
are going down pretty good
very nice very nice
all right let's shut the water off if i
do this at night all the mycelium is
going to die so i need to definitely get
some
glowstone on the ground or something
so that the mycelium stays alive when
it's dark
okay i don't see any fruit stuck on the
stairs or anything that's good he's a
little worried about that
and it all ends up over here so we're
going to need either another water
stream to push them
this way and gather them all together or
i'm going to set up a hopper minecart
down this middle part
oh man i'm all full here
not awful all full i'm not an awful
person
bad pun okay all right cool so now uh
what i'm going to do
next i'm gonna try uh make the
scaffolding things look a little bit
better
and i probably didn't pick up all these
but it's fine we're gonna be getting a
lot lots of stuff
in in a second here okay so i
firmed up some acacia wood i think
that's what we're going to use instead
of
the dirt here and we'll put ladders on
on the pillars so i want one over here
one over here another one there
and i'm going to try to connect them
together at the top as well so i can i
can cross between the different rows
all right and get the ladders going up
so i have it
these uh these are going up 12 blocks
from the ground level here
is is what i'm doing and that seems to
be a pretty good height where the plants
grow
pretty much to their full full extent
because once uh
once they reach these scaffoldings it
kind of affects their growth pattern a
little bit makes them shorter
like it blocks them from growing that's
what i'm trying to say
so at 12 blocks doesn't seem to cause
too much trouble
all right and then i'll probably just go
across like this
aha this this feels like a roadblock
one two three four five six yeah there's
a there's a few creepers there
okay moving on
okay so check that out guys i got the
beams running across the top here
that's what we're gonna walk on to
harvest the seeds and
i like the way it makes it feel too it's
almost like a building now that we have
something over our head instead of just
some random plants growing here actually
feels like they belong more so
and i got it stepping down every time
just threw some beams on the side there
to try to make it look better
and i was going to add some lights near
the top as well
going down i like this like gradual
sloping it has
gives it kind of a cool look i don't
like the fences on the top here but i
might have them on the bottom
let's try and decide what color i want
to use i think birchwood looks pretty
good
i don't like the dark oak here so
definitely not these
get rid of these uh the orange doesn't
really suit the area
because nothing else is orange around
here so it's between these two
maybe the birch because this is yellow
and and the birch is yellow right
yeah let's do that okay and then along
the top here we should probably get some
lights in two because
uh at night time i don't want mobs up on
top here i want to be able to use this
farm at night time if i
if i choose to as well so
i think i have some lamps yeah okay
let's do lamps do we have any
cobblestone here
got a little bit oh we got levers
already sweets planned ahead
all right uh so just uh occasionally at
the top here every so often
i think we'll just throw in like a lamp
maybe put a lever on top i don't really
want to put like a glowstone here
with trapdoors on the side because that
will affect the growth
if it's just a lever on top though it
wouldn't matter so much
does that look good like that yeah so if
we had those going
along every so often i think that would
probably be okay
um it'll light up the course fruit too
so the farm will look nice at night
uh-huh so this is the nighttime look now
i got lights in the top
along the scaffolding and i also put
some lights in the bottom
i think there's a nine block gap between
them and i tried to alternate them
two per row so it's in the middle on
this row
and then they're left and right here and
as far as i can tell the block lighting
in here doesn't
drop below 8 anywhere so that's pretty
good
this back row i i don't know if i like
this but that's what it is right now
oh i never even finished whoops i
thought i did
uh-huh do i
i think i put the lamps away already i
just been putting down two levers and
then the
lamps over top that's the way i've been
doing this
all right so we got uh a full crop
growing here too this is the first time
i had enough seeds to fill the whole
farm
it's 173 plants
so every harvest i need to get 173 seeds
to break even
all right okay so i think maybe let's
work on this uh
stream part next uh let me get the stuff
together for that
all right so i'm trying to think what to
do here we're gonna have a problem with
this water stream
uh let me show you what i mean so if we
just run
ice over here and then put a bucket of
water over here
you know it only travels eight blocks
then it gets to this point
so we need a another bucket of water
let's get some more ice down
and okay there we go so we need another
one like over here
it's going to flow back like that so i
got to put a sign there
to stop that from happening and now the
items can flow through
the only thing is if something washes
down over here
is gonna stop it's not gonna get washed
down
so i think what i'm going to do
to to combat that have a second
ice stream below this one
like this and then wherever it falls
down like
like over here have water in that spot
and the real ice stream is going to be
this lower one
i think the other way we could do it is
you could just keep going down gradually
one one block at a time but by the time
we get to the end of this farm it's
going to be a really deep hole
and i don't want to fall constantly in
this
this uh deep deep hole we did make down
the middle because it'll
get down like to about this point here
um
towards the end all right so i got a lot
of stuff to show you guys now i've done
a bit of work off camera here working on
this water stream business
and uh we're gonna get this farm
functional today for sure
um so first off i did the thing we have
a second water stream underneath like
this i've never actually done this
technique before the nice thing about is
it keeps keeps everything level like
normally i just go down one block if i
need it to be
a long water water stream sort of thing
um but this way everything just fits
within a four block height or so
which is kind of cool got ladders here
in case i accidentally fall in i can
climb out and i'm hoping that when the
stuff washes over the side here
it's not going to hit that ladder but
i'll have to double check i don't think
it will
but we'll have to see all right so all
the
all the fruit all the seeds and stuff
that i pop off the plants that are on
the ground they're gonna all wash down
into this middle
all right so let's go down here and i've
done
a bunch of stuff so first off it hits
these hoppers and
uh redstone crazy gizmo stuff
so these hoppers to start off with are
to
sort the items so we have one that sorts
out the flowers the seeds
and another one that sorts out the fruit
anything that doesn't get picked up by
these goes into this chest this is like
the garbage collection chest
alright if they go into
man i did not leave a lot of uh walking
space down here didn't i
uh if they go into the seed one
then uh it ends up in this dropper and
this
is a special dropper that
automatically shoots any items in it
they get shot out over here
up this item elevator right
and then i want those blocks back i
don't have them
whoops i guess i'll just cover it with
stone
it's fine it's all good not that picky
so yeah this is just uh how did i do
this
okay so if there's an item in this
dropper this comparator detects it
and then into the repeater and then back
around
to the dropper there's a more compact
way of doing that but just because of
the space
constraints there i had to do it like
that so the item elevator goes up to
here
and actually we can just throw some
seeds in to show you
of course since i threw the stone in
there it's in the in the chest here
yeah i'll show you what i mean so if we
just throw in the seeds
oh that hit the ladders oops uh it
shouldn't hit the ladders
because i don't think they have enough
enough momentum to do that
and i'll throw in a little bit of dirt
just to show you that it actually does
the separating so those seeds are coming
up the item elevator on top of a hopper
here
and that just puts in the chest so we
threw 16 in there we got
16 in there very good it's close to the
farm so it'll be easy like if
i need to do some replanting
everything's going to be right here
right next to it which is nice
um the garbage should go in here yeah we
got the dirt there
very good and then uh
coarse fruit gets sent into this dropper
this is the more compact way of doing it
by the way
all right goes over here shoots items
into this
ice stream that we got to set up yet so
i think
so to start working on this as we go
check out this other thing
all right throw down some signs this
goes
to that blacksmith house we were we were
working on
just to give that a little bit more of a
purpose i want to
set up something in that that building
instead of doing it right at the farm
here
all right so this might take a little
while
yeah let's not do the whole thing it's
going to take too long
so i'll just run ahead here and show you
we'll lay down some ice as we go though
all right so it's not a super long
tunnel it's a little bit long
but there's going to be another item
elevator up here
finish this off oh and
items should pop up over here
this is right at the house you know i've
never
seen a acacia forest by the like this by
the way
this is kind of cool all right if you
took out a few of the logs and you just
had the canopy cover i think it would be
a nice effect
um i don't like the color of these logs
really
i think it would look better if it was a
like a spruce spruce forest or something
but
i like the canopy it creates all right
so we're gonna
send these down another water stream at
the top here
so we'll put down some ice to that
okay so items will pop up right here and
we want them to go this way get some
more stone
all right let's uh i am a little picky
about dirt though i don't like having
dirt with the water streams
i always like to change that out so
we'll use stone bricks
okay all the way to
here is this going to reach i don't
think it is
anyway let's just put a sign there then
because we'll need two water streams
here
okay that'll wash over here and then
we'll have another one over there i'm
going to have to put
some stone in front of these hoppers i
did a really
lazy auto smelting setup here i'll show
you
oh or i don't know if lazy is the right
term quick
yeah let's call it quick so it's uh
when the course fruit comes by here it's
going to go into this first topper first
and then the second one third fourth
fifth it doesn't actually spread out the
items
uh like some of these do it just fills
this one up then fills this one up and
then
goes all the way down to the front so
uh we might only have one furnace going
at a time because of that
um and then in the back here we have our
coal
injection going into the side so if we
drop coal into here
goes into the furnace like so
let me get these back i want to split
them up but i have hoppers running along
the top as well
and again that's this is kind of a lazy
way of doing it where it's going to go
into this one first and then this one
and then
all the way down but it works if we put
enough colon
oh and oh i wonder if they fixed this by
the way there's a glitch where if you
break a block of coal or a block of
diamonds
into the individual pieces you lose some
so we should get let's see that used up
eight eight times
nine is not 64. so they haven't fixed it
yet
72 right
i think so let's hope so all right
but yeah all the coarse fruits going to
go into these hoppers down to the
furnace auto smelt
and these ones in the bottom pull it out
from there and they're going to put
everything in these chests here
cool so we got quite a bit of stuff done
on this farm already uh
we're going to give it the big test now
though i want to make sure everything
works the way i hope it does make sure
everything
functions properly and it auto smelts
the purple blocks and all that kind of
stuff
so to begin with i'm going to get rid of
the seeds here we got to make sure we
get 173c seeds from a single
pass-through if we don't we might need
to make some other way of getting seeds
for this first test i'm not going to
harvest these lower ones if we don't get
enough seeds though i might have to do
that
because these are these are pretty easy
to get to if we just run through
but i'm just gonna get the top ones all
right
the problem is i only got five minutes
to
to chop all these seeds and like get
them in those hoppers there otherwise
they're gonna start despawning so
as soon as i start breaking these it's
it's on
i can't stop until it's it's all
all done so i'm going to go through the
farm now try to get as many as i can
as quickly as i can then we will
let the water go out to break all the
plants
push all the fruit down and we'll see
what we end up with
in the end of this okay so give me a
little bit of time to
to do this
okay i think i got all i can reach here
i it didn't feel like 173 though
uh maybe a hundred
oh the leg i want some way of activating
the farm from over here too that way you
can actually watch it
better oh don't tell me the water's
messed up oh it's a visual glitch
okay here comes all the items look at
this oh and a pig
yes i gotta pick with the two okay
oh they're getting stuck on the ladders
okay we gotta get rid of the ladders
guys we can't have the ladders i'm sorry
46 there
that means everything got stuck on the
ladders right that sucks
um yeah let's just throw everything down
here
okay 57 there that's good
we also have to kind of make sure those
hoppers can handle the load of all these
items
are you stealing my plants oh you jerk
you jerk you're affecting the test
results
oh and they are getting stuck on the
hoppers
that's a problem i wonder if they went
to the second one oh that sucks
um
yeah we got a problem uh
it's too many items all at once and i
didn't realize that they could skip a
hopper
they went to the second one
let's just grab these before they d
these spawn on us i guess
okay so i'm gonna take the seeds out
yeah we have to change a few things here
because now these are going to go to the
garbage
i'm pretty sure
or no no um
if we had more coarse fruit they would
have they would have been standing there
too though
because there's only room for three more
stacks and we have like 10
extra stacks on us so that would have
been way way too many
oh and i need a block covering here
okay that's important
and
okay so all in all we got you know it
actually looks pretty close here i think
we even got more than 173
i had a few on me that landed on me
while i was harvesting those
oh and there's three in here yeah that's
473 128
plus 50 is 178 plus 7
is uh 185
so we got a little bit of a profit there
even that's pretty cool
um couple landed on the sides here i
kind of expected that
a couple along the back i want to put
something in the back here
a little bit more fancy like a wall of
some sort
all right a couple seats here
yeah all in all looks pretty good just
want to make a few more changes with it
okay you know what this is what we're
gonna do with the ladders since we need
a sign here
ladder will do the same thing just put
it like that
nice and simple gets rid of the sign
adds a ladder and then the ladder's high
enough that the items won't land on top
of it
that's a pretty easy fix all right
um i'm noticing something with our
dispenser
thing down there as well
let's finish this up okay let's go over
here now
i want to add a button on the front
maybe by this
chest that's going to activate the water
and i'm going to set it on a timer so
that it will
automatically close or shut off the
water after a certain amount of time
that it takes all the items to flow from
the back to the water stream
that'll simplify things a little bit and
all we got to do here is add a block
so it doesn't go to this hopper we
probably need to add
i don't know how to do this we need some
way of picking up the items faster
though
i have to think about that uh this here
we can actually speed up
this doesn't need to be on a two-tick
delay so what i'm going to try to do
is do a quick pulsar as fast as we can
if i run this back
oh wait a second
yeah that's right right i
i'm confused by that
there we go that's what i want
yeah i think that'll work right or is
this gonna let's take these out
oh no that's not gonna work yeah we need
that repeater
okay gonna put the repeater back like so
and
this is the last of my redstone again by
the way we got to get that which farm up
and running
it's a little bit faster not quite as
quick as i'd like though
and let's go double check on the
blacksmith building there to make sure
we're actually getting the purpure
blocks melting
and so i never did finish the inside of
this and i want to try
make the basement look a little bit
better but uh
this will work for right now oh there's
a torch stuck here
oops okay so it's actually uh filling
these up pretty fast
faster than i expected so they're going
into here
they're getting auto smelted and then
whenever they're done smelting this
pulls them out and
it's making the popped coarse fruit so
then i would just take these
and make the blocks
uh-huh we should get some storage down
here for the blocks as well
i had this all filled up with coal but i
think it dispersed throughout here
yeah so there's like basically an
endless supply of coal
going to the furnaces too they shouldn't
ever run out
cool so yeah i think that's pretty good
i'm happy with all this
all right well it's time we wrap things
up again for today's episode
so the comment says etho how many horses
have you
killed oh that means
we have to look at our statistics it's
been a while
james quit 794 35
days of play time i don't know when this
is uh keeping track last
but uh that's a little bit of play time
sneak time uh what's interesting here
i just saw this scroll through you guys
can look damage dealt
428 000 that's
oh i've taken a lot of damage too look
at that 206
000 that's insane that means i take like
just i i only dish out like twice as
much damage as i take
uh-huh zero cake slices eaten
the cake is a die
and yeah they track a lot more things
now than they used to
chest open five thousand two hundred
oh snap droppers are ticking dispensers
but look at that
1190 versus sixty
uh-huh all right here's the big one
though mobs creepers i have killed 710
creepers have killed me 15 times
skeletons
3 hundred they killed me five times i've
never died to a spider
i find that a little hard to believe
actually
two thousand five hundred zombies died
to him seven times
never killed by slime never killed by
gast
so this is not all time for sure
because i've definitely died to all
these things uh zombie pigmen have
killed me
16 times i think they're in the lead
i've killed about 30 000 though 21 000
enderman
[Music]
only 43 bats really now we got to get on
that then
2 500 guardians they killed me once
and cows my main source of food 2100
mushrooms 198 67 horses there's your
answer
never been killed by a horse to this
date
you know what's interesting about this
actually
look how many more skeletons i've killed
than like creepers
and other things and yet i've died to
creepers like three times more than
skeletons
you know what it is it's because
skeletons are annoying
so i actually have to kill them while
creepers and zombies and spiders i just
run by usually and just leave them alone
uh-huh and uh
scroll through these real quick i guess
just just in case you're wondering
80 000 what was that that was the
biggest number i saw
ink sax what oh that might just be dye
like bone meal and stuff
otherwise that doesn't make sense mine
290 000 stone
and yeah anyways
there's the statistics we haven't seen
them in a while
hope you guys enjoyed today's episode
thank you for watching and i'll see you
in the next one
take care bye bye
[Music]