hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another let's play episode
he's gonna be fine he's good he's all
fine okay so guys a new update has come
out we're in the 15 w49b snapshot now
the latest one here and there's been
some bug fixes they changed the way
cobwebs work and I just saw you can
sheer snowmen now so I want to try that
to start off with here I want to see if
you get a pumpkin off their head or what
the deal is all right where's my snow
got lots of snow need some pumpkins
actually let's go let's go use the farm
I have pumpkins there but you know we
want them fresh all right there we go
get a bunch of pumpkins and some shears
gonna run all over the place here okay
we could probably just test it over here
though here's good okay so let's make a
snowman and I think it chops off their
head but I'm not sure oh oh I thought it
would
oh that's funny it's the it's the knotch
sprite the one he made was that always
underneath the pumpkins I never knew
that I always thought they they had
pumpkin heads and I didn't realize they
were wearing like a helmet okay I don't
think I got the pumpkin off of that
though did I try it one more time we
have nine we have eight yeah you don't
get the pumpkin from it they're not
moving around either wonder why so
what's different about them is it just
the look did they not move now is that
the deal
can we oh he's moving okay
he's moving stop it don't make a mess
can I put a pumpkin back on them no no
that's it once it's gone it's gone I'm
gonna leave one of these guys I want to
see if it'll regrow though like over
time if that's a thing all right it
looks like it's a purely cosmetic thing
like doesn't drop the pumpkin doesn't
regrow once you share it it's gone if
you try to put it on their head again
with the dispenser it doesn't work this
does work right ah
oh yeah and before I forget guys I
wanted to show you this today this is
like a redstone riddle I got for you if
you know how I did this tell me in the
comments but check this out we have
items in these droppers right put down a
block next to its shoots an item outs
that's pretty weird right check this out
put down a redstone block so it powers
the dropper no item shoots out how did I
do that do you know if you're confused
get even more confused so now if I do it
again doesn't shoot the item out and
this one does aha alright guys so last
episode we did the whole pig power thing
we made a pig power switch and
experimented with the idea got a lot of
good feedback on that from you guys a
lot of you seem to like the idea I had
trouble perfecting it though last time
you guys gave a couple couple good
suggestions as you can see the pigs they
like the carrots right um my plan was to
switch to eating carrots as my main food
source I'm already annoyed with that
like I got to eat so often it's really
really annoying these guys they don't
actually like golden carrots though but
it turns out rabbits do can we get these
guys out of here I don't think this farm
works anymore anyway yeah rabbits say
like Golden carrots they also like
regular carrots oh man they're jumping
all over the place you guys still stuck
there
how did that one get out if these ones
can't kind of odd alright oh they're not
the brightest yeah so check this out the
rabbits are definitely following me here
the pigs could care less though they
don't want the golden carrot golden
carrots are one of the best food sources
in the game so I would much rather
switch to them than regular carrots and
so with that in mind guys I have updated
from pig power to rabbit power now I am
an I spent so much time on this so many
failed designs I got one now that I'm
pretty happy with I looked at your
guys's suggestions I tried a bunch of
them like using more than one Pig or
more than one rabbits trying to use
unpowered power rails because they have
more friction a lot of that stuff it
just didn't work out too well I tried
like having a timer that's that had to
run before the door would open and a
whole bunch of stuff basically it was
flawed flawed design right so I got a
new thing here went back to the old
method of using water and now this seems
to work pretty good you see like when
the rabbits in watching mode he does
these little hops he doesn't actually
jump into the water it's not until he
gets excited with the golden carrot or
regular carrots that he jumps he does a
jump he gets stuck in the water and
since the animals they float in water
his head kind of rides against the top
of the glass there then I have a stair
so there's a little bit of an airspace
there and the top of his head hits the
tripwire and then he falls down and gets
sent back to the start here so it's
pretty close to perfect I think there's
only one flaw with it if he's very close
to the edge there that last block he
sometimes won't jump or if I'm close to
him you see this he's not jumping now
because he's already
he can get to me so it's not until he
has to move that he'll actually jump is
the problem and what I ended up doing I
hooked this up just to a hopper hopper
timer and that works so great because I
can set how long I want like a cool-down
I instead a cool-down so like if he
activates the tripwire again it has to
wait for this timer to finish before
it'll activate the door again that way
it's not like open-close open-close
like it was doing before so it's pretty
smooth and unselected if I don't want it
to do anything or I can just hold the
carrot selected and they'll keep opening
and closing give them a second to find
the carrot again oh yeah it's got to
wait for that delay because I I took the
carrot away from them all right so yeah
there's a little bit of a cool-down so
it just opens and closes slowly which is
nice and I can set that to whatever I
want so I'm really happy with this I'm
going to again though just watch it for
a little bit and see if I like it if I
do this seems like it's going to be good
we're going to add these circuits to
more parts of the man cave probably like
the snowball fountain and there's a
bunch of things I'd like to connect it
to alright guys so I do have an idea in
mind for a project we could start today
it's a new project probably shouldn't
start a new project but I do what I want
you can't stop me no this one should be
fun it's kind of simple in concept but
it is a little bit of work probably it
involves tea and tea so you know it's
gonna be good and since the glider Wings
have come out I've wanted to make like a
tunnel underground that you have to fly
through and I just realized there's
quite a bit of space behind this
waterfall if we do it just right like my
my man cave here is is loaded with
redstone and stuff
let's just see what it would take to
start flying around here and what I want
to do ok this we don't worry about this
relics of the past I think that's from
the chicken farm what is this that goes
down to the fishing Hut this is part of
the portal stuff I think and that's the
ender dispenser thing up there just
trying to be careful I don't break
anything important here we're not using
TNT at this part of the tunnel because I
know I'm going to wreck something really
important if we do that but I want this
tunnel to kind of make its way over to
the library and also if we want to add
on to the man cave we can you can do it
using this tunnel as well as a one-way
journey sort of thing because we're
gonna go down oh oh you know although it
is hard to get going when you hit the
water isn't it let's just dig down here
quite a bit let's not worry about the
flowerpots and all this girly stuff here
let's get rid of it
alright dig like a madman here let's see
if we can get flight with this little
bit chopped out or if we have to go
lower because ideally what I would like
just a nice convenient thing I could be
like running by here and oh I jump over
the bridge and whew okay so this dirt
was in the way um I'm worried about
making a mess here let's take out this
dirt go down a few more blocks EDD yes
oh no no no no no no no no no no no no
no no no what did I Oh
I knew always always block off the water
always who did I just kill is this
Wilson no it's the portal thing oh and
it goes further oh no no okay
okay I got a call tech supports I only
found one redstone dust one repeater I
can probably fix it I think I saw where
the repeater goes already
that's like let's just double-check Oh
bad throw oh snap it's really hard to
add anything new to the man cave because
there's so much stuff around
I'm guessing this was set on four and
the redstone dust must have been just
over here right could it really be that
simple of a fix yeah this looks okay so
I'm good all right all right let's try
this again Oh what would you know let's
just shut no we can shut off the water
we need it to test this man um let me
fill in some blocks then yeah because we
want to fly through the waterfall that
would be a lot cooler all right slowly
chisel this away before we release the
water here I think I'm safe to break the
dirt now okay
is that enough to get through okay so we
run over the bridge whoo not quite I
think I gotta get rid of a few more
blocks okay here we go
here we go just mined out a bunch of
blocks let's see if we can get flight
now oh that was a bad jump that was a
bad bad jump
I like landed on the fence let's try it
again
I gotta get better at this oh that was I
don't know man we're losing so much
height this waterfall slows you down a
lot
oh man I was doing this good before
okay yeah so I'm kind of on cue here I
think we got a mind more around here I
was the guess I'm gonna do my first TNT
I'm scared it was fine it was good I
want to use TNT if we can because it'll
make the tunnel more organic clicking
which would be better we're getting
really close to that fishing village and
we are at Y 36 I'm doing it I'm guessing
we're gonna have to add some sort of
boosters along the way to make it all
the way to the library but will will
tackle that problem when we get to it
see I would like to do two TNT at once
oh man I'm really worried about blowing
up what's below though I'm gonna hold
off yeah cuz we're so close to this
place
I actually just saw it oh snap I just
about blew up the roof you see that the
blocks fell right on top of this feeling
here oh I'm gonna die I think oh yeah
right here right here getting pretty
close all right
oh my goodness guys like look at this we
just got a little bit done and it's
already so much fun I'm genuinely
excited to try this out when it's done
it's gonna be so much fun
alright so check this out whoo getting
better getting better like oh oh I
actually hit my head see I might be
going down a little too steeply actually
which is good cuz I was worried we were
losing a lot of height there let's try
it one more time
my plan is to then grow a bunch of trees
in this tunnel and like shear all the
leaves in the middle and then it'll be
like leaves all around the tunnel and
like wood and and stuff and then add a
couple key key points of interest later
too
but this is about the size of tunnel I
want what we have here this feels good
okay so the method I'm using to do this
by the way is just double placing tea
and tea seems to work very well I think
I want to start veering to the left
again we're trying to go pretty much
diagonally to get to the library here
but if we just do straight diagonal it's
going to be really boring so I'm trying
to like wind it a little bit as we go -
just to make it more fun all right
Oh what what are we at here now 28 we
got a little ways to go down yet ah I'm
only going to do one here if there's
ever dirt I just do one because it can
do a lot of damage through that dirt got
some guild see now I want to go more
this way get a real sharp turn you know
all right it's cool I'm gonna do more
blasting here and then we'll try it out
again you guys don't look at explosions
awesome so let me give you guys an
update now we're at y12 silver we're
like at lava level getting close to
bedrock here which means we kind of need
to come up with a way of making this go
further without going down any more
which the only thing that comes to mind
is that booster thing I made like when
the latter wings first came out but it
wasn't very reliable I don't know if I
could make it better but that would be a
cool thing to have like right over here
and ever we would probably only need one
or two to make it the rest of the way
yeah because we're only going up to
minus about 540 on the Zed so it's
pretty close it's only about a hundred
blocks further but yeah look at this
tunnel guys I use less than two stacks
of TNT too I surprised how efficient TNT
is at T is at making tunnels like this
is a really long tunnel look how much
how many blocks I mined out like I
didn't use my pick very much just when
there was some stray blocks every so
often alright let's go for a fly here I
got to get rid of these yellow and red
flowers too I do not like yellow and red
flowers anymore you got to go for pink
tulips guys it's it's all the crazy pink
and whites sometimes orange is okay
right now and then yeah I like these
flowers a lot more alright here we go we
don't care about the that girly stuff
okay whoa whoa oh man I hit the wall no
oh I suck
I got tried again gonna try it again I
haven't haven't tested like the last 50
blocks or so we've mined here so I'm
hoping open it's all good I've been
testing it periodically as I as I've
been doing this just in case like you
know if I'm not if the elevation isn't
going down enough I would want not want
to continue
making the tunnel because then you won't
be able to do that the whatever you're
extending onto it you know you have to
make sure every section is doable all
right try it again
whoo all right I like the speed we're
going through here too it's it's nice
and quick it's not too slow I know it's
more efficient if you if you go slower
but I like cruising through it like that
so yeah we made it all the way to the
end there that's cool very cool all
right
um mm-hmm do we try make the bounce pad
I don't know okay guys so I decided to
hop into a creative world here back
where we had this bounce pad to do some
research with it oh man that didn't work
really to see how feasible it is to
actually use like in our tunnel it turns
out it is not reliable you have to have
the right speed the right angle and hit
the right position with very little
likely way to it's even this where I'm
precisely controlling my camera angle my
position and like I'm holding forward
the entire time and even still it
sometimes is messing up on me like you
have to get it just right
to work I gotta keep hitting my head I
don't get it
wait a second there we go I don't know
why it wasn't working those times oh
yeah so it doesn't look like we can use
this in our tunnel it's just way too
difficult to hit the spot
I even like tried setting up let's go
into a different position here like you
see the redstone torches there if I keep
my cursor on that I was trying to see if
I could fly in and like have my cursor
level with that like I'm landing a
plane's almost and now it's it's way too
hard way too hard so with our tunnel
we'll probably have to do something
involving ender pearls like throw an
ender pearl up to gain height again and
that should one ender pearl should
make us get the rest away alright so
well anyways guys I think we'll have to
call it here for today sorry for the
lack of videos lately I wasn't feeling
the best this week so decided to take
some time off now I'm I'm trying to play
catch-up but here we go for the comment
of the day it says etho please do
minecraft story mode it's a telltale
game with currently as I write this 3
episodes hope you read this and take it
under suggestion now I love minecraft
minecraft is like my favorite game ever
but minecraft story mode is not
minecraft uh it's it's related to it but
I got to tell you guys I am I'm what you
might call like an old old-school gamer
I really don't care for the artistic
side of games so much like I don't care
about the story I don't care about the
graphics all that much i all i care
about is gameplay and i do not enjoy
playing games where i spend most of the
time watching cutscenes or you know i
just want to play a game when i play
game i want to be engaged with the game
not with a story so something like like
that really doesn't appeal to me so it's
probably not going to happen so sorry if
if that's something you want for me but
anyways just thought i'd i would let you
know about that because i have a lot of
people asking me about if i was going to
play this anyways hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode and thank you for
watching as always i'll see you in the
next one take care night
you