[Music]
hello
everyone this is etho thank you for
paying me a visit again today welcome
welcome
before us we have a left chest
and a right chest and a creeper
go away go shoo alright a left chest and
a right chest let's just
do a look around here what are we up to
here what is adelio
well i don't claim to be
a psychological professor or scientist
or genius of any type here
but i have very proudly put together my
own
self-designed psychological test here
and i want you to participate
with me i'm going to take the test too i
want you
to choose one of these chests either the
left one
or the right one and make a clear choice
before we do this okay
um and you might ask yourself they're
just
chess what's so special about these
chests well
they are special chests they have the
ability
to reveal some
some information about your feelings
that you
feel strongly about like maybe maybe you
like ice cream
these chests might tell you you like ice
cream but it goes deeper than that they
might
they might even reveal information
you've never told another person or
maybe
you don't even realize yourself until
this moment
wow this this sounds amazing doesn't it
yes alright so please participate in my
psychological test here i want you to
make a choice right now
left chest or right chest if you're
having trouble deciding just pick the
first one that pops into your head
okay you got it left chest right chest
here we go we're going
i am going to choose
the right chest because
when given a choice between left and
right in a situation where there's no
logical reason to choose between any of
them
i feel right always wins because it's
it's the right choice
so i'm gonna pick the right choice and
for all of you that picked right
it's gonna reveal something about your
feelings
that you either know or maybe you don't
even know who knows
all right the right choice
you are a fan of
minecraft and for me that's true i
i i enjoy watching uh other people's
mind track videos good be the below
vintage beef all the guys love them
and i'm sure you guys well i'm assuming
you guys are like if you're watching me
i'm part of minecraft so maybe
if you're a fan of me uh you you're
probably a fan of minecraft right
all right but the rest of you that chose
left at this moment
you're probably thinking to yourself
well i'm a fan of you etho i'm a fan of
minecraft
um which may have been true
at one point but probably not after you
see what's in the left chest
uh that that feeling may have changed
and it's going to reveal your new
true feelings to you at this moment are
you ready
here's the left choice
you are a fan of one direction
thank you for taking part in my
psychological experiment
all right well that was weird
weird but funny for me at least
uh and everyone else that made the right
choice um
i'm assuming those are the only ones
still watching anyway
uh the real test is the reaction i'm
curious what kind of reaction i'm gonna
get on that
but uh yeah here we are guys in the man
cave
i was kind of running around here today
thinking about different
things i want to do and i came up with
quite a few actually
so we're just going to go around
and fix some stuff maybe build some
stuff we'll see
one thing i did prepare already is a
whole bunch of jungle leaves
because we have this
place jungle leaves over there there's
jungle leaves here
here here i think that's the theme i've
i've gone with with this so i think we
should replace this with them
this one and this one too at least
so let's go ahead and do that
um i've been having some computer
issues lately and i finally figured out
why
uh and i'm experimenting with it on this
video
but basically when i would go to record
when i'd hit f9 on my keyboard that's
what i that's my record button
i quite often would have it go down to
15 frames per second or 10 or
or something like that or if i if i did
manage to get it to go to
30 that's what i'm trying to record at
uh
it'll be fine and then after a few
minutes when it splits the video into
another file
then there was a chance it would go down
to 15 or 10
and you may have noticed my videos
getting kind of choppy in places that's
that's why i thought it was my hard
drive failing
actually but it turns out
it's because i did not have uh lock
frames
set on fraps which
i was trying to figure out why i didn't
have that enabled like to lock the
frames that locks it at 30
so if you get less than 30 the video
will just look jerky but it will still
be recording at 30.
and i i remember why i didn't have that
enabled a long long time ago like i've
had this computer for two three years
now
and been doing this youtube thing for
about that long too
and when i first started i was able to
record minecraft at
like 90 frames per second
i think i think at 1080p no problem
and if i had the lock enabled uh
it would lower my frame rate down to 30
even though i could record
at 90. like it forces it no matter what
that looks pretty good um
so since since that time the performance
in minecraft has got
gone down or else my computer has some
other issue with it i don't know that
could be it too
but i can just barely record it 30
frames now it's like between 30 and 45
i'm getting
and the reason i'm having trouble now is
because
since 1.5 or whatever uh
it can't do 30 usually so it will just
default to 15 when i start recording
but just because i think it's
it has extra load when i starts but
anyway i got it sorted out now
we can record properly again so
that's good i tried defragging my hard
drive so many times thinking that was a
problem but it wasn't
uh okay there's one more
one more thing i wanted to do here this
door i think it's kind of glitched
so i have a pressure plate there to open
it this goes into our potion ingredients
yeah these pressure plates don't work
anymore it's like they don't even go
down like i walk over it
and they don't move i might have to just
replace them
but i've been noticing this and i don't
like the door should close when i walked
in
yeah they're not going down even it's so
weird
it's not like a redstone problem it's a
pressure plate problem do they work here
no hmm
let's try make new ones maybe
i don't think they would have a
different id but you never know
huh uh i don't understand
why they don't work anymore
like i don't get it
let's try let's pick some wooden ones
it's very weird okay wooden ones do work
stone ones should too though
that is so strange
all right anyway i don't know what to do
about that i don't
want wooden ones i kind of want the
stone look
but all right we'll keep that in mind
uh the other thing though i kind of want
to get rid of this wooden pressure plate
here because
when we first made this door we had
three wooden ones going across
and we didn't have these paths to the
left or the right
oh there's the other one uh
now we do though so when we go up the
stairs we might not necessarily want to
go into this room anymore
we might want to go here or here so i
removed two of the pressure plates but
we still have this
one that i sometimes step on
uh we're gonna get rid of it though and
maybe make a new
new way of opening the door so this is
the line of redstone
here that we're activating
i hate looking at old wiring i'm always
it's like oh why did i do that
it's such a mess down here
yeah it's definitely a bug i just
checked the mojang bug report site and
it has been reported already it's a it's
a recent one i guess
uh so they know about it but i did come
across another interesting bug here
check this out
iron doors they have this unique ability
right now
where if you right click on them with
anything
you can't use it like food
ender pearls your sword you can't block
when you
right click on it shovel
pick so
uh just i just found that out too i was
trying to interpol through the door you
can do it from a distance
but i don't think you can understand
that might be to prevent that even i
don't know
anyway it's not a problem with wooden
doors i just checked too
because you open it
although you can't eat anyway let's stop
doing that
uh what we're going to do now with this
door
instead of using a pressure plate
because when i come up these stairs i
always
close your eyes people you saw nothing
uh when i come up these stairs i tend to
bump this pressure plate like if i'm
going to the right here now very often i
would walk over it
so we're going to change this to a new
type of activator i hope
and we're going to use a minecart hopper
because there's a really cool
feature or ability with it that i hope
doesn't get removed because it's
it's not something you could do
previously it's really cool
uh if you have
let's trigger this can we trigger this
i thought we could
wait why can't we trigger this oh
because it's being powered
um wait a second
that that didn't work um
i need to let's get this button back
okay we need to switch this unpowered uh
what we are going to do i'll just show
you the trick
if we have a hopper
uh over here no not that low
let's put a hopper over here and then we
have
a track on top and the minecart hopper
if we
let's go back up if we throw an item on
the ground it has this cool ability
where it can pit it up through the
ground
like that which is really really cool
and that gets put down into this hopper
so we're going to use that to open the
door and close it
i think that would be pretty cool and
it's better than a pressure plate
because the mob
has no ability to activate this
so what we should do
let's get a comparator the thing i'm
worried about is
oh when this is powered i don't think
items are going to go through the hopper
yeah if the door is i think closed
yeah closed uh we won't be able to open
it doing that because
items are just jumping off being powered
right now
i think we may be able to modify this
and lower
the redstone though i hope oh what was
that that was
one oh no i should have checked before i
broke that
uh i'll have to lower this
tell you what i'll do some of this off
camera because i want to do a few other
things today and i don't want to waste
all our time on this
okay i added that in it's actually a
really simple thing there's not much to
it
so now to open the door
give it a junk block of any type we want
i will put wooden pressure plates here
until that gets fixed
and then to close it again
pretty cool uh it's it's actually not
too bad either like check this out
it's like how did he open that door
that's crazy i didn't see him do
anything
uh oh i messed up that time if you throw
it while you're running you
you don't even see it go out of your
inventory really
that's cool i like that
and let's just go check it out here i
pretty things up a little bit down here
too because i didn't like the cobble
look
uh here's the minecarts on the hopper i
put these half slabs here because i kept
bumping it and then it wasn't working
so now it's gonna be held in place uh
that goes down to
a dropper the hopper
uh and the reason i'm doing that is so
it will shoot the item out it picks up
because i don't want it
eventually filling up my chest or
something then i have to empty it
every junk item gets expelled that you
throw in it
so that goes to the comparator this
block there's redstone wire underneath
this block you you can't see it which
points to this block
and the repeater and then to that and up
to the dropper
and the rest of it's just pretty much as
it was i had to
this is from the pressure plates on the
other side they go through this way
and everything goes up to this one point
here and
and then it's like the door like normal
so that's cool this was it too by the
way
uh that is all
good and done we hardly go in this room
anyway
but i kind of wanted to get rid of that
pressure plate and we did it
uh the next thing on my list is this
area here we still have some torches
here and our goal is to get rid of
all the torches in our cave which we're
doing a really good job on like
there's there's no torches here guys
believe it or not we made it work
for most our cave most the finished
areas
if we get rid of all these
does that lower the light level down to
oh yeah it's way too dark
so we could either put some lights in
the walls
lights under the water but they wouldn't
work too well or lights in the ceiling
is another option um
actually before we do that
i never really liked
the look of this over here it's like a
stone
corner uh maybe we could
change this so that the water comes from
above because it just this is water i
placed here it doesn't really come from
anywhere
which can look a little strange maybe we
can make water come down
here is that possible what's this
that's from the chicken farm which we
need to fix as well
let's
let's do that oh i thought i fell for a
second there
uh make it go up
does this look better if we do it this
way
uh
no i don't like that option two let's
put
uh oak wood up here
maybe that'll look better and then the
water back where it was
yeah i like that more i think so we'll
do that on this side
i'm going to play around with the
lighting situation here a bit too and
hopefully come up with something
relatively bright
huh i just realized there's been a fence
missing here i wonder
how that happened
anyway okay so i put these lights here
what do you guys think of these
uh i kind of like them they're nuts
they're not too intrusive
they're off to the side
they're different i like that difference
different lighting methods
are good they add variety i was thinking
about putting
lamps here i'm not too sure how good
these will look though
let's cover these up
to light the lower part because it
doesn't quite light it up enough with
just those
um
hmm what if we let's try a few different
things here
do that too
um oops
huh another option
yeah another option actually let's take
these back
maybe we won't do that they look a
little out of place
they got that dark outline around them
and i have a feeling glowstone would
look a little weird too
let's do or let's try this let's put
uh maybe
see can we do yeah we can do that so
let's put
a light up here
and one over here and see what this
looks like
kind of up and out of the way that way
and it sort of matches this one i would
do it
more of these uh type of lights lower
except it gets
it gets shorter and shorter at the
bottom here top there's more
vertical space so that's another option
i kind of like that one more
but i think that's better than the ones
in the wall
um oh check this out we got uh
yeah because we got so touch i guess
that glitches back into
can we play some ah now they go out
too bad uh
anyway that makes this part all lit up i
think we're all above
light level eight or higher here
we look good cool so that's another
thing done
uh this we might convert i was just
thinking of it now maybe we should
convert this
to an ender pearl station since we don't
really need the chicken farm
anymore especially with hoppers and that
we can just
automatically collect eggs
yeah i might turn this into an ender
pearl
reloading station like walk in and get
ender pearls
but we won't do that today oops i want
those back
put those in um
okay what else what what else did i want
to do there was a bunch of things
let's let's put some item frames by the
mushroom farm
just little details and also i wanted to
add a
block somewhere too let's get
the clock going
do we have item frames please tell me
yes yes we do
perfect uh let's grab some mushrooms
and we can hide this stuff away oh that
doesn't go there
there we go uh
grab a brown one a red one and let's
make a clock real quick here
okay awesome
i like working on the on the man cave
here i find it really easy
to do stuff like it's just i feel so
free working on stuff here
there's no real rules like no specific
shape i have to follow or anything
and in fact that
you know it kind of gives me the shape
with the cave the cave form
and just follow the way the cave
originally was and it's
ah can i not do that i thought i could
oh i see
oh too bad i wanted to put clock there
i could put one here right yeah i don't
know if i like that as much though
just so you can see what time of day it
is before you leave
that's not too bad
yeah we might do that should we put a
stair there instead though
quickly
yeah i almost think that's better
okay and mushroom farm let's go down
here
uh got those should we put it like
like that uh
brown red
i wonder uh where else would we put them
they do seem a little strange there
let's harvest
oh wait wait we can't harvest it's a
stone pressure plate i forgot
um we won't change this so i'm sure
they'll fix it soon
we could do it like this
nah maybe there
maybe it's too many item frames
ah whatever we'll put it there for now
oh yeah and i can't harvest this either
all right uh what else i wanted to put
something here we need something here
this is just a
mess right now i also want to get rid of
this light in the middle of the floor
and there's a torch there
not too sure what to do about that
though
where could we put a light here
like we could maybe put one over in this
area
but we would need another one here i
think and maybe one
a little higher
uh well let's do the other thing first i
wanted to
try put a tree in that spot
let's grab a sapling here
we'll need lots of bone meal i don't
think this is going to look too good but
we'll try it
and if it works we'll keep it maybe
let's grab some vines too
bone meal one meal
do i only have two bones hmm i must have
moved them all
i really doubt we're gonna get a tree
with this
let's try put it right
maybe right here
nope i i just want to see what it does i
know we can make it grow if we get
enough bone mail let's go let's go
outside and grab some more
uh i did want to work on the outside of
here today too but i don't know if we'll
have time for that
let's go i think there's some in our
chest here
i'm scared walking around here at night
there's so many mobs in the forest
usually
i might be on peaceful let me check no
there's ender pearls okay let's head on
back down
using our shortcuts
if you guys have any ideas for the cave
you know don't don't be afraid to
suggest something i i do take a look at
the comments
we will get a tree come on i know it's
possible
oh maybe it's not
one two three four five
i kind of thought it would be possible
nope ah i was kind of hoping it would
like grow and
lean to the left somehow i would have to
clear out more of the top there i guess
oh well uh
let's see what else
i'm gonna put some vines back here for
now just to try them for a bit
and
hmm i think that's about
all we'll do for today we might continue
more
around the manitoba next episode i guess
okay just a couple follow-ups before we
end this with the mushroom farm i tried
moving the item frames back
here they're not really necessary i
don't know if we should keep them or not
but i think that looks a lot better than
here and here
and the water doesn't wash them away i
tried it so
if we want to have item frames i think
that's a good spot for them
i also got the tree to grow check it out
i converted it into a glowing tree so
it's
it's giving us light i also put some
grass here and
and use bone meal on it i think that
looks pretty good actually
and comes all the way up to here
pretty cool it does block the view a
little bit but i don't think it's too
bad
and i added a light here i don't know if
we'll keep this either but just for the
meantime
since this is gone we need more light in
this area so it's better than a torch
so i added that in and again it it
blocks the view a little bit if you're
up here you can't quite see that bridge
there but when you get down lower it's
not a problem
so i think that's good
and was there one more thing i can't
remember now
that was probably it alright so two
comments picked up for today guys
uh number one dear etho considering we
both noticed tons of creepers in the
scaly bob tube
i think you should add a couple more
extensions if
the ocelot system in the in the ocelot
system so you have a bit more accuracy
for the record farm
i hope my idea gets through uh we may
end up doing that
but it turns out i checked it out today
the reason we were having so much
trouble last episode with the mob
sorting was because they're seeing
one of the or some of the scaffolding i
built they're seeing it as a
path they can go to and so they
they were going places they shouldn't
have gone and i think we can fix that
uh just by getting rid of the
scaffolding but we'll find out later
uh second question etho this is a
question i'm really interested about so
please if you see this
put it in the next video the question is
uh who who were you inspired to make
who were you inspired by to make a
youtube account
and entertain us if so
were you inspired anyway i tried to fix
that i think
i made it worse uh who was i inspired to
well i've talked about this
i think a long time ago but but i'll say
it again
i was first interested in youtube let's
plays by proton john
and azero blade they did super
mario 6 not 64 super mario
world uh playthroughs that were pretty
funny
that's that's how i first got introduced
to let's plays
creeper uh and i thought they were
pretty cool
i had no intention of making one of my
own though this was before minecraft
even came out
uh then minecraft came out and i s i was
really
i really like co-star his let's play was
really well done i i felt uh he he
was able to stay real in it which is
what really caught my id and i wanted to
copy that most people on youtube they
they create a character for themselves
or they try to put on
a show or you know there's nothing
really wrong with that it's just
everything's so fake i i i like the real
approach
that code took to it and i wanted to do
that too but of course i came up with my
own
unique style of doing a let's play too i
didn't just straight up copy them
i don't think um so i like that
and uh i guess that's it guys
thanks for watching hope you enjoyed the
episode i'll see you again next time
bye-bye
oh no no no no no silver fishing
fishing fishing
bye bye frames per second it was nice
knowing you
[Music]
you