hello everybody this is etho thank you
for joining me once again I'm just gonna
grab a snack here before we get started
getting hungry
just about out of bread a mind getting
some beef again OOP sorry Joe so the
feedback is back feedback his back that
made sense about the ceiling and it was
kind of 50/50 some people hated it some
people loved it
one thing that I really agree with that
people said is in certain spots
it was very dark like it needed
something to break up the wide area
we'll head up there really quick here
oh man the poor little jowls okay let's
get out of here oh wait we need to get
these what are we at we're at 40 I'll so
far
nice run looting sword put that back
4346 Oh beautiful
yeah about about the ceiling for most
parts it's pretty good
the one this part here it's like really
wide and there's no break in between we
need to maybe put something over here to
break it up either like a sandstone
texture maybe or lights or something but
like over here it's good it's not too
wide looks pretty good so I'll mess
around with it sometime
off camera probably I do have something
really cool to show you this episode
something I've been working on and which
we will go check out once I cook this up
or get it cooking anyway oh I forgot to
drop off the leather oh well yeah I keep
talking about making a mineshaft I've
actually done it now it's very cool or
at least I really like it turned out
good I was just gonna do like a hole in
the ground and one wide
tunnels throughout but then I started
working on it and I decided I would try
make it look cool too so I put it right
over there right in the mountain like
the really sharp mountain tooth looking
thing over there that we put the glowing
tree on top way back when
thought it would be a good place it's
close to our base here and so what I did
is I just started doing this outline
thing where I put wood around a three by
three ship tunnel or shaft here and I
tipped that going then I decided to go
down here and I did like this cube
three-dimensional cube type thing and I
really like how it looks like quite a
bit I think it looks awesome and then I
just kept that feeling going throughout
here so this is a this is a lily pads in
water like we played around with last
episode with the ender pearls I did go
with it and here's the trip down this
gets us down into the mine shaft this is
like a little room I worked on I've done
most of the repetitive and boring stuff
off-camera here we're going to do a few
things around here today
add a few few features to it hopefully
but yeah you you fall down in the
corners of this water drop and then it's
easy to get back up with ender pearls
just walk on the lily pad to the center
and I'll pour it up and you're out
that's really cool and then I put like a
spiral of torches all the way up or down
which i think looks really awesome
redstone torches gives it a nice look so
there's there's one over there and one
over there so at the same level there's
always two and they kind of just spiral
all the way through and you can see I
have wood lines all the way down every
a fourth block is the pattern I've been
doing without these torches it was pitch
black like where I am right now so I
needed some lighting and I didn't want
to use regular torches I want to try
something with a little more character
something out of the ordinary so this
works really well and then the water is
just being held up by signs maybe we'll
go up one more time see if we can see it
yeah so there's a there signs here to
kind of see it I hope oh and we have a
glowing pumpkin below for lights we're
going to be adjusting the lighting
around here a little bit today but
anyway this is a this is the shaft here
goes out this way and this way this is
an intersection marked with the redstone
torches and it goes way down here a
little bit and I'll just keep extending
it further as I need to each of these is
a tunnel which I will take advantage of
or that I'll be mining out for resources
I decide to make this @y 12.6 like I
said I've tried this before and I found
level 10 is ideal according to what
mcedit said as far as resource counts
goes but ten eleven twelve are all good
levels to go mining the problem with
going mining it level 10 is you keep
running into the lava pools and in my
old shaft or mineshaft that I was using
that was really getting annoying after a
while it's a good way to get obsidian if
you need it because you just bring a
water bucket with you and you turn all
the lava you run into into obsidian and
you can mine it out as you go but I
would like to avoid that if possible so
going to get a little bit less blue
rocks and red red dust at this level
just a little bit less but it's pretty
similar
I find I actually got quite a bit just
doing this so far I think I hold some of
it back but yeah I got got a fair bit of
stuff so far and let's see mmm okay so
this thing over here is full of ender
pearls these are just in case I don't
have any on me and I need to get back up
just go at that and we get four pearls
we only need two really to get back up
but it just looks better if there's four
dispensers yes oh this room here is like
the main hub of my mind it's a three by
three thing of these cube sections that
I like and it's our way in and out of
the mine we've got pearls here in case
we run out also going to probably set up
a bunch of chests in here for temporary
storage so we don't have to haul all the
cobble and goodies we find all the way
back to our base or whatever we can just
store them here temporarily we'll
probably set up a bunch of furnaces for
smelting the iron and gold we find into
ingots and also we'll probably smelt a
bunch of cobble into smooth stone I've
already been doing it a little bit here
I also am probably going to set up
dispenser stations like this for
shooting out extended speed splash
potions so if you gotta go aways to get
to your your mining destination you just
come down here get a speed potion and
then take off to wherever you need to go
if it's a ways away with these main
corridors I have here they're going to
extend 100 blocks in each directions and
form like a square so it'll go like a
hundred blocks that way and then we'll
have another main corridor going 100
blocks this way then then 100 blocks
that way 100 block
this way and it will meet up meet back
to this spot here and form 100 by 100 2
or 100 by 100 square sections type thing
so each of these tunnels is going to be
one wide to high like a normal mining
tunnel it takes a long time to mine out
a big space like this so these are just
going to be your standard tunnels and
they will stretch 100 blocks in that
direction
type thing and we're going this way
because the mountains are above us and I
have no intention of ever making a mob
system in a mountain biome you know it's
not really good because there's a lot
more tunnels in them usually a lot
harder to light stuff up so that's the
basic pattern I'm going here at the
start of each of these I put a glowing
pumpkin and this works out really good
for lighting this area up actually
because that's a light level of 15 there
one block up is 14 13 12 11 10 9 8 mob
spawn at light level below 8 so it just
perfectly makes it and same if we go
like over here 14 13 12 11 10 9 8 so it
it lights up the whole thing and if you
were to put like lamp in the ceiling
here like right here that would be light
level 15 down 1 is 14 13 12 11 right
here and then 10 9 8 so it works out
really good for lighting and I'm
actually going to we're probably going
to do that today we're going to put a
few lamps in this main area here at each
of these places and get rid of all these
torches probably and I think that'll
look really cool so maybe we'll do that
now actually I'm going to get some lamps
and did I mention the minecart plan I
don't think I did
I may also set up minecart tracks to
haul the stuff we mine up from here to
our base to our storage room or whatever
I think that might be cool have like
storage of mine carts on the track and
we will probably be able to ride them
too so we'll have two ways in and out of
here instead of taking this you could
take the tracks back and I may I don't
know yet I may put tracks in all these
main corridors I don't know the thing is
that the goal of this is to get
resources and if I spend a bunch of them
just on looks and convenience and
everything we might be putting more into
this and we get is what I'm worried
about although we'll definitely get more
red dust and blue rocks then we put into
this I know but we might lose out a
little bit on iron if we get into mine
cart tracks I don't know we'll see we'll
see how it goes okay I'm going to get
the lamps and I'll be back another
really cool thing about the location of
the mine is it's next to all the glowing
trees here that we did before so looks
really cool at night and we also have
the ravine right next to it may make
bridges or something over that set up
some paths out here or something
I changed this to so it matches the
other style before the walls are more
like over here alright um sit down I got
the lamps a little install them here
I'm tempted to put them at at each of
these things but I don't know be too
expensive I think each one is a
glowstone and for redstone and then you
got install wiring for them maybe I got
an idea for the wiring for these
you know how when I think of lighting in
mineshafts I think of the lights that
flicker on and off randomly every so
often I'm going to try to do that with
these I got an idea how to do it I'll do
tear at least for these main this main
corridor here we're going to have lamps
and beyond that like over here I think
we may leave plain I don't know
or at least for right now alright so we
got the lamps there and the chest I was
thinking about it as I was walking I
think it would look really cool if we
have get a bunch of chests here I think
we should do it like this have in this
section here here here and here have
have designated for the chests and have
threw a chest here here here here here
here so six and then maybe crafting
table in the middle and furnace furnace
that might be cool but then you got the
problem of not being able open the chest
on on the top so we need to replace
these blocks with stairs so that we can
open the chest so I'm going to do that
and we'll see how it looks at least for
one of these all right that's what it
looks like here not quite happy with it
I think I should have put in one more
block so it's inset like everything else
is here like this is inset this is inset
the whole whole mineshaft everything is
in one block it doesn't look right if
it's flush with the wooden planks that
also fix another problem I'm having with
the stairs here they have a lighting
glitch so the lower half is darker and
it doesn't
doesn't look right so if if I move it in
one block I won't have that problem and
we'll see how it looks
yeah I like that a lot more looks a lot
better maybe other options too maybe not
have the crafting table and have three
furnaces just so it's a little more
consistent I don't know what do you guys
think we'd have to put the crafting
table somewhere else so if we do it the
other way so I'll set up the other three
of these one there there and there
mm-hmm slight change of plans here out
we can't put the storage in these ones
because it will leave a gap and you'll
be able to see chests from over here so
I'm going to put the speed dispensers
over here and maybe a second one here
just for extra quantity and this is what
I've done with the chests I think it
looks pretty good
so we got the three furnaces we got six
chests and then three trafficking tables
down here just to balance out the look
and there's six stations like that so 36
chests total it's a little bit it's
overkill really I don't think I'll ever
fill them all but just makes it look
better if every one of these walls has
something and I can also put like signs
like for each of the chests like one
here here here here here here
saying what's in the chests if I want
yeah so the dispenser thing will go here
like that dispenser over there and I
just going to hook up the wiring for
that you won't be able to see it from
over here and that just leaves these two
walls over here which I'll if I do the
minecart thing that sends the stuff we
mined to the storage room at our real
base then they will probably go here and
maybe here I don't know just just an
idea I'll leave them blank for now
because we probably won't do that today
yeah what was I going to do next going
to hook these up but yes I'm going to do
a tunnel above them so just give me a
minute while mine that out well we need
a new shovel so here we go 42 vision c4
and braking three great that's a good
one
oh yeah and check out what I got
I've been enchanting a few other things
and I got yeah I got another one best
pitch in the game and I got some shoes
another set here only feather falling
three though on that I thought I had
another pair I guess not so but yeah
this pick oh man okay so I dug out a
tunnel here we're going to hook up the
lighting it's really simple if I just
wanted them on I could just put levers
right on top of them but we want it
select it flicker kind of randomly and
to do that I think I'm just going to do
something like this where I have a block
torch and then redstone then on top of
that little put pressure plates
like so and then we're going to have
snowmen wandering around in here maybe
one or two and when they walk on the
pressure plate the light will go off for
a little while and I think it will be
cool you'll have a good effect I hope it
would be ideal if I could make that buzz
sound like the light bulb buzz sound you
know what I mean that would be really
cool alright so we're gonna hook these
up and a lot of people seem to be liking
the ultra hardcore series that's
excellent I'm glad everybody likes it
sore seems to like it anyway
we had a lot of fun doing that it's so
intense and I think people are really
picking up on that it's like every
decision you make in it is so important
every any little mistake could cost you
dearly or completely end you basically
because it's once you lose your health
it's so hard to get it back hi and what
I do here 1 2 3 4 1 2 3
why aren't they the same ok it's over
there oh right oh but yeah we that was a
ton of fun we're already talking about
maybe doing a season 4 we're thinking of
different ideas we could do it for it so
I think that's going to come out
eventually obviously after season 3 but
plans are being considered so hopefully
we'll have more in the future if you
enjoyed that series and what else is new
I tried streaming for the first time the
other day I'm just setting up my account
on Twitch and figuring out bit rates and
all that
fun stuff I have really bad internet I
found out like terrible minimal quality
is the best I can do
apparently I have about 400 to 500 I
think it's kill a bit upload per second
or something and I talked to hypnotised
about and he gets like 3000 or 3500 or
something crazy in comparison so yeah my
upload rates are not very good so 360
was the best I could do and oh well I
actually applied to become a twitch
partner now I found out there's a
special clause that if if you have over
a hundred thousand subscribers on
YouTube and over 15,000 views per video
you can pretty much again get instant
partnership or I hope I hope so anyway
we'll see what they say in a few days
but that would definitely encourage me
to stream more because I could make
money from it not that's the only reason
I would do it but that's an extra
incentive to it I really liked being
able to chat live with people like my
viewers a lot of fun so anyway I'll
finish this up and hopefully I put the
pressure plates all in the right places
okay I got it all wired here now all the
pressure plates are there got lights up
here no mobs should be spawning not that
that would be a bad thing necessarily
but just don't want the noise of them my
desk and I think we can put our snowmen
down so probably - I think - would be
good this one get out of here
yep go ahead go explore please yeah run
I'm a bad man
get out here go they're kind of going to
put block below you come on they don't
want to go mmm
oh yes okay get out of here will block
them in all right just leave that we'll
leave this open just for now in case we
have to come back up there's lights
I hear them pressing them I don't see
any flickering though oh there we go
I was kind of hoping I'd be a little bit
more noticeable we should get rid of
these torches oh I guess is kind of
noticeable went dark there get rid of
those yeah it kind of flickers it's nice
I like it good enough for me
we'll put redstone torches where we had
those other torches for looks like that
place is really coming together
maybe we'll get we have four at this
bottom row here maybe able to get rid of
that keep it at two like it should be
all right and okay yeah that's cool I
like it
um these dispenser things I don't know
this shouldn't be hard to wire I was
wondering if this would work if we do
redstone torch here that will only shoot
it out after we go off yeah what happens
if you put in loop another one over here
does it fire several times yeah it does
darn that would have been really simple
okay we'll all wire this and I'll be
back alright this is how I wired these
um under the pressure plate is redstone
dust that goes to this block here with
the redstone torch on it goes up to that
one that torch and then to that block to
the dispenser pretty simple I'll fill
that in
so you got to put speed potions and
those will have chess probably follow
them juice we need to restock it good
all right so those are done only thing
we got to do yet is the minecart thing
but we'll do that another day lights are
done here
this is pretty much done now this here
this is a special case now like for this
corridor we have the pumpkins lighting
it so we don't need overhead lights
necessarily but the mine shafts are
going to be running this direction right
so with this corridor it's also running
that direction and we won't be having
tunnels going this way you know so there
won't be pumpkins down here so we need
lighting overhead for these and I'll
probably put pumpkins they're going to
be a pain to place though because I
can't just put them there I have to
block underneath yeah I got plenty of
this stuff get a block underneath that
was a regular pumpkin darn it
there we go
remove it and it would look like that Oh
don't really want to waste glowstone on
it and torches when it be bright enough
um unless we lowered them and I don't
want to use torches if possible so yeah
anyway that's the mineshaft one thing
I'm thinking possibly I said I wasn't
going to extend the tree farm anymore
the donor tree farm so we need some new
way of showing respect to the donors
people have donated to my channel I had
I'm Way behind on on giving people a
credit they just they deserve so an idea
I had maybe is to give each donor one of
these shafts one of these tunnels have
their name beside it and then maybe I'll
keep track of what I get as I go through
it and I'll put how much coal lapis gold
iron whatever on record here - I don't
know like I said I just want to get
their name somewhere in my world and
that would be a really simple way of
doing it for a hundred by 100 square
liked it like I talked about that would
be 25 of these shafts so 25 this way 25
that way that would be 50 could get
quite a few names out that way
and it would be pretty a pretty simple
thing and that way wouldn't take a whole
lot of time for me to do something kind
of special for them because if I if I
take too long making unique things for
people kind of a problem I had before it
starts to take away from my time I can
use to make my LP episodes and stuff so
I know that wouldn't make people happy
either so I don't know let me know what
you think of that idea really happy with
this place so I think it looks awesome
and I'm going to have fun mining when I
finally do starts going to think about
the tracks I might do them yet I do have
quite a few tracks just sitting around
but I'm going to say goodbye thank you
for watching everybody
until next time