hello how's it going everybody welcome
back oh I was wondering how close they
were
don't die don't die don't die don't die
yes okay I almost died I was hoping it
was a regular Skelton uh all right today
is a wonderful day everybody it might
not seem that way after what just
happened but no look at this whoa golden
horse armor oh yeah this must be a new
fortress that I have not explored I was
out doing some courts hunting and oh
yeah nice let's go check this out there
might be more chests in my world I don't
have horse armor really I have it I had
one set an iron set of horse armor
that's it let's not go that way see I
think I came down the stairs no oh
another chest so this is one of the
things I've been lacking its horse armor
so let's see if we can try find a
diamond set on none in there that would
be amazing if we did all right
Oh another chest behind me there or did
we check this one no we didn't just a
saddle though we will take it so guys I
have a useful tip for you just in case
you don't know it's it's something I
didn't know for months and months and it
it really bothered me not knowing it
ever since we updated to this launcher
we currently use in Minecraft
whenever I would plug my headset in to
play minecraft her to record I mean I
would have to restart the game because
my sound drivers are sound whatever
didn't detect oh we got em already we
must have got this one too I didn't
detect the new playback device right so
I'd have to restart the game before her
to detect it so all you got to do is
press f3 s to reload the sound in
Minecraft so if you if you need it to
play in a new device just do that very
simple I feel like I explained that
terribly though oh man umm if you're not
getting sound through the proper thing
just did f3 yes that's that's the simple
version all right I just I'll keep
looking around probably head back soon
dead end over here diamond horse armor
please tell me there's a set here oh man
ok guys I got something to show you here
I'm distracted now though oh and it
might have got blown up so not too long
ago we got this alternate blocks feature
right so the blocks have a random
orientation well there is a 1 in 16
chance the same corner will line up
right next to each other like really
close so on netherrack it does this I
saw it on the ground sight is that a
ninja star
what on earth that's the pattern
netherrack does I'm kind of curious with
other blocks do when that happens well I
made it back your guys got tons of
courts and 55 levels for us to spin so
let's do that right now alright to do a
bit of enchanting there were two more
chests in that fortress none of them had
horse armor though sadly
but we did get two sets these are not
looking so good yeah these are really
not looking so good I'm breaking I just
will take that one did we try the
fishing rod I think we did I don't wait
maybe we didn't look at the see - okay
we'll just put it on this yeah big
mistake aqua affinity I'll take the risk
now that's so good protection for is
awesome that's all we got
protection three not so good I'll take
the feather falling though that's all we
got oh and braking perfect and
unbreaking perfect okay I think we're
just about out of levels I'll take a
look at the c3 oh wow that's perfect
right look at the c3 Lyra three on
breaking three I don't think I've ever
gotten
level three on all those before that was
pretty cool
efficiency for is great and one more
enchantment we can do let's do let's do
a pic now we won't do a pic that's
terrible
we'll take it alright so I want to check
something really quick here as well I
hear a slime jumping up and down if that
is a big slime I realized something the
other day we might be able to fix
something really old in our man cave
I'll now darn it there was a big slime
here before he must have despond is
there another one coming up oh there is
awesome so you know what I can do guys I
can name this guy and get him in one of
these minecarts there used to be a
minecart thing here that would pick them
up and then he's supposed to circle
around the tree farm here but it kept
breaking on us is he gonna come down but
if we name him he won't be spawn ever so
that is probably what we should try to
do I think I may have put something up
there to block them
oh now he's a stake in this time okay so
he should make his way up I'm gonna grab
a nametag or maybe we'll just test this
first I'm gonna test it first after I
destroy everything stupid dick all right
loss that give you the track back I
don't know if this works I kind of doubt
it will but we used to be able to pick
them up through the corner here oh it
does work then you would go in the
minecart and yeah he's going to go
around and around let's see if you'll do
a full cycle because I would like to get
maybe one or two of these guys doing
that just so we can have that feature
working again and then we'll just name
them we won't have to worry about it
breaking I can't keep up he's too fast
should touch him going around here can't
remember if it's set up for him to get
off or not or if he'll just keep going
around oh he keeps going around good
very good I have a nametag now and we
got another big slime to spawn eyes
having a hard time thinking of a name
for the slime and then I you know being
the nice guy in I thought of your family
and named it after someone close to you
so we're gonna call it a big momma
big momma mother of the slimes okay now
we just got to sneak our way through
all right big momma
don't worry oh man I was looking at this
- it actually looks like it's easy to
fix up what's wrong is this trapdoor
staying open too long when it opens so
if I just add a proper monostable
circuit to this it will probably work
again alright and for now we will just
manually trigger it's got big momma
woohoo double check there's no cart left
on the track or something dumb should
see or go by there yeah there she goes
let's see if we can catch her on the
other way
these trees are too dense I can't walk
through them all right you should be
coming around here comes Big Mama all
right we'll probably just do one and I
might fix that so that we can get more
on occasion when they spawn looks like
it's working though so that is good to
go once again so it's been a while since
I last checked the poppy farm it looks
like it is still working though hello
goodbye let's see what our town is that
oh wow okay that's pretty good one two
three just about four stacks of poppies
I guess I'll take this stuff to here
let's let's go check our chests this is
our nexus fund we are up to like ten
stacks of poppies if we want to put some
flowers around we are doing good so
that's nine plus seven right nine plus
seven 1664 well it's just it's three
stacks of hoppers plus a little bit
that's pretty good alright guys so for a
change we are going to do something
different today we're going to have a
real talk moments with etho new show
real talk with etho and i'm going to
build the nexus while I do it
kind of like story time some of you have
said you enjoy my stories and if if
you're not one of them I apologize in
advance for rambling alright so here we
go I realized that for after my intro
today I was a little bit hypocritical I
said today was going to be a wonderful
day well in all honesty in Minecraft
it's a wonderful day we got horse armor
that's awesome but in real life today I
woke up mad I woke up angry within the
first five seconds of my eyes opening I
rolled over looked at the time and I was
not happy with what I saw no now before
I tell you exactly why that is
let me tell you a few things first so I
am a night person I've always been a
night person can't control it it's just
the way I am and some some people are
morning people you know you you go to
bed early you get up early you you go to
are you you wake up in the morning and
you're you're ready to go you're you're
happy you get up and do your stretch
with a big smile and you're ready to
take on the world I love you
I envy you type of people so much you
have no idea I wish I could be you but
I'm not I'm a night person I hate going
to bed at nights and I hate getting up
in the morning there are two very bad
things
so you morning people though usually a
lot of you seem to have a problem like
in the morning you feel great everything
is good in the world nighttime comes
around and you have no control over your
tiredness you you just can't keep your
eyes open at a certain point and you
have to go to bed or you'll you can't
think you can't do anything creative
anymore so you just sit down and watch
TV and probably fall asleep watching TV
at night so there's that I have the
opposite problem kind of in the morning
I feel terrible absolutely terrible
doesn't matter how much sleep I debts I
can get a full eight hours I can get
even more than that I will feel terrible
in the morning regardless and I'm losing
my train of thought I started thinking
about what I have to do next year and
then that's it story gone but yeah I
feel terrible in the mornings I always
have a groggy voice and I'm not happy
I can't think creatively or anything I'm
not motivated to move
it's just bad all around right let's
just make sure we do this right before I
start it you've got to get these quartz
pillars up okay so
one above the piston gotcha all right
well anyway nighttime comes around like
I feel terrible in the morning around
afternoon I start feeling normal
but evening comes around and I feel
great all of a sudden especially around
like 9 o'clock
that's my prime time I'm feeling the
most creative thinking freely and even
at like late hours I don't actually ever
get tired like I don't have that feeling
of tiredness I can stay up till 7 a.m.
and that's when I start getting tired
one morning rolls around again and I can
stay up all day all night all day and
then the next like the next day I feel
terrible because I pulled an all-nighter
right but then night time rolls around
and I feel great again it's the weirdest
thing something about that time it's
just I don't know so where am I going
with this
let me think ok so I have tried on many
occasions to become a morning person and
to give you a reference I I'm in the
habit of going to bed at like 4 a.m.
every night and waking up after noon
it's terrible it would be fine like I do
I do YouTube stuff doesn't matter what
time I wake up really but the rest of
the world you function at as morning
people
you know stuff opens at 9:00 if I ever
want to do stuff with family or friends
I have to get up early or usually so I'm
stuck for good here
there we go and on weekends actually
that's the day I usually do stuff with
people I have to get up at 9:00 on
Saturday and Sunday generally and I am a
wreck because I go to bed at 4:00 and I
do terrible on weekends you might notice
I usually don't have a video one day on
the weekend because I can't think I just
kill myself waking up so early
so I've tried to get out of this cycle
I've tried pulling all-nighters and then
going to bed early the next day like it
like 10:00 p.m. doesn't work doesn't
work I still end up waking up in the
afternoon I sleep for 12 hours or
whatever so just this week in fact I
tried something different something a
little bit more sane well it's not more
saying it's more terrible actually
I have tried staying up for extra hours
every day and sleeping one extra hour
every day for a week and that involves
like waking up at at like midnight and
4:00 a.m. and you know all these crazy
times but slowly little by little I've
been making my way so that I went to bed
at 10 p.m. and I'm not super chilled
because I'm getting the proper amount of
sleep and I went to bed at 10 p.m.
yesterday
so if I got eight hours of sleep I would
wake up at 6 a.m. if I got 10 hours of
sleep I would wake up at 10 a.m. or you
know even 12 hours not that I would need
12 hours because I've been sleeping well
I would wake up it you know 12 either
way it should be an improvement and then
that would fix my sleeping problem right
nope nope that's not what happened I
looked at my clock I woke up at 2:00
p.m. I slept for 16 hours last night
woke up with a headache felt terrible
it's like no no winning my whole plan
down the drain and I don't know what to
do I'm starting to think I have a
sleeping disorder of some sort but I'm
not sure it's pretty strange anyway I
thought I would just share that story
time with etho if you've gone something
if you've gone through something similar
to this let me know if you found a way
to fix it because I'm running out of
ideas honestly I can't just go to bed
early by the way like if I try I can't
fall
sleep I'll just toss and turn for 3-4
hours until the normal time I go to bed
and I just I wake up the next day
feeling even worse and if I went to bed
late and I've tried many times to go to
bed early it just doesn't work for me so
I don't know what to do oh where did he
just come from don't panic guys we have
a situation here
we might might have just found one of
the guys Oh magic carp is back
bubbles are they all here again now
we're missing one we're missing blue
piece where did blue pee go guys
they are like just appearing out of
nowhere not there he's not there okay so
he probably didn't go through the lab
I'm guessing he either went down here or
down here can't go up there oh
lava not so good hey that's my mule what
are you doing here alright I'll take you
did blue pee for you
I wonder he might be in these caves or
he might be dead not good guys not good
could not find blue P and now Big Momma
is gone too which I don't understand
there's nowhere for the slime to
suffocate I don't understand what could
have happened something strange is going
on
minecarts not on the track that I can
see should not have returned
oh all four of them are there
that is so weird so it either died it
died somehow right
all right well I don't really want to
get another Big Mama there until we
figure out why the last one died so
we'll just leave that for today now
we're going to do a little bit work on
the library and that'll probably be it
for today I've decided to try oak wood
here after all we're going to go with
oak for the windows and then light gray
stained glass not the green stuff green
stuff looks weird
we don't want weird right let's go for
this okay so I think that's pretty good
right I was originally going to put
brick there but I decided to go with the
oak just so that we wouldn't introduce
another block type into the mix and I
didn't want to feel the need to make the
outside of the building out of brick
because that would not be fun collecting
brick for a building this size next up
here trying to decide what to do in
these spots my axe broke today by the
way actually very sad about that we did
all that enchanting and that's what I
should have made was the new axe earlier
today oh well one option is we could do
a slime block launcher to get up to the
second floor or we could do a staircase
right now we have no way of getting up
here so I thought the middle here would
be a good thing or a good place to go up
if we did let's not build out of wood
material if we did a staircase how would
this layout we got to get up to how high
at least up to here alright that is this
height that would be four blocks that
might be doable actually
um if we did a slime block launcher
though we could make it really compact I
decided let's go for a staircase here
after all so it lays out pretty good we
only need four steps to get up to this
level and this parts a little bit higher
so we would have another staircase here
this is only three steps and that's
that's pretty good and compact this this
library is very fancy right
sophisticated and elegant classy we
don't want to taint it with the slime
block launcher we got to keep that theme
going right sure why not
all right let's do it like this instead
okay so we'll have bookcases on this
side the side we have a few here and
then a beam running across and we'll
throw down some carpets so I saw
something very exciting guys two things
actually one Mojang is releasing a new
game a new game with uh they're working
with tails tail so how you say it I
forget their company name exactly the
point-and-click adventure games though
so they got that going and Jeb also
tweeted that they are planning on
getting into snapshots again starting
January and I'm very happy about that um
I was pretty concerned when Microsoft
took over because there hasn't really
been much in terms of communication and
like what's going on not a lot of
updates and my biggest fear was that
they weren't gonna update the game
anymore
so glad to see some response coming out
of that and things are on hopefully
we'll get on the roll again like they
were before
all right everybody well it is that time
once again it is time for you to confess
now it's common time but I know you did
it the bathroom then some
like that before you went in all right
here we go says thanks for all the hard
work time efforts and effort you put
into these episodes they always turn out
amazing for someone like me with no life
oh it makes my life a lot better smiley
face Oh super smiley face I really do
appreciate that your videos are
family-friendly you are one of the only
minecraft YouTube gamers that I
personally find entertaining while still
keeping 100% clean contents never stop
making videos you are the best seriously
yeah yeah I'm the best don't you forget
it
me no I felt a little weird fitting this
comment but it had like 800 up votes and
60 replies or something crazy that is
probably the most I've ever seen on
someone's comments not counting mine
obviously but yeah I thought that was I
thought it was one I had to pick because
of that Thank You Cassandra and
everybody else that's that replied and
that feels the same way I guess I really
appreciate all the support I gets and it
makes me feel good when I see stuff like
that um I try my best
alright I'm getting all lovey gushy here
let's do our pick before we end this
this isn't a pic it's a an axe I knew
that I also messed up earlier this
episode when I was saying what time I
woke up and yeah whatever you've
corrected me on it already probably but
I noticed it later um no we can't
enchant with that there we go new tree
toes choppa right here tree toes chopper
the last one that's silk touch which is
probably better but this will be fine
yeah cool all right guys have yourselves
a wonderful day for real the date might
they didn't turn out that bad actually
just had a bad bad wake up hope you
enjoy your day though hope you enjoyed
the episode thank you for watching see
you later
bye-bye