[Music]
oh our dear friend
we're gonna miss you but don't worry we
will remember you for generations to
come
and shall always appreciate what you've
done for us
say goodbye everybody he's doing this
for your entertainment
uh totally his will i'm not forcing him
to do this either
he could hop out anytime he wants
but what's he gonna do
oh yes
sorry buddy
all right let's go catch it parkour
oh no
oh what the duplicated tnt somehow
yeah i did i must have why wouldn't it
blow up if it was
laying on the ground that's weird
so some of you might remember this
tunnel uh did i get another one
i think i got another one i just saw
dude i'm getting so many duplicate tnt
what the heck
i'll take them but um
yeah there's a few glitches with tnt at
the moment oh
but yeah some of you might remember this
tunnel
actually you know i'm to pick up this
stuff before we lose it because i'm
almost full
or actually let's just test it real
quick
yeah some of you might remember this
tunnel originally i made it as a way to
go from
my man cave to the stronghold
but really i built this before i did the
nether portal stuff and now
this doesn't really have as much use
anymore
let's grab some of this not too much i
have plenty of cobble
uh then i thought hey you know what i
could still use it as a way of
transporting villagers and
and moving lots of items like with
storage minecarts at a time
um other animals you know
but now we also have uh ender chests
and we can are going to be able to move
animals and villagers through
nether portals as well so this really
isn't going to have
much point to it i'm mostly just
finishing it
so it's not left half complete
and i might use it a little bit i don't
know um
but i'm mostly i'm also doing this just
because i love to blow stuff
up i'm doing a lot of tnt
back
oh there's another one that just blew up
whoa and we're here
all the way to the stronghold sweet so
it comes out to
just over this part
where i was uh removing all the mossy
brick
and
then see the ice there that's from the
storage room we're building
up in here so yeah i'm gonna go pick up
that stuff and i'll get back to you guys
oh yeah and here is another glitch i
found with the tnt the other day
it kills me to do this but
put it down this is silk touch
silk touch picks if you hit it with a
regular one
it's fine if you hit it with a silk
touch
tool it does this
oh it's so sad
alright so i wasn't really planning on
finishing this tunnel today
but uh yeah i did i just
got into the groove so let's check it
out i was actually i got into some
major editing and this was a nice
project to do while
uh in between the editing because that
can take a few hours sometimes
and yeah got it all done there is
actually a lot to it
if i was to redo it though i would make
it a little less plain but it's okay
just the way it is notice how the grass
keeps changing too
as we go through the biomes pass through
several different biomes
um but yeah there's a lot to it because
it's a five by five tunnel and then you
gotta fill in all this
have to get all this wood thousands and
thousands of planks
um each one of these has a pumpkin above
which is
a pain to place all the walls i've
converted to smooth stone
made it clean and it's
it's just a really long distance
oh yeah and the power rails are spaced
every eight blocks so if we do send an
empty cart or storage mine carts it will
keep going
wow that's a long ways mountain biome
but yeah we're gonna head up back over
to the nether today
and do some work there and that's it
and so i'll see you guys there
and welcome back to the nether hub
uh so reactions were pretty good about
this thing last episode most people seem
to like it
and the colors and everything which i'm
glad because i really like it too
um there was a little bit of confusion
with some people
thinking it was done this portal skin
and they were talking about the levers
sticking out and all that
uh no it's not quite done
uh it's gonna connect to the ceiling and
kind of get wider as it gets near the
top and then
make like a donut shape in here ideally
so you won't see the levers and we might
get rid of these columns i'm not sure
yet
people wanted me to put fences or iron
bars here
which we might do although i'm not
really excited about introducing extra
colors but we might do it
so we're gonna work on this some more
we're gonna start
not not this not the portal we're gonna
work on the actual uh selector station
thing
uh but first we need more glowstone so i
am not
going to go on a glowstone hunt i got my
care package all ready here
and then some it looks like
oh all right i packed too much
uh but yeah i'm gonna go got silk touch
oh you know what i forgot is an
ender chest i guess we're gonna snag
this one too
yeah we'll just snake this put glowstone
in it as we get it
so we don't lose it if something bad
happens and this is my first time
trying out these tools i'm going to use
leaves
for getting up and down
if the gas shoots it it'll burn so i can
even potentially leave it behind if i
don't feel like removing it
um but yeah i might do a montage
or i might just skip this so see you
guys in a little bit
oh no no no oh you jerk
dang it's directing it all
who
not too shabby we got one two three four
five six seven eight
nine ten eleven and a half stacks of
glowstone from that trip
back to business here we're gonna
enchant a shovel
going through these things quickly
a little bit low but it'll do
all right let's head on over to the
nether
oh that was pro um i'm going to show you
the plan for the selection panel i saw a
really cool design for one
that we're gonna use
let's see get that going we'll need
these
and some stone brick
so we'll just set up uh an example of it
and get an idea of the size and all that
too
and then we will
build it into place so maybe let's just
build it
over here
okay it's going to be a little tough
with the half slabs
um
let's see
you know what i'm going to get rid of
the half slabs just so we can get down a
little lower
also somebody suggested i should put ice
under this and i didn't even think of
that that's uh that's a pretty good idea
all right let's do like this
i'm going by memory hopefully i can
remember it exactly correctly
otherwise it's not going to work
um
do this okay so first of all we need
buttons we need
five buttons
go over here each of these will be
represent a
selection of places to go destinations
and
nice spots under that we have the wire
and then
i think i can just fill this all in
okay then it's it goes repeater
and piston
that okay then i think uh
oh yeah above the buttons there's also
redstone torches
and then wait maybe not
something seems strange
all right i'm gonna check i'm gonna
check it one more time and then we'll
continue
no that was uh that was right um i got a
little confused i thought for some
reason the repeaters were supposed to go
the other way
put this here i thought the repeaters
are supposed to go this way for some
reason but no
they they uh attached to the torches
like that all right
then these blocks will come up
and then above that we have more pistons
with more blocks which will extend
to above the torches and then the power
will go from the torches to
glowstone lamps lamps just lamps
not closed stone lamps like that
all right so that's that's our selector
panel here it's a very cool design i'm
glad i
i saw it tried to figure out who made it
originally and
uh let's just say that was not an easy
task
i found a few youtube videos of it and
then somebody linked it all the way back
to
a thread on the minecraft forums and i
went there
and the image the guy
showing it wasn't there so i couldn't
confirm if he was the first or not so
somebody made it wasn't me and there's
probably a lot of
youtube videos of it so
yeah so this is pretty cool
so it's inverse the one that's selected
is unlit and the ones that aren't
selected are lit
and you can attach as many of these as
you want
keeping in mind the 15 block limit of
redstone
so yeah that's what we're going to use
and i think i'm going to let's see
stairs yeah let's try make it look a
little bit more sleek
i'm going to have stairs go up like this
and stairs below
like that
that's pretty cool very snazzy
and then the outputs are on the back
here um
basically when it goes through the
repeater here we need to
have a block behind her that with
another repeater whatever on top
to catch it
and then branch off from that
actually no we need uh we need to invert
the signal too
but yeah basically that's what we're
gonna do uh we're gonna actually have
two of those
of these though and link them together
uh just five buttons on each for a total
of ten
so we'll have one on the left and one on
the right
and then i'm going to put a mine cart in
between them
so that when we're in the mine cart
we'll be able to
reach all the buttons five here and then
five
over here so
that's the plan and i'm going to start
hollowing out a space
for our area here and we will get to
building
the official one
okay i think we are ready to go here um
since there's a lot of wiring involved i
want a little bit of a buffer before we
get to the selector
panels so we are going to
oh boy troubles already
it's okay i have a good feeling about
this
um let's just fill this in a bit
actually you know what we should do just
make an arch to begin with to get an
idea of how big of an
opening we want here um
you can either do it here
three wide opening or
go for five wide
let's try to do the five wide nice nice
and open
[Music]
needs to go up a bit more
yeah um maybe one more block
[Music]
i love this pick
you just feel so powerful when you're in
the nether all right um maybe let's try
up to here
[Music]
how's that look yeah it's a good size
and let's make it rounded
very good i like that okay then
i want a 3x3 thing
so let's try
yeah oh yeah that works perfect okay
three by three
same on this side
okay so that's going to be our buffer
just this little extra
3x3 edition then
we will put our selector panel here
and i want the buttons at eye level
um how's that gonna work
i guess the stairs on the ground then
buttons then stairs above
okay
um maybe let's go down
one block too that would be cool uh that
way we'll
we'll sort of look down at a nice open
room
and do do it like
i'm not really sure i could do that
[Music]
that and we'll just worry about the
front first of all we want it to look
good
then we can do the wiring afterward
since we already know what we're doing
uh actually let's let's start getting
some wool involved here
now some people said i should try to get
other colors of wool
in um
i do really like the purple but if we do
other colors
each of these because we got to build
four of these things and each one of
these would have to be a different color
i think
i guess it doesn't matter
all right how's it going to look
oh that's cool so our buttons will go on
that
okay
uh oh yeah let's let's change this to
stairs
all right yeah that's that goes good
then it kind of goes with this
and then we'll have the same over here
liking it um
then another column like that
okay and then we can do a floor whatever
we want we need it to be a full block at
the floor because we got to put minecart
tracks on it and stuff um
and let's change this to the wool color
too
and you know i want to put some
more lighting in here too let's put some
lamps down
here
i'll power these once i stop recording
okay we've got something going here
i'll i'm gonna mirror it to this side
and i'll get back to you
all right it's looking pretty good so
far i'm happy with it
i think the next thing
should work on is the tunnel so i've
decided already i want my rail tunnels
to be a 3x3
by default so if we center it
it would be over there
so i think let's just try
shape that out and see how that goes
[Music]
oh yeah and also i put purple wall on
the floor and i like that too
so it goes from the circle to out into
here
okay there's our tunnel
and yeah i'll encase all this with stone
brick later so it's gas proof
uh actually these uh these areas here
might be good for a door
to get to the wiring in that too behind
there
so that could be good
all right
so yeah let's work on the ceiling now
uh let yeah so we got these two columns
one there and one there let's do the
arch on the second one
too to be the same it would be
over here
i'm not sure if that will work
and let's uh let's mirror the floor
that
and that's and let's
try purple wool maybe a 3x3 and
see how that goes
very nice um
yeah that's that's good uh it'll be
brighter in here because these will be
on
right
let's do this over here
sandstone sides with purple middle and
we're going to go
over this later and fine-tune some
details probably
let's see how this goes it's all purple
all right and then we'll probably do the
same on ceiling
um
what if we do this
yeah this is looking good i'm happy
very happy
purple
and yeah we may change it to a different
color but for now i think purple's
what we'll just use
i actually really like the purple
that's okay now somehow we have to
connect this parts
um let's do this here too
the stairs
yeah i like that more very cool
all right um
let's go up
that go up
and let's just see what this looks like
yeah that's pretty cool i like it
um i'm gonna go through here
with a little bit of finer detail while
not recording and
maybe change a few things and also i'm
going to hook up the redstone
wiring for both of the panels and then
we got to link them together
basically we just have to attach this
wire on both of them together
in a way that they won't create an
infinite loop where
or clock or something down like that so
we'll have to be careful
oh yeah check it out it's all done
it's all wired
got it all in here and i even found a
very easy way
of hooking them together i i didn't
think they would be
within 15 bucks but they are so we just
need to run a wire
from one side to the other so
let's count it one two three
four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven 12 13
14. i sound that right one two three
four
wait 1 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12
13 14 15 15. so it just
barely reaches and we can do this
because these are stairs so we can run a
wire
through it like that which is very good
so let's fire it up
when we press one button all the lights
should come on
except for one
very cool so that's our selector panel
so if we push this one
the lights all turn on on that side even
it's much brighter in here with that lit
up
um so this is how i did the corners this
one seems to be having a lighting glitch
which i'll have to fix
um but yeah i think it's pretty good
so i'm not sure if i should continue
this
theme through the tunnel or if we should
transition to something else
um i'm
yeah i'm not really sure excuse me
what i'm going to do with the tunnel
itself if we do sandstone and purple we
need to line it so it's going to be a
lot of extra work
because instead of like a five by five
thing we gotta make a five by five plus
a seven by seven
it's a lot of blocks to do tunnels that
way
[Music]
very cool okay oh yeah so
then as we figure out our destinations
and wire them
up we will have these signs which we'll
write the names on
i think we'll put them here
[Music]
and then also this is how i'm going to
do the minecart stuff so
this is the center right here um
so i want a power rail here
and then another one there
and the track will go this way
like that minecart will sit there so
this is what's going to look like just
like this we hop in the mine carts
select our destination when we hit the
button
it will send power to the power rail
below and also
oh okay i gotta move that to
the other side
that shouldn't be a problem see i went
this way i can go this way though no
problem
uh but below here
we're gonna have a piston that comes up
i don't have any pistons no
dang all right
let's see where did i put them there we
go
and because we need a block behind the
minecart for it to launch
so that's what this is all about
all right so when we push a button power
rail will
power and also that block will come up
so it'll send the minecart off with us
in it
and then on the return we gotta make the
minecart to go
over a detector rail
which will make the piston come up to
stop it
and then it'll go down after a few
seconds or whatever
but it won't light up this power rail so
if it does it'll just send it back again
so we want it to stop and that's what
i'm planning
and then with these selector panels
we're going to hook them up to track
junctions
and that's how we will control
where the minecart goes
and that is that
yeah i like that a lot so
i think that's about all we're gonna do
with with this today
um in this main room i'll probably have
sandstone walls
with maybe lines of purple will going up
every
so often like maybe even over here
which will connect to the ceiling it's
going to start sloping this way
um and then i would like another purple
ring at the top
somewhere close to the outside
and somebody mentioned a cool idea of
having lamps
in a circle as well and have a minecart
going around
so that you can see the light going
around and around that would be cool
um but yeah that's all we're doing for
today thank you for watching everybody
let's go read some comments and call it
an
end oh once again
just one comment for today it's my last
book um
it's a short one too etho when did you
build a house on top of the mountain
i don't really know what you're talking
about i've never built
no house on no mountain you must be
mistaken
uh so sorry i couldn't answer your
question okay
take care guys bye bye
[Music]