hello what's up everybody this is Ito
welcome back guys to another one of our
wonderful 20 or 30 minutes together
doing things together welcome back to
another episode how are you guys doing
today I have been busy working on our
wheatfields here I seems like a lot of
you guys really like this biome
enhancement idea we built the wheat
field like this lake here the tractor
the amazing tractor last time and we had
a bunch of plants for other things too
but we just never got around to it um
but yeah looking at the comments you
guys liked it I'm happy about that
because I I do a lot of like planning
and resource gathering and doing like
these little things that have no actual
uh oh I'm killing the wheat on the
source no okay we just learnt something
don't I killed another one don't ride
the horse on the wheat field I didn't
run on it no problem and doesn't uproot
them anyway so totally lost my train of
thought there what was I saying great
now I have to watch my video back to
figure it out okay so like I was trying
to say I can spend quite a bit of time
in my episodes like planning something
resource gathering you know we'll spend
or I'll spend hours planning out a
redstone project we do and and it's cool
and everything like nothing wrong with
it
but I tend to do that stuff a lot and in
the end of it in our world here we don't
really like I put the redstone stuff
behind walls you don't really see it
ever
it doesn't affect our world visually so
it's cool to do something on it on a big
scale like this it's not exactly
complicated to plant a wheat field but
it's you know kind of nice to look at
you know anyway so one of the big
suggestions was that I build a windmill
so that's what we're going to do today
to start out with here I don't want to
spend the whole episode here doing this
kind of stuff but just for a little bit
I actually spent a good hour designing
this in creative and I'm pretty happy
with the outcome guys you're gonna see
this and you're gonna be like no way
etho you did not build that that you
copied that no honestly I I figured this
out on my own and I'm happy with it
oops yeah we're going to build it maybe
here most likely here because this is
where I'm placing it I've been trying to
teach myself how to build better in this
game for a long time like like years I
don't do a lot of building I've built
very few houses in this game and that
kind of stuff um but I'm trying to get
better it's one of those things like
some people say they're not good at
building and I said this before it's
it's not something you usually are just
good at right away it takes practice
experience much like redstone the more
you do it the easier becomes so yeah
anyway so this is the start of my
windmill and you're thinking yes II
thought you failed already it's it's
plain it's boring it's a circle cylinder
thing it's not going to be great you
will see just give me a moment here I'm
going to build this up a little bit and
then we'll start adding the details okay
so I think what we'll do here guys we'll
try to build a little of this together
just to show you how to start it in case
you want to make something similar and
then I'll try to talk to while I do this
it's going to be tough though
and then I'll try to finish the rest of
it off camera because it I'm guessing
it's going to take me at least an hour
to build this whole thing it's pretty
complicated
and I can't just do it off of memory so
let's see first off
um I want to know what you guys think
about the style a lot of you have been
wondering why I haven't been working on
the amplified bass it's because for one
thing we've been distracted by other
projects but also like I tried out that
building style there I was trying to
make the ruins and not a lot of people
liked what I did there and I don't want
to build something up that I don't like
her that you guys don't like so until I
find a new building style
I wasn't really sure what to do there
but I do like I like this one here so if
you guys like this let me know and then
this is probably what we'll do at the
amplified terrain um I pretty much got
this whole thing designed except for the
interior and I didn't figure out how to
do the roof yet big surprise you guys
know how much I love building roofs oh
not heard of creeper we're good
everything's fine let's see I think we
got to then do it here oh this is spruce
have I been building with spruce I have
man another reason I like building
off-camera actually I worked out okay I
had to go chop down some more dark oak
trees anyway but this should be enough
to finish a project now let's see let's
grab this this and that and and that and
everything so guys I have some pretty
exciting news I've been wondering if I
should tell you because you might expect
more from me but recently I have
upgraded my internet hah
that is right I went from a point eight
upload to a point or now not a point at
two point six upload so it's like three
times quicker which is awesome
loving it downloads way quicker to like
four or five times quicker and now I
know what you guys feel like like what
it's like to have good internet it's
nice it's really really nice
loving it um
now keep in mind though a lot of you
think that the reason I only put up one
video a day on average is because that
was this right yeah that's right of
course it's right Who am I kidding I
know what I'm doing
the thing is though the reason the
reason there's only one video per day
usually is kind of because of the upload
speed but also because I spend a lot of
time on each video and that hasn't
really changed so I don't know if you're
really going to get any more um now that
being said there are times when for
example the upload fails and then if
that happens I pretty much can't upload
it that day again I have to wait for the
next day so then you miss a video
for that day so if that happens there's
a good chance I'll be able to actually
get it up the day even though it failed
so that's cool um what else what else
yeah anyway I have too many series that
take too much time like these let's play
series are are tough where I'm actually
trying to create things takes a long
long time right now probably the one
that takes the most time is mine crack
for whatever reason I don't know I just
find that one the most difficult then my
single-player um those two I obviously
spend the most time in though and they
get the most views so that's good then
probably Terra Firma craft that started
out as a really easy series three chord
but as I've developed or progressed in
it it's taking more and more time um I'm
not quite ready to give that series up
though I'm still having fun with it and
then crash landing is a new one I start
recently and that goes really quick
that's an easy one
because I'm pretty much recording
straight gameplay but I don't know so
don't expect any extra videos we are
about eight minutes in or so so I'm
going to try finish yourself off camera
and then all I'll show it to you and and
then we'll move on to some other stuff
Oh No let they work oh yes it's done
guys I finished it the windmill is
complete Oh take a while there's a lot
of blocks to it but I think it took over
an hour actually to just to build it
even though I had it designed pretty
much entirely I did finish the roof this
time though which is good so I had a lot
of fun making this I have never made a
windmill in this game before ah
why couldn't I see him I knew he was
there I couldn't see him though um yeah
I've never made a windmill before I've
always had trouble like mixing stone and
wood together in builds so I decided to
try it again though and I think I got it
okay I find it hard to get the right
proportion like either I used too much
wood too much stone maybe used a little
too much wood I think it's okay but yeah
that's my windmill lots of details I
might have gone a little too busy with
it I'm not sure and there's some things
I think are definitely incorrect about
it like I have these slime block things
over here you're not really supposed to
have focus points in areas you don't
want people looking which is kind of
what this is I should maybe change it to
a stone block or something I don't know
Oh tell you what I'm gonna stoop to date
here you stole my block alright
everybody so this is what it looks like
in the daytime keep following these
stupid water pools he put lily pads over
them or something when I made this I
think I made the blade on it pretty much
first and from that I was able to tell
how big I need to make the building and
the general shape of it then I decide to
do these entrance things and then I
think I did these
canoes and start connecting the top with
the bottom and just adding details like
fences and stuff
try add more 3d depth to the building
and what not is kind of the way I did it
I did cheap out a little bit I made
three of the sides identical these three
with the balcony usually if you want
your stuff to look more interesting you
want more variation with it but I only
have so much time and then the side with
the wind Neal is slightly different
because it's got this like indent thing
that the the blade goes into instead of
a balcony there
I got hidden lighting in a few places
seems to do the trick pretty good look I
think it looked pretty good at nighttime
anyway that glowstone also lights up the
bottom here if we go inside haven't done
the interior yet entirely sure what to
do about it
what I would like to do with this
building I did kind of make it for the
looks but it's going to have a function
to hopefully I want to get a farmer
villager in here and then if you like
come out during the day and harvest the
wheat and replant it and that would be
pretty cool if we can keep them alive
anyway so if if we do that might try to
make away from him to get up to the
second floor I don't know it might be
tricky I think it would be really
awesome if we had a villager on the
second floor too and they would like
walk out during the day and stand on
these balconies got a fence gate here
more lighting let's see can we get on
the roof I don't think we can now we can
aha
let's see didn't really know what to do
it with the roof so I just made like a
cage almost yes I don't know I might put
a villager in here but anyways I'm going
to take a little break from the
windmills stuff there and we're gonna do
some speed mining oh yes gotta love to
speed mining still trying to collect
redstone and other stuff
for the nexus project that I'm doing it
little by little here it's gonna take a
long time to collect everything if I try
to do it all at once it's gonna kill me
so just little by little I'm I'm doing
it here hopefully get at least five or
six stacks of this stuff okay so I'm
probably done speed mining for today
this is what we got not too bad one two
three four five six seven eight stacks
pretty much I mined out like a 50 by 50
area pretty much everything within the
beacon range on this bottom level here I
don't think I'm going to do speed mining
on the lower level anymore I keep
hitting these lava pockets and they just
slow the whole thing down a ton it's
really annoying when you hit one of
these and you can see there's a lot of
them at least in this area but yeah that
it's a look gets us a little closer to
our goal so right now I am playing the
waiting game he's doing the creepy walk
which is good that's right dude the
creepy walk
I want a farmer villager for the
windmill and reject it where are you
going
there so painful waiting for these guys
to make make the baby villagers oh oh
come on he's got hearts two hearts ah no
he's looking at the wrong guy Alan is a
stupid purple one darn it you could have
been the world's greatest farmer but now
you had to be born a librarian with your
fancy lab coats and and unibrow you make
me sick look at you you're nothing but a
waste of space you contribute nothing to
society you knew we needed a farmer but
now you wanted to be a butcher alright
so I am tired of waiting it's not
happening
being a farmer I did unlock a
interesting trade not that one that is
kind of good but expensive is it you I
think the one guy yelled at earlier was
actually pretty good he is a looting
three four forty three it's on the
expensive side but that is a really nice
tree to have uh-huh yeah so we're going
to kidnap a villager farmer villager
from the other village that way I don't
have to wait anymore hmm
I think that's our guy let's check very
delicately let's not scare him now it's
a Fletcher
what are you Shepherd we need a farmer
oh no he's lost he saw us run this is
our guy oh but I watched him alright guy
over the fence here we go you are about
to start your new life today so the
tough part is getting them away from the
village because they try to run back
tried to build the windmill far enough
away that they won't try to get back
hopefully he'll see it as a new village
this is like cattle herding or something
oh no he's free it's good he got trapped
on the block this horse is surprisingly
slow oh and it broke no keep seeing
trapped there that's good okay let's try
to get him really far with one oh no he
got free come on guy you can have the
place all to yourself now
come on he's been working all right
horse you're too slow why are you so
slow ah my last fishing rod - I gotta go
make more okay guy I know you hear a
zombie I would be scared if I were you
too
but please don't run please go inside
this is a great place you're gonna love
it
where is that zombie okay you're free to
leave soon I just have to check the
place out sounds like he's over here oh
yes yes yes
got him yeah I have some dark spots it
turns out I thought this was filled
solid I guess not
we can make this top floor bigger then
which is good I guess but I'll just
light it up for now so we're gonna let
this guy free and we'll see what happens
this is technically a proper house like
it counts as a house so he might stay
which is what I'm hoping all right whoa
whoa just want to put this block back
where does it go
over here good all right guy you can
choose to stay or you can choose to
leave if you leave bad things will
happen to you and he's gone all right
let's see how far he wanders from the
house I'm hoping it's counted as a
village right now and he'll run inside
at night so far good he's planting the
crops that's awesome
exactly what I wanted
he's so methodical as he does it to
perfectly straight line he pauses after
each one looks down mm-hmm oh man you
see all that land out there that's yours
it's all yours
my gift to you just don't die don't run
away we have an understanding I think
he's going to stay I'm going to watch
him for a bit if this does work I'm
gonna have to put a fence around this so
he doesn't get killed okay here we go
it's just turning night our friend here
is enjoying the evening cool breeze on
his patio is he going to go inside we
shall find out probably time to go
inside guy you might want to go inside
I'm pretty sure like all this farmland
won't spawn mobs so if we could put a
fence around at all and make sure
there's no like dirt patches anywhere
should be pretty safe okay guy come on
there we go you were having me worried
um so until I get the fence so I'm going
to lock them in and I'm a trial it up
there as well so you guys were telling
me if I spam right-click we can actually
name them so I'm gonna try that I don't
know if it's gonna work doesn't look too
good there might be a specific way of
doing it I don't know I'm trying really
hard though or draft a little shift here
let me try hold shift
now I don't think it's going to work
guys come on all right everybody that's
gonna do it for today but I got do
comments picked outs first one says what
if you build the storage room half
underground and half above-ground like
build it in a mountain and have the
entrance be above ground or underground
and make it go underground something
like that okay I got a little lost there
I asked last episode if I should build
the Nexus above ground or underground I
like the idea of doing it a little bit
of both
I think the majority of you actually
said build it underground which
surprised me to be honest but yeah I
think we'll do it kind of underground
mostly underground but maybe some above
ground as well
anyway second comment Keith oh will you
ever I plan to
I'm going to do it I'm not quite ready
but I will I will sometime sometime soon
I hope all right
thank you for watching everybody I'll
see you in the next one take care bye
bye