hello everyone this is etho how are you
guys doing today I hope you said good
it's gonna be really awkward if you
didn't say good I'm doing excellent
doing nobody you know I see it guys I
see it in the comments you you always
tell me I'm a bad actor and you know
what that's why I punish you with it
sweet sweet revenge oh yeah no that's
why we keep that that's why we keep the
acting to a minimum around here okay so
I'll tell you what happened yesterday I
tried recording an episode of us
finishing up the lab here and we had to
add a few things which we'll check out
in just a second but the episode didn't
really turn out too good
it wasn't bad but was kind of NIC kind
of boring so I decided to scrap it and
instead of us like slowly building this
and running running into millions of
problems and me getting frustrated we're
just gonna check out what we built
yesterday in the episode I never air I
only had like 10 mins recorded or
something bit me so much but what we had
left to do with the lab here is we were
gonna make it so instead of having water
bottles in these chests and had like
having a nether wart at the start of
each of these brewing chains and then
going to sugar redstone or another word
spider eyes gunpowder all that we
skipped a step of adding the nether wart
and instead we start with awkward
potions here but then we got to
distribute those aquaporins we brew them
over there and we got to send them to
all these starter chests so like here
let's chests here that one there that
one there there's eight to drop off
zones we have to send awkward potions to
so that's
that's what the episode was about we
were building a minecart system to to
move them around and I think I think the
lab is done now you just have to test it
out I haven't tested it to see if it
works but let's go check some things out
so kind of finished up this area bits
didn't really know what to do with this
wall we have all this wiring back there
so kind of have to be one thick and
that's about the best I could do it
adding depth to the wall here we got the
five brewing stands for brewing awkward
potions and we have hoppers above here
that are supposed to distribute water
bottles so they run across these hoppers
at the second level and they get dropped
off into these and and the broom stands
can pick them up if we go up here this
is what I've added to fill the bottles
to make water bottles
you got a chest up here they're the
first ones we're doing by the way I
tried to do everything for the first
time on camera when I can this is
working so so these things to be falling
maybe I gotta stand a little more
centered yeah so the idea is we're gonna
have a huge huge buffer of water bottles
here and these filter down through a
bunch of hoppers to these chests and
these are gonna be a big buffer of water
bottles there's I think there's a double
chest there there there there there it's
over five double chests I think and then
we have all the hopper space to do so
it's a lot of a lot of space for water
bottles let's just throw a few more in
here and then we take these water
bottles and we have to send them to
those brewing stands so let's head on
down once we finish up here
doo doo doo doo doo oh yeah look at that
party those bottles are jumping around
whoo-hoo
all right so the thing is I've added so
much stuff here I can't even get around
it's so bad okay I think we can hop down
here
okay so right above these hoppers are
the brewing stands let's go over here
and all those water bottles end up at
this chest okay so they filter into the
hoppers and did they go down oh they did
they did go down that's good so oh yeah
we can see it even the brewing stands
are filled with water bottles now that's
ah this mess this was part of the
problem I tell you go through here and
close this back up okay so these get
filled up with with bottles they brew
into awkward potions and this lever here
is to control a clock that controls
emptying and filling these every 20
seconds it switches much like we had for
the brewing I could've sworn I had a
better way of getting down and I must
have closed it up okay so let's go down
and see this thing running so switches
all the water bottles they go to these
hoppers down here and they float to this
chest which gets filled up with awkward
potions then we need to pick these up
and I break this can't break this yes
alright they get picked up here or at
this hopper oh these are from before
don't mind these don't find these all
awkward potions good good so a storage
minecart will come here they'll get
filled up and then it gets sent up this
rail line and this distributes it to all
the drop-off zones so minecart goes
around
does a loop and then it goes off to each
of these branches and there's a hopper
system here let's actually get a
minecart running here we'll check it out
okay maybe before we get to the minecart
thing there's something I want to check
out here I'm wondering what happens if
this backs up and we get stuck with some
awkward potions in here and some water
bottles is it gonna make mundane potions
because that will be a problem I've went
ahead and I filled this totally up with
water bottles which are now being used
at like totally totally full its double
chests this one all all of these totally
full this should be just about full as
well this awkward potion chest where is
it
stick this out sounds hey awkward
potions awkward potions yeah it's
totally full so let's go back out there
and see what happens to this brewing
setup when it gets backed up let's find
a way we've done this before we'll go
through here yay
awkward awkward and that's all the space
there is this is totally we'll take one
of these out and have a water bottle in
I'm not sure if oh wait no see I'm
wondering if these awkward potions get
transformed into Monday and potions if
you do nether word on them twice if they
become mundane potions we might have a
problem come on
now they're good sweet all right that
simplifies me a lot I was worried about
that so let's do the minecart thing now
see how that works all right we got the
minecart and storage minecart here
please tell me it's filling it's full
okay good
this was supposed to mmm every time this
power turns on it was supposed to send
power through here down and to the power
rail below but it doesn't seem like it's
launching it let's let's change it let's
change this to for next time this turns
on let's see if it turns the power wheel
on I think the minecart did move it just
need more time should happen any second
so every time we brew a set of awkward
potions my church should depart from
here it's only gonna run when this
systems running okay there it goes I
don't want this running all the time
because I find that really annoying when
you have a minecart running all the time
so it's gonna make its way through all
these drop-off zones it's dropping off
the potions into this hopper here and as
it's dropping it off there's always one
one potion in this hopper and that
that's how it knows it's in drop-off
mode if there's no items in this hopper
there's no potions that means it's done
dropping off and then this this power
rail turns on and the minecart takes off
if there's two or more items in here it
also takes off because this is the thing
I think I had the most trouble
explaining last episode oh wow it came
back sorry I only had three in mmm
that's less than ideal
see since it's empty it just goes over
top these these are powered by default
but if if there is an item in the
minecarts it'll send an item to this
hopper this turns that compared Iran and
then there this comparator goes to a
redstone torch above so if items are
passing through the hopper this power
rail turns off because that redstone
torch goes to this wire which is what
powers this if there's let's see if
rings if we can see it happen see it
stops it unloads I mean it picked up a
bit more this time yeah it's got fully
fully filled up so that comparators on
now that's done dropping stuff off
there's no items in this hopper so that
goes that goes back off torch turns on
and it powers the power rail again the
thing I'm worried about is this minecart
getting stuck on one of these drop-off
zones which should be pretty rare with
this setup
all right maybe let's this watch this
for a little bit see if we spot any
problems or anything it's starting to
fill up the station's here which is good
we need these all to fill up before we
turn the brewing on for the first time
good good so we're just about halfway
there I think and it seems to be running
okay I want to see I've been playing
around with the timing on this let's see
if it picks up a full chest of potions
or not no darn it okay that time it
picked up nine it looked like four eight
so we're gonna go down here we're gonna
change the timing on on the clock again
the problem with this it's just the
timing isn't jiving very well it's that
five cobble in it just so happens that
the time it takes it to do the loop is
like rate when it returns it's ready to
go again
so if we delay it a little bit it'll
give it time to pick up potions out of
this chest and this seems to be keeping
up okay with brewing awkward potions now
kind of have we run out of bottles maybe
that might be what it is cuz we filled
up quite a bit of chest space already oh
okay there's a little bit left but it's
running out we're gonna have to refill
that soon I got my internet back guys
I'm very happy for that if you didn't
know my main internet line went down for
over a week I think it turns out what
the problem was at the switch box near
here it got flooded and the cable
shorted out but I did have my backup
backup internet line it was definitely
helpful but when they fixed the new or
when they fixed my main Internet they
may have used wires from the old backup
line that's supposed to be disconnected
but I'm getting free internet from but
now no longer works because they they
used it to repair the broken line so
yeah I lost my backup line which kinda
stinks I wasn't really using it just for
emergencies like when my main line went
out but yeah I don't have a backup line
if it ever goes out again which kind of
stinks so I might need to get another
provider
just in case it happens this is going
pretty good though let's head on out
over here things out I'm very happy this
is finally just about done seems to be
working ok no awkward potions there yet
and then there but I think this chest is
full that's full and this one's just
starting to fill I think cool so we'll
give it a little time and then we'll
fire up this master switch here and we
will see everything running ah man this
thing is crazy it's been running for
like an hour total to get the potions
throughout the whole thing it's not
because it's it's slow and it's taking
it forever it's just because I went so
so crazy overboard with this whole
building there's like a thousand bottles
in the system already between water
bottles and awkward potions and have you
even started brewing yet it's gonna be
like two thousand three thousand potions
in the system at all times I think which
is which is cool because we'll have like
an endless supply but it's it takes a
long time to start it up here I tell you
it's gonna have to run for another hour
- I think to brew everything but that's
where we're at right now this is the
grand beginning for ethos lab once we
pull this switch I think I think
everything's set up in a way that it's
not gonna go crazy so here we go ethos
lab is officially open
oh man feel the leg oh man this is gonna
be crazy okay
have I said crazy yeah I think I have
so all these things are running right
now every 20 seconds it's gonna flip
40 seconds total for every 3 potions per
chain this is becoming healing potions
this is becoming healing tools over here
we have extended regions happening over
here we have extended strength happening
and weakness
splash weakness over there it's
happening this is pretty cool so it's
got to do so many brews and it's gonna
fill up all these chests starting with
this back one that's not supposed to be
there starting with the back chest and
this one will fill up then this one then
this one this one's already full we can
have this thing running as this ring
happens whoo pretty cool never-ending
potions it's what I've always wanted
we still might do a little more with
this lap but I think we'll leave it for
the time being I kind of wanted to set
up some minecart system to send it
through send potions throughout other
parts of my world like it would be nice
to have speed potions everywhere
wherever I need them now the thing is
okay here's a problem though this is
gonna run out of gas steers very soon we
don't have enough to fill up all these
chests with our regen potions and we're
probably never going to so I think oops
I think something we can do
we got a hopper there we got a hopper
there let's put in an on/off switch for
all these I think if we power this it'll
shut it off
forcefully and we'll have to do that
with the regions because it's just not
it's not feasible to get that many gas
dude okay so when it switched this
didn't fill up with potions that's good
this is still continuing on though so
that'll stop it if we want it to stop
let these finish though yeah so this has
been running for quite a while now
actually and all the chests are filling
up with potions it's wonderful it's
awesome
once these fill up it's like they're
gonna last forever it's gonna be really
easy to maintain the potions supply once
once they fill up this is this initial
startup phase that's that's quite
expensive and time-consuming got some
night vision starting there it's getting
to the point now though where we are
running out of ingredients and I'm gonna
have to stop it actually because
remember this chest that was full of
bottles glass bottles when we started
while almost full I think there's three
three stacks missing those have all been
used up they're all in the system right
now and there's still room for more so
it's it's a ton of potions in here what
else do we got going on yet poison
potions there we got our speed potions
yeah so it's adding up let's take a few
of these actually and over here we have
slowness lots of potions ready already
very good weakness ones over there
strength just full
yeah that's full so it looks like about
two double chests cut done in the amount
of time you left it it's pretty good but
yeah well we'll shut it down for now and
we'll finish it up later when we get the
ingredients together again and
it'll turn this off as well one thing I
noticed with this it was not keeping up
anymore like this is empty there's no
more awkward potions in here this one
was starting to run out so what that
means is this cannot keep up with this
which I expected that because we have
seven chains running here or we had and
there's only five brewing stands here so
this is just a little bit slower but
that's fine because it's it's only this
initial startup that's really taxing on
the system all right so maybe one more
thing we'll do this episode I have a lot
of people asking me about the library so
let's go check that out let's take let's
take Zenith Z and this is a good horse
go for a little ride mmm I had to skip
the night there it was pretty rough
Zenith took some hits wasn't nice but
yeah let's go check out the library it's
just at the end of this path here a lot
of people are interested in the library
there wondering what state it's been at
we haven't been here in a long time I
have worked on it a little bit but I
think we need to maybe redesign a little
a little bit of our plans because I was
originally planning to make a big
rectangle with it
and after working on eco Corp on the
minecraft server I think this is what
I've done that I haven't shown just this
little wall here after working on itto
Corp on the minecraft server that
buildings only maybe 20 by 20 this one's
like 40 by 40 with with a the layout we
had here an isochoric me for ever to
work on or to finish it's I like to put
a lot of detail on my builds I'd rather
build something smaller and spend a lot
of time on it and get it the way I like
it then just build big plain walls and
that kind of thing
so I think if we do a 40 by 40 with this
we're gonna have problems so we should
we'll fight a little bit but yeah we'll
try work on this sometime soon I do like
this look here the bottom of these I
think this was supposed to be a wall
here and we got the window and a wall
I was having a little bit of a problem
with my building here I was adding in
way too many windows now that we have
clay blocks I almost want it incorporate
those into this instead of using wood on
the inside maybe clay would be nicer I'm
not sure though let me know what you
guys think but anyway that is the
library and this is the comment picked
out for today it says etho you see
anything you like from what Jeb's been
tweeting send flowers and new biomes
it's really sweet man if you haven't
done so already check I really butchered
that if you haven't done so already
check it out
I swear I can read I swear yeah I've
seen the screenshots of the biomes and
they they're looking pretty good pretty
excited about we got a new block type it
looks like that bog earth type thing
which is pretty cool I think I think
they've shown about three or so biomes I
can't quite remember now the one that
really caught my eye though was a
floating island biome that was really
cool now I really hope they added to the
game I'm not sure if it's a biome or
just a setting that could be applied to
all biomes when you when you generate
your world but yeah some pretty exciting
stuff coming out and there's someone
that plays survival minecraft a lot
that's that's a feature that really
appeals to me I know some people aren't
overly excited about new biomes because
they don't really affect them but for me
I definitely look forward to him you
think there's something like human
jungles when they came out you know some
people weren't too excited but I I have
definitely settled down in jungle biomes
a few times now
they're they're really nice and I expect
these new biomes will be pretty cool too
so can't wait till the next patch that's
gonna be it for today guys hope you
enjoyed I'll see you next time bye bye