hello how's it going everybody this is
Ito and welcome back we're playing some
more minecraft today guys and yes I have
been working on the Nexus today so I was
a little while ago now but if you
remember I had I did a bunch of work on
this thing and then I ran into kind of a
problem and it seemed a bit weird to me
at first and it still does but basically
the codes were reversed with our system
and I thought about it a little bit in
our English language we go left to right
you know like hello how's it going I'm
typing left to right on screen here
right
but with numbers when we do like combo
locks for example when you have to
include the zeros like say you have four
digits generally we go right to left so
to iterate through this it would be like
zero zero zero zero zero then the one
and the two one on the right instead of
on the left ends it's kind of opposite
isn't it like we don't go one and then
then this would be two you know we go we
go the other way so basically the way I
was doing with with the system this was
one
this was two you know it's going left
the right oops
and that that's not right that's not
what we view it as as proper so I
flipped it around so now go zero one now
zero two zero three etc etc and the way
I did that I just flipped the displays
on this to to fix it and it seems to do
the trick but I had to do a whole bunch
of rewiring in the back year I spent
like three hours on this today it was a
big project it was pretty difficult but
I had to disconnect all the wires and
reconnect them differently and and it
seems to be good now which is great
so yeah I'm basically just trying to
work out any rough edges with our our
design here trying to make it as
intuitive and uncommon at surely to us
and one other thing that caught my
attention here that I'm going to try fix
we just requested item zero zero out of
the system which tada is coal as it
turns out so it's got the code zero zero
there I looked where that is in the
system right where it's actually
physically located and it turns out it's
down here on the left side at the very
end so this is item zero zero with our
current set up I don't really want this
to be our very first item again thinking
about what comes naturally to us since
we are I left the rights language and
that kind of thing I think what I'm
going to do is make the very first item
the top top of the storage room and on
the very left towards the back so that
would be I think this row here this is
last row right I think so so this is the
very very left very back corner of the
whole thing and the item number 256 or
whatever should be the opposite of it so
downstairs very rights very front of the
room so I wanted to go from 0 0 here 0 1
0 2 0 3 all the way down and then I want
it to start on this side and then go
over a row and then another row another
row once it gets to the very right of
this go down and start on the left and
then make its way to the right kind of
like a typewriter you know once you hit
the end of the rows you go down the line
from left to right
alright so that's the plan with that in
order to do that so as I was building
this whole thing since it's a pretty big
crazy complicated project
um made a few mistakes on the way as you
would expect and some of these switchers
let's see if we can find one here I
think it's the blue one we got to change
you see how it's it's like this I think
to do it properly
I put the piston on the left side and
block coming out this way but one way I
can sort of cheese it and fix it is just
invert it and steal this block is this
going to work can we just do this and
then switch it like this yeah so that'll
be the opposite now and I got to do that
for all these blue ones in total there's
only two there's one more up here that I
got to flip and then I think it'll start
at the very very left side at the very
back where we want there no oh I just
thought I just discovered something that
that crushed my spirits here guys my my
fix the flipping the displays wasn't so
much a fix as I thought had to make
things a lot worse here three hours down
the drain uh so I got it so that this is
item zero zero the problem is instead of
this being zero one like I want zero one
is all the way down here which was an
enderpearl and then zero two was all the
way over here so it's not going smoothly
through this now like it was before or
it's going from one to the next it's
like hopping all over the system by
sixteen and that is not so good because
when we're looking to get a piece of
wool for example we want all the wool to
be grouped together in our code system
and all the glass and all that kind of
stuff we don't just want it to be random
items so I have to know to back up and
try to fix it another way or maybe I
just won't fix it because I don't know
how to fix it to be honest
all right well I just loaded the back up
here guys I made some of the fixes that
we applied before so this was zero zero
like we wanted and another problem has
shown its ugly face though
we're gonna have a lot of problems to
fix it feels like now so this is zero
zero there should be zero one but
instead when I put zero one in it it
gave me a second one of these and then
zero two hopped over and skip this and M
gave me pink zero three skip this and
give me gave me pink again then zero for
whatever give me blue so it's it's
skipping every second one and giving us
the same as the one before something is
messed up I need to try figure out what
it is so it could be one row of these
Pistons this is this is what's supposed
to be switching these Pistons here and
maybe they're not I don't know let's try
this out so they were extended right now
right that's extended okay let's try
switches and see if that does anything
so it's on an even number right now
let's try an odd number if it's an odd
number it should be different
we'll go for three all right let's go
check it now see if it if it didn't
change then something's something's
wrong that's not getting powered for
some reason and oh it did change well
how about that I need to probably spend
a lot of time figuring this out then I
think I spotted the problem thankfully
this one's an easy fix
very easy in fact you'll notice on the
other side those repeaters are on and on
this side it is off up to this point
because the repeater is missing here for
some reason I might have broke it while
building who knows so that should do it
now
just been doing a few more tests here
things are actually going pretty great
for a while and then more problems this
is actually a good way of debugging this
like figuring out where the issue is I
just left it writing I and this follow
the blinking lights to where it stops
and then that's usually where the
problem is as is with this case just a
slightest little mistake you know will
will wreck everything and in this case
redstone signal only travels as far at
can't power this one
one last dust needed to pass a signal on
further so fortunately I'm going to put
a repeater there and probably have to do
that a few more times here for each of
these ones affected oh man oh snappers
things are happening guys progress is
being made I'm now in the middle of
building the code table to this thing so
I got to put one of each item in the
chest give it a code I got to name it on
an anvil and it it takes a level every
time so I need like 256 levels total to
do all these items and yeah it's coming
along here while building this table
though ran into another snag a little
another little problem I had to have to
work out fixing here there were a few
items missing in our system there mainly
the food items there was a bunch of them
missing so I put them in I went and
killed a rabbit and killed a pig and
cook some of the meats and you know made
some golden carrots we're missing put
them all in the system and then now that
I'm checking it again they're still not
there for some reason so for some reason
not all the food items are getting to
where they need to go so I've made a
little item debugger here try figure out
where the problem is because I've tried
following an item in it like it's faster
than me so I can't just go in and walk
this and see where it stops because look
it gets too far ahead of me and then I
don't see where it goes so I'm going to
have several items going here and
hopefully I can see what is going on
where the trouble is all right they're
still going
ah I'm expecting to see a problem up
here but so far still so good
still so good yes that made sense oh
yeah this is where they're stopping aha
that's where all my food is gone aha
that works oh look at this
those are all the items I tried to put
in the system I wonder what this was
supposed to be before and why it got
messed up maybe this was emptying and
something I don't know alright I spotted
the problem alright well I just had an
idea here we need a lot of XP to do all
this to to name everything in the anvils
and I've had like over a chest of coal
ore that I've been considering just
throwing away because I don't really
want to break it all like and just break
it you know like I have lots of coal
laying around it's not something I
probably would ever do just to get the
coal from it but it works out pretty
good in this case because we get a
little bit of XP from this and I don't
have to go all the way to the end or
something like that which is what I was
doing was taking quite a bit of time
walking back and forth here so I got
like portable XP here and this way I can
actually get the coal out of these ores
two birds in one stone type of thing you
really don't get a lot of XP from it
though I'm noticing you need to bring a
lot of coal but every 16 levels I get
basically then what I do drop off the
coal and I will go up into our room here
woah and start taking the items out from
the droppers here starting from this end
and working my way down trying to be
careful what order I place them in my
inventory here but I'll grab 16 items
then I go to the anvil name them all put
them in the chest break some more coal
this one's messed up there's no way this
is supposed to be dirt
all right I don't know why it's dirt
I'll have to fix that later because it's
supposed to be like slabs and stairs
here but that one got overwritten
somehow the other one I figured out what
it was I'm pretty sure it was just
regular clay
I got her done man I can't believe it I
did it all in one day here finished the
tables oh my goodness I went through
like 20 anvils aiming all this stuff it
was insane
so now ideally there's a couple spots
missing and why is there a sign here I
don't understand like these are flowers
and plants somehow a sign got mixed in
the middle there don't know what that's
about but for the most part its complete
here got to figure out what what belongs
where this dirt is too because we have
two dirts pretty sure yeah here's here's
the real dirt and this is supposed to be
podzol but yeah if all goes according to
plan I would actually be really amazed
if this worked let's be dee let's try to
get BD we'll just pick a random one here
see if it works or not we should be able
to just pick any item we want now though
and request it this has to be flipped
again though see what I did with the
displays I switched this light here with
this one this one with this one this one
with with that one and so so forth that
I had the right idea of switching the
displays I just did in the wrong way
what I really need to do is switch this
light with this one this one with this
one this one with this one because
binary also is right-to-left I found out
I just looked up like on the wiki it the
binary wiki so this equals one and this
is 128 all right so I I did this
backwards because when this lights on I
count
that is one leaf if this is on off off
off off off off off I count that as one
currently so if I flip the display so
that that light is over there then it
all works out it's all in the right
order but until I do that I'm gonna have
to enter these codes in backwards I'm
not doing it sig is it's going to take
me two or three hours to flip the
displays again do it properly here what
did I say I was gonna get stone brick BD
so I would have to enter D be the
opposite of that's dB
D is this button here Rd good and then B
for that one
and B all right so now if there is no
mistake somehow miraculously here we
will actually get stone brick to come up
out of our system pretty shortly here
but I've already fixed about dinner so
things today ten or so mistakes I've
made with the system so I would be
pretty shocked you know I thought
something would come at least maybe
we're out of stone brick is my only hope
here right now so let's follow the
redstone see where it's going where is
the problem this time it's going to left
down here all the way over here and if
we enter down here I should actually
hear it clicking Oh actually wait let's
check something maybe the bridge don't
not go in far enough
I just wish I could fly through the
blocks man like this just drives me nuts
you have no idea try to get around this
place is so annoying I can't see down
there okay it's gone there
oh yeah same problem is before I never
extended this woops
okay now I hear a clicking so I got to
go to the opposite side and do that too
all right let's go back though we'll see
if we got stone brick
hopefully hopefully see if it picked the
right item anyway it did not hit no that
would have been nice so pick this 1995
so yeah got some issues to work out here
yup so I'm just back to bug squashing
here I just found another one just
another really simple thing again easy
to miss but big effect ah yeah look at
this I'm trying to send the signal to
this repeater here but it's going
through two blocks instead of just one
this is supposed to be lime-green there
we go so that that one should be fixed
now ah yeah I think I got it now so I've
been a bug squishing for quite a while
here taking care of all the little
problems and now I'm actually getting
the stuff I request which is amazing
guys it's absolutely incredible
I love it let's do a couple more tests
here a couple examples on camera alright
what should we pick let's try get
regular clay 5e is the code so if we hit
5 which is this button so I'm I have to
activate this set of lights first and
then this one so 5e these next because
the displays are messed up I still still
very confused about that to be honest I
did something wrong that's all I know
I'm still trying to figure out what I
need to do to fix it but if all is well
this should be clay yeah it looks like
clay to me oh man that is so cool okay
let's try another one here let's say we
want some lily pads d4 so D oh that was
a three whoops
d4 I seem to be able to like select the
code pretty quick here which is great
it's not too tricky pretty easy to find
the item I want thanks to this table as
well now I know a lot of you guys are
worried like what if there's new ID
in the game which there are like I would
like to get the new per per blocks in
here but yeah we got lily pads let's go
for red wool to a rights to a good yeah
if I want to put per per blocks in here
for example I have to take something out
something I don't really necessarily
want like leads for example not a high
priority item I could replace that with
another type of block but I can't really
expand the system nor do I really want
to because the level of complexity of
this thing already is just insane so so
yeah but yeah it seems to be working and
of course if we want to put an item back
inside to just put in this chest seems
to get there automatically sorted pretty
good n Stone f5 let's do it
f5 BAM give me that in stone here let's
take a nap real quick before I wake up I
bet you it'll be there i shadow know if
there's any stone inside the system
there might be do we have any stone we
have in stone oh yeah oh that's so cool
it's finally working guys finally so
happy this project do not build this
ever in your world that's all I can tell
you because it is insane so yeah just
kind of got a weird feeling guys like
man I'm I'm done I'm done with this
build the technical part of it anyway
obviously we got some building to do the
building itself has not been built but
all the head-scratching hair-pulling out
part of the build is done all the
tedious repetitive copy this this thing
256 times is all done and I just feel
kind of strange ah man this is it's a
relief though because honest
guys when I started building this I knew
it was going to be a big project I
underestimated just how big it was and I
didn't plan it all out in creative mode
like believe it or not this wasn't all
figured out in creative mode most of the
figuring was done here in survival and
there was a very good chance it wasn't
going to work in the end of all this but
we pulled through somehow it does
actually work and seems like it'll
actually be practical which was another
thing I was worried about like yeah
maybe we can get it working but is it
something I can actually use at an
efficient way in an efficient way
I kind of blurred two words together
there and it seems like we we're going
to be using it so that's great very
happy about that for the building itself
I decided I want to build it out of
those new purpura blocks I like those a
lot they also seemed kind of futuristic
like because they're purple right purple
is not really a natural color kind of a
odd block I think that's great for this
I like the way they look I'm going to do
pepper and quartz and maybe one other
type of block mixed in here with the
main room and then we got to like
connect this main room to these hallways
because I want to still be able to enter
into the storage room even though we
don't really need to go in there but may
as well make a way of getting into there
because I kind of designed it around
that designed it so that we could and
yeah this feels so good
so if you guys are sick of like
technical Nexus building episodes like
this one I can tell you I sure AM man
they are not easy to do um this was the
last one probably if you enjoyed them
well I'm sorry all good things have to
come to an end even the bad things well
would you look at this I went to my
storage room here was demon see this
guy's he snuck up behind me and started
attacking me and now he's like he's like
my best friend or something he does
even care about me anymore pretty weird
do you know do you not want to kill me
anymore I wonder that's pretty weird so
why is this why are you not attacking me
did we go to counseling together or we
did we make up somehow I don't know oh
okay well he's he's had enough of me I'm
gonna name this guy we'll call him the
windmill master no he's dead
never mind how did he die
wait a sec did he fall down there all we
did ah
well anyways guys it is that time again
to wrap up episode I I do want to say
something though I know a lot of you
have been feeling the lack of Minecraft
lately and I do apologize for that going
to try make an effort to get more videos
outs I don't know what it is honestly
like it's not that I'm losing interest
in the game it's just distracted I guess
playing other games real-life
distractions that kind of stuff has have
come up and when I went and did the
comments there's like wow as that much
time really fast since the last episode
it just feels like the other day I did
one but yeah it's been like two weeks so
I haven't been too good but I'm gonna
make more of an effort I do apologize
alright but let's get to the comments
for today says first one etho would you
be able to upload minecraft in 60fps
well I just recently started uploading
terraria in 60fps but other games like
Ark I have a hard time keeping that
frame rates especially when recording
and minecraft is another one of those
games like everybody says this game has
simple graphics and all that but man
does it run it doesn't run the best I
have a pretty big struggle to keep up
with the
60 FPS while recording so probably not
going to happen I also don't have the
best internet it's bit it's a lot better
now than it was a long time ago but
still below average I would say so 60
FPS doubles the size of the upload and
and that doesn't work out too well for
me so yeah probably not going to do that
anytime soon
unfortunately until I'm technically able
to alright and the second question is
hey ether just wondering do the new
items in the snapshot breaks the Nexus
and I think the Nexus will be okay as
far as I know nothing has changed with
the redstone I I do know they've done
some major potion reworking though so
one thing I am concerned about is ethos
lab here in fact I saw they added the
lingering potions now and we are not
going to be able to incorporate those
into our system here I don't think not
not like super well I think one thing we
could do is add a like instead of this
being glowstone we could add the
lingering potion ingredient here and
then we just dump items in that we want
to make lingering in here and then they
would they would get the effect applied
but one of the other things about them
updating the potions is I think all the
previous like the old ones were broken
so all these ones we have brewed already
might not work when we update and this
will all be like a bad batch basically
and that would kind of suck but maybe
they'll fix it up before before I update
the snapshots we'll see anyways gonna
wrap it up here thank you for watching
guys hope you enjoyed try to get another
one out to you soon and I'll see you in
the next episode take care bye bye
you