[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and we're back again here having
some fun with the 1.14 update that just
came out look at this guy he's just just
looking at me silently judging me right
now he thinks he's taller than me but he
doesn't know I'm crouching huh huh look
at this he's still taller is any no yeah
so we're doing a bit of a goofy project
here we settled down into the village
last episode we're gonna build it up a
little bit more today now we're probably
gonna trigger the raid and then yeah I
probably go home and leave them with
however it turns out I don't know the
main reason we're doing this of course
to show off the new stuff that came out
with updates we're calling this dumpster
ville by the way it's a great name good
name we want to check out the new stuff
in the update but we also I'm kind of
curious on a couple village mechanics
I'm a bit hazy about like I've read
through the wiki page and stuff but I'm
still not really sure how some things
work mainly the doors unhe zeon like do
we still need doors for villages I don't
know it sounds like we need one bed per
villager alright
the villagers need to be willing to
breed so we can either trigger that
through trading let's try this out so
apparently if we this is what I copied
from the wiki page wiliness is granted
the first time a new offer is traded or
at a 1 in 5 chance of some subsequent
trades so every time we trade we have
like a 1:5 chance of triggering their
willingness but this is a new trade here
so I think it's like guaranteed if we go
for the lapis not only one only one oh
that's kind of cool it automatically
takes out of your inventory now that was
a big pain before oh yeah he got the
green particles if they get the green
particles that means their willingness
got triggered so now that guy's ready to
breed guaranteed but actually let's
let's just make sure here let's Darren T
it's gonna happen so you got the green
particles he's willing to to breed so we
know for sure now the farmer and the
cleric are willing to breed we have
enough beds in the village so it all
comes down to do we do we have enough
doors the doors matter we'll find that
out tonight when they meet together
probably if they don't get any hearts
two nights we probably got to add more
doors where did he go there he is aha so
this is another new thing that came out
at 1:14 it's really cool we got
ourselves I want to call him a traveling
merchant but he has a different name
doesn't he yeah wandering trader
wandering traders are a thing now and
these are pretty cool cuz I got some
unique trade items like coral got a
bucket of puffer fish and it's like from
a it grabs like a I think six or so
trades from a huge list of possible
things so every one of these guys you
find they're gonna have different things
and you can get some some cool stuff
they also spawn with llamas I think
sometimes so we got some llamas here and
there's some leads connected but they're
invisible now because I think you drink
an invisibility potion already and
somehow that affected the leads so what
I'm curious about here apparently like
no matter what you do to this guy if you
name him with a name tag or something
he's still gonna despawn in 40 to 60
minutes guaranteed and apparently the
llamas go with him if they're attached
with the lead still so I'm gonna try
steal one of these guys from him can we
do that no how can we make them detach
without killing the traveling guy I want
to see if like one will despawn and the
other one stays like if we can detach it
but I don't think this leads to really
doing anything I don't think it's
actually recognized as connected so you
should not be able to stretch him this
far okay I think he's still connected
actually like if the wandering trader
guy goes to the right this guy seems to
go to the right if it goes to the left
he goes to the left even
I got him trapped in blocks here and he
can't go I think if I remove these he's
gonna like slingshot towards him yeah
okay
oh hey there's a lead on the ground no
wait a second
no I'm not seeing any hearts here okay
let's give this guys some food so that
should trigger his willingness to be its
well he just threw those right out did
he keep 12 no he didn't keep keep very
many I think he needs 12 of them the
triggers willingness you hold on to
those okay so I think when the traveling
merchants these spawns the the white
guy's gonna go with them but not the
brown guys oh that did it that did it
okay so maybe the doors don't matter
actually then cuz here they're willing
to breathe this might be our first baby
villager in dumpster Ville oh my
goodness the first baby dumpster villian
it's so cool uh-huh so now that they
make out the baby they're no longer
willing to breed so we gotta either
trade with them again to trigger their
willingness or we can just give them
food to trigger it 12 carats all right
hold on to those we want another baby
tonight or right now even you can do it
right now
they seem to get stuck on these flower
pots so they might be there a while you
didn't make it anyways let's get back to
it here guys so we're gonna we're gonna
do a bit more building we we're very
limited on our block so you just
teleport didn't you I don't like when
you do that we don't have like red clay
or anything like that here so we got to
keep it pretty simple like wood and
cobble pretty much but I want to build a
barn for some animals
No oh I liked how they look though yeah
he's gonna he's gonna keep poking
himself okay they're gone
oh we can't put put a fence gate over
this it turns back to dirt right
that looks a little funny doesn't it uh
yeah you know what guys if something
doesn't look quite right it's a big
goofy not my best work it doesn't matter
it's dumpster bill but overall I don't
think it turned out too too bad actually
so we got ourselves a barn now we gotta
get some animals here I do the final
changes here I actually don't mind it
with this darker wood either it might
even look better but it doesn't matter
I'm gonna change it alright
is there a way to detach all these guys
all at once quickly
I guess just run away alright so I'm
pretty sure that wandering trader is
gone now I can't find him anywhere
let's just do one more double check for
the white alpaca I think he'd be spawned
with the other guy there's lots of
animals around here like if we need more
this is a great place for a village
these guys knew what they were doing
yeah I'm not seeing that other L pacta
anywhere so I think you D spawned with
the knot man I really want to call him
the traveling merchant that's the first
thing that pops in my head every single
time I struggle not to say it wandering
trader yeah he despawned with the
wandering trader but this guy got left
behind because we detached his lead but
this guy's not friendly to us I don't
think or is he no so by default they're
kind of like wild alpaca we can't like
look into his inventory or anything now
he's got the hearts so we can we can
equip him oh so he doesn't have a carpet
on it I was wondering about that so they
kind of got a special look compared to
like wild alpaca like he's got the
scarfs and stuff on all right
ah do we have any wool kind of want to
see what happens now if we put a carpet
on them I wait to make some let's do
that let's do it's just the white ones
is it two or is it three I always forget
it's two okay you got our carpets
all right so if we put this on them I'm
kind of worried it'll get rid of his
default look oh no it dies it oh that's
cool man I'm having like a lot of fun on
this villager like I'm sure we could
spend the whole episode here if we
wanted to we're not going to though
we're gonna we're gonna trigger that
raid soon just gonna do a couple more
building things there's one more thing I
want to build here for sure and then
we'll trigger the raid probably well
actually we're gonna add one more thing
onto the barn - yeah this will work
right if we do this I'll get these non
non non ring bark blocks what are they
called
it's a spruce wood okay like we don't
want to use these because they have the
ring
we'll use these and then I think you can
strip these still alright yeah alright
it's that's more stairs we got some
slabs on us yep cool how's that look
yeah so we could put some like hay bales
or or that under here it'll look a lot
better well we only had enough wheat
there for three hay bales but just
imagine there's like eight more in there
would look pretty good right uh-huh
so for our next building projects we're
gonna bake a statue I really want to
make it a statue to show off our
prosperity in this village you know but
we're gonna need 27 emeralds for it for
what I have planned I did some mining
here we got we've got some dire rights
some Granite's
and some andesite with the new textures
I wanted to try to do a build with them
to see how they look like I did this
thing over here and I'm liking the new
textures like from what I've seen so far
I think the plan is we're gonna actually
keep keep using this new texture pack
that came out because most you guys seem
to prefer it there's just the odd block
I wasn't too fond of personally but
overall it does look a lot better I
would say this guy he he treats the Bell
by the way he can't craft it this is
that's the only way to get it I believe
or to steal them from villages and
you'll notice
things are getting cheaper like it's
originally 36 but because I've been
trading with these guys my popularity
and the village has gone up and things
are cheaper than their default price for
me now which is nice but that trades
locked out right now so the only way to
get it through a refresh he has to go to
his workstation here the grind wheel and
now yeah now that now it's refreshed he
was able to restock he does I think
twice a day so now we can trade again
get a few more emeralds ooh actually
there's another goofy idea I want to try
out now so before we do the statute
we're gonna try something with the
campfires so these are new as well in
114 and they are amazing they are one of
the coolest things added probably let's
just pop one down here's kind of like a
hangout area it feels like okay that's
oh that's so cool they got smoke
apparently you can cook food on here do
we have anything to cook no I am just be
another cow here or something just to
show it oh no my sword burns things I
forgot so you can cook up to four things
around the campfire at a time and
they'll kind of sizzle like that for a
while and then BAM they pop off you got
your cooked meats doesn't take any
charcoal or anything like that it's free
cooking and it's quick but it's only
manual you can't like hook a hopper up
to this or anything unfortunately so
there's been a bit of a development it
turns out I when I went and got the
chicken I saw something over here that's
it's a bit worrying yeah so there's like
a team just kind of sitting outside the
village waiting for their chance I don't
know if he's gonna shoot at the villager
he looks like he's aiming he's really
aiming so this is not like like we did I
thought we'd have to go to the outpost
to trigger this it looks like they just
randomly occur as well so these guys
just randomly occurred probably because
our village is doing okay now we got
like six villagers at least but they're
not shooting at the guys and it's like
they're not crossing the line
so yeah it's kind of hanging out there
they're respecting us nope now they're
not I did not make a shield that's one
thing I forgot actually oh that's a
Johnny three hearts guys it's kind of
checking out like what kind of damage of
you oh okay how about we sent a roll no
no sword cuz I think they'll make it too
easy okay we triggered it voluntary
exile Oh run run you fool no dude are
you fool it's okay it was only the
nitwit
oh yeah success we got ourselves a
crossbow what kind of what kind and what
you're doing here quick damage Oh
so when you pick it up I guess it's like
charged you hear that is it over here
then this this is where the sound team
from yeah okay come on guys there's only
like three guys there but I think
there's gonna be many waves this is like
the easy wave oh no there's got to be a
lot of guys cuz that didn't make the bar
go down by much this crossbows so slow
no stay back
the Johnny's hit really hard oh oh okay
switch into the trident as cool as the
crossbow is we need quick charge like
two or three on it so we're gonna get
stopped here last guy let's do a
finishing blow with this oh the wolf
yes good job can't here they come uh uh
so do they not all have crossbows he has
a crossbow these other guys don't though
right oh they got axes it's like
wondering cuz I didn't see any weapon at
all Trident this is so good Oh
this might actually get kind of hard
like when we get the lease showing up
here let's eat something gate Wolfie I'm
gonna I'm gonna release you note I
didn't want to feed you help me out it's
almost nighttime here
oh he's shooting the wolf will help our
little wolf buddy okay
Raiders remaining - can we sleep during
the raid is that allowed
oh yeah look at that no problem okay I'm
actually like more worried about zombie
showing up oh okay that was close
yeah that guy didn't like three hit kill
us actually that's that's a little scary
let's actually get our boys in action
here we'll have like five wolves because
these next raids might be a little tough
actually here we got one Raider left we
in ring the bell to highlight his
location he's up there okay cool cool
this crossbow is almost done done skis
this last guy he doesn't fight it all
right oh no he does he's gonna kind of
weapon I thought if they had the banner
they couldn't fight but I I guess they
can okay what is this right three level
four
somebody rang the bell sounds like it's
up over there oh yeah there oh there
come down from the hills no I think I
like the default bow over just the
default crossbow honestly oh that guy
like fell in front of me the nice thing
about the crossbow though is if you got
them pre-charged they can be pretty good
oh it's the Johnny's the Johnny's are
the scary guys so attempted to use my
sword Oh
Oh what
that was a little GT okay where's the
trial it got him I am healing so slow
let's switch over to the pork I think
our saturation is not very high with the
bread I think that's the issue okay I'm
a little worried
I left the villagers to fend for
themselves know how they're doing hey
we've got an emeralds you at least got
one farmer alive and we got the
blacksmith competing here two guys
remaining oh we do have a beast oh
snappers and a witch oh and we totally
missed oh here he comes
no no no no no no no no all those leaves
I placed he's gonna try to destroy him
Wow okay yeah he's a big guy he's he's
fast and I don't have a shield the
shields like the ultimate counter to him
oh I gotta got stuck on the blocks dang
I'm pretty sure I broke my last bed yeah
we're back home having so much fun over
there
all right well thankfully we got our
boat rode here or else it would be
really hard to get back there but it's
gonna be it's gonna take a little bit of
maneuvering to find that spot again I
think we wrote down the coordinates
somewhere so we should be okay
there's our other boats yeah the roads
not quite finished either unfortunately
but this takes us to I believe our
underwater base not there I think we
gotta go to the end here doo doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo
okay okay very good let's ride the
bubbles and then I think we gotta go to
north east south west
can we fly yes we can and then we
basically just gotta play dodge ball
here as we try to make our way back and
try not to fly too quickly because
something can pop up right in front of
you at any moments and you don't want to
snack your face into it but we're almost
back we gotta get to minus three
thousand on the zed a little bit this
way
whoa-oh there's a village is that the
village yes oh and the raid is still in
progress really well snap that's not
good
can our dogs take care of this guy for
us I don't want his hop down there and
die again
man I saw him where is he oh he fell in
the hole yes heap he pulled the
whatchamacallit iron golem and he went
in the hole and he can't get out now
sucker at least I think okay we're gonna
head your up in here can I sleep did he
find his way back up what a guy man he
might even be able to hit us through
blocks I'm not sure okay you this is
this house isn't for you you're supposed
to defend me get out there and do
something I don't like these Ravinder
standard they're nasty so big and tough
okay we get all our things hopefully
hopefully nothing despond and he drops
the saddle oh yeah so saddles are
renewable now because of those guys
although yeah I guess with trading they
were before anyway they're farmable I
guess you could say rummaging through
our town like they own the place oh my
bad
oh he's got regen really really wow so
the witches actually aim the potions
pretty well if they can if they can do
something like that okay guy out even
though its regen though we can kill them
that's good okay yeah if you if you just
don't dive in the rates probably not
that hard if you pick them off one by
one
[Music]
although they're really helping each
other out and they're gonna have speed I
think now you guys ought to be a potion
fly oh and I missed okay got him nice
nice we're hanging in there not feeling
too confident about this here we go
the guy riding the Ravinder even Snapp
not really that many witches in this
raid though the witches are pretty nasty
I think we can outrun this guy right or
not maybe it's hard to say
villager run Sheena brought them over
here actually this is pretty intense we
got the guy on top he's found through
the leaves no oh snap
this is wrecking my whole village I
spent forever on this thing man look at
the tree it took out the whole tree oh
that tree
poor little tree nothing but a twig
we're down to our last wolf okay I'm
being a bit of cow a bit of a coward
here hanging out on the roof son I'll go
down now that the Ravinder is cleared oh
there's the guy up over there I think
he's attacking the villagers where's
that an invoker cuz that can happen too
right
this guy's acting a bit weird yeah
that's an invoker hold snap okay this is
next-level I have so little experience
with these guys I don't even know how to
kill the the guys Oh
defeats
did they they killed all the villagers
no there's one left
oh come on that's all you need to to
restart right no I don't know I don't
know how to kill these guys
Oh killing the guys okay we're switch
I'd give up we're going over for the
sword because we lost already anyway
apparently oh we got totem have been
dying out of the deal
oh man they hurt so bad I don't even
know how to kill these guys you just hit
him with a sword Angus okay so how did
we do here the raids over I think we
lost it we have one farmer for sure yeah
I'm not seeing oh we got another
villager okay so there's at least two
guys here still we didn't repopulate
all right everybody well I was actually
pretty fun I enjoyed that a lot they did
a great job on the raid system and
overall in the village here the
villagers do much better now at staying
alive I think than they used to like you
had to watch them like a hawk before and
they were always getting killed by
something I haven't had one just
randomly die yet so that's that's pretty
interesting so we were gonna build the
statue to like show off the prosperity
of our village and whatnot but now it's
gonna be more like a memorial for those
that that fell in battle or in fell and
running I guess they didn't really fight
anybody right so I want to challenge
myself to try make a villager statue now
that we can like make granite stairs and
andesite stairs and all kinds of stuff
like that
so looking at the villagers obviously
the arms are a prominent feature the
feet are a little bit different so
that's why we we did them a little
difference and I guess we want the arms
to stick out
it'll probably take a little bit of
messing around to get this looking good
but we're just gonna do the rough shape
of it first and we're gonna try to do it
with a three by three head we're gonna
keep it pretty small and proportional
you know so it'll be probably something
like this 3 by 3 so 1 2 3 will kind of
just look at this as it is the big thing
though is we can make like granite
fences which is gonna be important for
the nose how are the proportions there
that's pretty close actually yeah we can
will you make that work okay so I got
the stuff together here for a
stonecutter that's one of the new
workstations and it's actually a very
useful machine that got added in this
update so let's let's get one of those
going no recipe we got no stone uh-oh I
think it's like this well we might need
stone like raw stone I wonder where we
can get some of that all right I think
this is three pieces oh you make it now
yeah there it is okay stone cutter
available so it's one iron and get three
stone and we lay that down it just looks
like a saw but I don't think it hurts
you know a little disappointing on that
front ah but this is really cool so we
can put stuff in here like our Granite's
and just like how outputs a single
single block so one piece turns into one
piece of wall and the great thing is
like normally stairs you need like six
and the site to make four stairs like if
you just craft them this way right you
only get four it takes six blocks but if
you use a stone cutter it's one to one
so you you save on materials which is
actually a pretty big deal there's a lot
of value in using this thing especially
if you're working on a big project so
I'll be cool I think we want a little
bit more detail on the feet or the shoes
I don't know if their feet or shoes
so yeah let's soups add some detail here
something like that
uh-huh and now we got a we got a mess
around with rounding up the arms and
stuff and the main reason what we wanted
those three emeralds the two of them for
the eyes cuz villagers have green eyes
oh that looks freaky and they kind of
hold an emerald like in between their
their hands now so I wanted one over
there and I guess we'll probably put
like some more granite here for their
their actual hands you know I lowered it
by one cuz it looked a bit too tall and
we're just adding the details now to
really sell it so we're gonna try give
it a bit of a neck right I rounded out
like a an arm here and I think it looks
pretty good actually
okay we're gonna give them a coin purse
that's what the diamond block is for and
just for a little bit more texture on as
coats we will go for actually let's just
do raw andesite down the middle like
that how's it looking right now I think
we're pretty close here's the big thing
okay here's what here's a good idea
we're gonna put the fences for the nose
obviously and then get ready for this
daylight detectors for the eyebrows
perfect right I think that's I think
that's a really good idea okay let's
finish it up here or that will do
another arm so I think the arm is like
this and then we kind of curve this one
like so so it looks like it has a bit of
a bigger shoulder right and let's
actually get some slabs just for a
little bit more shape oh so you have two
slabs oh that's great yeah that works
out right
okay so put one slab there I think the
hands are maybe a little bit shaped word
but I think it'll be okay
I think we got it let's take a look at
our work here oh yeah yeah there we go
oh one more detail one more detail they
kind of have a neck a little bit of a
v-neck on these guys too right so we
should add oh let's do it with this we
just want one stare one little minor
detail addition right over here let's
change this to a stare so it looks like
a v-neck okay how we're doing oh yeah
there we go
I have an idea for something else I
wanted to check out today too we'll just
do it real quick here if we can but
basically with observers and Budd
switches in general you're able to
detect when you someone goes to bed
right like if you hook it up to the bed
you got a detect oh not that way and not
that way this way yeah so check this out
when we go to bed plays the note block
when we wake up it plays a note block so
let's see if that works
on the villagers as well so hook the
observer up there and note block here
cool now let's go to bed not a lot of
room in here all right let's just do it
out here we should be able to hear it oh
it did work oh cool so that allows us to
check when a villager goes to bed at
nighttime when he wakes up cheering the
day which is kind of cool that unlocks a
couple new redstone e things we can do
like maybe when they go home at night
time they turn on the light on that
house and you can see clearly someone's
there you know or in our case here we're
gonna try have like a campfire indicator
so basically when they go to bed this
grass block will get retracted and when
they wake up it'll they'll go back in
place which means there will be smoke
when they're sleeping basically we
easily see
someone's at that house okay it's night
time are you gonna go to that house yep
went to bed at debated our piston thing
and tada
[Music]
so you can see the smoke from a long
distance - right so we can clearly see
somebody's in that that house and like
if you were to design the house you'd
probably like put a chimney in it or
something and you could you could have
like a smoke signal that activates at
nighttime I think that would be really
cool you can see it all the way from
over here I put a hay bale under the
campfire so there's more smoke - aha so
you could put that in every single house
or you know noteblock things or maybe
you have a counter hooked ups every bed
and every day it resets and then when
they go to bed
it'll keep a census of how many
villagers are in your village you know
you got some fun things you can do with
that now when they wake up piston goes
back in place and there's no smoke all
right everybody well I decided to head
back home here because it's about time
to wrap up our episode so next episode
will probably actually get into building
some stuff on our basis getting a little
bit more technical with the updates and
for sure we will probably play with TNT
a little bit next episode because if you
guys didn't see TNT actually drops all
the blocks out now which means you can
probably use it in a lot of farms a lot
of resource collecting I'm actually
really excited about that change
if you blast it again though like if you
have some blocks on the ground already
and you TNT those get destroyed
let's throw an ender pearl down what
kind
oh I'm close to TNT yeah so then an
ender pearl got blown to bits so you
kind of have to blast it once collect
its plastic and collected so it's not
like super easy to do but when I woke up
this morning like one of the main things
I just had to find out today first thing
on my mind was I wonder I wonder if you
can do like depth charges now and like
have the blocks float up in the water is
that is that a thing
because the sand lands where the TNT is
so it allows it to blow up underwater
and it looks like all the blocks kind of
float don't they
very slowly though that's the only thing
that was pretty slow there's still some
down there that aren't gonna float -
mm-hmm cuz I was thinking you could just
keep blasting over and over with depth
charges and actually mine resources that
way but it's probably not the best
because those ones on the surface I
think would be okay yeah didn't get
blown up oh and the second blast
nothing really floated not too many not
to me blocks loaded up that time okay
I was curious I thought we would try it
out yeah most of them are staying under
under the water here because it's kind
of downward turns anyways let's do the
common the day I picked the short and
sweet one it says etho why don't you use
shaders in your LPS I might have
answered this one in the past I can't
remember but main for most reason a lot
of you guys don't like shaders so if I
use shaders in the series automatically
a lot of you guys just tune out and you
don't want to watch it gives you
headaches or whatever reasons you have
it's just it's not a good thing it
doesn't add much benefit some of you
guys might like the series a little bit
more with the shaders but then a lot of
people does this tune out entirely
so overall generally not a good idea to
use shaders when you're making an LP
series because you alienate a lot of the
viewership second main reason though is
like let's say we were to do it in our
vanilla series here you have to install
Forge so you'd have to wait for a new
forge update to come out for like 114
before you can even think about doing
the shaders so we would have to wait a
long time probably a month or two at
least whenever a new update comes out so
that wouldn't be good and the third main
reason though is like it takes a lot of
computer power to run shaders which
means my fan needs to run hard all the
time and
just generally it's not as nice while
recording if we were to do it in like
mod packs like a lot of mod packs take
up a lot of computer power as well
you're just barely getting enough
framerate so if you add shaders on top
of that it's not a great experience
either so you got to really pick and
choose your series where you use shaders
it's generally never a good idea but
sometimes I do it just because I like
them a lot uh-huh like in the terra
firma craft one that time anyways that's
gonna do it for today hopefully you guys
enjoyed this episode thank you for
watching as always if you guys got ideas
for the next episode let me know in the
comments until then take care have a
good day bye bye
[Music]