what is this bunch of cheaters if I
can't fly you can't fly that's the rules
did I place blocks here this is getting
weird
uh-huh well I can't go any higher
oh my shirts my shirts on we got an e
throw on my back J he's looking down at
me he's trying to figure out how to get
me oh oh oh that worked that did
something oh now I'm really in trouble
here ah alright alright enough of enough
of this oh yeah he's down oh man
so how's it going everybody this is
ether welcome back guys I am here at the
poppy farm right now so we lost a couple
villagers here I was trying to figure
out what to do about that if I should
bring more or actually the easiest way
is probably just to feed them they're
probably really hungry and they should
make new villagers from that and then I
don't have to do anything right because
this is a village because we have eight
currently oh yeah he's got hearts
already no I missed
Oh get me back up there good Oh perfect
landing tube okay this is a little bit
later now there's three in there there
was two before so we definitely got a
baby so it seems like it's working
still only four there and then there's
only two here that's nine total we need
ten for it to start producing the iron
golems again I fed these two but they
haven't made a baby oh oh they're
sharing food did you see that all right
I'm sure they'll do it in time I just
got to wait a little longer let me show
you guys what I've been up to I've been
working on that that eats road tunnel
and I think it's coming along pretty
good all right so it's just down here
and oh you know what we should try out
today maybe the rabbit farm here they
changed the the behavior of the rabbits
and I haven't tried this thing out yet
that hasn't been used at all really
because before they were more like pets
and they would teleport around now they
don't do that so I can actually farm
them a little easier so this is the
tunnel this is a design I start or I
decided to go with it's just about done
there's still this downward slope area I
got to work out the details too but this
is the design I decide to try out I
think it's kind of cool I'm hoping this
carpet doesn't catch fire so far it
hasn't which has surprised me I think it
might be out of range
lava and fire behave differently in
terms of how they catch stuff on fire
I'm pretty sure otherwise this would
have went up in flames already if it
worked the same as fire but yeah we got
cyan carpet running down and then it's
sort sort of like a little dome section
at each of these kind of cool got lights
in the sides got to put the water down
and get some signs go and then we can
probably test it out I have not figured
out how to do the corners yet or the
launching stuff so that's that's
probably what we'll do together here
yeah alright guys so we're going to do
some eats Road research here this could
be fun it's been a while since we tried
this eats road or eats stands for ethos
advanced ramps trans
rotation system it's an old design I
came up with boats you make like boat
roads but unfortunately game mechanics
kind of changed on the way and now
they're even more fragile than ever
before you look at a boat and it breaks
now it's insane so I don't know how this
is going to go down we're going to try
it out so one of my old favorite things
was what I called an ez loader which is
basically this setup here this was a way
of loading boats into a system and
aligning them properly against the wall
let's see if it still works basically
you get a boat and you place it right in
the middle here and it should go
underneath it might've you know what I
never did I never put the water here
let's try it again can I get this back
please oh that is nice
oops when I used to play around with
researching this stuff I just I had to
chop down so many trees because every
boat you would lose a little bit of wood
when you would test it out now you can
actually get the boat back though and
good oh wait woah yeah oh yeah that's
minecraft oh man I don't think it's
working I think it's stuck oh man oh I
wonder you know what maybe I didn't have
a block over top so it possibly floated
up and can't get underneath I think it's
like stuck here somewhere oh yeah it is
all it's kind of under underneath here
what's going on oh it's stuck in the
glass panes I think no yes
Oh No okay where are we all right we got
out let's try it one more time with the
blocks should hold the boat down and it
just explodes great so that is not off
to a good start not at all
let's try one more time we'll hop in at
this time actually let me if we're going
to do that let's change this out to
glass okay here we go yeah it hit the
glass panes hmm
are they fatter now because this used to
work like not long ago now it doesn't
seem to fit between a block in it and
like a half here huh that could be a
problem
uh-huh okay I got to figure it out here
guys so what what it's doing I think the
boat is still rotating when it hits the
wall here so it's not perfectly aligned
against it so it's like over a little
bit and then it hits get the glass panes
because it's not in the right spot if we
yeah if you notice there's like a little
gap between the wall and the boat still
we got to get all the way over to the
left I think it's not letting me move it
when I try though oh man oh man I'm in a
boat I actually I don't know because it
looks like it it's within the glass
panes right there's a little bit of gap
there but there's also a little bit of a
gap between the boat and the wall let's
see if we can push it any closer
it might just no I doesn't go at all it
doesn't budge so that is it's like it's
fatter now yeah it is actually fatter
now that's that's weird
all right that's no good that's no good
at all that means the glass panes in the
middle are not going to work boat to fat
we're going to try the old ladder way
instead then we will have to do the
water like this or else put pressure
plates in the middle to keep it from
flowing all over the place here let's
put a block here to water here all right
and if this is the way we have to do it
then I have to redesign the tunnel you
know maybe just maybe we should have
tried to figure out
to how to do it before I designed it
that might have been the way of going
about it but no I build it then I find
out it doesn't work and then I change it
that's that's the easy way this still
works
Wow all right that works that is great
um does not look quite as good let's see
what could we do here
oh I'm drowning if we just move these
out one block how bad is that going to
look and put a ladder on it
there is no netherrack ladders or nether
brick ladders or anything like that
unfortunately so this might be hard to
to fix and make look good can't place
ladder on that ah why can't you put
pressure plates on glass and stuff I
never understood that like is there
actually a reason for it I wonder um mm
okay let me get my blocks how else could
we do this because if we just put like
this on it and then bladder ah so much
worse isn't it the ladder is I was
really hoping we could avoid using the
ladders too because then now we're
mixing wood with nether brick and that's
just
ah too bad okay option two no ladders
let's just try to use the fences they
stick out a lot more which I don't like
as much but they do blend in like I want
to see if it's like really in our face
now and if it's not too bad
oh and it doesn't even work what Oh
because yes this gap from from this half
to this is over the boat width actually
you know what we can use the fat boats
to our advantage here because before if
you want to put blocks in the middle
you'd have to use full blocks and it was
kind of yeah not quite so nice we could
get away with using panes or even like
nether brick fences running down the
middle one block up and the boat
should stay down right let's try it out
then we could still keep the design on
the walls we wouldn't have to change
anything I think we might be on to
something
all right yes this actually works well I
might just do glass panes actually I
think they might look a little better a
little less intrusive
okay so playing around with some more
stuff here glass panes in the middle I
don't think that looks too bad right
kind of like that we might just do a
really simple launcher here so I got the
easy loader I put a dispenser here and
this actually works it'll dispense the
boats and they seem to get stuck
underneath the glass which is cool and
basically they come by you'd have to
catch the boat while it goes by though
it doesn't hold it which is me being
just a little bit lazy the only problem
is when I get in it does that and I
don't know exactly what happens there
because the game D sinks a little bit
and it's hard to tell if I actually make
the jump here if I if I like fall down
or what or if I actually break the boat
up here like the pieces of the boat are
down there you see this is the pieces
but my player ends up up there so I
don't know actually you know what we
might try just yeah let's do this let's
let's put some water down here and see
what it does with that oh that melted
quick yeah that that should stop it from
breaking so if the boat is actually
going down it should be different this
time right a lot of trial and error
trying to figure this out
oh okay so it is actually going down all
right
that's good to know so I got to make it
do a jump here and then catch a water
stream and get underneath the pains in
the middle again
for coming back up to the hill we're
going to do slime launchers which is
something I tried a long time ago and it
actually worked
so I think we can pull that off
basically we're trying to do a little
bit of everything here we want to do a
launcher I'm trying to do it an uphill
downhill section and then a corner and
hopefully we can pull all these off that
would be pretty cool
all right cool so I got a little bit
more done here I got the downhill worked
out I haven't done the uphill and I
experimented a little bit with the
corner the corner is tough to do boats
break so easily
it's insane even with cobwebs um so yeah
let's just do one one more drive one
more ride here and then we'll go do
something else I think for today so kind
of dee sinks there and then it catches
up it's weird but it gets underneath the
glass panes no problem so that's good
it's working pretty pretty well yeah
let's go and let's go try out that
rabbit thing I want to see if that farm
still works with the changes to the
rabbit behavior so just let me drop off
some of our stuff okay let's go so yeah
rabbits like they don't teleport to you
anymore so this farm might work a lot
better now close your eyes children oh
I'm sorry I didn't warn you far enough
in advance there so before I used to
have to tie them down with the leads so
they went teleport away I don't think
that's required anymore so got some
carrots here they were trampling all my
crops and stuff too so shouldn't be a
problem with them staying put now
whoa oh man they got up somehow
they're like a bunch of balloons all
tied to strings trying to float away
they are dying like crazy what is going
on we got one guy here oh yeah they all
jumped out somehow oh and I'm trapped
all right so I'll have to build this up
higher it looks like before they weren't
able to get out and let's try feed them
they don't jump anymore either it looks
like so I might have to put some water
down there so that I can feed them okay
so I built it up a little bit higher
they shouldn't be able to get out now I
think what we'll do here as well oh did
I lose that oh no oh I died got it here
okay so that's right yeah so touch of
course so these guys they don't need to
be on leads anymore so I'm gonna try
free them right clicking does not seem
to be working though oh there we go i
freed them all in one click there okay
so they're free that's good and see I
got some the care Tommy let's see if we
can breed them without them jumping I
think they have to be jumping otherwise
we're gonna have trouble here can I even
reach them I don't know if I can no okay
so this might be a this might have to be
a half slab
because if it's only what it is right
now they can get out and if it's if it's
a log up then I can't reach it so let's
try it in between solution here
hopefully this will still hold them oh
he's trying to get out all right now I
can reach them hopefully yeah it seems
to be working we got some baby bunnies
down here I'm wondering if I'm gonna try
one more thing here I'm gonna try change
this out with a half slab they're not
free good oh I can't place it though oh
there we go we got it can I get rid of
this one I'm thinking it might be easier
to feed them this way I can feed them
from from the front instead of having to
climb up but I think the babies will
just fall out through there hmm
yeah if it's like that I can't reach
them so all right maybe I'll just keep
it the way it was yeah it should work a
little bit better now oops
all right maybe we'll head over to the
Nexus next year I did a ton of work on
there nothing like new but I got a lot
of the repetitive stuff done today spent
a few hours on it so let's go take a
look at that please let me place this
where I want to it's not letting me at
all
all right so here's the Nexus update
guys basically I think the wall used to
be about over here like this was a solid
wall all the way down so I cleared out
all this land then I built these front
faces no facades is that the right word
face plates that's what I like the
column yeah built the face plates if we
go down I also started working on a
bunch of the redstone this part is like
nuts because I can't see
so dumb I can't see what I did before
cuz it's all so compact and covered up
yeah I got all this redstone done as
well um we're just about to start the
second layer on this stuff actually yeah
so this is what I'm working off of I
have to try copy this and I can't see
what I did so stupid so I I stare at it
try to memorize it then I walk over
build a little bit forget I have to come
back and look at it again and try to
make out what it is and yeah this is a
nightmare
but little by little it's coming
together the second layer to this is
going to start umm where maybe we should
try figure that out so we need I think
this is the lowest point on it so how
tall is this all one two three four five
six seven eight blocks tall no it's got
to be more than that alright it's eight
over here oh that is the top wait a
minute no because we need a water stream
here yet
so water nine if we have like redstone
above these hoppers that might cause
trouble - is there any redstone there no
so it's about nine bucks tall that means
the second layer is gonna start hey
let's get some stone bricks yeah we need
one block for the water so water has to
run over top these hoppers I think we
can start the next layer there then that
means yeah okay it looks like we need
one block for the redstone to go on then
the redstone level then this is level 3
level 4 and then the next faceplate
would start five blocks
from that so see do we have any more
cordis I think we're running low on
quarts I need to get more cords that's
like the worst block to get so one two
three four the next face plates in
relation to this would start here then
so they go up four blocks and the stairs
go over top like that all right
so somehow we need to tie that in and I
think I'm going to try make up a
platform up I to so we can walk and
access the the droppers in the chests
like we can down here so there would be
a platform sticking out a little bit
higher here like at this level sticking
out at least two blocks I would think
maybe three hopefully that's not too bad
that'll give you that that should give
you an idea of the height of the
building but yeah anyways guys we'll
have to work on this another day because
we're we don't have the courts or
anything to really play around with it
but we'll have to try make something
cool like in these five blocks between
and try make it look good it would
probably look better if like I move that
back a block or two so it's not
perfectly straight all the way up but
for the simplicity sake of the project
I'm not going to do that I'm going to
keep it straight because all the
redstone in the back and stuff in the
water streams I think I'll just be
easier if everything is straight and and
easy to figure out um
because like oops this middle part the
redstone from this side of the panel and
and this one are pretty much going to be
touching in the middle here and we can't
move them any closer together we could
only move them further apart so yeah to
keep things smaller it's it's just
better to keep it all straight
anyway I'm right
let's get to the comment for today this
one says I talked about the hunger bar
last episode like how it used to be
compared to how it is now and somebody
replied and said I have mixed feelings
about the hunger bar
I like how you regenerate health now I'm
not a huge fan of bringing around a ton
of food with me either it is nice to
have instant house boost after you eat
to have an instant yeah wait what yeah
I'm not a huge fan of bringing around a
ton of food with me either it is nice to
have an instant health boost after you
eat if you're down to one heart now and
you're in the middle of several mobs
then you have practically no chance of
surviving if your food is down I also
like how in the old patches you could
instantly eat the food okay I think I
get that like if you're being swarmed by
mobs before you could just like eat um
like 10 10 steaks one after another and
you could take so many hearts of damage
if you did it right all at once so yeah
that is kind of one of the benefits of
the new hunger system I like that as
well
like if you get swarmed you deserve to
die I think um yeah there's positive
things about both of them one of the
things I did like about the old one
though like he says or she says you
don't they don't like bring around a ton
of food with them yeah that's that's
true it kind of stinks having your
inventory full but then on the other
hand in the past I used to not carry
food with me because it was so annoying
after having to have in your inventory
so I would die a lot as a result of that
and I kind of think that made the game
more fun like when you you're at risk
you know I don't know there's there's
mixed feelings about it for sure both
systems at their benefits and their
flaws I think anyway we are going to
have to end the episode here I thank you
guys for watching hope you enjoyed it
I'll see you in the next one take
there have a good day bye-bye