[Music]
readings everybody this is etho and
welcome to another let's play episode
how you doing you got enough toilet
paper hopefully you do or is it gonna
get nasty uh yeah welcome to the
underground village do you notice the
difference I did a big big update on it
but it looks pretty much exactly the
same basically got rid of all the
torches we used to have torches all over
the ground here and we have now switched
over to hidden lighting we got the lamps
down here in places I wanted to start
off talking about my new buddy here the
grind stone I have recently become very
interested with this guy I don't know
about you guys like when I first came
out I was like okay that's kind of a
cool thing you can you didn't put two
pieces of gear together and they give
your ability bonus and and disenchant
things for a little bit of experience
probably the biggest thing is getting
rid of the enchantments on something and
although the work on a tool so you can
start fresh with it is a pretty cool but
now recently I've been doing some
testing with it a bit more and it's like
oh oh this thing might actually have
some crazy potential so one of the
biggest things is I think it's the
ultimate way of storing portable
experience in the game so you can have
your chakra box in your end chest carry
that wherever you go then inside the
chakra box you got a grindstone and you
have a crazy enchanted book so you can
combine a bunch of enchantments onto a
book I think this one has 15 on it put
down your your grindstone and disenchant
it and you get the experience from all
of those and normally like that you
disenchant something it does it gives
you a little bit of experience but it's
not anything crazy but when you've
combined like 15 different things it
starts to add up I think I was seeing it
giving like about 300 experience at
times even let's test it out here though
so I'm still like in the testing phase
trying to figure out if it's actually
good or not this pitch has 33 durability
at the moment it has mending on it put
this in
disenchant now here's the biggest thing
about it as well it's dense experience
so normally experienced so you only get
a little bit at a time but when you
absorb this we got our pick up to 611
there uh-huh
so I thought that was kind of
interesting it's like fast easy portable
experience as long as you have those
crazy enchanted books but that's where
the idea probably falls apart because
how do you get those crazy enchanted
books I think the ideal way of doing it
would be to set up a villager trading
hall get their trades down to one
emerald each and then have like 12 to 16
different enchantments you could buy
from them and then you have to combine
them together on an anvil to make it
super dense crazy book when you consider
everything though it's probably not
worth the time it would take to create
the books for it at best it might
function as an emergency repair kit like
if you're far away from an experienced
farm it could be an easy way of
repairing your tools if you get stranded
and something's about to break I wanted
to point this guy out to you I'm gonna
call him cheap though this is a weird
villager he's like from before they
revamp the villager trades I think and
I've discovered he doesn't need to
restock so I can just press spacebar to
refill it cue spacebar spacebar Tuesdays
for cue and that's kind of nice I don't
know if I should take advantage of that
or if it's if you guys would view it as
cheating anyways I think the goal for
today guys is just to do a bunch of
random projects I have a few ideas in
mind starting with this guy there you go
and he does didn't suffocate very good
didn't I get you out of there
haha okay what if we do this look at
this guy I made you a path it's a
wonderful path yet you go up and you go
down okay now I block you in now he's in
place and he was able to check out my
redstone here everybody's happy uh-huh
what did I say about this one guys this
is a really goofy gizmo I call it the D
colonizer 9000 if you are like me and
you don't have a working iron farm in
your world you need other ways of saving
on iron costs that's where the D
colonizer 9000 comes into place we got
this guy here we go on the bucket of cod
trade hit Q a bunch of times the buckets
get emptied of the cod and they wind up
down here and then over time eventually
the cod suffocate and they end up in
here Oh looks like a couple went in
there if you use if you fast some will
end up in here I think beautiful okay so
the way this works is pretty simple we
got ourselves a fisherman villager next
to his barrel workstation and a bed that
allows them to refill his trade when it
gets exhausted and it gets cheaper the
more you use this one so it went from
three to two let's see in the back here
it's pretty straightforward the
dispenser ejects the cod in the bucket
and we have a comparator to check if
there's any items in here if there is it
runs on a pulse this is in subtract mode
and then we have an item filter
underneath that that picks up the
buckets this is the standard standard
item filter here this is what grabs the
Cod puts it in this barrel or any other
random thing that doesn't belong
next project okay so we spend a lot of
time in this area we got our tree farm
over there I use that thing all the time
now
we got the Nexus we got the super
smelter we got this village I still
haven't built there's some other random
stuff over here so this is like a pretty
key area in our world and right next to
it is our Guardian farm which I feel
I've kind of realized I'm underutilizing
at the moment like it's so close to our
main area the way I set this up is
actually pretty crummy now that I look
at it so we got an auto sorting system
for it and stuff which is cool that's
all kind of taken care of it's an old
system though you can hear the drop or
elevator activating which is annoying we
can up upgrade that with a bubble stream
the big issue with this farm though is
there's no way to manually kill the
guardians they just fall down here and
die on top of the hoppers so it's a
passive only farm we want to add in a
switch here so that we can choose if we
want to kill them or not because
Guardians actually give a lot of
experience they give 10 points each
while most hostile mobs only give you 5
except for like blazes they also give
you 10 so this would make a great
experience farm if we set it up properly
I think we couldn't even switch out this
with this new warp planks maybe but I
think what we'll do is let's try it here
probably you just put some hoppers
underneath this quartz this way they
don't fall us far oh I don't know how
much help they're gonna have I need to
be able to one-shot them with a sword
though
oh really huh well that I did not expect
maybe we do planks here as well also I
built this a long time ago and it looks
like it has a few issues now with the
pathfinding so they fall in the lava and
they try to get out well before they
would just fall right through and as a
result a lot of them are just dying in
the lava and it's killing our rates like
crazy in the lava
I think the lava needs to go bye-bye
yeah it definitely helped a lot
I made a new sword here as well that has
sweeping edge three on because the other
one I was using didn't have it now we
can test this out properly I'm
experimenting with a killing chamber
idea like maybe we'd do something like
that where we have the trap door above
that way it holds us in place so one
swing there seems to have killed wait a
few yeah sweeping edge definitely helps
a lot I think they're all gone pretty
much pretty much can you see they're
coming in a much faster now than they
were before
whoops this isn't gonna work
Master Oh I'm messed up so bad guys oh
they're still getting in oh man that was
scary i disrespected the Guardians there
I tried modifying the farm without
shutting it off properly and they
started to get free and I couldn't close
it up and then yeah I died like three
times in a row they're trying to get my
stuff back thankfully I didn't lose
anything
shut it off properly this time and this
is how I modified it so the idea is we
stand here they don't seem to be able to
shoot through this area and we can get
in and out of this nice and easy do I
like that we gotta add some hoppers
under the courts here yeah so check this
out I think we're gonna rip out this big
hopper chain we have here it leads to an
item elevator which we're also gonna rip
out and all the Redstone for it over
here place that with a bubble stream and
then that goes to a big chain of hoppers
that runs over some item filters we'll
leave the item filters but we'll get rid
of this top chain of poppers and replace
that with a water stream as well those
are gonna have to go to a dropper and
then the dropper is gonna have to shoot
the items into a water stream and we're
gonna hear that constant ticking sound I
was trying to avoid so I just have
another idea maybe we get rid of the
quartz here get rid of the hoppers all
together and we try set it up so that
trap door is open upward
and then any items on top of that oh do
they not fall through oh never mind
that's not gonna work oh fence gates
guys the perfect solution here so these
are great because they're a block and a
half tall it was gonna be very difficult
to power anything at this level but if
we can go down a block with the fence
gates that makes it a lot easier to do
the redstone and these have an a nice
additional effect that stuff can fall
through between them so as the guardians
diet most the drops are gonna fall down
below and go into the hoppers and then
after a while we'll just want to open
them to drop anything that lands on top
of them okay so this killing chamber is
actually getting kind of complicated
there's a lot of problems we gotta solve
with doing this so the good news is they
don't seem to be falling between the
fence gates the guardians are big big
enough that they don't fall down and we
don't want them to the next issue I kind
of found out is some of the experience
will fall down through the fence gates
as we're killing them which isn't good
so we have to like create a way of
getting the experience that falls down
back up to us also got a our water
elevator hair that should be good I
think
you got this whole sand down below there
let's go back up here so what I did like
as we kill the guys here this double
check it actually works so we get most
of the experience most of it comes to us
but some of it is gonna fall down there
so what I ended up doing is putting a
iron trap door here because experienced
and pass through that if it goes
underneath us and then we got a little
chamber here a little hole that the
experience can travel through into here
and then up to the iron trap door here
excellent so check that out I got the
redstone installed through this thing
now so we go in here we make our kills
they drop their stuff some of its gonna
land on top of the fence gates you can
see it floating around out there
so then when we back up we step on a
pressure plate and that opens the fence
gates for a split second all the drops
on top fall down into the water stream
and occasionally I have noticed a couple
Guardians will fall through as well it
doesn't happen usually because they're
always jumping around and it's only if
they get unlucky they'll go through if
they do go through though we have a
killing thing at the end here for them
but items come up the water go over top
all the item filters and then any
guardians that get through end up
hitting these magma blocks and dying and
the way we did the redstone here isn't
quite ideal but it works like we're not
designing this thing from scratch I
gotta make it work with what we had
there so we you see the fence gates over
there
repeater powers it through the block we
run a redstone torch up to the repeater
and another redstone torch here another
repeater and they all each of these runs
to an individual fence gate and then in
the middle here we run it up to a
monostable circuit and the pressure
plate powers the repeaters here okay so
check it out guys ivory added the lava
blade so that we can run the farm
passively like they will die from mob
cramming but you need like so many
Guardians down there for to happen this
is a more reliable way of doing it
unfortunately we will lose some drops in
the lab a blade but it's not a huge
issue the other thing is we have a
system in place here for sending the
Guardians to a nether farm a little
weird we hit that button the pistons
extend and close off the way down here
and water gets ejected and then they it
lights a portal and they get sent
through the nether that way and you can
turn that on and off just by clicking
the button like a so
and checked it out down below here you
can see the guardians are on fire
they'll burn up and then the drops will
either fall down between the fence gates
there or they might land on top you can
see some of the items are on top
unfortunately we have to clear those so
I installed a hopper clock down here
this just triggers every like minute to
two minutes I think I got a bunch of
items in here when it triggers it goes
to the fence gate control here oh you
heard it so that just released a bunch
of the items and that'll prevent stuff
from getting stuck this only runs when
we're in automatic mode though when we
switch over to manual killing mode the
hopper clock doesn't run and we have a
switch for that over here now so right
now it's an auto we switch to manual
that shuts off the lavvo blade up above
and the hopper clock down below and any
remaining guys on fire should burn up
here and then we're gonna start getting
the other guys accumulated also I've
added another switch here for the nether
that that'll turn the portal on and stop
them from coming down here if we switch
that oh yeah now you can see they're
starting to build up oh when you go back
to killing the manually here and then
when we step on the pressure plate
that'll drop anything on the fence deeds
down below as well my favorite thing
about this though is we got it to work
without any annoying dropper sounds
which is incredible that was kind of
hard to do but we made it work this is
only part of the plan though we've spent
a bit of time on this today longer than
I expected but the other thing I want to
do is rip out a bunch of this tunnel
maybe instead of having the way up and
down here way over there we'll probably
move it closer to the killing area and I
want to add an enchanting area down here
now that we're gonna be able to get
experience and this is also where I'm
planning on building like a villager
trading hall I think would be very good
because this is very fast experience and
you need experience to like combine the
books you buy from the villagers to your
tools and stuff okay so next project
here
the zombie pigmen farm and we have an
issue that's been around for a while now
actually we have these slime pushers
that knock the experience points to the
center here and they used to all end up
at the slime block in the very middle
but you can see a lot of it is not
anymore and it gets launched up to us
when we stand in the center platform
there but the problem is most of it is
not making it to the center anymore and
it's not getting launched up so I'm
gonna try replace the packed ice here
with blue ice which should be a little
bit more slippery check it out it works
again yeah so the blue ice did the trick
it can get to the middle no problem now
I don't know if you guys know this but I
actually have a bad habit of not
finishing things so it just occurred to
me this zombie pigmen farm that I use
all the time like it's one of my most
used farms in the world believe it or
not does not have an enchanting table
even let's add one usually I like
charged up on XP here and then go
somewhere else to do it and I don't know
it just never occurred to me hey maybe I
should actually just add an enchanting
table here it's so dumb alright so we're
gonna do 15 bookshelves around it and
then we will oh oh man I'm one short
really ah that sucks
okay I didn't bring any wood with me
okay we're gonna put carpet over top
we're going to underneath here I think
I'm gonna add some barrels just for
storing books and other things we need
cool so we got that installed up here
now I had to raise it up one more block
because otherwise it was obstructing the
view of the top layer here we got the
barrels we can store stuff in I put an
ender chest over here and then the
enchanting table above that
and go to town and yeah it's gonna be
nice I wish I had this a long time ago
to be honest with you I haven't used the
blast furnace very much I know it's
meant for ores but I'm wondering if it
does the swords it does okay so the gold
farm also doesn't really deal with
swords at the moment I think we
shouldn't smelt them down into Nuggets
maybe get our redstone chest out here
yeah so the gold swords from the zombie
Pigman farm they kind of just fall down
here and they just sit on the bedrock
and D spawn over time it's not a good
method of dealing with them honestly it
causes a lot of lag and I just never
bothered to fix it it's like a running
theme or something here so what we're
gonna do is set up a blast furnace here
and that way like we can put them in
here and they'll gets melted down but
anyways guys I hate to do it to you but
I'm gonna have to cut this episode a bit
on the shorter side today otherwise I
got that delay it another day and you
probably don't want that but I'm totally
out of time here I'm supposed to be in
bed right now says etho you can easily
fix the zombie Pigman farm by replacing
all the spawn platforms with magma
blocks zombie Pigman can spawn magma
blocks but pagans can't uh-huh
I liked how he threw the word easily in
there that's kind of what I'm trying to
avoid doing I know it's fixable but I
don't know if you guys know this it took
me I think six hours or something to
build that farm originally not counting
block collection time so to tear it down
and rebuild it and collect magma blocks
it's gonna take like ten hours at least
I don't want to do that if I can help it
we can I think maybe cheese it if we get
the fungi I think the pig at the pig man
the pig Lynn's are afraid of the fungi
and we can chase him off the platform
with that maybe and that would be a lot
easier to do than replacing the entire
thing and rebuilding it
so that's kind of what I want to try out
first but anyways that's gonna do it for
this episode guys so thank you for
watching I hope you enjoyed it and take
care you have yourselves a good day
bye bye
[Music]