hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
back guys this is it we got it look at
this empty empty empty empty empty get
away spider you will not wreck this
moment for me last load of items to put
in to the Nexus and then it should have
one of everything pretty much in it I've
done a lot to this again today but we're
not we're not going to spend the whole
episode here we've been spending a lot
of time at the Nexus lately but I have a
few things I do want to show you here we
go last load those will funnel into the
system so yeah check this out guys I've
added in a display today got eight
lights up here now they show us what
code we have selected at the moment so
if we press three for example that would
be one one zero zero so one one zero
zero if we press it again it applies to
the other other set of memory here and
by doing this we can choose what item we
want to get out of the Nexus depending
on what code we enter and we can
actually see what code we have selected
now which is really cool
glad we got that I fixed up all those
problems we were having last episode but
there are still a couple issues I don't
really understand like this is happening
why is this happening I don't know let's
grab them a couple issues with this
elevator I've never had trouble with
these elevators before now strange
things are happening which I'm going to
have to get sorted out occasionally I've
seen a couple items sitting at the top
here too I don't know why like they'll
land on the glass sometimes but other
than that it seems to be running okay so
items are going into the system they're
getting sorted out where they need to go
and if we go look down one of these
hallways now hopefully ooh
we're doing this all live right now
I've been trying to do this jump all day
today and I've messed up pretty much
every single time yeah so oh no you
don't go there what was that about
Oh No why is Stone getting into these
wait why Stone it's getting one stone in
each of these for some reason stone
stone what whoa
pink dye now I think we have problems
darn it glass glass okay that's good
maybe we just had a couple oh no still
issues filler oh we don't want that to
come out Oh
still not not 100% it looks like darn it
okay okay couple issues guys I don't
know why there's stone going into each
of these let's check the side that one's
okay whoa clay good good no stone in
these ones this one's missing for some
reason what wait okay that's that one's
good oh man this is all so complicated
and messy it's crazy that's my goal
though I got to refine this make it
perfect and eventually maybe with enough
persistence we will work out all the
kinks here that looks good we have the
six types of wood six planks no stone
should be six types of fences yeah
that's good
dirt course dirt uh-huh oh that's empty
wait if that's grass
oh you know what I probably have pods
alai probably never put the pods all in
alright for the most part this seems to
be okay I don't know why that top row
there was messed up
the other
Rose seemed okay but I'll have to look
over it a little bit better you know
what it is I think I just solved the
mystery like I just checked all the
droppers some of them had stone in quite
a few of them had stone in some had dirt
in some had other random things like as
we were doing tests we we were putting
items into the droppers and I think also
before I put in the filters like like
the item here um I was digging out this
room and and stone was like falling from
the ceiling into these hoppers and that
still was in the dropper from before I
never cleaned them out so it's not
because it got sorted him properly
also there was filler blocks in some of
these because like ender pearls
well maybe not maybe not if we if we put
one of these in here is that messed it
up no it's good okay that's good so I
think it's all all fine I think it's all
good just some random junk fell in the
hoppers and I never clean it out from
long ago not not now okay so now guys we
are doing some benchmarking here trying
to figure out how fast the Nexus
actually is I put it in a random code
and it was for pink wall I found out so
I just tracked it down here turns out
it's a at the very end of the Nexus
pretty much so it's about as far as an
item can travel to get to us it's got to
go all the way down here and then fall
down go to go through a whole bunch of
ice streams eventually it winds up in
the middle load all the way over here so
if we request an item this is the code
for pink wool apparently so if we pull
this as soon as we pull this lever the
time it takes for the pink wool to get
here is kind of what I'm checking and it
is a little bit long unfortunately items
can only travel so fast you know
it's like maybe 10 seconds oh no that
was not 10 seconds I just checked our
video here to be precise and that was
about 17 seconds so at the max from the
time we pull the lever to
about 17 seconds for our request to get
delivered plus the amount of time it
takes for us to to get the item so it
takes point 2 seconds per item per item
yeah per it and if we're requesting 64
like a stack of items times point to
that is twelve point eight seconds so
seventeen plus twelve point eight at the
most like to get to request the stack of
items it'll take about thirty seconds
for it to get here so that's that's
reasonable I would say for only
requesting white one item though and
it's close to us it might take it only
ten seconds or so so there's going to be
a little bit of variation within how
long it takes items to get here I think
that's not too bad it's about as good as
you can get I mean I've tried really
hard to optimize this thing and I think
we'll have to live with that alright so
we're going to move on here pretty quick
guys I just want to show you one more
thing the next step what I got to do
next with this project to move forward
with it basically I got to go through
all the codes here starting with zero
zero so no lights on zero zero requests
the item I don't know what item we're
going to get here doesn't really matter
too much I kind of would like some
logistical order to it like like if
we're requesting wood I would like wood
to kind of be all grouped together oh
it's cool okay we got coal that's fine
so then what we got to do take one one
piece of this coal and since we use the
code zero zero there we're label it zero
zero and then put in one of these chests
and then zero one would go here zero two
zero three and it's going to form a
table where we can just hover our mouse
over to see what the code is for for
that item and that way we don't have to
remember the codes in our head we need
some way of like checking it and since
it's got an extra piece Ariens put it
back in the system move on to the next
one which would be zero
one right Oh dad press those two quick
together I wonder zero one wait what
what let's press it one more time okay I
think those got out of the sink I might
make it so that side resets once it
starts on this one again I'm not sure
although actually if we do one zero it's
going to turn this light on then zero
zero zero zero zero zero zero that's
what I want
is that right one zero would come next
did I do something reversed here I might
have done something reversed because I
want I want it to go in binary order
here where this these lights come on
first then these ones okay we got lapis
so that that is correct I'm pretty sure
that's an ore like the coal is so this
would be one zero all people are going
to be raging I'm not sure if that's
right I think it's supposed to go zero
one next those problem but I seem to
have done something wrong here yeah I'm
almost certain next one would be add to
zero maybe I can flip the display so
that'll fix everything because I think
that would do the trick right okay
anyways that's kind of the next thing I
got to do I might have to look into why
that seems to be reversed alright
everybody so I decided let's head over
to our amplified base here next and
we're going to do a little project here
something I've been wanting to do for a
while like a year but just never got
around to doing it so we're going to do
it today we need a better name than that
- by the way amplified bass just sounds
very
generalize doesn't it doesn't really
doesn't really catch we need a good name
for this place so if you guys have ideas
do let me know in the comments but yeah
like a long time ago I made this slime
block launcher thing and tried to build
it on a server and it didn't work on the
server but it works great in
single-player um I've never built in
single-player so that's what we're going
to do here we are going to make a slime
block launcher to go from here to there
we're going to dig a tunnel in the
mountain there and it should lead up to
another area we built further down here
we're going to try to chain them
together several slime block launchers
and just see what that is like so here I
think what we got to do we'll put down I
guess we only need one piston because
we're using slime blocks tools they'll
stick together this will have to be note
blocks or something that doesn't move no
blocks there we go alright so this
actually maybe this goes down well we'll
try it at this level first the idea is
though this is going to push us up and
then we're going to have another
sideways pusher let's put it I think it
was three blocks up so like up here and
this will push us sideways when we get
knocked up and yes I just said knocked
up I'm not pregnant you do not prove
anything it never happened all right and
that should be good okay so I'm going to
run some redstone here
I guess the pressure plates will go or
should we use tripwire I don't know I'll
try to figure it out here we'll see how
this works okay here we go guys so this
is pretty simple as it is right now to
step on this this goes up and then two
redstone ticks later this goes out as
well and then I retract so if we run we
should get lift off here I hope we did
not
darn it okay why did we not get liftoff
is it because we got to move this one
forward maybe I bet you that's what it
is yeah I'm going to try move the top
one it forward one more block oh is this
gonna kill me go to pain now we're fine
we're good alright attempt number two
let's give it a go Oh No
darn it okay maybe I got a lower one
block I have this all figured out before
but I think the creative world where I
figured out is gone so I have to kind of
remember how to rebuild it and test
number three so it's it's lowered and
pulled back one let's give it a go oh no
still no still no good ah oh oh oh no oh
no that was a skeleton all right all
right
heal up heal up lots of baddies around
here maybe if I change the timing on it
that will do the trick because we've
tried every combination now and none of
them have worked okay okay check it out
check it out this is so cool whoa whoa
all right
so I did move it back up so we got a
little bit of headroom here which is
nice I didn't like it all load lowdown
and cramped and I lowered it here so
it's one below the pressure plates what
I got it at is a timing of three on that
repeater so we got redstone underneath
here right still underneath there and
then it goes up or it goes down to this
piston first powers this block goes down
and then another repeater on one tick to
go to the top piston here and that seems
to do the trick very nicely so now what
I want to do is chain these together
so um and I wanted to work two ways to
not just one way I want to work both
ways so I'm going to build like a
pretend one over here so let's imagine
we have another pusher up here to knock
us this way let's see what how smoothly
we can enter onto this platform if it's
in this position all right so we don't
really want to hit our head on that top
one there but we want to land on the
bottom all right here we go oh we're
shorts we're a little bit short so we
might need to move it forward one block
and that'll probably be our distance
here Oh Oh didn't activate oh I don't
have my weapon equipped wait let's not
fight that guy's about to jump down and
tackle him but that would have been
pretty bad alright so I'm starting to
set up a second one over there but it
doesn't seem to be working quite right
okay let's see if we can get it whoa
yeah I don't know why but I can't get it
to trigger the second time whoa that
wasn't quite right here let's try let's
try run from here like this one's not
hitting us for some reason the top one
oh it does this we run from there might
just because it might just be because of
where we're positioned after that
happens whoa yeah then trigger again
very strange exactly oh no no no no no
no no no always a stupid silverfish
get out of here oh oh he's so little I
can't hit him got him got him
whew that was close
well I've been doing some testing here
and it seems to be based on where we
start running like I put a border here
so if we align ourselves right against
these blocks it seems to work every time
then whoo and oh it didn't work now what
I wonder maybe it's because I'm
recording in my frame rate slower
because I locked my frame rate at 30
otherwise I get about 120 oh at that
time it seems very inconsistent
unfortunately I was hoping like we could
chain a bunch of these together and they
would kind of flow smoothly go back I'm
not sure that worked that time yeah I
don't know I don't know if I can
actually get this thing to work 100%
worked again worked again hmm like it
wasn't working at all and now it seems
to work every time let's get rid of this
we'll just run it like normal works and
failed yeah I don't know don't know I'm
gonna have to experiment experiment with
it quite a bit more I think if you have
ideas let me know what I could try here
but I think we'll leave it there for
today so something else I want to do
today just a quick little project here
as hook up these lights in the nether
hub we never did do that we got chickens
in this one kind of wandering around
randomly but I don't really like the
effect like it's like that's the fact
kind of lame so we're gonna redo it
we're gonna put a minecart in here and
have it go around and in a precise order
all right so let's let's get up in the
ceiling here I don't know how many of
you guys watched the minecon stuff I I
missed most of it but I did see well
especially on the reddit they were
talking about it they revealed some
information about the 1.9 updates and
some spoilers I guess so I'm gonna be
given a couple spoilers but yeah it
looks like they redid the end quite a
bit they improved it a lot by the looks
of it they made a way for light from
what I understood there's like multiple
islands you can generate in the end and
you have to like hop between them or
something they made like a levitation or
maybe it's you know I don't even know
what I'm talking about how did it go I
think they said there are ways of
getting to another island like if you're
done with your current Island I think
you can hop to another one with like a
portal I think but there's also
fortresses like a new fortress to
introduce and there's like levitation
potions they introduced that you got to
use to climb up the tower because it's a
very vertical tower let's see how's it's
going to work can can these bends I
don't think they can bend can they if we
put one over here does that bend no it
doesn't Bend it's gonna be a little bit
complicated darn it why Janet why can't
I have made this straight seriously mmm
Oh what do we do then well if minecarts
are going to be a pain then we abandon
the idea and we switch to red stone
because red stone is amazing everybody
loves it never lets anybody down like
minecarts do and it doesn't make stupid
sound like my records do I don't know
you know we could've did it with my
girls but then would have heard the
minecart no he's going around all the
time that probably would have drove me
crazy this is probably for the best
alright so we'll just do something like
that it's gonna take a lot of repeaters
those only problem but yeah the the
tower they introduced has a new type of
block a purple brick block with a few
different variations and that looks
really good I think that's going to be a
pretty big kids and there's even a way
to farm it they introduced a new type of
crop very weird what was it called
chorus or something yeah weird plant
that grows in the end and it's kind of
like chopping down a tree you get that
and you can make bricks out of it and I
don't know it looked pretty cool they
they had a new mob to the show she'll
make her stump something something like
that and that was probably the coolest
thing they showed because it is like a
parasite worm type of mob that enters
blocks I don't know if it was able to
move between them I didn't quite
understand that but they they go into a
block and then the block opens up and
they shoot out of a projectile and the
projectile had like pathfinding to it so
it could actually shoot you around the
wall and stuff which is really
cool-looking
so yeah some cool stuff on its way
pretty excited I kind of hope there's
more to it than what they showed though
because there's been a year I think a
lot of people are hoping there's more
than they showed but what they did show
did actually look pretty good so I'm
happy about that all right let me try
get this hooked up here
okay I just about got this done
but ran into two pretty big problems
here it's only actually 3/4 done I ran
totally out of redstone again I looked
around we are all out I'm gonna have to
farm up some more maybe get that witch
farm up and running kind of haven't done
much with that other big problem knows I
accidentally hit one of the Pigman
they're not life friends anymore come on
guys
yeah we all get along we can we can sit
on the couch all day and play Super
Smash Brothers or something like the
good old times but no no they don't want
to do that anymore they hate me we're
good ok so this is what we got so far
whew oh snap oh that was a mistake over
there all right I'll have to look into
that so yeah I'm just gonna hook up this
one to when we get more redstone and
instead of having go all the time my
worry with that is it's gonna light the
game out quite a bit any lighting update
you do in Minecraft is is bad and also
any redstone clock you build is bad and
we have both here this is a redstone
clock and a lighting updates constantly
going on so we don't necessarily want to
run all the time but maybe randomly
we'll make it trigger over time all
right anyways I think we'll wrap it up
here for today I picked out a comment
that says etho have you ever heard of
the game risk of rain it's on Steam and
I think you would enjoy it and possibly
make a series out of it I can't remember
if I answered this one before I might of
or I might have thought about answering
somebody to ask me that question but
I'll say it again in case I didn't
I love roguelike games risk of brain is
a roguelike game I did buy it I have
played it for about an hour I think
can that's it I something about it just
didn't appeal to me you know I I wanted
to like it I know a lot of people love
that game but I just I don't know I
didn't really get it I think so but I
might give it another try some sometime
down the line I'm not the type of person
that just totally cuts off video games
like I don't like it right away I'll
usually try it again down the road and
see if I like it later so I'll probably
give it another shot
sometime in the future but anyways
somebody else asked about Zenith I
didn't have another book to put the
comet in though but Zenith is alive
Zenith is fine kind of sits here and
hangs out I don't ride Zenith around
very often because I don't want I don't
want him to die and he's not my fastest
horse anymore unfortunately does that 14
hearts he's a boss this is my quickest
guy right now whoa he is fast he's got
13 hearts did we ever name this guy even
I don't think we did no he does have a
name oh and he's a good jumper - man
this horses this horse is the best after
zenith zenith is the best obviously it's
only three it's only three okay it's not
that high it's just really cramped in
here anyways I hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode I hope you have a
wonderful day I'll see you in the next
one take care bye bye in before Zenith
dies
you