ah yeah hello everybody this is etho and
welcome back guys to another episode of
the let's plays series it's like the
most stressful thing I do in my world
here is harvesting the coarse plants cuz
I gotta move quickly I only got five
minutes and then they they start these
spawning on me I made the farm too big I
think because I gotta like really move
here I gotta try yet
every seed I can reach because otherwise
you lose seeds and then you're gonna run
out eventually you got to make sure you
get a profit every time you do a harvest
so more than one for me to plant it's
kind of tricky alright I think that's
good enough let's pull the switch real
quick here before they start
disappearing on us oh here comes a leg
oh snap I love watching that every time
I look at all the goodies look at all
the goodies so we pretty much used up
all our perper blocks working on the
nether there so we got to get our stash
back up here alright everybody so first
thing we're gonna try to do to here
today is get our mob system up and
running at full speed again so we got to
get the the cats and the dogs inside
again twelve of each in minecarts it's
gonna be a little bit tricky but I'll do
it off camera here I just wanted to
check out one thing we tested out the
teleport issues last episode and I had
one cat teleport to me when I didn't
want it to and I wasn't sure why
somebody in the comments said it's
because when they turn into adults
they'll teleport to you so I'm just
trying to watch these kittens here I
think they're about to turn hmm kind of
regretting this it's like I got it set
in my mind I'm gonna watch these cats
until they teleport and it's like yeah
but it takes us 20 minutes to grow up I
kind of thought like the time was almost
gonna happen but it seems like if you
stare at a jitan it'll never grow up
that's what I've learned so far and they
just stare back at you it's creepy there
we go oh my goodness it just happened
okay the other guy should do it too
yeah there we go confirmation so when
they turn into adults they teleport to
you so it just happens the one time it's
not gonna be a continuous problem I
don't think all right cool so I got to
get these guys inside here my plan is to
hopefully get them to teleport to me
let's try this out actually so if we sit
them up and I go inside here they're
gonna follow me inside or is it gonna be
a problem should teleport to me all
right maybe not oh man okay maybe we
gotta go up higher here oh there we go
there we go okay so I got to get a
little bit lucky with them teleporting
to me yeah so it's going pretty good
here guys we just about got all the cats
and dogs back in the mob system here in
minecarts and while doing this I
realized like I must have built this
before like carpets and trap doors and
stuff cuz I use slabs to stop spiders
from spawning we can change these now to
carpets or trapdoors that way like if a
mob is here and he wants to walk over
there he can walk overtop it maybe cuz
right now he's got to go around which
isn't so nice and also I think the dog
might be able to see a little bit better
if we replace the slab here with a
trapdoor because it's not quite as tall
right you'll have a little bit more
vertical view distance so hopefully
he'll be able to see more skeletons so
that's what I'm gonna do with this and I
don't know what's gonna happen is the
minecart gonna fall I really hope not I
don't think it should hi we did this
with Drew awesome so we take that out
all right it's all done so we're just
getting rid of all the torches you see
we got the carpet in place now instead
of the slab
we'll have to just keep an eye on it I
don't know for sure if that stops
spiders from spawning but I think it
does so we'll just we'll have to check
it out all rights last few torches here
I marked all the dogs with a blue collar
so if I see them somewhere in the world
I'll know they came from the mob system
and not just some random dog or
something you know oh okay we're free
good it's nighttime we should sleep and
then we'll head down and check out the
rates at at the fall chamber area okay
let's go down the llama Vader quickly
quickly quickly come on don't have all
day here
whoo okay you stayed up that could have
been bad all right so what kind of rates
are we gonna get there's a few mobs on
the surface there so it's gonna slow
things down a bit
but they should be spawn soon let's go
check it out oh I'm seeing them falling
that's a good sign oh yeah
oh yeah just like it used to be maybe
even a little bit better that's pretty
good I'm happy with that that's like
maybe one a second right okay pretty
cool so let's go back up now I just want
to make sure there's no spiders inside
because they're gonna cause problems if
they're if they are let's hope that
creepers done creeper gone creepers gone
we're just gonna climb up the outside
here and listen for spiders I hear
witches
not hearing any spiders so that's a good
sign yeah I think the carpet did the
trick yeah so last episode guys we added
in this pass over here it goes all the
way over there nothing too fancy it
still needs a bit more work - it's just
gravel I want to mix in some other
blocks but today I also add in another
path over there which connects up to the
course farm over there so that's awesome
we're gonna do a little bit more biome
enhancement today not not work down the
path I want to try something else here
something I've never done before it's
like a basic building skill a lot of
people have but I don't or at least I'm
not sure if I do I got a try make this
river bank look cooler so I just I think
I just blasted this out with TNT a long
time ago or maybe I even used the pick
it looks like I used the pick because
there's still dirt and stuff here all
right
I've seen a lot of people they mix in
like cobblestone and andesite and it
really looks cool so I want to try see
if I can do it - if I can be cool like
everybody else I don't know it's you
know that's probably not a good way to
start it I don't know exactly how to do
it though but yeah people just like
mixing slabs and cobblestone stairs and
cobblestone and somehow it looks really
good afterwards so that's what I'm gonna
try we'll see what happens when I work
on it here for a little bit I guess
aha so check it out everybody I spent
maybe 10 minutes on this section here I
think it looks okay right yes you love
it you absolutely love it
hopefully I don't know I'm trying to
like I'm whenever I build something I
look at it afterwards and I'm like how
can I make this better and nothing's
really coming to my mind unfortunately
but just doing this I didn't find it too
difficult actually like you can see
throughout we got andesite makes kind of
maybe one quarter of the blocks or
andesite and that really does most the
work I find and then
just stagger the stairs and slaps route
look for any square-ish areas and try to
stagger them like like over there for
example you see oh we got like a square
there it would look better definitely
look better if you just put a slap here
because then it staggers it more right
yes and that's kind of what I did
throughout here again over there would
probably look better with a little bit
of a slab there uh-huh but I didn't like
go back and forth every time I just kind
of did it now that I got a I got the
pattern kind of figured out maybe we'll
do a little bit over here together just
to show you what I did so first thing
replace all the grass or dirt with the
stone we'll try to do this quickly so
I'm not gonna spend forever on it you
guys are like etho everybody knows how
to do this these are basic building
skills you should have known this 20
years ago but for my first time doing it
I'm so excited
uh-huh I will become a good builder one
day guys you will see I just have to
keep practicing things like this okay so
get the basic thing and then every so
often does make sense an andesite you
know try to stagger it don't put like
big lines of it or anything like that
every so often you want some mossy
cobble I tried to keep it close to the
water because that makes more sense and
also put in some cobblestone blocks in
places I tried I tried to polish
andesite and it really stood out like
maybe I'll put a block down just so we
can see it like it really stands out
wherever you put it so I got rid of it
like when you look at this automatically
your eyes go whoop right over there
it just stands out too much for some
reason the borders on it I guess right
all right and then mix in some stairs
and stuff in places try to stagger that
and yeah not really much to it honestly
so just a little section like that
spinning a couple seconds on that let's
see what
looks like right now needs more up over
there but yeah you get the idea so I'm
going to do a little bit more with that
and then we'll probably go do something
else and there we go guys so check it
out I got both sides of the riverbank
done now and I tried really hard not to
do it
don't judge me harshly but I did end up
mixing in some leaves with it which I
think makes it look better it breaks up
the solid stone look but I know leaves
are a slippery slope you got to be
careful about how many you use and like
over using them and that kind of stuff I
might have overused them a little bit
here there's quite a few actually but
eventually I would like to plant maybe
some trees at the top here and maybe put
in some fences and stuff to some man
man-made looking things I think would be
cool but let's go down at the river
level here and take a pass through aha I
think that looks way better than what we
had though at the very least so I'm
happy with this with that cuz this is
kind of what it looked like before
just plain natural Minecraft boring
stuff you know so well what are we doing
next everybody well I tell you what
we are having an eco problem right now a
really big ego problem is check this out
less than two stacks of redstone left in
the whole world so I'm a little bit
scared about that we're gonna head over
the which firm today and see if we can
get that working a little bit
differently right now the way it works
is well originally I wanted to use snow
balls to knock the witches off the
platform one snowball per witch and I
found out you can't knock mobs shooting
snow balls out of dispensers so I
switched it to arrows and then I found
out I couldn't get it one one per would
so it ended up being I think like 27
whoa like 27 arrows to knock one witch
off the platform or something crazy like
that so that's why it's not a very
effective
farm and why I don't really use it in
currently so we got to change it try to
make it a bit more practical and I
thought I'd show you where it is because
we never go out here case you're curious
alright well I think our nether portals
are broken again it didn't take me to
the right world okay what's that guys
like I gotta I gotta figure out how to
get out of here there should be oh yeah
over there don't worry I can fix this
I can fix this just go back all right
here we go okay so right over there is
the witch farm let's go check it out
okay so we can see there's a few witches
in there right now I did end up lighting
up most of the caves in the area so the
spawn rate should be pretty decent with
this thing and we got most area flooded
or all area I can't remember if it
finished no I think I still gotta cut
off some over there to some of that land
needs to either get lit up or or blown
up but yeah you can see we got seven
dispensers in the back there those are
what we're shooting the arrows and
that's flashing right now because the
tripwires are activated so when there's
a witch in that area that shoots arrows
until the witch falls down here alright
so I'm thinking oh there's a chest down
here with goodies inside
yeah rigidly I wanted to use spectral
arrows as well but can't keep up with
the glowstone demand cuz I looked really
cool when the witches got highlighted as
they fell to their death I think what
we're gonna have to do is replace it
with a water flushing system so let's
count how long this is
and see if we can use water so up to
let's see here so this this is the end
of the platform three five seven and I'm
gonna add tribe yeah that pure so water
travels eight blocks right so this is
the furthest distance oh I broke a thing
here looks like it's nine blocks long
just one too far I think I got a plan
here let's go inside I'll just show you
what we're gonna do hello okay so my
plan is we're gonna rip out all the
wires all the all the string here all
the trip wires are gonna go we're not
gonna tech detect one of which spawns
here instead we're gonna keep it running
on a clock constantly so it's just it's
gonna always run whether there's a witch
here or not and my plan is since we need
the water to travel nine blocks which it
can't right that's one short of the edge
there if we just raise it up the
dispensers one block higher I'll spread
an extra block so all these dispensers
we're gonna raise up by one and instead
of dispensing arrows are gonna dispense
water buckets pretty simple really
yeah so they're gonna go up here with
water but it's inside we're gonna rip
out all those hoppers and it worked
pretty good
wait a second here one second one second
did I just do something cool so I had a
ladder here and I removed it and you can
see there's still a floating ladder bit
here in vanilla minecraft I had no idea
you could do this or wait oh why is it
doing that okay is there actually a
block there I don't remember putting one
there okay it's not that impressive now
I think this is about ready to go guys
so it's really really simple compared to
what we had so that's the bottom of the
staircase there you can see the wire
comes up oh actually one second you see
the wire comes up one two three four
five six seven and then runs up to eight
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
so we don't need any more repeaters from
that bottom there runs to all three
layers here and behind each of these ice
things here is the dispensers with the
water buckets in so pretty simple and
then all that we're gonna do is set up a
hopper clock to eject the water and then
retract it over and over again so it's
gonna be laggy because water updates are
pretty laggy but this is the only thing
in this area so I don't care how late it
gets really as long as it works
so just a standard hopper clock nothing
fancy comparator comparator get our
hoppers and I don't know what kind of
timing we're gonna want on this we'll
have to experiment a bit with it okay
get our redstone and then this will
connect to over here so you hear that
the ejected the water so as it goes back
and forth it'll eject and retract
constantly let's just try it with maybe
ten blocks
okay cuz we got to give it time for the
the witches to flow off the end - we
don't want it to be instant all right so
let's go see what that's like oh I'm
having a hard time in the water for some
reason like every time I go in except
for that time and that time a lot of
times I go in when I'm flying and then I
can't get out like you do this thing
where you're really close
can't really jump you know what I mean
okay is this all working are they all
objecting yeah all at the same time and
retracting all at the same time it kind
of looked like they weren't you see that
like it kind of lopsided to that side
I'll play that's not an issue
everything's good on the other layers
looks okay so watch him retract once
yeah they're lopsided - why are they
lopsided because they're all activated
at the same time as far as I can tell I
guess oh that wasn't there before
okay so maybe we can get rid of one or
two items like it feels like it's a
little bit long well know better once we
get some witches in there but I'm just
gonna cover over this so we don't get
mob spawning and I think it's it's good
to go um okay so we have a little bit of
a problem here we're not getting any mob
spotting or nuts
not very many anyways I saw one pack
spawn of four which is in like two
minutes here so I guess there's probably
still a lot of caves I gotta be lit up I
thought I got most of them but
no-nothing spawning its darked in there
it's definitely a which area and when we
arrived here there was a bunch of
witches in so I don't know why it's
having trouble now although they were
probably there when we left originally
yeah so our rates are garbage right now
that's gonna be the next mission is just
lighting up caves and stuff but I think
this is good the way it is all right it
looks like we actually worked on
blasting this mountain previously it's
not done though obviously so that's one
of the markers that red posts there and
there's like another one off that way we
got to get rid of all this land here
when I got up here you see all the dark
spots there was no mobs which okay I
really find that too - well yeah so if
there's no mobs up there it means
there's a lot of dark spots for them to
be hiding cuz this should be full of
them if it's the last dark spots near
the witch firm and it's not well
actually like just play a few mobs here
it's not too bad
I'm sure there's a few caves we've
missed though gonna need a lot more TNT
but that's all I had on me unless maybe
we left some here
in these chests let's check it out cuz I
don't mind blowing up more mountains Oh
baby
yes three stacks of TNT here we go
oh yeah let's feel this this is time
[Music]
okay fine was a bad idea I can't see
anything
[Music]
whoo-hoo uh-huh actually clear quite a
bit that was good
well anyways guys it's about time to
wrap up the episode for today so let's
wrap up the episode for today I guess I
don't know where I was going with that
so comment I picked out says Theo quick
question what is your favorite music to
listen to I'm also wondering what the
name of the song from episode 472
tasting eye candy is that is fat rats
mana tea I think is how you say that fat
rat mana tea if I ever used music in my
videos it's always gonna be in the
description by the way or in general
it's a good idea to look at the
description sometimes I actually write
something some cool stuff there
it says personally I like to listen I
like listening to twenty one pilots aha
I think I've said this before but my
favorite band of all time is Paramore
very good stuff
I like quick-quick music fast music high
tempo upbeat sort of stuff I hate music
that's repetitive like highway to the
dangerzone repeat that 20 30 times and
call it a song I hate that kind of stuff
I also don't like rap I don't like
hip-hop and country and oh yeah and I
don't know if you could call this a
category of music but like any 70s 80s
or 90s radio music I don't really care
for with exceptions of course but like
growing up I listened to the radio eight
hours a day every day for months I've
listened to the radio a lot in my life
and I've gotten so sick of some songs
and I'm ready to move on from them but
beyond that like I like most music I'm
not too picky about it and lately what
I've been listening to most is this like
monstercat on youtube if you don't know
what monster
that is go check it out through a search
you'll probably find some songs you like
if you like electronic music I think is
what you would define that as right I'm
not so sure there's a there's different
styles and stuff of course yeah anyways
hopefully you guys enjoyed today's
episode share your favorite type of
music and more importantly what kinds
you hate it's usually more entertaining
but yeah thank you guys for watching
hope you enjoyed it and I will see you
again in the next one take care bye bye
[Music]