huh
i've seen a lot of villages in this game
none like this so this one has a really
strange fence around it
very weird very weird
oh you have to see what this looks like
will my computer crash let's find out
that is a lot of tnt
here it comes
woohoo
oh that's awesome
it's working
well let's go take a look
it's raining sand
oh man the fun you can have with mcedit
is unreal
oh it's actually very very simple
all right all right i think we need to
do an anvil round though
i want to see what that looks like too
i was exes
oh boy
creative mode is pretty fun
oh you can have so much fun with tnt
oh wrong way
oh yeah right right right anvils and
i'll send you to that too
then we'll start the episode
i got some bad news guys it does not
work with anvils after all
because the pistons can't push them
sideways when they're stationary like
that
ah they have to be falling to be moved
otherwise this would have made probably
the craziest sound you've ever heard
before
and this definitely would have crashed
me
oh well
so yeah guys we are in a new snapshot
today that
this is the 13w18b
and they added a few new recipes to the
game
for leashes for the hay bales let's get
our stuff back here
where it belongs um
and we gotta go get those horses today
that we found last episode
so we're gonna head out there pretty
quick i just want to make some of that
new stuff
uh there's also i oh
that's from a previous episode um
yeah i think we use these saddles now
for the horses they got rid of the
the unique horse one and this just
we use this on pigs and horses now i
think that's the way it works
uh we also can craft let's try this out
i think we can craft the the leads
that's what they're called
let's try this out and slimeball yeah oh
it gives you two
cool so i have never actually used these
yet like not even in creative so let's
check this out
okay i can't just i thought it was like
a fishing hook like
it would shoot it out but i guess that's
not how how it works
um we gotta find an animal
is there any slimes oh there is slimes
good
we do it on a slime no
unless we gotta attach to the fence
first
and then no
i have no clue how to use this thing
all right anyway maybe it's not for
these mobs anymore
uh let's check out the hay bales i think
we have some weed in here i hope
and we're gonna head out on our
adventure here pretty quick
uh what else has changed they added uh
chess in
nether which is pretty cool
can we wonder what the tool is for it
doesn't look like anything maybe it's an
axe let's check that out too
where is my axes i don't have any there
we go
now no tool
interesting interesting i wonder if it
conducts redstone
over there and good
looks like a normal block
anyway guys let's go on our adventure
i'm going to meet you guys at the horses
and we'll ride them back or something
all right i think we're getting really
close oh yeah there they are
right on that mountain they're still
here they didn't despawn
i i don't think they do anymore in this
snapshot is is the rumor i heard i don't
know if it's true though
yeah hey guys where's my favorite one
where is he is it wrong that i have a
favorite one there he is
i've been waiting to see this guy again
oh no he has oh no he's going to be a
slow guy isn't he
he has a lot of health
he does look really cool though i'm
gonna call this guy zenith i think
with a zed i don't know what you call
horses i've never had a horse before
let's try this out we're gonna
i wonder if they changed the saddle i
think that's the same saddles they had
before
and i can ride them woohoo
yeah i don't know if this is a fast guy
or not i kind of think he's going to be
a slow guy
because i think that bar on the right is
his health
awesome all right let's uh let's try out
these other guys too
we got to bring a bunch of them home uh
there's this guy this is the one that
gave us all that trouble
he's got less health so i think he's
gonna be slow a little quicker
it's really hard to tell though
i wonder how far they can fall before
they take fall damage because it looks
like they jump
really high actually
all right and then there's these two
this guy looks pretty nice too
i like the multiple colors on them
horses man i'm gonna use these guys a
lot i think like any time i have to go
somewhere i think i'm gonna
try to use them but we'll see
oh this guy has a lot of health too i
think
cool all right so these leads
i looked on the wiki and i think slimes
are like one of the few mobs it doesn't
work on
actually yeah look at this so now they
can follow us
i'm i wonder if we should ride them home
or if we should
that's pretty cool or if we should just
get them to follow us like this
because we're gonna bring all four home
if we do it this way where's that other
guy
oh he got disconnected how'd that happen
come on guys don't stop and eat
oh i see if you get too far away they
just break okay i'm gonna ride them home
um do you drop it anywhere
what happens if you jump on with the
lead on
oh it just breaks doesn't let you oh no
no i still got this guy look at this
i wonder if he can keep up that would be
so cool if you could
just bring them all like their horses
they can move quick
i don't know doesn't look like it's
gonna happen
come on
he's trying really hard though
oh no it broke we're gonna ride home
guys i'm gonna get lost
um it's getting late i think
yeah we gotta go this way do they go in
water
too deep water oh
i don't know he doesn't have an air
bubble thing i think he's okay
let's go three deep now that's the limit
there then he'd
get knocked off and he starts swimming
you can hop on him when he's in the
water though
okay which way we gotta go not that way
not that way
this way right
off into the sunset
oh he was taking damage i think
that's cool i jumped the water
oh this is so cool
oh man
oh he got shot no get away
i'm gonna try to get really good at
riding the horses
oh deep water deep water don't go there
so water is their big downfall
see where we gotta go oh did he recover
health
when they eat the grass that must cover
their health
oh i almost made it
okay where are we going we're still
going this way
oh there's so much deep water all around
though this is tough
um let's try jump from
here to there then we'll
try to get onto that other little island
oh no come on guy
get out of the water are they trying to
kill him
oh dang i hit him zenith
oh i hit him with my good sword what are
they doing
all right
what what hit me
um
all right then
go zenith you okay you okay
oh oh he i can't ride him anymore
oh no okay this is bad news
um i gotta relog
and i logged in in the water so they
were trying to get me after all
that's a issue with dismounting i guess
so where's my horse at oh he's over
there still okay good
and he's down a heart and a half
it's not too bad considering i hit him
with my sword he must be recovering as
as we're going oh that's a ravine
he is really good at maneuvering the
mountains though this is
very impressive like holy smokes
you know how long it takes to walk this
and he's just like dude he's just
amazing i gotta get some feather falling
horseshoes for this guy
and he'll be he'll be golden you can't
do a straight up
jump with horizontal movement though
um
i don't i don't know if i can i don't
think i can fight while i'm on them
either
oh
wow this is so cool
oh darn okay that hit me at least not
him
oh man oh we're almost home that's my
waterfall
i recognize it he just plows right
through the
enemies too whoa
holy we just jumped like between two
mountains there
please don't take damage he's good oh
beautiful
it's so funny though when they go to eat
if they're in water they just sink to
the bottom
and they take a bite out of the ground
out of the sand
all right actually this is pretty dense
area i don't know if you can get out of
here
we have to go all the way around
this is the river i made guys
oh no see that
zenith stop eating
stop eating
all right zenith we're almost home
stay away from the creeper
and the lava well
the cactus there's a lot of obstacles on
the way home
oh go go should be
entrances right around
where is it there it is so
i wonder how he's gonna do in my cave
here
ouch oh this is so
awesome they're so fast too this guy is
so fast
he does pretty good in here this is
amazing
oh so cool i don't think i should ride
him around here too often but
he can if we want to
there's wilson zenith meet wilson wilson
is very sad he's not done yet
uh you know what i want to do i want to
do some experiments with the
speed potions and stuff with this guy
too so we're going to stop by the lab
here i'm going to get some potions ready
um i wonder seen it
you just stay here for right now there
you go
i'll be right back
i thought about it afterwards but uh
after i got the potions i'm like
maybe he can jump down here i'm not sure
that's quite the drop
but uh he stayed put it's all good
so i got some potions i'm
particularly interested in speed two
um actually let's yeah let's do a speed
two to start off with
so how quick is he going to be
if if it does work oh i think it's
working
yeah it's definitely working
wow
out of my way nature
that is so fast
like we are flying here
look at the zed coordinate it's just
like
it is moving wow
yeah horses i like them a lot they are
very cool
very nice addition mojang i i like it
that potion i wonder if it's still
i think it wore off now oh no no
it still hasn't
man
and you can even use them while you're
on the horse which is really cool
i jumped the river wow
watch this scene probably get up here
he's like a four by four this guy
oh watch out for the lava whoa whoa whoa
i hope you guys aren't getting motion
sickness from this it does
it does make the screen move pretty
quick
okay he's having trouble getting up here
oh that damaged me not him that damaged
him
very cool though
jump the river
ah
so much fun okay was there anything else
i wanted to do i wanted to try see if i
could like
battle mobs from the horse too there's
nothing really around so i guess we'll
use this sheep
it would be really cool if you could
like move independently of him somehow
like if he helds
like control for example if i could turn
without the horse turning with me
because i think if i do this it's gonna
hit him oh no
okay that is really neat
so i'm guessing there's if i aim
high enough it's not going to hit him
really i can't hit him at all that's
awesome
so does that mean
oh they just keep being better and
better so i can fight mobs while on a
horse
or even other players presumably there's
going to be so many game modes that come
out of this too
huh let's go find a sheep
wow
if you guys have played with the horses
you're probably like it's just a horsey
so
but i haven't like honestly all i've
done with the horses so far i like
hopped into a creative world
looked for him to see if they would
spawn i didn't find any that spawned
so i just put a spawn egg in
and while riding it for like after like
a minute it glitched out
and then i recorded an intro to one of
my
let's plays and i haven't done anything
with horses since so this is like my
first time riding it too
oh do you see that that was cool
you must have spawned that guy
oh the horses are so awesome
there's there's a couple more things i
want to check out here
let's go into the village oh i missed it
let's go into the village i made
hey uh i made an invisibility potion i'm
just curious what this will do
i want to get him but not us
all right i didn't live with that
now i can see without him in my my face
at least that's kind of cool
otherwise you see his head all the time
now it's like i'm just moving super
quick that's kind of cool actually
horses they're like the the jet pack of
vanilla
oh ladders are too
but like look how quick these guys are
all right so that's neat the other thing
is
see if i had if i had wood wooden
buttons i could shoot them with a bow
i'm sure
oh i'm getting some jitters here what's
this about
this is weird
i'm not lagging i'm at 30 frames here
this is
i gotta relog i think
it's a zombie congo line
yeah very strange it seemed to get
better when it turned again
for some reason uh let's try ender pearl
on a horse
can't right click okay let's try ender
pearl off a horse and get on a horse
okay we get the damage but we get sent
back to the horse
right away
let's see if we can go to the nether
can we go while on the horse
doesn't look like yet
all right but he can go through on his
own
and we can meet him there
all right we're in the nether
this is scary you hear the silverfish
yeah silverfish got free and now i'm
pretty sure most my tunnel here is
silver fish blocks
because uh i lost control of them
oh he took four hearts already i should
be careful
how did he take four hearts i thought i
was taking the damage
oh and it's not loading or no it is
loading i'm just
whoa whoa okay
yeah the ceiling's not high enough here
looks like he's recovering even in the
nether though
uh i'm guessing
he's not gonna like lava too much even
with a fire resist potion i'm guessing
what he'll do
is the same thing he does in the water
will where he will swim to the bottom
and then try to eat
in the lava uh
i'm assuming that's what's gonna happen
i don't know if i really wanna
because i i don't even think i can move
them out of there
with a lead should we try it
venus you're such a great horse please
don't die
although no you know what he can't drown
it's lava
he moves very slow
oh i'm afraid to let him go a little
deeper
all right okay i don't like this
it's not too bad actually
yeah he won't take drown damage
pretty sure
that hmm i wonder why the fire resist is
only at three minutes
only at 3.4 is it
that was a six minute potion that didn't
get used too well i
probably not aiming too well yes so i
think
we could actually potentially go
swimming with this guy in lava i wish i
brought a
night vision i think that would let me
see under the lava even
he moves very slow though
but yeah you can get through lava with
them i think
it's kind of tough not being able to see
though
okay i can see a wall i think we're
close to the edge
oh i saw i saw it yes we can get out
oh we're in a bad spot though let's go
this way
fire horse
very cool
and if you thought it was hard to see
before
try to get a flaming horse try riding a
flaming horse then you really can't see
and i didn't even use my pick well on
them
very cool okay how do we get out of here
that's my next question this is gonna be
tough
i can't remember where we came from
what a nightmare
another pool i'm looking for a ledge we
can get up
this is kind of okay might be able to
climb up to this
oh what was that can we place blocks
while on the horse
oh yeah we can
look at that build a staircase
you can't hold shift when you're on an
edge show so it's very easy to fall off
stuff you don't want to
okay we're getting back up um
can we go this way uh his fire resist
might have worn off i'm not sure
i want to try to as high as we can here
he's wider than one block though is the
thing it makes
tunneling kind of tough
it is doable though
yeah this doesn't quite look familiar to
me
stop it
whoa
oh stop stop oh dear
let's go get him let's go get him we can
dig him
jump jump zenith
oh so close
oh he's going back down let's go let's
go
we can get him yes nice
oh zenith the ghast hunter amazing
i really wish i wasn't lost what is this
why did i build this do you know zenith
oh that's a path i know what this
is oh and it's fresh there's still stuff
here
um we have to go this way
this will take us home i'm pretty sure
i think oh no we're getting farther away
we gotta go this way
zenith is a gas hunter like you wouldn't
believe
can we get through the fortress
oh there's blaze
i know how to get home myself
i can do everything on a horse this is
so cool
okay i am worried for you though
i don't like being in the nether
oh this is my nether farm okay
how how do i get out of here
um
oh i am so forgetful
um can we get out on top the hill maybe
my tunnel should be really close to here
i just can't remember how to get to it
i don't think there's a horse access way
it's a problem
there's no way through up here
can we get through here
whoa
we just about took a tumble
oh no you did it bear in mind
zenith oh this isn't good
oh no oh dang see this no
oh man
what the heck
this game oh
my horse survived at least but now i
gotta
i got to get him out of there
okay i'm really really worried he walked
off the edge here
not sure he is a brave horse
oh no
oh he passed him
oh he's still got fire resistance oh and
he's still trying to kill me
okay just wait a second let me get my
stuff back
we're gonna head home i know the way
back now
yeah that was crazy
so i didn't imagine that before i
thought i saw a zombie's
pigman skin on me before
interesting okay zenith we're going home
just me and you buddy
um if i can remember
how we got into this little cave
it was down there it must be over here
oh i think we just passed it
there it is okay we're gonna head back
to the fortress
don't hit the pigmen
yeah if we go back to the fortress we
can get home
no problem
go through here then go straight oh
that's a problem
okay it's not this way
this one there we go this will take us
right home
oh my goodness
good job zenith this is our
rail tunnel and we're all set we should
probably modify our portal here
at least for right now
all right this should work
there we go
home sweet home
and we're gonna go through the creeper
mouth woohoo
into the water oh but there's no way out
of here
oh you're almost out gonna get more
height
come on
see this
there we go yes you're free welcome home
sorry about that we're not gonna go back
to the nether like that
it's too dangerous it's way too
dangerous
but that was fun i i enjoyed that
and oh i'm white again
i will let you sit here for right now
and i just it's time to go read the
comments
um i think we have a traffic jam here or
something
gridlock i have never seen them get
stuck in this thing
i wonder what's going on here
he's the guy holding things up
he's not moving at all
huh very strange
rare problem though i mean it's okay
i'm curious to see how far it's backed
up
if we go let's just check something here
if we go by the slime farm are they
backed up all the way to here
oh no you can't even see him
yeah you can see one right there
anyway uh what else guys there is
i forgot to point this out earlier but
there's a cold block in the game now
i want to try make one of these see what
it looks like
i saw a picture already so i kind of
have an idea it's like the redstone
block texture except shaded black
let's try it out and you can use it for
smelting stuff
oh yeah looks good in the interface
that's pretty cool i sort of wish the
the colors were blended a little bit
more like we have
right on the edges and then dark in the
center but it's
it's good looks like
coal i guess um
all right and we got a comment picked
out the really nice thing about this
though is you can compress your coal
into
like nine nine stacks into one stack
which makes a big difference with coal
because you can get it really easy with
fortune three
but yeah we have a comment out etho i
was really wondering
if you are ever going to consider making
more pvp
minigame type videos
i really think that your viewers enjoy
them plus you're pretty good at them
i'm sure your viewers love the dramatic
parts that make it so
interesting anyway thanks for reading
this
if if you do keep up the good videos
thank you sir or ma'am
it was a sir catman
chaos definitely a guy uh
you know i don't think
like i know some people really like the
pvp
stuff but a lot of people that play
minecraft could care less
with pvp and i don't get the greatest
number of views on them
um i will still upload a few here and
there though
because it's something i enjoy doing and
i i know viewers like him too
the thing is though in minecraft i do
feel
there's this transition going on in the
game like it's not just
a building focused
game anymore the pvp in it is actually
getting
really good now uh
and it's you can make some really neat
games
within minecraft and once you learn some
of the strategy and techniques in pvp
it's a lot of fun to play too
so i think as the game develops more and
more and people make more and more
custom maps more
people are going to be playing pvp games
and there will be greater interest for
it but at the moment
it's sort of so-so still
but uh yeah anyway guys i had a fun
adventure today i hope you guys enjoyed
it we're going to get back to building
next episode
i will see you again then have a good
day