hello everybody this is etho
and we're going to start out today's
episode with a good old
enchanting level 50 hoping for
silk touch
oh that's that's pretty good i need lots
of those
yeah i love getting these efficiency for
picks
for uh projects where i have to dig out
big areas
uh i've kind of been wanting to get a
good stockpile of these like 10 or so
but i
i use them up as quick as i get them it
seems
um yeah so before this episode
i decided i'd hang out around the cave
spider
xp machine here uh
i've been hearing a lot of people
commenting that i should try to do at
least one enchantment
every every episode so i was pretty
close to
being level 50 so i i had some stuff to
do on youtube
so i decided i'd just leave my game
going aft here
while i took care of uh the youtube
stuff
anyway a few like 30 or 40 minutes later
i kept hearing this like static noise in
my speakers and i just recently bought
new speakers because
usually i get cheap ones and they after
about a year or so they always
develop this static noise that never
goes away
because they're cheap speakers anyway i
thought my
new i got bose speakers this time
went for something more expensive hoping
it would last longer
and so when i heard the static it's like
oh man these speakers are
garbage already what's going on
and then i remembered oh yeah i got my
minecraft running and i have
like 500 spiders here screeching
and that was what was making the static
noise because i turned it down to like
five percent or so when i afk
was like i was playing around with my
speaker volume computer volume trying to
make the
static noise disappear and it's like why
is it so loud what's going on
it was the spiders
yes i think about the time this episode
goes up we should be
pretty darn close to a hundred thousand
subscribers
a hundred thousand man that's that still
blows me away
uh i want to say thanks to everybody
thank you very much i'm glad you guys
are still
watching my videos and still find me
somewhat interesting or entertaining to
watch
i try my best when you think about it a
hundred thousand if you've ever been to
like a sporting event like a coliseum
where there's maybe five ten thousand
maybe twenty thousand people
then think about a hundred thousand
people all watching you
it's uh it can be pretty
i don't know i'm all alone right now
in my uh in my room here but uh
there's really like thousands and
thousands of people watching me which is
pretty
scary sometimes but at the same time
you guys make it easy for me because
you're usually pretty nice in the
comments which i
really appreciate it's very encouraging
i'm glad so many of you enjoy my videos
and i hope to continue
and this is uh i think this is the only
thing i've changed since last episode
uh the ceiling here it's nether brick
sandstone stripe uh i kind of like it
wash it i really like it
uh this whole nether brick sandstone
thing i think it looks
best the higher it is like the higher
the ceiling is
right now where i am
the sandstone's kind of close to eye
level so it's not quite as good as i
would have liked but overall i'm pretty
happy with it i might do
a sandstone pattern in the center yet
and once i get some dark green wool i'm
going to do a slime face
at the pad here seems to be working
pretty good
so today i'm going to try to do somewhat
of a subscriber special
100 000 subscriber special uh
mostly just by doing a longer video than
normal
but i'm not going to set any specific
length because i don't want it to drag
on
like that one time i said i was going to
do an hour one
do have a few projects in mind
well one main project and i think we'll
probably start that right away
so let me get my supplies together and
we will
go and start a new project very excited
about this one it's gonna be
i don't know if it's gonna be a lot of
work or not we'll we'll see how it goes
okay actually on second thought here i
think i've decided on
what design i'm gonna be using for this
and uh the one i've chosen
is gonna take a lot of materials and
we'll probably take a
long time to build as well but we can
get it started today i think
uh pretty quickly and uh
it will take a lot of materials i'm just
collecting flowers right now yellow
flowers for yellow
wool uh i'll need a lot of ink sacs for
black wool
i may just try to get some sheep
together so i can
breed the color sheet
and uh have them regrow their wool and
all that to get it quicker
but uh i think just for today i'm going
to use up my stock
right now i have a good stack of flowers
there's a few at my base too
and i'll need a lot of iron for this
project
probably at least 500 and at least
um at least
a thousand redstone i think
no even more even more it's gonna be
huge
uh should be pretty cool though when
it's done
yeah this is crazy i've made
four stacks of pistons plus i had some
left
laying around here so each piston of
course is one iron and one redstone
and that has tanked my iron supply this
is all i have left
pretty much so sometime soon i'm
definitely going to need to do some
taping
again um i will need
i'm going to bring some dirt with me
these are all the flowers i've collected
i got
four and a half stacks or so
and this is my wool chest i only have 64
ink sacks plus a stack
of black wool so that's that's two
stacks total at the moment
i'm going to save six there for sheep
which i'll probably have to
breed and and shear and everything to
get
the rest of the wool i need
so let's make our make our yellow here
and we'll probably have to make several
trips if you haven't figured it out
already we're heading to the end today
and i will
i will see you guys at the stronghold i
guess
okay we're at the stronghold uh i guess
it's only a three minute run with the
speed potion
from the base to here it's good to know
i got all the supplies here safe and
sound
gonna really need a lot more black wool
though
so we might have to use a substitute
until we get more
um so let's first go into
the end here and i'll give you a rundown
of the
plan and everything
okay lots enderman around
that's for sure
so this is what i've done i've made
i better get out of here before the
dragon finds me
he's still alive but i've made an
obsidian bridge out to nowhere
oh that's a bad time to push my
side key just about walked off
and it goes quite a ways away um
it seems the easiest mob system to make
in the game is in the end
because once you get all the way out
here there's no land
so you can get highest efficiency
and you don't even have to kill the
dragon you just have to build out
into the void area and you are free to
do whatever you want
so for example if we run up ahead a
little bit
i'll just show you how effective
spawning rates are
in the end here it's going to remove a
couple torches
okay so it's dark here endermen need
a light level
below eight to spawn if i remember right
i think it's below eight and
i don't know if that's 24 blocks away i
think it is
so we're going to be making a mob trap
out here because we can get
super high efficiency for spawning rates
and if we have an enderman farm in the
end we don't have to worry about making
one
in the regular world which makes things
a lot simpler because these guys have
annoying properties
as you know they can't touch water
without teleporting so that makes
transporting them difficult
they like to teleport around they're
super aggressive they're three blocks
high
while most other mobs are two
so yeah this is going to be fun
my idea here is
as long as we're 144 blocks away from
that mainland
they will spawn on anything i build out
here that
is dark and that's not a half slab or
glass or anything like
that
okay so i've been thinking of a lot of
different
enderman farm designs and i came up with
my own one
um actually you know what we're gonna do
we're gonna head back to
stronghold
whoo look at that score amazing
absolutely meaningless okay so
maybe we'll use dirt as a visual aid so
one farm idea
and i think i've seen someone do this is
to do like a funnel thing
because you can't move the enderman with
water so you
have to come up with other ways of
getting them to a central point
if that's what you want so
kind of like my blaze farm you just keep
doing like an inverted pyramid with
pistons and pressure plates
and
enderman will spawn so if they spawn up
here they'll get pushed down
to the lower level and then another
piston will push them further and
eventually they all group to the center
that has a few benefits obviously you
can get all the enderman
together in the center has a high piston
cost
and they're likely to take
take damage or have other problems from
the pistons when
when you do that and if you have one
intermittent you guys
why oh great
no leave me alone
get out of here you idiot i should just
break that spawner i don't think i'm
gonna do anything with it
i just can't bear to break spawners it's
it's against what i like to do
and we got lava flowing again great yeah
so if you have a funnel style
if this if say it goes in 10 blocks
uh if you have an enderman spawn at the
highest one the tenth one it has to go
through ten pistons to get to
the center so the bigger you make a farm
like that
the more piston action is going to
happen and the more lag you're gonna get
and possibly other problems so
not gonna do a funnel style even though
they're pretty cool
uh then there's uh i don't know if you
saw a dot damn
iron lung one where where the blocks
i'm doing a terrible job explaining this
i'm going to separate it i'm going to
set up a demonstration
right so with the shifter style i got a
small example here
the idea is you would build it up in the
air
that sounded really weird you'd build it
up in the air
enderman would spawn on the pad
then you would hook the two piston sides
up to some kind of a clock and what
would happen is
extend one side then after a certain
amount of time the clock would make
that side extend and then it would
repeat
and that causes the blocks to shift so
that when the endermen spawn on it
uh they have a chance of falling through
like that
and then they would fall to their death
or fall to the point where they're low
on health so you can
kill them for xp that's the idea behind
it
and you could very nicely make it up to
maybe like a 12 by 12 area of blocks
because pistons can push up to 12 blocks
which would be 12 times 12 is 144 total
that's quite a bit of area uh from my
previous
okay my previous experiments
with uh remember the ice base
i found you need
probably a thousand blocks spawning
space minimum to utilize
a mob farm to the maximum at high
efficiency
so that's what i'm going to be aiming
for with this enderman farm about a
thousand blocks or so
and see how that goes uh the problem
with this shifter style
well nice thing about is it's pretty
simple to build
um 12 by 12 set of blocks you would need
24 pistons which isn't bad
you would have to have a clock running
though which does cause lag
and when the blocks get moved that
causes quite a bit of lag too
so it is a bit of a laggy farm
especially if you
have like eight sets of 12 by 12
blocks that adds up quick and the lag
yet
adds up quick too when you do that so
i was really leaning towards this this
style but i
found that endermen will
take damage as they fall through that
they take a little bit of suffocation
damage so you can't
get an accurate amount of health on them
so that you can one hit kill them with
your fist
other thing about this style is you
don't get them collected to a central
point
which is something i won't be doing with
my farm either
just because it complicates it
i am aiming to make an xp style
and maybe i'll set up one more example
of another farm i was thinking of doing
another style but that i decided against
oh yeah i forgot there's also one other
really major reason why i've
decided against using this style even
though i like it for its
relative simplicity there's an issue
with
sometimes mobs not falling through it
as you can see i'm not falling through
it right now that tends to happen if
they're standing between
two blocks you can see the blocks the
block line is right there
and i can't draw straight
so sometimes they'll get stuck in there
for quite
a while if because uh
if they get in a place where they won't
fall through and then they stop moving
because of the
idle timer where their
mobs will stop moving if i think they're
32 blocks away from you
after a few seconds so if that happens
they might be stuck there until they
despawn that's an issue for sure
if i stand over here fall right through
so another thing to keep in mind i do
really like the style but
just a few issues with it
now for a very different style of farm
i was thinking of doing something like
this just have rows of blocks
up in the sky for the enderman to spawn
on
and then in between these rows put signs
or fence gates
i would probably recommend signs just
because fence gates seem to have a few
issues at the moment
but to put signs in between for the mobs
to see as blocks so that
they will attempt to walk on the signs
and then they'll fall down
and no pistons no redstone
it would be pretty efficient the only
issue is uh
sometimes when mobs spawn they don't
start walking
right away it might take them a few
seconds and if it takes a few seconds
and they are long ways away from you up
in the sky
uh they're gonna get stuck there until
they despawn
so probably about half of them
maybe maybe a little bit more will fall
down and the other half will get stuck
on top here
and they'll eat up your mob spots
until they despawn so very simple but
somewhat inefficient
all right i hope you're not getting
bored of this i have one more
farm design style i'm going to show you
that i that i rejected but
it also has a few benefits and along
with it a few negative things
again you would build this style up in
the air just imagine
this is repeated over here i don't have
enough resources here to demonstrate the
salt properly
but the idea is enderman would spawn
only on the pressure plates
and when they do that um
they get pushed off pretty much
instantly
so you would repeat it wire repeater
wire repeater
all the way along and same on this side
they get pushed to the middle so
it's a seven wide thing
and these are sticky pistons pressure
plate sends power to
the redstone to the block to the piston
it extends
pushes the endermen down they'll fall
and depending on how you set it up
they'll either
fall to their deaths you guys where do
you keep coming from
it's the third one i've killed they'll
either fall to their death or they'll
fall just to the point
where the one hit will kill them
this farm design is nice for that
because you can accurately get them down
to
a fist hit to kill them
this is probably the quickest design as
well
because as soon as they're on it they
get pushed off while the shifter style
for example
uh you got to wait for the clock and a
lot of the times when it shifts they
don't fall down
so this one's really good for that
negative thing about this um it's pretty
big
for the spawning space so if you had a
16x7 area
you would only have 32 spawning spaces
in that instead of let's see calculator
16 times 7 is a
112 so
for 112 area you would only have 32
spawning spaces so it's
kind of inefficient it's also very
resource
intensive because you need sticky
pistons
for each spawning space you need one
sticky piston
and either redstone dust or redstone
repeater
averages out to i think three redstone
per spawning area kind of expensive
and from this is what i came up with my
design from
it's very similar to this i'll show you
that now it's the last last
last one i'm going to show you
just about blew up my chest
jump blow up bed gotcha
sorry i was eating eminem's when he came
out
so all those designs i've shown you so
far are all the ones i've rejected
uh it's not because they're bad designs
they're all good they all have their
pros they also all have their cons
it's a thing and i was having a hard
time choosing between them but until i
came up with my own design
here that i think is going to be pretty
good
basically i'm going to set up rows
that will make it three three wide our
demonstration
gonna set up rows you'll have torches
like this
so it's uh four blocks wide and then uh
above that it's gonna be black
like this and on top of that
redstone torches finally at the very top
we have
pistons
might be hard to build
gotta get into a pattern stop let me
place my piston
first one's going to be hard to start
pistons will go directly above the
redstone torches
and this is tailored especially for uh
enderman
takes advantage of their height
so go like that and then i'll have stone
pressure plates all along the yellow
thing here
don't have any on me at the moment so
we'll just use wooden ones
like so
there and then when the endermen spawn
on the pressure plates
the piston will extend and push them off
down they'll fall
uh i think i gotta drop them 43 blocks
if i remember right
to get them down to one or two half a
heart
health
and that's all there is to it so it's
like the last one except
it's uh squished in a little bit more
the other one was basically three blocks
wide
and this one's two so
it's quite a bit more compact it is
still very resource intensive though it
takes
three redstone per spawning area
one each torch and then one in each
piston these are regular pistons each of
these will take an iron
so in total if i aim for the thousand
spawning
spaces like i would like uh it's gonna
be a thousand iron
and about 3 000 redstone i guess
definitely not doing that all day i
don't have that much
be a project i'll keep working on but
we're gonna get started today at least
i'm gonna
probably put down a little bit of a work
area
at the end of that obsidian bridge thing
and once i have a work area then we will
start
building it finally
right on okay we have a little bit of a
work area set up here
just a little square i will be extending
this out further
as i find time to we are going to be
building
our mob trap directly above here this is
the center i've marked out
which is at x 320
and zero so good spot it'll be easy to
figure out numbers if i need to
and you can just barely see
ender island over there so we're well
over 144 blocks away which is all that
matters so that
endermen won't spawn on the island
instead of our
mob trap i think it's actually 250
blocks or so away from me
so got a little bit of uh buffer zone in
case i decide to build something further
like closer to the island too like if i
set up other farms and stuff i don't
have to worry about it
okay and i was at y50 here i've decided
to go down one block so i just poured
water down and was able to build under
my bridge here
and i'm just going to keep it at 49 for
now and then when i get the farm set up
then i might
make my floor two blocks thick and i'll
put stone bricks or something down here
to make it too thick just as an extra
safety and in case i need to
er or in case i decide to switch it from
an xp farm to just an
ender pearl collecting farm that kills
them
upon hitting the floor because uh
at level 50 they will stay alive but at
49 i think they'll die
so from level 50 we need to go up
um what was it 40 43 blocks
so all the way up to 93.
i'm gonna pillar up and then i'm going
to place my ladders
i'll see you at the top
okay we're at the height i want to be
here we're at y93
and now i think i'm gonna leave an eight
by eight
uh middle section here free
in case i wanna build some kind of fancy
elevator
maintenance elevator to get up here
at the moment i'll probably just use
ladders while i'm building this
or until i decide what i want to do for
an elevator
so we're gonna make an eight by eight
square centered
over here so we need to go out four
marks
yeah four blocks and i'll highlight that
out
all right so this is the center the
eight by eight that i i'm going to leave
blank until i figure out what i want to
do with it
will probably be some kind of elevator
not sure exactly what kind
one two three four five six seven eight
okay and this is the very center right
here
this will give us something nice to
build off of two so i'm gonna go ahead
now and
actually starts the farm this is the
first block
being placed for it and i think it's
going to look
really cool when it's done that's
another reason i really like this design
and you will see so we're just we'll
probably just do one ring on it
today and i'll extend it out further
later
as i get the blocks and stuff blocks in
time
go all the way around i will have to
remove this cobble
for the enderman to fall down
should be void now that i think of it
okay
and now we're get
we're gonna space it two blocks here
that and we will start our next strip
like this
and then in between we'll have the black
hole
at these corners i thought it would look
really cool to have watermelons
and do something like this just have a
four by four
square to bounce out the look
but i'll have to be careful because
endermen can steal watermelon i'm hoping
i can
maybe put half slabs above this or
something to keep them from doing that
i'm not sure how it's going to work out
i haven't tested this really
um okay
so maybe i'll talk about some other
stuff
ooge is out now i'm sure you guys have
seen it a lot of you
i hope you're enjoying it it was a lot
of fun playing with the goude and bw
and spellbound caves we're still not
done the map we're close
i think we're probably two thirds to
three quarters
done at the time i'm recording this
uh having a lot of fun with them
it's a really tough play in multiplayer
though
because the lag issues mobs don't really
behave properly
i'm thinking what i'll do since some
people seem to want me to do it single
player as well
is uh i might do a skill run of the map
afterwards
after we finish and try to see how quick
i can beat it
or something like that because i i
really do like that map
with all the potions and stuff it's uh
it's a lot of fun
you're almost like superman in that map
at times until you die and lose
everything
then you're just back to normal
so the way that's going to work as well
i'm still going to be doing legendary
episodes
uh i have about eight hours seven or
eight hours of footage from ooge
already it's really easy to make
episodes for it so i just have to
basically load in my in my editor and
hit
convert and it's pretty close to done
so it's not
bad okay i gotta get down
get our black wall
don't have the ladder set up just yet
uh what was i gonna say yeah i'll
probably
like instead i don't think they're going
to be replacing videos the og series
it'll probably just be bonus so some
days i might have uh
more than one video up
the time i release it depends a lot on
uh
good and bw i'm just
i'm sort of trying to trail behind them
with it uh
give them a chance to get more views and
that way i don't have to worry about
syncing my my times i'm free to
edit it however i wish and
make sure my episodes are like 20
minutes or so 20
25 minutes so
all in all it works out pretty good for
everybody if i do it that way
i won't be doing oh dang we need
enderman up there
i won't be doing a kill counter because
i edit with virtual dub and it's
extremely difficult if not impossible to
do it with that
so until i get better editing i'm very
limited to what i can actually do
i should have put torches up here
so here's evidence of the spawning rates
it's just crazy
even though it was pretty bright up here
from these torches
these guys still managed to spawn really
quickly
and you know what i forgot the black
wool so i'll be right back
i guess i didn't have any black wool
here so i had to go back to the
stronghold to get it
and i brought my pistons and redstone
torches
these guys um still got a few up here
when this is all done i'm not going to
have any torches up here
at all so these are just temporary
and the next thing i got to do here is
run along and put redstone
torches all along here on both sides
as i showed you before
i'll be really careful not to fall or i
will get ticked off because i got
some pretty expensive items on me
anytime i lose redstone i lose it
i just thought about that okay uh and
what i'll do then
is i'll put black wool on top
i had a look at this from the bottom too
and it's looking amazing
i think you guys will be impressed just
gotta make sure i don't fall here
okay and then like i showed you before
redstone torches all along
like so and i'll put the pistons on last
these corners are mostly just for looks
i may
actually you know what i'll do i'm gonna
put
uh torches on just for looks mostly
do a clockwise spiral
like that and i may try hook up some
pressure plates to these two
but i don't know how effective i can do
it i might be able to utilize two spots
here
two or three i don't know
um yeah i'll wait putting those on
okay so i'm gonna go all along do that
for all these
and then i'll be back
i got that done and i uh i pushed the
enderman off there was one left up here
and it was weird he just
all of a sudden teleported and i see him
or i did see him down there holding a
soil block
i think you despond now i don't know
where he got the soil block from i don't
think any were missing up here
a little strange i don't think they'll
pick up these watermelons unless they
get pushed off and they're next to them
like as they're falling down i think
they can only grab them if they're
like they can't pick them up if they're
below them only if they're
beside them i think is the way it works
but the next thing i'm going to do is
i'm going to go all along with the
pistons
like i showed you before do that
they are a little bit challenging to
place but not bad
i make it look harder than it really is
okay and then the other side
and so one block over here they'll be
able to fall down
and where this cobble is will be air as
well and they'll be able to fall down
here
when they get pushed
so the only thing i'm missing now is the
pressure plates
so those will go all along nice thing is
since
the pistons are up higher i can walk on
this
on these pressure plates without them
pushing me off
so this is getting pretty close to
operational
it's one side i don't have enough stone
here to do
the whole thing i'll have to make
another trip
but i'll finish up these other sides
with the pistons and
use up all my pressure plates here then
for these corners i think what i'm just
going to do for now i'll probably change
this later is i'll just
uh cover it like this so the endermen
can't walk
over here or spawn on them just for now
until i figure out what to do
okay and the really cool thing about
this design as well
mobs can't spawn on pistons so i don't
have to worry about them spawning on top
here
and the only place they'll be able to
spawn is the pressure plates so that's
what we want
works out perfect can't spawn on half
slabs so this is fine too
they won't be able to spawn here because
they don't have a three block high
clearance so
this should work out so i'll give you
an update as i get a little bit more
done here
well she's all done here we got the
first string complete
uh there's no more torches up here
it's all good we got the pressure plates
everywhere pistons everywhere
so we are ready to try it out and see
how it uh
performs it's exciting
very curious to see what happens uh this
uh
is by no means complete though this is
only the first string it's the smallest
ring
or square or whatever you want to call
it uh there's only actually uh
65 64. yeah 64 spawning spaces so that's
pretty darn
small still at the bare minimum i'll be
doing three
rings or three squares
and what i found from looking below this
having a pillar all the way up in the
center looks pretty bad so
i'll probably do a water elevator or a
boat elevator
but for now i'm just going to get rid of
it completely
until i come back to add another ring
oh i missed the torch somewhere we got
enderman down there
so yeah here we go
so they should oh we already got a pearl
i didn't see it fall though
that scared me ah
stop jump they keep dropping right in
front of me it's freaking me out
um did you fall
nope
one of these guys has full health it's
that one
let's kill this guy turn our volume down
too
so
the ones that land on the on the chest
here or whatever they uh
you can see they're surviving
um but they're one hit kill then so when
i raise this floor up
they'll all be a one-hit kill
or if i leave it down like this i can
just
have it auto harvest the ender pearls
and i'll just have to run around
collecting them
but are you ready to see it it looks
really cool from below i like it
there it is and as uh
as the endermen step on the pressure
plates the lights
flicker which is really cool too
so as i add more rings
um each ring will add 64
spawning spaces plus whatever the
previous ring had so this one was 64.
next one will be 128 and let me get my
calculator i think 192 comes next
at 192 and then you would have
well anyway yeah so it by the time i get
to three rings it'll be quite a bit of
spawning space
um
actually i'm gonna add it up just to
figure it out
all right so i added it up uh so the
first string
64 if we have two rings we'll have 192
spawning spaces three rings is 384
four rings is 640.
five rings is 960. so i think our
ultimate goal
we might shoot for five rings
by the time i add the second one on
though this is going to be three times
faster right 64 to 192
about three times faster maybe a little
bit less
um it's gonna be pretty cool when it's
all done
and so the the dragon is alive still i'm
able to do this with
it alive but i will end up killing it
because i have no way of hauling
these back to my world or any xp i get i
will be able to haul back until i can
kill
or until i kill the dragon so at some
point i will be doing that for sure
um but not today i am going to head
back and we might do something else yet
good news i made it back safe and sound
it's uh it's actually pretty surprising
as long as you have a speed potion
i didn't have any armor or any weapons
or anything as long as you have a speed
potion and maybe a little bit of food
you can run through the night no problem
without much risk which is pretty crazy
um i think i'm done here
i think i am uh there's one thing we
need to do yet though
we have to say hello to an old friend
oh hello old friend how are you doing
we all miss you haven't forgotten about
you though
it's good to see you're well
uh i wanted to take a tour of this world
again just a quick tour
to see how things are working and see
how things look
and everything because the lighting has
changed since uh
since i've said goodbye i haven't really
said goodbye i still have the world
i like to check it out um
my card's still running that's good
uh oh you know what i want to check is
my diamonds chest and everything
the chests look really weird now
um yeah what what kind of supplies did i
have when i quit this
that's pretty good
not bad oh oh i wouldn't mind that
yeah i forgot how much iron i had that
was crazy
how much clay did i have i actually had
some wow
whoa anyway
just wanted to check things out here i
was curious to see if the mob system
would be working
it doesn't seem like it we are on hard
i'm gonna head down there i might have
the lights on
one of the big issues that was breaking
this world before was the enderman
uh move-in box round but they have since
been nerfed
so now everything should be pretty much
fine except for the passive mob systems
yeah lights are on
i don't know if you guys can see
a lot of people have been saying the mob
vader is broken too
no they're going up
i just saw a creeper go up it anyway
let's get rid of the spiders
know how well you can see
yeah it's been a while since i last
checked this world
yeah they're going up
oh it's good that's cool with the lava
dripping down now too i like that
all right uh i'm guessing though most of
this stuff is too far away so the mobs
will go idle
and uh it won't work
i don't even know my way around anymore
want to check out the ice base yet and
what else should we look at
i'm not sure where to go
okay i'm gonna see the ice base and i
want to
what else was it no i think just the ice
base
yeah man it seems to be working still
pretty good
no enderman in it because as soon as
they touch water they'll teleport
rates are still really good i'm
surprised
just how good they are
i can't remember how deep it was i don't
think it was
i think it's because it's uh not that
deep that it's still working pretty good
yeah i really miss that uh timer the
tune
i might uh re-add that in my new world
sometime
and i want the the final fantasy victory
tune
as well but i don't know how to
oh that was perfect
i guess i had an enderman in my house
i think if you hit them they don't
teleport when they're in mine carts
i'm looking at you yeah you're mad
aren't you
oh
hey what are you gonna do huh
what are you gonna do you got nothing
um let's head up as well you can hear
he's trying to teleport
oh yeah i had stuff below too i forgot
about that
completely forgot about this area it's
been that long
hmm eats road
quick kits
oh yeah
the old old old mob system
and uh i don't even want to think of
that um
yeah i'm pretty sure eats road doesn't
work
i don't have any wood uh
we might try that later
let's go up to the top there and see how
things look
i can't remember how i used to get up
even
i think uh i don't think i could make it
through here
oh yeah that's weird i don't remember
doing that
this is what i like about having old
worlds when you go back and look at them
gives you gives you a good feeling
oh yeah
chocolate island man good times lots of
good times here
sizzler
it's working good
and all all that stuff up there is
broken for sure
baconator
yeah cool to see this stuff again i hope
you guys are enjoying this
uh i'm gonna head to the ice base i
think
that's that's the other main thing i
wanted to see
curious to see what kind of rates it's
getting
all right i'll see you guys there
hopefully i can find that at least still
all right i made it here uh i remember
the way no problem
just like it was yesterday it seems the
biomes though have changed a lot
this is raining here instead of snowing
and i don't know exactly what happened
here but it seems like there's enderman
damage i think
the reason for that is because i didn't
load a backup
before i came here today
so when i was checking things out a few
months ago i
must have triggered some enderman damage
but i'm sure my
old save i don't have that problem
this is it though
looks pretty good now
the new lighting it's a big improvement
the snow looked terrible before
like when 1.8 came out but i think it
was in 1.9 when we got the new lighting
engine
it's a much it's a big improvement
that's for sure
i don't think there's anything up here
all that passive mob farm stuff's
broken definitely
yeah this is pretty pretty much empty up
here we have the passive mobs order
that's it
oh i heard a pig
interesting there's a pig
one pig
yeah so i may try
by the way my world is just as lightly
as it was before i thought
the game
had some optimizing or something it
probably has but i'm just
like back in my other area there still
having low
frame rates like i always had so
ah yeah okay i'm going to try to find a
backup maybe an older backup i wanted to
see this
mob system running
so this is kind of cool i've loaded up
backup from episode 100 and surprise
surprise this is where i logged in
fits perfectly for today thank you
everyone
100 000 subscribers
amazing
and this is where i die nope there we go
yeah a lot of people have been wondering
where spazz is
uh he didn't want to show up today he's
uh he's busy in his own world these days
ah okay i guess i have to try survive
i wasn't very smart when i released
these uh
these world downloads
all right we gotta survive this
otherwise we have to take the long boat
ride back
here so i think that water is probably
our best bet
seem to work yeah spaz he's busy with
his own thing these days
uh setting up traps for you guys that's
what he's been doing
never has time to visit anymore
he's gonna be the villain in the ctm map
it's decided uh
he has a lot of mean traps that's for
sure
a lot of psychological mind benders
uh so this should be
let's switch back to hard here
i should be able to see if this is
working or not this is the main thing i
wanted to check out today because i
will be making a mob system sometime
soon this was a design i really like so
i'm curious to see how it
has fared after the patch
54 up there or so
it's pretty good still
yeah not bad i bet you there is quite a
few getting stuck up there though
because of the idle timer so if a mob is
32 blocks away
i think it's 32 blocks then after a few
seconds they will just go idle and stop
moving
until you get close to them again so
the rates definitely aren't like they
used to be
i remember these just pour out of here
all right good to know
so i think that's uh that's it for here
today
some people wonder if i miss this world
um
definitely had good times here i don't
usually
get overly attached to things though
it's fun to come back and visit
for sure but uh i'm enjoying the new
world i like how
well we got enderman everywhere i like
how things aren't
uh quite so broken in the new world like
a lot of stuff here broke
uh oh t went off what
a lot of stuff here broke i had a lot of
incomplete projects and that was kind of
bugging me too here
new world's a lot better and as i build
it more
i'm sure we will become just as attached
to it as we were this one
what was that blast from
oh it must have just triggered somehow
weird all right uh
we're done here let's head back to the
real world the main world our new world
yep so we made it back here i hope you
guys enjoyed today's episode we should
probably wrap it up now
i wanted to give you a longer one today
without
dragging it out too much uh hopefully
hopefully you didn't feel it was dragged
out i tried really hard not to
and i think we might just hit an hour
just might yeah the thing is though to
make this episode it took me two days so
that's kind of why i don't like to do
long episodes
um i just it just takes too long i put a
lot of hours into making each episode
and i
and it kind of shows with people's
reactions because my lp is
seems to be everyone's favorite thing i
do on my channel so
because i put the most effort into it
so i'm glad you guys still enjoy
watching my videos
um the common opinion now upon
minecrafters is that lp's the whole lp
thing is kind of
done with people
people need to do something else to get
started so
i'm glad you guys still find my uh my
videos interesting
that they've withstood the test of time
so to speak
and i'm still not bored of the game i'm
loving the game i had a comment
recently a few weeks ago someone said
they basically said thanks for the video
etho
um take it easy though don't feel
don't let it be a burden making a video
every day for us and uh
really it's not it's kind of like uh
i'm living a dream here because uh
the way this works i'm making money
through
oh we got another one i'm making money
through the ads on my videos from people
viewing them
and i'm getting lots of views on my
videos which is great
and minecraft is my favorite game
so i'm basically getting paid quite a
bit of money i'm not allowed to say
exactly how much otherwise it would it's
part of the adsense
contract but it's
it's hard to say this but i'm actually
making more playing video games these
days and i am for my real job
so yeah this is pretty awesome
i basically get paid to play my favorite
video game
and then
then when i read the comments and stuff
i get people telling me how much they
love it and
how much they enjoy my videos and that's
just
it's such a great thing so
thank you everyone you make this fun and
i've been talking to a lot of youtubers
lately
and quite a few of them have said they
don't like reading their comments
just because people say mean things
and i still love reading mine so that's
that's a sign that you guys are nice to
me because
it's a lot of fun reading the comments
and i still do read pretty much all of
them so
don't feel like you're not being heard i
might not reply but i'm definitely
taking the time to read them usually it
takes me a good hour to read
the comments for one video so
yep and what else is i going to say
oh yeah it's going to give you some
statistics of my channel so far so
for those of you wondering my lp series
i think this is episode
was this 142 143 i can't remember but i
i checked it today and the total if you
were to watch my
episodes from episode 1 to now it
is 61 hours
total time and that is equivalent to
basically two
and a half days
so if you're new to my channel and you
just start watching episode one that's
how
how many hours it'll take you or how
many days days
it will take you to watch them all so i
thought that was kind of interesting
although i do encourage you to watch
them because
well i was a little rougher when i
started i'm still kind of rough
but they're pretty good
um some other information
let's see daily views have really risen
for me lately
um so i watch my statistics on a website
called socialblade
so if you go to social blade i'm not
trying to do a plug for them or anything
but if you go to socialblade
and type in ethos lab you can see
statistics for my channel
and yeah actually i'll leave it at that
if you want to see the statistics
just check it out there but basically my
views have risen
quite a bit my subscriber rate has risen
quite a bit
especially recently today i checked it
and it was like at 900
subscribers today which is crazy
absolutely crazy i think my average is
about 500
now or 600
which is a quite the increase and of
course i want to say oh thanks to all my
youtube buddies i have quite a few now a
lot of people i talk to and hang out
with
and thank them for supporting me all
this time
um i think that's
uh i think that's it i did organize
information for new
signs to add to the tree farm here but i
don't have any sandstone right now
and it's getting late here i don't have
time to mine it so
i'll have to do that some other day but
it is ready i got all the information
ready
and that's the end of my rambling so
thanks guys i'll see you next time