so this is what it's like being a cow
you guys do anything fun or is like bump
into each other all day
that you can't prove that was me note
did oh well what's going on ah there's
no evidence to me since wherever I walk
cows explode into flames not a murder so
I don't want anybody calling me a
monster anything like that for like
keeping these cows and inhumane
conditions stuffed into these little
areas bumping into each other all day
even after I killed them all here for no
I didn't kill them they burst even after
they burst into flames they have all the
area in the world it's just what they do
that's what they like so I'm doing them
a favor overcrowding them all right very
good so we got some food nom nom nom nom
nom
I was running dangerously low I had to
have to refill there now we got like
eight stacks at stake which is awesome
should should be enough for today's
episode I go through food really quick
in this game like from all the inter
purling and and falling and dirtiness
and I don't know I just I do a lot of
jumping to it yes I go through food
really quick but yeah welcome back to
everyone to another episode here to
start off with I want to deal with the
zombie problem we've got with this thing
with our mob system that we've been
building so right now we have cats and
dogs or ocelots and wolves I guess is
the proper proper name we got them in
there and that's chasing the skeletons
and the creepers down into the water
here but if you hear it we got like
zombies stuck in there so we got to get
some villagers to attract them we'll
probably put those just on the outside
this is the middle right yeah that's the
middle so we got to figure out how many
we need or that we can get away with and
to figure it out we kind of need to know
how the zombie tracking works on the
villager
so that is our first project for today
I'm gonna head over to a creative world
and try to figure that out and then I'll
show you what I figure out so I'll see
you over there and here we are I have
figured a few things out it's actually
pretty cool
so of course as you know zombies are
attracted to villagers they home into
them pretty quickly as you saw doesn't
take them long to start walking towards
them although that guy's a little dumb
um they detract them from a very long
distance as well as they get farther
away they sometimes take a little longer
to find the villager usually it's pretty
quick and this is about the limit like I
don't think this guy will will find the
villager even this guy's having trouble
oh he did it just takes a little bit
longer
this is at like 40 blocks away alright
that's kind of cool but the thing I'm
interested in is the height that the
zombie that the zombies will track the
villagers so I found out at this height
here yeah here and this site here is the
limit if this guy goes one block lower
there let's just do it one at a time
I'll show you that guy's a block oops
Wow he he decided he wanted to go there
really quickly Danny
so yeah you see they don't they don't
see the villager they don't need a line
of sight to them either I that guy
started walking because he was trying to
get over here if they're tracking the
villager they their heads will look down
at them but you see the head is straight
across all right so if we move this guy
up one block and of course I mean kill
him and get a new villager we're not
actually gonna move them right away they
start tracking in
so that is five blocks below this path
here all right
and then upwards pretty much the same
deal five blocks above is the limit so
if we go put some zombies down once
again they are not seeing him drop them
down one block although I guess the baby
zombie heads are yeah the baby zombies
won't see them because their head is one
block lower so keep that in mind I bet
you he'll track this guy down here
though oh yeah I think you saw him there
learn to tell me anyway so with that in
mind we can do one more test really
quickly here just show you this
we got a villager down there and a
zombie up here he will not track them
because this is one well unless that guy
goes up the staircase
you reckon my test one oops I was trying
to chant one two three four five six
blocks down it's out of out of range so
that level zombie can't see them go one
level up pretty much right away alright
whew okay so now with what we know I've
marked this out we have six layers in
the mob system which I marked on this
side here that three to the layers
starts and then on the Left here is
where I'm planning on putting the
villagers so counting from here like if
we have a zombie spawning here if we go
one two three four that's within range
that the zombie will see a villager up
there even a baby zombie will see a
villager there if we don't care about
the baby zombies we could go one higher
with the villager from there - there's
good there
there's good from there to there is one
two three four five blocks down so again
that's within range going downwards so
the only two layers that won't see the
villager at that height is this one and
this one so we need a second villager we
could increase the distance between the
two villagers like I could raise this
one higher but we're at the top of the
mob system anyway so I don't really care
so now we got to figure out how to get a
zombie villager up on on these blocks
and then convert them should be fun Oh
skeleton skeleton no all right this is
it we're gonna get one oh no his helmet
broke oh my I don't have a helmet either
no see
oh please live please live he's not
gonna live he lived
yes all right
there you go I'm going to give you your
Apple now I kind of need them to stay
put let me get rid of this ladder maybe
he'll move a little closer
it's the template some block there mmm
here let me try sand just can't I can't
let him walk that way again or good burn
no ah
start it oh I just noticed another
problem I went inside here to check up
on it and I guess all the cats are out
of position so I'm gonna have to put
them where the wolf is try to force them
together otherwise we'll just keep
coming loose I think because when I'm in
the area and I'm fighting the mobs they
like stand up
to try help me out and then they I think
they're getting out of place that way
dad's really tough to push the two
together so this is how I'm doing it
like that a little bit place one more
and yeah once again I do not recommend
this type of mob system setting this up
has been really difficult like building
it's easy getting the cats and dogs
where you need them insane
okay I know zombies don't really have
brains but this guy has some real
problems he's totally ignoring me like
totally well it wasn't easy but we did
it we got one villager up there and
number two is right over there all right
very good excellent we have the
villagers in place one two we have the
ocelots and the wolves they've been put
back into place and they should probably
stay there now I think everything is
working pretty good with this now
there's a one issue I've noticed though
because it's based on an even number
like like that we got trapdoors there
and there
the middle is two blocks wide basically
we have to put these guys on one of the
sides and because of that any zombies on
this side of the spawning platform
sometimes one of the zombies won't fall
down he'll he'll just stay like right on
the edge of falling down because he's
tracking the villager that's not till
another zombie comes by and that he gets
pushed down from the other zombie
not a big deal just like like when I
when I checked it sometimes there'd be
like three zombies stuck in there total
but that's not a big deal
anyway so I've been trying to decide
what to do on the outside of this thing
we're done with all the inside and the
workings of it I couldn't come up with
any good ideas so I've decided we are
going to convert it into like a snowy
mountain which doesn't make sense
because it's in the desert but that's
what we're doing and there's jungle
trees next to it but we'll try make it
work I mostly just want an excuse to to
make some snowy animal statues because I
love sculpting animals in this game and
just sculpting stuff period I don't do a
lot of it but a lot of fun so I have a
penguin design that I want to I want to
do here we'll have one on the base level
let's see I'm trying to remember it I
think it goes like this nice fluffy
tummy on him I just I don't know I just
will do it out of black all right
goes up like this and then I think I got
wings here just make them stick out like
that oops let's see if I remember right
it was six tall what are we at right now
we're at four okay so his head head is
like two blocks I think go back up and
pretty sure I had it solid black do that
give them a nice beak and a couple eyes
oh yeah
that's how you make a penguin or how I
make a penguin I should say let's go
take a look oh yeah awesome so I'm gonna
be let's see where's my chest I brought
out or I made a whole bunch of snow
blocks I'm gonna start converting this
area
to a snow world which should be pretty
fun basically just going to spam snow
everywhere try to make it form a cool
shape and after we do that I might start
adding ice around the area to and maybe
some other little decorations I have a
couple other animals or at least one
more animal I want to do a wooly mammoth
as well maybe a walrus
I might attempt a walrus and maybe a
polar bear we'll see how daring I am
with this though but we'll definitely
have a few penguins so check it out we
have a pretty good start to things
already I covered the whole thing with
snow and now I want to start like
building the mountain trying to make it
look less flat so I started on this side
let's go check it out our penguin may
add some stairs to get up here I'm not
sure yet I've made some artificial like
Cove areas which I may put things in got
like frozen lake here I don't know
frozen water also known as ice and comes
up to a second layer here and haven't
really started on this other side yet
but I thought it would be cool if we put
the woolly was this here before it must
have been here before I don't remember
doing that that'd be cool if we put the
woolly mammoth right on this ledge here
he'll need a little bit of space he's
kind of big but let me show you my
design
alright so start with his hooves see if
I can remember this is a little more
complicated than the banquet and I think
it comes up one and oh look it's it's
black and the blocks black in my hands
for some reason because I'm standing on
the I think it is yeah do you stand on
slow sand everything turns dark oh I got
my whoops all right yeah I had a little
problem while recording this episode
already my power went off for hours so
recording this has gone on for several
days now but hopefully we'll wrap it up
here yeah my power went off last night
and I was like just about ready to
finish recording this and upload it and
that happened it wrecked what I had
edited already so I had to redo that and
oh man such a disaster sometimes things
don't always go my way um I think this
comes up and then like he needs he needs
his trunk
oh no it's basically an elephant right
brown elephant um we're I'm assuming
they are extinct you never know
do we want to element so you come down
one more they have really long trunks
okay and then we want our our beautiful
ivory I think it goes over there okay
and when you see pictures of mammoths
they usually have pretty long tusks so
we'll make these come out a bit more and
make them curved a little bit see that
good enough tell you what I'm going to
try make it a little longer and we'll
decide if we like that more like I
really whoops
how many times did I do that here give
them really long tusks it's a really old
Namek alright and one over here and then
got to figure out the rest of his head
he needs ears take this away oh oh I
think they're on the wrong level aren't
they
he has some straight oops how did I do
that
what's that oh my goodness I should have
made the platform a little bit further
because I keep falling off of it
just one block too short oh and I missed
click there there don't touch it I don't
care if I lost the quartz block I'm not
I'm not going to get it alright let's
try to get on top here I'll smooth out
his head a bit more and I think yeah I
think this comes up and then this comes
out he's got big like Mouse ears which I
don't think is quite right but I know
sometimes you see elephants and they
stick their ears out like really far and
that's what I'm trying to copy give him
some eyes um that right maybe we will
bring the ears back a little bit more
keep them separate from the eyes so
we'll put them like back here yeah here
somehow this feels a little off I might
have to make some adjustments all right
so it's fixes neck man give them a
little tail or should we have a droopy
tail I think their tails are pretty
short actually I think elephants or
mammoths don't really have long tails
oops
all right now how can we see this from a
good place
let's let's just build off a little ways
it's like a side shot of it go up a
little bit I'm going to add probably
some way of killing the zombies too
because they they keep a track getting a
track to that spot to the villagers so
I'll add some way of killing those ones
too on the outside
that's pretty close I think that's
that's about right
make a few adjustments yeah he seems
maybe a little too tall I'm not sure you
know what it might be maybe should lower
this like down to there and squish it
down a bit
all right everyone so I think I'm done
working on this for today we got a lot
done actually but we're gonna go on a
quick little guided tour of what we got
done before we end it with our with our
zombie buddy here so I got this side
kind of done we got a nice little
waterfall was a fake glacier sort of
thing up there and it goes down to a
pool which I'll probably make another
waterfall once I figure this out this
area he goes up all the way to the top
probably put a bunch of stone down I
need to get more stone into this instead
of just all solid snow no don't do it no
wait what is he doing oh I thought he's
gonna jump off but he did all right well
he kind of did but not in the right spot
he is so confused I think he's trying to
hide from the Sun no oh creeper oh maybe
not
should put on sunscreen all right so
added some icicles in a few places as
well just and like these overhang things
which I think are pretty cool probably
do a little more that kind of stuff and
I changed the mammoths so I just I made
his head go down a bit more his head
isn't as well-defined but he doesn't
look gigantic anymore either so I'm not
sure which I like more I think I like
this one though with the head lower
uh-huh and what else should we do maybe
one more thing we'll try I'm going to
try and make a an ice tree that that'll
be the last thing we do so here's the
plan we're not actually going to make it
out of ice I decided to try make glass
tree instead and I guess we'll go up
here acacia trees have a pretty cool
growth pattern so we're going to use
that I'm not going to do like a custom
tree I'm just going to copy the acacia
tree we put one here let's try it out
put some dirt down geishas appening make
it grow should be able to grow right
yeah alright so that is our layout for
the tree that Asia wood looks good
pretty good the Taoiseach wood looks
good pretty good the Taoiseach wood
looks good in in snow biomes so we can
keep that the way it is but I might
replace all these leaves with maybe I'll
just do the light blue glass and see how
that looks and then we'll probably have
to change it up just a little bit I
don't know about this guy's it's a it's
just a little too flat I tried doing a
few things I tried using pains and
randomizing those a bit didn't really
work out now I tried changing just like
randomizing full blocks a bunch of
different colors try to give it depth
but the tree like the Titian trees are
actually pretty flat I should have maybe
made a custom tree instead umm anyway
let me know I might tear it down but
I'll see what you guys say about it umm
if not maybe yeah I don't know I'll see
what you guys say if we should keep it
or not
anyway here is the comment for today
etho what is your favorite color
and number is a simple kind of weird
weird wired weird question to ask but it
is interesting as well I love watching
your videos thank you I can't remember
if I answered this before but my
favorite color is green
which is why I like the grass so much in
this game pretty much like this color
green maybe even a little brighter but
this is very close to my favorite color
um second pretty close favorite color of
those blue I really like blue as well
like well it's kind of transparent but
light blue especially um favorite number
for some reason no reason that like no
reason that I can think of is 137 137
don't know why that's my favorite number
it just is for some reason I decided I
liked that number well a lot of people
actually like seven as a number and it
has seven in it so maybe that's part of
it and it has 13 in it I don't know
something strange about that number
maybe mathematicians out there know
something special about that number I've
never looked into it but for some reason
I like that number alright anyway so we
got our penguin Mountain here the top
down this thing's pretty cool the
zombies will walk all the way up it
they'll get to the top and then it'll
drop down and I might put like a slime
block that launches them out when they
when they drop down there because
they're trying to get to that villager
and that's the closest point they can
get to is when they land on there but
they can't get up there like from down
here so that they have to walk all the
way up and then fall down just kind of
interesting um and I think the only
reason they do that actually I'll have
to experiment with that yeah I'm not
going to comment on it I don't really
know anyway that's it for day today guys
I hope you enjoyed it and I will see you
again in the next one bye bye
you