[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back guys to another
episode of the let's play series
hopefully you guys are having yourselves
a wonderful day today what have I been
up to what C fo been doing in the world
here well we're still working on the
projects guys trying to do the what is
it the the fixing the finishing and
there's a third one - what was it the
forgetting that's right yep so in line
with our plan we figure out last episode
guys we're gonna be focusing on fixing
projects finishing them or if they're
broken beyond repair and there's nothing
we can do about it if we can't fix or
finish a project we're gonna forget
about it is that is what we got planned
so that hopefully our world will get
into better shape for the world tour at
Episode five 50 here and in line with
that one of the projects I worked on
fixing up it wasn't actually broken but
I felt like a little bit of work could
really bring it to the next level here
and I'm actually using this farm quite a
bit now this flower farm to grow these
fungi before we would stand here we're
told right click and this would bounce
back and forth and stuff or pop off now
all we got to do is hit start and it's
all automatic so there's a dispenser
with bonemeal underneath there and every
time the floor shifts they grow some
grass and then when it chips again it
pops off and grows it again we hit stop
whenever we're done when we got enough
products then I added another thing up
here this is the quick collect we used
to have a hopper minecart that ran under
this and pick stuff up but it was way
too slow wasn't able to pick up
everything I figured why don't we just
add some water buckets to bring this
stuff to us here there's a composting
station over here so if we want to break
stuff down into bone meal if we're not
gonna need it for anything like a lot of
this grass stuff so then we also have
some hoppers that run under this
composter and it delivers the bone meal
it produces to the dispenser that grows
the grass so that's all kind of
automatic we manually load bone meal in
over here as well and I'll just show you
underneath here really quickly so yeah
this is the composter above this hopper
and brings the stuff to the dispenser
and unfortunately it's a little bit hard
to see the wiring down here but
essentially we have two observers on
each side here they detect when the
grass moves this one here this one
checks this one and then sends the power
outs over here this runs up to one set
of the Pistons and also to the dispenser
with a bone meal and then this one runs
to the set of business now last episode
one of the big projects we worked at
fixing up was our gold farm number two
we transformed it into the new bloom
farm or golden iron farm and it seems
like it's gonna be a pretty important
project to our world so I decided let's
go the extra mile with this thing and
we're gonna work on making it pretty
cool today hopefully oh here we go here
we go yeah there we go one two three
four five six six seven uh-huh so thank
you guys very much for your help in the
last episode in the comments I could not
figure out why we were only getting like
two or three iron golems at a time it
was driving me crazy
one of the first things that I saw
suggested and one of the first things I
tried you guys said get rid of these
slabs here so apparently if we do an f3
be you can do it there that blue line in
front of the villager is where he's
looking and in order to spawn an iron
golem the villagers need to see the
zombie here and you can see like where
they're looking is in line with these
slabs these slabs were blocking out
their vision to the zombie and that's
why we weren't really giving any iron
golem spawning yeah so we've made some
pretty big changes to the goon farm here
since last episode and we're about to
make some more big changes so just
wanted to show you where we're at before
things get too crazy so we've added in a
hopper clock here to control the iron
golem spawning and that goes to each of
these zombie chambers I got rid of the
Pistons that were here and we went with
trapdoors instead those open up and
allow the villagers to see the zombies
those two all four of these things here
before we were using white terracotta
for our spawning platform and I ripped
that all out it's all gone we got it
replaced with magma blocks now which has
two advantages it doesn't spawn the pig
lens the guys that steal the gold yeah
it's pretty nice you don't really want
those when you're making a gold farm
right so we get more Pigman spawns as
well because of that because they're not
spotting the other thing the magma
blocks do is they slowly kill the iron
golem so if there's ever a situation
where there's nothing on the platform no
zombie pigmen to kill them they'll still
die which is great that gets rid of them
keeps the iron flow going today what I'd
like to do with this farm our main goal
is to get it working quicker right now
when we spawn the iron golems like every
two minutes or so we got to wait for
them all to die and then 30 seconds
after that we can spawn in a new set of
them if we move the iron golems 16
blocks away from the villagers though
like right away we can spawn the next
wave like within 30 seconds of that so
we can go from like 2 minute waves down
to 40 second waves probably if we can
find some way to drop the iron golems we
can't move them with water though like
we do in the overworld we need some
other sneaky things so I'm planning on
putting a zombie Pigman in the middle
giving him a name tag or something so he
doesn't despawn then any iron golems
that spawn on here will run to the
middle and then fall down how to do all
of that though is gonna be a bit of work
here we pretty much have to build a
second spawning platform to the farm
which is gonna take a lot of glass and a
lot of other resources so I'm collecting
sand at the moment and good stuff all
right so let's melt that into glass over
at our super smelter wait a minute did I
say super smelter I meant our new and
improved and super smelter here yep yep
so the other day I ended up absolutely
gutting the super smelter just ripped
out a good 70% of it I would say down to
the bone we got rid of the fuel
distribution system minutes we were
using copper mine carts before
spruce planks we got rid of all that and
replaced it with water streams so that
we could hook it up to the bamboozler
and supply it with bamboo fuel instead
so we have the bamboo plants down there
growing in the column and get squished
into the water screen and flies up
emerges in the middle here goes down
it's down this water screen over top of
all the hoppers here that go into the
furnace fuel slots how are we doing how
far did we get so it goes down the right
side of this middle chamber oh no that's
not a good sign we got an issue oh so
much bamboo what do we do with all that
bamboo stacks on stacks of bamboo stacks
on stacks of bamboo there's still more
bamboo here oh my goodness there's so
much bamboo what do we do get entire
depressing queue from all the bamboo
very good very good so we gotta fire it
up here again that's coming up come down
goes through change the water stream a
little bit over here I straightened it
out and then I added a ring over here
now so that aligns to this side of the
glass instead of a left side against the
trap doors here that way it won't fall
into the hopper spot so it goes down the
stream here to underneath the slab and
then goes over this set of hoppers into
these furnaces and we got redstone in
our way we jump over top of it like a
ninja we go over we keep going forward
it goes to the left aligns against these
trap doors oh no it's not a trap door
thickness here though it aligns right
against the edge of the block
I was wondering like why doesn't it fall
in the hoppers here that's because it's
it's on the edge of the hopper still
okay so it goes down the middle again so
there's like two separate water streams
in the middle here now when it goes down
this side it falls down here goes
underneath this water stream to the left
upper water elevator
looks like it kind of gets stuck on that
slap but it'll go down apparently so
that's fine and and it goes down this
side and we oh we are totally full now
it's just I think we just reached full
capacity so now this is supposed to go
back to the bamboozler and I had that up
yet so I am gonna shut this off we are
full of fuel
uh-huh so that was quite a big overhaul
to our super smelter here guys a big
project but I am happy it is done again
there wasn't anything really broken with
the super smelter before but the fuel
system wasn't really working the best
you saw even when we broke some of those
furnaces they had some unsalted items in
so like The Closer furnaces were getting
fuel but the further one further away
ones weren't so that was an issue check
this out this is all the spruce wood we
pulled out of there so again I don't
hope that's not true so I didn't want to
keep using spruce wood because that
takes a bit of time to farm out right
even though we have a pretty good farm
for it I would much rather use bamboo
and the only way we could really use
bamboo is if we redid the distribution
system so that's why we did the revamp
here now check this out oh yeah and
there used to be a chest here for
putting fuel and obviously that's gone
because it doesn't get supplied here
anymore it comes from the bamboozler
yeah let's throw in some sand again we
still have the super quick feed system
to it so that's cool the distribution
for the items is exactly the same that's
the only thing I didn't change about it
and I also redid the elevator so when I
built this originally we didn't have
bubble streams in the game right no no
water elevators like this so I had a
quad dropper elevator which was both
amazing and horrible it made so much
noise
it was so laggy so instead now we just
have a very simple very effective water
elevator here brings items up they get
dropped on top of a minecart here upper
minecart this is sitting on top of three
different hoppers which splits the items
evenly
into three different hoppers and then
that allows them to fill the Shocker box
here and three times the normal fill
speed because again with this super
smelter I think we're smelting twelve
stacks per minute with the drew twelve
point eight items a second so it needs
to be able to handle that and even with
the three hopper speed it gets backed up
a little bit you see this is filling up
so we kind of need like bore but it's
good enough I think as long as we don't
run it for too too long
we got a dispenser back here we can put
empty Shanker boxes in and then I just
grab these and go I gotta work on an
interface for this thing I wanted to
show to you guys before I covered
everything up here so you can see how it
works
we also have a redstone line running up
to a light this tells me when we're low
on fuel that light will go off when
we're down to our final stack of fuel so
that's good I don't want to run the
bamboozler again and what else oh yeah I
did the mushroom thing here too so
mushroom is kind of like my go-to wall
material now I think because it's so
easy to farm I didn't like that it
looked like stone and dirt and stuff
mixed in the walls here so I replaced at
all with mushroom blocks and same sort
of deal with the bamboozler here we had
dirt and stone showing on the wall so I
replaced all the walls here with the
mushroom blocks and I think that looks a
lot better it's a nice clean look to it
now we still got to build some kind of
structure over top of this though I'll
probably keep the glass open like this
because I like to how it looks when you
look down here you might notice I'm back
to eating fish here again even though he
got the farmer villager that I
desperately wanted we unlocked all his
trades we got the golden carrot trade
and then he wandered out over to here
and then you won't restock unless he
goes back to the village I put a path
for him to climb back up
over here guy look you can get back but
he's not taking it he he doesn't like it
they're wandering a lot further than
they used to like they would never go up
to the top of these stairs and now they
all seem to be doing it so I don't know
I'm gonna probably put some tracks here
some minecart tracks and then they won't
be able to cross it it's trying to get
up here nah you stay in a fault it's the
pit and never get out again
Oh oh he's trying look at that he's
really trying okay so check out this
amazing contraption here you put down
your fungi
you hit the button BAM we got crimson
wood tree can chop her down we get the
next one going this is just a very
temporary setup guys until I can make an
automated one probably at the crimson
keep we'll set up like a TNT crimson
wood farm but for now this is how I'm
farming crimson wood and the shroom
lights and stuff and I built it here oh
look we got true mites they're actually
kind of rare but I'm trying to get like
at least two stacks of them for the goon
farm at the moment one of the resources
we need but what I can do with this as
well a lot of times the shroom might
spawn up pretty high actually so I can
take the elevator and then just fly over
here and your mom it you know and of
course we also got ourselves a composter
here for making bone meal you guys don't
know nether work blocks have an 85
percent chance of adding a layer to the
compost bin seven layers equals a bone
meal what does that mean I think it's
it's like eight per bone meal maybe
something like that oh and by the way I
did figure something out here with our
base so behind the waterfall we've had
this area for a long time or basically
we can fly through and get to the
library but it's a mess right I just
blew some TNT and made a tunnel through
here and that's pretty much it I put
down some grass what I think I want to
do with this area is turn it into like
an abandoned mineshaft sort of thing
like have some planks on the roof and
have these little areas these little
stashes and behind
these is where I'm gonna stash a lot of
my stuff that I have a lot of like I
don't need to have all these pumpkins on
hand so this is gonna be like a bulk
storage just throw now bunch of barrels
and I'll probably decorate this a lot
nicer but yeah I need to get some basalt
here man I keep forgetting to bring fire
resistant potions or I think even if you
have frost Walker on your boots you
don't take mega man block damage kind of
annoying okay so we're gonna try you in
a zombie Pigman in the middle there at
some point but for now I think I'm gonna
bust out this so we gotta lower our
collection system to the platform we
build below oh I gotta gotta bust this
out we're just testing this right now I
just have a tiny platform built down
there oh we're fine I think they're mad
at me right now though just one of you
needs to cross oh you crossed oh but you
fell yeah yeah okay this this could be
it block it and then and then what I got
to put down a trap door so he can't get
out I think we caught a guy I don't want
to do this maybe we'll put some glass
blocks above them yeah I think we got
our guy here so I'm at a name um this is
our center of attention I'm gonna try to
get this trapdoor right I'm gonna move
that to over here flip that up then
we're free to get rid of this one we got
a glass block above his head so
hopefully iron golems will be able to
see them when they spawn on the platform
around them but then we have enough of a
gap here where they shouldn't be able to
hit them I think it's one two four do we
need a three block gap I'm not sure
we'll find out I guess yeah okay good we
got some iron golems so the next part of
this is we don't want zombie Pigman to
spawn on this layer actually we only
want iron golems too and we want them to
fall down to the Pigman below
so the that layer down there is where we
want the Pigman in the spawn and iron
golems up here here we go again
so I kind of want to watch this and see
if they can hit this guy in the middle
no they weren't able to okay good so
they're gonna fall down looks like they
can't reach they'll fall down they'll
get out of the way of these villagers 16
blocks away from them pretty quickly and
then they'll do their fighting down
below there instead of up high here we
got to pay a visit to our bulk storage
here our old bulk storage which is like
out of space that's why we need a new
one yeah this is where I keep a lot of
stuff mostly just cobblestone and stone
and stuff but I know we got some wool
here too don't we a lot of cobblestone
yeah there we go that's what I'm looking
for we want some whoa we got to make a
bunch carpet yeah they're not spotting
on the carpet I thought iron golems good
ah can you tell I don't do much with
iron golems alright we gotta get rid of
the carpet now it's not gonna work
so I read something or I heard something
before that iron golems could spawn on
glass if there was a block below that's
why I thought it would work with carpets
as well but apparently both those things
aren't true oh no I can't get them to
spawn glass so I think I might have been
duped the other problem with this is if
they target this guy and they fall down
you see they're surrounded by zombie
Pigman but they won't fight them because
they're locked on target with this guy
hey how's it going things good with you
things are going all right with me
things are progressing you know we're
making some good progress on this build
so I'm underneath the spotting platform
the new one we're building for the
zombie pigmen and I got to move the
collection system so I'm tearing it out
up above and we're building it down
below here I put in a layer of the salts
we got shroom lights surrounding us
magma blocks above us and now I got to
go through here put down the rails for
the Mahavir minecart this every so often
we got to put some power rails in if you
find yourself in an odd situation like
this I've kind of learned a couple
couple little tricks with it so if you
want to move quickly you gotta light
your wings you got you got a jump if you
jump you can kind of move a little a
little faster you can't also enderpearl
when you're when you're like this it's
kind of nice you know
all right everybody so check it out I
think we've got the goon firm pretty
much all built for today anyways oh yeah
there we go we got some iron golems we
got I think seven that time so it's not
always eight but usually it's it's
pretty good um yeah I think it's pretty
much all built but we might need to do
some fine-tuning with it I'm still
messing with a few things so one thing
you'll notice first off here is I shrunk
the platform at the top here it used to
stick out all the way up to that edge Oh
down below there and I think I shaved
off three or four blocks all around the
perimeter that is so that when iron
golems spawn up here they will see the
center of attention right away if they
are beyond this border here sometimes
they couldn't see him and they would
just wander around this way they see him
they get off the platform as quick as
possible now we also had an issue where
the iron golems would see the center of
attention they would fall down there and
then they would still want to attack
that guy the way I solved that was by
lowering that platform down there
another two blocks down you see like
they went to that guy but now they're
fighting the guys down there
it's okay that's because they fall over
16 blocks away from the center of
attention
that means he's outside of their target
range and then they find a new target
that way so unfortunately we did not get
this down to 42nd waves though like I
wanted I think it's that 55 second waves
at the moment we got 68 items in the
hopper clock but this might be something
I find tuned a little bit better might
be making some adjustments on that but
as it is right now it's pretty good I
think it's about twice as quick as what
we had originally so that's cool that's
cool
let's go take a look from over here and
get an idea what the farm looks like so
yeah the top layers for the iron golems
bottom layers for the zombie pigmen and
the gas and stuff the iron golems they
definitely could be ramped up like if
you wanted to make this farm a lot
better double the number of villagers
double the number of iron golems look
you can get 16 per wave oh man that's
this thing would be crazy yeah check
that out looks good
go to the center of attention they fall
down they find a new target all the
zombie pigmen rush to the middle if they
get scattered and like as soon as they
fall down they're 30 seconds after that
then we can spawn a new wave of iron
golem so that's pretty cool and you see
we got a hopper minecart system running
right now so that just picked up a bunch
of stuff we got item filters here so
when this hopper minecart takes off it
passes by these five hoppers this one
puts a one piece of gold in this one put
some pieces of nuggets ghast here iron
and rotten flesh that means the the
hopper minecart doesn't pick up any of
the golden swords or anything on the on
the ground they're just items we
actually want to collect all right so it
automatically unloads once it's done it
takes off we also have a second hopper
minecart going this one as it arrives it
sends a pulse to this thing so if the
other one is sitting here it gets out of
the way and then this one takes its
place yeah so this is what it looks like
underneath the platform the hopper mine
carts they bounce back and forth they
pick up the items through the magma box
here
according to their filter that we set
with these hoppers as they each put one
item in um and then on the return trip I
made it so that the hopper minecart
passes over top of these filters so that
drops off at least one item back into
here and that way we never need to
refill these it's all automatic now
unlike before how do we do this time oh
we got a guest here nice nice
I've noticed that a lot of time it's
like totally full on iron so I might get
rid of this is not zombie flesh here and
just have a double iron filter I'm not
sure if we're getting it all or if some
of it's the spawning uh-huh
but let's take a step back let's look at
the farm so I think it looks pretty cool
too so I used basalt and shroom lights
and magma blocks I like it I think that
looks way cooler than it used to
we also have a bunch of shroom lights
over here this is stop zombies from
spawning on top of this glass oh and I
almost forgot to show you guys this as
well so the minecart unloads here and
then down below we got a bunch of item
item filters set up and they funnel into
each of the categories so we got iron
over here we got golden nuggets gold
ingots flesh and a whole whopping three
gas tiers probably won't fill all these
up but hey you know we got in there if
we ever do it just they just can't make
up their mind guys pick it up like 50
swords at a time uh-huh so unfortunately
with this farm it doesn't work optimally
if I'm down here or if I'm on the
platform on the side they're observing
it we actually have to stand over here
because otherwise we get the odd zombie
Pigman spawning up here or gassed and
then when the iron golems spawn they'll
want to fight these guys up here instead
of going down like they're supposed to
so because that carpet trick didn't work
or putting glass overtop we I don't know
how to stop these guys from spawning
besides just standing here
if we stand here they won't spawn but
iron golem still will and I think with
that guys it's about time we wrap up
this episode for today which is a bit
unfortunate because I had some big plans
for the Crimson keep I thought we would
get today but that'll have to wait until
next time we'll probably get a lot done
there next time comment of the day says
etho I was curious as to what your
production process is like for your
channel like how is your time split
between building filming and editing our
episodes ever only a day of playing or
do you film over a couple of days
you try alternate between day to day
what series you film for anyway I'm
loving the new episodes but thank you
very much um so the number one
time-consuming thing for this series and
a lot of my series for that matter is
the designing and planning of stuff so I
try really hard especially with this
series to show you guys something new
every time I try to come up with my own
redstone devices and that sort of thing
and that that stuff takes forever like
so much time
you gotta come up with an idea you got a
you got to build it and test it and then
optimize it and then you experience
twenty other problems on the way you got
to fix all those and then you gotta
collect the resources to build it so
that's another that's probably second
most time-consuming thing and then comes
the building then comes filming then
comes editing in that order I would say
editing is still probably the quickest
part of making my episodes our episodes
only ever a day of playing they used to
be like in the past I used to record
like two or three in a day sometimes
even it depends a lot on the series
though like something like terra firma
punk or enigmatic on number two i can
almost always record an episode of that
in a single day but like the let's play
series here it's very rare that i get it
done in a day it's usually at least two
in this case i've been recording this
episode over four or five days now i
think i don't think all those were full
days though but yeah it's been a bit of
work and do you try to alternate between
day to day what series you film for yeah
i do for sure
I usually will do like a let's play the
hermit craft and Terra Firma pond
then maybe back to the let's play it's
nice to do it that way it gives a lot of
variety for what I'm doing in the game
that way I don't get burnt out on
Minecraft always doing the same thing
right and hopefully you guys like it
that way as well kind of goes along with
my whole like having a hundred projects
going mentality I do that between series
as well it carries over uh-huh um but
yeah I do also give preference like of a
certain series is more popular than
others I'll usually try to record it a
little bit more than the other ones so
right now hermit craft is by far the
most popular one and it's also a
multiplayer series and those usually get
a little bit more about preference as
well just because stuff is
time-sensitive on those but anyways
that's that's it for today thank you for
your questions and your comments
hopefully you enjoyed today's episode
until next time take care have a good
one bye bye
[Music]