[Music]
check this out
oh you gotta love this game oh
yep
ah oh killed torch killed the torch
not totally useless pick that efficiency
negative one on it or something
all right i'm gonna re-log here's the
moment of truth
ah very good we can dig again
so yeah what i'm doing here i'm just
trying to make a huge delay
for this portal gizmo we hooked up last
time just testing something
and i'm not going to go any longer delay
on this if it doesn't work this time
i'm just going to do
do the simple way but what it's supposed
to do
hit this lights the portal
now it's going through the delay the
huge delay
and after a certain amount of time
it should disable itself
that's a really long time wow
so i thought if i do this and i go into
the portal quickly
like like i definitely went in before
that time was up
i thought i'd be able to return and then
when i return the portal would go out
but it's it's like uh the redstone still
works even after i'm in the nether here
yeah see it disabled the portal
sent me out here
so i'm not sure if there is any way of
doing that actually
uh doesn't seem like you can do it with
redstone for sure though because
that was a long delay and it still
didn't work
uh i gotta get some boots man i don't
have my feather fallen anymore they
broke
and i keep killing myself because i'm
used i'm so used to doing things like i
was just running around and i jumped
down here it's like
oh yeah i can't make that fall without
my boots on
and killed myself killed myself a bunch
of times since i've lost them
oh i figured it out guys i know how to
do it and i got it set up
this messy massive wiring
does exactly what i want it to do so
i'll just run you through this
so we still let's get this back in
we still have it working the way it did
before we have the water in there
if we want to clear the portal press
that
as many times as we want
there we go i guess there's a little bit
of a delay before you can hit the button
again
not that you would ever need to this one
lights it
that one clears it now this is the new
option the third option is this piece of
redstone
ore actually let's wait before we put
that in
so if i right click it
enables the portal then when that
redstone or
stops glowing like that it triggers this
but flop or whatever and that makes the
water shoot out and disables the portal
the cool thing about this one there it
goes
cool thing about this one is since it's
um
changing the block type or
whatever block value or whatever uh
a redstone signal a redstone signal is
not occurring so
it doesn't doesn't shut itself off
here i'll show you i can actually use it
and this portal will remain even after i
go into the nether
so i have the option to come back
through that portal before it's disabled
i hope yep and then
after well there you go perfect
so once i if i come through a different
portal and
come back into this area it'll do that
or if i come through the same portal
this one here it'll do that too so
the wiring is a mess and it could
probably be made a little bit more
efficient
but you got a
bud flop over here next to the redstone
or block that there's a
two two redstone torches depending on
where this block is
it powers the stuff so if it's there it
goes through here
it goes to this monostable circuit that
is set at four
um and then to the dispenser it sends
two pulses
one that's three ticks long that comes
three ticks later
and same thing with this side
there's another monostable circuit here
we really only need one but i have two
just because they're spaced out so far
i figured it'd be easier and
yeah so i'm sure you could copy it from
seeing that or mostly so i'm going to
put this
like this it's not super pretty or
anything but does what i wanted to do
all right moving on so there's been some
changes
with emerald city um
i'll take you through them real quick a
lot of people did not like my houses
i was a bit shocked because i thought
they looked pretty good but
no people did not like them
at all mostly because of the sandstone
so i have tweaked them a little bit
they're still
still the same shape and everything but
i have gotten rid of the sandstone
and i i didn't think i was going to like
them as much after i did that
but i do like these more now
and hopefully other people like them a
bit more too
and i don't think i'm going to change a
b on this even if people don't like it
just because i think this looks good
and we still have our creeper face um
now we still i'm still playing with the
floor in here though
somebody suggested i try mossy
cobblestone so that's
what's going on here
but yeah a lot of the trouble is because
it's swamp grass and there's nothing i
can do about that either
i don't either get rid of the grass
completely
this does look kind of cool i don't know
i don't know what i'm doing anymore
uh
but we'll figure something out i'm sure
i did kind of want to put
trees in that in here which is why i'm
pushing the grass so much if we get rid
of the grass i don't think we can have
trees and
and bushes and flowers or anything
even i'm not sure if they would work as
even with the grass but
i would like to try that
uh so we're over here now at the ice
tray
oh i was juking them uh
version 2.0 has begun i've ripped the
old one up
and i'm making it bigger changing the
pattern
this is the new pattern like this and
this is also the pattern i plan on using
on the reed farm if i
expand that from now on because i think
it's the most efficient
but yeah the old one was 16 by 16 the
new one's going to be 32
by 32 which is gonna be
i think 10 stacks of ice per harvest so
it's going to be really good um
it's gonna come in handy because i use a
lot of ice it turns out
like a lot of times instead of using
water buckets and that i'll just use ice
and it's really handy so
i'll i'll definitely be making use of it
and this is how i'm doing the wiring i'm
not sure if it's the best way
uh but it's definitely the easiest for
me to
do it because it's an easy repeatable
pattern
um just just show you so i would have
when this is all done i'll have one wire
going uh horizontally
which will connect to all these these
threads and it will
do this goes goes all the way down like
that
so pretty simple pattern
uh so i'm just about done laying my pad
here i ran out of blocks
gotta get some more but i just wanna
give you a feel for the actual size of
this thing
this is like three quarters of it it's
large it's very large
a lot of area so
i should go quick though there's not
really much to building this thing
oh man it always happens like
when i'm doing stuff like this i usually
i'm watching a video you know i'm not
really paying attention
to what i'm doing and always happens
when i'm
just about at level 30 creeper comes up
wrecks your day man
so much stuff
uh but yeah we're making good progress
here
um
making good progress and gonna put the
pistons in now
just gotta go all the way along
do that it's gonna be
i think three or four stacks oops
and then cover that with snow
amazing montage begin
excellent
incredible
amazing
terrific
bye
[Music]
wonderful
magnificent
yes so it is done i think it's all done
this is going to be our first
test see if it actually works
uh this controls that that makes it so
the water freezes quicker because
otherwise it freezes on the outside only
and slowly freezes inward this way
since there's a block next to every
single water block it will freeze very
quickly
and this does the double pulse so here
we go first test
let's hope it works
it's looking good looking very good oh
look at all that water
yeah i think it made it all the way
and they still have water so it picked
up the water again it's good
double pulsed and i think
let's give this a go
oh couple ice blocks went up because we
did not
do use that quick but look how quick
it's freezing stuff in the middle
ah this is going to come in handy this
is great
awesome magnificent
terrific fantastic incredible okay i'm
gonna stop
this is my first ice harvest with this
new
ice tray uh froze over very quickly i'm
happy with it
i'm going to try i've never tried this
before but i have
a silk touch shovel um with efficiency
on i'm not sure if the efficiency works
or
if you can even pick up ice with it i
think you can pick up the ice
i'm just not sure if i'm guessing the
efficiency will work too but we'll see
we'll see what happens here
i i don't really want to use these too
often because if i
if i hit the snow it's gone the shovel
will just destroy it
okay it picks up the ice and it is quick
okay it's not the ideal tool for this
though because
like i said if i hit the snow i'm gonna
have to do repairs
be very careful but i only have i think
one silk touch pick left
and i may have a few shovels
but i would like to get some new picks
for sure
sometime soon
and in total from one harvest we got one
two three four five six seven eight
nine 10 11 12 stacks just about 13
and i added it up and it is 823 ice
blocks
so pretty good won't have to come here
too often to do this
oh no
no what happened why didn't it pick up
the water
ah just this side too that's strange
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen hmm
not sure why i did that
must have been just after the repeater
yeah
something's wrong with it
well i'll look into fixing that i'm not
sure what happened there
okay let's try it again real quick here
before the ice freezes
oh i forgot the bucket it's like what
what's going on um i also seem to have a
lot of budgets now i'm not exactly sure
why
it's all very confusing
see if any of these shout outs there's
ice in front of the dispensers
uh instead of placing the water
it's gonna shoot the bucket out so you
gotta be really careful
okay i think it's fixed what i did is i
just increased the delay
before the second pulse occurs i had 11
ticks before now i have it at 12.
i think that was the issue although it
did
it did work the first time so it's
strange it went the second time but that
is
minecraft for you
all right guys so i'm going to do some
enchanting now this is
this is actually my first time back into
the end here
for a long long time
um i haven't been here since 1.3 came
out and
even before that it's been a long time
i'm gonna try get some boots and
maybe do a few picks what is this
fortune
oh nope
nope oh i do have another pair okay cool
uh but i'm gonna do i'm gonna try to get
a couple pairs anyway
oh and there was diamonds okay
sweet so yeah one 1.3
um i'm noticing the background looks
different in the end it's really purple
now before it was like a
fuzzy darkish green i would say
i think they changed the background
texture
it's first thing i've noticed anyway
in 1.4 it sounds like there's going to
be some big changes with
the way mob systems are going to work
like the xp um oh
yeah two hits could kill me
i better be careful but yeah like the
longer you stay
next to a spawner the less xp you're
gonna get from the mobs
until you leave it and then it will
start uh producing mobs with more xp
again
and uh it seems like
this enderman farm's gonna still work
even with that change but like my blaze
farm
probably won't work anymore um
for xp anyway you still get blaze rods
in that if that's what you're going for
but yeah blaze farms um
skeleton farms zombie farms thief spider
farms anything with mob spawners
is going to be affected it sounds like
um it does seem like there's gonna be
like even with the changes though from
what i've heard it seems like you will
be able to exploit it still
um which is the way it always seems to
go we always find a new way of doing it
taking advantage of the system
the way it's implemented or at least
right now from what i've heard
it will reduce xp
you get from the mobs by one every
so many seconds i think it's like 25 or
30 or something
um i think now i'm just going by
guessing here i haven't actually tried
this
or tried any of the snapshots yet but i
think
you could set yourself up on a minecart
or something that moved out of range for
the spawners
at the precise time where it attempts to
decrease xp by one and then move
yourself back
i think i don't know but that might be
an exploit because it's not a constant
everything in minecraft well not
everything but a lot of things in
minecraft are
based on whole numbers so it's not like
it's every tickets counting down
like a decimal number it's it goes down
by one and it's
after so many seconds it's not like one
every
twentieth of a second or something so
yeah we'll see what happens with that
but i'm going to
oh i went over not paying attention i'm
going to do some enchanting
i might as well do a pick first since i
have 32
right supposed to do this first oh
i gotta get some armor on this is
dangerous
uh let's do a diamond pick here
oh wow
oh that's okay
um hmm didn't know i had this stuff here
oh all right maybe i don't really need
to do a whole lot of enchanting
like i thought
that's cool
okay
diamond pick what shall we get
another one awesome that's great
oh eat uh yes i'm going to try to get
like maybe two pairs three pairs of
feather falling four boots
and
i'll get back to grinding xp here
man yeah one thing i am also noticing
since 1.3 came out is the mobs are a lot
more glitchy and they can get you
in places they're not supposed to be
able to
that's what happened there um that was
under
was under the roof but they i guess
somehow were able to reach me yep
oh and of course the one thing that goes
over the edge is the feather falling
four boots i had on
so yep gotta get another one
all right here we go
no here we go again we're gonna do three
pairs three more pairs
ah yes it's about uh
two and three chance just about next up
we have same thing that's good that's
good news
hey now this guy
this guy is really freaking me out he's
mad at me
but he's not attacking me
why
i don't want to find out
okay we got enough for another pair
there's also another
guy mad at me i think running around
somewhere
which has me a bit nervous but we are
okay
um yeah i'm gonna have to make this
place safer now because i am taking hits
every so often
all right guys well we got i think two
pairs anyway
which should keep me going for a while
all right cool
all right guys that's all we're going to
do for today i got one comment i've
picked out
to read possibly build a large chamber
beneath the city
filled with doors question i should have
should have heard that with an
inflection they would be out of sight
but would still count as the door counts
still
allowing for more villagers to be
spawned without the nuisance of
unsightly doors
i i think that's what i'm going to do
i'm going to have a few doors
underground
just to get the villager count up higher
but i do not want to do
infinite villager breeders because i
don't really like those
um but yeah it'd be cool to have some
underground and if i do the fountain
idea
i'll make them come up during the day
through the fountain
yeah cool all right guys thank you for
watching and i will see you
next time hahaha