[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys to another episode of our let's
play series
check this out i saw something super
cool over here
we have a squid stuck in a one by one
thing of water here
i've never seen that happen over here
before so i thought that was kind of
cool we're gonna have a brand new friend
hopefully he'll stick with us for a
while call him katsudu
whenever i get a pet squid though they
always die i don't know how they do it
he's gonna find a way to suffocate
though i'm sure
but we'll deepen as long as we can here
so guys uh today to begin with i
have a brand new redstone concept to
show you we're gonna
look into how we can store memory in
minecraft so
currently in the game there's probably
we're going the wrong way
there's probably two main methods of
doing it
uh you got piston tapes i'm sure a lot
of you know what piston tapes are
it's readable memory it's it's
kind of big it's bulky you can't really
change the length of it it's kind of a
fixed state memory
and you can't really write to it then we
have
like t flip flops and we can use
redstone to store memory but
that becomes very big very bulky and
very slow
so today i was trying to think of how
can we
finish up this simon game because i ran
into a problem
where it's uh it's gonna be too slow
um the the idea i had
became very big and bulky and uh
there was no way to do a turn in less
than like 20 seconds so that was a
pretty big snag to the project here so i
was thinking about ideas of how to store
memory
uh first let's look into maybe some of
the issues
of storing memory so let's say for
example
an arrow is a zero stone block is a one
in in memory here right so we can we can
send it through a hopper and detect
you know if it's an arrow or a stone
block and then cause different things to
happen
but then when we want to recollect all
this stuff together here what happens is
it stacks in the chest right
so we lose all that positional
importance
information of like where all the blocks
were and now next time we
we read through this it's gonna be eight
arrows and ten stone blocks not
not the order we had before so that kind
of sucks
so another idea here is to maybe use
items that don't stack such as swords
so we put a sword in here and makes a
signal length of three
we can detect the difference between an
item that doesn't stack
and one that does very easily so that
only goes the distance of one it doesn't
turn the light on
while the sword does so we can detect
the difference between the two without
using item filters that's kind of cool
but likewise same problem happens here
because we're using an item that stacks
the stone blocks
check out what happens
now it works the first time
[Music]
but because item stacks it messes up all
the positional information which is
what's really key here
and next time we want to read through
this it's going to be all messed up so
that's no good
the other problem is we can't really
detect a difference between
items that don't stack we can't run
these through an item and filter and
figure out oh that's a diamond sword
and this is a diamond axe there's no
difference
we can detect between these two they
both emit a signal of three
and we can't check what the item
actually is so that's that's a big issue
as well
yeah so i was trying to solve this
problem today guys because if we could
get this sort of memory to work
it's going to be a pretty big deal it'll
be a huge improvement to like redstoning
uh in minecraft we'll we'll be able to
do more complicated stuff
um and it turns out it actually is
possible so there's one item in the game
in minecraft that doesn't stack it's one
item per stack
that we can manipulate to figure out
what it is if it's a one or a zero
and that is the water bucket or or live
about it could work as well but i think
water budgets a little easier to pull
off in
in survival here so what we want to try
to do here is make a
a water bucket reader machine
i guess is what what it would be called
i have an idea of how to do it
uh might take a little bit of a figuring
out i want to see how fast we can get it
to work as well if possible
so in minecraft you can place
water buckets using dispensers that's
pretty key
to this so if we put that in here and we
power it
we got water and then we can pick it up
again afterwards too which is nice
uh if that wasn't um
a water bucket let's say it was a sword
another item that doesn't stack instead
of like placing the water
it'll shoot the item out so we can we
can
use those two differences to figure out
what item is actually in there fairly
easily
so what i'm thinking we do we set up an
observer block
um like over here
wait which way do we face it that way
yeah so if it places water it'll trick
the
it'll uh trigger the observer block if
it's a sword that shoots out it's not
going to do anything
right and then below here
we can have a hopper if it's a sword
it'll go into the hopper and then we can
detect that
if it's a water bucket it's not going to
go into the hopper it's going to trigger
the observer so those are the two
differences
all right so it's uh not done here just
yet but this will show you the key
concept and also the key difficulties or
challenges
with doing this so this is our data
reader
what we'll have is a data stream the
water buckets
and some other non-stackable item like
like a shovel for example
they'll be arranged here we want it to
run through our data reader
and trigger the redstone either this
light will turn on or this one
and then it'll end up in this chest down
here in the exact same order it went in
originally that's that's the goal of all
this right
so here's here's the first challenge
so if we just let this go it's gonna
fill up the dispenser and then this is
gonna shoot it out in a random order and
then it's gonna not end up in the same
order down here so that's a
that's a big no-no we need to handle
this one item at a time
uh if it's a water buckets we it'll do
something like this
so we're gonna eject it and pick it up
right away so that's still
still a water bucket in the system and
you see it triggered this
observer over here that light turned on
if it's a shovel in there
it's going to go into this hopper into
the chest down there
and a comparator can detect that very
easily you notice though we have no way
of sending the water button into this
chest that's that's our first real big
challenge here if we put a
hopper underneath that'll kind of work
but
as soon as that goes in there it's going
down we don't have time to
activate it for the observer to detect
it right so we need to somehow
lock this hopper as that happens and
then as soon as it picks up the water
again
then this unlocks and puts into the
chest
ah yeah so this is a little bit later
guys i've been fine-tuning this
trying to get it perfect working on the
timings of everything and i think it's
about
about good now uh this is basically a
hard drive in minecraft
if you guys aren't understanding exactly
what i'm doing here
so up here we have
eight bits of information or a byte a
one one zero one zero one
zero one what does that mean that means
nothing until we actually make it do
something
uh basically but our reader device is
able to read it
pretty much as fast as possible the
speed of hoppers
2.5 items can flow through a hopper per
second in minecraft
and that's how fast this can read it so
check this out we're going to unlock
this
also pay attention to the ordering
because we want to preserve that
as it goes through the reader
so there we go and down here exact same
order as before all the waters back in
the buckets
which is also important now just because
we can read the information that quickly
with this doesn't mean we would always
want to a lot of times we probably just
want to let one bit
of information through at a time and
that's easy to do as well just do
something like this
you heard the water bucket go through
and that's where it is over there
so for my simon memory game for example
this is this is how i'm going to do it
i'm going to let one of the answers
through
and that's either going to display it on
the screen or it's going to check if my
input
matches red green blue or yellow we need
two bits of information to represent
uh one of the four choices
and this is also the key behind
computing if you didn't know that
so let's say we wanted to do math you
can add numbers together
binary um you can
we can use this for making musical
sequencing
we can use it for making a display for
example let's say we wanted an
8x8 display in minecraft one of these
readers might represent a single pixel
on that screen
and if we had 64 of the readers
we could update the display 2.5 frames
per second
and like totally animate it if we supply
it with the
stream of data
lots of different things you can do you
also store programs using memory
so you could make a programming language
in minecraft lots of crazy things
we might get more into it later but i
just want to show that off for today
and let's go do something else okay
so uh i tell you what we're gonna do i
thought about it for a bit here
we're gonna do something i've been
dreading just
dreading don't wanna do it but we gotta
do it i got called out on it recently
again
on that uh eye candy episode a lot of
people are like etho you gotta finish
this pyramid it looks so
ugly i don't know what to do with it
though
i'll show you what i did before when i
tried to finish it
so over on this side did a lot of
experimenting
nothing really worked and i mixed in a
bunch of spruce wood
made these little arches and things i
got to tell you guys though i really
suck at building in the desert
like i tried to build in a lot of
different styles
i think the deserts or sandstone themed
stuff i have the most trouble with
because i don't know
if there's really i don't know what
blocks to use with it i just can't
figure it out
i like the gates here right but there's
only one type of block here just
sandstone
i don't know how to mix anything in with
it and make it look good
you know a little bit of wood here and
there like spruce wood sure
that's fine but if you have too much of
it like we have on that side of the
pyramid i think it looks really ugly
and i've seen other people's desert
builds and i honestly haven't really
liked
anything i've seen like no desert builds
it's just one of those themes i don't
think looks very good
but we'll try it out here so anything is
better than what we have here this is
just a big flat wall
we got to give it some personality so i
was figuring
i do kind of like the shape of those
gates and what we did there so maybe
we can try to mimic that style we're not
going to mix
really any wood in with this i don't
think we're going to try to give it
contrast using
shadows instead of different textures
like spruce wood
all right so maybe we bring the corner
out and we're going to do this castle
wall store
sort of style because that creates a lot
of shadows i think it looks cool
and maybe we will do a bit of arches
as well
um actually let's let's bring this up
one more block
i want this corner to kind of stand out
a bit more
bring this up one more block like
so all right
and then let's try do an arch here
okay yeah let's check this out so let's
take a step back
looks pretty plain ah man
okay how about how about we do a little
bit more with this corner let's bring it
out one more block
and maybe make it a bit wider like uh
five blocks five blocks one block out
try that out aha yes yes yes
so that's better right i think that's
better uh kind of a key concept of why
shaders look so good is it creates a lot
of different
shades shaders shades on a block right
and shadows likewise by building out
like this by bringing this forward one
block it creates a shadow over there
which adds contrast to the build and
same with the arch over top there now we
have
shadows on the wall there and it just by
having those variations it makes build
a lot better than a flat wall like we
had here originally
is is my concept anyway so i
realize this is about the same shape as
one of those corner things
over there actually so let's duplicate
oh we fall down again
let's duplicate what we did there so i
think it's these two blocks
are stairs i'm gonna fall again i can
feel it
turn these into stairs
nope not that way and that way we have
uh sort of
a running theme throughout this build as
well because it's kind of copying what
we did there
okay and then i think it's at this level
we had a stair that going this way
and we'll break this off this gives it
way more personality that way
and there so i think that'll look pretty
good
um we might remove blocks here as well
kind of like we have
over there okay
and then let's maybe try
just so it's not like an arch and then
an arch and an arch let's
let's break it up we'll do something
like this
a little short little piece and then
another arch over here
and in between here we might put some
birchwood
right over here right nope wrong way
okay okay you gotta be careful when
you're building not to have
too much of a repeating pattern you want
to break it up a little bit
that way it stays interesting and
finish up the top here and then we'll
check it out
okay and there we go let's go take a
look
and we're going to try to do this on
each of the layers
okay that's kind of cool we got to get
rid of the blocks over there though i
think that's messing up the look a
little bit
also i feel like we need something up at
the top there it's pretty plain still
how about if we replace these with
stairs
do something like that maybe that'll be
cool
or maybe we need to bring a line forward
like you know what i mean like run some
blocks like over top
here and run a line
we'll try this first okay
oh i'm seeing a lot of faces now looks
like they're angry
all right so check it out guys i did uh
one layer here one side of the pyramid
one layer
it's got a lot left to do but i think
that's probably what we'll run with i
think that's fine i'm okay with that
uh it's still pretty much just sandstone
up there right i got a little bit of
birchwood
fences mixed in too but it's pretty much
the sandstone but
by bringing it forward and creating
arches and stuff it creates all kinds of
contrast
and the wall looks pretty crazy now
maybe a bit too crazy even
but i think i'm okay with that so i did
not like the eyes that were being made
so i
i moved those little little pivots a bit
and i actually tried to make a pattern
with them so it goes up like a wave
uh sort of thing i did the same thing on
these uh gates
uh i think that's a key concept don't
just do random try to create
patterns for the eyes to pick up on like
you see up there i got like an
arching pattern goes up and around same
with over there go
it goes up and around it's not just like
random chiseled blocks all over the
place
so now we oh i'm stuck in the reeds so
now we have a bit of a pattern on
on the wall there too which i think is a
good idea
a lot of times when people do uh
these uh sand builds sandstone builds
they mix in buttons maybe we'll try that
too i don't know if
we'll roll with that but just to try it
but usually they put them at the top
there
the adobe look
no not there
um
might be better like oh over here
oh now i'm breaking everything darn it
now
okay at the very least here we should
also mix in some smooth stone and some
chiseled
block so we haven't done that yet so
probably
at the bottom here we i want some
chiseleds and then smooth and chiseled
we'll do that pattern i think that'll
make it look quite a bit better
mining mining mining money mining mining
binding mining sandstone sandstone
building building building building
this place miss place shopping shopping
shopping shopping chopping chopping
chopping chopping tree
tree so swimming swimming swimming
swimming swimming swimming swimming
swimming
[Music]
all right guys so here we go that is one
side of the pyramid uh
possibly possibly all done
i want to wait and get you guys feedback
before i do the other three sides here
um overall i'm pretty happy with this
but i feel like it does need some
changes still right
there's a i know there's something not
quite right about it still
for one thing i think it needs a top
right something that stands out that's
not the same repeating pattern something
that's different
kind of like a highlight i also feel
like maybe we have too many of these
indents when you see them all
like all the all the sides done here all
the layers
there's a lot of them it looks like
there's at least 30
or so of them and it's kind of chaotic
maybe a bit too much
but i'll see what you guys say about
that as well maybe we need to remove a
few of them though
or or change it uh possibly we need to
break up the pattern a bit more too
like have a line that runs down the
middle perhaps that
kind of sticks out or put more of these
towers
in it or maybe windows of some sort i'm
not sure exactly
i want to see what you guys thoughts are
on that
um something i'm going to do here though
i want to make it look like sand is
blown up alongside the building here and
settled
so it's kind of uh
kind of going up on the side here right
um we'll do that
also we should get rid of all
all the grass around the building here
it's kind of taking away from it
and something we're not really gonna see
too often but if we're ever flying we
might catch a glimpse of it
uh like all the building we did over
there you see how there's birch
wood at the top of the the wall there
and on top of those gates there's
birchwood
we should replace the sandstone here
with birchwood as well
i think that'll help give it a bit more
color
a bit more texture and also this is
where we're going to hide the lighting i
think so if we want to light up the
the pyramid here put it in the floor and
you won't be able to see it from down
below
so i think that's a good spot for it one
other idea
possibly mix in some birch leaves
i don't know like if we have a vines of
this running down it'll help break up
the look of the whole thing
is there any other block we can do that
with
like leaves are kind of the the one and
only block i know
that does this right
kind of like that vines
oh that's very straight there but you
get the idea
it looks pretty bad i think
maybe we won't do that but uh
yeah i thought i'd tried it anyways oh i
have an idea
let's try something here i just realized
melon blocks kind of look like
they could be cactuses right cacti
we need we need some more decorations in
our sandy city here so maybe cacti are
the way to go
but just normal cactus plants don't look
very good i find
because uh they can't branch out like
this right that's that's the main issue
with them
let's go ahead and try uh make a
standard cactus so maybe it goes up like
that
actually we should make this bigger
right
let's make it go up one more block
like so and then
where should we do it let's do it here
that'll come out there and then you want
to go one block
lower and then this goes up
and then we will put maybe a flower pot
on top to look like a flower
you know how they get the pink flowers
it needs a sombrero too on top of here
maybe
okay well let's let's try this out for
right now
does that look like a cactus question
i think you could pull it off it kind of
looks a little bit goofy with too
too long arms like that though maybe
this should be smaller no that looks bad
that looks bad hmm
nope yeah maybe it was right the first
time i'm not sure
now it still doesn't look quite right
anyways
there's an idea i think that'll work
actually it's a pretty good texture for
cactus i think
all right another thing i was thinking
of maybe we can try
put some flower pots on the on the walls
here to decorate i don't know if you'd
be able to see it from down below
but we have like these archways right i
feel like we should put something
in them or possibly we do like a
cauldron
plant so like you do that and then you
put uh
maybe spruce wood would be better oh it
kind of connects to the walls of that
sucks
could put a stair there though
no that's not gonna work not enough
space there it would have to be brought
out
one like over here
do that and then you probably want at
least two leaves
that's not gonna look very good i don't
think probably can't see this stuff from
that
down below yeah it just looks like two
leaf blocks
can't see the flower pots at all down
here
what do you guys think should the cactus
have a sombrero or a flower on the top
i thought i'd try the sombrero kind of
actually
kind of actually works i think i don't
know
i put some wooden buttons on for the the
spikes as well
anyways let's wrap up the episode here
for today we are gonna read the comments
which says hey ezo you should revive the
stronghold base and if not
then do you think you could at least
make it look okay
uh maybe we'll head over there just real
quick here
okay so we're over here at the
stronghold base now i don't go here too
often so some of you might
have never seen this even this is a very
old part of our world
which was going to be like my main base
that was the plan for a long time but
then it just never really worked out
and i think i got distracted with stuff
i'm not sure there's not a lot here
like we started building a storage room
system here
obviously this is way outdated i would
never finish that
so probably most of stuff on the sides
would get torn out and redone
um there's a silverfish farm here which
is actually a pretty cool thing i think
and
what else this is where our portal to
the end is
um believe it or not i actually thought
this looked good
back in the day i thought this was a
very good build now when i see it it
makes my eyes bleed the only thing
the only real good quality of this is uh
these tiles on the walls
i think that's a cool cool little trick
i noticed a lot of people use this too
in their builds um
but beyond that most of the space is
pretty bad
up above though there's something
important there's the mob system
uh the plan was to make a bomb factory
where you make a skeleton
shoot a creeper and then when you
combine the skeleton with the creeper
they blow up
and i was going to try to make a tree
farm automated tree farm using that we
still
possibly might do that i would like to
the big problem i had a lot with this
build
was uh controlling the mob ai
it was very difficult to make a creeper
sorter using
the kitty cats it wasn't very reliable i
would build it it would work in creative
and then when i tried out here it
wouldn't work
but now they've changed it creepers are
actually smaller than zombies and
skeletons so you can separate them very
easily now
so we might be able to get this working
one day
also i think the snowman got loose
i don't know how that happened
hey anyways hope you guys enjoyed
today's episode we might
we might eventually finish building this
base or at least the bomb factory
but yeah hope you enjoyed it thanks for
watching guys until next time
take care bye