hey everyone this is etho welcome back
guys how are you doing today he just
fell down right as I started whoo I said
this last time but you know I haven't
really had many creeper explosions in
this place and I'm really worried if one
does happen I might not be able to
repair it like it originally was but it
didn't happen today so I'm happy just
got back from another TV run I really
liked you even I do it quite often
actually and once again I got another
nametag bunch of iron which we will use
today I think I'm gonna be making
something to start off with here and I'm
not I'm not gonna cheap out on my hair
I'll let you just what that means but
yeah it just got back from shaving I'm
going to show you what we're up to
pretty quick here just want to drop this
stuff off first five more M rows 28
redstone very nice drop off the nametag
drop that on Rails what else don't we
need oh I got the gold okay I am level
32 actually let's do an enchant to start
off with two before we get into it I'm
going to do a sword at yes good I really
need some looting swords and we'll get
this iron smelting this hardened clay
I've been gathering hardened clay or
clay like a crazy guy here we're gonna
be using this today as well for our
starting build we're gonna need a lot of
it
alright let's go and chant this sword
and then we'll head out come on looting
diluting looting very good response on
last episode guys thank you very much
for that
ah yes looting three everything else
kind of junk on it but we got looting
three and that's all that matters
alright so let's put this away
we're gonna need order you're gonna need
where any a bunch of roses need some
bone meal to start off with yeah we'll
just we'll just take that you know with
and we'll probably need a lot more clay
we're gonna get some more oh there's
iron so what are we up to guys what are
we up to well we have this thing called
the mine crack reddit's where people
like the posts like fan art and all
kinds of stuff
and there's this particular fan art that
caught my attention there's been this
like long long kind of running joke with
the Minecraft guys how they like to use
my name as a verb like like etho it it's
been a third or last UHC the not last
one but you wait to see number nine
I was with Kurt's jam and beatable oh
and Kurt Kurt said you've been a soda
and I said it would be so cool somebody
drew like me shaking my head and shaking
my fingers like with the caption you've
been etho and somebody well a few people
did actually but there was one that
really caught my eye that I really liked
and that's what we're gonna try build
today I saved it to my computer just
because it was it gives me a chuckle
every time I see it and I thought I'd
save it to my computer and then if I
ever want to laughs I can look at it I
kind of forgot about it then like the
other day I saw someone in my channel
comments
was actually using that that picture
it's actually an animated gif for their
channel icon so I saw it next to their
comments and it reminded me of that and
it gave me a laugh in it
I started looking at is like you know I
bet you I could build that in this game
and it would look pretty cool so that's
what we're gonna try to do so this I'm
gonna show it to you now this animated
gif was made by mad monkey the dreamer
mad monkey the dream and this is what it
looks like oh man it's so awesome sink
cracks me up every time I see it I got
so much sass in this animation it's like
nuh you're wrong you've been easy
alright so that's what we're trying to
build guys and we're not just doing like
a flat 2d image of it I want to do like
a 3d sculpture of it so I got to build
myself and I thought it would look
really really cool if I put it on a side
of a mountain so we're this spot here
we're gonna try like put the red circle
around the mountain here and then my guy
coming out of the mountain like sticking
out of it I think it's gonna look really
cool I don't know how tough it's gonna
be to do I'm gonna use set blings a 3d
sculpture filter for mcedit to to get
get my character you know to make him
his filter doesn't work with the new
clay blocks and stuff though like it
doesn't use use them so I'm not gonna
look too too similar to what I look like
here really but then I'm just gonna
change
most of the blocks over with clay and
just use that as a reference I want to
use it for my hair because my hair is
really complicated so we got to flatten
out this mountain a little
I'll probably get rid of this tree yard
of the tree and move this back a bit to
let me take this whole mountain back a
bit flatten it out and I was trying to
guess that the dimensions of stuff here
and I think we're gonna do like a 24
diameter circle yeah so maybe maybe I'll
work on this for a little bit
tried to get it nice and flat and then
we will start working on the circle or
something together and see how it goes
this poor sheet man he's been falling
for so long like for months and months
in my world here I've noticed this guy
he's keeps falling over and over I'm
tempted to help him out but at the same
time I just want to leave him because I
think he'll be there forever
and it's kind of cool this is our our
hunk of marble here this is what we're
gonna build our sculpture out of nice
and flat surface to work off of it's
really smooth at the moment but we're
gonna we're gonna it's not gonna look
like this at the end of it because the
circle this is 26 blocks across and I
think like 28 up the circle we're making
has a diameter of 24 so it goes pretty
much to the edge and the only place
that's gonna be really flat afterwards
is in the corners a little bit
and we can smooth that out we can put
some land there it'll look pretty good
we'll plant trees and maybe make some
fake waterfalls on the sides I think
it's gonna be good
so let's get to actually building a
thing here I brought a bunch of colored
clay blocks with me we're gonna we're
gonna use I think red for the circle and
since it's 24 and that's about 28 I got
to start it 2 or 3 blocks off the ground
I think I'm gonna go 3 and I might have
to add
some more to the top there we'll see how
this looks so I think gonna go eight
blocks at the bottom here I think that
that'll be the start of it and actually
you know what I just kind of want to see
what these look like with my character I
couldn't decide between blue clay and
cyan and I think we're gonna use this
for my shirts okay I think it's the
closest match my my shirt and my mask
and headband and everything it's like
it's it's navy blue right the cyan the
one I'm buy right now it's it's not
quite blue enough but this one next to
it is like too blue there's no
in-between so I have to decide between
the two I think I'm gonna go with the
cyan just because ninjas they're usually
like wearing dark clothing and stuff and
I would rather be gray than really
bright blue I think so we'll go with
that
and again there's not really quite a
match for this shirt of mine but I think
we'll go with lime for the most of it
and then those like the the e in the
backwards II that you see will probably
be the dark green and I think the skin
did I bring anything for the skin I
think we're gonna use white I think this
is like the ideal thing to use for skin
with people like that's almost exact
match in color that's pretty good okay
so we got that our blocks figured out
let's get to it here I looked at a
circle generator before I started we
gotta go to threes and then a couple I
think three twos like that and then go
back up two threes a couple more of
those Oh
is this smaller than I thought it was
there should be a one block gap from
this wall here I thought because it goes
out one more three four five six seven
oh oh I wonder if I measured wrong
what's going on here
it looks like if I do that the circles
gonna be like way up in the air too
I'm gonna double-check my circle I might
have got this wrong okay so what the
problem was this red ring the circle I
wanted to make was actually 26 blocks
diameter the one I was looking at the 24
it does not have as nice of it doesn't
round as nicely so we're gonna stick
with this I think now what we got to do
it starts hollowing out some of this
cliff face because the idea is I'm gonna
be in behind the ring and then sort of
come out like and be leaning forward
from the ring so kind of like this like
when I'm holding shift pointing let's do
my let's do my fist out ah something
like that
so TNT time okay I set it up in a way we
can have some fun here so let's let's
see how bad my name is higher whoa not
that high Ariel I'm so glad you see
Aeros rendering in the distance now Oh
get them all quickly there we go there
we go
and two more down here perfect and I did
it without blowing up the clay that's I
was worried about that okay so I'm gonna
polish that up and we'll start building
me actually you know what I should do -
ah up there I I did it's two blocks
missing now what we should do is maybe
do like a semicircle of glowstone in the
background because in the image it it
kind of looks like it's glowing in the
back we might try to do that later let's
do that let's do my guy first though
awesome I got five blocks clear doubts
in depth now it should be enough space
to start building so let's get to it
let's make me oh boy I've never actually
made my guy in this game before so and
yes I am Kakashi for those of you that
haven't clued in yet I'm gonna start at
my waist like where the ends of my where
my arm or my hands end at there so I
think we're going to go two pixels two
blocks for the waist and I am a very
very slimming size eight eight eight box
wide around my waist and my arms are
chunky four blocks so I got some muscles
on me I tell you
let's I'm gonna build it I think one
block away from this ring just a little
bit of a buffer and
let's get with the cyan to start off
with here so eight blocks should end
right where this ring bottom ends
because that's eight blocks as well and
we'll go here I'm just gonna do the
front I think on camera here or at least
some of the fronts and then I'll do the
sides in the back on my own so I think
it's just solid blue yeah I like to I
can just use myself as a reference as I
build this then I guess we should do the
arm on the side too as we go that would
probably make this easier so I'm gonna
have my right arm sticking out so I have
to put the arm on this side
and we'll make that match up with the
bottom of our waist so over here I guess
and I have got my wrist bands I'm gonna
put that over here and my vest
so my vest looks like it's mostly green
all that all the way across except I'm
gonna use clay for the zipper let's see
so let's do it like which side is it on
zippers on the left mostly so I'm
looking this way that would be right
there and like that okay this is stuff I
gotta like flip the image so many times
in my head and then there's a dark spot
dark pixels in the corners oh wait a
minute can't cover over that clay block
in the way I can't see yeah as if er
goes straight up back up
this is stuff all right oh you know what
I did I went over my arm and my arm is
only two blocks wide for some reason not
for like it's supposed to be so I'm
feeling pretty badly here already oh man
let's fix this my arm let's make let's
make it pink now I'll have to move this
over now make that goal of at least two
so what was it was dark dark in the
corners right this will have to be moved
that will go here then I think let's
just check this alright
oh but you know what I'm not doing I'm
not making them lean in okay ah this is
still tough I want I think every three
blocks we go vertically we're gonna lean
in one block so we'll basically start
bleeding here yeah okay and same with
the arm that's and I'll I'll take out
this this line later let's keep going
here so then it looks like we got light
on the two sides dark for two blocks so
lights over here lights two blocks dark
and then zipper and then light again
actually it's light all the way up
pretty much but maybe let's do the sides
first oh yeah that is looking good
that's pretty accurate I would say let's
get our slant going here yeah it's that
it's pretty similar I would say
I'm gonna work on my right arm now and I
might do my head off camera here because
it's pretty complicated and it will be
tough to record lots lots of detail to
my hair and stuff so I'll be right back
so this is what I've been using as my
main guide throughout this build
especially for the head because the
heads the complicated part but I got my
chiseled good looks like nice nice
sandstone face there I have look how
look how firm my my pecs in my abs are
they're nice stone brick and we have
like birch plank arms and yeah so it
doesn't look quite right that's why I
wanted to do it with the clay box and
this is the outcome yep there we have it
I am one snazzy-looking guy I tell ya so
that turned out pretty good a lot more
lifelike and a lot more true to my
actual guide these these clay blocks are
a huge help they introduce colors that
we didn't have before and it makes a big
difference and I would say that is very
very close you even though they are
somewhat limited like I can't get exact
colors it definitely looks pretty close
that's pretty cool we'll take a couple
looks around here in just a sec I'm
gonna try one last thing before I'm I'm
kind of done with this build of course I
got to smooth out the mountains and
stuff still but I'll probably do that
another day but I want to try put
glowstone in the back and I've been
trying to decide between doing like a
semicircle behind my guy you know or
trying to do a flat wall of glowstone
and I think what we're gonna do is a
flat wall of glowstone for a couple
reasons the semicircle is better because
it it's cheaper
like I don't think you'll take as much
clothes stone do you do it that way but
Oh like it's better in that sense but
overall the flat walls better because I
think the semicircles gonna create a lot
of shadows and stuff which will instead
of looking like a just a flat glowing
background it's gonna really stick out
if it's a semicircle so we don't want
that but I'm gonna make up backup just
in case it looks really bad we can
revert before we do the glowstone but
I'll try it out and see what it looks
like here all right well this is what it
looks like at night there's no torches
around or anything so it is kind of dark
still even with the glowstone but it
does help quite a bit
I let's get a day shot though here I
just pull hotter in the middle of the
water to get a better perspective of
things here so let me know what you guys
think of the glowstone is it worth it I
use six and a half stacks on this and
I'm not quite done it ideally I think it
looks better during the day and a lot
closer to the original fan art too so I
I think it's pretty good but let me know
what you guys think ideally what I would
like to do is you see the sides there I
haven't changed over to glowstone that
would be nice to do to buy you six and a
half stacks on the glowstone of
glowstone on the back there my hair is
like 63 blocks of iron it's just about a
stack and there is so much clay in this
thing this was a very expensive build
altogether and I didn't do behind here
either because I ran out not that you
can really see it this is what it looks
like on the inside this is my beautiful
hair my very expensive hair most of the
iron blocks are on the top sadly so the
most expensive parts the part you're
least likely to see
but it's okay I'm worth it give you guys
a tour inside and you see were wandering
here I should put some torches and I
have a feeling I'm not gonna be able to
leave this head empty I'm gonna want to
put something here just so people can't
see I have an empty head this is my arm
very nice it's very nice yeah so weird
walking through you the size of this
thing is insane all right where did we
come in what's over here yeah let's get
on his arm it's my eye and my other eye
nice cold block this is quartz oh yeah
all right yeah I'm holding myself it's
amazing
let's get a few distance shots here I
think what really makes us look cool is
the 3d effect and we can't really get a
good sense of it up close like this so
he I guess let's go from the side here
he's sticking out like three his head is
like three blocks outside of the red
ring and his arm is way out there so it
is pretty 3d and like even little
details like the math sticks out
unblocked and the hair there's quite a
bit of 3d effect to it that mountain
over there it's kinda in the way isn't
it I wonder if I should do something
about that to you it looks good though I
think it looks really good
you've been he thought now whenever I
see it it's gonna make me smile remind
me of the fan art yeah there's a good
view over here
you've been echoed during the day I
definitely like the glowstone more
though I think oh this is a good shot
right here well cool I will try to work
on this more I like do some work on the
mountain and stuff make that look nicer
but overall and maybe get some glowstone
if if people like it
try finish that off but overall I would
say that is a success so pretty cool
well guys I'm afraid it's that time
again time to end episode 2 wrap it up
so here is the comment I picked for
today says ESO do you have any pets if
so what kind of animals and what are
their names I do not have any pets I
haven't had a pet and I in like 10 to 15
years I would say it's been by now
growing up I did have all the dog lovers
I know you hate me I had a lot of cats
growing up like outdoor cats and they
were they were pretty cool I liked them
they kept themselves like you didn't
they didn't need a time a ton of
attention you know I usually just go
check on them once a day or so whenever
you felt like it feed them they looked
after themselves and it's always good
you could pet them they loved it when
you pet them or give them attention and
had a couple really cool ones too like
there was this one when can I had
snuggles she like she was she had
kittens and stuff she was a mother and
she was crazy she would like go in the
water like choose to go in the water
herself like
and like hunt ducks in the water catch
him and then like bring him back for her
for her kittens like just crazy cat
always look both ways before crossing
the road and just really really smart
and brave and very friendly to people
you know she would like to see ever had
kittens you could go see him and she
would just love to show show you her
kittens and it's pretty cool so that was
probably my favorite cat growing up now
growing up I also had cousins and they
had like they had so many pets like
every time I visited them like usually
once a month they would have a new pet
and it was always some crazy like pretty
exotic pets even like they had they had
snakes they had hedgehogs and like of
course they had fish and and the usual
stuff too but their house stinks so bad
I I think that's what threw me off
having pets ever again it's just like no
way do I want that in the house it's not
healthy and it's just really really
nasty to live with that stink all the
time and they were getting sick all the
time I think it's because of the pets
this is my open you know no expert
anyway that's it for today guys thanks
for watching I have a great date
you