hello everybody this is etho and welcome
to another episode of Minecraft here in
our wonderful world looks so nice I got
a riddle for you guys at a challenge if
you guys think you know minecraft very
well I think you'll like this one
so I have a redstone torch here and a
light but this is no ordinary redstone
torch this is a something special I made
I want you to try figure it out so I'll
demonstrate it to you imagine a line
running like from here down and when we
cross that line
stuff happens okay so this is a
proximity sensor whenever we cross the
line it works ok and I want you to try
figure out how this works and I'm gonna
tell you what it's doesn't use it does
not use command blocks because we're or
plain vanilla here it doesn't use
monster spawners or mobs at all period
do you know how it works this is a I
think a new method for for sensing like
player position I am going to say though
it's not very practical
and has absolutely no use in creative
because there is command blocks so I
pretty much just built this for for the
fun of it to see how it works and it's
it's pretty cool alright so I'll show
you how it works I think it's I think
it's gonna surprise you so this is
actually something I talked about on
feed the beast
is it flashing no okay
it works different at night too so
there's that too
basically I got a wire running all the
way down I decided to put it at like Y
11 so I could get a bunch of redstone
and other things as I as I built this
all right here we go oh no it keeps
going here it is okay uh-huh
we have to to pass here they stretch out
about 120 blocks each direction and then
at the very end guess what there is I'm
making you guys think really hard this
episode if you thought this was gonna be
easy
that I was gonna do all the words you
got another thing coming to you there's
a cave up there yeah so at each end
there is a dispenser with items in and
those go to a tripwire
I could probably set this up so the
items get recycled but I haven't and
when the tripwire gets tripped sends a
pulse and that runs all the way to the
other end of the thing so what I'm doing
with this is I'm detecting where I am in
the world by detecting if chunks are
unloaded which is something I didn't
feed the beast
and then this is just a RS nor latch to
figure out what state it's in so you see
that pulse right there so we got close
enough to the other dispenser here for
it to do that and you might wonder why
it's not doing a constant loop like just
always going and it's it's pretty
interesting the way this game deals with
unloaded chunks so if you have a
redstone Satan I'll go to an unloaded
chunk it will actually keep going like
it'll load the chunk and the redstone
cycle will keep going
but there are some things that don't
work in on little chunks like block
updates for example you can't have you
can't like send redstone signal to an
unloaded chunk and then have havoc oh
and I got a clock and have wheat growing
in that unloaded chunk or anything like
that but you can for example trigger a
dropper here and that will shoot the
item out but since it's in an unloaded
chunk items don't actually fall or move
at all they just get dispensed and then
that's it and then when you move closer
to it the item falls and hits the
tripwire and then it sends it to the
other end which will only activate when
I get close to that one so yeah it was
this a fun fun build I thought you guys
would find it interesting
I was curious to see how it would work
the weird thing though is it at
nighttime I think like mobs moving
around might affected somehow or
something I don't know it's a little
strange I just finished building it so
I'm still learning all the oddities to
it and you could set up something like
this like with three points and then you
could precisely figure out where the
player needs to be like I'm just
detecting if I cross a line basically
but you could figure out precisely to a
chunk I'm sure it can't detect your
vertical height though oh you jerk
there's so many mobs in my world because
all the caves are lit up here hey but
yeah it's pretty cool so yeah checked it
out like yeah
it allows it from a distance to so it's
like I don't have to walk right by the
light either it will detect when I cross
over here all right walk back there's
about a 16 block air range you have to
cover before it'll trigger they'll let
you triggered here but then I have to be
about 16 blocks over for it to trigger
the other way for the chunk to load
anyway
I thought you guys would find it
interesting also I saw a post on reddit
a while ago and they put like glowstone
hanging from jungle trees and I thought
it looked pretty cool so I did that same
thing over here oh hey Jackie I've still
never gotten who's gonna win that he's
got armor but he's got a spider my
money's on the armored guy come on
armored guy that is a battle man look at
that oh you got got rid of the spiders
are they gonna keep fighting
no is that other guy shooting he's in
the ground now that is so weird oh oh oh
the I lost chainmail guy got owned is he
still in the ground look at this guy
it's like a is this the East gelett and
he's like crawling on his knees and
through the grass to get us here can we
get a record oh I don't want to try
right what was I talking about let's go
let's go look at the trees why not
probably gonna add a few more lights but
I like to how it looks just just to try
make things look a little bitter on top
of the world here
pretty cool all right
I got some other things to show you guys
so let's get to that actually you know
what guys a few more things here I was
gonna ask you like I built this as a
this is a technical experiment basically
but we can't make it do something and I
was wondering if you guys have ideas
what should we make to do I thinking
about maybe a fountain with water and
lava that that change depending on what
side you are at the line but I figure
you know collectively all you guys will
probably come up with a better idea so
if you have an idea for for a build here
let me know using that feature and
another interesting thing like with
triggering triggering a dispenser in an
unloaded chunk if you have TNT in it it
will dispense the TNT but the time
doesn't actually count down on it so
when you re-enter the chunk that you can
dispense hundreds of TNT all at once in
one spot and when you re-enter the chunk
then it starts counting down and all
explodes at once so with that you can
pretty much make the furthest cannon in
the game you know there's always been
this challenge at minecraft to build the
farthest shooting cannon and with that
you could have potentially thousands and
thousands of TNT all in one spot but the
thing is your games not going to be able
to handle it so now it's more how much
senior game handle instead of you know
what clever wait Oh what well clever
wait can you get all the TNT in one spot
you know it's it's pretty much figured
out now let's see one more thing what
one other thing was there
ah my memory stinks oh well since we're
all the way back here I'll show you what
else I worked on after last episode we
built the bridge last time but then
after that I also started working on a
path as the video was rendering and yeah
I think it looks pretty cool let's go to
sleep see you can see it with the lights
on oh it's date so this path it's made
out of that cyan hardened clay there's a
lot of monsters around oh no don't
can I sleep it's still kind of dark out
oh I can't cool yeah it's it's cyan
hardened clay with stone brick on the
sides and then leaves on the side of
that just for aesthetics and I think
that looks pretty cool
each of these lights is controlled by a
light sensor you can see it under the
leaves here and there's basically a
redstone dust under that and it goes to
a redstone torch and up to the light and
sunlight than or moonlight can shine
through the leaves here and and they're
all independently working and the path
comes up here you can see there's like
no stairs here it's like the idea is I
wanted to make a horse path basically
and they can walk up one block jumps you
know but if we manually do it we got a
we got jump it ourselves and good thing
I turned around it's not done yet I'm
still working that putting sensors under
the lights and also finishing the path
to it's not quite done goes around here
we got a nice view might do something in
this area I made it go through a hill
here and then that's about as far as I
got the idea is I want to get it up to
the library here though which is at the
top of the mountain and have a nice
horse path to get to that
I still do kind of want to do an East
Road though to get to this library so I
haven't put that idea out of there yet I
put down torches to how I think I'm
gonna make it go but I'm not sure yet
like a line of torches you can see it
the own like that I tried not to make
the path straight just so it would look
a little more pleasing and then our
library's at the top here and we're not
working on that today I know a lot of
people have been asking me to but today
we're mostly going to be doing
experiments and stuff in my world I
always have lots of projects going at a
time and I like it that way because then
I never get bored of the game I only
have like one or two projects going it's
not I might not necessarily want to work
on them that day and then it's like I
don't want to play so that's why I like
to have lots of stuff going and the
problem with that those people like I
know I always have people asking me to
work on the village the Emerald City and
a lot of stuff people get projects they
want me to work on they have their
favorites and Wilson and I don't always
work on it but eventually I do tend to
get stuff done so don't worry we'll
return to stuff it's not like I bend the
ideas totally right still haven't
thought of that thing I forgot anyway
the other thing we're gonna do now back
to experimenting here we're going to the
nether I figured we would do this
together on camera here because a lot of
people weren't sure about this myself
included do beacons worked in the nether
what do you guys think
again I had a lot of different comments
about this people weren't really sure
some people were sure I think but most
people didn't know basically well I
don't know at the moment Ashley we're
gonna figure it out you can see these
are all disabled at the moment I can't I
can't activate the beacon can't hit
checkmark it's all grayed out oh it is
working
interesting oh okay now it's that's done
okay check oh that did eat it though it
works it's just a little bit glitchy
which I don't know if it's supposed to
work or not gonna give me speed yeah
give me speed okay it seems to work
pretty good the thing is I started
building a big pyramid and I was having
trouble getting it to work though so
we'll see if we can actually make it
worked here so I'm gonna put a pyramid
underneath here
you see there's no options now there is
it's a little weird and I don't think we
have any buff at the moment so with this
big pyramid it's not really working
properly oh okay it's here now I don't
think I can put something in and make it
work so it is strange if you can get a
beacon on top of the bedrock so it will
work like normal I think because it has
sunlight I'm wondering if we break some
of these blocks and put them back if we
can get it to work her maybe there's
some other trick we could do no okay we
dismantle the pyramid the Earl at layer
maybe we can make it work then
oh boy I'm sure I could get it to work
if I messed with it enough because it
was working like it the small steel so
I'm sure there's a trick to making the
big one work maybe I'll mess with it a
bit off-camera here I was hoping I would
have figured it out by now but I'll be
right back okay so I was having a little
trouble getting it working down there
maybe because I had blocks above it but
sad to build it here where it was
working built it up a little higher
I had the 3x3 going it's not very sound
seems very loud to me today I don't know
why I had it working at the 3x3 here and
then I added on the other three layers
once I had it working and so a level for
beacon should work 50 blocks away so
this is 13 here and if we go we would
have to go to about 63 then for it to
stop right at 63 all right is it
refreshing yep one more block 64 way now
it is not so yeah it is level for beacon
I'm wondering if we can get the speed 2
here so let's try that I was really
worried about breaking it off camera
because then I'd have to rebuild it all
if it does break so that should work
speed - yep speed - works perfect
so beacons are possible in the nether
without putting them on bedrock so what
makes it not worth is the next question
so I'm going to put some blocks above
here I put one right here all right it's
still working
no it's not hmm interesting
I think because nether rat is all
natural right and I put that there
or maybe it just needs three blocks now
it's working they can go up one more
maybe no maybe it's just gotta be
another rack above break it and it works
I think we found the the reason here
let's try a different thing let's put a
ladder above
you're gonna refresh do that refresh no
problem so it's like it gets cutting out
the sunlight that portal so annoy SL
that's zero interesting let's try one
more other block and not refreshing
let's try slabs cuz that's what we have
above there nope okay so that's what it
is pretty simple and they kicked in cool
so if we built it if we put beacon above
here or some other place even you should
work fine
I think I'll allow maybe put up above
here there's one more thing I should
probably point out with this it turns
out like it's working right now right
but if I manually place some netherrack
like stuff I placed myself that wasn't
naturally generated that way it doesn't
work and I'm guessing if there's a
closed stone or another breaker or
another quartz or something above it's
not gonna work either but I could be
wrong
alright guys it works we have a speed to
beacon now level 4 has a radius of 50
blocks diameter of a hundred and I put
it right above the netherrack they're
like two blocks above with the beacon
directly above the center here
so pretty cool we got speed - it works
and still gotta finish the ceiling in
here I don't know what I'm doing yet
though but I tell you once I figure it
out we will do it don't you worry
anyways I think we should get to reading
the comments for today first one a few
episodes ago someone asked for a guide /
walkthrough of your world but you threw
it away because we see all the things
often you might be partially right we do
see some stuff often like the stuff in
the man cave but I don't know what they
all do we just see the front of the
system and you do not interact with
stuff I've never seen before every now
and then like the thing in the river and
the thing you visited on your first
horseback ride please do a walk through
ESO so yeah we I think I am gonna do
walkthrough of the world here let's make
you the goal Peppa sowed 275 that sound
good because it has been a while before
I shown before I not before since I've
shown everything use the right words so
episode 275 hopefully I don't forget and
I will give you a tour
next one Ito do you like cookies and
which could use do you like the most
I love cookies nom nom nom nom chocolate
chip I love chocolate chip the most yeah
pretty much I'll click these are good
though
chocolate chip by far my favorite though
alright guys that's all for today I have
a good date thanks for watching bye bye
you