[Music]
really
that is fascinating i never knew that so
you're telling me
colin mockery and ryan styles had a baby
together
and that was the first testificate
that explains so much oh man oh hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode
of minecraft so we're over at the
village we got little baby villagers a
new librarian
you better sell mending or frostwalker
one other two
i think we got one that grew up here
though so i'm gonna check them
is it you it's not you we know what
you're all about
depth strider three and thorns one i've
been trying to breathe these guys
get more little babies so that hopefully
one day we could get a frost walker or
mending book and uh hopefully that this
is the day
i've gone through quite a few librarians
and no no such luck oh
oh is it you don't die if it's you
no this is an old guy what does this one
have punch
to silk touch okay
i know there was another one i saw him
oh they're making more babies good good
i think i've gotten everywhere oh is it
you
this is him okay we finally found him i
checked every house and he's over here i
guess
yeah so new trade what do we have
yes oh yes i finally got the mending
22 or emeralds that's a little bit
pricey but
oh this is awesome okay let's do some
actual trading and see if he unlocks
frostwalker
if you give me mending and frostwalker
that will be amazing that will be
incredible
i actually went to uh the end and flew
around looking for
for more fortresses because my elijah
wings keep wearing out on me
and without the mending i won't be able
to fly for very long
so this guy is amazing
power four okay not the best
all right what's the last book it is
infinity for six emeralds that's pretty
cheap
this is a really good librarian okay so
what we're gonna do
is encase you with glass yes perfect oh
you know exactly the drill
awesome so until i get you moved you are
not moving
anywhere you're staying right there
whoa hey how did i do that
okay uh so something that's been going
around lately guys
is uh this whole thing where you can
apparently equip villagers with
armor you can even give them thorns and
then they can kill you
azuma posted a video on that and uh
i think cub fan has a video on it so i
wanted to try that out here and also i'm
pretty sure i didn't actually watch a
video so they might have shown this
but i'm pretty sure you can also give
them
a dragon head i had a brain fart there
i was going to give this to the the
farmer we have here that guy over there
but this guy he
is special he deserves it right so we're
going to try it on him
i'm pretty sure this will work
oh that's funny i almost want to let him
out just so we can see him now
um maybe i shouldn't have given to this
guy well i gotta move him anyway
right maybe i'll i'll add this guy to
the project pokemon although we do have
a librarian there already that's special
[Music]
okay i freed him but he's not moving oh
here he goes here he goes
[Laughter]
[Music]
oh that's awesome oh and the mouth is
actually moving as he walks too
i think just sweaty walks though yeah
yeah it opens and closes that's great
okay i'm gonna put him back before
before i lose them here
gonna do some trading gonna get some
ending books and put it on all my stuff
because mending is absolutely amazing
cool uh-huh so if you guys are like me
and you got a pair of elytra wings and
you're like well
i'm going to get mending on it
eventually and i'm just going to keep
using it and then one day when i finally
get the mending i'll put it on
there it does get to a point it turns
out the pair i had on
is too expensive to repair normally you
can repair it with leather but it
doesn't let me here
and when it gets to this point
apparently you also cannot put the
mending book on it so this pair is
pretty much
done for after i use use it up here
but uh thankfully i had another pair um
ready to go here so we can put mending
on it oh it only costs three levels
that's pretty cheap
got done breaking on it already and
let's give it a name let's call it
above
the law yeah law of gravity
obviously
this is amazing all right everybody so
this is a little bit later now i am
doing an
experiment i've wanted to try for a long
time but i just wasn't able to get
mending until now
are we friends are you gonna be my
friend
i think he likes me hey you're cool
i like you alright so
i have put mending on pretty much all my
gear here but i've also made a new set
of armor
which allows me to kill these spiders
when they run into me it is my
prickly poncho prickly pants and i got
my prickly pumps
all three of these have thorns on uh i
did not have enough thorns books to do
a helmet though unfortunately so
yeah basically the idea is i want i've
wanted to see if you can make an afk mob
system where the mobs run into you they
kill themselves they commit sudoku
the puzzle game right
and you would have like a a beacon setup
that gives you healing and resistance
and all that kind of stuff
and the interesting thing about it is
normally i would never use
thorns because instead of taking one
durability
when something hits you it it causes
three deer ability to be lost so
stuff breaks super quickly if you have
thorns
but if you combine it with mending i'm
just checking if
if the xp you get from the mobs is
enough to repair it
compared to how much damage it takes
and so far it almost looks like the
armor is breaking
i'm gonna have to test it for a little
bit longer
94 93 the boots are taking longer to
repair
oh now we're back up to 95.
i don't know it's kind of weird
i also heard there's might be a glitch
in the game
which i'm curious about
let's see how did he die he was so far
away
wasn't he i don't think that one touched
me he just died
that was very weird oh yeah and because
they're attacking me
it counts as my kill right so i think
the looting effect from my sword
takes effect and i also get the special
drops so like
spiders give me spider eyes which you
normally don't get if you just drop them
and and obviously you could apply this
to lots of other different farms this
concept
um yeah i heard though there might be a
glitch where if you
put an item with thorns in your off hand
it applies the thorns effect here let's
switch back to our normal armor
but it doesn't take durability which
would be super cheaty
oh i better better heal here too this
guy is spinning like a dj
look at him go alright so this has
thorns
let's put that in our offhand
yeah it is hurting them even though i
don't have thorns on anything here
interesting and is it taking durability
oh i gotta keep eating
because i don't have a beacon set up
here i'm just eating to counter the
effect
uh is this taking damage i don't think
so
it's repairing because it's in my
offhand anything you have in your
offhand repairs with mending
let's see 295
oh thunderstorm new horse
yep new horse oh snappers
oh okay you gotta pay more attention
okay i'm getting owned i'm getting owned
big time
got him oh i'm dead go go go go
okay that was not a new horse that was
one i found before
it's trying to get a charged creeper
all right everybody so we got some more
crazy stuff going on here
i have decided let's go into a creative
world
because i was having a lot of trouble
testing out this whole thorns concept
in my lp world that spider farm for
example
i wasn't dropping the spiders from the
proper height so sometimes they were
taking more than one hit to kill
with the thorns armor and that was
throwing off the whole math the whole
point of this is just to see if the
armor is able to repair itself
so we need we need to make sure all the
mobs die in one hit from the armor
so i decided let's go to creative world
i set up a quick enderman farm here
because it's one of the easiest farms to
to do this with although it doesn't make
a lot of sense
you would probably want to do this idea
more with like a afk wither skeleton
firm or something like that so
something that has a special drop like a
wither head or spider eyes from spiders
or
gold ingots from gold from zombie pigmen
that kind of thing you know enderman
they just drop ender pearls so you don't
need to farm extras
of those uh but let's just use this to
try out the concept so let's go
oh we are in game mode zero good so what
you would do
set it up so that you can afk and the
mobs come attack you so with enderman i
have a line of sight set up here so that
they
i get into this loop of pain this never
ending onslaught and we're
just checking if we can gain any levels
and if our armor can keep up
repairing itself also i wanted to know
how
how good the beacon was at keeping us
alive so we do have resistance to
and regeneration but if i stop eating
they do actually kill me you see my
hearts are going down so i have to keep
eating
on hard mode here in order to stay alive
on normal you might be able to
survive this i'm not sure let's go to a
difficulty
can't spell normal
maybe okay let's not eat
see if our hearts stay up or nuts
see this is more bounced
uh looks like they are going down still
though
so yeah you would need to play on easy
probably to do this
with enderman anyway um if it's a mob
that does less damage
it's a really stupid idea i'm just
telling you that now it doesn't seem
like it's gonna work
and also the durability on the armor is
going down
so that's no no bueno uh
but it was a fun concept to try out
anyway if i get rid of like
my full set of thorns here um
let's say i just do one piece of thorns
three and the rest is regular armor like
protection
protection armor here put that on so
because when you use thorns you lose
three durability when its effect takes
place
you just have regular armor durability
is gonna go down a lot less
but i think what happens as well the
endermen don't necessarily
die every time they hit you
if you don't have as much thorns
although it looks like it's just about
every time right
you see the endermans turn red and die
on the side there
right there i think i got hit six or
seven times in a row without any dying
so you do want more more thorns
pieces than just one
um and even with just
one it seems like the durability still
goes down
right
it's like just a little bit of a loss on
the durability yeah it's going down
quite a bit actually
the chest piece so
yeah that is the idea it doesn't work
just thought i would show you though
now one other thing here if you do the
chidi thing where you put the thorns
piece
in your off hand so you don't lose the
crazy
durability from the thorns effect and
then the rest of this is just normal
armor then
it seems it can actually keep up
repairing the armor so it would never
break when you're afk
because that's what's going to kill you
if your armor breaks when you're aft
eventually
you would die from the mobs right with
this method
it seems like it can keep up with xp you
get
and you even gain a little bit extra my
levels are going up ever so slightly
here
maybe maybe you could get this to work
but this is a bit of a cheating concept
because i don't know if this is
intended they might eventually patch
that feature
it's hard to say you never know with
mojang
wait a minute here i just had another
idea let's be thorough
i forgot you could probably do something
with shields too right
so in survival mode you can put
unbreaking on the shields but mending on
a shield
you cannot put thorns on a shield though
all right
so this would lower the amount of damage
you take right
oh man that shield is breaking fast and
it's
gone all right that mending did not save
it
all right guys so we are back in our lp
world now i think we're done with the
testing
i have decided let's go ahead and just
do it just do it why not
i feel like building something now we're
going to make an afk spider farm
a cave spider farm i think in my world i
actually don't
really have a good way of getting spider
eyes i've just been using the ones we
collected like
hundreds of episodes ago i had at one
point probably three or four double
chests and this is what we're down to
now
uh this is like i think most of my stash
you use them up
not super quickly but because i use
potions a lot you do use them
with potions fermented spider eyes and
and like damage potions
use them up poison potions that kind of
thing
so slowly over time here i am running
out of them
and since we're looking for a farm to do
this with i think a spider farm is a
good idea
so off over this way
a long long time ago i believe we found
a dual cave spider spawner
another one i have two already and i
found another one over here
that i think we'll use
just so i don't have to modify the other
ones was it this ravine or was it
was there another ravine after this i
think there was another ravine after
this
yeah okay and also beyond the village if
we ever want to expand it this is
probably where we're going to go
off to this area is this ravine no this
is just the mine shaft
okay i want to show you guys where it is
if we can find it
and dead
and free all right good
now i'm all disoriented where where were
we i think we ender pearled up here
yeah oh yeah here here this is it
so this is a ravine we found a long time
ago
and i remember being off this way
i think floating floating
oh it's over there okay yeah i guess
it's kind of above the ravine
can we get to there let's just enter
pearl i guess
so there's one over here and then i
think there was one more
this way yeah right there
side by side perfectly united
can't ask for much better so this is
going to be great
and i haven't made like a mob spawner
mop farm
what did i just say i haven't made a
like a farm that uses mob spawners in a
long time so i'm
kind of curious how the mechanics have
changed i heard there was a change
recently i think in 1.8
where it takes a nine by nine spawning
area now instead of eight by eight
so we'll test that out and also i just
want to get used to
how the cave spider path finding works
and all that kind of stuff because i
haven't done anything with them in so
long so i think this will be
a pretty fun project oh i actually had a
way down
from the surface interesting so yeah let
me clear out some space here
i guess i'll set up the beacons already
to do that
okay very cool guys so now uh we got a
fair bit of space cleared out here i'm
starting to enclose the spawners making
a room just big enough to maximize the
spawning potential
from the spawners how many times did i
say spawn in that sentence i don't even
know
alright so i'm going to leave one
airspace above
one airspace below the spawners and then
water
at this level here to push them off of
here
is what i'm going to try to begin with
here anyway
so in the past this is what we really
got to test
they used to only spawn in an eight by
eight that was true with all spawners
favoring the negative coordinates so
let's test the positive coordinates here
which is this way and this way so this
way and this way are positive
x and z um that means in the past
let's count it from the spawner spawners
over here so one
two three four and
one two three four so this row
all the way down here they used to not
be able to spawn it and
all the way one two three oh i think i
got marked here actually and all the way
down this row
so let's make a dark
at that row and just see if we can get
any to spawn in this tiny little space
we give them
and if they can spawn in here that means
it's true
so and it'll be a nine by nine then
so i'll oh
oh wow okay that was fast i did not cut
there that just happened right away so
that was awesome
so it is true it's a 9x9 now by the
looks of it
so i'm going to make my room here that
big
[Applause]
oh oops okay a little problem has come
up here
because we're doing a 9x9 area guys the
water
doesn't reach all the way if you put in
the back here because it only travels
eight blocks right
which is perfect for spawners usually
but if you want to take advantage of the
full 9x9 space now
uh that means we have to do a step down
somewhere like this
which doesn't look as clean
but yeah i guess i'll do that uh the
reason we're doing this whole water
thing instead of dropping them right off
the bat
by the way if they were to spawn at this
top block
compared to this bottom block that makes
one heart difference
in their total health after we drop them
here oops
i fell down um we want to get him to
exactly one hit to kill him with our
thorn's armor otherwise we're going to
lose a lot more durability on it
and that can't happen as we saw in our
testing the threshold is very
very close at the moment so we don't
want to lose
any more durability on it
so we're going to try to drop them
consistently from the same height every
time
okay so i put the water in the back
there you see how the back is
is higher than the front they still have
the one air space below the spawner
totally free though um
so the water brings them to the edge
here we drop them down
and i'm just watching how they behave
like do they try to climb
do they get stuck anywhere that sort of
thing
and also i'm trying to find the sweet
spots
where they don't die when they hit the
ground but i can kill them with a punch
like that so that's good
are they dying it's like a big
big mess here string everywhere the idea
is
we stand over here underneath the
spawners so we're within range of them
we drop them down to one hit
oh yeah see some of them are falling too
far still
so i might have to raise this a block or
maybe even a
half slab maybe i should do a slab
because it's like just on the verge of
sometimes like
depending on where they are on the water
when they fall down
they might be a little bit higher a
little bit lower
because they kind of swim on the water
you know they go up and down on it
so i'm gonna put some slabs down here i
guess and hopefully that'll fix it
okay still not working even with the
slab higher
some of them are also taking more than
one hit to kill so i'm trying to add a
thing here
to ensure they always fall from the
exact same heights but they
are really wrecking me
as i try to do this nice love more yes i
have another stack of glass
good gonna get this in here pretty
quickly
i'll polish this up afterwards oh if it
works
yay heal up again yeah spiders are not
as scary as they used to be that's for
just sure one of the worst enemies now
you can heal faster than
the poison affects you even on hard so
it's not really a big deal
so i left a slab spacing there hopefully
that is enough for them to fit through
if they climb above that like they were
doing um they should eventually let
go i believe fall back in the water and
all will be good
i'll just have to monitor it for a
little bit here
oh okay clean up the rest of them
let's go to our spot our special spot
here
oh man i think i heard some more to
spawn
are they gonna fall down are they stuck
up there
i think they're stuck up there oh no one
got through for sure
they didn't die they should be one hit
kills for sure
what oh no way
are they climbing as they fall down
that must be what it is then
or maybe just before they hit the ground
they pathfind towards me and then start
climbing on the wall towards
towards me i think that could be it
yeah this guy was not a one-hit kill
again
so they're clinging on this wall as they
fall down i'll have to remove it then
okay so guys i think we might actually
have this working
pretty good now we're getting great
spawning rates
um you'll notice my hearts are not going
down
i have solved the inconsistency problem
as well so by removing
oh let a few of these guys die
uh by removing the walls as they fall
down you see how it's three wide up
there now
they have no way of clinging to them as
they fall so
it's consistently getting them down to
half a heart one hit kill with the
thorns
um so that's great
my armor is keeping up which is a big
thing it's not wearing down
and here's the next big thing you see my
hearts are not going down but once i run
out of food
totally forgot about this but i'm also
going to take extra damage from that
hunger damage who knew i never even
thought of it
all right let's get a couple more guys
maybe jump around a bit get my hunger
down quicker
okay when i go down there they stop
spawning it's only when i'm up here
that i'm within range of them and if i
set it up like this where they hit me
into the
the back wall here i'll never get
knocked out of the spot which is
important as well
okay so food is all gone what is my
health gonna do here
we are on hard by the way
looks like we're we're taking it oh it
went down a full heart there
but we're back up to half oh and a half
down
hello okay back up to half
it's fluctuating a bit more than i'd
like to see but it seems like we're
surviving right
you'll notice sometimes i take damage
like two hits in a row there it's kind
of weird
oh and i think that's why it's doing
that
hearts the spiders
aren't truly doing much damage oh now
it's down two hearts
i'm getting worried it's like it's
gradually decreasing
[Music]
which is a problem
okay guys yeah it's looking like i'm
gonna die eventually here this is like
10 minutes in just
very very very slowly losing my health
here
on hard on normal i would be fine i'm
pretty sure
you know what i think it is though
i don't think these spiders are doing
much damage to me let's just go away
in a little hidey hole here
let the poison run out and see if i can
recover then
we could do something like set up a
hopper timer
uh to pull us out of danger so we we're
not poisoned constantly and see if we
can recover that way
let's see if our hearts go up now that
we're not poisoned
so we're at one one and a half one
i kind of get the impression i can't
heal at all
the the damage from not having food is
equivalent to the regeneration we get
from the beacon
which is why i'm dying slowly here
yeah ah
that that kind of stinks
so the only way to recover health then
is to get like instant health potions
dispensed on us every so often
that complicates things greatly
otherwise it's a beautiful
mob system i gotta say or i gotta eat
but then i can't do this afk which is
the whole point of this
oh man i just realized something too you
guys are probably really annoyed this
episode because of the damage
ticking sound i got so used to it i
never even thought of it but yeah it is
really annoying isn't it
i'm sorry um
i wanted to show you one more thing here
the looting effect from my sword
does work so normally you get zero to
two string
per kill that time i got three i believe
and a 33 chance of getting one spider
eye
so we're at 37 we just got four spider
eyes
three spider eyes three more right
i'm very bad at counting
so yeah definitely getting the looting
effect so that's cool
the idea is we would set up a hopper
kind of like where we're standing
or a few hoppers actually to pick up the
string and the spider eyes
item filters to sort it and it seems
like
if i actually want to do this i'm going
to need some sort of brewing system to
keep me alive as well
unless you guys have another idea but i
think like a
instant health potion every five minutes
or so
should do the trick but yeah otherwise
it's totally
an afk spider farm
oh i'm an idiot
i've been trying to fly for like
two minutes here i took my wings off
oh i'm so stupid it's like man i really
got bad at this all of a sudden i can't
fly at all
oh i'm still bad at it apparently oh i
had it there but i hit the wall
still learning
nope oh here we go
there we go there we go once you get
going it's nice and easy
i do find my space bar on this keyboard
though is not the best like a lot of
times
because i have to hold like two or three
buttons down at the same time
sometimes the space bar doesn't want to
work
um but yeah guys we're gonna have to
finish it up next episode
we are pretty much out of time here so
let's do the comment of the day
and if you have ideas for it let me know
so that i can actually
implement them leave a comment uh it
says etho
how do you feel about the observer block
that might possibly
be implemented into minecraft in 1.10
if it is added would you do the long job
of fixing
all your redstone machines that use buds
or what
so if you guys don't know the observer
block was a talked about
potential uh bud switch
properly implemented into minecraft so a
single block
bud switch uh they were talking about
doing that for 1.10
uh honestly i would not update my
machines
or my redstone stuff if i didn't have to
if you guys don't know
bud switches let's see if i can find my
redstone here
got that got that oh i need a block bud
switches
are pretty compact already i don't
really see the
need to add a special block just for
them
um you can do it in three blocks
a vertical one like a so that's all you
got to do so every time you place a
block next to the piston
it detects it or whenever
the block next to the piston changes and
there's a horizontal one too let's see
if i can remember how to do it
i don't use this one as much although
it's pretty good too
oh let's steal that steal that redstone
block
like i saw i think you also have to add
another block at the end if i remember
right
let's try it now yeah looks good without
that block does it work
no it spans out ah
so yeah they're pretty compact as it is
the only reason i would change it is if
they broke redstone
here's the thing though that it confuses
a lot of people bud switches
like they've talked about getting rid of
the quasi connectivity
in minecraft that's the diagonal
powering
um so for example this redstone block
here
powers this piston it just doesn't
update
right away so if it's gone it stays
extended
and that that's how a lot of butt
switches work but that is not the only
way they can work
they're they're kind of two separate
things in minecraft so
yeah even if they get rid of that
feature bud switches will still be a
thing
just you have to do it differently um
and also
other redstone uses quasi connectivity
so it's a good thing
that they don't remove it because it'll
break a lot of stuff not just bud
switches
aha anyways ramble ramble
uh i have done some more work on the
the nexus here guys i don't know if you
remember but this middle part was all
like
grass and stuff i've tried to make it
look a little bit cleaner a little bit
nicer i got like
glass all over here now glass instead of
grass i know it's amazing
such a change and also i redid some of
the redstone stuff too and made a few
other things nicer like i got
a couple extra chests so it can handle
items quicker
the dropper elevator i was using here
before used redstone torches
now it's just using redstone wire
redstone torches cause lighting updates
so it was lagging my game quite a bit
actually
when it was running and since it runs
like all the time
definitely wanted to change that so
that's good we do need to make a
building here still so i'm
trying to think of plans of how to do
that oh yeah and i removed like a bunch
of land over here too
there used to be like a big mountain
over here it's gone now
my big problem with this though is like
this is where the main room is going to
be
somehow i got to figure out how to
connect this area
all the way over here it's like a long
stretch
to get to here um i almost feel like we
need to build another big room over
like in this area too and then connect
this room to this room
but i don't know it's gonna be a big
project to finish that still
but anyways i hope you enjoyed today's
episode guys thank you for
watching and i will see you again in the
next
episode i got mending i'm so happy
bye bye