hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back to another episode and he's so tiny
do you even know he was there he was so
short so yeah the village
spent some more time in the village this
guy loves that table go up I'm sorry
they like this well they like to look at
the animals in the well for some reason
although I guess I'd do that too
who's the how can you blame them you
know so yeah I worked on the door some
more there we go I think that's gonna be
our final look works pretty good I added
a clock there just for looks I was not
able to put lamps up there so I put
glowstone and covered it up covered up
the ugliness hopefully and this is our
portal room so all in all I think it
turned out pretty good I like the look
of the portals it spelled stouts we have
a nice viewing window over here check
things out from the outside it looks so
so it's the big block of wood basically
a whole bunch of planks put together but
I really like how it looks from this
side so yeah we got our portal room all
all good to go there and actually this
village I am pretty much done with I do
need to add more doors though so yeah
last last episode as trying to hang
around here to get the villagers to
repopulate the village and nothing was
happening and I could was like I was a
little confused by it because when I
first found this villagers like 9/10
villagers in it but then I went up here
and I looked and
saw there's not many houses there's one
two three four five six counting this
one seven eight nine nine houses so it
if each of those has one door and it
takes three doors to make a villager
we're only gonna get like three
villagers total in this village it's
kind of sad oh yeah I tried doing that
that doesn't do anything now
it's kind of sad like you have to have
three doors
her house the way villages are set up
they're always going to die on their own
you have to protect them
everything the odds are against them
zombies are gonna kill the villagers and
even if light one or two survive they'll
never repopulate the village because
it's not set up in a way that that'll
happen there's not enough doors so you
need to add like three doors per house
on average and yeah it's about the last
thing I gotta do to it
oh yeah and I did something pretty cool
like the goal of this was just to
repopulate it and keep them safe and
maybe spruce it up a little bit but I'm
not gonna like modify any of the houses
or any of the wheat farms or any of that
but I did do this I added these levers
to every one of the wheat farms and what
that does pulls the ground down then it
pops back up so yeah looks simple
alright that took I took a lot of
pistons I tell you where is what what
else can get rid of here I throw the
sticks away yeah it's each of these farm
things is seven plus seven times four so
we got 28 oh I might get another
villager just one
that's the one I think yet just the one
see ya 28 and there is I think in total
two one two three four five I did it
with every one of them it's just for
completions completing completionists
sake or whatever the word is there's
about nine nine farms nine times
twenty-eight is about 250 Pistons sticky
pistons so yeah it took a little while
to do but I think it's a cool addition
to the village the way I wired these I
guess I'll show you fix it after for a
lot of the Pistons it's really easy you
can just run a line next to them but the
places where the water is it's a bit
it's a little bit more challenging
because the waters in the way so you
have to go waste or at least the way I
did it is that went along here and
actually I can't exactly show you but
where the water is it goes down here it
goes to a repeater then it goes to the
block there's a redstone dust above that
and that points to that block and that
block so it powers the Pistons on the
sides and it runs to the back so not too
not too difficult the main expense of
course is that all the Pistons just way
it's laid out it's not a very efficient
farm but it's for the cool factor all
right so I'm gonna fix this up we'll go
do something okay guys so there's
something I want to try out today or
figure out today I should say with this
mob trap it's been running a long time
so we should get a lot of items when we
go to the end here but then don't
we are going to what we get we did get a
fair bit okay maybe maybe it is okay
let's see two stacks of gunpowder it
still seems like it should be more 30 mm
well regardless I want to setup
experiment here what I'm gonna do see
what do I toss I'm going to I want my
gun powder that's what I want
there it is okay so I kind of have this
idea that maybe like you know how you
can enter the end very quickly there
might be because some chunks are always
loaded in its rounds where you come in
here possibly that's one idea the other
idea is maybe every time an item enters
the end its it causes it to load for you
know a second or two and as that
accumulates eventually five minutes goes
by and items starting spawning so those
are the two two main ideas I have why I
don't seem to be getting as many items
as they expect because even though I got
two and a half stacks it has been
running for a very long time so what I'm
going to do is set up this line of dirts
and plant wheat on it and see if there
there's a line somewhere where it stops
growing when I'm not in the end or or
check if it even grows at all if it
doesn't grow at all it's that means the
area is not loaded
my theme sounds I know how loud that was
for you guys my finger sounds like Frank
great now that almost busted my eardrums
okay so yeah I'm gonna plant two lines
of wheats and we'll see if we can notice
any lines forming in its growth pattern
or anything like that and from that we
should be able to figure out exactly
what's going on
okay there we go guys we have our wheat
all planted
I accidentally updated the elevator dang
it
when I put the seeds next to it it's not
a super perfect test like it's not
exactly evenly lit or anything like that
but it's it'll do the trick for what I
wanted to do so we're gonna leave now
all the land is hydrated I think and lit
swell enough for it to grow so either
either it's not gonna grow or it's gonna
grow with a line in it somewhere
or who knows maybe it'll all grow we'll
find out we'll check that later in the
episode don't ask so yeah I think we're
gonna hang out around this part of my
world for like 30 minutes or so because
the idea is there's a creeper by the way
the idea is with the the wheat there in
the end it should be growing right now
if those chunks are loaded so we'll be
able to see definitely if we stay here
for about 30 minutes or so my time not
your time don't worry it's gonna be much
faster for you yeah what was I gonna say
because yeah the idea is in this light
even in this part of the world there's a
few chunks my spawn in this world's
around there and there's a few chunks
around that area that are always loaded
no matter where I am in the world so I
think possibly that might be happening
in the end as well because when you go
through the portal it's very quick and I
think those chunks were already loaded
but we'll find out we'll find out and
that sucks I'd died maybe while we're
here I'll show you the waterfall because
I did do that took care of that there it
is I still want to modify it a little
bit but I think that's pretty cool
nice waterfalls some people were worried
I was just gonna have like a water
stream up at the top but no I
I made an artificial lake here that's
actually ice down there if you're
wondering why there's why I'm not
sinking because I'm on I'm on ice right
now so yeah I got a I made a fake fake
Lake here with flowers around then a
stream that comes from the top of the
mountain flows into that this I haven't
connected to anything it's just a stupid
water bucket stream and it looks like I
got a spill here which I don't want I
don't think yeah that's the waterfall
let's see I'll go show you guys the
chicken farm maybe and while we go over
there I'll talk about feed the beast I
have started playing feed the beast as
some of you may have saw on the mine
crack mine crack feed the beast
and I am having a ton of fun with that
that is that is awesome
I love the the Industrial Craft and
build craft mods and that like the whole
generating power and then powering
machines that do all these crazy things
and being able to I don't know just do
all kinds of crazy things with it I'm
having a blast with it I might start
uploading episodes of it I don't know
how how often or how frequent that will
be probably just as I have something
interesting to do chicken farm chicken
farm it's like it's good in everything
there's it I don't think it replaced
this vanilla minecraft though to be
honest because there's something that
worries me about the Mojang attitude I
kind of have been picking up on it this
is the chicken farm it's getting off on
the table like maybe I'll finish my
thought
like to me it seems more and more
they're encouraging people to look
forward to the Maude API for like if
they want features in the game go to the
motto API I'm worried they're gonna
focus on that more more so
instead of you know adding features
themselves because the problem with mods
like feed the beast is they don't mix
together all that great and some stuff
is overpowered some stuff you know you
don't use and but the stuff Mojang adds
I find is really bounced they put a lot
of thought into it and it makes for a
great game so I hope I hope they don't
get the wrong view of mods in the game
like I think they should still continue
and I think as far as I know that they
still plan to ticket they still plan on
continuing adding features and stuff to
the game like they're doing that the
redstone update then it sounds like they
might do a biome update which would be
awesome but I don't think mods really
replace that beats Mojang would add
themselves because they're the Mojang
ones are a lot better in my opinion not
that the feed the beast is bad or
anything I'm having fun with that but
it's definitely not balanced that's all
I'm saying
so yeah chicken farm so it's the chicken
firms pretty good I think I might change
it a little bit yet eggs come up problem
is if the chickens are right up against
the glass the eggs can still fly out of
that containment area I built for them
like you see there's an age here so if
they lay an egg when they're right up
against the glass sometimes it will pop
through the glass still most eggs stay
within that 1x1 air space though ooh
that looked weird I don't think they're
down there why is my Oh Oh an egg and
egg landed on the wooden pressure plate
above so now it's locked on now I don't
know what's powered what's not powered
today
well I can break it and then it'll be
unpowered when they replace it that's
how I know so I might fix this about 1/4
of the eggs I figure are flying out of
here
don't really know how to fix it without
using water or something which is what
I've been trying to avoid though so yeah
what else should we do maybe you know
what let's work on this today are all
work on this today anyway remember I
want to put water down below here to
hide the portal room I think that would
be a good good thing to work on while we
wait so I'm just gonna put a little pool
water maybe some flowers down here and
some grass and just try it'll look a
little bit nicer you know what when that
creeper got me I think my pick it hit
the cactus and I did not didn't I pick
back so I've got a new one I think it
was almost dead though so it's not too
bad but yeah I've been filling this in
I'd hide the pumpkin lights for sure
just trying to shape it look good cut
this out a little further I will still
be able to get to the wiring for the
portal room so if we want to look at it
we still can yeah oh yeah by the way
this is the I don't know if I ever
showed this this is a setup for the
crafting table the block switcher blocks
whopper so it's pretty pretty
straightforward
huh just like that okay I think we're
about ready to fill this in I think will
make the water at this level here and
want to fill this in too though it's all
lit I'm able to fill it get rid of all
this extra space we don't need yeah that
too
good enough okay so it's lit in there or
we should be safe to fill that in or
cover it up I mean like so this should
probably be down so got to make it look
like this wood is being supported by
something let's get rid of all the the
dirt showing to you oh I'm all I'm all
right so this should do it got a layer
of water now where the dirts OH
hmm I musta messed up there there's some
dirt showing here still for some reason
good enough good enough uh can I get
light under here no it's half slabs
how's that gonna look I wanted to be
kind of lit but I don't want to be able
to see the torches that's pretty cool
all over the place I didn't want to have
a waterfall over there to possible
yeah yeah that's good
or should I bring it up one more I
wonder yeah well we'll leave it at that
I'm gonna try get a waterfall here hmm
what do you guys think what do you think
it's good
maybe a little too fake I don't know let
me know in the comments I kind of like
it it like I'm trying to make it look
like it's it's coming through the rocks
I guess it like ground water alright I
like it with the water lit too
what I did here is I kind of hold this
out and put some hidden lighting behind
here so it lights up the waterfall a
little bit without it being you know too
much too much you know what would be
cool actually
maybe clay
and I want to make one of those or two
of those those pots I've never made one
before blue you're nuts can't remember
if you need bricks you might need bricks
yeah I have no idea what the recipe is
is it solid clay blocks it's probably
bricks
yeah dance breaks yeah one sec bricks no
okay I'm gonna make them off camera
there we go flower pots that's pretty
easy to make it actually doesn't take
much I want to put some some rainforest
trees down here not there right there oh
the water is suspecting me out of here
and yeah add a little bit more character
to it
yeah I like that yeah that's that's much
better doesn't make much sense but I
think it looks better
all right cool I think 30 minutes may be
up by now so let's go check out the end
again depending on the results we might
have to do one more test
I realize this is what we've been
looking for
i I don't know what to expect so it
didn't grow okay so these chunks are not
loaded so what I'm guessing it is then
when an item goes through maybe the
wheat is or maybe chunks load a little
bits every time and the items might be
the spotting from that over time so what
I'm gonna do now is afk around my
storage room here and to see if the
wheat grows while I do that any
significant amount so let's get out of
here remember how the wheat is right now
and we'll check it's probably in 30
minutes or so and okay so don't don't
forget and I think have to walk that ya
thang I think I've waited long enough
it's been about half an hour to an hour
let's go see how our wheat is doing if
it's changed at all going through we got
good it's about 2015 Oh miss waters
updating let's get out of there I kind
of suspect it's not grown okay I can't
tell I think I don't think it's grown
all that much
definitely not five minutes worth so you
know yeah you know what it probably is I
think it's because like my mom sister
was working really great before I think
when they introduced slimes spawning and
swamps I think that's lowering my rates
more than I expect and that's why it
seems like the numbers are off but as
far as I can tell maybe it grew a little
bit I'll have to compare the video but I
don't I don't notice any huge difference
with the wheat so doesn't seem like the
chunks are loaded any significant amount
of time all right well that's a good
test glad I know that's I think I think
we'll go read the comments all right got
one comment today guys here we go
hey eat though as a longtime subscriber
I've gotten I've gone through a lot of
updates with you what was your favorite
update version in Minecraft
I'd appreciate to know that I guess one
point seven point three my personal
favorites my favorite update I would
have to say is the current update that
otherwise I would be playing a different
updates yeah I think that's what it is I
did really like one point seven point
three as well before the adventure
update it was it was kind of a different
game with the adventure update you know
it changed it a fair bit I do like
having the sprinting and stuff I think
that was a good change I don't like the
new food system though compared to 1.7
points 3 I think the game was better or
more enjoyable before when your house
wouldn't just recover on its own you had
to actually eat something to make it
recover I think that was a better better
system another version I really liked is
when they fixed the sapling bug I don't
know if you guys remember that back in
alpha but there was a long period of
time
where's tree leaves one of these spawn
you'd have to break them manually to get
saplings and that was the most annoying
glitch I think ever in this game so when
they get when they fixed that finally
after weeks and weeks I really really
liked that update yep alright guys
that's gonna do it for today thanks for
watching take care have a good day
you