[Music]
hello
everyone how are you doing today uh etho
here once again we are at the stronghold
base
gonna be working on the mob system a
little bit mostly just testing it to
start off with
after last episode i decided to
investigate where we left off with it
how close we are to making our bomb
factory uh work and
we were actually really close i'm
surprised
i don't know why i didn't uh test it
earlier but it looks like it was all
all set up for a testing so we should do
that today all i've added is this little
water catch thing so when a creeper and
a skeleton fall into here
if they do they won't blow up the whole
machine
just a safe detonation for right now and
then we'll we'll
remove this and make them move somewhere
else once we confirm it is working
but um we're gonna test it out we're
gonna
we're gonna operate it manually first of
all
and then if it seems like it's working
the way it's supposed to we're gonna set
up a redstone
uh system to make it run automatically
is the plan
let's see are you guys going the right
way
all right where are you going where
are you going it's really hard to see
through all the glass what's happening
exactly
they need to go to the left here i think
this is wrong
no maybe not
can we get some creepers in the house so
we can test this out
uh or a skeleton skeleton
okay the skeleton's going the wrong way
let's switches
creepers are you going which way are you
going
i think i need to switch this for the
creepers too yeah okay there we go
so what is going on here
uh this is some terrible separation we
got mostly creepers in both tubes
but uh
why did that happen and they're really
glitching through the glass
like what's this guy doing
all right well we were trying to set
this up so even if
the wrong mob gets mixed in it should
still operate so hopefully it'll work
okay
so i think we got to manually operate
this
to start off with the idea is we need to
drop a skeleton
down which should be this tube here but
it's mostly creepers for some reason
this time
and then we drop a creeper down later
why is the skeleton dying
anyway we'll try this out
okay that should be a skeleton but it's
not
and he's just sitting there
okay let it creeper through
okay this is not working very well let's
try this again
i don't think it's gonna work unless we
get a skeleton it's the thing so this is
actually
good that the snowman's not shooting
because the snowman won't shoot at a
creeper
all right this should be a skeleton now
he did nothing why
why did he do nothing
and we're out of creepers okay this is a
terrible test i'll recalibrate
here wow okay so it's very
subtle i didn't pick up on it when it
first happened i thought an arrow
fell down uh while we were recording
that last
segment but after re-watching i think
that was a piece of string actually
from the tripwire down there
must have broke somehow i'm not sure
let's go inside
okay let's put this down
so we don't fall there's a there's one
piece here
yeah and there's one piece missing so a
tripwire broke right
here
from this piston maybe
does that make sense
we're doing a little bit of bug fixing
okay maybe that's what happened
that's connected if we put glass
underneath is it still
that's still working it worked the first
time then it broke
because that has to open up these ports
here so the snow golem can shoot at the
skeleton that's here
it opens up for like just over a second
not sure why it broke okay i'll get some
mobs lined up and we'll try it again
okay we got our first mobs coming and
i honestly have no no idea why that
tripwire broke
which has me worried it's going to
happen again
okay so when we set this automatically
set this up automatically we're going to
test if there's a skeleton there and a
creeper there and if there
is then it's going to run a clock that's
going to
make all this stuff happen only if
there's one in each side
because there's no point running this if
there's no skeleton or no creeper in the
equation
now don't break the tripwire
oh you were too slow too slow bro
he uh his snowball hit the glass it
looked like
and so this would still get triggered
maybe
oh he shot the creeper then the second
time
uh but nothing blew up that's good i
haven't made a backup in a while maybe i
should make a backup because i have a
feeling i'm gonna blow something up here
the tripwire is not breaking that's good
he got knocked onto the pressure plate
push back i don't have it wired where
the
redstone will make a creeper come up
it should work this time
no okay so skeleton didn't shoot the
creeper he needed more time
what was that was that an arrow let's
try again
oh i wasn't supposed to release the
creeper
[Applause]
i love working with with mob systems
it's so much fun
okay creeper will work this time no okay
there's a skeleton needs more time it
looks like
that's the flaw right now
oh man i think it worked i hear a
creeper sizzling down there i was
testing it some more
he's mad at one of the skeletons but he
can't reach him
and they're bouncing around
if you could just get close to the
skeleton long enough it's the one with
the chainmail there's a skeleton with
chainmail on
that he's mad at
all right that's cool
let's close that up
oh that was another one
yes yes it worked
that's two in a row that worked i wonder
why the first few didn't though
oh you missed bro
fail all right let's try it again
nice shot beautiful oh i wasn't supposed
to hold that
we got two creepers in looks like it was
a success
nice
this is gonna be so cool when it's
automatic
creeper he shot him
so it's working now i don't know why i
didn't work the first few times
are you not reaching him
he's mad at him you can't reach him
though
that was like slow anger his temper just
king
kept getting worse and worse and then he
had enough
all right well that's good it looks like
it's working pretty pretty decently
the next step of this is going to be to
get it to run automatically
and to do that might be a little more
tricky than i thought i'm looking at it
here
and i thought i was going to be able to
run the tripwires going
this way like if we had a block here
and tripwire on this and on both sides
that's not going to work because then
you need like a
you need the trip hook you need the
string and then another trip hook so
that's three blocks wide
and it's not going to be above the water
stream here we need to
check if they are in front of the trap
door basically
for both the skeleton and the creeper so
my new idea is to make it run this way
but this also is kind of challenging
because if the
if the trip hook is right above
didn't mean to do that it's right above
the door like right in that
spot there it's gonna power the door
directly so that doesn't work
so i've tried moving it back one uh
which seems like it would work okay
except
if we connect this string here
there's no clicking because it's not
working because this is a solid block
below
so if we get rid of that
uh trip door break or the trap door
breaks
um and that's no good but i think what
we can do
let's get a crafting table going here
is make stairs or something and i think
you can put a trapdoor on that
uh we won't be able to power the block
the trapdoors on
but we can power beside it
all right let's try this now
and we'll probably have to fix this
actually
okay can we put this on the stair yes we
can good
let's go down broke this let's put this
back
and now the fun part of trying to get
out of here
oh bullseye
all right
so is this going to work
we don't want it to power the trip the
trapdoor oh it's the trip door now
and it's clicking okay so it is powering
but it's not activating the trapdoor to
do
that we're gonna probably have to put a
block
next to it here and then we can power it
from the outside
either here or here
should work out okay
i just hopped in the water stream here i
was going to pretend that was a skeleton
to see how this worked
and i noticed another problem this trap
door is
not opening and closing really quick
it's staying open while we're here
because i missed this but
uh the block the trip hook is connected
to is right next to that redstone we
just laid after the
after the piston so that piston is doing
nothing
you gotta fix that
and that's fixed so what i've done is
i've made a branch off over here now
in the clock that goes back this is a
piston below that's the monostable
that goes to this block over here
um so no longer the redstones running
next to there
goes down to that piece of redstone dust
and we can hop in and test it out
interestingly
when we go through this we don't fall
through the trapdoor
we kind of glitch out like this uh
when a skeleton goes through though they
fall down
oh we fell down the second time maybe
it's too quick
[Music]
um we'll find out soon
well this is it this is going to be our
first automatic
test of the system let's hope it works i
have not made the backup
so let's hope nothing explodes too we
want the creepers to explode just in the
right place
uh so let's get over there quickly
quickly quickly
things are moving things are happening
uh there might there's
most likely going to be some timing
issues but let's see just
what happens here i think this is the
spot we want to be
we are waiting for
can i break that yeah skeleton and
creepers
come on we got the creepers there's a
zombie
in the skeleton
spots
that seems to be twitching too quickly
after all
we can fix that actually really easily
if we can get there we cannot get there
oh it's a nightmare working up here
uh we just need to extend the delay on
that one
mana stable we put in where is it
we're missing the show this one here
let's make it two ticks
that should do it let's get that down
okay we got skeleton uh
golem tried to shoot him but the glass
came up or he missed or something
oh is that gunpowder or is that redstone
i hope that was gunpowder
okay the system has stopped because we
are out of skeletons it's waiting
for one to come by even though we have
creepers
okay here we go we got some skeletons in
the creeper
let's see if this works let's go down
quickly
okay skeleton
and snow golem i don't know what you did
there but it wasn't it wasn't very good
for some reason the creeper didn't come
down
there he goes oh because he wasn't uh
i think it worked maybe not
did he see me when that piston came up
yeah the creeper only gets released when
the skeleton's shot that's right
and they're drowning because it's
getting backed up creeper you don't
belong there
get out of here
you got a skeleton you got shot that
should release a creeper
hopefully yeah they're not
fighting each other though when they get
released i might be
interfering with it we get one more
come on because i think he might be
seeing me
because this is open here i should cover
it actually
there when that piston comes up i think
he was
catching eyes of me and he changed his
his his desire to explode on me instead
of the skeleton
and we are out of creepers once again
come on
here comes the creeper only one
let's see what he does
what oh no he didn't get released it
looked like he did
i don't think he shot him
no hmm
the skeletons aren't shooting the
creepers i don't know why
let's move away a different angle i have
a feeling we might be interfering
somehow
because yeah i think that time he got
hit by the skeleton when we weren't
there
are they mad i think he's mad he's mad
he is so mad
that worked finally uh it's gonna need
some tweaking but i think we can get it
going
anymore
it doesn't seem to work too well when
we're up there though
anymore any more come on oh we got a
creeper in there
[Music]
i find it's very rare for for it to line
up where there's a skeleton
in one and a creep or another
unfortunately because they spawn in
spurts like there'll be a patch of
skeletons that patch the zombies
patch of creepers and i need a bigger
buffer here because a lot of times they
just drown
waiting for the proper guy to come
um this thing's giving me a lot more
trouble than i was expecting
oh whoa okay
i changed the timing on something that
did not work out too well
well i really thought we were going to
get this working today but
there's still a lot of bugs to it a lot
of timing issues
and a few other little issues i'm having
a problem now where
it seems like the skeletons are shooting
the creepers but the creepers aren't
detonating on the skeletons i don't know
why
i'm guessing it might be a timing issue
too
but uh yeah we'll work on another time
snow golem's dead i'm too lazy to
replace them
uh let's go let's go head out head back
to hmm what should we do now
uh i guess you know what let's head on
head on over to
the gold farm i'll show you the progress
that's been made
there i've totally built the frame and
everything for it i also want to get
some
more ender pearls i usually have a stash
around here
there we go it's running low though
i need to go farm some enderman soon so
yeah let's head on over to the gold farm
through the nether hub uh i've been
having some internet problems by the way
i don't know if you guys
follow me on twitter i i said
that my main internet line has gone down
which it has
and i do have a backup line but it's
it's only got like a point for upload on
it
it's really slow my main line is really
slow too that's that's
8.8.9 upload
but now with
the main line gone my upload speed has
been cut into like a third basically
so it's gonna be tough for me to get uh
episodes out until that's fixed it's it
they said it's gonna take a week just to
get out and check on
what's wrong so
hopefully it works out but uh
i don't know they've been doing road
construction around here i think they
might have cut a line accidentally but
i'm not sure what the problem is
but yeah here is the gold farm we have
all the frame
done so it's just waiting on pistons and
redstone
and string
i am so clumsy today
oh my goodness ah
today ain't my day
fell off the ladder i've never seen that
before
that must be a new death message uh i
don't think my stuff fell on the fire i
think it's okay
oh i hear a lot of guests out there i'm
scared they're gonna blow it up
oh my boots are so close to the fire
that's the main thing i want to get
back here those are good boots
got a pic shovel good i don't think we
really lost anything
had a lot of redstone on us too that
would have sucked to lose
and you are shooting at nothing i'm not
in your line of sight fool oh i am
i just didn't see you there
okay let's head back up if we can
probably a bad idea
and he took out the ladders great
i have backups yes
um so this thing the gold farm has a
total
of 1024 spawning spaces
so to get pistons and redstone to all of
this we're gonna need
1024 pistons which works out to
needing over 2 000 redstone because
each spot needs a piece of redstone plus
a piston takes
a piece of stone and we will need 1024
pieces of string for all the trip wires
as well
so got a little bit of resource grinding
to
go to this is what it's supposed to
look like by the way oh
i lived uh yeah like that
i did not think i walked that far off um
we're gonna we're gonna leave here
before i die again
um so i got
maybe a quarter of the redstone needed
for that a little over half the iron
needed
and like a quarter of the string so we
got a ways to go
before we can do this
let's head over to the man cave now
i've also done something here
all right through
so yeah just a little thing here i
kind of refined this spot it was just
grass before and
it looked to look pretty plain and
there's also torches and stuff there
which i've gotten rid of i'm really
happy with how the lighting turned out
for this
it's very well lit up but you can't see
any torches
because there are not any instead we got
these
these pumpkins one there one here
and one here i'm getting pretty good at
hiding lighting
i think i've i've learned a few tricks
especially working on my
ethel court building on minecraft i
learned a lot building that
just the way this is set up there's no
real angle
like you can see it if you're if you're
on the grass but you're not supposed to
ever go on the grass there's railings
and stuff to prevent that
so from up here you can't see it
can't see it from here really you can
catch a little bit of a glimpse i
suppose like just right there
see very corner of it but
otherwise from most angles it's not
possible to see it so that's cool
and what else what else i i raised this
arch one block because it was blocking
wilson's face
now you have a nice clear side of it
from from over here
because before
it was running down at this height and
when you're over here blocks
eyes
and i think that's i haven't done much
around here have i
um i haven't worked on the lab
what oh no i have sort of i've been
gathering the ingredients needed to
fill all of these so
yeah that's going to take a it's going
to take a ton of stuff each of these
that's still empty that's empty
got the carrots in there
uh with my setup here i sort of need to
fill all these before
we turn it on for the first time
otherwise we need to
find a way to disable these individually
which we probably should do
or work out a way of doing that
okay i might have spoken a little too
soon about the lighting because i forgot
about this angle here you can see it
but i never look i never looked down
from this angle
never and from here it
is pretty much fine so yeah
um there was something else i was going
to show you i totally forgot
i started making a path down here
because this wall has been been plain
and empty this wall i still need to do
too
but over here i decided i think we
should make it connect to this
this artificial river i built because
there's no real
good way of accessing it at the moment i
was gonna make
maybe a little path on the right here
expand it a little more if we can
if there's space while digging this out
i made a vine float too i thought that's
kind of cool
anyways let's get to our comments for
this episode
first one says i was wondering what is
your favorite map
of all time unsure territories
runes of the minecrackers etc i think i
think you means between ctm maps first
also what is your favorite map of all
time
all inclusive i hope you'll see this
keep up the good work and peace
favorite map of all time from ctm maps
that's a tough choice i think
objectively uncharted territories 2
is the best one i've played that's a
really good map but the one that
probably
left the best feeling or that i enjoyed
the most just because it was uh before
the adventure update was probably
legendary legendary
awesome map very very tough
especially when you're new to the game
and you don't have
natural regen it is brutal
um yeah canopy carnage also very cool
uh of all time though i haven't played
any adventure maps i don't
i don't think since i've been playing
minecraft believe it or not
haven't played a lot of maps and mostly
just ctm maps
i have played quite a few pvp maps
though too
and of those i would probably pick uh
nail nails a classic i've had a lot of
fun playing that
uh i also enjoy hudu and calamity and
revolution and there's a bunch of other
ones too
but nail nails like the the go-to map
um second comments
lol try losing power during hurricane
and for two weeks and one month
uh that's in with regards to my comment
last episode about how bad it is to lose
your your power for for a while
um yeah hurricanes they stink
because it usually goes out for at least
a week or two
i've been in hurricanes actually i was
in hurricane charlie
and power went out for i think a week or
so but i left the area
so i only had to endure like two days of
it it was pretty bad though
no air conditioning super hot had to
like sleep outside because the house was
so hot
um yeah yeah
and then hurricane ivan i almost was in
i got out
just in time i was like the airport was
shutting down and i got out before it
struck
and i heard the power went out for that
too and pretty much any hurricane power
goes out for quite a while
uh so yeah i would agree that stinks
anyway that's it guys hope you enjoyed
the episode i'll see you again next time
and i'll try try to keep up with the
uploads
hopefully the internet internet gets
fixed soon
it's like i'll wake up in the morning
and it's still uploading and it's like
ah
because it's it makes it so i can't do
anything hardly
can't play on minecraft or feed the
beast or really
watch videos or anything until the
upload's done so
lots of patient waiting but yeah
see you guys