Hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and we are back again guys with
another let's play episode so I ran over
to the zombie Pigman farm here as soon
as I updated I just updated to one point
14.3 I heard some rumors some people
were saying this was gonna be broken but
it looks like they got everything fixed
up so they made some big changes with
the zombie Pigman and AI but it's still
working all is good here the only thing
I noticed that's kind of weird if I go
down here and you look up you'll see
these guys are just falling off the
edges like non-stop they don't seem to
respect gravity anymore I made a little
bit of mistake here I didn't bring any
ender pearls which means guess what I
have to - this is it this is a big
problem with the lava creeper face thing
oh alright that works well sometimes
sometimes I miss thing I get stuck in
there when I do that oh yeah look at it
look at everybody the Beast the monster
the Yeti of all ice farms is ready to go
we're gonna test it out here today six
thousand three hundred blocks of ice per
harvest that's about over ninety eight
stacks of ice or 11 stacks of packed ice
or over a stack of blue ice per harvest
I think it's eight hundred and forty
Pistons dispensers and iron buckets in
each of those dispensers meticulously
filled with water and placed by yours
truly totaling over three thousand iron
ingots that was a weird noise or about
six stacks of iron blocks when is this
thing more clay than I can count and
redstone working harder so hard any
potato out there is gonna feel like a
couch potato that's how hard this
redstone is working yeah
right so it's it's not quite done it's
almost done we got to build one more
piece to this thing it's gonna be quick
though we need to add some way of
clipping all the ice together so it
funnels down each of these lanes falls
down this hole let's go down you see it
all combines to here that shouldn't be
there goes and it just ends right here
so we got to make some way of funneling
this up and putting in a chest or
something is the last step to this whole
process so we'll probably put like water
elevator here all right good stuff so
now whenever ice falls down one of these
holes it's all clicks together and it
ends up at the top of our water elevator
here well that actually really flies
doesn't it okay let's maybe put a
covering over this so it doesn't do that
because if it's got a little bit of
horizontal momentum it's gonna fly out
of there all right that'll stop that
from happening so one thing we're gonna
set up a chest array now to store this I
think we want to start knot right here
actually yeah I'm just gonna put down
five rows of chess like a so so with our
ice farm we're probably gonna be
harvesting ice at about 10 10 icebox per
second maybe even more than that which
is like way faster than a hopper can
keep up with so we need multiple hoppers
running and storing this ice all at once
otherwise it's gonna back up and
overflow and it'll just despawn on us so
I'm gonna try set up a chest array like
this it's a bunch of them together
nothing too fancy right oh that was a
bad place I did so good until the very
last one oh now I can't do it so it does
it not attach if it's facing that way
seems that way so it has to attach to
the side now that it's side facing it
will attach yeah Oh interesting still
getting used to that
it's very strange
so what we do we just set up hoppers
running all along here underneath so
that way like when this one fills up
it'll go to the next one that'll fill up
then the next one next one next one that
way five sets of hoppers will be running
at the same time and be able to keep up
with the rate we're getting nice and
I'll split into the chests you know
it'll fill up from the bottom first and
then fill its way up to the top chest in
each of the rows so all we got to do is
add one more block of water to this
right and it's good to go oh and I do
have water very good yeah and I guess
I'll just cover this all - all right
everybody well I think we're gonna do
our first harvest now that the the farm
is complete and hopefully working
flawlessly Oh sometimes on the start you
got to get a good rhythm going
good rim you know you need that rim all
right this is good so I think the pick
isn't gonna last the whole farm though
we're gonna run out of durability so
I'll just go until that happens but we
should be able to do most of it and
basically we just go along here there's
a spot there that doesn't freeze because
it's a different vial and we got little
pushers here so when we get to the end
it like launches us forward so we don't
have to walk forward and you saw some
Isis fell down the hole there so then we
go to the next one and the same thing as
long as you're like left clicking for a
while before you start moving I think it
it works okay I'm starting it a little
bit lag has me worried I think that ice
should be going into those chests like
that look good right we'll see if the
primary tanks anymore if it does we
probably have a problem somewhere
we'll try keep going here and they'll
just do one more row kind of together
here oh yeah look at that beautiful
transition there that was smooth
smooth boy yeah I think this is a last
row we can do with this pick it's well
maybe one more let's do one more this
might be the last row I can't tell
there's 15 in total we're very close to
finishing here that pick is running
mighty low oh oh I don't want it snap I
don't trust it
we're at 36 okay that's as far as I'm
coming yeah yeah okay let's see let's
see what kind of damage we did here
what's going on
oh this was the last one oh I shouldn't
have stepped on that wait a sec I'm
gonna block this so now I just made a
bunch of budget subject whoopsies
okay let's go let's go see what's
happening here so first question is that
was the last row yeah that was the last
row almost one pick is enough for the
whole thing is it frozen at the start
here not quite so we would have to wait
awhile for the next batch when we made
the farm the kind of the goal was to
have it all frozen at the start by the
time we got back there but it looks like
we got to wait probably 5 minutes or 10
minutes for this to finish freezing
close though it's very close this is
this backed up at all there's 5 hoppers
enough it looks like 5 hoppers isn't
enough soon assuming it went in here
even yeah it's going in excellent
oh yeah so these last two barely got
used even just a little bit of overflow
in there so it's mainly the first 3 so 3
hoppers is kind of enough oh man yeah
that actually worked really well I'm
very happy with that so it took about 7
minutes I just checked the video 7
minutes to do the full harvest all 15
rows which is not too bad and I guess a
lot of the ice was in these top 5 chests
so it fills up the top and the bottom at
the same time so if we take some ice
here put in this hopper here so half
goes into here half goes into the bottom
when the bottom fills up and the top
fills up it's gonna go into the two
middle ones at the same time so that
means the hoppers are kind of running at
the speed of 6 hoppers because they're
at
double efficient efficiency uh-huh-huh
anyways I've moved all the ice together
here just kind of get an idea of how
much we got and there's 50 or 95 stacks
plus 41 here and we didn't finish that
last row we left about three stacks
there and remember what I said there's
like 98 stacks in total so I think we're
very close to 100% efficiency with this
which is really cool I'm sure we lost a
couple blocks here and there but all in
all we got a pretty good nice firm and
then when we go to craft them what we'll
probably just do is get like that a
crafting table genius I know all right
now you have a crafting table we move it
kind of close here and like as these
chests fill up then I'll just bust them
and like stand here and do the craft so
one chest one double chest gives you how
much blue ice 4200 I'm having a little
bit of internet trouble today it's like
going on and off so you're gonna get a
CA a brief glimpse of me without the
mask on today I know I'm beautiful can't
I can't hide it anymore yeah so that's a
little strange it actually wouldn't let
me log on in offline mode which
surprised me like I can't play minecraft
if I don't have internet but it came on
briefly enough where I was able to get
on and then it went off but I'm still
logged in I just lost my skin I guess I
don't know it's kind of weird anyways we
got a bunch of levels here we're gonna
do some enchanting no protection three
is not good enough for us weeping edge
yeah yeah I think we'll go for a book
respiration three that's always a great
one yet I like it that's still the same
knock back - we can do better efficiency
for what about the boots I'm breaking
through yeah I'm gonna dress the pic so
with our new ice farm we're gonna want
to tried yet o multi shots got to get
that one we're gonna try get like four
or five extra picks there so that we
don't have to keep hitting back
oh just a falling for I'm distracted two
piercing three I'm on it
piercing four yeah I'll take it
protection for that could be good for
the helmet oh that's all I got
oh and we're out of levels now yeah like
I was saying there though we wanted to
try to get like five extra pics at our
ice farm with silk touch unbreaking 3
efficiency 5 and mending on if possible
that way we don't have to do a repair
after every harvest we might be able to
do like 5 harvests in a row and then
repair all five at once so I'm just
gonna combine some of these junky pics
we have and we got we don't have a lot
of mending books unfortunately I lost my
emeralds again in the world somewhere I
probably put them in a beacon base and I
don't know where so yeah that's all we
got so I wanted to try out the
grindstone a little bit more today as
well I haven't played around with that
much but I saved some of the gold swords
from the zombie Pigman farm and I'm
curious how much xp we will actually get
from disenchanting them oh gotta make
the stone slabs first oh there it is
okay make two of them I get I guess so
you can take the swords right now we got
four levels four and a half
put it in this enchants its Oh give us a
full level from one this only has
knocked back one on so it's like a
really low enchantment value and give us
like a third of a level there okay
interesting so you do get a decent
amount I want to give a lot this one's
got three on I'm assuming it matters
like the better than enchantment the
more XP you get right yeah another level
there smite four in other levels worth
about sharpness too so there's gonna be
less than a level yeah it is okay so the
quality of the enchantment affects how
much he actually get alright it's very
good very good so now we're gonna start
working on our village here some more
today yeah I just kidding Justine we're
actually gonna go work on
next today I made a joke about that last
episode and some of you seemed pretty
genuinely upset I didn't work on the
Nexus when I said I was going to like
it's no problem we can work on the Nexus
if that's what you guys really want
personally like I could be wrong about
this but I feel like you guys don't want
me to work on these old projects maybe
you actually do I don't know if to me I
try out to always do something new and
exciting for you guys and like working
on old projects like this just feels
kind of boring and I try to do them
off-camera like I got the ice farm done
today for example like I do I do some
stuff off camera alright but yeah this
has been incomplete for a long time so
maybe we can do a little bits here and
there yeah so the floor in the main room
here concrete powder just came out I was
pretty excited it looks horrible though
I got a little too excited I we're gonna
change that out with something a little
bit more easy on the eyes there's
supposed to be a room over here like
with a wall running along probably and
then for this side of the wall we're
gonna leave it as this glass we just set
up cuz I like I like to have this looks
I want to be able to see the wiring
because that's the most interesting part
of the Nexus right you look at it it's
like whoa that looks crazy so we want to
have that see-through but just having
the glass there makes it feel a little
bit more finished and we don't have to
worry about creepers like wandering out
and blowing up if they spawn in there or
something although I think it's pretty
much lit up I'm not sure though for the
main area here not super happy with how
this looks but it's I don't think we'll
change it I was kind of curious I think
we've tried this in the past and I
didn't like it but I'm gonna try it
again now that the textures have changed
and my viewpoint has probably changed a
bit too I feel like we need a border
along this path I think it looks kind of
try me the way it is is that what we do
no I tried a few different things here
we got some smooth stone it doesn't
quite fit it nether brick I do like
but I feel it's it's too dark and we
haven't used nether brick anywhere else
in this build so it kind of stands out a
bit too much we have used diorite in
quite a few places so we could use that
but I don't know if I actually like it
yeah I don't know that it's probably my
second choice so I think we're gonna go
with just this here I think that's fine
because we have like light courts a
bright block here dark blotch here I
kind of want something in between to
transition between you know and if you
look from a distance it kind of changes
your view maybe of what they look like
like I I did like the nether brick up
close but from a distance I think it
would look pretty bad uh-huh well we
ended up going with something totally
different here but still pretty close to
what we had originally we still got the
prismarine but a different color in the
middle and just put glass over top of it
this is kind of like a cool tricky in do
generally whenever you make a path like
this it looks pretty good because it
creates lots of shadows and stuff having
the the middle lowered by a block and
the glass allows it to feel like it's
flat ground still though which is which
is cool without the glass here like the
color difference is a lot more extreme
as well like this is quite a bit
brighter than this right but when you
put the glass over top
it sort of mellows it it up Nell's out
the look a little bit and it's pretty
easy on the eyes I think so I'm happy
with that I ended up doing that in the
main room as well just to keep the the
theme and I wasn't really sure what to
do okay so to finish the Nexus what do
we have to do guys what is all involved
well we have to build like some kind of
finished looking front to this thing
that needs to be done we got to build
these side rooms that are supposed to be
here
some staircase to go up and down and I
just noticed like we never did add the
second there's like no roof on the
second floor I think I ran out of quartz
and I didn't want to get more at that at
that time I was tired
on this so I never just never finished
it right and then at the back part here
it's like I got a connection tunnel to
the two sides but that's that's where it
ends
so we might want to build some walls and
stuff here to finish it off
maybe block this all off so you can't
see this or we could just put an end on
both of the tunnels here would be fine
too probably and not even worry about
that area yeah like just you know what I
mean like build a wall here and just
like forget about all this extra stuff
because that has no purpose it's
probably smarter to do that the only
purpose of this is to connect the two
sides together
yeah b7 okay okay let's do this
b7 it's so slow this is why we can't we
can't show it in the episodes of guys
it's embarrassing okay if I made an X's
nowadays oh I would do it so much better
I tell you what guys I don't know what I
would do but it would be so much better
alright alright well we spent a fair bit
of time on this we got a lot of it done
but unfortunately there's still no
ceiling ran out of quartz locks what
else is new right oh my goodness so
that's probably as far as we're gonna
get on this today but that's about what
it looks like on the other side as well
ooh yeah this is the other tunnel yeah
gotta do a little bit of mining up here
too to finish it off but there was one
other little project I wanted to do
today something I keep putting off but
we desperately need bamboo you know we
got this bamboo a few episodes ago and
still haven't done anything with it I
don't have any scaffolding I've got a
lot of comments about that's like oh
those still pillar enough with the logs
and whatever yeah I don't have I don't
have the scaffolding so we're gonna make
a farm just a little simple one one
thing you will notice it grows quite
tall and I think this is all fully grown
and some of its taller than others so I
think the height is random as well and
you can break it with pistons so that's
probably the way we'll we'll do it cool
all right well I figured we would start
building one of these firms at slab city
we might build several of them but we'll
put one here for sure because we haven't
been here in a long time
and it's gonna be like a squarish firm
this is a square city alright it kind of
works out and also there's a lot of
heights and stuff here so it would be
nice to have a source of scaffolding at
this actual city I
so that's what we'll do I'm gonna put it
over here just a seven wide one and I
may eventually end up making a huge one
of these as well I'm not sure we don't
need anything crazy just yet though
because you can't make bamboo farms for
sticks and maybe we'll want to hook that
up to our super smelter or something
but I don't know there might be better
things to do yet so what is this seven
wide right three four five six well um
oh I think it's supposed to go this way
actually interesting yeah this is the
other pillar okay so now it's seven wide
so we'll hollow this out this is where
we're gonna put the bamboo probably dig
a hole it's gonna be hard to visualize
this until it's actually done but we're
gonna have a hole here where we're gonna
put the bamboo down and it'll grow up
until we can see it here and it'll look
kind of cool right
we'll have glass in front like at this
level here and some sort of piston
harvesting device down here as well okay
so we're gonna have dirt bamboo pistons
border yes
that's gonna work okay that's the height
we're gonna go for here by the way not
depressed just morning voice this is the
next day and yeah my Internet's working
again woohoo got my skin back on and
everything was able to login
we're gonna have some whatcha McCall
it's sticky blocks what are they called
slime blocks yeah at this level here
which means they're gonna stick to
everything that's what we're gonna push
to harvest the bamboo but in order to
make them not stick to everything we
have to put terracotta or something non
movable by them so that's what's going
at this level oh yeah I guess we'll have
to put them underneath and above as well
right so their eyes they'll stick
okay now that should be fine we're only
gonna have to use one piston to move the
whole slime block arm thing here and
we'll just put that over here and then
basically we put a observer up higher
and connect that to the piston so when
it grows to a certain height then it'll
do a harvest so bamboo can grow twelve
to sixteen blocks tall one two three
four five six seven eight
we got the observer at the eighth block
here as long as it's at the minimum of
twelve we'll be fine
so we could go even for blocks higher if
we wanted with us but it'll be it'll be
fine over there I think and then we got
the piston right over there we just run
a redstone up to this and oh we gotta go
one more up right yeah let's put it over
here so now the observer will power this
line power the piston actually we need a
repeater in there don't we otherwise the
slime blocks are gonna get stuck out oh
did that do nothing hmm I'm good at this
game guys trust me all right yeah I
think we need a repeater okay I got the
repeater up there but that wasn't the
problem I figured it out though we're
gonna set this one to two that way when
the piston extends it doesn't leave the
slime blocks like where the bamboo is
that it'll pull it back but you know
what the issue is we need terracotta
behind here as well it's sticking to the
stone ah man okay easy fix
not a big deal let's pretend that never
happened
okay now we put this back now it
shouldn't be able to stick to anything
right we got it all taken care of okay
it's kind of weird they like grow random
distances apart from each other like I
can't fit between these two it won't let
me fall down but I can fit between
these two here yeah so I pulled it back
so if we left this at one tick bambam
I think the slime blocks would get left
behind yeah you see they would do this
instead so that's why you need the
repeater okay so now we got it so that
when this grows up place that there yeah
it'll grow up to the observer and that
makes the slime blocks go out and break
all the bamboos right the odd piece will
land on top of the bamboo but I think
most of it should land on the dirt and
then we need some way of collecting it
right so what we'll do from this wire
that we're using for the piston right we
will just trail it down to here and then
we'll set up a minecart
hopper to run underneath the dirt to
pick up everything up basically so and
then we got to put in a chest somewhere
too which I haven't figure out where
we're doing that just yet
might save that for another episode if
we can't finish this today yeah uh too
big of a project no I'm actually running
really low on time here this episode
supposed to be up right now and I
haven't haven't posted it yet so I might
not finish this today let's see what are
we doing here this stuff isn't powered
either did I bring the levers those are
tripwire hooks not leavers oh man I
thought I had it all planned out guys I
thought I I was doing good yeah we don't
have any leavers okay I'm gonna use a
redstone torch usually I keep leavers in
my redstone chests I don't know what
happened to him
okay something like this so those power
rails are powered put the hopper
minecart over there so now whenever that
extends it's gonna make that my cart go
and pick up all the bamboo that's on the
dirt let's test that out just trigger
this oh I didn't hear it go
they moved a little bit right oh we need
a longer pulse that's the problem
yeah okay um well it's not a big deal if
we just extend this right go to four and
let's try that again
yeah now I think it went okay let's try
one more time make sure that's not
messed up yeah here it go cool so that
I'll pick up everything there and then
we just got dropped off at chess
somewhere but that's probably as far as
we'll get with this so we need a wall
here and then we need glass here going
all the way up huh this place is really
dangerous now what's going on usually
there's like one or two mobs here the
lighting is not quite perfect but man
there's like there's like ten today what
happened look at them all there's a
creeper creeper skeleton sounds like
there's a bunch of below anyways we're
gonna finish up for today's episode with
the comment of the day as we usually do
this one says etho have you ever thought
of making another modded pack I know you
currently have other series going on but
would love to see a building slash
technical modded series I love your
content especially your LP series keep
up the good work
why thank you James I really appreciate
it funny funny I saw a comment on this
actually because recently one of the
reasons why I didn't post terraformer
Punk for a long time is because I was
like sneakily trying to phase it out and
I was either gonna start project though
zone 3 or I've been really dreaming
about making a new modded single-player
like a season 2 of that I loaded up my
original season not too long ago and was
like oh I want to play this I want to
play this so bad just start up the
season again you know but it was really
laggy so I kind of I kind of feel like
we should start a new fresh season with
up-to-date mods and
because that old one was a 1.7.10 and it
would be cool to do a new one and to see
how that goes but after like a couple
weeks I started getting tons of comments
for the terraformer Punk series so I
figured we should dip back and just
finish that up and we'll do another
modded one later when we have time yeah
I I do enjoy the Terra Firma Punk series
this is hard to record because not a lot
of interesting stuff happens in it
generally so it's hard to fill up an
episode when like nothing happens is
this the nature of it but it's it's a
fun series I do enjoy it as well
anyways that's gonna do it for today
guys hope you enjoyed it thanks for
watching until next time take care have
a wonderful day bye bye