[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
guys
to another episode of our let's play
series how you doing today
uh it is feeding time feeding time for
the cows feeding time for me
first we feed the cows and then we eat
the cows
um
all right so we got some food again guys
uh i definitely
go through a lot of food now like since
the lighter wings came out probably two
three stacks of steak every episode
if i was to guess because flying takes a
lot out of you
you shoot yourself with the arrows and
that causes food to be lost
and then to heal up the damage from that
as well also causes food to be lost now
so
losing food all over the place it's
crazy
uh but yeah today guys is the minecart
special episode so what i want to do
is do a little bit of experimenting a
little bit of research we're going to
get some mine cart stuff together here
and just goof around with a few ideas
all right guys so lately in our modded
minecraft series we've been playing a
lot with the railcraft mod
and the railcraft mod allows you to do
some pretty cool pretty advanced
minecart things there's like
uh minecart switching
so you can tell where a minecart is on a
track and prevent another minecart from
colliding with it real easy with that
there's minecart routing so you can tell
a minecart
where to go really easily like if it
when it gets to a junction it knows
which way to take
based on its destination tickets and
there's just a lot of other really
useful things like holding tracks
and other gizmos like that so it got me
thinking here
what is preventing us from doing that
kind of stuff in vanilla minecraft what
is the limiter
uh are we able to do more advanced
minecart stuff
in this and i kind of think we are
we're gonna check it out here today
there are of course a lot of problems
though
and i'll demonstrate the first one here
so if we go to
f3q f3q brings up this list of all the
other f3
things you can do so we're gonna do f3g
show bunk bunk chunk
show the chunk boundaries here so we can
see it very clearly
uh one big problem minecarts have is
when chunks unload
so let's say this chunk unloads here
uh and this one's still loaded a
minecart can then go from this chunk
into this one since this one's unloaded
the minecart gets
uh saved into memory on your hard drive
and it's gonna end up around here
meanwhile those other minecarts can
can approach here and they all kind of
merge together
and join up i'll try to demonstrate that
i'm going to leave this area and come
back
and we'll just see what the spacing is
like on those minecarts it's not going
to be the same it's going to get
all bundled up probably
so we're back here now and
mine carts are going the wrong way
they're bouncing all over the place
so once you have the chunks unload
bad stuff can happen and it can make it
almost impossible to make
uh advanced minecart systems because you
don't know what the mine carts are doing
and you can't control them when they're
all joined together like this so
yeah first thing we got to figure out is
some way of preventing this from
happening
yeah and basically it's the same deal
over here if we have a straight section
of track like this
let's say we send five mine carts going
this way
and this chunk over here is unloaded
well then they're gonna all merge
together
when this chunk reloads there some of
them are probably gonna go backwards
some of them
are gonna be stuck together if we have
any junctions down the line and they're
probably not going to work properly
because the mine carts will be
too close together and that sort of
problem
so yeah the plan is to build smart
tracks
i have an idea for regulating the flow
of mine carts here on a single piece of
track
and it basically stems with this idea
here
set up these little junctions and little
holding areas
every section of tracked every chunk
here so we would do another one over
here
like so and
here let's get this powered again i'll
just show you show you the concept
so let's say yeah let's say we send a
minecart down here it's going to go
straight
because the track is pointing that way
it's going to get that little wobble as
it goes by that but it's
it's not going to affect the minecart
really
what we want to do is make set a rule so
only one mine cart per
chunk here so when a minecart enters
this chunk
we then want to switch his junction
so it goes into this holding area this
little holding area
so now if another minecart comes by
while there's a minecart over here in
this area
then it's going to wait
and then once that mine cart is out of
this chunk into the next one over here
then we want to release this one waiting
and that'll prevent them from bunching
up together so this would flip
and then this one would get set free
like so and same kind of thing thing's
going to repeat itself
um so what we got to do then
is probably set up some sort of detector
rail over here
like at the very end of the chunk here
the end of this section
when the minecart goes over the detector
rail it's going to then
uh switch this and release the minecart
here
and yeah i think that's the concept
this is like solving a puzzle i got to
figure out how to do this exactly it's
going to be a bit complicated probably
okay so i set up a little thing here to
test out we got an rs nor latch at the
junction now
uh basically when the minecart goes over
this detector rail
it's gonna push the redstone block over
it's gonna power
the junction uh that'll cause any other
minecarts that come
right after the previous one to go to
the right here
into the holding area and then when it
gets to the other detector rail
way down at the other section here it's
going to send power back
uh over to the minecart release and also
to
this piston goes underneath here that
will push the redstone
block back and it should allow more
minecarts to then
pass by here so let's try it out with
one minecarts
first off you see how it switched and
now it switched back
okay so that's all good uh let's get rid
of this one minecart we'll send to this
this next time that's the real test it
should hold one of them until the other
one
passes by the chunk and with this setup
we should never have three mine carts
trying to to pass a certain chunk at a
time
yeah so it make sure it holds it until
it's free to go
aha very cool so this is great it seems
to do what i wanted to do
but now it is time for the real
challenge guys the big contender over
here
over here yeah so i've taken this and
now i set up a loop
of this smart track so it goes around
like so
and we're gonna see if it can handle the
minecarts now if it
it prevents them from colliding because
that's what it's supposed to do
when we leave the area here so as it is
right now
we just have one minecart on it kind of
does this
you see all the junctions getting
switched whenever these
redstone blocks move it's a real mess
right now it doesn't look good
but i'm just trying to make sure it
works before i refine it i guess
all right so let's get our chunk view
going so you can see what's happening
here there's three chunks total so
there's this one
this one and this one that it goes into
and there's four of these junctions in
total
uh one on each end and then in the
middle straightaway section
there's two over here and
over here all right so for total
that means i think you can handle three
mine carts at the most
but if you have a longer track it'll
handle more
we get these going hopefully
you see that one was waiting there oh
that one snuck in though
uh oh oh
works perfect all right there might be
something special we got to do to add
the minecarts
let me try that again okay i think that
messed up because i'm not using
monostable circuits anywhere
with this so this junction is not
switching fast enough i could add them
and
this would get a little bit more complex
but just for right now
uh let's just see if it works when it is
working
so i'll have to be careful not to load
them too fast
they have to clear a section before i
add another one
but that the big test here is that it
doesn't break when we
unload these chunks okay oh that one got
stuck
wait what's happening why is it going
over there
now whatever all right so i'm gonna try
get out of here um
and see if i can do anything to break
looks good
no
no darn
you know i left the area and came back
like 10 times i thought it was going to
be good
it wasn't having any problems but this
time
it messed up
okay good news i think i got it fixed
here uh those monostable circuits i
talked about are actually really
important
so look at this piston here you notice
how fast the arm goes out and
and back in it's like real quick now
uh before it was going out for about a
second and then
retracting but you'll notice how quick
the block gets pushed back afterwards it
wasn't able to push his block
back uh when it goes over this detector
rail
previously but now it is able to so that
should fix it i'm gonna again do the
same thing
fly away and come back oh and i fell
down the hole
the stupid hole this is the hole i felt
out when i killed that dragon
like back in episode 150 and lost all
the experience
looks good all right let's try it a few
more times
oh they're all stopped
no why did they all stop
darn oh
this is like a detective riddle you know
trying to figure out why did it break
why did it not work
because you can't see it not working you
have to like figure it out afterwards
but yeah there's no minecart over there
so this one should have been free to go
and you can see the junctions actually
switched uh the problem is it did not re
it did not move when the power rail was
lit up
so this chunk was unloaded and if a
minecart's in an unloaded chunk
um the redstone stuff can happen but the
entity stuff
doesn't happen unless you load a big
area which we're not doing here
so yeah the power rail turned on
but then the mine carts didn't unload
chunk so it didn't move
and it got stuck here um long story
short we
can't send the power rail uh a pulse
like i'm doing here
instead we're going to rip this stuff
out
we need to connect the power rail
directly to our snore latch here so when
the block the redstone block is over
here
that power rail should be lit and when
it's over here it shouldn't be
okay so back to testing here again you
see how the redstone block directly
powers the power rail now
if the redstone block is over there this
is powered for sure
and if this doesn't work i don't know
what's going to work
all right let's get out of here i'm
again i'm going to fly back and forth
unload the chunks and reload them and
just see
if i can get it to mess up hopefully not
because i don't know what to do if this
doesn't work
ah
go well i hate to say it guys but i
think i'm going to give up
on this i don't do that often but
honestly i don't know what the problem
is and
it all looks good to me maybe you guys
can figure it out i don't know
uh i felt like i was very close with
that but
just not working don't know what to do
at the very least though i'm going to do
something like this with my minecart
tracks this will
prevent minecarts from flowing backwards
becoming a problem
at the very least because if they try to
they'll just
do that and bounce back and keep going
straight like they should
uh this will not prevent minecarts from
merging together though
which may or may not be important i'm
not sure yet
like that was supposed to prevent
anyways we're going to move on to
something a little bit more fun
hopefully
because that was getting frustrating uh
the idea of
minecart routing so the idea is when a
minecart gets to a junction like this
uh it should know whether or not to
switch the junction automatically
it's sort of like the minecarts
intelligence and we do that using
tickets
like you do in railcraft so
let's see do i have any hoppers yes i do
okay so here's something cool whenever a
minecart passes by a hopper like this it
picks up exactly one item
uh if it's if it's going at full speed
anyway or it should
all right so that should grab one piece
of paper yeah
and likewise when it uh goes over a
minecart it'll drop off
one item exactly you see where i'm
getting with this
so we can give minecarts tickets uh like
this
and we can receive them using items
orders
and on these tickets or random pieces of
whatever
we can give them a destination string
using an anvil
let's say this is destination number one
then when it gets to a junction that
that matches this it'll cause it to
switch
all right let me try set that up okay
guys
so this is uh pretty cool from what i've
seen so far
we have a little test track to try out
the cart routing here
so one of these things is a ticket
receiver
and basically it's just an item filter
so what you do is put some garbage items
in here
i made two two switches actually so we
have destination one
and two we'll put number two in here
all right and while uh there's more than
papers in there the signal goes three
blocks
which then goes to this wire up to the
junction like so
um let's grab the extras out of here
all right so yeah if there's there's
more than 41 in there
then then it goes through all right so
we have one junction right here and then
there's another one i set up right over
here
okay so we'll call this one destination
one
put the junk items in put 40
41 items in here 41 tickets all right
and there's three final destinations
here so there's one over here
one over here and one over here
depending on which tidgets we put in our
mine cart will determine where it ends
up
in our little sample track here so if we
put this here with no minecraft or no
tickets in the system
it's going to end up right over here
every time
all right if we do destination one
let's try that out
so destination one i think we'll get
past this first junction i'll go to the
left now
uh and then it goes right over there so
if we give it destination one
and destination two then it should end
up over here i'm pretty sure
all right let's try that out
destination one and two so both ticket
things are are loaded now
i'm gonna have a lot of fun playing with
this i think i want to set up some big
fancy
cart network eventually yeah so it
should have got both tickets this time
oh it didn't work though
maybe my timings aren't quite right i
thought that would have been good
there's 22 in each of these oh i didn't
grab this one
let's move this oh because the detector
rail here
okay you can tell i didn't test this out
yet exactly
let's move that over here a little bit
of a mistake there because it's
receiving power
from that so it couldn't uh the hopper
wasn't putting any items out actually
okay let's try it again oh we got one
made here
okay so i should grab both tickets
and this time go over there nice
that is really neat so yeah whenever we
need to take a junction
we can we can tell it to do that um
depending on which tickets we give it so
another cool thing you can do let's say
we want a storage minecart to drop off
some items somewhere
um i just set up a little thing here to
sort of demonstrate that let's say
it needs to pick up some grass blocks
and deliver them over there
so we would give it the two tickets
those tickets will fill up the first two
slots of the mine carts
and then the remaining slots can hold
items right so they're
gonna go there and as it passes by those
hoppers it'll take this one out then
this one and it'll just leave the grass
blocks
remaining and any other items won't be
taken out of here
oh it's nighttime i gotta sleep here
pretty soon so like if we put redstone
blocks in there
they're not going to go into this filter
it's only going to pick up
the tickets out of there
all right then if we send this away
it goes to the left and then should end
up there with just the grass blocks
inside
it's pretty cool it didn't grab all of
them there's still a few in there but
yeah
all right guys well unfortunately i got
to get going here for today
uh that first idea didn't work out might
be able to get to work
but the item or the cart routing i'm
really excited about i think there's a
lot of potential with that
and it was surprisingly easy and quick
to set up so
definitely want to use that but let's
get to the comments
of today it says ethos lab what enchants
are used on the flying circus bow
that i use for flights i have unbreaking
3 punch 2 infinity and
mending also very important is to get
unbreaking three and mending on your
armor
and protection for if you can otherwise
uh your stuff breaks very quickly
and you need a good xp system to keep
everything
from breaking what i want to try out
here i'm curious now that i know how to
fly if you can actually fly with a punch
one bow
this has power too which is not ideal
but should be
good enough to try it out anyway right
so here we go
i don't know if it has enough kick to to
get
altitude
would help if i could actually hit
myself
very slowly losing altitude i can't gain
the speed
yeah i think you need to punch two bow i
got a little bit of height there
might be barely possible
but definitely not easy yeah i
definitely recommend a punch two bow
second question here it says eso are you
going to play starbound again now that
is officially released
starbound is out guys if you didn't know
like out of alpha
it would be interesting to see your
opinion of the game now compared to
early access
so i played starbound when it first came
out
and they were doing constant character
resets there's a lot of stuff
missing from the game it felt pretty
plain but since then i have played it
off camera just for fun
and i was very impressed but kind of ran
out of time and
was only to play able to play like three
hours and then
like was never able to return to it i do
want to play it again
uh i wanted to see what you guys have to
say though do you think if
you would be interested in watching it
if not i'll just play it off camera
whenever i find some time uh
yeah definitely definitely want to try
it out
off camera might make a series on it i
almost
almost started recording it the other
day but i
thought i would see what you guys have
to say about it first
all right hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode
thank you for watching until next time
take care
bye bye
[Music]
you