hello welcome back to everybody this is
etho so pretty sure that's actually a
bug that noise because I just had it
play three times in a row I don't think
I'm the only one like three times in a
row let it finish playing and it
happened again finished playing happen
again
three times within like 20 30 seconds
and it just happened again so either
there's something really weird going on
with my Dame and I'm the only one
affected but I think everybody's being
affected by that in the snapshots that
noise I'm talking about of course so
anyway enough blabbing last time we
worked on this boat target game I wanted
to get that done today so we could try
it out
but this boat target game um yeah it's
not going to happen
bye-bye ah could just eat four more
blocks don't there goes that arrow it
almost cleared the whole thing with that
yeah so it turns out I went into
creative for a moment to see how
difficult it is to actually hit a
falling boats with a bow and arrow and
it's pretty difficult but not too
difficult I think it was actually about
right it falls pretty quickly um the big
problem though quite cheap let's say you
got a boat over there um so to hit it
you would shoot about there right but
there's a bug in the game I don't know
if it's a snapshot bug eye or what but
the boat is visually below where it
appears to be as it's falling so in
order to hit a boat that appears to be
at that height I would have to shoot
like over here
is what I found out so that's not going
to work out too well yeah as it's
falling only not when it's stationary of
course so instead we're going to do a
chicken target shooting game I still
want to do a target game so I started
setting that up at the Mantid let's go
check it out okay so I decided to put it
over in this area where we have the vine
farm I want to expand out further this
way as as we build more things well this
is one of the places I want to build so
I don't have a lot set up to it and we
won't be able to do much we're going to
do other things today but I just want to
show you what I did
we're going to have dispensers these
will be full of chicken eggs and I got
an egg delivery system up here we got
hoppers and then a chain of hoppers
going this way and there's gonna be a
big buffer of chicken eggs in these
chests and these are our chickens so the
reason I didn't want to do a chicken
target game is because it's gonna take
forever to get the eggs to actually try
this out um so that's why we can't do it
today it's going to take hours and hours
to get enough eggs but those chickens
will grow up and they'll start laying
eggs
chickens are pretty easy to shoot as
they're falling actually so we don't
need a lot of vertical height I don't
think and I did in this area where I can
actually back up quite a bit because
they're going to be falling along that
wall there so to make it more difficult
there's not going to be much vertical
height to shoot them in and also I can
back up quite a ways if I wanted it to
be more difficult to hit them with the
bow and arrow so that'll be good and you
know I actually do need a chicken farm I
don't have one in my world yet so I
think we're gonna also get some way of
harvesting chickens out of this do maybe
we'll build something over here later
to get feathers is what I mostly need
from those guys so yeah that's what we
got so far so what I want to do next
everyone we're going to expand part of
the Manta here we're going to build
builds we're going to create we're going
to destroy a room over here a long time
ago I talked about an idea I had of
storing my valuable stuff inside of a
cave instead of like a chest like I
don't know if many of you have played
Donkey Kong Country it's it's an older
game now 1996 I believe at the very
first level of that game though there's
this cave you can go into and it's like
this giant cave where they keep all
their golden bananas they have a pile of
them of their hundred golden bananas and
it's it's been stolen and you get it
back later in the game spoiler alert I
basically want to make a pile of my my
ores here like a pile of emeralds and
iron and gold and diamonds and all that
stuff instead of keeping it in this
chest that you can visually see how much
stuff I got playing my world here so
yeah we're basically just making a giant
cave where is that and I'm lost my own
place here over here um and I scouted
around a bit this is the slime farm over
here apparently as usual there is so
much junk around underground I have to
be very careful where I dig out so we
can't go that way we're going to have to
make the entrance to it like something
like this going this way and then we hit
something else here this is from the
mushroom farm
so we'll try make it come up two or
three blocks so we avoid that we might
accidentally destroy it here though I'm
not too sure what's going to happen
hopefully
things go okay though um yeah that did
not come as far down as I thought it
would I guess that's good all right so
we might need a few more TNT here but we
got our cave our room did it we didn't
destroy anything I am surprised there's
a cave here oh okay this is by the river
this got closed off I guess yes I think
this dead ends if I remember right yeah
so I must have blocked that off before
now we've opened up to it again um yeah
that's cool we didn't we didn't destroy
anything I built so that's good I just
we got to go down like three or four
more blocks here yet though okay we're
going to take a quick break here because
our nose-picker
is about to break it's about to pick its
last if we don't do something so I
wanted to see diamonds three diamonds
five levels doesn't quite repair it all
the way or if we do it this way brand
new pick it is four levels and it
repairs it all the way so that's the way
to go okay I don't manage everybody I
just realized that was last the my TNT I
am running low
it seems I've looked both bases over
here ends at the man cave I might have
some hidden somewhere but I don't know
where but thankfully I do have some
gunpowder left so we can make some more
but this is it this is the last of my
gunpowder - what's over here so I'm
going to have to start collecting more I
haven't spent as much time at the
stronghold base as I used to so I think
that's why I'm running low let's see how
much can we make one two three four make
three stacks so that that should last
for quite a while
now there we go
so I noticed something weird the latest
snapshot it seems silver fish are
spawning in my silver fish farm even
when the lights are on and they where'd
he go see down here they can't swim it
seems they just drown in water and they
can fight the current you see that guy
over there uh-huh so there's been some
changes with mob behavior I noticed
creepers are acting weird too earlier so
who knows what's about to come with with
the next update with the AI changes yeah
here's another example so I think
they're trying to make creepers and
skeletons and that more intelligent like
the zombies are um so currently it seems
they're really dumb though but they're
probably it's probably a work in
progress this creeper hello guy I am
surrounded by TNT this is your perfect
opportunity to come kill me unless he is
more intelligent and he just doesn't
want to take damage oh hey guy and I'm
out of here
oh you didn't even set them off come on
guy I should have thought about leaving
ah how difficult is it to make tea to go
off that's gonna fly at me beautiful
all right ah we still need a little bit
more
we're almost there though let's see just
get a few more down I'll dig the rest
out by hand
run oh that oh there's one right by me
oh man if that went off this one here
that could have been bad that would have
made me sad
still launches you forward sometimes
very interesting lots of floaty arrows
too lately all right so we're getting
close to the mushroom room down there
I'm going to dig the rest out I believe
and I'm just outside of my haste beat in
unfortunately where is that okay we got
it over here I have a I don't think I
said this on video but I set up a hate
speech in now - so I got speed - in
haste - in in this area but we need more
beacons very badly
because I would love I would love that
haste over here for example yeah I love
that sound mmm I've changed my mind
let's do more why not we have three
stacks outlaw we had um hey guy we
thanks for helping uh yeah I could I
could probably do it love that sound
okay I don't think there's anything back
there
oh snap that was close that hit the
wiring it might have hit the wiring I
can't remember what that looked like
did not go as far down as I wanted
either darn it okay that's that's not
bad though all right so we got a
nice-sized room blown out here I like it
might need to be bigger we will see how
this goes
I've gotta do a lot of polishing of the
walls and and such but I figure we
should start decorating it try to figure
out what style we want to go with for
this room unfortunately I checked around
the whole thing is desert biome Oh such
a tragedy so that means if we did a
grass and like tree theme like I have in
the rest of the cave it's gonna be
yellow it I don't like yellow grass
vines will be yellow oh that really
stinks I wish it was forest biome I
really like grass and forest biome maybe
even more than jungle to some extent
it's more it goes better with brown I
find then the jungle grass jungle grass
is more green though so on its own it
looks better for sure but anyway so I
thought I got so much coal I don't I
don't know if I really want to make a
coal pile but maybe we will do the floor
out of coal and see what that looks like
so let's let's get it going out that
will make the room very dark and that
will make the the gems and that really
stand out if we do it this way the other
idea is like if we want to do paths we
could use slime blocks to get green in
here maybe I don't know how does this
look over gold stone that might be cool
and I don't want to put everything on
one big pile
think we'll split it up the gold should
probably go in the middle though like
we'll have a big pile of gold in the
middle that's what I'm going to get the
most of I suspect but then we'll hide
like some up there there's a tape over
there we'll hide some you know kind of
spread it out try to make it look cool
okay get this going so if we do want a
path actually I just would have to start
about here because it comes up we're
going to have stairs I should be careful
not to lose this cold though it is
valuable to some extent
I wonder how annoying it would be to
have a slime bath mmm
like made it go around the gold pile in
the middle it looks pretty weird I'm not
sure about this I've never like built
with slime blocks before it's so bouncy
I'm not sure if we should do that maybe
we should use something else for the
floor and we'll decorate walls with it
or something instead that could get
annoying to walk on all right anyway
let's let's get the coal going there's
that sound again about the hundreds of
time I've heard it today today got the
coal and I'm gonna get my gold and just
see what it looks like so I'm guessing I
want the pile like right here be the
center so I'm going to go get the gold
we'll put it down yeah so let me know
what you guys think about using coal for
the floor if you like it we may even use
it for the walls and the ceiling I have
I have enough we can do it if we want I
have probably a double chest of coal
blocks at least because I've always used
the
blaze rods pretty much for my smelting
haven't used my coal for anything really
except torches um if we if we do make
the whole room black we will have
glowstone piles for lighting and like
we'll probably have it like running down
the walls we might try to a stalagmites
and slide tight thing with like slime
blocks or other other ores so it won't
be totally black everywhere but it would
just be like the background color if if
we do coal otherwise I'll just keep my
coal in a chest because I don't want to
make a pile out of it um but I got the
gold
let's start our gold pile see what it
looks like try to do a pretty random as
I as I make a perfect square maybe have
a few piles and places I don't know
can't really blocks the door I should I
should be careful about that but yeah
let's try me a big pile in the middle oh
yeah
we're going to get lots more in the
future yeah alright so let's try even it
out a bit got to really watch for
creepers I tried to light this room up I
would be sad if this got blown up I
don't really care about the coal or the
diamonds or anything but gold and iron
kind of a big deal
lapis I have lots of lapis I'm
considering not putting it in here but
we will see we probably should actually
because it's it's sort of valuable and
it's kind of fill up the room pretty
quick here just with what I had not even
counting what I'm going to get in the
future alright pretty good looking pile
what's that look like so far
that's not bad it's a little too
vertical I think it should be wider at
the base that's fine all right so that's
our gold pile and as I use it up I'll
take away from the pile if I get more
I'll add to it sort of thing um let's
take a look again yeah cool okay then so
you know all that stuff I said about the
coal how we might do it and and do this
and do that
forget about it we're not doing the coal
I spent some time in that room and I got
sick of it very quick and I checked the
video and it looked really dark so I
don't think long term it's a good idea
so I decide just to try the grass and
it's it's not that bad actually
um so let's go check it out I did a an
arch over here now um this tree used to
be over here the the logs and I move
them over make it look like an offset
tree just so we can walk by easier um
got some stairs going on here and flower
pots and stuff I don't have any of the
new flowers really I guess I never
picked those up so I'm gonna have to
head back to that flower for some time
to to get more and then we got rid of
the coal here we got grass it's it's not
too bad kind of I'm glad I chose gold
for the middle because it matches the
grass color the closest and if we do
tall grass and other things it'll it'll
probably look better too but then I also
started working on these upper layers
because I want to hide stuff up up high
as well not just all in one big pile
like I said so let's head on up I don't
have a ladder or anything yet such I
didn't get that far but if we go up we
got like railing you can look down at
the gold pile very cool
OOP don't fall down i chiseled the cave
over here which is pretty cool I think
so
you still have the stone that goes out
oops
and then you can sneak in all I'll
probably chisel out a bit more and hide
some stuff over there or something but
if we go further you got some wit stairs
here diagnol ones comes up to this part
so we got another fence area you can
look down it just wanted to get more
layers in this place just the way the
tnt blew blew up it it like made all
these caves up higher so hey let's take
advantage of that makes it makes the
area cooler I think and then I polished
up this area here pretty good I think
I've got some stairs and we got like to
to loot stashes over here so maybe we
will go get our emeralds and hide them
over there okay so we got 23 of these
dirty emeralds this is from the old
villager trading when they would accept
unlimited paper villager trading that
was still pretty easy the emeralds with
so I don't know
I thought they would eventually they
would change it so emeralds would be
pretty tough to get put - that never
happened so all emeralds are kind of
dirty but we were just going to use
these for building only that's our dirty
emerald pile let's get our iron here
this will probably go away pretty quick
this is from one of my beacons actually
I replaced with gold
alright cool oops two more two more
blocks will they fit yes II do there so
that's our dirty emeralds and our iron
stash we got our gold pile so there's
still diamonds lapis maybe I have so
much lapis those
think and I have incredible amounts of
coal what else is there is my missing
one I feel like there's another resource
in this game I can't think of it though
mmm slime I guess and glowstone
glowstone will use for lighting possibly
what else is there anything else this
would it check let's go check just in
case I'm forgetting something but yeah I
got a lot of lapis way too much lapis Oh
quartz maybe hmm I do have a lot of
quartz how would I store that though
would be block of quartz maybe so we did
iron we did gold lapis this isn't all my
lapis by the way I have about double
that at least
at my other base diamonds there's
redstone I don't know if I want to stash
that Oh anyway so we we got a good start
to that there's also another path I want
to make to go to that area so we kind of
found out that this connects somewhat so
we'll probably do something like this
and have a walkway going going over here
come out in this spot because I like to
have at least two ways of getting to
each area in my base it makes it feel
very spider webby I guess I don't know
how to describe it like every area has
pretty much two or three or four ways of
getting to it but anyway guys I think we
should probably wrap up the episode
we'll do the comment though of course
for today picked out one which says hey
etho what type of player would you
consider yourself to be when playing UHC
ultra hardcore
do you consider yourself to be a PvP
player at
player or maybe prefer playing solo etc
I find I do better when I play solo like
I tend to win more battles but I prefer
I like for for fun wise entertainment
wise I think team games are better I
enjoy them more solo is more serious I
find it's one type of chicken farm looks
like they all grew up how many eggs do
we have others are not full see I think
it would be at this end um looks like we
got a few let's see
PvP player I haven't died two mobs once
yet and you ate see like in all our
seasons I've always died to another
player which I guess that makes me a pvp
player I definitely would much rather
die to a player than to a mob getting
the better of me it's usually more
action-oriented
if you died to a player so I think
that's kind of cool team player I try to
be a team player I might not always
communicate the best especially in a
tense situation but I try but yeah I
think I do prefer playing the team games
just because they're more fun but I do
enjoy the solo once just because it's
more of a serious serious match as well
I don't know it's good to have a balance
between the team games and the solo ones
I find but anyway that is going to be
all for today everyone I hope you
enjoyed today's episode and our our
little project here we got quite a bit
done on it actually we only have maybe a
little bit more to do in this room
try polish it up a bit more but yeah
hopefully the gold pile grows but as it
as this grows I'm going to be taking a
way to set up beacons in different
places that's another thing I could put
in this room actually is my beacons I
think I got four spares right now that
aren't being
used and I got like eight with their
skulls saved up currently as well so
could get quite a few beacons but I hope
you guys have a good day thanks for
watching and I'll see you again in the
next one bye bye