[Music]
hello hello
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back to another episode of
our let's play
series so guys last episode we started
building this super small tree this is a
colossal
64 furnace array and our goal
is to make it as quick as possible or or
at least within
practicality right and so far i think
it's off to a good start we're going to
try to get this up and running today
the key to the whole system to make it
quick though is we have a splitter
system in the middle here so let's check
this out
again uh basically we throw our our
items in here to be smelted
you see how quick they empty out and
then they go into eight different
hoppers here
uh like a stack will go eight items into
each of these hoppers so eight hoppers
total
and then there's gonna be eight hopper
mine carts that pick up the items out of
these hoppers
and then they're gonna run across the
top of these furnaces here and drop off
one item to each of these as it goes by
that's kind of the plan to this thing so
i've made a couple design changes since
last episode for one thing i've raised
up the splitter system by a block
and that allows us to sneak in some
redstone here
right underneath these hoppers so we can
easily control these
these power rails now on on both sides
uh
just by sending a pulse to this thing
it'll make the
hopper mine carts move we got to power
all this stuff here
though which it's not doing right now
and
i also made one other big change down
here we had a hopper minecart running
underneath the furnaces before and now
i've decided to change that out to a
hopper chain
instead so that'll pull the items out of
the furnace and
send them over to our dropper elevator
in the middle here
i think it's going to be about the same
speed using a hopper chain but the nice
thing is
we don't have to control the minecarts
this way it's going to be all automatic
so one less thing for us to worry about
i did realize though there's a problem
with this whole thing let's say for
example
some fool let's say i'm i'm being an
idiot
and i drop off a bunch of dirt
uh should that not go in wait a second
where where does the dirt go oh maybe
that furnace was full already
aha so i already got some garbage in my
furnaces here if you get garbage items
in your furnace array i've i've realized
there's no way to get it out like it'll
go into the top here you can't pull that
out with a hopper
or a hopper mine cart right
so you have to like come underneath here
break all these hoppers
because all the sides are blocked now
and take it out manually which kind of
sucks but
yeah it's that's kind of the issue with
the furnace arrays i guess
like any array you do that's going to
have that problem
so make sure if you're playing on a
server you're not playing with stupid
people
or don't let them use your smeltery
because they'll jam it all up
but anyways let's get to this here we
got a couple problems to solve with our
smeltery thing here
first off how and when
do we tell this minecart to start moving
like under what conditions do we want it
to leave like that
i think once it gets eight items that's
the perfect time for it to start moving
because it'll drop off one item to each
of the furnaces
if it only picked up seven the last
furnace wouldn't get one right
and then they would have to go back pick
up one more item and then drop it off to
get this thing
running at maximum efficiency we want to
make use of all the furnaces right
if it picks up nine items it's going to
drop off two
and another one which isn't a problem
but it's going to take longer for the
minecart to fill up here
and then we're wasting time as well so
eight items is the perfect amount
the problem is we can't detect when this
thing has eight
eight items in it and also when we
drop off our items to be smelted it
might not even get eight items
is the other issue so for example let's
say i want to smelt something i only
dropped 34
off into here it's not going to get
eight it only got five
right so if we're detecting eight this
thing is never going to
leave and i'm never gonna get my items
so i think what we want to do
is detect when it starts receiving items
so we'll probably put a comparator here
and hopefully that turns on
if we put something in this chest yeah
it does okay good
so i think all we gotta do is set up a
bunch of repeaters here i'm gonna try
eight
eight repeaters set at four and it's
gonna wait enough time for the hopper to
get eight items in it hopefully that's
our goal with this
so let's throw in a bunch of stuff here
and we'll
check out the mine cart real quick here
okay
look at the mine cart real quick four
five six seven
yeah i think it started moving on eight
right that's good
yeah so i really like this it's uh very
simple to do right but also
it it deals with the problem of not
waiting for eight items like if there is
an eight
so if we only put 32 in it'll wait for
the eight items but if it doesn't get
them it still goes anyway
right because it's based on timing not
on actual numbers
so that's cool the only problem with
this
maybe is i can't jump
i can't parkour what happens if we put
in a whole bunch of items let's test
that as well
i'm worried it's not gonna
deal with this too well so if it has a
lot of items it'll wait for eight
and now it keeps bouncing is the other
problem so it's only picking up
i picked up five i think six
five or six right so only the first five
furnaces are getting items
because of that these ones have none
that's not good we want them all to get
items
okay all right guys so
this is actually a pretty challenging
build once you get down to the details i
thought this was going to be easy
so i started making a list of what we
want to do and uh number one on startup
leave at exactly eight items or
out of items to smelt so that's what we
did here already right
uh we don't want it to leave at seven
items we don't want it to leave it nine
it would be fine if it left at 16 items
though
because it would drop off one on the way
and one on the way back the key is that
we evenly distribute
items to the furnaces and at 16 or more
it'll drop off two items
in each of the furnaces at eight items
it'll drop off one item to each furnace
on startup though we don't want it to
wait till it gets 16 items because
that'll take longer for this to fill up
right it'll waste another two seconds
so we have a special startup sequence
here
that only activates once as soon as we
put the items into the smell tree
and we make it activate only once with
the sticky piston here the spinal stable
circuits
i've added a little bit of delay because
it was only actually dropping off seven
items to the furnaces so hopefully that
fixes it
the other thing though is that to make
it stop and pick up 16 items here
before it does the next cycle i've added
in a clock sequence down here
so as items smelt in the furnace they'll
pass by this hopper
here will detect that then we make it
run to a clock
uh this is like a a delay timer and then
this is our comparator clock that
activates the dropper elevator still
following me
because i've lost myself already long
ago uh
and then every time we finish
a smelting cycle once the items smelt we
tell this uh
hopper minecart up here you see how the
the line goes up here
we tell all the hopper minecarts to
deliver some more items to the furnaces
so it'll start another cycle
so it'll keep running until it runs out
of items to smelt
is what this does uh is the hope anyways
we gotta test it out so let's start it
up
and hopefully everything is set up
pretty good now how many should we do
let's just do four stacks of items
and we want this to leave okay let's
double check it delivered eight because
it wasn't no it only delivered seven
still
so this last furnace isn't on
okay but now i think it's waiting to
pick up 16 items or more
so it should deliver two items to each
furnace now
why is this oh maybe i gotta make this
minecart rail go
one block further because it's still not
giving items to the end one
i think that's what it is
okay okay
but you can see as as items smelt here
they activate this comparator once the
cycle is done
see that turned on activates the dropper
elevator here
i think that was lag i don't know why it
stayed on for a while
and this first furnace seems to have got
more items because they weren't going to
the back there
like they were supposed to okay
we're getting close it still needs more
tweaking
i just realized there was a lever here
watching this last hopper
okay so i've unlocked this hopper here
i noticed this furnace was only getting
one item instead of two like when there
was 16 in the mine cart so i've extended
it by a block here
and i've also extended this front part
by a block there used to be a furnace
down here
problem was the front the very first
furnace was getting two items when the
other ones are only getting one
so let's let's try it out now let's try
out these changes we're gonna put in
three stacks of items
so this should go at eight items
and i also shorten the timing by two
ticks up there
and then it should go again pretty soon
here so it's got enough for another
cycle okay as soon as that first cycle
finished smelting it sent this one
now each of these should have two
good looking good guys this will keep
running even when there's
there's no items left that's fine but
it'll stop once
all the smelting is done
all right guys let's break up this
episode a little bit we'll return to
that
but i got something i want to show you
uh in the man cave here i'm i'm pretty
excited to show you this actually
the other day i felt like building
you know so i i decided let's work on
the man cave a little bit
there's a section we never go down that
tunnel over there
we always go down here uh we always go
up there that's like the old school part
of the man cave this is our main hub
over here
this is like the lesser used farms and
things
um totally did not see that creeper
yes we don't go over here too often but
this area is pretty much finished as
well it's nice i like it
but this other tunnel that we never go
down
hardly is like our wire axis
area and i finally polished that up
a little bit here so added in like a
little archway here we got hidden
lighting all over the place with these
leaves you can see we got some glowstone
down there
i decided to put in a window over here
to look down on wilson
which looks good from this side i'm not
sure if it needs some adjusting though
because on this side i don't know i'll
see what you guys say about it
what is with all the mobs in my world
this is not a safe place
yeah i feel like that maybe doesn't fit
the theme in this side of the room so
maybe
oh wilson's trying to eat me one second
uh maybe that needs to be changed up but
i like i like the looking down window
side of it i think that's good um
and then over here actually let's look
over here first
so this bridge i changed it used to be
an oak bridge and i changed it to jungle
jungle wood and then i hung some cocoa
beans off of it
and i think that looks pretty nice i
added in an extra lamp here
you know some vines in the area there
was a big hole in the wall here now we
have the fence with hidden lighting
um lots of lots of little details to
this like i've even
fine-tuned the shaping of the ceiling
the stone part of it
used to be a lot more jagged now it has
more flow to it
i've added a trim up there just lots and
lots of little details have been done
here
there used to be nothing but just grass
like
this kind of grass now we have leaves
and tall grass
flowers over here um if we go across the
bridge this is the part i'm most happy
about
this looked really bad here if you
remember it was a two wide
long walkway and i didn't think i'd be
able to make it look
anywhere decent but i'm really happy
with this i put some orange clay over
here
problem is spacing we did not have a lot
of spacing here
because we have our firework maker right
over here
and we need to run some redstone right
over here so i've maximized the amount
of space
like right on top of that clay is the
wiring here
so i've i've popped the wall out as far
as i could this way
yeah so i've become quite a fan of
orange clay now
i've never really used it too much up to
this point but like
dark oak orange clay spruce wood
i love that combo even if you have some
oak wood nearby it looks fine i think
we got another ugly brick thing in our
man cave
to get to the wire room uh-huh
and got a weird looking archway here i
don't know what i was doing but
i kind of liked it it's unique then i
refined the staircase it was a big mess
before it's
it's a very standard sort of staircase
now
over here is our wire access to the
elevator and also this goes down to the
potion lab wiring
that because that's the main point of
this tunnel is to be able to reach a
wiring on on different things
um threw in some hidden lighting here
and some flowers
these leaves and things weren't here
before either so that's been refined put
in
or i made this bridge a little bit more
fancy we have
this and some railing um pretty good
view from up there down to here
and this goes over to wilson so that's
kind of a complete cycle there
the goal with the man cave is to get rid
of all the torches and also to connect
all the areas together in many different
ways so we
we're doing that with this i like it you
can jump down from there
which is cool then over here is our
firework room
firework factory uh this was all stone
previously and now i've i decided to do
the red mushroom blocks i like this look
a lot too
dark oak mushroom blocks leaves i think
it looks pretty cool got some more
orange clay there and another wire
access area
to things i can't even remember oh this
is to a bread maker
the fireworks stuff a portal system from
the
the potion lab
so that's cool what else i just uh did a
little bit here i added a
a leaf decorative thing there a wheat
bed
more orange clay and that's about it
that's about all i did here
so that is pretty cool i'm happy with it
all right guys so we're back at the
smeltery again we pretty much got the
item distribution and
and smelting all set up there we need to
hook up our
fuel system for the furnaces and also
this
this dropper elevator needs to be set up
i have to move where it was this was not
working i tried it out
gotta rebuild the whole thing i hate it
when you
when you need to move something one
block in minecraft it's so hard to do
like there's no easy way of doing it
just want to push stuff over by one
block
got tear it all down rebuild it
yep no way around it's
okay so i'm going to move it forward by
one block and then it'll start going up
here
all right and we're going to do the quad
elevator i'm going to try to get it to
work here
i think the pattern we want to do
is let's see i got to move this forward
so we're going to
grab the signal from here
and then i think we want to stagger our
wiring all the way up like staircase it
so it goes from here
to here to here to here all the way up
following that pattern
uh so this wire here will power this
dropper this one will power this one
this one will power this one one tick of
delay between them
and see how that works out let's let's
flip it on
this is gonna be my torture for the next
few minutes
i gotta listen to this and test it out
make sure it works
uh-huh that's with the sound
all the way down to four percent guys
i had it louder before and this has been
running for a few minutes now
starting to lose my mind here oh it's so
bad
okay let's test it out though let's make
sure this works
so we're gonna throw um
29 stone bricks into the left there
let's throw in 29 grass
into there and then let's also test out
these front droppers
so eight eight sources are convoluting
down to
one basically that's what we're trying
to do here
let's put in rails into there
and then power rails into there so all
those items should make it to the top
eventually
hopefully fairly quickly let's get out
of here
oh my goodness the sound oh i went way
too far
where am i i'm lost i think i went over
the hill here
okay so those should end up in this
double chest at the very top
hopefully they didn't get stuck this
time
yeah so everything is there right i
think so i think it's all good so the
dropper elevator works
it's just really loud and annoying and
laggy
but you guys wanted the quad dropper
elevator so i delivered
right yeah
all right guys very cool so this is it i
think we have the basics of our system
working here we're gonna do the first
official test let's get down our hoppers
i was worried they're gonna push each
other for a moment there it's like no
it's all for nothing it doesn't work no
they seem fine though
i put some redstone blocks down here
these are just the power of the power
rails
so four blocks will power all eight of
them and i don't think it'll lock the
hoppers so that's all good
uh let's get down our other ones yeah
these are all empty here
so we're going to do a speed test as
well we want to see how quick it'll
actually smelt things now too uh it's
not pretty the system's not
polished up or finished in that regard
but it's this basic
functionality right now is what we're
testing out
uh this i put down two hopper mine carts
here
sort of as a temporary thing this is an
easy way to give it fuel
until i figure out exactly what we're
doing with that
um so we got another one running on this
side whoa
and that works pretty good all right
let's
hop up here though and we'll try it out
now i think we're all good to go for our
first
tests oh i'm lost
okay is there anything i'm forgetting
those look like they're still in
position
right i clean clean out all the garbage
out of the the furnaces so they should
be
hopefully okay okay this is empty yeah
so here we go guys our first speed test
we're gonna make some cracked
stone bricks by smelting stone bricks
and at the very minimum it's gonna take
oh i felt the leg already
why is it lagging it should be lagging
already it's the dropper elevator that
lags
uh it's fine now yeah now i can feel it
i can really feel it now yeah so we had
some garbage items left
in the in the elevator it looks like
that's where that furnace and stuff came
from
okay seems like uh maybe the elevator
needs to run a bit longer it's not
delivering a full stack
every time is it or maybe it is 43
to 35 yeah it's not quite
running long enough so that's an issue
there's more items in the elevator just
didn't deliver them
but yeah that's the rough smelting time
of this thing
plus like 10 more items or so
so that is pretty cool i'm i'm really
happy with that
i think that is uh that's a winner
yes everything seems to be running good
yeah no problems
those ones are moving right yeah those
are going to
cool uh we can't check the furnaces but
it looks like they're all on here that's
a good sign
okay so in total we got six
just about seven stacks of items we put
eight stacks in though so that means
there's about a stack of items stuck
in the dropper elevator so we need to
make this clock run a bit longer
that's why that happened you can see
when we unpower this
this slowly bleeds away that's what
controls how long the
elevator stays powered for
so we need to make this longer somehow
and then all should be good with that so
that is pretty cool let's double check
we got our
eight stacks up here
plus one there must have been one
garbage item left in the elevator too
before we started aha but yeah it's a
very
very quick uh thing i'm happy with that
seems cool
about 10 seconds every stack of items
and very short startup and ending times
too so that's cool
anyways let's get to the comment of the
day it says one thing that would be
extremely cool with the auto smelter
would be
to make it so that you can just place
down a shulker box in a certain spot
just add a hopper to the input chest so
that way
you can take a shulker box from let's
say the gold farm
and smelt down the armor into nuggets
yeah so i would like to do something
like that have uh
let's see i want to make a building for
this i want to maybe have a shulker
input and output
system to it and also if we can i would
like to control whether we're using
planks for fuel coal lava buckets that
sort of thing
would be the last few things to making
this perfect i would say
um i would not ever smelt down gold
armor and
swords into nuggets though that's just a
waste of fuel
waste of fuel and a waste of time in my
opinion it's never gonna happen for me
uh but yeah hopefully you guys enjoyed
this if
if you want to see more of this let me
know or if you want to see me work on
something else let me know in the
comments i'm
not really sure what i want to work on
next in the world here
so until next time
thanks for watching hope you enjoyed it
uh i messed up my outro take care bye
[Music]
bye