[Music]
um
yes um so level one
i died and i am very sad
very very sad about it 209 levels down
the drain
it happened i thought ah no big deal
just fight a wither
do it all the time right i forgot to
bring the right bow though i brought my
punch bow where did he get me
did you destroy everything already you
jerk
i think you did oh no there's my xp
did you really destroy it all
everything my elytra wings my pick my
armor
he doesn't even care about me
what what's going on why doesn't he
why doesn't he chase me he knows i'm
weak
yeah he destroyed everything oh that
sucks
so we could buy that i i do have a good
chest plate what we need is
you you sir you're the good guy right oh
it's just oh i thought it had silk touch
on too
okay uh we can we can make this work
though
22 each man i kind of regret using all
my emeralds to build a beacon now
because i think this is all i got left
i better get one more
aquafinity
[Music]
so
oh i totally dodged that i think i
jumped over it
all right round two
[Music]
got my good bow this time
and that makes a world of difference
and he's down a vengeance is mine
all right guys i got uh got myself
re-geared here pretty good
pretty good uh for the most part i'm
i'm all set now once again uh it's kind
of cool i gotta
like run around the world and uh use
some of the gizmos i don't use too often
anymore like the armor we got
the library mechanisms with all the
books and stuff it was kind of fun
uh but it also took a very long time but
i'm re-geared
and the good news is we got the nether
star
so i can do my stupid little intro i
originally planned for this episode
bears beats
battle star galactica
question what bear is best
false panda bear or
i also would have accepted alexander
keith's
but we don't have either of those in
minecraft we do have the polar bear
though
and i've been wanting to get one of
these guys for a while i looked for one
a few
uh quite a few episodes ago and i wasn't
able to find one turns out
you don't really want to look in the
tundra or extreme hills or anything even
though there's snow there you gotta find
them in ice plains or
ice spike biomes or icy mountains
but not the tundra so i found one guy
here after flying around for a little
bit
uh they're not super common from what i
can tell
uh the problem with these like old
worlds like i have
here is if new bob's come out it can
sometimes be difficult to get them
and i only see one oh there's
wait a minute maybe they are more common
than i thought there's a bunch of them
over here
okay okay so the next challenge is how
am i gonna get these guys back
and can i breed them once i get them
back because i would like to
oh he's got a cub
she's got a cup that makes more sense
they don't get the hearts anymore when
you feed them wheat
okay okay well i brought
obsidian here to make a portal i guess
let's do that and we'll see if we can
get them through
and take them over my boats
ice highway if we can oh
no i wasn't between you and your cub the
cub was
right next to you oh they kind of leave
you alone after you run away i've like
done nothing with these polar bears
since they've come out
so i don't even know how they work
really
oh they get angry fast though your cub
is right next to you i know like they
get angry
if you get between their cub and them
but maybe if you're just close to them
when they have the cub okay well you're
perfectly where i want you
right now actually so bye bye and your
cub is all mine we're gonna run away
together
oh you went through okay so
i'm kind of scared to go through already
because i know there's a good chance i
won't be able to get back through the
portal
it might link up somewhere else so we'll
try this
we'll get a couple of them through here
i don't think there's any way to breed
them
currently in the game i'll try fish
though
but it doesn't seem like the wheat's
working
okay here we go through the portal where
is this going to take us
are we going to get them home safely
oh man you took them right here uh-oh
i'll save you no i won't you're gonna
die
oh i just punched you oh you die
and they dropped rails when they died no
i broke a rail uh okay
so it actually took me right to this
portal that's great kind of
except they killed them uh but it looks
like two of them survived here so we got
the little baby in the boats
already i'm gonna put down another boats
i guess and just run them down the
highway here
this should be fairly easy i just
might have to be careful careful about
running into the wall
might suffocate them as i go down the
path here at least with the big guy
okay you go in boat
he's so big are you gonna suffocate if i
brush against the wall
no it's good it's good okay sweet
this does not look right and yet it's
very awesome
okay man i'm so glad i built this ice
road like it's it's
oh hello it's proven to be quite useful
so far
all right so this will get us to the
nether hub but beyond that
uh i'm not really sure where to take
them
okay so we got them over here and i went
and got some fish and stuff just to try
it i don't think it's gonna work though
oh oh hey why are you mad at me
i guess i guess the cub is still nearby
right
okay
that's actually very awesome
it's like dancing on command i like it
i wonder if that changes the collision
like when they stand up if
if i put a tripwire above it if you
could activate it somehow
turn it into a proximity sensor you know
[Music]
all right so fish doesn't seem to be
working i brought a few different types
like salmon seems to be the one that
should work
uh like when they were first added wheat
would give them hearts but i don't think
it actually
would breed them so yeah i don't think
that's part of the game yet
um i did think of a place where we could
put them though
so first thing i'm going to do is
oh yeah i brought leads oh okay
it gets them out of the boat too i
didn't expect that
that's interesting so it's kind of like
a
like they're considered a neutral mob
but they will attack you too
if you upset them
[Music]
i don't think you can lead uh wolves can
you
like the wild wolves now
i'm kind of want to try that out oh
what's that that looks like an enderman
picked up a piece of netherrack
okay can i lead both of you oh you went
back in the boat
oh now they're both in the boat
actually here am i gonna fire resistance
them first
i gotta try to get them through the the
creeper face which is always a challenge
especially when mobs are mad at you
i guess we'll do it one at a time it's
probably safer
here we go yeah feel free to maul me
okay so i gave him a fire resistance
and a regen so i should be able to pull
him through here right
apparently they're really good swimmers
all right i'm just going to keep them in
this pool here that way we can see them
i think that would be cool
i don't think they'll drown right we'll
try this out
i'm gonna get the little baby
what did i just do
yeah they're they're pretty good
swimmers this is cool so we got
ourselves a little polar bear
display in the man cave here if we want
we can go swim with them
and occasionally she seems to get mad at
me oh just grew up the baby just grew up
oh snap oh it was so cute before
can we uh yes we could fence them too if
we wanted
uh yes that's pretty cool i like that um
i really hope they add the breeding and
stuff with the polar bears because then
you could do some
some cool stuff with them i think or are
you going to get stuck underneath those
ladders
might i better remove those just in case
occasionally they seem to like go under
the water for a long time i'm a little
worried they're gonna drown in this
thing
but it hasn't happened yet so i think
we're okay
trying to learn how to how to fly in the
what do you call this third person view
front view camera whatever it is
you do the fall and then the fly and
but anyways guys let's move on with our
episode here today we're gonna try to do
some building now
and i'm just like having fun figuring
out how to fly in third person view
there
getting a lot better at it now um
yeah so we're over here at the amplified
terrain base i have a project in mind
that i think is going to be pretty cool
if we can get it to work here
uh i want to try to build a clock tower
oh not enough altitude
you know what i didn't put on this bow
is unbreaking so it's like
breaking very quickly kind of a problem
uh gonna have to stop using it here
pretty soon oh no
i can't get up
up into the sky up up and away all right
so i want to try to get over
over to there right yeah we're gonna try
to build a clock tower guys which uh
isn't a super difficult thing to do in
minecraft but to make a working
clock tower it's gonna be pretty tricky
i think it'll be a good challenge
and i wanna maybe build it like right
right up on the wall like above the the
tunnel here or else maybe up over there
it's got to be somewhere we can see it
though there's not a lot of spots
unless we're flying we would see it a
lot easier if it was up there
we'll think about it for a second here
but yeah to build a clock in minecraft
like not a digital clock i'm talking an
analog
12-hour clock with the with the hands
and all that stuff right
no minute hand just the hour hand
probably is all we're gonna do
uh is very difficult because
let's say we set the time on this clock
and then we leave the area here the time
in the game is still going to
keep running but the chunks are going to
unload here
so the clock's going to stop and then
when we come back it's going to be the
wrong time right
or if we sleep in a bed it's going to
change the time in game and the clock
isn't going to change so
how are we going to deal with that i am
not exactly sure
that is the challenge with this so i was
thinking about using daylight sensors
for it
uh but it turns out they're not super
good either because
they mostly detect oh hello
mr scary pants over here they mostly
detect like the sunrise and the sunset
that's when they change the most like
you can get a signal out of these
i'm not comfortable over here there's a
lot of
oh actually i might not have the oh i
don't have a nope
we're not on the side right now
okay so i decided to hop into a creative
world just to show you guys this makes
it a lot easier
um the minecraft day is divided into 24
000 ticks so like every thousand is one
hour
in game one hour on the clock that we
want to want to show here
so if we go to 23 000 that's like 11
o'clock
in-game and you see the redstone is at
two right now
just switch to three if we go ahead one
hour
in game to twelve o'clock
it goes way up like seven or eight right
so it's not like every one hour in game
moves the redstone
one block uh that makes it very
difficult to
to use this for timing the daylight
sensors here
but what we're going to use these for is
for re-syncing the clock
every day i think so we're going to use
like a hopper timer or something to
keep track of the time because that's
consistent
this is inconsistent
and then like if we leave the chunks or
if we sleep in our bed
every day just after that we're gonna
set the the clock
again um using something like this if
you
this is a cool trick you can do with uh
comparators by the way
put a redstone torch then a repeater
hook them together and then another
redstone torch
this allows you to detect a specific
redstone distance so this will detect
the third one wherever the redstone
torch is here
uh so if we go to 22 000 for example
the redstone shuts off here if we go to
24 000 though it's going to turn it all
on again
but it didn't activate the note block
here it's only
if it's exactly three that it'll
activate so if we go to twenty three
thousand
it's at two right now
jumps to three then it activates the
note block so that's how we can detect
when it's a certain time in the day like
right after we sleep
then we're going to set the clock and i
was just playing around with the layout
here i think this is what we're going to
go with it seems like a good spacing
between the hours here
so that would be twelve o'clock one
o'clock two o'clock three o'clock and so
on
um if you compress it smaller it just
doesn't look as good i don't think and
this makes it
pretty nice because we can draw a hand
like that
i will probably use pistons sticky
pistons to make the hand come out
too i think that'll work out pretty good
so we're back in our world again now and
i got
unbreaking three on the bow i put it on
fixed it up a little bit
and i have started on the clock
it uh it's gonna be crazy
you see all that green those are pistons
i don't know if we're gonna be able to
control it as well as i would like to
without having trouble with like budding
and stuff but we'll see
we will see and yeah we're not going to
worry too much about the looks today
we're just trying to get that working
but i would like the tower to be maybe
like
at least that tall and go down to
like there at least i'm going to remove
a lot of that land over there
and then make a flat spot for the tower
to sit on i think would look pretty cool
and i put it out way out there so
you know you can see it from a wide wide
range of angles hopefully
not just like if we're just up here
looking there
you know should be quite doable
over there so uh what i'm gonna do next
trying to figure out how to activate
these pistons probably
i don't know let's see where's the
center
this is gonna be nuts i might make it
where i get rid of these ones
just to make it a little bit easier on
myself but we'll see
well i tried i really did try here
but i can't figure it out this is a head
scratcher
uh i almost think it's not possible
but this is a good challenge for you
guys maybe you can figure out a way
so i got i got that 12 o'clock working
you see the the hand comes out like that
no problem uh
where's it where is it there it is okay
then this one
i thought i was going clockwise but i
forgot i'm on the back side here so
i'm doing counterclockwise apparently
from where i started
so that's 11 o'clock that's working good
that's that's doing what it's supposed
to
no problem there uh but then beyond that
like that really tricky thing about
working with pistons is you got to be
careful of budding and all that stuff
and generally you need two blocks tall
to activate them um
which doesn't work when you have the
pistons all clumped together like i do
here
so that's 10 o'clock and you see there's
a piston there that's supposed to be out
and i just can't get it to
to work even to get this one to work as
well as it did i had to do like a
update trick here and uh
yeah beyond that it just kind of keeps
getting worse and worse i'm running out
of space here to
to do the wiring so
yeah not really sure what to do about
this
we might just have to only light up the
lamps
which kind of stinks
alright guys so i decided to i just go
ahead with it here anyways it's not
going to be quite as cool as i have
originally hoped but
should be cool nonetheless we can
activate like three out of the four
pistons on the arm so
we'll see what it looks like hopefully
it's not too derpy um
this might be a really derpy build i
haven't built it yet so who knows how
it's going to turn out here
but let's see here what we got to do now
uh so all the arms are are sort of
figured out like how
how to activate the pistons and all
these levers that you see are the
connection points so this would be
the 12 o'clock one o'clock
two three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven that's where
we have to connect
to make the arm pop out like that and
the light to turn on
um so if it's if it's three o'clock
for example we want that to be on
right but we don't want any of the other
arms to be on
uh which is a tricky thing but i realize
we can just do that trick we
we were planning on doing for sinking
the time as well with this
so this is not like the ideal place to
do redstone
kind of floating in the mid-air here uh
but yeah basically what we're going to
do is have a dropper
output a signal and then we'll do that
whole redstone torch repeater trick
that we did before and then then we'll
know if it's exactly
like one o'clock exactly two o'clock and
so on and so forth
all right so here we go guys i thought
i'd show you this before i add any more
onto it
because it's just going to get more and
more crazy looking
but it's actually very simple it's that
trick i showed you earlier with the
redstone torch and the repeater
it's just repeated many times here so
this device over here is what keeps
track of what time
to display on the clock depending on how
many swords are in the dropper
changes the hand on the clock so it's
it's actually a fairly simple concept so
we can
we can switch them between this dropper
and this one um
if we shut it all the way off here let's
go see what time it is i think it should
be
six something i realized
while doing this like the time zero in
minecraft is when the sun comes up right
but in the real world
you know the sun doesn't come up at noon
or at midnight uh so i had to
i decided to shift it over six hours so
the sun's gonna come up at
six am uh seven or eight am
might might have been better now that i
think of it but it's at 6am that's what
i did that's what we're going to live
with here
depending on where you live in the world
and what season is and all that stuff
affects it right we're going by harvest
harvest moon rules here
okay so 6am the sun rises um you can see
this wire is totally off uh when one
sword goes into here
this signal goes a distance of two that
shuts off this redstone torch so this is
the one that controls
the hour six hands so if this
wires off then the hour six is not
out anymore um then we do the trick here
so right now it's at this one so we
should be whoa i fall down
wait a minute getting really good at the
parkour here yeah so now we're on hour
seven
uh and you can see what i thought i'm
talking about with the the whole hand
being a little bit derpy
um yeah we're missing pistons
in places which i don't quite like but
it's better than nothing right
we got two swords in there shifts one
more hour on the clock
so it should be eight o'clock now and
then nine ten eleven twelve
i only got it up to 12 right now i
haven't done one two three four
five which is going to be the second
half we're just going to copy the same
concept over there
so once this gets to
6 seven then we start adding to that one
um we'll need a device to to switch it
over
and then uh what we're gonna do
is every morning right after you sleep
we're gonna get all these swords to go
back
into this dropper that'll set it to 6
a.m on the clock there
basically and then every night we'll
probably use a moonlight
detector as well to sync it so every 12
hours we're going to resync the clock
basically
and then we're going to use a hopper
timer every thousand game ticks
to add one hour all right guys
so this episode is getting a little long
already here so i decided just to
uh plow through this get it done um
and it's just about all done here i'm
gonna run you through it here
in just a second but you can see we got
the hopper timer running there that's
supposed to add an
hour onto the clock every time it it
does a cycle
uh at the moment i got it really sped up
just so we can
see this changing quickly but that's
supposed to run
every 50 seconds of real time to
add one hour on the clock here um
the way this works we have a reset
right over here this is kind of where i
left off on it
and basically the reset gets all these
swords back into this dropper here
sends it seven pulses or whatever
and that sets it back to six o'clock on
our clock here
so i'm just going to flip this real
quick and we'll go take a viewing spot
over here
you should be able to see it uh counting
okay so we missed six a.m but it's at
seven eight
and nine kind of goes around the clock
here
when it gets to 5 it's going to stop and
what we got to do
is resync it using daylight and
moonlight sensors
so that's that's the last part of this i
haven't done yet
but yeah it seems to seems to work
pretty good i need to
really figure out how i'm going to do
this face on this clock how to make it
look good
as soon as we add some blocks over top
of it it's going to create more shadows
on the clock and it'll look a lot better
than it is currently because right now
it's kind of exposed to the sunlight
um yeah so it goes to 5
and then before it goes to 6 we would
resync it again
otherwise it's just going to shut off
like that is the plan
so to resync it is
a relatively simple thing to do here
if he can get around oh getting lag
spikes too it's not
helping
okay okay so i'm trying to hurry here
before the sun comes up
we can test this out i got a daylight
sensor set up there
uh what i figured out in creative before
is if i
uh run at a distance of seven that's
right after you wake up in a bed
which is probably the best time to
resync the clock so if we ever sleep
it's going to be the right time
basically um what we got to do is just
connect to over here
let's kind of put this in a random
random spot
i'll have to move it later but i just
want to try this
okay do this so that's going to
turn on uh right when we sleep here
let's go get our bed quickly
and we should be able to see the clock
turn to
six right i believe right okay
oh actually do we have time let's turn
the clock on yeah we got a little bit of
time here
let's turn the clock on again and we'll
try to re-sync it while it's running
here
just to show you that it can be done so
i'm going to flip the lever
can you tell i had no torches while
while building this whole thing
all right yeah so we'll do that we'll
get it running
again oh
and i guess let's sleep over here so
yeah you see it's running up over there
so when we sleep in our bed it's gonna
turn it back to six o'clock
that's what it's supposed to do anyway
okay here we go and then again we gotta
do that with a moonlight sensor as well
i think that would probably be at seven
distance as well oh oh
oh wow it actually works like that okay
you can actually see it go back that's
weird
all right so are you confused as i am
basically what we're doing though we're
gonna have a moonlight sensor as well
to set it to 6 p.m when it's that time
and as long as we're in this area for at
least 10 minutes at the absolute longest
or if we sleep
at any time it's going to set it to the
correct time on the clock again
so that way if we leave the area and
come back and the chunks unload
that's not going to be an issue it'll
it'll fix itself
is the whole concept of this clock so i
think that's pretty cool
pretty cool so um
just run you through it quickly we saw
most of this again it looks crazy and
complicated that's just uh
that trick we did repeated many times
and i had to connect
each of those to one of the one of the
hands on the clock
so that made a lot of wiring here that
that's what makes this look confusing
but from the daylight detector and the
moonlight detector
um whenever we want to reset it to six
o'clock
uh we pull the signal from that send it
down this line here
got a little monostable circuit there to
make sure
uh it doesn't stay on for long i don't
think that's important actually
then we have a well actually it kind of
matters because otherwise
a clock would run for a long time here
but we have a pulse extender here
to make sure at least seven pulses get
sent to the reset
comparator clock which sends the pulses
uh those go down to here so this is our
reset line over here
this is our addition line right right
over here that the
the hopper timer is running to so every
time it goes over this it adds
to this dropper and you can see we got a
little piston mechanism here
uh this only goes up once once all the
swords are out of this dropper
so then it starts adding to this one i
had to split it into two
because there's only nine spots in the
dropper inventory and there's 12 hours
on a clock right another way i could
have done it is use ender pearls
and just like detect the signal from 0
to 15
and do 0 from 12 that way but i kind of
want the signal to spread out further
here so that i'd have space to
to do this trick here um
but yeah anyways that's really all there
is to it
complicated confusing yes yes yes
hope uh hope i made some sense there
though and uh
basically got the clock done here i'm
gonna have to do a couple more a couple
more things in testing
and then we can build our actual tower
which will
make it look cool hopefully
whoa don't see that too often uh so on a
sad note guys unfortunately
polar bears are gone i don't know what
happened like when i left
they were here like when i went through
the portal to the amplified terrain they
were here
when i came back they were gone
so yeah maybe you guys can fill me in do
they despawn
because i don't know much about them to
be honest
and i couldn't see any drops in the
water here like no fish
from them dying so i'm kind of thinking
they despawned somehow
but one other thing though i believe
this area here might be part of my spawn
chunks so possibly
the area was loaded while i was at the
amplified terrain base
and they could either kill themselves or
despawn that way as well
which explains it anyways let's do the
comment of the day and wrap up here for
for this episode
it says this series never fails to
remind me
how great minecraft is etho is one of
the most creative people i have ever
seen
yes yes i'm truly amazing
no doubt about it no thank you for that
uh the reason i picked this comment
though uh just to
to reiterate i i don't really say this
often but one of the main goals with
this series
since the beginning was i tried to
always come up with new ideas to try do
things different or think outside the
box the reason for that
mainly while i do enjoy it of course
um is to give you guys ideas to make you
think outside the box
try to extend the life of this game make
it fun for you for longer
if you have more stuff to do in it so
maybe after watching this episode you
try to build
a clock maybe you try do it different
than i did maybe you'd figure out how to
do it better than i did
you know that's that's always been the
goal of the series
and why i kind of play the game the way
i do as a side note of that
i don't really aim to finish projects as
strongly as
as you might when you play minecraft
it's more about introducing ideas than
finishing ideas
uh but i do try to just because it makes
things nicer in the end of things here
anyways i will finish a clock tower i'm
pretty sure
um anyways hope you enjoyed today's
episode
thank you very much for watching have a
wonderful day
take care bye bye
[Music]
you