hello hello how's it going everybody
this is
etho and welcome back guys how you doing
today
hopefully you're having a great day
that's it's almost like an optical
illusion
what's going on I got to be careful if I
fall down the ladder there's no way of
catching it again all right here we go
we're at the top so guys we are back at
the witch farm area again here yeah we
worked on this last episode got a bit
done on it but today I pretty much got
the whole thing together in its basic
form where it'll function and over the
last few episodes I just wanted to show
you this - I've been clearing out the
land around here so those those pillars
there they kind of mark the boundaries I
wanted to clear there's another one
there another one there and all that
land is gone look at all that all those
islands like everywhere you see a flat
spot like that there used to be an
island there I've been clearing it all
out the only thing we really got to get
rid of is from there to there we have
this giant island in the way I could
just light it up and that will stop mobs
from spawning on it but I think I want
to blow it up so we might do that today
- but let's head down and check out the
witch firm see the changes we made to it
carefully very carefully alright so here
we go ouch we have a triple-layer which
farm here now it looks like some spawn
in the top there - alright so let's go
inside I have a very lovely door
installed right here
okay look how convenient that is it's
amazing okay so I just want to show you
how I ended up doing this after we
played around with it a bunch last
episode so I decided to fill it in on
the sides and then these dispensers
shoot the arrows that push the
which is off the edges here and they
fall down and you can see I got some
hoppers right at the bottom down there
so they should die from fall damage
would collect the drops and that'll work
as a very basic mob form right now we
can add more on to it though later but I
was worried about filling in the sides
before because if you do that I thought
it would be crease mob spawn rates oh
hello
did not realize we were going to be
there I think I'm gonna get out of here
now okay yeah so I decided to fill in
the sides there I was worried about
doing that last episode but then I saw
in the comments a lot of you guys said
that's the whole checking 20 blocks away
from a spawn location no longer was a
thing in Minecraft 1.9 so basically like
if you're trying to spawn a mob on a
dirt block over here it's gonna check at
this height up to 20 blocks all around
it for air spaces and if those are
blocked with blocks then there's a
chance it's not going to spawn the mob
in from what I understood before anyway
I never actually looked into the game
code but that's what a few people said
um so yeah they changed that at 1.9 a
lot of you said in the comments so I
decided to investigate it just to be
sure I didn't want to rely on just the
rumors
so I created a little testing in a
creative world here and we'll go check
that out now here let's do our fancy
teleports to the creative world okay
guys so here we are in a creative world
where I'm doing an experiment that's
been running for probably an hour to
actually um so I got to spawning
platforms set up down there that one has
no block surrounding it that one has
three layers of blocks surrounding the
platform they're the same size as the
witch farm as well there are seven by
nine so previously this one should spawn
less mobs because there's less air
surrounding it and I was just testing to
see if that's still true and you can see
on our scoreboard here this is kind of
the important thing the less air one is
that one and the
are one is that one and this one
currently in the lead but I suspect
that's just due to inconsistencies and
probability around a hundred they were
both equal and then less air kind of
pulled ahead but in the past like in one
point eight and before you would have
expected this one to spawn way more mobs
which isn't happening anymore so it
seems to be true let's just go down and
look at it closer to - no not game-mode
0 that's how you kill yourself I want to
change the time time set zero there we
go okay yeah so exact same number of
spawning spaces inside this one just has
three blocks surrounding it which would
made a big difference before this is the
command blocks I have I have running to
to make this work so it checks if
there's a mob on the platform if there
is it increases the score by one and
then teleports it into the void to kill
it okay well anyways guys hopefully that
was clear enough and I didn't ramble too
much basically it doesn't seem to matter
if you build next year spawning
platforms in 1.9 so that's why I filled
it all in oh there goes and we're doing
our first test guys oh that's so cool so
I put only like 16 spectral arrows in
each of the dispensers and every time at
which spawns we can clearly see it which
is really cool although it looks like
they're despawning quickly I just read a
range yeah they're not actually falling
down and hitting the hoppers I don't
think I think they'd the spawn despawn
before that happens
uh-huh so basically I'm gonna have to
light up the caves for us to use this
mob farm I can't just like go up in the
sky and have it work because when they
fall down they get out of range and then
they just instantly despawn before they
hit the ground oh oh here comes one
woohoo alright
so yeah there we saw the which hit the
hopper and died so if we're close to the
ground they can make it all the way in
splats and then we get the drops but I
got to light up all the caves which I'm
starting to do it'll probably take many
hours to finish it all so we'll just
have to do a little bit every every
episode probably or I'll do it off
camera woohoo but once I get them all
lit up then the witch farm should work
great okay this is gonna be fun though I
haven't done any caving in a long time
like look at this I haven't killed a bat
and so long oh man I missed it
that's so cool yeah cuz I always do
speed mining now so I don't really go
caving for redstone or anything and once
we get the witch firm set up I won't
need to do speed mining even cuz red
stones the only thing left I need to get
and the iron of course but usually pick
up a little bit of that every project I
do we have to dig something else oh we
got a dungeon
we got a dungeon Oh baby double chests
there's this new terrain - we might get
something good here named dig that's
pretty good
I'll take it and I've got take the red
stone and Oh diamonds horse armor oh
that's awesome I don't think I Eve I've
ever gotten that before actually in my
single-player here cool so I did a whole
bunch of caving today guys I got a lot
of it lit up under the ground here
that's gonna help out the spawn rate
still a fair bit but we got more to do
but we'll do it another day cuz I've had
enough I did get like 10 stacks of iron
and two stacks of gold diamond horse
armor was a good find
and a whole bunch of redstone as well so
it was a good run but now it is time to
blow some stuff up I usually don't do
this much TNT so I'm not sure
this is going to go this is a nine by
nine and four tall big clump of TNT this
is going to be pretty crazy I think
it'll do like a fifteen by fifteen all
all around if I'm not mistaken here we
go let's trigger it's got a special
remote detonator
okay and I'm getting all the way out of
here oh that sounded like a lot of TNT
how much did that actually do though
yeah not cleared out a decent amount
right
the thing about TNT like you spend a lot
of time setting it up so if you don't
use a lot you kind of waste a bunch of
time just from the set-up cost of it but
the more you set up the more you waste -
all right let's do another one
yeah that worked okay
run run run keep running I love that
sound how did this one do oh wow this
one went oh there might have been a cave
down there I don't know it looks like a
dug down pretty far though no there was
no cave here uh-oh so we were trying to
hit y63
so we went two blocks too low but
overall it's fine
alright everyone so I decided to come
back to base to the man cave here we'll
do some stuff around here now but are
you ready to see it I'm using the 44 B
and there's a weird visual glitch in
this current patch oh man this place
looks so weird so all the stairs and I
think the fences and a whole bunch of
things have the texture kind of messed
up on them right now and it looks kind
of crazy around here especially like the
storage room here
oh man not the best look ever in this
update though there's a couple cool
things they finally added a recipe for
the end rods really glad they did this I
was worried they weren't going to but
they did an a they picked a pretty
clever idea for one too so it's blaze
rods and course fruit and I just had
four for that I wasn't expecting that
okay that's cool so that's the recipe
for the n rods these things are are
really nice actually so they have a
light level of 14 it's the same as a
torch it's not as high as glowstone but
you can do a couple weird things with it
that you can't do with torches like you
can put them on stairs like that which
is kind of cool and put them upside down
so it's like a it's like a block that
you can place basically anywhere weapons
if oh I can't put it there
can't put there oh yeah uh-huh team put
them on fences oh you can yeah so you
basically put them anywhere then what do
they look like on fences that's cool
so the base is the same size as the
fence and check this out too another
cool thing about these end rods is they
actually have a collision box which
makes them really good for like
tillering up if you got to reach
something just stack up like this and
then you know reach what you're going to
do and then to get down let's go out the
little ways here just to make this fun
they break very quickly like slime
blocks so like it's a quick little tap
will will break it you know you don't
actually have to mine it so I think we
can bust this down pretty fast
let's try let's try this out hopefully I
don't die from this oh there's no fall
damage either because of my wings so
that is awesome
uh-huh and they added a recipe for those
crystals that you find in the ends that
you'll the dragon and you use those to
respawn the dragon now you need four of
them you put them around the portal and
they'll reach
on it let's make a couple of those so so
it was like this seven and that the
expensive thing is the gasps tears what
oh did I only have oh okay that confused
me I just had only had nine glass box
there though it's like man I got ripped
off it took all my items and it didn't
give me enough but now that was right
that was right um
yeah these let's go outside the man cave
because they do explode where's a good
place to to play around a C's ah maybe
I'll go by the water here that's a good
idea I don't know if this is a good idea
no I don't like the spot let's go a
little bit further away oh yeah I got
this problem here guys I don't know
what's happening but my the the poppy
farm is having a little bit of a problem
I think there's swimming men or
something but they're not going down
like they used to and I keep clearing it
but they still they still keep getting
messed up yeah look at this he's
swimming out of it what a guy it's a
little bit of an AI change with iron
golems I can probably just get rid of
the water trailing down here then that
should fix it this is such a bad idea
but I got to do it oh no he doesn't
activate it oh darn it I thought he was
gonna bust the crystal okay so here's
the deal
I've tried picking this up with a boat
that didn't work I've tried pushing it
with water that doesn't work but you can
move it with a piston I believe they
have a huge collision box though so I
wasn't able to place another block in
between there but if we move it a little
further away now we can yeah so let's do
this a little bit a little closer
alright now this should move it
yeah so you can move them around with
pistons and I think you can stack them
to this way let's put another one down
yeah and yeah so now you got two
together that is 2 right it looks like
3/4 a second
and also they explode uh-huh
so as you can see here it left a pretty
big crater as well it's a bigger
explosion than TNT does more damage um
the big difference about that those
crystals though compared to TNT if you
set off to TNT for example the first one
kills you the second one destroys your
items you can see even though we had 2
crystals there I got all my items back
even though it killed me the thing about
that as well like if you have a big pile
of tnt somewhere it makes a big area of
an explosion like we did earlier today
those crystals it seems like only one of
them will cause damage to land and all
the other ones go to waste if I'm not
mistaken maybe we should go and create
them and just test that alright so this
side we have a 3x3 2 tall room here with
a single crystal this is the kind of
damage it does so it basically shaved
off one or two layers on the outside of
that this side again the same thing
three by three by two tall room but we
have about 20 crystals here and about
the same sized room so they all go off
at the same instant
unlike TNT so next up guys there's
something we need to investigate here
this just blew my mind when I saw it
earlier you might remember like several
times now I've gone looking for donkeys
we had one donkey in our world here and
then he he drowned in this water
um and I haven't been able to get
another one since I've gone looking for
donkeys never found one like because one
that's worked when I started this world
donkeys and horses weren't a thing so a
lot of the land I've explored didn't
have horses on and of the land I have
explored I have had a hard time finding
donkeys since they came out but look at
this I turn over here today and I see
this and I'm like what we have a donkey
unbelievable so here's a story behind
this I had two mules in here before one
over here one over here recently I think
a sly must have got inside this pen like
a baby slime fit inside and he jumped up
activated the tripwire and then my one
mule got out and drowned over here is
what I'm guessing happened so we were
down to one mule our last one with with
no donkeys to make more and it seems to
have converted into a donkey I think
because of one of the patches like an
egg with glitterbug of some sorts and
this might be a super donkey it seems
pretty fast right because like donkeys
you find out in the wild in this game
they all have the exact same speed and
jumping height as each other this the
mule I had there was bread so I think it
might have better stats jump seems
pretty average I think the speed might
be a little bit quicker though than a
normal donkey now maybe not maybe not
it's hard to tell I would need a donkey
to compare the two but anyways let's see
if we can breed the donkey here with my
fastest horse and I'm going to give this
guy my diamond armor too that we found
earlier
alright so horse breeding has been a
little bit buggy I don't know if this is
gonna work yeah come on guys give me
some hearts give me some hearts
okay just right-click okay got some
hearts yep yeah now it's not looking
like it's working unless this is still a
mule it might just be like a skin
let's try breed the two horses together
that might actually still be a mule it
just looks like a donkey
now horse breeding is broken okay we'll
have to try this later but we might have
a donkey here now which is awesome if
it's true alright so well you know what
guys it's been a while since we last did
anything on the Nexus here I thought
maybe we'll try solve the next problem
today
the next thing I want to add is buttons
for requesting items so right now we
just have this lever the longer I pull
this lever the more items we get out of
the system but I want to set up buttons
so that like I don't know how many we
would want but maybe we'll have one that
requests eight items when we push it one
that requests 16 one that requests you
know 32 64 so when we press the button
what we're going to want to do is
activate a hopper clock probably some
long delay timer thing so when we press
it then the wire activates for a certain
amount of time while this is being
powered its releasing items in the Nexus
but we can't just use this straight up
hopper clock I love hopper clocks I use
them all the time but there's one
built-in problem with them that's okay
so like when we press the button here
it's active right now it's active it's
active it's good now like if we try to
use it again we have to wait a certain
amount of time before it finishes
resetting and that's what I want to try
get rid of that little delay aha so I
was totally expecting I have to do
something complicated here you know and
gates or something
turns out hopper clocks are even cooler
than I thought I just learnt a new trick
with them and it's built into the hopper
clock look at this look at that light
over there
normally when I would want power out of
a hopper clock I would take it from the
redstone block here so this this
satellites here but you'll notice that
didn't shut off until the very end of
the cycle which is just awesome so as
soon as it's done compress it again as
soon as the hopper clock finishes so all
that is it's the comparator reading off
of this hopper once this all finishes
all the items end up in this hopper so
it's really simple I just never realized
you could do that and effectively that
doubles the length of time that the
hopper clock can run here if you do it
this way so you pull the signal out like
this and it is going to do the trick
alright everyone so I think we're going
to wrap up our episode here for today we
got the which firm pretty much all done
bunch of land cleared out caves lit up
and we did a few other random things
which was fun here is a comment I picked
out though it's a pretty relevant one
because recently they announced they're
going to stop adding or slowdown at
least adding new features to 1.9 in
they're focusing on fixing the bugs and
stuff now says hi etho what bugs do you
find the most important to solve before
1.9 comes out okay so first off this one
really stands out it's a it's one I'm
constantly reminded of I'm sure they'll
fix it the visual visual issue they're
probably the biggest one though and it's
actually the reason I updated to this
more recent snapshot I was hoping it
would be fixed but it isn't yet
let's see if I did replicated to yours
we go down the minecart track
we talked about the horses today that's
a pretty big one personally I would like
it were they fixed snow balls and eggs
shot from a dispenser so that they cost
not that can happen
it's currently like if you throw a
snowball it causes not to that but it's
a shot dispenser in
not
problem
the world has stopped loading
alright let's just let's go into the
skate mode is it actually this is kind
of a nasty way to end the episode isn't
it here let's go back into here
nothing nothing you saw there pay no
attention okay now when you load back in
everything is fine
yeah the snowball thing would be nice
for the witch firm though and there's a
few others for sure they're kind of
steeping me at the moment though yeah I
can't think of any those those are the
three or four though that really stand
out to me uh-huh
anyways guys I hope you enjoyed the
episode and I will see you again in the
next one take care bye bye