[Music]
hello
everyone this is etho welcome to episode
number 275
guys and as planned we're gonna be going
on a world tour today gonna go check
things out
and you know i wasn't really too excited
about doing a tour
like a little while ago like i was kept
getting comments about it and i didn't
really see the point of it
but now you know i've thought about it
i've kind of put myself in your guys's
shoes
and yeah i think we should make a point
of doing tours
every so often in the world here because
uh
i there's like it's surprising it really
does surprise me but
like there's on average 2000
2500 people subscribing to me every day
and that adds up very quickly like
you know 10 days that's 20 000 25 000
people
actually the average is like 70 000 a
month so that's a lot of new people
visiting my channel and of those
uh i'm guessing most of them have not
watched all my episodes so we really
should
do a tour and even those of you that
have like
very loyally watched me for a long time
i'm sure you've even missed a couple
episodes so
doing a tour i think is a good idea
after all
i know i always really enjoyed it when
like doc
dot dm does the world tour or other
people do a tour of their worlds
even just to see things again that were
built a long time ago is really cool
i don't have a lot to show like i'm not
much of a builder really i like to
mess around with ideas and stuff and
tinker and
and i don't get a lot done uh
not as much as i would like to but we'll
go through stuff today and
check out some of our builds try try use
some stuff
show you how it works and maybe even
talk about some of the history
how the game has changed and how you
know
stuff has changed that i've built
and maybe actually maybe just to start
off with here
i will introduce how i teamed to youtube
originally because a lot of people asked
that question too
um basically it was like two
i think two and a half years ago um i
got this game i was playing it for like
uh a couple weeks well i lost interest
of it
for a while because i was playing in
creative like uh
creative worlds and not like the
creative we have today like other
and a different type of creative mode
where you could only play on servers
really with it and i got bored of that
then i heard about the survival mode i
came back to it played it for like two
weeks straight
like eight hours a day i was so addicted
and in the world i built in that time
i had a like a mini dock
at like where i would put my boats and
stuff
and they kept drifting out to the ocean
and it was really
annoying me so i looked online to try to
find
some kind of device someone built that
would uh
let me dispense boats you know so that
they wouldn't keep drifting away in the
ocean
and i could not find anything so
i decided to try to build it myself i
did it turned out really well i liked it
thought it was cool and i decided to
post it on the minecraft forums for
people to check out
just like as a one-off video had no
intention of sticking around and making
a series or anything
but it got a lot of attention it was
very surprising
and it encouraged me to release a few
other videos and
those got really positive responses and
since i've always had like
a liking towards let's plays on youtube
i decided to create my own
and uh here we are today so
that's just a little quick history of
how i got into this
uh but let's start our world tour here
now that we've now that i've blabbed for
so long you've
lost half the viewers probably all right
the dedicated ones though those of you
still around
this is the first thing i built in this
world
uh this creeper face oh ah
i really should stop talking about past
but
for those of you wondering i had a world
that went from like episode 1
to 104 i think and then we started in
this world
after the adventure update i had to
change worlds
uh so since like episode 104
we've been building stuff here but yeah
this is the first thing we built in the
world i decide i want to settle down in
a cave
and try to
[Music]
try to follow the natural landscape of
the cave and build stuff in it and
try to avoid using torches
the finished areas don't have torches
but some some of the new stuff like
stuff i'm still working on
has torches around which i'll have to
get rid of over time
this guy he shoots fireballs out of his
eyes now randomly every
every few minutes he'll he might shoot
some
fireballs out of his eyes and behind
there's also my portal to
the nether this waters just for looks
for the at the moment
this is like an intersection area here
it branches off
lots of lots of different directions uh
go up the stairs
and we have a jukebox here um
put a record in lights turn on
terrible record let's not play that one
um
originally when i made this it was
hooked up to a bud switch that would
turn these lights on now
i've switched that to comparators
because the bud switch
stopped working um
lots of the hidden lighting in this area
is like below pistons
there's like like i think pumpkins under
these pistons which are lighting up the
place
this is a mushroom farm i built for some
reason has no mushrooms growing
just a little quick fun project i did
near the start of the world
step on pressure plates and all the all
the mushrooms get harvested and come to
you
just a really small farm uh this is also
another thing i built early on in the
series
this is the watermelon and pumpkin farm
i hate that sound the this has
changed a lot since i've built it uh or
the game has changed a lot
before you used to have to till soil for
it to grow
uh watermelons and pumpkins on it now it
it grows on any soil doesn't have to be
tilled
and there's pistons running all along
here that push
push up and then break the melons and
the pumpkins
and then when you leave it's just like a
t-flip flop
that goes back down um before
i used to have a hoe in here that i
would use to re-till this that would get
shot out when we enter
and it doesn't do that anymore well it
could
if we put something in here it'll still
shoot it out
but uh the way i built this it's
in the past if you walked on tilled soil
it would become until they also changed
that
which is why i have these uh guard rails
at the top here to keep you from
accidentally
walking on what was tilled soil in the
past
and then we put our stuff in here after
the harvest
very nice get out of here
ah that's much better all right so on
the other side
over here we have something that
probably confuses a lot of people
because i don't use this anymore
and actually i don't think it's even
working anymore
uh this is for a cave spider experience
system
i have two cave spider spawners in this
area
this used to be abandoned mine shaft all
this area here
and in fact this you know those big like
i think it's like 13 by 13 rooms i can't
remember exactly that you find at mine
shaft sometimes
that's what this cow farm is i tried to
keep the shape
the original shape we had and made that
we'll get to this in a sec
uh i think one of the spawners
for the two spiders is over here
yeah down there somewhere and
the other one's a lot easier to find
it's just up over here
yeah right there oh no i lost it
no let's hop inside
this is before lamps and and lots of
like
other lighting options we have now so
the way
i kill the lights in here just the
piston moves in front of
a pumpkin we got four of them all around
and that kills the lights when they're
being powered
and this has gone through
quite a few changes over
over time uh go back
here if we can go back here
there's a whole bunch of wiring a lot of
this can be redone so much simpler
now too it's it's almost hard to look at
it
uh this is a big timer thing i had it
set up so if i hit a button
it would start a one minute
timer or not one a one hour timer here
uh just a whole bunch of five minute
timers chained together
and the point of that was so if i went
afk
i wouldn't accidentally spawn like
thousands and thousands of spiders
in my world here and then corrupt the
world when it when they
when they cause it to crash you know
which was uh happening to me
quite a bit actually
so that's the point of all this and
there's also
an override button to it i think if we
press it it will turn on the spawners
yeah okay i'm gonna redo this though
sometime in the future and i'm i think
i'm just gonna make the spiders fall
and collect the string from them because
that's all i would really want for them
i have better experience farms
nowadays uh
this was really cool back in the day
though like this was
i built this when enchanting first came
out and
at that time like
using spawners for experience wasn't
really a thing like people had
had like a zombie and and skeleton
grinder things but they only used that
for the items like they didn't
try to keep the the mobs alive in the
system they
killed them and
you know i found if you clear out an
eight by eight by
three area you would get lots of spiders
spawning very quickly and
and then i also came up with this
staircase system for the spiders it like
wraps
it it merges the two
spawning systems together and then they
go up the staircase
and they go over top this way
and then to the left and then they
fall here um
just the right distance for them to be a
one hit kill
or east or at least it used to be i
don't know why it's not working now
not even close to one hit kill
their targeting has changed a lot though
in time
and i think they get stuck in this thing
too now
oh that noise it takes me back
uh it was a real challenge to set this
up where they wouldn't get
stuck or climb climb around in the thing
but obviously that doesn't work anymore
this piston at the top was to free them
if they got jammed
uh-huh and i think this is a shutdown
yeah a force shutdown
anyway this served me
very well for a long time it was a great
source of experience and i have tons of
wool
in my world from making it from the
string i got over time using this thing
and also around the time we were doing
this
i made my very first enchanting station
here
i automated it in the past you needed
30 bookcases around the enchanting table
to reach level 50. now it only goes up
to level 30
and i could control
the number of bookcases around it by
quarters basically with with these
levers
so if i wanted different numbers i could
change the combination
and there's a light above a light below
very cool at the time i didn't have a
theme for this place like i didn't have
all this wood around and
and and stuff so i i just made out of
sandstone because that's
a block type i really like and
so it feels a little out of place but i
think we should keep it that way
just because the way it originally was
and wire goes up to the pistons
oh how the game has changed um
let's see we got path this is a river i
made just for looks basically
i actually really like it um
it has a nice uh curve to it and
the way i made this water it's ice i
melted so it doesn't flow
unless it's updated yesterday actually i
was taving
around this area trying to light up some
of the few remaining dark spots
i had no idea there was a cave here it
just so happened a creeper exploded here
and there was like only one block thick
stone here
and it opened opened up the passage i
was like
hey that's my place over here so
we might expand into that cave there
pretty soon the river
just goes down here and that's about as
far as i got
i might expand further out this way in
the future
i have a feeling i'm gonna have to
really get moving because i could talk
for
hours probably on stuff around the world
uh this is my slime farm here it's a
just a basic elevator to move them up
and then they drop
over here they get separated by their
size
this is for the small the medium the
large
if we go over here this is where
oh man why is my world lighting so bad
something is going on
250 entities that does seem like a lot
uh this is a slime spawning pad here
it's just
at level 40 like the highest it possibly
can be in the world
and then it brings the slimes up there
i did it that way because i thought it'd
be cool to like do something with the
big slimes
for fun and i set up a track
a minecart track thing that picks them
up
when they step on that pressure plate
which uh
continually seems to be breaking for
some reason
and then randomly it seems to fix itself
but if we go up here
yeah see carts get stuck very weirdly
sometimes i don't know why
it goes back up carts come down they go
into this corner they pick up a big
slime they go over here
fall down and go
through a track system underneath here
basically this goes around a tree farm i
built
i did this in honor of all the people
that donated for me i got a sign for
everybody and when they donated
and i dedicated a tree for each person
and this was like my first main tree
farm
actually i think this is my only tree
farm in the world
which i do still use occasionally but
usually i just go outside and grow trees
and cut them down
because i generally just use jungle
trees for wood
and there's no space to grow them in
here
over here is a piston elevator
these do not work in s p too well and
even sometimes glitch out in single
player
usually it works i'm actually kind of
surprised to then
this takes us up to the surface we got a
nice little bridge area that we built
recently and you go down this is the
main entrance to the cave
actually before we move on here a lot of
people have been asking me where do i
put the comments after every episode
and they've just been piling up in these
chess
mainly until the library is done once we
finish the library
then we'll move them all over there and
organize it the way it's supposed to be
let's head over to the tail farm now i
finally
i have a way up to it to the ufo
you come up here uh there's a
actually pretty complicated water system
uh below us here and
if you get a fishing rod you can go down
at the center of the ufo and hopefully
this still works
uh you can go fishing for cows
which is a lot of fun oh we didn't make
it
i hope this still works no i'm not
getting the lift like we used to uh oh
what's up with that they used to fly all
the way up no problem
um i lost that guy
ah dang
yeah they won't go they used to go in
this water here
and then they would all
water takes them and it brings them over
to
this place here and drops them down i
guess that's not working anymore
oh venus i'm sorry it's our horses
all right we have zenith here and we
have donkey
our new friends um
the cow farm slash wheat farm here is
actually kind of interesting
i made this a long time ago and
at that time if you walked on tilled
soil like we talked about
it would become untilled um but there
was a trick you could do in the game for
a very brief amount of time
where if you put fences underneath the
tilled soil you could run
and jump on it and it would never get
trampled
so the whole farm is has fences
underneath it
but obviously that doesn't work anymore
there's also pistons on the side here
and i think was this for that
oh no that's for the light now i'm
getting serious leg when
i switch that what's up with that it's
just the light
that is really weird i click it once and
it clicks twice even most of the time
okay uh the the wheat farm
switch is here actually
i gotta reset my game something weird is
going on
all the wheat comes out the sides or all
the water comes out the sides
uh it harvests all the wheat falls down
the center
these guys they don't fall down though
because of the iron bars although now if
you breed them they can fall down
and then they end up where they don't
belong
flick that back up
and you're ready to replant
and we have our tail pixel art over
there
and our world map there which i'm still
trying to fill out
that's actually really tough to do
because uh the maps they don't have
coordinates on them so
to line them up side by side is a bit
challenging you have to do it by
sight and sometimes two different areas
look like they belong
side by side uh we have our tools over
here
and then we have on this side wheat and
seeds
and the entrance is here you drop down
and you can exit over here
with this area which we're still kind of
working at this is pretty new
we have jeff in the cage doing what he
does best nothing
and this goes around
i'm going to try set up a shutdown or
something for the slime for him to
eventually because i really
really get annoyed by that slime sound
all the time
i'm not going to go into detail about
these we just built these recently but
we have a snow farm
and we have a wheat carrot
potato and cocoa bean farm here
it uses bone meal to grow them uh if we
if we head on head on down we have
wilson our
tamagotchi pet over here we're trying to
build
this is a big redstone project lots
lots and lots of complicated stuff is
going on with this build
and it's actually my favorite build i'm
working on at the moment
although it doesn't really make great
recording
because it's mostly all redstone and
people get bored of that pretty quick
but i've recently designed a bladder
system for wilson
a digestive system and an immune system
which we're about to put in
which determine like uh how he handles
his food and when he gets sick and stuff
which is i think it's going to be pretty
cool when it's all done
he's got happiness hunger weight and
health stats and his age along the top
there
and when this is all running it will be
changing constantly
and our goal is to try to keep them
alive
over here we have a brown mushroom farm
which is not quite done this is sort of
a
it's not an exciting project really so i
don't do too much on it too often but
little by little it's getting close to
done
um and basically there's pistons here
that
switch the lights when mushrooms grow
and if we go over back
let's see what else is there to see here
i guess there's the potion room we could
head on
head on over to the potion room um
again this is one of the things i built
a long time ago
oh yeah project pokemon here the goal
was to collect the six wise men like
six all the six different types of
villagers in the game
this was back before villagers actually
had a purpose
they the villages spawned in but there
was no
trading villagers didn't breed or
anything they didn't really do
anything and they just existed and
usually they died
and i moved them over here and
eventually i will move a priest and
blacksmith here
they have to be like originally
generated
uh villagers i can't breed them to get
the bree the priest and the blacksmith
to complete this
and i just found a priest the other day
from a village
so i think we can complete it finally
got chests over here for trading
crafting table uh let's go in here too
real quick
this is one of the most requested
projects people want me to finish
and it's one of the
it's the ch it's a project i don't know
really what to do with
uh i i originally wanted to like hollow
out a big space here and
build tons of buildings in a nice open
feeling cave
but i realized very quickly that's not
actually
very doable in a cave unless you hollow
a
really really really big space because
i feel these are pretty small houses to
be honest and they take up a ton of
space each one
so kind of my new plan is to instead of
building
here the houses i want to
not really build houses just build
little compartments
for the villagers that they can
retreat into in the cave here and have
them run around the cave this area
instead of
off on their own place here and maybe
get them to do stuff that way
um we have potion dispensers here
um with secret chests behind the lava
and crafting table
uh this is the potion room i don't have
to worry about jeff escaping anymore so
i can actually use the door
this is the first 3x3 door i really made
in the game
and i cheated by not putting a block in
the middle
but it has a cool cool pattern to it
spiral door i really like it
very poor redstone in it though
i could improve it a lot now um
potions and stuff gets stored here
we have tom here making the potions
and the way this works you
have a list of ingredients if we need
glass bottles
we hit the glass bottles button if we
need netherward we hit the netherward
button
and it all falls from the ceiling we can
fill the water bottles
with the water here
i built all this pretty much when
brewing came out
which is around the same time enchanting
came out if i remember right
um
and it all goes into the brewing stands
around you there's 10 of them total
and then if you need other ingredients
like redstone and powder glowstone
spider eyes whatever you hit the other
buttons
but maybe i'll just put these away for
now
people ask about that too by the way you
hold shift and you double click
on the item and it takes them all out or
puts them all in
case you were wondering
lay it on doesn't even try to escape
good guy
good guy tom okay
uh to fill the ingredients there's this
other
room up here uh you throw
block on the ground to open the door
pressure please close it
this is where all the ingredients get
stored these arrays of dispensers
there's 10 dispensers per item and
they're all marked
glycerin melons nether warts
please powder mega mccream
uh again all this could be greatly
improved nowadays but that's
back in the back in the day this was
actually pretty pretty cool i've got an
upper layer
for glass bottles and i think gunpowder
is up here yeah
i got a lot of gunpowder up here
and it all flows down to the center
and i think can i still get down to the
the messy wiring yeah
so it all branches off from the buttons
down here and goes all kinds of
directions and stuff and hopefully
water will never fall down here and
wreck it all
okay how do i get out
i'm lost i think it was think i went too
far
yeah gotta go back here
cool cool that's the brewing room
and what else do we have there's so much
stuff to show i don't think we'll have
time for it all
uh we got a nice waterfall here and a
bridge
we have the furnace room the blazer rods
get stored there
cold there all my cool blocks
uh you put stuff in the furnace these
are all attached to
bud switches so when you put an item in
it turns light on and plays a tune and
also turns on these main lights here if
any of these furnaces are running
we have a light up here that turns on
during the day
and you may have heard the tunes that
play at day and night
that's also connected to that system uh
storage room here
really really like the storage room
although i need more chests now with the
new blocks that have come out
um and again a question that comes up
often is do i use cheats or mcedit or
whatever
and no i do not uh all this
was gathered by me
this is an old world though so i've had
plenty of time to collect stuff
and there's more at other bases too
they're just here we have a block
swapper here to make a crafting table
come out
there's an anvil there
um this is for ender pearls but that's
not set up yet
um then we have the pop-up sheep farm
here this is actually one of my favorite
things i've built
it's probably not working anymore but we
can try it out
and this room goes along with it
before when you cut or when you would
cheer the sheep the wool would always
land within a three by three
area around the sheet but now it like
jumps way farther out which
sort of messes up the whole thing this
thing was
really like amazing combination of
redstone mechanics water mechanics
item mechanics and all kinds of stuff
work together really cool together
but since it involves so many
things that rely on physics of course
those change with the game
quite often and so a lot of the features
with this farm i don't think are really
working anymore
we have a manual resets
drops the sheep down light turns off
there's a master master manual reset
for all of them
they all go down and then there was also
a water reset
that causes water to fall from the
ceiling and if
there was wool within
the area it would fall down these grates
here
and uh reset for
only the ones where wool was on the
ground and also the wool would get
collected
and it gets sent to this thing here to
this room
kind of like this it's uh but since the
wall go
like jumps out further than it used to
it doesn't really
wash back into the grates properly
and if we go down
yeah this is the thing here so this is a
a soil block
when a grass grows to it or spreads to
it it triggers one bud switch
and then when the sheep eats it it
triggers a secondary one so it's two
bud switches connected connected
together
and then that makes a piston push the
sheep up
since it's in a piston it doesn't
suffocate because it doesn't count as a
full block
and i'm not
sure if sheep eating grass will cause a
block update anymore
it doesn't look like it i saw that in
the patch notes so this farm
i think is broken i hate to say it
but yeah game changes
constantly and breaks stuff constantly
okay i've actually uh just been watching
it here for a little bit to see what
it's doing
and it is still kind of working just not
like
it originally was um
the bud switches do get triggered when
the grass spreads to the soil but not
when the sheep eats it it looks like so
it's basically twice as slow as it
should be at the moment
there's not really anything i can change
to fix that's just the way
it's just fewer things can be detected
by bud switches now
compared to in the past and sheep eating
grass is one of them
this is the other side of it there's
some fences here when
the wool lands on top of the pressure
plates above it
it triggers the thing to reset and also
the wall flows down
here to a main collection system
but let's move on time
is running out this episode's gonna be
so long i can tell already
uh where should we go next let's go to i
think we're about done with the man cave
here
pretty sure uh we have
our snowflake there that's we have a
portal on top of that
i think i'm gonna actually connect that
to the portal we put on top of the
nether
so when we go through that we'll end up
on top of snowflake
we have our our abandoned mine shaft
here and
our original glowing tree is up there
that's the one you see
in my outro and sometimes i use that for
my intro as well
blowing in the wind and again my intros
my outros are all made by l the hedgehog
greatly appreciate what he's done for me
and i have growing trees throughout the
swamp here let's head on
into here though um
i did this mostly for fun
instead of for function but it does
function pretty good too we have a whole
ton of storage down here i wonder if
there's anything good
actually
just a lot of random stuff i think
yeah i think i used to keep the good
stuff in this chest
uh we have some potion dispensers which
are empty
oh not totally there is a snowman that
walks around
above here and it makes these lights
turning off some turn on and off
sometimes so they flicker
like you can see this one's off at the
moment
just to kind of make it a little
creepier down here
if we go further we have
this thing which is glitching out
actually
i wonder what that's about oops
there's a boat hid in okay
let's get rid of that this was when
when the multiple colors of planks
wooden planks came out like the jungle
wood
the birch and the spruce i made this
thing and
if you put a boat let's just make one
see if it still works
if you put a boat where that lamp is it
makes the lap turn on and also
automatically destroys the boat
oh i can't place it anymore
that's right you can only place bloat
you can only place boats
uh if there's enough air spaces now you
can't place them in walls and stuff like
you used to be able to
like i cleared these out used to be full
of planks and stuff
if we go up
boat up here this is where i would store
the boats
then you break all the chests and you
hit this
that seems to be broken too man lots of
stuff broken
or did that get disabled
of stuff is broken man so down here i
dedicated
a mine shaft to again to all the
donators
i don't accept donations anymore i do
really appreciate the ones i've gotten
in the past so but now
i am getting getting more than enough
money through
the adsense program so i don't feel
right uh
asking for donations or or getting
donations from people anymore so
don't feel the need to contribute
anymore this
is supposed to work with enterprise
again the physics have changed sometimes
you fall through
i actually made it up though so that's
kind of cool
um we have a
river hey good thing i got a boat we can
actually take this for a ride
we have a river here this was all pretty
much
man-made i'm gonna stop recording for
just a sec i'm
actually processing part of this episode
as i go here and it's
lowering my frame rate a lot so i'll be
right back
and we're back uh i decided to wait till
night here
to show you what it looks like with all
the trees and stuff it's pretty cool
uh i'm still getting bad frame rate
though i don't know
why i think i need to reset my computer
or something
you know it might be steam or something
too
i don't know oh wow these boats are a
lot harder control now
oh boy okay do i not have another one
man well anyway there's a river here
uh i i would ride it but we are pressed
for time and
i don't have a boat so we'll just move
on real quick here
uh we oh
we have our field of
sugar cane here this is for
when uh we were exploiting the villager
trading system to get emeralds for
emerald village
uh we have our our uh
glowing jungle trees there we just
planted those because
i used to get all my sand from this area
here and i left the big hole in the
world which i didn't really like so i
covered over it with grass recently
planted some trees and tried to cover it
up
basically um ellie all the mobs
around man
it's crazy here at night because all the
caves are lit up now
pretty much um
we are going to try out the fireworks
today
i recently redid them i'm curious to see
if it works i never did try
uh this is for the redstone controlling
it all
what i did is i got rid of all the fire
randomizers
and instead i didn't put a comparator
here though
darn it i will be right back i want to
try this
okay i think i fixed this now this is
like
the best randomizer in the game at the
moment
it said all it is is a dropper facing up
and it goes to a hopper item goes in the
hopper and then back down pretty much
instantly but it does
trigger this comparator and
these eight items here they stack
into 64. but the sword does not so it
counts as like a full stack
and if you send it a pulse and it
goes to any of these eight items the
pulse only
or the signal only goes one block but if
it chooses the sword
it will travel three blocks and it will
actually trigger
the dispenser above which has the
fireworks in
um so it's like a one in nine chance
with this setup
of course you can take items out if you
want it to be like one and eight or
one and seven or 50 50 whatever you want
or you can
combine two of these together and and
make it
even less odds so
pretty cool um
we'll try this out at the end that was
at the end of the episode though because
it's daytime now so we'll keep moving
keep on moving we'll come back to this
later
let's go i really don't think we're
going to be able to see
everything today oh man i totally forgot
about this thing
we got to do something with this guys
this is my
my detector thing when we when we cross
a line it can tell if we
or it can tell when we cross the line
that's what i'm trying to say
what is dude that looks really weird
when it's not rendered
i thought i had a floating like piston
door there for some reason
oh look at all the villagers all in one
house
this is the first village i found in my
world
i totally i totally cleared it of all
villagers and i brought them back to the
cave and i think it
yeah i brought all the villagers back
actually so it was totally empty and
then i decided to restore it at one
point
and upgrade it so i put a fence around
it
keep the mobs out i upgraded it with all
these lamps
over here that go throughout the village
i added extra doors so that the village
would actually function
because with one
one door per house they don't ever breed
um i also
i also made these wheat farms actually
function
pull the lever does that
tons and tons of pistons
one for each block because i wanted to
keep the
the shape the same like compared to
normal
villager wheat farm
if we go here we have an entrance to the
place this is
this is actually a pretty nice door it's
very very fast three by three door again
with the block missing in the middle
uh nice window here if we go into here
takes us to
the nether obviously
but like a little branch off in the
nether we can use this to transport
uh villagers to that village if we want
or take them from it
this goes to
the place where we got the villagers
from originally here
the villager purifier area
this is a big overly complicated thing i
set up just to
spawn zombie villagers from a zombie
spawner here
wait up is off why was it on
uh it spawns them from there and then we
can sort them out
or send them to a killing area here
any zombie villagers we collect end up
in these little
places and then we can
cure them with weakness potions and
there's mine carts to send them out to
the portals
and a few other it's actually pretty
complicated redstone here
this is set up in such a way that it can
tell if there's a villager in the spot
and it only dispenses weakness
and the weakness potions and carts and
stuff
if there's a villager there needing it
to be done
got a ceiling pretty cool ceiling up
there
let's move on let's go out i'll show you
i'm trying to avoid cutting this episode
so you can see how
all these things are related and
positioned to each other
if we go further this way we have
our big mob farm here it's made out of
snow
this goes to our second main base which
is more of just like
a test area for me at the moment
but we can go down and check it out
so we have our mob system this is where
i get all my gun powder and stuff
mainly uh we have a
sorting system to separate the mobs it's
not quite working perfectly at the
moment
and we're gonna later really add to this
thing and make it
um into an automatic tree farm and stuff
looks like it's backed up too at the
moment
skeletons fall down creepers run
straight because the
cat scares them and zombies go to the
left towards the villager there
it's actually running really good at the
moment i'm surprised
oh there we go failed
all right um
did i show this the rest of stuff
a lot of this might change still like
this all this wooden area and stuff
i'm not too happy with it it doesn't
look bad either
but i probably will end up changing it
then we have this silver fish farm here
this thing really like this thing it
we have a silver fish spawner there
they end up going to this this stone
here which is generated by a stone
generator
um every time a silverfish enters a
block
it will send out a new one and it
creates this big strip
of blocks that all collect together in
this one spot and then we can
then we can collect them all and move
them other places if we want
uh-huh
okay we're really gonna have to keep
moving here because we're like 50
minutes in
from what i can tell and uh we're not
gonna be able to see everything today
so i just got some stuff
uh this is the end i haven't built a lot
here
i've angered some endermen here i
oh wow i still have that set up i
haven't come here too often i don't use
my
ender ender as much as i used to i
mainly use
of course you're mad i wouldn't want to
be you either
um i mostly use my blaze farm for
experience instead of the ender ender
here
but every now and then i'll use this one
too
this one's actually quicker you can't
place
wow you can't place boats
in water anymore even like it it won't
let you
for the eats road
i have a bad feeling about this
i
shouldn't be doing this but i can't stop
because i want to see what's
going to happen here this is a new one
for me
all right so we're riding the eats road
um this is kind of cool oh we're
dropping quicker
i'm gonna die
what the heck
guys i don't know what happened
um
yeah so i don't know how if we're going
to see the ender ender after all
i think if i if i can break the boat
we'll be fine uh-oh
i better be able to kill myself here i
did make a backup before i started this
episode but
um
this could be bad i'm gonna re-log
okay each road is a bit out of
commission hey we did end up at the
end of it though that's good uh this is
my
[Music]
my ender ender here uh this
was one of the first of its kind like
this
uh when i built this enderman farms they
were
like always at the main island there
people were not building out in the void
so this was a big
change with the way people made enderman
farms
and people weren't really making
enderman farms for experience before
they were
mostly doing it for ender pearls but
when i built this to my surprise it was
a really
good experience farm
um and then people kind of took this
idea and
made it a lot better like panda he uh
he discovered that trick with the vines
that allowed you to stack
spawning platforms together in the end
oh he's still mad let's go back let's go
back
uh but basically they get dropped down
to one hit kill
from our ender ender up there it's a
whole bunch of pistons
and pressure plates when they spawn on
the pressure plates get pushed down
and they fall like 40
43 blocks i think it is on to our
platform here
you look at them they all cluster to one
point and you kill them
all right i brought us back here we're
gonna go to one last place before we end
this
again i'm sorry but we don't have time
to see quite everything
this episode but i feel we did uh
pretty good with the amount of time we
had or that we used
uh this is another hub
it's going gonna be the main branch
branch off to different areas
for quick travel in my world
uh which is sort of set up sort of not
supposed to be a selector panel for
choosing different destinations
and if we run through the tunnel here
we will eventually get to
the dual blaze farm which is
what i usually use when i want
experience in my world
there is another fortress up over here
i got really lucky with this one too as
i found this is like the second fortress
i explored in this world and it just
happened to have a
dual blaze farm in it and they were
positioned really nicely from each other
and it all worked out pretty good
granted this took me a long time to
build
because i went through so many uh
so many tests and stuff with it why are
they free
why is he free he must have spawned in
the fortress and
this is wandering around i'm guessing
so it's pretty loud i got it all on a
clock
which activates that conveyor belt there
which brings them all to one central
point
they spawn here and here
they go down this like funnel thing that
put that
moves them all into one main spot
and then at the at the bottom of the
funnel there is where they connect to
the conveyor belt
pushed to the lava which forces them to
swim up
to this killing chamber here
you open the gates
lets them up they swim up to the very
top there and then when you're ready to
kill them you hit the crusher button
that closes the gate again and activates
the crusher
puts the block in their head space so
they take suffocation damage
gets them down to like one hit kill
and then you throw a damaged potion at
them i'm not going to do that though
because i think i'll hit one of these
big men here and they will probably kill
me
uh-huh up here is the wiring for the
the pressure system and everything
pretty simple each of these uh repeaters
counts for eight ticks because of the
way i have it set up
um using a special pulse extender
and yeah i think that's about it so
let's sorry to rush through all this
it's it's a lot to show in a single
episode
we're gonna go to the firework display
and read a comment
and we'll call it an end
man i went afk for just a little bit
during the day mind you
waiting for it to be night and i come
back
and i'm dead some skeleton with a flame
bow killed me
during the day apparently uh
yeah let's end this episode with
fireworks i have no idea how well this
is going to work like
how random and whatever it's going to be
but we'll see
or if it's even going to work oh
it's not going to work without another
piece of redstone
which i don't have
how about that is there
any anyway i could fake it um
that's oh you know what i could do this
is what i could do
improvise
right oh man they're going quick that's
good
awesome they're still pretty random
looking too
[Music]
yeah i'm happy with that
all right i love the fireworks in this
game so much
gotta get more of them here though
that is a really good speed for him i
like that
yeah yeah very good
excellent all right question for the day
etho do you prefer coke or pepsi and i
may have answered this in the past i
can't remember
but uh neither i am
sort of allergic to pop uh i don't
really have any allergies but i
if i was to say i have one it would be
pop because
[Music]
when i when i drink pop
and i'm under a lot of like stress like
bodily stress like either i'm tired or
i'm working in the heat or something
doing a lot of physical work uh i tend
to get nosebleeds from
drinking pop weirdly is what i found
is seems to be the root cause of them i
don't really get them anymore now that i
stopped drinking pop
[Applause]
in the past i used to have it like
daily and i would get really bad
nosebleeds like almost
like go to the hospital because i lost
so much blood
and they're not stopping type of
nosebleeds so they were pretty serious
but uh i'm fine now that i stopped
drinking pop
um i think i did prefer coke though
uh anyway i hope you guys enjoyed the
tour i hope you liked the episode
sorry to rush through it like we did
especially towards the end there
didn't quite see everything but uh at
least we got a fireworks show
ugly brown you make a return
alright guys thanks for watching bye bye