ah come on
why isn't this working there's
definitely something wrong with this
middle head not functioning quite right
so hello everybody this is etho how is
everyone doing today welcome back to
another episode I was admiring the the
horse animation and physics in it before
I started here very flexible very
flexible very spaghetti bone-like
structure to this guy I liked it Vigo is
Charlie the Unicorn
or the pink and the purple guys could do
this to you
and even just left and right is amazing
so sleek so snazzy amazing yeah so start
off with today we're just gonna fight a
wither real quick I I only got two
beacons in this world and I wouldn't
mind getting a few more around here
definitely could use a few more can
access your inventory when you're on a
horse you gotta get off so we weren't
sure yet another one here
I've been improving my wither skeleton
farm and it seems to be working out
better get that you should probably run
to we're gonna try to fight them on a
horse and see if we can keep the horse
alive this we're gonna try strafing to
the right
constantly not working okay are you on a
cactus what's going on oh he's doing the
withered thing now that horse is a lost
cause I'm sorry he's known as Venus the
horses they do this thing where they
gallop that pursuit they take you wither
damage makes it really long I'm gonna
die here run away that was convenient
oh I never used I never used that that
probably would have helped we got 20
seconds that was a bad throw guy I'm
pretty close to pretty close to one of
my bases here session to leave them
alone for too long go down I'm down here
oh please for the smoke quick almost
there almost there
once it's sort mode it's like whoa come
on come on come on yeah oh look at that
look at that achievement that is fancy
stuff it was like glowing and everything
whoo-hoo we got our third nether star in
this world I'm gonna live I'm gonna live
this is what I fought them with - by the
way I forgot to show you got a power
five smite for good stuff so I brought
what we need this is gonna be our third
beacon and we're gonna try to put it to
use today excellent so that one pretty
well we got our beacon here in the ender
chest plus I took the one off the nether
sealing because I wasn't really using it
and we need it for what we're about to
do here so I got iron I got we're gonna
have to use gold because I don't have
any more iron not yet anyway we'll get
more pretty soon I think
but last episode I talked about I like
have to resort to mining for branch
mining for redstone which is something I
don't mind doing once in a while I don't
really enjoy branch mining in this game
I think it's really a really bad idea to
branch mine when you're playing survival
I think it kills the fun for a lot of
people ends unless it's something you
enjoy doing of course but I think a lot
of people when they're branch mining the
thought enters their head that's you
know what I don't like doing this this
isn't fun I could just be playing
creative and get all these resources and
not have to mess around with it I think
it I think it's a bad bad practice in
general if you're playing survival cuz
it'll kill your joy so I try not to do
it I like to go TV but even caving too
much of it isn't good either and I've
been doing lots of caving like too much
so I don't really want to go caving
anymore so I had this idea while branch
mining last episode which I tried out on
the minecraft server and it worked
really good actually better than I
thought it would I guess we'll set up
let's do 700 negative 700 100 yeah I
think that's a good place it's this can
be grindy too though don't get me wrong
but I enjoy doing this this is kind of
like mining sand sort of thing which
which I don't mind doing by the way this
is raped by the realistic mining cave if
you're wondering with the bed and that
was all about up there okay so we're
gonna go all the way down to Y 11 or so
and I'll just show you how to set this
up and how it works idea is it's nothing
like super like amazing or anything like
that is just setting up a beat in with
haste to on it top to your beacon and if
you have a second beacon you can even
set up speed to right next to it get
efficiency 5 pick oh I was digging
straight down that red stone excellent
sounds like we're coming down at the
cave I'm gonna push forward as I mind
that one so even if there was lava I
think I would have lived I think okay so
what we're gonna do is this red stone
I'm gonna have to take it maybe we'll
just set up a little base here get our
ender chest down that's what we need I
don't want to get my fortune pick I
think I've packed one you're gonna want
to have a fortune pick with you maybe a
silk touch as well and since I I could
afford it I made five efficiency five
picks that are named so I can repair
them costs thirty three levels to repair
them each time and you pretty much get
that just from doing the mining here
from like redstone and stuff as you come
across it and I'm gonna set up a beacon
right here to beacons right here so give
me a moment then beacon aider old baby
so I got I got these set up
you guys select what we want from them
though so let's change this to a Stu has
to be maxed out beacon to get hey Stu of
course and these have a range of a
radius of 50 blocks so they go quite
aways no hurry
[Music]
creeper could be come in any moment this
is an open cave not the best place to
set up okay and I said I had five of
these only I'm sorry I had five on my
mind though so we're gonna take one out
you can see five I got plenty of
inventory space here and I just set up a
little champ here like drop off
cobblestone and dirt sand and the
goodies we find and stuff it's
definitely a cave must I think it's
above it must be above so I I messed
around with this for a bit I on the
minecraft server I tried to slate mining
every single block and isn't that that
was fine but I found if you're going for
efficiency if you just want to get as
much as you can I think the best way of
doing is probably to dig it
y12 I'm guessing I meant wrong pick
that's fortune so yeah if you have
efficiency five and hey Stu you can mine
do the super mining thing which is
amazing I love it
I do have speed - yep
so what you do you just go instead of
doing little branches all over the place
just take everything out sort of - high
area if you can and it won't be long
you'll get it pretty crazy how much you
can actually get from doing this I
believe that more redstone and you can
go a long ways away from that beacon
before you have to move it again
definitely got to watch out for lava
though you might want a fire protection
on your armor if you're doing this
yes what's the time it's pretty easy to
avoid the lab I find oops so when you do
come across something you want like
redstone take out your fortune pick line
it up and once your inventory is all
full then you can drop stuff off and
yeah just from just from mining redstone
in that I find it yet you can get 33
levels pretty quickly before year like
before this pick runs out of juice even
ten levels already there's more redstone
and if you do this swiping motion left
and right so you don't usually break the
the redstone or whatever block you
uncover I find emerald so they break
pretty quickly so you might have to be
more careful if you're if you're trying
to keep your emeralds from breaking and
yeah
it goes pretty good yeah if you get iron
quick doing this gold quick but
especially redstone and unmentionable
blue stuff the diamonds pretty cool so I
think I think the way I'm gonna be doing
it that's probably the most efficient to
do it at y12 and i think i'm gonna do it
at at y5 is where you reach bedrock so I
think maybe y6 would give you a good
coverage that leaves two or three blocks
I think it's wait a minute okay so this
is why twelve one two three four five
yeah I think that's good there'll be
like two or three blocks between the two
layers that way and since the ores they
they form in a clump you're most likely
Anna's gonna see anything that forms
between the two layers as well and
diamonds go down or start it I think why
16 so just like a couple blocks above
where we're at here so most likely we're
gonna see just about every single or
like picking out these blocks and bring
the shovel with you because there's tons
of drips and gravel along there
oh yeah so check it out this is like
this is maybe ten minutes later so I've
been doing a bit of mining I used up the
durability on one of the pics and I just
wanted to show you how much space you
can clear out with one and I've been
trying my best not to mine any of the
ores I saw just so yeah idea of how that
words are spaced out too and yeah lots
of redstone oh baby so I think my
redstone crisis has been solved and yeah
this can be grindy - don't get me wrong
but it's personally I find it enjoyable
it's there's something very peaceful
about digging like in this way and like
Seth and Paz commented on that - when we
were mining out the clay on the
minecraft server that just digging a big
area somewhat enjoyable it's very
relaxing branch mining is - I guess in a
way so I don't know whatever floats your
boat I guess but this this is the way
I'm gonna be doing it and not only that
there's also a downstairs I started a
lower level just to try it out and it's
pretty good it's not not quite as
efficient on the lower level I think
there's less diamonds and also you have
to deal with the lava a little bit more
this is a good example though like if
you if you see couldn't you weren't able
to see these diamonds from the top layer
but you can see it from that the bottom
layer here oh yeah and you get tons of
XP from diamonds
that's about all they're good for yeah
yeah so it's pretty good pretty good I
like it
eighteen levels so it's gonna cost 33 to
repair the pic if you want to while
you're doing this if you don't have a
good XP farm and XP is actually really
important to you you can like clean up
this lava as you go bring some iron
budgets with you and pick it up and use
it to smelt all the cobblestone you get
if you want and you'll get XP from that
too
I don't think I'm gonna be doing that
maybe I might set up an auto smelter
just to get the stone I don't I don't
think I'd really bother for it or bother
with it for the XP because I have an
Enderman farm but that's another way you
can get XP 2 and you get XP from
smelting the iron and the gold and
whatnot so well it works out pretty good
and it only costs 3 diamonds to repair
the pick which we've definitely turned
up in this in this excavation and if you
do this and you're going to go repair
your work pick make sure you don't like
if you do it this way
it's 33 levels if you do it this way oh
it's only 27 but you don't get to keep
the name on the pick so you lose the
name which means you won't be able to
repair it in the future or at least not
for cheap so do it that way but anyway I
guess that's enough mining for today I
used up the durability on another pick
so I did double what I did before and we
got that's we got that going that and
that for the iron and gold you get a lot
of gold from it it's it's pretty pretty
good way of getting gold especially but
yeah and check this out I have not seen
this much redstone in my world I think
ever four four stacks of blocks plus we
got that we got a good amount of
repeaters and comparators so Wilson Oh
Wilson I might just finish your brain
after all I haven't haven't messed with
them in a long time but I've I've had
that urge again he's still he's still
dead people keep asking about him he's
that project it's good
be awesome if I ever finish it but it is
really complicated and I keep changing
my mind with what I want to do with it I
think I need to simplify it some more
maybe I don't know okay so I got
something to show you guys this this is
a a glitch maybe I thought maybe it was
a display error like with the snapshots
but it's still there I haven't tried
trading with this villager but this is a
really really weird trade I think it's
glitched out just some extent so this
guy Tom our buddy Tom here somehow his
trade changed I think cuz he we give him
a book and he gives us that so we just
have to give him a book for that I I
think there used to be an emerald here
and it's gone Oh exactly so I'm
wondering if it's gonna work it works
okay thank you Tom could you get a few
more trades like that please isn't that
uh I thought till maybe librarians do
trade that I don't know I haven't been
treating very much I thought it was a
priest thing though no new trade ah
what's going on Tom huh that new sound
effect he's like getting angry okay that
unlocking very interesting and he got
paper sweet just take all of them why
not get more okay there we go
whoo I'll take that trade any day more
like that please Etha has just earned
the achievement delicious fish
I wanted to do a little bit of trading
with these guys my original plan with
this by the way was to get all the
villagers here and unlock all the trades
so I hit a brick wall with this guy
the butcher he needs pork and I don't
have any pork this guy he's needed fish
for a long to uh a long time here twelve
coat fish how am I supposed to get that
well thanks to the fishing huts I've
actually done some fishing so after a
very very long time we finally unlocked
the trade with him
I hope nope wait it got cheaper what is
going on what is going on here I'm
confused
yeah I brought I brought more just in
case this is all my fish come on man
come on
nope no way he wants more fish what a
guy alright well we can't do that this
guy I hit the end maybe but this one
Mazal trade with him to you let's see
what he gives us a little paper here
they're really really talkative aren't
they I guess it's because I'm trading
that makes sense nope alright Tom what
do you got
you must have unlocked something new hmm
no why not is this one open again
what or was it never closed now it's
closed for sure okay okay I went and I
fished six more of these guys for that
greedy little villager he better give us
something new this time I'm gonna be
very upset because a long time to get
fish oh my goodness
but I'm very excited about this this is
the first non-fish catch I got and I got
a saddle so that is pretty cool that's a
good item like I've never gotten trash
or anything that was the first non-fish
thing that found alright come on
don't be greedy farmer oh there we go
bread I'll take some bread if it'll make
you happy today when I went when I went
to record I noticed this orange piece of
plastic on my floor and it came from my
headset so my last pair did this to
where the glue seems to give out after
two years or so or a year and a half
whatever it's been so I put the piece
back where it belongs but the goo like
that's holding it together
he's seeping out everywhere and I
decided to wrap it with electrical tape
that I had in my drawer and apparently
the electrical tape was very old too and
it's doing the same thing where the glue
is like running and it's it's like
getting all over my hair now it's
terrible my hairs sticking to my headset
and it feels so bad
alright chicken I don't have any chicken
so you will we'll come back to in the
future let's go back to this guy this is
my new best friend over here he wanted
books oh I was one for there short why
did I do that oh you know I think I'm
gonna think do you actually have to do
that hey hey stop moving
he is dodging my cursor all right uh
click didn't do it either mm-hmm what
else you got I think that's gonna open
up the book trading into you yeah yeah
that's back yeah these are open again
this is a glitch right guys I don't do a
lot of trading
but I'm pretty sure that's supposed to
cost emeralds could you imagine if that
was looting yourself thinking it was and
it was free that would be so cool I'm
probably not gonna use these but still
hey why not all right we can do that
don't run away from me I'm trading with
you that hurts and he's gonna want
another 10 more you I know it already
yeah I knew it uh is it worth doing I
just want to see what all opens up she'd
probably set up a proper village I did
start that one I should I should work on
that more
all right so so many projectile books
okay let's go back I find the guy rid of
this torch that was here by the way I
put in a light that I think that's the
best way of dealing with it
so this area is totally torch free which
is awesome that was the last one that's
been bugging me
but I just gotta stroll today don't do
it again I know you're greedy Tom and
underpaid oh that's the worst start it
I'm doing it
I don't care guys been here forever you
better have all these trades unlocked
one more come on I've given you like a
stack of emeralds now no that's free
again right yeah I'm gonna take
advantage of that he's gonna charge me
that much I'm definitely taking these
all right anyway that's enough trading
uh I just thought this one was really
interesting okay everyone so it is
common time for this episode I picked
out three today we haven't done three in
a long time get things rolling around
here literally didn't hear it rolling uh
where's my other switch how come I can't
remember how to use this thing I thought
it was over here it is over here yeah
alright oh maybe we won't run that one
that is causing a lot of leg okay so
comment number one etho are you you
thought are you or any other minecraft
guys gonna play feed the beast again so
currently the feed the beast server is
down it's we didn't I think we sort of
decide as a group that we're not gonna
be using it anymore not because we
weren't really having fun with it it
just it doesn't work too well with
multiplayer there's too many problems to
make technical problems like server
crashes and lag and stuff so I don't
think we're gonna be doing too much
multiplayer stuff with it although we
might can't talk too much about it but
we might do feed the beast again in the
future with a different different style
to it otherwise I might do it
single-player eventually one day but no
definite plans at the moments setting
question AES oh I'm really new to your
Survival Series this is the first one
I've watched and I was wondering if you
have a recent world tour I could watch
check on this tomorrow
episode 275 was my last official world
tour around this place and I believe
it's the video that plays if you check
out my channel and you're not subscribed
so episode 275 if you want to see a
world tour and third comment this one's
a weird one I thought it'd be fun to
answer it though hey etho I've been
looking at videos on lucid dreams or a
dream where you know you're dreaming and
either take control or wake up and I'm
wondering have you ever had a lucid
dream if not what's the best dream
you've had so generally if you get more
lucid dreams if you go to bed when
you're not super tired I find but I
always go to bed when I'm super tired so
I don't dream anymore at least well I do
but I don't remember them you always
dream unless there's something wrong
with you so generally I don't dream
anymore but I talked to a youtuber about
lucid dreams he kind of brought up the
subject because it was something he did
before and he was telling me the process
involved with how it works and all that
and he said never never do it because he
kind of went crazy from it because he
had ideas that I sort of tricked your
mind into
you have to do these things to your mind
and basically it worked out where he
couldn't tell if he was dreaming or not
if like you couldn't distinguish between
the real world and a lucid dream so he
was starting to go crazy from it so be
careful if you if you get into that
stuff and I'm wondering have you ever
known that there's a dream if not what's
the best dream you've had what about one
of my favorite dreams I I had it was
actually a dream where I died and I
thought it was kind of comical basically
a nuclear bomb went off at the end of it
and I saw the explosion coming towards
me very quickly and I screamed and what
do you do when you when you die in a
dream you wake up not in this dream that
what happened is everything went black
and then credits started rolling up in
my eyes or whatever in my head like it
was a movie or something I couldn't read
the credits so but I'm guessing I was I
was the main producer and everything of
my dream yep okay thanks for watching
everybody next episode we are most
likely going to go do some exploring my
plan is I put a lot of thought into this
I'm gonna switch my world over to
amplified terrain and that means
everything we explore here on out is
gonna be amazing
like some of the coolest stuff you can
see I've tried recording an amplified
terrain my computer can handle it once I
have the area loaded pretty well it's
not the greatest for exploring I would
have to explore there ya have it all
load then start recording but it's fine
if I like start building in an area
should be okay yep okay have a good day
everybody I'll talk to you next time
thanks for watching
bye-bye
[Music]