[Music]
wow
now isn't that just the most beautiful
thing you've ever laid your eyes upon
it's breathtaking absolutely beautiful
you might be thinking you know your wife
your girlfriend no
you might want to reconsider because
this stuff sparkles
look at that sparkle uh
i got a bunch of redstone we might need
it today so
i went caving for a bit got tons of
redstone iron all the good stuff that we
need
all the time and we are going to
probably enchant something once i finish
uh
yes i'm using fortune right yeah
just gotta double check because i would
be very sad if i was using my other pick
um yeah we'll probably get the level 30
easy from this we will enchant the sword
i think
yeah i didn't quite finish getting all
the redstone but we did get
thirty
so i keep trying to get unbreaking three
on my swords now
that it's possible i want to see it
again i i did it once
unbreaking three looting three come on
whoa sharpness for unbreaking three
knock back to fire aspect two enchanting
swords has got a lot more fun
oh they don't stand that chance
that's a fire aspect no
fire aspect look i've used it that many
times and it still hasn't taken any
durability off of it
oh there we go first one
that is pretty cool unbreaking is very
nice
we used to durability
out of all those swings why is it not
setting mobs on fire though
huh even when it doesn't kill him
anyway whatever no big deal
um i actually don't really like fire
aspect anymore now that zombies can set
you on fire it's actually
very dangerous sometimes when you use it
but i've been working on something i've
been wanting to do for a long time
everybody
and it's finally done
the map has been complete oh it looks so
much better than what we had there
before doesn't it like with all the the
unconnected item frames that were empty
and now we have a nice beautiful
map um
you can't really see a whole lot from it
from a distance except for maybe the
basic terrain um as i was doing this was
actually kind of sad because
you know it wasn't surprising but a lot
of the stuff i've built is underground
and you can't actually see it on the map
so there's not a lot to see
from it but it's kind of encouraged me
maybe we should start building on the
surface a bit more in fact as i was
running around
mapping out my world here i saw a lot of
very nice areas
especially around these mountains this
area here is very nice
so we might want to start building there
sometime soon in the future
but i'll take you through some of the
terrain
and stuff some of the features of our
world maybe we will
expand this i didn't pick the best spot
for this actually
we might uh we might set up more maps in
other places
these aren't too bad on your computer
anymore
because dinner bone has it so it only
renders the map i think
when it loads now instead of like every
frame like it was doing before
so it's a lot easier on your computer
but
we are right there you can see my little
wooden bridge
over here that goes over top the river
this is my man-made
river that goes all the way down here we
got the trees on the sides
that are all lit up it also splits off
this way this is that
fake overhang fake terrain i built over
top that the river goes underneath
now we got the snowflake over there this
is the ravine
that i first saw in the world close to
close to spawn that's the glowing tree
up there on the
the snow-covered mountain now um
that's the giant reed farm over here uh
the jungle
jungle trees with the hanging glowstone
is over there
that's also where my sand pit is i
covered that all up
trying to make it look nicer this is the
cyan
clay road lined with leaves that goes up
towards the library which is up over
here
and you see it's all flattened out and
yeah we gotta build that still um
let's see what else this little thing is
the spawn platform right up in the sky
and little sheep farm over here this
is the lake firework lake over here with
the you've been ethos sign
there um there's a desert up this way
which i didn't really know about i
usually don't go up this way because
it's mostly water
but yeah if we go a little further
there's a desert
and let's see down
this way is towards the strongholds base
if we go down
uh it's actually about 800 blocks from
here go straight down
and apparently this is within range on
the map
this is what my new pit for getting sand
where i've been moving the silver fish
and where we fight the withers usually
it's over there um pretty much
all this section here
to the right is mountains and you can
see some places where the snow's falling
already
this is probably where we're going to be
expanding in the future if we want to
build on the surface
let's go this way because round here is
a very nice
nice area and we might want to try
extend
the water like try to make rivers that
go out that way
if we take out the land here
uh there's just little land pieces
connecting or preventing the water from
connecting all the way through or we
could go over top and do the same
pretty much and make it go down maybe
and yeah
there's a snow biome there i think up to
the left
here is a jungle biome if i remember
right
and yeah so that's our world this part
of it
there's actually quite a bit around the
stronghold base too
that we can't see on here like the
village and all that
but uh nice little overview of our world
anyway
i'll give you a quick overview of the
world too from on top this tree you can
see a lot of
the things i pointed out give you a
better idea help you visualize where
things are
um that's the water that way mountains
that way stronghold is that way
and not much is back that way but
yeah what do you guys think of the new
rendering code in the snapshot
personally i find it makes everything
look pretty good like especially stuff
in the background
except for maybe the leaves i don't like
the way leaves look very much
and i've tried changing the settings you
can't get them to look the way they used
to i don't think
like not too sure what is it's like
they're more transparent now you can
really see the birchwood through those
trees for example
it really stands out and then when
there's a big clump of leaves like
in pretty much all these trees it looks
like they're solid blocks like
they're very non-transparent
so it's like it's like they they're
really transparent but they're not
they're they're really untransparent
non-transparent whatever
so i don't know maybe they'll they'll
change the leaves up a bit
but everything else i think looks pretty
good
um different acts
so the plan for today guys you don't
often see this i'm chopping down trees
right now
and i actually do a lot of things in my
worlds that take a bit of time that you
don't really see
like chopping trees collecting sand
collecting clay collecting quartz going
caving
and something we touched on last episode
that we're going to
maybe work on a bit more today except in
a different way
is moving items around and just general
general transport and that in my world
takes quite a bit of time
yeah i don't mind if that breaks um
so i had this idea today it's a little
complicated um
might not work perfectly but we will see
i
i did mess with it in creative already
and i think i got it to work
actually spent like i spent two or three
hours oh there it goes
uh trying to get this idea to work like
just the basics of it
and i finally figured out a way to do it
uh it was actually kind of frustrating
because it used to work no problem and
now it's like game mechanics have
changed and i had a lot of trouble with
it
but the idea is we're going to try
build a portal network
almost like the internet in my world i
don't know it's
uh i want to try
link all the portals together in a
certain way
um not the not the overworld portals
like the ones in
in this world just the nether ones i
want connected together
and to interact with each other in
different ways and if it works out the
way i'm planning
we will be able to move myself
items like like if i want to move
several stacks of ender pearls
um or even moving animals like silver
fish or
anything in my world i'll be able to
move
everything within like a 2000 by 2000
area
uh to another part of my worlds within
30 seconds or less i think with if this
idea works out the way i'm planning
which could be pretty cool um
but we'll see how it goes and it's going
to take a little while to set up
for all the portals but
let's let's get to it i'm going to hop
over to the nether
we'll try rig up one of one of the
portals the way it needs to be
for the stronghold base first off
[Music]
all right so the stronghold portal was
over here before i'm moving it right now
uh just in case this becomes a more
permanent thing i want it in a better
spot
and i want to try and make a 3x3
i think it looks cooler i like odd
numbers a lot more than even numbers
in this game
that should work good
and stronghold
oh okay yeah we're here good
and will we go back
yes we will awesome
i think as we work here i'm going to
just disable this one
so we don't hear it the whole time uh
the idea is actually really simple and i
can
demonstrate it real quick here i'm
sure you're familiar with it let's
pretend
let's pretend uh soil blocks are nether
portals
like like this one here so if you have a
nether portal
and we'll use stone bricks for an
overworld portal
so those two are linked together and
they're
in the correct position in overworld and
and the nether right
now if you build another overworld
portal
like a thousand blocks away and you go
in this one it's gonna take you to the
nether portal all the way over here and
then when you go through this nether
portal again
it takes you to that one so
when you when you go through
an overworld portal it checks 128 block
radius
in the nether for uh for another portal
so that 1024 divided by 8
is 128 blocks and if there is one in
that range it will link to that but then
it
when it goes back to the overworld it
checks for the nearest one within i
think 256 blocks
radius so it's only going to check like
up to here and of course since there's
one right where it's supposed to be it's
going to link up with that
one right
so you can use that to
to get quick transport like a long
distance
because you go you go into the nether
and then you go
back to the overworld you've moved a
thousand blocks just by going through
two portals which is pretty cool
uh the thing is you can't get back there
right
you can't um you have to walk it right
so that's why people set up several
like multiple portals in the nether
right so if you put the
nether portal another one linked up
properly with this one
if you go through this one you go to
that one then you can walk in the nether
it's only 128 blocks or so
and then go to that one and then when
you go through that you go back down and
you go
there and so forth but you don't go from
there to there anymore or from there to
there
unless you do what i'm trying to do and
that is
uh enable and disable the nether portals
so that for example even though we still
have the nether portal set up
i want to disable them so i can go from
like
from there to there you know and send
items or animals
through the portal go to there then i
can send them through again
and they'll end up here you know and i
can do that with many many portals if i
set it up right
which is what we're attempting to do
right now
maybe all uh
actually you know an easy way of
disabling a portal
there we go much quieter
so let's begin this is
how we are going to do it
um see if i can remember how to build
this so
dispensers this one's going to have
flint and steel in
if you have flint and stealing you can
lights
like the portal with that no problem
and obviously
we will put that in there so we got to
send two pulses to that
it'll pick up the the lava and it'll
break the portal
and that's how we're going to enable and
disable the portals flint and steel
and lava bucket pretty simple
uh we'll get a button maybe we'll just
put the button down
here
and
do that so now when you press a button
it'll light the portal
and we want it to go
let's see let's take out some of this
let's set up the
the lava budget thing so that's a little
more complicated but there is an easy
way to do
it if we
see i think uh
you get a sticky piston a block
and send a repeater
through it like that so when that goes
it'll it'll activate it once and now to
get it to activate again
we will also split the signal
go this way we got to set it to two to
give it enough time
and
block like that like that
and that so go into the dispenser then
it
does two ticks goes to that dust and
back to the dispenser and it'll click it
again
two clicks very good and all we need to
do now
is connect um
oops this button to
i think 10 to 10 or 11 repeaters it's
got to have 41 ticks
so i'll set that up
oh you can tell i've been here for a
little while we got tons and tons of gas
out there but i think i got it working
now
um so yeah if we go around we have
one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven repeaters
all of these are set to four except for
this one it's set at one
so it's 41 redstone ticks total
and i also set up two more buttons here
this is just a manual
uh enable for the portal this bottom one
goes right to that dispenser like so
and the top one is a manual disable
which goes right to
the disable mechanism up there
nice and simple so this is for the timer
takes four seconds to go through the
portal
and then it disables it so
ah this is what gave me all the trouble
though because in the past
let's say we had an eight second timer
on this thing eight second redstone
timer
uh you could go in within the first four
seconds and then
the redstone would continue after you
went through for another four seconds
and disable it all on its own no problem
not anymore in the game when you go
through
a portal and you leave the nether the
redstone
stops it actually stops where it's at
and remembers
next time you load up the chunks unless
you got some special
chunk loading setup going on it will not
disable the portal
so i had to figure out how to make it do
that
and i team up with a bit of a cheaty way
so it takes us four 40 ticks to go
through and then there's one tick
left let's hope this works
you heard the piston go right as we went
in there
so now i'm gonna drink this just in case
we have trouble i can't remember if this
was still a problem
um we go through
[Music]
oh did it actually work what the heck
uh usually i have to do something else
to make it work
but that just worked on its own
that's interesting okay
is that a good thing or a bad thing i
kind of liked it the way it was before
hmm let's try one more
time maybe maybe there's mobs here that
are keeping it
loaded or something
okay i'm gonna go back through
oh unless yeah this was taking us to
that portal before right
ah anyway i guess that works so
if we go through this one we we got
teleported a little bit of ways
in the nether here because this takes us
to the village now
instead of to the stronghold so that is
the general idea
behind it the real complicated part to
all of this
now
is what i would like to do is set up
like a destination selector outside of
each of these portals so
have like a wall of buttons and let's
say go to stronghold hit the button
and then that needs to disable all the
nether portals
except for the stronghold one it needs
to turn that one on
which is not by us it might have to
send a redstone signal like 100 blocks
or more
to turn that portal on
and then we would go through here
on the timer and then when we go back
out
uh we should end up at the stronghold so
we have to set up like a redstone
network now
to enable and disable the portals
properly
but first we should set up a few more of
these which i'll do off camera
because we only have one right now we
can't make a network without
a whole bunch of them
okay i actually decided to get started
on the redstone network after all
and that needs to connect to all the
portals and i need to set up in such a
way where they can send
information between themselves and
figure out which one needs to be on
which ones need to be off and
not that simple of a feat really
i tried planning this out on paper like
trying to figure out how many wires i
was going to need to do all this
even using tricky tricky methods and all
that i
figured i'd need at least three
connecting to all the portals
turns out i only need one
thanks to a very awesome little device
um and by the way right now
i've connected the redstone network to
the lava
bucket so the idea is when i select the
destination from the panel
it's going to disable all the portals
and then it's going to turn one of them
on the one that we selected
so the network's going to
disable all the portals first of all so
this wire goes to the
disable for this portal
and this is the awesome little thing
right here
this is a two-way repeater i saw this on
a youtube channel called redstone
innovation and it is the best two-way
repeater i've ever seen
in minecraft to date it is so good
um these are two sticky pistons
redstone block it's a little more
expensive than some of them because you
got to use redstone
blocks but there's no repeaters
i think it's pretty good like regarding
like lighting updates
and a nice thing about it is actually
carries the length of the signal through
it
um so
let's see i'm just going to break this
for right now
actually you know we can do a little
test here let's go up let's go back
up here
so the way this works we'll just turn
this on manually
this is not the timer so it's going to
stay stay on
and as i use my nether portals i can
keep them on too if i want
because this thing is going to be able
to disable all of them at once
oh don't you don't you shoot at me
and i've also tested these two-way
repeaters
in creative to make sure that they work
in unloaded chunks and they do
so if we go all the way over here this
is about where
another portal is going to be
this is like the start of the nether hub
right here
up here so if we send a signal down here
uh what it does is it pushes or makes a
sticky piston extend
this goes out and then
when this block comes out instead of the
wire going straight into that block
it connects to this and that prevents it
from looping back
and to towards itself again which is
what
uh you gotta do when you're making a
two-way repeater
but yeah that goes all the way down so
let's disable that this will take care
of
um disabling all the portals but we
still need to tell
a specific one to turn on
nice thing about this is we can connect
anywhere in the system like if we have a
portal here we can connect between
two of these repeaters and it will still
send
the redstone signal to all the portals
no problem
um two-way repeaters would be very nice
to have in the game
like their own block actually because
they are really cool so yeah that
disabled the portal
all the way from over there and it would
work
going from here down that way too
um
what was i gonna do i had something else
i was gonna do
oh yeah i gotta talk about so how am i
gonna enable
a specific portal well this
this carries the length of the signal so
let's say this
this redstone wire turns on for 10 ticks
and then off
uh with that pulse we're going to
disable the portals but i'm
also going to try invent some kind of
decoder
that will only let a signal through if
like for example this is on for 10 ticks
it'll let a signal through if it's on 9
or 11 ticks it won't
and that will be the unique code to turn
one of the portals on and one of them
might be for nine ticks one for ten
one for eleven so we can send
information through
the single wire uh depending on how long
it's on for uh to all the portals as
well
so that's how we're going to turn a
specific one on we'll give each one its
own unique
uh timing and that makes uh
sending the signal pretty easy too we
just need to
send a certain length of pulse to the
wire
which isn't really that complicated
and that is the plan but it's going to
take a little bit of time to set it all
up
which we won't do all today but that
is that's what i got in mind
um kind of a fun little technical
project
that will probably be really useful too
so we have a little bit of a problem
here
the map the map is doing something very
strange it's almost like it's
all the colors started to run and now
it's a liquid surface on it or something
i think what it's doing actually is it's
like rendering the map properly but now
also rendering some layer above it
yeah i don't know and the weird thing is
i've tried reloading
and it's still doing it so i might need
to completely reload the game or leave
the area and come back and that might
fix it
we'll see but yeah here is the comment i
picked out for today
um thank you everybody for your feedback
about the new computer
lots of great advice was given and
here's some of it it says
etho i would say that as you are very
technical person
that you should not just buy a computer
build one and before you say it's more
expensive or it's too hard
it's not it's less expensive and it's
straightforward
ask b dubs about it i'm sure he'll back
me up
also for two grand you could build a
very very
very beastly computer much better than
anything you can buy with the same
amount today
and that kind of goes along with what
most people said uh
as far as i could tell though people
said the one i was looking at was a good
good computer good value but that i
should build a custom one and i would
get
more for my money
um i don't know
i i used to always build custom
computers in the past
and then one day i was this lazy and i
decided i would just buy
a store-bought one i was very happy with
that computer then
the next one i got was also store-bought
this is going to be my
third store-bought one um
i've actually been really happy with
store-bought computers compared to
custom ones i was
i always had some weird technical
problem with the custom ones like
oh i don't know what i don't know what
the deal was like
stuff would fry every now and then of
course it was a long time ago when
windows wasn't as good and that kind of
stuff but you know
i had trouble um
the thing is also well actually i'll
i'll say one positive thing about custom
computers somebody brought out a really
good point
that when you buy a store-bought one
chances are they're going to put in a
really cheap motherboard or
very basic motherboard that's a really
important part of the computer because
that's what
connects everything together basically
and you'll want a good quality one
which you probably won't get with a
store-bought and if you build a custom
one you can
choose whichever motherboard you want
that almost had me consider building a
custom computer actually but
i decided to go with the one i was
looking at and some of you
probably were gonna call me a fool for
it
but we'll try it i'm gonna try it out
and
if i'm unhappy with it i'll probably do
a custom one next time
the thing is in canada i don't think
custom computers are much
cheaper i've priced it out in the past
they actually costed more i think
nowadays it's about even
maybe a little bit cheaper but you gotta
factor in shipping and all that
um the main reason though is i don't
want the stress
of of ordering all the parts making sure
they arrive
putting it all together making sure i
don't fry something
and just the time i save not doing it
is definitely good value because i
i very very much value my time
i don't have a lot of free time so if i
can get out of building a computer
definitely going to go that way
and it just turns up it turned out that
the computer i was looking at
went on sale 50 bucks cheaper the next
day
and free shipping so i went with it
we're gonna get that store-bought one i
was talking about and hopefully it works
out the main thing i'm worried about
actually is a fan
i since it's from the web i'm not sure
if the fan is quiet on it or not
and if it's loud it will get picked up
and recording which would really suck
so we'll see what happens
anyway that's going to be it for today
guys thank you for watching as always
and i will see you again next time bye