hey hey how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back guys how you doing
hopefully you're having a great day I'm
back here at the Blais firm trying to
fix it this happens to me every project
we do you might not realize it but like
there's always one little detail one
thing I have trouble getting to work and
it has shown itself again with the blaze
project I've spent a couple hours on
this one little problem okay here we go
they're getting crushed and it's a
stupid little thing it's not even all
that complicated I just can't wrap my
head around it okay so when we kill them
here if what I just did fixed it
then this should not release the next
ones this block up here should not get
released see how they sit on top of it
like that
it shouldn't let the next load down
until I pick up the XP okay don't don't
yes yes oh uh oh it looked like it was
good except for some reason the crusher
activated again but then it'll activate
so Kay that was odd so when I pick up
the XP then they should get let down for
the next next load of them huh oh I
almost got it now I got to figure out
why the crusher activated there yeah I'm
not really sure I'm looking at this this
doesn't make any sense to me at all I
just added the redstone here right this
is a little delayed checker thing I
added so it checks to make sure items
are off that iron pressure plate for a
certain amount of time before it
confirms that I picked up all the XP
right somehow that redstone over there
is activating this hopper clock here and
they are not connected
which has me so confused unless maybe
I'm being tricked let's try something up
here so there's a trick you can do with
pistons by the way normally if I use the
solid block here and we had a redstone
signal above it would power both of
these Pistons but if you just use a half
slab it only powers this top one and not
the bottom one which I need in this case
but maybe maybe I'm wrong now it only
activates the top one all right I'm so
confused okay here we go again guys yeah
it didn't happen this time what is going
on I don't know all right look only good
guys yeah
plays firm is working perfectly all
right everybody so unfortunately there
hasn't been an update since last episode
so we can't play around with the glider
wings and the new boats today in our our
world here because you can't get them in
survival like they work in survival but
the portals are broken so you can't
actually acquire them which is a big
deal so rather than doing another
episode in creative today we're just
gonna do random things that's that's my
plan for today my plan is to not have a
plan whatever comes to my mind whatever
random idea hits me that's what we're
doing basically so first random idea I
was walking by sandy City here decided
let's try to finish up this wall going
around it so that is what I'm doing here
I'm working on a gate right now probably
going to build two more gates in total
so the deep entrance is right here right
yes I think so okay so I'm just going to
copy what we built over there over here
and one more of them right up here by
the pyramid I believe yeah over here
this this row goes over to the Nexus and
some other stuff
I'm not sure if I should get rid of the
reeds here or what I kind of want to
have a straight wall going over top them
because of the sand launcher thing if we
built the wall up in front here I think
the sand would run into it right let's
see how high we can build before it does
is it going to hit that if it's gonna
hit that it's gonna hit the wall dududu
come on man hurry up people are waiting
okay and hit it yeah hit it okay well it
looked like they only flew three blocks
up or so so that is a it's not going to
work if we like build around the reeds
we have to go just straight across here
I think yeah so we might just rip these
out because there's no conceivable way I
can think of where you would ever build
over top plants like a wall over top
plants right okay just taking a little
bit of a stick break here I'm in the
middle of building and ran out of food
ah I got a bit of a shot here though
check this out
whoo-hoo so apparently I missed this one
there's a sweep attack with swords so it
doesn't just attack one mob attacks
several mobs I did not know that uh well
it doesn't attack them I think if this
pushes and back I don't think it
actually damages them so around the
targets you can see it pretty clearly it
moves everybody back a little bit it's
kind of cool apparently it doesn't work
if you're running let's try that yeah
you have to be walking or going slower
right let's try walking oh it doesn't
work from watching me because I got
speed beacon
just a little slower sprinting her shift
shift-clicking not shift-clicking what's
it called sneaking we're sneaking right
now and it works
ah yeah so we got all the walls done
around sandy city guys are you ready to
see them here we go oh I need someone to
do sound effects for me I'm sorry that's
that's the best I got
but yeah we got to get the wall going
all around here now put in two more of
these gates I really liked how these
gates look by the way even though they
don't have much texture to them like not
many block variations I just love the
shape of them I think it's really nice
um got another one over here
and the whole place is enclosed now it
gives it a good feeling I think we have
all this free space so like all this
over here and over here where we had the
reeds there I filled it in so we can
build something here as well and in this
corner once we do all that once we get
houses in here or whatever I want to put
then the city is done so it's getting
there it's kind of a big project this is
all part of the whole biome enhancement
idea by the way so this was just empty
sand empty desert here for a long time
and I wanted to do something make it
more interesting and I think it's kind
of doing the trick right and it looks
kind of cool I love those gates my
favorite part of the whole thing the
houses it's okay but the gates yes
that's where it's at um so yeah whenever
I feel like building some more onto this
if I ever feel like building houses we
have space to do it I didn't actually
hook up the gates though like the
redstone and the Pistons and all that
because that's a big project it's like
it it would take me like an hour each
one and I have to like copy the world
here so I can go in to expect a term
owed and look at what I did because I
can't remember it's been so long since I
installed that
um anyways let's move on to another
project I I was thinking we owed I not
finish the wall here oh yeah this parts
a mess isn't it somehow we got to blend
this wall into two the water here that's
right
totally figure out about that oh well
let's pretend it's done for today okay
we're going to head up here though on
the mountain here to check out that ice
cube
if I remember right last time we checked
it out it wasn't working and I just want
to maybe look at it with you guys so you
can figure out what's wrong
mm-hmm-hmm-hmm I think we got the
problem figured out guys it's uh it's
not working
what's wrong with the mine guard the
minecart is not running I wonder if it
got stuck somewhere I tried looking down
here and I couldn't see it anywhere I
said I missed it maybe a baby zombie
spawn down here or something I don't
know because it looks like I filled in
the tracks right there's only a one
block I space
nothing should spawn in that except
maybe in these corners
yeah there's no cart there we got to
find the carts if we find the cart maybe
it just stalled out let's see let's
check over here it looks like there's a
bunch of track down here all right I
want to fix this before we need it
because then when I need it it's gonna
be like Oh got to wait forever to deform
a giant ice cube again because it takes
like a couple hours to do it if I need
ice at that moment I want ice I don't
want to wait for it okay it definitely
stalled out why would it stop there I
wonder that is very strange oh I
shouldn't have done that
oh and I'm down to my last two inner
pearls you can't spam them anymore so it
might be tricky to get out of here oh
yeah that's a problem okay
how do I fix the cart guys I'm going to
maybe just make a furnace my cart and
send it down you wouldn't believe it but
that that endermite that spawned he
bumped the minecart and got it going for
us
he kick-started it so I didn't even have
to do anything it just threw the ender
pearl and it worked and her mites are
not totally useless it turns out it's
great
so that's fixed what do we do next good
question
let me think about it okay so I was
trying to think what to do next year I
had an idea for our next random project
we're gonna build a TNT launcher that
launches TNT randomly oh snap okay so
for our firework Lake here we have
firework launchers they activate
randomly but I want a TNT cannon that
does it too so normally you don't want
something like that TNT has to be
activated somewhat precisely otherwise
it blows up all over the place right but
you know it might not be that difficult
oh I broke the slime block it's fine we
didn't replace it there we go good as
new
so yeah we'll fill this up with TNT
we'll just do something really simple
here slime block will launch the TNT up
vertically and it will kind of be like
the old vertical TNT cannons we used to
build okay so here's what we're gonna do
we're gonna have a randomizer right so
we'll fill this up with a few few items
that don't stack and then one item that
does and just put that in here for right
now this is just the test anyway so if
it selects the the chainsaw it will send
a signal out two or three blocks
actually otherwise it will only send it
out one block so let's do this redstone
to our TNT dispenser thing okay and then
TNT takes four seconds to blow up right
yeah let's hope I'm right hopefully that
didn't change so probably at the
doing the two and three second area is
where we're going to want the piston to
activate so here let's just get this
down to the ground like so and we'll
just see if we can get the right timing
so that was four eight twelve sixteen
two seconds right there let's wrap it
back like a so two two point four two
point eight
should we go longer that's probably
about right okay so I think that was
three seconds so with the firework
launchers there there's a clock that
runs constantly as well so we'll set up
that over here just to mimic it okay
it's the regular clock nothing too fancy
Oh actually let's do it like this back
like this okay so that's everything
right I think so let's let's hope I did
this right so now if we send this to
there it's going to pick one of those
items at random yeah and the the Pistons
triggering okay so if we figure this out
all correctly we should just be able to
throw some TNT in here and it will never
blow up the redstone that seems wrong
because I just saw I will just try it oh
why why so many oh my goodness oh my
gosh stop it stop
oh snap why did it shoot so many alright
I rebuilt it everything's good I slowed
down the clock this diamond I also
increased the number of items in here so
there's only a one in five chance of the
picking chainsaw it looks like it's not
gonna do it this time but I don't know I
felt like I got tricked there too like
why did it shoot so many TNT I expected
maybe a few not that many though I feel
like it's safe to put the TNT didn't
this time I'm only gonna put 12 in no.6
see if it does it again okay I think
it's working fine now it must have just
been too fast yeah three seconds looks
good
that was like at the top of the arch
where it blew up and yeah it doesn't
shoot it too often we don't really need
it to shoot it very often it's just a
random explosion every so often the
firework show is what I want that looks
safe good but now we will try to speed
it up just to see what the limit is good
kind of want to to go at once here but
I'm scared because we can easily get a
repeat of what just happened then even
even with its sped up here it doesn't
happen very often does it I feel like I
got really cheated there
check goods I'll try speed it up oh why
did - oh that's a little scary but it
flies sideways I get uncomfortable shot
- okay it's happening a little bit
faster than I want now I had a blood oh
okay so I did a little bit of
terraforming over there I actually
didn't like that little section that was
hanging out so that that was fine
ah but yeah underneath the firework Lake
I set up the cannon so got the clock
over here and then down one of these
lines go on a little bit further here
this is where I made a branch out and it
goes up to the randomizer got a one in
six chance and then it's got the three
second delay before activates the piston
over there and then it goes up to the
dispenser up here so I think that's good
to go next firework show we we see we
should have TNT exploding as well
okay everybody so unfortunately we have
a call episode here for today but as
usual I picked out a comment and it says
this is in reference to last episode the
reason you don't go up on the slime
blocks is because you must hold space
for the gliders to work but if you hold
space on the slime block you don't
bounce so I saw a lot of people saying
this where did this rumor start you
don't have to hold space I went the
whole episode last time not holding
space unless I'm doing it wrong but it
seemed to work perfectly fine for me a
lot of people said you got a hold space
though so yeah as far as I know you
don't need to
I also saw in the comments so the reason
I was having trouble with my slime block
launcher is because sign blocks are
acting a little weird in 1.9 so maybe
they got to be fixed I don't know I
don't know don't know too much about
them but that's just what a few people
said so maybe that was a reason but
maybe not I don't know all right well
anyways guys I hope you have a wonderful
day and I'll see you again in the next
one
take care bye