[Music]
greetings everybody this is etho
welcome back guys this has become my
life right now this is what i do
i put coblin control v to paste
and then filler rinse and repeats
i am currently in the process of putting
the filler blocks
in the nexus the giant storage room
building you see to the left
and it is a big job
it is a very big job it's a quarter done
right now
in total we need about
three chests of filler filler blocks
and that equates to about 90
levels just to name the stuff so i've
been running to the
end farming ender pearls and then
getting some xp there then i come back
and i start enchanting a whole bunch of
cobble
and what do we need this for well i i
showed this before but basically all i
gotta do
here's our filler chest some of it uh
what i got to do i go
over top here and then i gotta put in 21
cobble in each of these hoppers all the
way down
and there's 256 in total so 256 times 21
is a lot
and uh hopefully i get that done today
i'm starting to feel like some sort of
machine it's so repetitive it's like
drag drop and then try figure outs
it doesn't divide very nicely
unfortunately
but just i usually split it into 16 and
then try to get the rest from somewhere
and i have to do math in my head it's
terrible like
i have to try to figure out how to make
18 every time
drives me crazy and this is about the
pace i go
it's taken me a little while but this
will be a big step to get done again
uh and hopefully
the progress on this thing seems to be
moving slow is just because every single
step
i gotta multiply by a 256 it seems so it
takes a long time just to do one
thing but we're getting there
and 18. all right
you know what of course it would work
out this way
you guys you know you sometimes face
palm in my videos
i'm face bombing right now
right there you hear that i figured out
how to divide them that's all you gotta
do
just like that i need 21 in each hopper
then i do that so much simpler than
what i was doing wish i knew that at the
start
all right
i really like the cinderman farm
this anvil right here this is a special
anvil
okay i'm pretty sure i used it about 20
times before i went to the end and now
that i got back
i started with 39 levels i've only been
using this anvil
can we use the remaining five
on average you're only supposed to get
like 24 uses
out of an anvil but it's random right
last one yeah so it did like
it's up to like 60 something that's
that's pretty crazy and it hasn't broken
yet
and victory dance
yes we got another step done on the
nexus guys the filler is all in place i
finished it
so i ran and i got our books the great
book we made before we even started
building here
and it's flipping through the pages
let's take a look real quick
this is the groups i made on how we can
organize
items and
here let me just show you something
really quick i know this is a pretty
confusing project there's
it's a storage room everyone always asks
what is the nexus what is he building
it's a storage room with an automatic uh
sorting system and an automatic
retrieval system is what we're trying to
do
so we we have a spot free on each of
these hoppers
now what we got to do uh we have to put
a unique item in each of those like from
our list here
so we got our stones we have dirt
wood sand glass wool
random blocks random blocks again the
clay the hardened clays
uh redstone stuff we have all the plant
stuff
dyes mine carts i think something's
missing there isn't there
activator detector
is that it i feel like there's one more
thing
not a furnace minecart uh something
something's missing there though
uh stairs and slabs and then we got the
oars oh and food
other items okay
so there's a lot here i added it up we
have 325 items
in this list now the problem is we only
have room for 256
items in our storage room here so we
have to not store
certain things so
unfortunately not everything's going to
make the list
and if i was to make this storage room
any bigger i would die
so we're not doing that oops i wrote
something okay so we could probably
let's see like i got wool on the list we
could for sure get rid of carpet
so that's 16 unique items there off the
list
uh we need to free up about 70 spots
because usually when i
i need carpet i just craft it on the
spot anyway you don't even need a
crafting table just need the wool
um so carpet for sure gone
and let's see
dies i might should we get rid of dyes
yeah let's get rid of dyes
what we'll do we'll have like a maybe in
the main room at the front we'll have a
die chest
um and then we could probably get rid of
the hardened clay
too to i don't know
sometimes i get colored clay though when
i when i go mining in the mesa
and i won't have a spot for it if i get
rid of that
let's see there was one other thing for
sure
ores okay there's a couple here i think
i planned on storing like blocks of iron
and iron ingots and then iron ore that's
why there's a three here for the three
different types
really we shouldn't be storing blocks of
anything because then it gets confusing
if i need
iron and some of my iron is it as an
ingot and some of it's in block form
and i run out of ingots i might think
i'm out of iron but i
have hundreds left in block form you
know so we should only have one type
so it's less confusing so that'll free
up about
four to eight spots i guess
uh i think we had glass why can't i find
glass
where's the glass yeah over here
i have pains on the list i think i'll
get rid of that
and i'll just toss them if we ever have
extra i don't use paints very often so
that'll free up 17
because there's 16 different colors and
then the clear
clear panes anyway that's sort of the
next step to this
once we do that i then got to connect
all these ice streams together
right now we just have it running down
the road so i'll have to connect them
horizontally here
that one to that one that one to that
one that one over there to that one and
so on and so forth
when i do that the item sorting will
work
and then to get the item retrieval
working we then have to connect the
redstone together
in each of these rows and hook it to
some
master board type of thing like this
whoa and then we pretty much will have a
fully functioning nexus
and then we just have to add other fancy
stuff which is when things will get more
interesting again with this project
um because right now it's very
repetitive
uh anyway that is sort of the
what's going on here i'm gonna leave
this i'll just throw it in here for now
let's go do some other stuff though uh
today i was working on some more pathing
stuff
hopefully this doesn't take too long
and oh in the water
uh the lakeside path over here
lakeside road i guess we'll call it yeah
so we got gravel running
down here and this used to be just like
one block wide now it's
that looks a little bit nicer and out of
enterprise darn it
i guess we're walking the rest of the
way then up here at the desert city i
did something as well i saw a cool post
on the minecraft reddit
about using upside down stairs uh to
give
texture to like sandy paths like look at
this this is an upside down stair
and i think that's really cool it's like
a
gritty type of texture it's very subtle
it's it's hardly noticeable but i
kind of added that throughout the
pathing here also uh
i don't think i had this here before the
cutting through the sugar cane so i put
that in today
and uh that's about it
got it up by the well here it's a very
subtle detail but i like it a lot just
having that
that one more type of texture in the
ground it's very cool
all right so i do have a project in mind
for today guys and it's something i've
wanted to do for quite a while
this this is a hint over here you
thought this was a windows reference
didn't you oh
how foolish how foolish you were this is
a foresight
into what we were doing today
yes it's no coincidence that they're
they're similar
maybe maybe it is um i am a little uh
weary about starting a new project
though because we do have a lot going on
currently but uh
i'm gonna do it i love starting new
projects we have been working on
the stuff we have started too so i don't
feel too too bad about it
um let's take a look at our map here
to scout a location we're actually going
to use the maps and not just for show
to help us make the decision here i
think there's
no there goes a squid i think there's a
forest
um by my base where's my base that's the
snowflake over there we are right there
uh gold farm that's the path up the
library
the library is up there i
think we want to go this way
what is all this land here
i'm confused now
okay uh that's that's by the you you've
been ethod logo
there i think we want to go this way
yeah i didn't realize it was planes over
here though i thought it was forest
this whole area or maybe we'll even go
far up over this way uh we're gonna be
establishing a game zone
in my world though i want to make like
little mini games kind of like good land
i guess
for those familiar with it
and we'll put it on trial if i can make
one good game
then we might make more but if this is a
big bust
then uh we'll just forget about it
because the game i have in mind is
actually
pretty complicated it's something i
wanted to try
though for a while we're going to be
making a simon says game
if if possible and
i think this will be fun because
there'll be a lot of variety with with
the projects like
if we're making lots of different games
uh oh
no make it make it make him it yes
just barely did it
[Music]
okay so that big open area we saw that
this is it right here it's part of the
mountain biome
i guess i thought it was plains but no
it's mountain
extreme hills nice and flat uh then this
is the forest up here
this is right by the man cave but i
never go
never go here i've only seen it a few
times like when i'm
out exploring and i'm making my way back
i'll i'll walk through here and it's
like
where am i this seems so foreign
but it's so close to my base
like i i feel so lost just watching here
i think we were aiming for up here
and i saw like a snow biome further
further up right so this would be pretty
good spot for something new
it's close to the main base uh it's a
forest biome so we can make it look nice
if we
do anything with grass and
is this ice biome yeah up here and it's
relatively flat so it'll be easy to
build off of
okay huh look at all the animals here
you can tell i haven't been here i
haven't murdered them all yet
and ice biome right by the desert uh-huh
this
is this is where we fought the withers
and i've been getting sand right
yeah okay it's all connecting together
now
let's get an upward view yeah that's the
big pit over there
so i think that'll be pretty nice up
over here
yes i'm going to start at the very edge
of the forest biome here uh that's the
library up there
if we build more games then we'll just
make our way closer and closer to the
man cave this direction
all right so we are building a simon
says game
or hoping to i'm sure most of you are
familiar with simon says it
is a memory game
i'll just explain it really quick just
in case you never know some people
may never have played it or heard of it
it is
a memory game where you got four colors
red green
blue yellow right and
uh it plays a sequence of those colors
randomly and you have to try to copy
that sequence so it'll be like
red green blue then you've got to click
red green blue and then it's going to
add one more onto that so it'll be red
green blue then something else random
like
yellow okay that's not very random
red green blue yellow then you enter
that and then it adds one more and it
keeps adding onto the chain
and it gets very difficult and you have
trouble remembering it at a certain
point usually around
20 to 30 for me um is where i fail
and uh once you mess up then then you
lose and you gotta start over
so uh that's what we'll try to copy here
if possible
brought some stuff here to set up a
little base we're just gonna run through
some of the logic today
and i really like this kind of stuff the
problem solving i haven't got it all
figured out or anything i just have a
a rough idea of what we could try um
so we'll probably use a
dropper or a dispenser to get a random
selection right
so we got to randomize the color every
time we add to
the sequence and this is a pretty good
way of doing it
blue blue yellow
green so it's random
very good now the issue is
uh we have to somehow keep that chain
and not mess it up like the order
they come out of here we gotta copy it
every time
and if we for example try to
let's get some some hoppers going if we
put these items into any sort of form of
storage like a chest or a hopper or
another dropper
uh what's gonna happen is
so that time we got red green
green see they kind of bunch up
so that's going to be an issue because
then when we
continue this or if we try to get them
out of there
we're going to lose our chain as it
should be
so just it just keeps that they all
group up and then
red is going to come out first then
green and blue so that doesn't work
that's that's kind of the problem we got
to solve here
the other way we could try to do it is
we use items that don't stack
if we had like four different types of
swords in here for example
uh they wouldn't stack but then the
issue is we can't detect them
because we'll probably use an item
item filter to detect uh
which one is chosen so we'll have like
four hoppers
it'll go into one of them and depending
on which one it goes into we can grab
a redstone signal off of that and then
do a comparison
to what i input into the the game right
um by the way maybe i should just do
this as a little diagram
uh simon says there's a few different
ways the game's kind of laid out but
it's basically
four different colors like this right
and you step on a pressure plate or
something
to put in your inputs and we might use a
sticky piston underneath
somewhere we'll make it bigger than this
of course
but we could do something like this like
when it's showing us what color it is
we could make it pop up for each of them
we have to have some visual indication
of what color
uh it's telling us so so we'll either
use pistons or
or pistons they're probably the best
um i was thinking we could put lights
behind like stained glass or something
too but that's
probably not as obvious
oh snap i think i just had a great idea
i was originally gonna
try do something with ice streams and
like locking items behind gates
type of thing it's a little hard to
describe without actually doing it but
we're not doing it now
uh the new way i just thought of which
is probably a lot simpler and a lot more
compact
we have our color wheel in here right
whenever we need to randomize a new
color we uh we send a pulse to that hey
piggy
yeah keep walking just distracting me
that's nice
and then to keep our sequence we can
just do something like this make a a
loop
like so uh unfortunately it's not going
to be quite this simple but
just to give you the idea and
when we activate this you know i went
and got some cobble because i was gonna
make a lever and then i never did that
i wanted to do that off camera there we
go okay
got our lever so now when we
power this once we now have
that in there and we will have to power
all of these but i think there's an
issue that if you do this then
it will trigger a dropper more than once
sometimes
depending on where it is in the chunk or
what order it processes this
but uh here let's just try this and we
will connect this up to here now
piggy i know you're very curious
on what i'm doing here but you're very
distracting so yeah
it keeps them separate this way was
no it was red first wasn't it i think
the blue jumped the
head oh man my memory stinks that's why
i'm building this game
to help me out so it was blue red this
should have blue in now
it has nothing red
red where did the blue go it must have
jumped ahead yeah so it skipped one
there
so what we're going to actually have to
do
is uh put a delay on these i'm pretty
sure
but we'll set a limit to the game maybe
only 40 or
50 maximum
if i get that then i win type of thing
because we have to set a specific limit
uh that's how many droppers we use
to like how many how long the chain can
get
um but yeah we'll probably oh that's not
going to work
we need a block spacing in there
but yeah if we activate the droppers
like this where we have a one tick delay
between each one
then there will be
no issue with them jumping ahead like
they were doing there
all right so here is a test to try out
that idea we're basically just trying to
store
the memory right now there's more
complications that will come later
but let's do it one step at a time uh we
want to make sure the items don't bunch
up and
they keep their order and they don't
skip any spots that kind of stuff
so i have the piss or not piston loop
the dropper loop here
and it's probably easier to keep stuff
in a line like this than to do it in a
square like we had
because then i can just put the
repeaters on both sides nice and easy
all right so it's going
counterclockwise yeah so it goes whoops
don't kill me zombie don't you even
think of it
i had a creeper blow up right over there
and blew up my wiring oh and another one
i'm gonna have to chop these trees down
very soon
although he came from that cave there so
yeah it goes around the bend like this
and then shoots around this way so it
does a loop like that
the redstone wiring i have going counter
clock
no this is going counterclockwise
redstone wiring is going
clockwise opposite of that so we want to
activate the end of the chain
first and then go to the beginning
so it goes like this and each of these
is one tick delayed from each other
right so let's just try it out this is a
start here
with our colors in it's going to go into
this this way and then back around
um so just hit the button
and it activates all the way around
makes its way to the start here
because if we did it from the start it
would jump two spaces
right we don't want that so red
good please work
please work yeah red moved ahead a spot
and now we have blue
red blue yellow good
so it seems to be going okay red
blue yellow green nah
see it is kind of random that you get
one of each right
remember my example i i did one of every
color
it happens and blue yeah so it looks
like it's going good
um all right so that is good we can
actually store stuff in memory this
way without it having any issues
okay so that's awesome we can store
stuff in memory it's very
important to the game but on its own it
is totally useless to us unless we can
actually read that memory
so what we would do uh
just this is technically the start of
the chain maybe
but yeah we would then need to compare
my inputs with what is next in the thing
so let's say
it's red right we need the game to know
it's red
right now it's it's not doing anything
it's moving items around
so we would probably
set up an ice stream it's a good thing i
brought that ice after all
because we will need it let's see let's
grab that
again this is not a polished version of
the game by any means we're just
we're just working out the steps to it
so
let's move this get out of the way we
would set up an ice stream
and probably have that go to an item
filter
and i'll i'm not actually going to set
up i'm just showing this as a
demonstration
so one of these would be for red
type of thing one of them would be for
green one of them for yellow
and blue and if it goes into that hopper
like when an item shoots out of here
it'll go into one of the hoppers
then we can use the comparator to
trigger a redstone signal and save that
um and then when i click a button
or a pressure plate it'll compare which
one of these got
activated with what button i push and
if they match then it counts as a
correct answer and it'll move on to the
next one
in the memory chain here or if it's
wrong then we need to make this
the game reset so we would have to
move all the items through the chain
and probably put a hopper underneath one
of these
to pull the items out and then put them
into the start here
again um so it's going to get very
complicated at this point
i'm going to probably do some of this
stuff off camera
and hopefully have something to show you
for next episode
but uh we will call it there for today
i'm going to
get the comment prepared for today and
uh we'll wrap it up
okay so i just picked out one really
quick question here to finish up
it says or jojo boy i like that name
jojo boy says hey etho do you think you
will do another ctm map
uh complete the monument map uh you know
i haven't done a custom map in minecraft
in a long time like a vanilla one not
i've done modded ones
crash landing was one but i haven't done
a vanilla
uh custom map in so long that
uh yeah i might actually
wanna do one again maybe not necessarily
a ctm map maybe a ctm map but uh just a
custom map in general would be fun
so uh i'll put it on the table might
happen
all right so uh thank you for watching
guys
hope you have a good day and i will see
you in the next episode
take care bye