hello again
welcome to minecraft 1.1
it's out the new patch
oh you know what that sound is
let's see if we can make it in time
here he comes
hey there he goes
that's awesome
yeah 1.1 is out today i thought we'd
start out by enchanting a bow
because you can enchant bows now which
is awesome i think there's
there's at least four
attributes you can get for a bow if
that's the right word
so i know one of them is power one of
them's infinity
uh power i think is like damage for your
bow shot
infinity from what i've heard allows you
to shoot
uh without using up arrows which is kind
of interesting and then there's a flame
one
and i can't remember what the other one
was
and also they improved the randomness
randomness thing
so it's a lot easier to get higher
numbers
as you can see we just went we just had
a 49 there
haven't seen a 50 yet just passed to 48
48 again 48 47
so pretty cool oh i just saw 50
and missed it i just want to scan
through real quick
another 50 showed up there
how quick are your eyes
overall it's a lot easier to get a good
enchantment level the one you want which
is awesome so i'm going to go ahead and
get one on 49 or 50 hopefully and then
we will enchant this
sweet we got a 50. so previously
with enchanting i've only ever seen a
level 50 two times total
out of all the enchanting i've ever done
and every time it showed up i either
passed it
or i didn't have enough levels for it
but today
we're going to do our first level 50
enchantment on my first
i have enchanted a bow already but this
is my first high level enchantment i've
done on it so let's see how this goes
infinity one is that good i don't know
sounds good if i was to guess i'd say
infinity is probably the rarest but
that's just my instinct not based on
fact i have no idea
so let's try this out apparently if you
have at least
one arrow in your inventory it won't
you won't run out
and that seems to be true
oh so you can't actually pick them up
that's what i was wondering about
because it seemed like you could create
infinite arrows if you could pick them
up
awesome so i wonder if i have more than
one in my inventory if uh
if it'll use them so we had 22
still 22. okay that's awesome so it
doesn't use them at all but you can't
pick them up
after you shoot them so that that seems
like a fair trade
good skill and bows do
break fairly quickly so it's not i don't
think it's overpowered either
so all in all that's a pretty pretty
awesome addition to the game
all right i've heard another interesting
rumor about the 1.1 patch
that i want to try out here so we gotta
we gotta get us get ourselves a helper
here first
all right he'll do
there we go okay so what i want to try
i've heard that if you shoot a um
an arrow through lava now that
apparently
it will catch mobs on fire i don't know
if it's true or not it's just what i
heard
here we go
nope oh yes
yes unbelievable
that was a tip given to me by bwo
awesome so it does work
yeah pretty sure that won't work
let's get a bunch around it just to be
sure
it did work on the mobs though so that's
cool i bet you if you do it on like cows
and pigs in that it'll probably give you
cooked
pork chops and stuff too
if i was to guess
all right anyway enough goofing around
here
all right so i just checked the forms
and apparently there's a rumor that
trees and stuff can catch on fire from
flaming arrows so i just wanna
see if that is possible or not
apparently it's a little
challenging to do
it might only be from if you get the
flaming enchantment too
one thing i'm noticing you gotta shoot
the arrows slowly through this lava here
otherwise
they seem to go right through it without
catching fire
although if i make this a little bit
wider probably
we'll be able to do it more often
yep much better
yeah loving this loving the bow
enchantments i guess the other one i
missed was a
punch which is like knocked back with
the sword
you're not seeing any fire i really
would be surprised if it
did catch fire uh with the
infinity enchantment on the bow
apparently you do need an
arrow though right now i can't shoot if
i don't have
at least one arrow in my inventory
yeah i'm pretty sure fire won't spread
doesn't look like it's
no okay it's not uh
not for surely proof but i would be very
surprised if that did work
and there's been some big farming
changes with the new 1.1 update
apparently now you don't need to till
your soil
for pumpkins and watermelon which is
pretty pretty big in my opinion
watermelon were really good before and
that just puts them over the edge
so we're gonna try this out see if they
grow here
quiet quiet usually i shut this off for
episodes when i forgot today
i would like to enchant some more bows
well that was weird the audio just quit
there
the cave audio seemed to cut off
but yeah watermelons are really good
food source now because you can set up
fully
automatic farms easily you could before
but you had to
use that bud switch piston trick which
took up a lot of space a lot of pistons
and was a little bit glitchy um
now it's really really easy our buddies
are still
looking cool over here
do an epic turn oh yeah right round
hey um
a lot of people seem to think that the
ai improved with this patch as far as i
can tell it has
not actually probably come later
if it does come oh yeah and the big
thing we gotta check out here is the
wheat farm
there's apparently some changes with
trampoline
and i went the wrong way here still not
used to
having that a little bit more fixed
let's see we gotta go over here
i'll clean this up eventually
right so i'm going to
i'm not going to do the whole thing just
in case
this doesn't work i'm not sure if it
will work
i've heard different things but i know
it won't trample if i'm walking on it
or if the cows walk on it it sounds like
they won't
trample it but if uh i think if i jump
or if they jump on it
it will trample the farmland
we'll see what happens here
yeah you just saw you trampled it there
she just trampled
there if you want to get technical um
we'll see what happens here i got plenty
of seats to waste anyway
and if this doesn't work still i will
probably eventually make a new farm
i actually really wanted to make a
redstone project
lately i'll probably do something a
little bit more
redstone intensive soon because uh
i'm in the mood we'll see how that goes
there
actually what i've been wanting to do is
set up the trivia game again
and i have figured out a general idea of
where i want to build it
it's going to be in the tree farm-ish
area
most likely somewhere around
in the walls maybe or i don't know
i will have to work it
finishing this a little bit better i'll
probably
replace a lot of these trees with the
regular trees and
with the pine trees as well so we can
get all three types of wood in here
and if i get time today i will try to
add some more names to this and if i do
that then i can
release the world again so hopefully
it doesn't get too late here it's like
10 30 right now so
depending on how long it takes this is
actually
three days later from the intro you saw
two or three days played race for wool
tonight
um i'm not going to tell you how that
worked out in case you don't want it
spoiled
but i will be releasing video of that
soon
and let's see oh yeah fence gates
sounds like there's another slime coming
up fence gates have been
changed i do not have any here
i do have some apparently you can
control them with redstone now which is
an awesome
improvement
they should have done that from the
beginning
awesome so i wonder how it's going to
work out i'm going to get some redstone
together and just see how
we can cause this to open and close
so i just want to take a minute to see
how the fence gates interact with
redstone
so first of all let's try torches next
to it
yep that does it um we'll send
power directly to it with a wire
that opens it if it's not pointing at it
does not power it
if it's at the same level anyway
okay um let's see
repeater yeah that works i
can pretty sure it doesn't send power
through it
nope um
see what else oh yeah let's try
send power through a block to it
that opened it okay
oh it's stuck open now that's weird
wonder why that happened
hmm
was it doing that before
that's just when you remove the repeater
okay that's probably just a
unrelated glitch in the game uh what
else can we try here
power above yep that opens it what about
if we have it like this
redstone torch above that works
um it's good to do this when new block
comes out just to
get familiar with it new input device or
receiver
okay so behaves much like i was
expecting
um try maybe from below yet too
so the thing that really interests me
about these
is i believe this is the first block
that opened it good i believe this is
the first block
um that you can move with pistons that
you can then
control with redstone so like doors
you can't move with pistons trapdoors
you can't move with pistons
um and that has a collision mask i
should say
so might be some potential uses for that
i have to think about it
sure somebody will come up with
something cool
all right let's move on to something
else
so overall i can say i really like the
1.1 patch
but there's one change they made i don't
like
and i think it's really stupid that they
did this but the latter
collision mast is gone so
they act a lot different now to a lot of
people this wasn't really a big deal but
it does
bug me quite a bit it wrecks a lot of
parkour maps adventure maps um
and it doesn't seem to really have any
benefits so it's just an annoying change
in my opinion
so you can't stand at the top of ladders
anymore which means i can't jump
up here so i'll have to make that go all
the way to the top
if i want to use it like i
was originally there but the main reason
it's annoying me
is because ladders were actually quite
useful for dealing with mobs
when they had a collision mask and you
could even use them as a mob
evader if you could squeeze two
like slimes together they would
automatically climb up ladders or two
oops two of any mob would be able to
climb up the ladders and now i don't
think that's gonna work
uh eats road you'll have to use
trapdoors or something instead of
ladders
which again is annoying
if you use the old design of course we
have glass panes now
another change of course is you can
apparently get apples from these
oak trees
with a very rare chance
villages i've heard have a
chest you can get i don't know what's in
it
there's been some biome changes smoother
transitions
oh yeah let's let's check that out
smoother transitions i'm curious about
that because
i know over by the mountain there it's
really
really nasty or it was
it's all brown the grass let's check it
out now
yeah i don't know it still looks pretty
brown to me
um over here it seems like there's a
sharp change too
let's take a look
um it is smoother but not
it's still really noticeable
kind of uh spreads it out over three or
four blocks instead of
changing instantly which is better but
it's still
really noticeable
i'm out of food
oh yeah we got an apple from that so i
guess it's a one
in 200 chance of dropping from oak
leaves when they die
or decay which doesn't sound like much
but i think your average tree
probably is going to have i'm just
looking at
like this is a really small tree here
i'm sure there's at least 25
leaf blocks there so every eight trees
you cut down like that will probably
give you one apple which isn't bad
really
if you cut down a big tree like that
you're
most likely guaranteed to get one
so um
it's nice there in the game they've been
in the game for months now but there's
no way
there was no way of legitimately getting
them until recently you
you could get them in strongholds and
now you can actually get them
from a renewable source
and once you do get apples you can make
golden apples using nuggets now
you only need eight and every
iron ore you get can be converted into
nine of these so it's
not not a terrible trade
to get such an awesome item
let's see let's try this out so i think
um these have been nerfed though
in the latest patch see we got four
heart damage
eat it we got i think four seconds of
regeneration
um only recovered three hearts in that
time so i think
eating a golden apple probably boosts
your hearts by two and a half
in that time if i was to guess and of
course get a little bit of hunger from
it potions
are probably better the regeneration
potions but
you do get you do uh gain food from this
too so it's it's a cool item to have
i'm glad they added that into the game
let's go check out our farms see if
there's been any improvement
but yeah okay well
these are growing without needing to
till
that will simplify that quite a bit
oh baby two big ones two medium
and four small ones awesome
i have to set something up with that
i do have a plan for the big ones
a general plan there's a reason i wanted
them separated like that
our farmland is getting trampled we just
saw it
so yeah we'll have to still
i think i'm gonna still leave that for
the cows and since they can't
coexist i think the cows win
okay okay let's uh let's play around
with this a little bit before we end
this episode um
i want to try to get these guys into
minecarts because as you probably know
it looks
hilarious i don't know if we can do the
corner thing anymore
oh you can okay
i'm really surprised that still works
it's been in the game for a long time
so i'll probably set up an auto
mine chart track for these guys um
curious to see if they'll press this
pressure plate down while they're in the
mine
i cart push it can i
hmm can't push him
okay hey
just love how it looks when they're good
in my carts
so i'll be making some decorative
feature using slimes much like uh
if you ever saw my boat dispenser
version 2 video
uh like a year ago it's one of my first
videos
i had this thing in my world with cheap
going
um sheep going around a loop for
decoration
and i think the mine cart was on fire
too i can't remember
so i probably will try to do something
similar
to that with slimes i might try make a
endless loop for the big slimes to go
around the tree farm or something just
for comedic value
let's see
it won't be there we go that seemed to
work
i will have to be careful though that i
don't uh suffocate them like that
have to give give them space
so i'll probably make the minecart track
go down
um there and that should meet up with
with the tree farm pretty nicely
it's right over there
yeah let me know you think of that idea
just to have these guys going around and
around
automatically on their own the minecarts
will pick them up
when it detects there's one in here and
then they'll
send them around the loop
okay i think that'll be pretty cool
and the minecarts
track will probably come from this side
actually not
not from the side although that may be
this side
i don't know we'll see but that's the
idea for that
uh i am going to end the episode here
though today
because it's getting really late here
and i need to get up early
uh i will try to get an upload of my
world though
even though we didn't do the tree thing
there's just not enough time today
okay uh thank you for watching i do like
the 1.1 patch i just do not like the
ladder change that's the only thing
they shouldn't have done but whatever
see you guys