[Music]
hmm
guess what i want to do right now
besides that
i'll give you a hint
can you figure it out you know what i
want to do
i'm sure you got it you're probably
thinking the same thing you want me to
do it as well
let's shut these guys up
whoa all right all right
all right there's a lot of them quick
pull it
pull it pull it
oh no i'm not gonna get it i got it no
i didn't get it
there we go one more oh
ah
oh man what a mess
what a mess
that didn't turn out too well oh there's
still some big guys
oh there goes the clock it is all right
it's all right it's all for fun
there we go good as new hey
all right everybody what do we want to
do today what's our goal what's our plan
what should we do well i know what i
want to work on it's just sitting there
waiting for us calling for us it wants
to be finished
but uh i was thinking about today i
kinda i gotta keep myself in check i
think
because ever since the redstone update
came out it's like all i want to do
is redstone stuff like all all my
project plans at the moment
all involve redstone uh which isn't
necessarily a bad thing like it's what
i'm known for on my channel
i like doing redstone i know a lot of
other people like redstone stuff too
in logic and all that stuff but
you know there are people that don't
really find redstone too interesting so
maybe i should try add a little more
variety
because the last few episodes we've been
working on this i think we're going to
work on this today again
by the way just uh maybe not the whole
episode so
we'll maybe work on this for a little
bit and then go do something else
but uh what i i'll show you what i got
done here
i kind of went ahead and did a few
things just to so we could get right
into it
quickly today and then we'd be able to
have time to do other things
i got the smile wiring partially in
place here
for controlling the smile and also the
eyes
can be controlled by this wire at the
top
this makes them both extend uh people on
the reddit by the way they
gave a lot of good suggestions on how to
do the wiring for this smile
they saw a cool pattern that if i can
control
what which of the four smiles i'm
showing by the length of the redstone
signal if i set it up right
which would probably be a good way of
doing this i'm not sure if i'm
going to do it that way but i'm
considering it
i'm not sure if it's actually easier or
not i'll find out as i get into it i
guess
the other big thing i've done is i've
added in these hopper variable things
which we've talked about before and
this this stone and this wire here this
controls
the stat bars on the other side the
lamps
and it goes left to right on this side
and
left to right on this side because
that's the way we read here
in english land english language
i don't know why i said that you know
some in some languages they don't read
left to right i guess that's why i said
it
so i i figure that makes sense to do the
stat bar that way
as well even though logically the
easiest way for me to do it is probably
to have
the variables on the other side also
far away because you see there are
they're on the right side here like
those ones it would actually be easier
for me to put them on the left
but just because the way we read and
whatnot
anyway i got the age barg
done too up here so what we got to do
what we're going to work on now is
connecting stuff together
oops so let's work on the happiness i
guess
uh by the way if you guys missed this if
if you're not up to speed of what i'm
doing here i'm making like a tamagotchi
in minecraft
and we're we're mainly focusing on the
logic behind it and
and how to make it all work together
and with these variable hopper timer
things i can
i can do addition and subtraction sort
of
in minecraft the wire on top locks it
and the one on the side here this
block and torch dealio allows me to
switch between addition and subtraction
right so these these pistons control the
eyes we want these to be retracted if
the pet is
very sad or very happy or dead
those are the three times we want these
pistons unpowered
so we're going to use the length of the
wire
to determine oh
when when we change this basically so
this would be super sad
that's if it's at that level nothing
changes here
if it's at two three or four then those
need to be extended if it's at five
they need to be retracted or if the bets
dead then it needs to be retracted as
well so
i think we got to do something like this
we need an andy
for sure if it's only at
at one block distance the pulse or the
the redstone we don't need to do
anything because we don't need anything
to change right
it's only if it's at two three or four
that we need to
to do something so i figure we need to
do this
have the and gates
um as soon as the signal gets
two blocks distance they'll switch his
torch
and you can see now it's letting up a
signal through
the hand gate so this would get powered
at uh at two
and then we need to make it unpowered
like this
if it's at one like it is right now or
if it's at
five so um
it gets to 5 we want to do this
basically
and that would unpower it so 1
2 3 4 5 6.
get all the way up there
wait no no one two three four four five
yeah that's right
how do we position this i'm not truly
sure
oh good news guys i think we got it
figured out here
this is our our circuit here our logic
matrix super doohicky chickawatt
mahuku that's a new one
all right let's do a demonstration first
of all
so i'm going to put in just enough to
get up to
all the way so right now it's at zero
i'm going to put it in here you can see
it's going to start going
let's go over to this side real quick
that's our happiness bar it's at one
eyes are our squinty eyes now it's a two
this is
sad face just regular sad face and eyes
come out like that
then three's neutral four's
a happy face and then at five it's
supposed to switch again
by the way uh i think our pet name it's
wilson that was the unanimous
decision on in the comments i think
wilson's a good name
can't think of a better one honestly and
it switches
so let's go back up and just see exactly
what it's doing
to make that happen um
maybe we'll run it again
okay let's get up here quick quick oh
man the parkour i've done
oh no oh no
or that i haven't done i should say
trying to build this it's really tough
to build this stuff let's uh let's start
over
that was terrible
absolutely terrible parkour is a
very large requirement to doing redstone
in case you guys didn't know that so
once it gets to
two this torch switches this torch comes
on
because of that and it powers
the pistons below and you can see it's
going to get further and further until
it gets up to here
this repeater is really important if i
didn't take that into
account before but if we didn't have
that
this torch would always be powered and
it would just send the signal back to
itself
which we don't want this this acts as a
diode this way
and then it switches sends power here
this torch turns off that gets unpowered
all is good in the world now the really
important thing about this setup
if if our pet dies and his happiness
wasn't all the way down
it might be it at two three or four when
these are extended
we need to be able to override it and
this setup allows us to do that
if i send power to this wire here it'll
override it
which is really really good and this is
all up and out of the way i believe so
i'm pretty happy with this uh
oh hey so if
i think that's our health bar there if
any
power if there's no power in this wire i
guess
then then we send power to this wire
to override i think that's how we have
to do it
um this guy man he's just waiting for
his chance
just waiting he wants me so bad
oop dangerous
hates redstone
yeah that's how you spell redstone with
the space no i know i know
um all right let's get rid of him
i'm gonna go see where he came from
oh no you don't
oh he brought a buddy
and now from his perspective the signs
pointing at me
oh that was a miss
get out of here
all right so i put in that override line
of wire so even though the happiness is
at three when the eyes should be full
they're not because the the health is at
zero
so he's dead uh it's being overwritten
and we can we can see this working
uh let's see if i can get up high enough
to show you i really gotta
set up some proper scaffolding
yeah okay so that's the variable for
the health it goes to that comparator up
to that
redstone dust there gets to that torch
goes over top
that wiring that way that goes all the
way down to repeater and to our override
line
there okay those are all the steps so if
we were to
give him some health if he was still
alive
uh we would see a difference
yeah you heard it switch he's alive
he's got spirit in his eyes now
and now he's got the full eyes and he's
got one one health bar
now i really want to try to get the
smile working this episode too because i
think it'd be really cool to see
the whole face working together linked
to the
the happiness bar here uh so hopefully
we can get that done today
i have no idea how to do the wiring
though
it's going to be really complicated i
think
um let's let's head back here and see if
we can figure something out
oh just kidding it's all done i got it
all
i got it all hooked up here uh it took
me a while to figure out and it's
pretty complicated but
let's let's look at the demonstration
first and then maybe we'll go over the
wiring real quick
i did this off camera just so we could
get it done today
and hopefully do something else so this
is the variable for
the happiness uh
i'm gonna switch it so it starts
incrementing or increasing i mean
so right now super sad we see it's at
level one
happiness oh
level two his eyes they became fuller
they're a little bit more
pouty he hasn't given on
up on life at this stage level three
neutral face
oh so cool to see it change
wilson's gonna be a very
very emotional happy face level four
level five is the super content with
life
face oh yeah
so that's all directly linked with the
happiness bar there with our variable
that is really cool to see it and we can
even watch it go in reverse
switch it to subtraction
so again the idea with these variables
is we'll keep them locked
just about all the time the only time
it's not going to be locked is when
we're either increasing or decreasing
the stat which will only be for
like split seconds at a time
oh he's just normal happiness now
and i also link this up with
the health and
my plan with this by the way the way i
figured out the wiring
uh i decided what i need to do is have
like if he's dead dead face must
override everything
because uh regardless of whatever the
happiness level is
dead face wins so
i made sure when i wired it that if all
three
three lines of redstone were powered
that it would make the dead face that
was my
my first thing um let's go
let's go kill him sounds so wrong
sorry wilson i'll bring you back though
come on there it is all right so he's
dead now
sorry wilson dead face
and we can see this even if i turn this
so it starts adding happiness again
uh there will be no change man i i don't
know what happened but i got this like
cut in my lip and it's bleeding right
now and it's
driving me crazy
must be dry air uh but yeah
see it's a level one still dead face
level two still dead face so it doesn't
change
the other thing i figured though is i
want
sad face to be the default if there is
nothing powered
which isn't the opposite of dead face
though
is the thing so to do that
i added in some extra
man i don't know how i'm gonna show this
even
um
well this this line goes to
uh second and fourth row on the face
on the smile and it's just such a mess
to see
if i spend too long on this we won't
have any time left either
this goes to the middle
and then this is the outer
there and there this top wire so this is
connected
to here you can see i added an
extra torch here though extra redstone
torch to invert it one more time
but i can access this sooner from my
override line which is over here
this is my my main override
coming from the
from the health bar up here so i just
drew off from this line that we did
before this repeater is really important
it prevents
current from backflowing to here which
would totally
uh wreck our face so it goes down
to here down down down
to here to this one redstone torch this
torch
is connected to all three of our main
lines
so it goes down here
it goes into this one over here and also
to the one above
this one goes um
it's complicated i'm sorry guys if you
want eventually i'm going to put my
world up for download again and you can
check it out closer
when i do that uh
the main thing is i had to do it in
order so go sad face
happy or sad face neutral face happy
face
um at full power is happy face that no
power is sad face
so it goes to here this is that's this
is it's
uh i hate you face this is sad face
wait no
wait a minute i'm lost
well anyway um neutral faces here
neutral face connects to two of these
uh then finally happy face since it's
the absolute
opposite of sad face i just have to
power all three
so goes down one further here
to this repeater
and then that goes to the outer
outer edges of the smile anyway you get
the idea i hope
um now that we got that done that was
probably the toughest part of this whole
project i'm guessing
although stuff like feeding it and
that's going to be pretty complicated
too
but as far as
the variables and everything that's just
going to be a lot of
uh timing stuff which isn't super
complicated it's going to be a mess to
wire though for sure
um and then we have to do the
interactive stuff
but we're gonna leave this project here
for today and i think we'll go
go do something fun not that this wasn't
this was a lot of fun for me
we'll go do something else something
different
yeah so i thought for a change maybe
like for the next five or ten minutes in
the video we'll just go
go on a little adventure go exploring go
collect some glowstone and some
nether quartz that kind of thing and
give me a chance to
talk to you guys because you know the
way i do my videos i don't
like people often comment i'm i'm like a
man of mystery i don't reveal anything
or or i'm not going to now either by the
way
but uh no um i don't really talk too
much about
other stuff besides the game and that's
largely because of just the way i do my
videos it's like i don't have a chance
to because i'm
very direct with everything it's lots of
cuts lots of
you know to the point stuff so it makes
it tough for me to talk so
every now and then it's good to just
take it take a moment to relax
and do something like this so
um what are we gonna talk about today
guys
uh i think i'm gonna
talk mostly about my channel
maybe some of my plans with my channel
um there's been some
[Music]
some thoughts i've been having uh
first of all let's let's talk about this
uh as you guys know
i don't really do hd on my
on my channel i do tutorials in hd
usually
and everybody requests it but
um i'm very limited on the internet i
can get where i
where i live it's not that it's as
simple as
paying more to get better internet it's
not actually available
is the problem um
so i haven't been able to do hd videos
really like i've tried it in the past
but it was a huge hassle
um because it would take like i upload
my videos
during the night like when i go to bed
and then i was finding like even when i
would wake up the next day like eight
hours later
uh videos were like half done uploading
so
that would make it so i couldn't use my
internet really for
most a day as well which was not really
all that nice you know so i kind of
stopped
doing like i only tried hd videos from
maybe 10 episodes or something like that
and then i
gave up it was too much hassle uh
but now i've actually switched internet
service providers
and even though
like my hardware hasn't changed at all
there's still that limit
uh turns out this internet service
provider i was with
was actually throttling my upload
thing guys man so
it was even less than what i could have
got
so the new guys it's pretty much doubled
my
upload speed from about 0.4
to how much we get about
0.8 oops upload 0.8 upload speed
uh so let's that's like double and i'm
finding now when i upload my videos
they're done in two three hours usually
which is
you know definitely within
reason you know uh i kind of have that
eight hour mark if it's done in eight
hours
i don't mind doing it in hd so
yeah i think i might be able to switch
to hd on my
on my channel or at least i'm gonna try
i'm not gonna promise i'm gonna keep it
it's more than just like uploading
there's other hassles involved with
switching to hd
like i have to it takes longer for my
videos to
process um minecraft i better use these
i brought that for a reason
um i might have trouble like recording
in hd as well like my frame rate's not
going to be as good takes more hard
drive space
takes longer to upload as well if i ever
try to do more than one video in a day
it's going to be
a hassle for sure but i'm going to try
it
hopefully soon i was supposed to do it
this episode but i forgot
i was kind of hoping to find some courts
let's go further out i think it goes
stone pretty easily anytime
um the other thing is i've tried
streaming in the past and i wasn't
really able to because of the upload
speed but now that
it's double i
i might be able to try stream again
it's not something i'd really plan on
doing regularly but
i don't think i've been out this far
maybe i have
but you know once in a while maybe once
every two weeks or something would
definitely
be nice to do because with my videos i
don't
really get a chance to interact with you
guys
like i would like to it you know it's
it's me talking i don't actually get
that one-on-one
that you kind of can get uh streaming
um and there's a lot of things i do that
i
could stream like i play
i play pvp games a lot but
i guess my attention wouldn't really be
on you guys it would be on those so
maybe that's not the best
hey but
i have been here but like
um
i'm gonna do it oh and i didn't even
kill him are you kidding me
but like working on my map or that kind
of thing that's definitely something
that would be great for streaming i
think
i could get input from you guys and also
a really relaxing thing to work on while
talking
uh and be able to look at the chat easy
um so yeah i might try streaming i'm not
going to announce it
at first my my twitch
account is etho tv i believe
on twitch if you want to subscribe or
anything like that
um i probably won't announce when i do
stream to start off with until i'm
comfortable with it because it's not
something i'm too good at
um the other thing is i got a call from
google today
someone from google which oh here we go
they were kind of encouraged me
encouraging me to run my channel more
professionally
because i'm very bad at that um
yeah i'm lazy
i hate to say it when it comes to
channel stuff because it's not
all that fun to do things like
thumbnails and
that's not really what they talked about
though the main thing and this is
something i definitely have been wanting
to do for a long time
is uh add annotations at the end of my
videos so
when you finish watching one of my
videos you'll see
links to like three other videos of mine
and
the idea is to try to encourage you to
watch more of my other videos
so i might start doing that it's not
going to be
intrusive or anything but i need to make
make that a point and also i might add a
subscribe button
at the end of my videos or something
like that maybe a like reminder i don't
know
exactly what i'm going to do but yeah
they kind of want me to
do a better job with that kind of thing
and it would help me out if i did
um so this dead ends doesn't it
what's up here that's the other thing
i haven't really had any contacts with
google so it was nice to
nice to get a call from them as being
being an
independent guy on youtube i'm always
worried what happens if i have a problem
i don't have anyone to
uh contact so turns out they were trying
to contact
me for weeks and i just had no idea
i wasn't checking my email frequently
enough
so now i kind of have a contact at
google again
which is good um
but yeah enough about the channel
um i think we're about
ready to wrap up this episode i guess
tv shows guys watch white collar it's a
good show
yeah that's all i got to say about that
it's like uh
well if i say more then and i'm lying
aren't i
it's an fbi detective type show it's
pretty good though if you haven't seen
it check it out
uh watch from the beginning though
um but yeah i guess let's get to the
comment reading and we'll
call it an end for today
[Music]
here's the comment i picked up for today
guys it is
our 250 episodes that's crazy
that's a quarter of a thousand oh my
goodness
yeah um the comment are you planning on
making
any ouge in the near future ooch series
i don't see them as a filler but as a
special ooja is like uhc
the first two seasons every time i get
home from school
i click on the huge video with the
tinkling feeling in my
stomach maybe you're hungry dude you
gotta eat after school
uh just the little pranks awesome quotes
and the overall chemistry are like
the best thing on the tubes
that's cool i'm glad people at least
some people like ooch
uh yeah so oojas
myself good and bwo playing ctm maps
basically
um last one we did was final fantasy two
by three two um
we didn't really discuss like if we want
to do another one afterwards but
the impression i kind of got from good
and sort of from bwo
is that they're done with ctm
um yeah i don't know
i think bw prefers just other style of
adventure maps more so
and i think good's just done with it but
i don't want to speak
totally for them um
i might do ctm myself still i'm not sure
yet i'm kind of on the fence about ctm
maps myself
uh but i'm guessing ooj isn't going to
happen i think
that's done for um
could be wrong i don't know uh
but who knows maybe i'll play with
someone else in the future
i'm i'm open for things like that that's
for sure
um or i might just play myself i don't
know but yeah
that's kind of where we're at with with
uge it's on the fence
nobody's really said anything about it
uh but i'm i'm under the impression that
it's done for
yep but we had good times for sure i
enjoyed it
um but yeah that's it for today guys
have a good day thanks for watching
bye
[Music]