hey how's it going everybody this is ESO
and welcome back guys I've been hanging
out at the blades farm here this thing
is actually pretty good this is my first
time like really really using it I
missed my story doesn't have looting on
it anyway alright s-seem story's pretty
good I've done a bunch of a chanting
here
it's pretty nice every time we we
trigger it we get enough to do an
enchantment it's all measured out just
the right number of vases and I've been
doing quite a bit of it here alright are
we gonna get dip Strider
we got nothing else darn it that was the
last thing I had to do here though man
so I made four sets of armor here and I
think that should be pretty good if you
guys don't remember last episode we did
that wither fights and I died gracefully
but now we have a wither or Lucent world
and we didn't have any armor really to
deal with it so it's looks like a pretty
good set Oh
respiration Oh
depth Strider yeah yeah so we got some
stuff there it's good
so yeah I think we'll try to kill this
guy again what could go wrong right
we have full protection armor this time
instead of the mix with blast protection
so I want to see if that makes a big
difference or not now cuz I don't think
the blast protection really helped us
out last time like I took a lot of
damage quickly and I'm gonna try not to
spam click this time
well that might help my chances do you
should be up over here somewhere our
gear is also probably on the ground so
if I can recover that that would be
awesome got to be around here somewhere
right
I don't see him guys
you see whither I don't see whither the
last thing I oh okay that's bad off I
don't see him in easier that's like the
worst case alright I guess
oh there's a bullet coming here blue
bullets I guess I'll check my stuff here
and we'll go in oh I see it now he's up
over there okay
alright and do the strength very nervous
about this again oh I don't want those I
want these
okay let's hope for the best though he
just actually still damaged from the
fight still have half down on his health
okay that's a good start
this is not the terrain I want to fight
him in though it's like really rough
here see let's try to get away from my
stuff if it's still there don't spam
click don't stand plea
okay not taking as much damage I feel
and ease down baby look at that
so protection for on everything seems to
be a lot better we had the exact same
setup otherwise where's my star fool you
died right here why can't I see the star
oh man
I'm like the most blind person guys you
probably saw in I didn't it doesn't blow
up from the wither blasts so it should
be around here was it on fire no those
are my shots let's not worry about the
start right now I'm more more interested
in my gear here which should be around
here if any of it survived yeah there's
some pearls did he get everything else I
mean you destroyed everything else there
it is
oh man okay we got it
oh yeah you got to love the new sound
effects in the game man
it just makes killing cows so much more
satisfying it's like you're actually
clobbering them you know like crushing
their bones so good so yeah guys I made
a little bit of a discovery with my
world here I guess one of the snapshots
caused all the tripwires to vanish
disappear from the face of the world I
got a I gotta go and fix all my trip
wires in my world I can't get that here
all right let's grab a few more so this
is the spider farms spider farms are
affected the blaze farm was I fixed that
already
trapdoor sounds oh yeah
and the big one though the Enderman farm
2.0 guys I have to like place a thousand
string to fix that thing it's gonna be
nuts I don't know which snap shot did it
but it was one of the recent ones I
think doc said it might have been the
one where they made it so ender pearls
didn't trigger tripwires I don't know
anyways so I watched that footage back
from the wither fights compared it to
the first time we did it the second time
I forgot to take a regen potion so I
made a mistake there but I was fine
without it survived in the first fight I
was taking at most two and a half hearts
damage with two pieces of protection
four and two pieces of blast protection
for the one we just did with full
protection for armor I was only taking
one and a half hearts at most so it was
a lot a lot better state like half the
damage alright that's fixed very good
alright so well anyways guys I got a
project in mind for today this was
brought up in my comments again last
episode there's something that's been
long overdue
this entrance here guys this entrance
it's such a mess it has been for a long
time
I was hoping if we just like left it I
would eventually think of something cool
to do with it but that still hasn't
happened and it still looks bad so we're
just gonna try clean it up a little bit
today and see if we can make anything
happen with it because right now it's
just like we could only make it better
right I don't think I would make it
worse all right so here's here's the
first thing we're gonna do this like a
little archway here way too close to the
stairs I don't know what I was thinking
when I did this we're just gonna maybe
bump it up one block see if we make this
work all right
we're just gonna make little adjustments
and stuff around here and see if we can
come up with anything that looks half
decent then I guess we'll Boop we'll
have to do that this that's my official
bed by the way up there a lot of you
guys wonder like etho why don't you
build a bedroom in the man cave look
we've got a beautiful bedroom there what
do you talk about look at this access
got a ladder nice gold ceiling and then
you just click on it
I wonder if this still works I haven't
used it in so long okay well that was
terrible thank you for that all right
it's a wonderful bedroom top notch I
should make it a tutorial on this it's
it's so good all right I just killed our
beacon hopefully that didn't mess it up
too bad ah let's see so I'm gonna do the
archway up one more block like so and I
keep like switching let's put the wood
over there that way I don't keep doing
that okay like that and then can we move
this little little thing here forward
one block maybe that'll do the trick
guys listen to this you listening you
hear anything I hope you didn't cuz I
just got a new office chair and it
doesn't squeak when I lean back now it's
it's so cool
for I've gotten into the habit of
sitting up straight because if I ever
leaned back while recording it would
make this giant squeak sound and I would
like to have to scrap the footage so I
just got into the habit of never moving
while recording and it wasn't very
comfortable now I didn't like lean back
and stuff oh it's it's so good simple
pleasures of life alright so yeah let's
get rid of this and something we'll
worry about that later I did this thing
here I think my original plan was to put
water in this lake channel so let's try
that outs and just see what it looks
like see if we wanted to do that let's
make sure it doesn't make a mess of the
man cave those who will block off some
of the paths here and I brought some ice
to do it okay so if we just put water
here
let it flow what does that look like can
we do it both sides and try beat it it's
gonna try flow somewhere here I'm gonna
stop it oh oh it didn't make it all the
way down
alright let's bust this good how does
that feel it might be okay another thing
I'm gonna do here I'm just gonna go long
and span the walls here with leaves and
see if I like that or not and then we'll
start making little refinements to the
whole thing here okay well it's starting
to do something here right starting to
take some sort of shape it's okay for
for first rough draft so we got the
water kind of evened out now and I've
added in these like dark oak pillars as
like a supports type of thing and then I
did this slab thing running across I'm
trying to make it similar to other parts
of the man tube like borrowing similar
things I've done but also trying to make
it a unique section of the man cave like
you that I did the water over here for
example so it kind of copies that having
the water on both sides
and you know arches leaves all that kind
of stuffs pretty common throughout the
cave here but it's it's a little bit
different right like nowhere in the cave
do we have leaves on the side like this
right now it still looks pretty rough
pretty bad but we might be able to
refine it might make like a path going
this way just so it's not totally even
on both sides too and I guess we want
some some sort of entrance something
that makes it feel like you're going in
into something right right now it's not
quite giving that feel the way I want it
so I'm gonna build up pillars here I
think just to give some height on our
sides see if that makes it better
oh all right we want that feeling of
being enclosed as we go in yeah and then
have like maybe leaves I don't know
leaves might do do something here too I
feel like we need to maybe I'll just
mark the area jumping around all over
the place like an idiot here all right
maybe if we bring it out like this and
sort of start rounding it and then maybe
one more like that that's kind of the
amount of space I want open as we go
down here right so then I want to build
that up so it's sort of straight over
here kind of like a quarter circle I
guess you would call it quarter steer oh
man I think we're getting close here
guys we just now got it done that's
let's start that is way too dark all
right
this is unfinished area kind of if we
ever want to add another passage here we
can
is the idea kind of like a little secret
tunnel over there but yeah guys check it
out we're getting really close getting
really close to done with it I think so
I've added in some lighting on these
like pillars here all the way up so we
got it here like every step another one
there another one here and then this is
the last one there I did a I did a thing
here I really liked how this looks
actually and I don't really like this
this part though I got to do something
else with it it's not looking right like
it for sure needs a backdrop so the
leaves aren't you can't see through the
leaves you know but even still I don't
think that's quite looking right but I
like the the dark oak logs I think that
give gives it a nice contrasting color I
like this little fence thing we got
going up and the leaves on the sides I
really like just a lot of little changes
need to be done with it
of course this squid makes sound now -
and it's like freaking me out it's like
a very very alien creepy sound let's try
some things here lots of little tweaking
and changing I'm doing - its I just had
a fence down there - oh but then it
connects no that's gonna put some
flowers and stuff on the side here -
we're gonna have to pay a visit to our
flower farm though I think I've pretty
much used up our stock
what else should we do this area needs a
few more leaves good I guess
and what else what else the man cave Oh
baby our home sweet home finally has an
entrance so let me know what you guys
think about this I just added in a
little bit more structure to it so we
got the the Oaks slabs and stuff here
some more dark oak pillars and and stuff
like that I also put a backdrop in so
you can't see through the leaves anymore
I think that makes it a lot better and
if we go down through in some vines some
lilacs we need maybe some pink tulips
and some white tulips but otherwise I'd
say it's good I took out the torches
back there because we got the offense
wall here so if there's anything that
spawns it'll be trapped anyway which i
think is kind of cool and what else what
else yeah I think that's that's about it
I think we've got note we've gone over
everything the only other thing I gotta
do is move out all these comments of the
day these are the very original ones
here the first I think the first episode
we did it was 204 Ethan what please if
what I mean I've never looked at these
did they interrupted you so please if
you so know ah
yes these were definitely worth saving
hey what happened all the text oh my
goodness I've never looked at these I
didn't realize they got every book when
did this happen a long time ago that was
310 369 369 is okay
oh snap
that kind of sucks well we have it
preserved in video I guess it's only the
last like 100 in some episodes we have
actual comments of the day and then a
few words from from the other stuff I'm
gonna move those to the library though
now that we have a spot forum the other
thing we got to do here get rid of these
last couple torches or our goal is to
get rid of all the torches in the
finished areas so if we get rid of those
it's that dark that is pretty dark ah
what what can we do here maybe above
this dragon head again we'll just do one
of these I like how these look I don't I
don't mind doing them and check it out I
emptied them all comments have been
moved these chests have been here for so
long guys it's gonna be weird with them
gone I don't know if I'll be able to get
used to it alright so those are gonna go
we probably want to get rid of these
mushrooms these have been here forever -
they look a little bit out of place
thing is now that the chests are gone
and the mushrooms are gone it's gonna
look too plain isn't it we're gonna have
to do something else here alright so
maybe for the lighting the rest of it
here we will put some glowstone over
here I think that'll do the trick
oh that's the beacon up there okay we
can take this out though yeah let's just
put a bunch of clothes stone up here
right above the leaves that
let's go underneath it just check the
lighting so it says light 9 that means
that our feet it's probably 8 so that's
just above mob spawning level which is
good alright the only thing is I don't
know about like over here light 7 oh
darn it yeah that's gonna be too dark
right in the corners that's the problem
there's always like the corners that are
hard to light
or the very middle of a path one or the
other all right and then we just cover
this back up maybe what we can do is
actually let's let's try this
put some bushes in here maybe yeah let's
try this it looks a little uh a little
strange doesn't it
here let yeah I like this actually let's
get rid of this fence down here and then
one more bush here that's pretty good
yep so I think we did a pretty good job
here guys I'm happy with it I had the
only thing though this wall seems very
plain to me now what do we do with it I
don't know the thing the thing about
this wall it's like right right there
you know like we don't have any any room
to work behind there and we have to
leave this stone here so a little bit to
limit it maybe we'll just put like a
crafting table enderchest sort of thing
over there it'll probably be fine
there's also one dark spot left here a
light level seven block but other than
that I think I got it I got them all
maybe one over here too oh no it's like
level 8 I think we're good uh-huh so I
got something to show you guys this kind
of blew my mind the other day when I saw
it and I I don't know if it's something
I missed or I'm pretty sure it's
something new in the snapshots look at
this and drop an anvil and tada what how
long has this been in the game I have no
idea like my punching bag so it does
that on fences and on fence gates and
the cool thing about fence gates because
it's an entity like a like a moving
entity
it'll actually fall through a fence gate
too and I think I tested this out on
creative and it was like crushing cows
and and stuff so I'm tempted maybe to
you to make a cattle crusher like I did
in my modded series because you can move
pit or you can move anvils upwards as
long as they are not in block form so I
think you could do like a cow crushing
anvil thing that never breaks could be
cool anyways I just wanted to show you
guys that in case you've never seen it
alright everybody so one last thing
we're gonna do here today I hopped over
to the gold farm gastn gold farm we're
gonna reset up the iron golems and I'm
probably gonna end this episode afk here
let's see this one double check these
still work in the current version
because it's always miss you know all
right go Gilda zombie pigman oh no
that's not gonna work that is the worst
oh my goodness is has gotten really bad
now man really oh the last one just died
there too ok so it's gotten even worse
than the last time I checked because
before they would take damage
occasionally but it was pretty rare for
them to actually die now they're just
getting hammered by these guys I want to
leave this place but I'm keep picking up
stuff and I can't break the glass to get
out and throw it and break it and to
slow way too slow ok we're getting out
of here oh man this gold farm might be a
riperoni then hmm
that's too bad I really like this thing
but we still have the other one
it's just not super efficient
unfortunately all right guys I'm gonna
get on with the comment of the day it
says sorry etho but the statue doesn't
really fit in the library it is too
large and doesn't go well with all the
wood interesting idea though also the
red carpet looks amazing don't change it
yeah so we're gonna move grandpa wither
bottoms over to the underground village
area I guess I think is the idea now and
yes it is a reference to don't starve
with her bottom oh we're all good oh I
love wings they're the best thing I
would have just died all right we're
good
I mistyped the the comment of the day by
the way all right
yeah it's a reference to wicker bottom
from don't starve anyways guys I think
that's gonna be it for today I got a
stay away from those blazes in this
version of Minecraft or at least in my
version if a blaze attempts to shoot me
it crashes my game and it hard crashes
it like you cannot join it again after I
have to MC edit and delete the blaze so
I am very scared to be around here
anyways I hope you enjoyed today's
episode hope you're having a good time
off if here if you got time off and I
will see you guys in the next one take
care bye light
you