I couldn't think of an intro so what'd
you get this is my angry voice I hate
hates making dispensers more than
anything in this game why why do we have
to do it this way why can't there be a
simpler way this is the worst most
painful oh I miss click No
okay we'll get through this we'll get
through this you know it's one of those
moments guys like when I'm making
dispensers I'm thinking to myself is
this it am i turning into a cranky
person have I become bitter
that's what's it happening here well I I
don't think that's what it is I think
everybody hates making dispensers I
don't think it's just me right
I hope not anyways it's like the only
recipe in the game where you you have to
use a non stackable item in the crafting
recipe so if you got to make a stack or
two like I just did
please tell me nobody enjoys that
because I certainly don't and I complain
about it every time I have to do it but
yeah today guys we're gonna head over to
the end this thing is not as fast as I
remember it I haven't used it in a while
this is our our ice road to the end
I remember you get hungry pretty quick
on it did they change this where you
can't like I'll maybe my timings to stop
this a little bit faster now I feel like
I used to be able to get through this
look faster though huh okay we made it
we made it this is our portal to the end
let's hop in we're gonna be building a
bee farm today guys finally it's
happening
so Iowa's is gathering some materials
for its off-camera mostly we're got like
two chakra boxes full of stuff and a
bunch of stuff in a redstone box as well
yeah so we want to build the bee farm in
the end here but we don't want to build
it on the main island probably so so
that we don't have to worry about the
dragon killing it so we're gonna go to
through one of these portal things
oh you can't just walk through them yeah
it was curious I don't think I've ever
done that before I always use the ender
pearl okay yeah this area over here
looks like it should work for the build
I was mostly concerned like I don't want
to build it over top the void in case I
fall while building you know I like the
idea of having the island underneath us
as like a safety net as we make this
thing so we're gonna come out of the
portal here we'll probably have some
sort of a room like we'll come out we'll
have a room in this room we'll have
storage for all the honey we collect
from the bee farm so I'm guessing this
room's gonna be at least 9 or 11 blocks
wide so this is 11 here and then beyond
that is gonna be where we actually make
the honey so I just put down a bit of a
floor next to this portal thing we're
gonna go through and make sure we
actually land on this and not on the end
stone down below when we come through so
we'll go through and then we'll come
back
where did we end up pretty close to
where we want to be okay
so put us oh that's interesting it puts
you inside blocks even that I didn't
expect let's try that again that was
interesting yeah or no it didn't put me
in blocks I'm just crouching right yeah
I thought it put me inside that block
over there for some reason
okay everybody so check it out we got
our basic layout to the beef farm all
set up here and it doesn't look the best
that's true
it's true but we're not really going for
looks with this be far more going for
efficiency and production which is why
we're building it in the end in the
first place because if we build it in
the overworld the bees will sleep during
the nights and we want them working 24/7
so if we build it in the end they never
sleep it'll be busy as bees over here
alright um so yeah with this design we
got the bee farm beehive over here
flower right in front hoppers underneath
that this is supposed to be tilled land
but I got to set up some water for it to
keep it tilt and then when items land on
top of the tilled land here they go in
the hoppers down below here yeah so
whenever the beehive updates observer
triggers flips a trapdoor which one goes
down to the dispenser and that will have
some empty bottles in to collect the
honey or shears to make the honeycomb
but yeah we got the same basic design
copied four times so it's just mirrored
between these two and then we have
another set over here and now we're
gonna like start expanding it out this
way I'm thinking in blocks of like 15 so
this is our first first one here then 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 alright so we got 15
over here so that's gonna be 60 beehives
because 15 times 460 will probably aim
for like 120 with this farm and just
take it from there and see how that
works see how much honey we actually
produce I don't know like how big this
needs to be
probably should place the dispensers
first now I have to hold shift here
oopsies all right so I don't think this
should take us very long to build it's a
pretty simple design just copied many
times so it's just like how many
beehives do we actually want to set up
the big trouble we're gonna have is I'm
gonna run out of iron it takes a lot of
hoppers to build this thing and I don't
have a lot of iron left so we'll see how
far we can get with it and we still have
that issue with it possibly getting
jammed so I'm just gonna run like a
bunch of redstone over top the observers
here probably flip the trapdoor every so
often if it gets jammed that'll that'll
fix it and then that should be fine
the other thing that's gonna take a
bunch of time is breeding the bees once
we get this fully set up it's gonna take
a while to build up the population so
yeah otherwise it's it's an easy thing
to do awesome good stuff so check it out
we got our first section complete tier
60 beehives all set up ready to roll
ready for the bees and let's let's put
them in there so I brought over some bee
nests with us with a few bees inside now
the tricky part with with these we got
to make sure like when we place them and
break them afterwards that we don't
anger all the bees and have them sing us
and I'll die right so I'm gonna set
these up maybe over here hopefully the
bees will come out come out to play yeah
some of these might be empty I'm not
sure hopefully some of them have easin
okay whoo we got some at least okay they
both popped out here I'm gonna break the
nest now they're gonna get mad at me
oh I should have sealed that that's not
good okay I messed up pretty bad there
but as long as you have flowers they'll
follow you around so I'm asking them
back inside here now we're gonna start
the be breeding hopefully yeah or go
first baby bee it's gonna take a long
time because each hive can handle three
bees and we have 60 so that's a hundred
and eighty that we need here
the other big thing I just realized like
for each beehive we have one dispenser
and two hoppers for distributing like
the glass bottles or the shears so that
means to fill this up with last bottles
all of these all sixty of them is gonna
take like 42 over 42 chests of sand it's
melted into glass
and made into bottles so we're gonna
need a lot of sand which I wasn't
prepared for oh yeah you know this is
actually gonna be way harder to do than
I thought isn't it cuz like breeding the
bees is gonna take a couple hours here
maybe and then collecting the sand like
42 chests of sand that's gonna take a
couple hours - we might need to break
this up a bit the thing about the bees
like you can breed them every five
minutes but like once they go into their
beehive they don't grow any more or they
don't the countdown doesn't go down
anymore as they're in the Beehive and
like when they're babies they don't grow
when they're in the Beehive and I think
they spend only like a quarter of their
time out of the Beehive so if you can
breed them every five minutes it's
actually like every 20 minutes then yeah
unless like what I've been doing is I've
just been standing here holding a flower
so that they don't go back inside so
that reduces the time for these first
few bees but eventually like there's
gonna be so many I can't do that for
them uh yeah I'm like really struggling
here I'm trying to decide like what to
do like I could just go farm that sand
like it's not a huge deal
but like I think it's really important
you build a witch farm in your world
before you build the beef farm so that
you can get the free bottles from the
witches to use with your your bee farm
we actually do have a witch farm it's
this really trash so originally we had
an arrow method like where we would
shoot the witches off of a platform with
arrows that was very gimmicky mostly did
just for fun then I tore that out and I
replaced it with a water system here
which is not good at all so I'm gonna
maybe switch this up with a shifting
floor system fortunately in my world
there there are no like dual witch farms
or quads like some people have you have
to like you have to pick a special seed
to get that pretty much like chances of
actually finding one of those randomly
are extremely low so probably the first
thing we should do is just make sure
shifting floors still work in the game I
know there was an issue I think a one
point four point one where mobs wouldn't
spawn on soul sand anymore I think
that's that's been fixed now again I
just want to make sure we can actually
fall through so I'm gonna stand on the
soul sand here press the button and yeah
I think we fell through here actually
let's add some barriers yours yes so
it's a little bit more clear try this
again so it doesn't go we don't fall
through on that we have to be standing
on the soul sand for it to happen yeah
and we fell through the ground okay
that's good if a mob spawns on the dirt
though the soul sand will will go over
and then it'll switch back and then
they'll fall through so yeah it looks
like that's still still fine okay so
we're gonna tear out this old wiring
here the hopper clock just runs up to a
bunch of dispensers with water buckets
in we're gonna get rid of all that and
then start fresh here
so to be honest I don't entirely know
how to build one of these but I'm gonna
try my best here and hopefully it'll
work hopefully I don't miss any crucial
detail to the design ah but yeah I think
all we got to do is like mixin soulsand
every second block and we originally had
ice here so I'm just gonna leave it ice
for right now while we're building this
might change it later
I got more yeah we do okay good so we
shift this back and forth like left and
right here so we got to get a bunch of
pistons on this side and this side that
that'll do that I think we can maybe
stick in some trip wires at this top
layer and detect one witches spawn but
I'm not entirely sure if that'll work um
we're gonna get our trapdoors flip them
up here and do that all all the way
through here and yeah so it's a it's a
triple layer which firm just one single
like spawn area though so the idea is we
shift the top the top layer all the
witches on there will fall down to the
second layer combined with them then we
shift that second layer they fall down
again we should shift the third layer
and then we're gonna drop them like
20-some blocks down below where they'll
die from the fall damage or get to a
one-hit kill if we want to kill them
ourselves and that's I think all that
all we have to do with there right I
don't want to do a Windows Update I
think that's what that was awesome so
check it out here we got it set up and
functioning so it goes top middle and
then bottom I have a 5 tick delay
between activating the layers I might
need to increase that to 6 or 7 cuz I'm
not sure if they'll fall down in time
I think it's pretty close as it is right
now but yeah top middle bottom then it
waits a few seconds here four more
witches spawn and then it triggers again
and they should fall down here there is
no no place for them to fall at the
moment we just have water underneath
here so I have to dig a big hole or set
up some kind of killing area below but
this was actually a lot easier to build
than I thought like the Redstone this is
pretty simple so we just have lines of
redstone here running to the Pistons six
sets of Pistons two per layer right and
the Pistons are just behind the ice here
and up here and over there and then we
just activated it all on the back here
you've got a hopper clock running right
now I just have I think eight or nine
items in here umm it goes to a
monostable circuit here and both sides
we have a two tick delay between like
this left side of Pistons activating and
on this side and then it goes down like
a staircase here to each of the layers
but yeah I guess let's try to get this
thing done since it's so close to to
being done so what we're gonna have to
do is get rid of all this water I did
not bring in these sponges with me so
I'm just gonna use dirt I'll probably
leave one layer of dirt here while on
the building so they don't keep fallin
on my head like as I dig this
very good very good so making some
pretty good progress here it's just
about done I'm noticing when that bottom
layer moves some light is shining in so
we should probably try to stop that I
did move a beacon closer to here with
haste to so it's able to dig out this
hole pretty quickly but it is looking
like our spawn rates are horrible so we
got a we got a bit of work left to do
here mostly got a little caving next I
think try finished lighting up the rest
of the caves oh we are spawning a couple
guys it looks like yeah so this is the
hole we dug nothing too fancy so I just
realized like the walls weren't right
they were like an 8 by 8 or something
it's supposed to be a 7 by 9 so I just i
double-checked this like wait a minute
so I got that fixed up now it's a 7 by 9
area here with this being the center
point I guess yeah so we got a couple
options on how we could collect the
drops together from this we could set up
like a hopper minecart running
underneath some slabs to pick them all
up or I think we're just gonna use
hoppers it's a lot easier a lot less
hassle and it's not really that big of
an area that I don't mind spending this
much because I found a beacon that was
made out of iron as well over here so I
got about 2 2 stacks of iron blocks
again pretty happy about that I don't
mind spending it on the hoppers here
well we got the witch farm totally set
up now like it's totally functional look
at it oh it's just amazing no it's
horrible it's really bad so we got to
decorate it still looks it looks nasty
we have a lot of subsystems to set up
like a sorting system for the items
everything is getting collected into
this double chest right now
but we can like do stuff in the area and
we'll be collecting the drops and as we
improve things it's gonna get better and
better but the big thing the rates look
at the rates here this is horrendous
I have believe it or not lit up a bunch
of the caves in the area
but it's the final few that make the
biggest difference so I gotta find those
final few caves light them up and we
should see a big improvement although
I'm not entirely sure how fast this is
supposed to run like if it's working
perfectly because I've never made a
witch farm before I got nothing to
compare it to nobody's stuck in here
that's not the issue
there's something over here
[Music]
eat your food okay we got some guys oh
you got a few guys
that was a good one
all right so well that was pretty fun we
did a whole bunch of caving there got
three four five six seven about seven
and a half stacks of iron a whole bunch
of redstone again nametags horse armor
and we lit up the area here pretty good
so I guess cut down and to see if that
changed the spawn rates on these witches
chin of theirs yeah it lit up a whole
bunch of caves but I'm guessing there's
a few more in the area all right what
kind of rates are we getting
disappointed so far
um I got a bit stuff they're almost the
stacked glass bottles man but even when
this is running perfectly it's gonna
take forever get that as many glass
bottles as I want and we're getting
nothing nothing how come on I did so
much hey we got one boy
yeah so it's not like a problem with the
farm it's just the spawn area is so low
that if I don't perfectly light up all
the caves it's it's not gonna be great
and I got a bit more to do but I'm kind
of creeped out now but anyways guys you
know you know what it means when I say
but anyways right that means it's time
to wrap up the episode for today with
the comments of the day as we as we
always do so I picked out this one kind
of like it it says etho as your fan base
grows up or ages I think he means we
realize that being an adult is very
scary do you have any advice for your
fan base as we enter maturity keep up
the good work okay little disclaimer
first off here this advice might not
improve your life might make it worse no
guarantees but my general general life
advice here we go let's see let's go
financial first off so I would say
budget your money I think a general rule
is you don't want to spend more than a
third of your income I think it is on
housing every month so if you're renting
or if you have a mortgage or whatever
let's say you're making $3,000 a month
you probably don't want to be spending
more than a thousand of that on your
housing on your rent your mortgage
whatever it's generally a good idea to
always be investing at least five to ten
percent of your income per month as well
case you have a problem something comes
up that you don't expect you want to
have a little bit of a nest egg to go
off of you know don't go don't live
paycheck to paycheck very dangerous
because as soon as you run out of money
you gotta you gotta go credit then you
fall into debts which comes to the next
big etho advice don't go into debts if
you can avoid it maybe without your
housing it's fine like getting a
mortgage I would say it's better to get
a mortgage than to rent but
like be careful about like going into
debt buying a vehicle or something like
that I think that's a mistake like buy a
junker vehicle don't go into debt get in
something nice in my opinion I think
you're setting yourself for a lot of
stress and trouble down the road
if you do that let's see what else we
got here let's go for maybe lifestyle
like health let's go learn how to cook
yes that's a good one maybe try to only
eat out once or twice a week
beyond that you're gonna have a little
bit of trouble maybe with your with your
health and your weight and stuff and
maybe I'll just do one more here so
let's go for psychological advice
whoo-hoo here we go okay so a lot of
people they have problems they want to
solve in their life right maybe maybe
you want to find a job maybe you want to
find a spouse or whatever maybe maybe
you want to lose weight how do you lose
weights you set the goal to lose weight
right no no no if you have a problem in
your life the only way to solve it is
with an action setting a goal does not
solve your problem that's very important
to keep in mind you can have the goal to
lose weight but that's not actually how
you did you do it you have to have that
have an action guys you have to work out
you have to avoid eating garbage food
and you can't go like kay tomorrow I'm
gonna eat better tomorrow I'm gonna go
to the gym and work out actions only
exist in the present is the other
important thing to keep in mind so if
you want to lose weight the only time to
do it is now right now can't do it
tomorrow you can only do it right now
that's the only thing you can control
keep that in mind
likewise if you're trying to find a job
or whatever that's you got to do it
right now that's the only time you can
setting a goal to find a job isn't gonna
do it nope you gotta you gotta start
looking right now uh-huh anyways guys
that's it for today's
pisode thank you for watching hope you
enjoyed it take care have a good one
bye bye
[Music]