[Music]
uh-huh
all right so check it out guys what is
going on over here well i think you
probably know
uh lately we've been using a ton of
black stone
on our nether tunnels oh they take so
much it's insane
so we can get a bunch of blackstone just
by trading with the piglens bartering
with them
and we've been doing that but i find i'm
using it even faster than i'm getting it
that way
so i've decided just to go to the nether
here and tear down one of these bastions
they are
absolutely loaded with the stuff the top
half of the bastion
is the blackstone bricks up over there
but if you go
down a little bit you'll get to the the
foundation
and this is like the regular black stone
solid pretty much
all the way down to the lava level and
there is so much in there
we can get a a good stockpile of this
stuff and that's what we're gonna do
here
and also this is a great way of getting
the
oh dear
oh dear i don't have fire resistance
don't have fire resistance
kind of an oversight on the way here um
okay come on come on oh yeah it's
perfectly fine guys
tons of yielded blackstone that you
would never find otherwise because it's
like hidden
within the foundation not on the surface
level so you got to like mine the whole
thing to get to this
and also there's like tons of just like
gold blocks throughout the thing too
which is kind of nice
all right here no oh it gets knocked
back
awesome so back over at our nether hub
here we have another
tunnel uh reworked this is the very
first tunnel we ever built the stone
brick and iron bar one here
that goes down to the stronghold and our
dual blaze farm
you can see now we got some blue ice
down the center and some black stone
slabs and basalt on the side
but i did leave most of the tunnel
intact and then uh beyond here we got
the blackstone design again
left a little opening there so we can
still see the frog when we go through
and this leads down to our wither
skeleton farm the gas blaster 3000
and the goon farm and i think there's
one more thing over here
but it's a little bit of a shorter one
in the comments i saw some people asking
about the silverfish farm if i was gonna
fix it before the world tour so i
decided to
take a look at it here and i think it
actually works just fine
except i think the piston tapes broke
somehow
because this one is jammed please get
rid of that
oh that's a stone block not a silver
fish block that's weird
okay um let's go down here
and just bust a couple of these and see
what happens that also was a stone block
not a silver fin block okay
let him through oh i hear it running
that's a good sign
yeah i think uh i think it is jam
somehow there's some regular stone
blocks
mixed in there instead of silverfish
ones but you can see they entered the
stone block
it comes from a stone generator
and then when they enter it it updates
there's like a block update detector
there and then it pushes it over
and it all goes up into a big slab of
silverfish blocks in this uh
this big clump here all right so it's
looking like we used up our last beacon
on that bastion and i left it out there
so
it's probably a good idea to farm up a
few more withers here we have enough
skulls to spawn in nine more at the
moment
and i thought we would try automated a
little bit so we got to
carved pumpkins in here we got a bunch
of iron golems set up
it didn't work oh no
move one over here just test this oh now
it works okay it's trying to be all
fancy here you know all
all automated and stuff
oh i did not want to do that
oh this is not going well let's let's
head back
i guess we'll just have to spawn them in
manually all right so we got five iron
golems in there let's try this out so
the idea is they're gonna surround the
wither
we got this loaded in so all we gotta do
is hit the button
hopefully he won't fly away so there's
two good ways of doing this we can
either kill the withers with suffocation
that's good if you're doing a lot of
them
uh but if you're just doing a few the
iron golems were pretty good
they do a ton of damage quickly the only
downside is you got to repair them every
so often
and as long as you got enough iron
golems they should auto kill it too
yeah so we got the another star there
great
and then uh since we got them sitting in
here they can't walk
in the way there so we just reset and
yeah if they take a little bit of damage
you can just repair them with iron
cool so i am really excited about what
we're going to be doing next here i
asked you guys last episode
if we should focus on finishing projects
this episode or if we should just have
fun and
do the end reporter thing it sounds like
most of you guys want to see the end
reporter so that is what we're going to
be
messing around with today oh this is
going to be cool so
there is actually a lot of uh a lot of
different ways we could go around doing
this i thought we would kind of look at
a few options and then i'll pick one
and uh see see how it goes i guess so
first off
how are we going to load the ender
porters is a big one i kind of like the
idea of always loading it
while facing down like this just throw
it down
set in place nice and easy so to do that
it's looking like we're gonna need at
least six blocks of water
in the bubble column here so with just
five water blocks in the bubble column
when we throw it
we always hit the soul sand it's not
enough to slow it down
so we want to go with at least six but i
have noticed rarely
it will hit the soul sand still so we'll
go with seven
as a safety another really important
design question we need to answer is how
many
ender pearls do we want at each ender
porter because every time we use it
we're going to use up an ender pearl and
that we have to replace that somehow so
do we want to
maybe just every once in a while load 10
or 20 ender pearls into the ender porter
or just have
one at any given time i just want to
have one ender pearl
and every time we use it we have to
reload it i think that's the simple way
of doing it
and uh when we get lots of moving
objects like this in the game
it can cause lag as well so it's better
have to have fewer and because we're
gonna need to replace that ender pearl
every time we teleport it makes sense to
have a dropper loaded up with ender
pearls
that way we get one after each teleport
to replace the one we use
yeah we got it okay so we're at six we
throw it we're at five
and we're at six now we're at five so
that way we can teleport many times and
not worry about running out of end of
pearls
and uh yeah i'll just be convenient now
another thing you'll notice here is when
i teleport
i'm not above the water that's actually
a big problem because if i want to
quickly
replace that and i throw it it's going
to hit the ground i want to be over here
after the teleports
so i tried out a few different ways of
controlling that for example
one idea was to maybe put a cobblestone
wall here and then that space between
the wall
and the edge of the block isn't very big
i thought it would align us
over the water a bit um but what
actually happens
is oh that time it's
grabbed us it doesn't always do that
it's uh inconsistent too
yeah a lot of times it does this and you
can see we're still over the land even
though there wasn't enough space because
it
uh teleports us into the wall
which uh that's no good so what i
actually found works pretty good is uh
if we use trapdoors actually so we just
have a trap door over here
and like a redstone torch to keep it
open and then we just got to control
that redstone torch
and flip it down when we want to
activate the ender pearl yeah so check
it out we load the ender pearl like so
and then when we
activate it
we are over top the water and we can
just throw another one easy
easy to reset the other thing though is
you can see the trap doors closed for a
while ideally we want to be able to
throw it as soon as we teleport aha so a
stone button powers redstone for one
second we want to shorten that that's
too long
so we use a monostable circuit just the
sticky piston facing up
and then from that we set this repeater
let's try two
to see see how that works we're gonna
have to fine tune this a bit
figure out the sweet spot that might be
too fast
all right that was good if it's too
quick it might not allow the ender pearl
to land on it in time
so let's just do a few tests
oh yeah you see it didn't trigger so we
gotta make this a little bit longer then
okay so a setting of four seems to be
what we want any shorter than that and
the ender pearl isn't guaranteed
to land on the trap door and any longer
than that and we're just wasting time
so yeah it's good easy to reset awesome
so i think we got the basic mechanism
figured out for triggering it
now let's talk about the ender porter
network because that's important as well
so the idea is we're going to have end
reporters spread throughout the world
lots of them so ideally we want them
pretty simple to make as well because
we're going to be building
many interporters but how do we teleport
between them and how do we set them up
is a big question like we could do a
grid style maybe every 100 blocks of
parts
pretend these are end reporters by the
way the cobblestone blocks
maybe we equally space them between each
other you know and like every 100 blocks
have one um but the problem is let's say
my super smelter is right over here i'm
gonna have to teleport to an end
reporter and then walk like 40 blocks
in my super smelter yeah so i don't
really like the idea of doing a grid
style network because it's not going to
take us
exactly where we want to go we want to
put the end reporters right at our
important locations like our super
smelter our end portal
our guardian farm etc but another
network design
is a hub style so maybe you have a bunch
of end reporters and then
one key one in the center of the mall
and it's like
we gotta teleport from this end reporter
to the hub and then to
the next location or from here to here
to there
um but the problem with doing a hub
style
is like if we want to go from here to
here we can't just do that we have to go
to the center and then there the
advantage is we could make a really
fancy hub and have it look cool
the network style we're actually going
to go with is more like
synapses in the brain i would say like
where anything within rendered distance
of an end reporter we would want to
connect to so maybe we could
from this one connect to that one that
one and that one while those ones might
be a bit too far away
and then when we get to this one we
might be able to connect to this one and
this one and this one
and each one will probably connect to
between one and four um and that way
there'll be several different ways of
traveling through the network
and should be pretty efficient one other
key thing we got to decide is how we're
going to handle
traveling long distances like if we want
to go a thousand blocks we can't just go
from here
to here um because the wire is going to
pass through unloaded chunks
and then stop so i have decided i don't
want to do any chunk loading systems i
don't think
it's going to complicate things a lot
and also they're more likely to break in
future patches
so we're going to stick to just what's
within render distance i think so if we
go to
video settings i usually play around 17
chunks loaded
i think on servers a lot of times it's
10 that's 160 blocks
radius um or 12 which is 192. so that's
a pretty good distance still um
so we'll kind of plan with that in mind
like between each of the stations
and then there's one more complicated
thing to figure out how do we handle
going from here to here because we're
going to have to pass through these
other stations
do we somehow tell them in advance that
like when we get here we want to go here
and when we get here we want to go here
or do we
do we go from here to here and then
manually say i want to go here
and then manually say i want to go here
that'll take a little bit longer
probably
but it'll be much simpler ideally we
want to be able to send the signals
pretty quickly with standard redstone
you can go 15 blocks and then you need a
repeater
so this adds a tenth of a second delay
between each of these things so if we
want to go
160 blocks that's one second of delay
and if we go a thousand and 600 blocks
that's 10 seconds so it does start to
add up
over long distances and we'll probably
be putting down quite a bit of wire
between our ender porters to get them
connected together
and that got me thinking maybe i should
try to figure out something
better or something faster and kind of
got to thinking
tripwires might be the answer so a
tripwire
can go 40 blocks the string
plus there's two blocks for the tripwire
hooks themselves and then
another two blocks for the blocks they
connect to so it's like
44 blocks of instant wire and then
you can also attach redstone to that
after so we'll probably do a mix
that's like 60 blocks of instant wire
and then i also figured out a way to
extend it further
so to connect the redstone up to another
set of trip wires
and then we go redstone tripwires
redstone tripwires we can go as far as
we want basically
um we can't just activate the string
with redstone we need to
push an entity into it so i was thinking
we put a minecart in a dispenser
and then on a slant right below the
string
and that way right when it spawns it'll
be in the string and
keep it going so it should be close to
instant if not
instant and
yeah just like that we'll have to run
the minecart into a cactus or something
though to
get it back in here after that so so we
want it self-contained
um but yeah let's just do a quick little
test here kind of get an idea of the
speed
so just uh again this can run another 40
blocks i just have a short distance
there
just because i don't have space but yeah
we can go all the way down here and
basically get it instantly triggered
like so that's pretty cool all right
well i could talk about it all day but
talk is cheap right we gotta actually
get to
building the end reporters now but i
think we covered the concepts pretty
good there
and uh some different ways we could do
it uh i've decided
roughly how i want to do ours uh-huh so
we got two ender porters built at the
moment one of them is at our guardian
farm and the other one is at
our end portal and we can go back and
forth between them to test this out and
give it
uh a trial get a feel for how it's gonna
work
um and i discovered a few interesting
things while building this but i guess
first let's just go for a test run here
so
the way i'm doing it at the moment i got
buttons on the ground
this one's not hooked up to anything
it's just this one it's just the end
portal
there we go teleport review sets by
throwing another
ender pearl and it's good to go so we
can go through then portal or if we want
to go back we got another button
i haven't found a proper position for it
yet but it'll take us back to the
guardian farm
so our end portal is at about minus 450
x and 850
zed and i'll try to give you an idea of
how far we're actually teleporting
go up the ladder and we're going
diagonal
so in total it's about 370 blocks of
wiring i ran back and forth down there
to get to our guardian farm all the way
over here
here we go so this is at negative 240
and about 710 or so
and yeah one one of the big problems i
discovered while building this is slimes
slimes are actually a big issue because
we're using tripwires
and uh yeah they can spawn and then they
they jump in the tripwires and
activate the ender pearls when you don't
want them to so
i had to slab everything that was
spawnable
to stop the slimes from spawning it's
not enough just to torch it up and light
it up
to stop hostile mobs you gotta stop the
slimes because
you're pretty much guaranteed to run
through a slime chunk if you're going
underground like this
so we got two wires one of them to go
one way one to go the other way and then
we got a space in the middle so we can
walk down here without
activating them and you can see i did
figure out how i was going to do the
minecart thing
so we got the minecart it goes out goes
around rams into a cactus and then the
hopper picks it up and puts it back in
there so it seems to
work pretty fine actually and then
there's also our mortal enemy to worry
about
you hear that the bats if we have a
location where bats can spawn
like a dark spot then they can fly into
our tripwires as well so we got a
lot of things to worry about oh and by
the way i think i came up with a better
way of activating the trap door than
what we had before
so the other way we were doing it we had
like four ticks of
on the repeater and then it ran through
the torch and then to the trap door
that's like .6 seconds
um the new way we're doing it it comes
up here
there's a sticky piston there um we just
have one tick on the repeater and then
the redstone torch so that's 0.3 seconds
it's like half the speed
and then after it goes through here it
cuts off the redstone signal
this extends and then this can't power
this anymore
and that just activates us a little bit
quicker and
actually with the wacky trip wires and
minecart thing we got going on there
it is pretty much instant as far as i
can tell and that saves us about a
second or two every time we teleport
which is important because like if it's
not fast and convenient and wonderful
we're just going to use rockets
and this will be pointless right so we
wanna we want it to be good
and as far as i can tell it is pretty
good right now i'm happy with that
all right so good stuff so i thought
we'd take a break from that
and do a bit of building today after all
so
i've been in the area here and i stopped
by the blaze farm is like oh
maybe we should try uh get that done
today actually so it's very close to
done we got the style all figured out we
got
the important stuff all put together
here and i do like the look of this
place actually
i know a lot of people don't like uh
purple and sandstone and stuff but
i do so i'm a rebel that way
but you will notice like top half's done
but the bottom half here is
not done it's close but we got a lot of
netherrack showing and stuff so
i brought over some materials here and
we're gonna
just work out what we're doing um
try figure out the final look of this
place and actually call the dual blaze
farm finished
would be cool something that kind of
blew my mind the other day was the stone
cutter
and i noticed now like i'm i start
crafting slabs like this again
and people are like etho you got to use
the stone cutter
and it's like no no it turns out it's
the exact same material cost
uh for most things so three sandstone
will get you six slabs just like that
right
um and same with walls same price on
the stone cutter as the crafting table
the only one that's cheaper is the
stairs
so we definitely want to do our purple
stairs in here
i don't know what you would call the
style of building i guess maybe abstract
but i i really like it actually i find
it one of the easiest styles for me
um a lot of times i like really struggle
with like
deciding what to build and this style is
just like the spam blocks and
try to mix them together and come up
with weird random shapes and it doesn't
really matter
if it doesn't make sense right it ends
up looking kind of crazy at the end of
things and
i like it a lot actually ah yeah we got
her done guys the duo blaze farm
is finally finished after probably seven
or eight years or whatever it's been
aha this place has a lot of history
actually it's gone through many changes
over over that time it was basically
done before just
the final touches now right so yeah we
got this area
looking a little bit better now i would
say i like it a lot
it's uh very abstract or alien like
and put some slabs over here because i
was worried about gas spawning
if we left this all open um now we have
some chests down here for storage so all
the blaze rods from the killing chamber
up there
funnel down to an actual collection area
which is nice
got end rods all around here for
lighting and just tried to fill in all
the spaces with
something and mix up the materials um
let's see here
there was actually a lot to this is a
big area so we got like a
little design here above the minecart
tunnels
this was all netherrack before we had to
do something with this
and um you can see a little bit of
another act back here but only from this
angle basically
behind the rails um
let's see this was all netherrack all
over here
we got a bit of a design just like just
a
bunch of randomness yep it's kind of the
theme
and uh yeah i think that's about it
we miss anything i think we got it all
uh-huh so we come over here we
smack the guys and there's a hopper
minecart underneath
that it picks up the drops and they go
into the storage
oh i missed it there it goes
the downstairs area does actually kind
of matter because the floor is glass
here so we can see it from up above when
we're at the blaze spawners so
it's kind of nice it got done uh and i
think that's a
pretty good view from here too oh
snappers it looks like
boats actually work pretty good nowadays
oh never mind well we did get up
actually wait a second now i struggled
so much trying to get this launcher to
work a long time ago
uh it seems to be a lot better now
yeah yeah that's cool ah man
now i got a daunting task ahead of me
you know how it is when you guys have
company over you gotta dust and clean
the house and
scrub the toilets and all that fun stuff
you guys are gonna be visiting my world
here soon so i gotta i gotta do all the
cleaning
get things running the way they're
supposed to around here and pretend like
everything's perfect all the time
uh-huh like there's so many little
things that you don't even think about
um now i don't know how to restock this
thing anymore remember the snowball
fountain that's been out for a long time
the creeper eyes that shoot arrows the
flaming arrows that's been out forever
here
we go get some arrows back in this thing
you know you guys will see it and he's
like oh yeah i forgot about that that
was so cool
all right all right we gotta go
refill the timer make sure it has items
in it
we gotta get some snowballs for the
snowball fountain
uh for some reason the snowball fountain
doesn't seem to have a minecart anymore
i don't know where it went
so let's get a new one down there
and of course we got one sandblock on
our slime pads so we gotta go clean that
off
enderman put a grass block in the cow
farm so we gotta
get rid of all the grass chocolate
island
i can't have you guys killing my
villagers so we're gonna top them off
here with some healing
because i injure them every time i press
this
they're probably pretty low
he's fine uh
i don't want him to die during the world
tour
i'm sure i did more uh good than bad
there right yeah
we got trampled crops all over the place
we got to take care of here get them all
nice and
nice and orange again
we gotta refill our ender pearls
we should probably fix up our tools here
as well don't
sleep in the nether
no i'm not even going to tell you how i
lost my last sword
so earlier in the episode when i was
working on that nether tunnel a gas
bond while i was distracted in real life
i was
i was like talking to somebody on the
phone and
the as soon as the gas spawned my reflex
was oh
hostile mobs are spawning i go to sleep
and i slept in another
i remember last world tour i think i
spent like four or five hours just
cleaning up
chests around the world this time we do
have a couple of them around but it's
not nearly as bad as
as last time thankfully we got a we got
a couple of these to clean up though
so it turns out the cactus farm has an
interesting quirk about it
so the way it's designed during the
night time zombies can just wander into
the water channels down here and uh
lately i have discovered like lots and
lots of
drowned zombies down here uh looks like
we only got one today
not too bad and yeah there's definitely
a lot more
little things that need to be taken care
of hopefully we can get them all done
for the world tour but
that's all the time we got together here
for today so let's get to the comments
it says
etho how did you get an ocean monument
on
land aha that is a great question
because there's something a little bit
special about my world here because it's
so old
this was actually generated before
jungles were even in the game
and after i think they added jungles
then they changed the way
biomes generate like the way seeds are
so my world's from an older seed and if
you load up the exact same seed nowadays
this is all
ocean uh where we're standing right now
and it just so happens there was an
ocean temple structure underground in
this area and i
mined it out and and made an actual
monument out of it
um yeah so it's it's kind of weird like
that
um by the way last episode i kind of
brought up the idea about
resetting the world and i got your
guys's feedback so thank you for that
it sounds like by far the majority of
you do not want to reset which is great
to see because
i don't want to reset and i'm glad you
guys don't want to reset
uh like 80 or 90 of you i'd say don't
want one
i think last time i asked that it was
more like 50 50.
so it's good to see it's skewed more
more the way i want it to be
uh but yeah i think that's gonna do it
for this episode
until the world tour oh yeah i gotta
shut this off otherwise you guys might
shoot the the minecarts when you're not
supposed to
uh-huh they should all stand still here
are these full of arrows yeah okay good
got any left in here oh no they're all
gone now
okay but yeah thanks for watching guys
hope you enjoyed it
and until the world to our next episode
or is it a world tour i don't know maybe
ethos been trolling this whole time and
you know ten episodes getting you hyped
up for it and then not a world tour on
550 wouldn't that be great i think it'd
be pretty funny
bye-bye