[Music]
hi hello greetings how is everyone today
uh we're going to get right into it
right right into it
let's go here i just killed all the
redstone
one second
okay good got it fixed so what we're
gonna do today
we are going to set up a little place
for our
buddies we
liberated last episode
uh they're gonna be staying i think
somewhere in this wall here
we're gonna set up a little place for
them they don't get houses or anything
like that i don't even have a house so
why should they get one
uh we will set up a nice area for them
though a little
piece of paradise for them or something
over here
because uh and then as we finish up
places we might let them stay in
rooms i don't know we'll see
so kind of curve the corner here a
little bit
so we got flat wall here and two
one two flat wall so they'll go against
this flat wall
their room so i'll clean up this area
and uh
we'll see how it goes
enchantment break here we go
hmm
got mixed feelings about that i guess
it's good
okay so this is a kind of look i got
going on here
we've got three windows and then the
door
to the place will be over here this side
again we'll have three
windows um
something like this i like having the
glowstone below because it
brightens up the glass and lights up the
area
outside here because i'm trying to
light this cave without using torches
when it's all
all finished here so i don't have to
have torches around here or anything
which is good this door will probably be
those pistons aren't in position either
store will probably be another
another brick
i surprised i actually accidentally
called this stuff netherrack
last episode and i don't think anybody
corrected me
don't think anybody did unless i missed
it
okay not that you should
because i know i know it's not
netherrack
these pistons um
let's see it's going to be tough
positioning these
so when i do uh these double piston
doors that was pointless
i uh
just a second i need the pistons to be
facing like this i'll have uh
just one block behind them with the one
piece of redstone on
and then i have a redstone torch below
this block
here is the way i usually do it so you
can you can hide them in
is pretty good this is right next to
this window here
so so have uh
two pistons like that and that one wire
there powers both pistons
okay and same for the other side
that no no that doesn't work what am i
doing
ah it has to i need another
two blocks width for that to work
there i can't put this here because then
you'll see it
oh nuts i thought i had that figured out
yeah actually that should be fine
usually when i do these though i put the
redstone
wiring behind the pistons but if they're
off on the side
like this it's not a big deal either as
long as
i got blocks here to hide the wiring
and i'll just have a door frame around
here
this glass will probably get switched to
iron
so it matches that door just a smaller
version
this will go all the way through same
with this one
and yeah so if you
see where is that i think the redstone
is above here
so if you have a redstone torch below
that uh both pistons will extend
so you just have to connect uh
two redstone torches together below that
and then
control the door that way
all right and this will come over top
like so
this will be all wood
and i'll probably make this glowstone
just like the other door
okay yeah this is uh this is going to be
a mirror of the other side there too
you got the redstone over there
so these are special little chambers
these things here
not gonna tell you what they're for just
yet you might have figured it out
already
all right i like you when building those
quick like this
oops i really don't mind using that
stone bricks
like as filler blocks anymore because i
have all those blaze rods so
it doesn't really cost me anything to
convert like
cobblestone into stone bricks so
if i ever have to fill holes sometimes
i'll use these even
just because it doesn't bother me
okay
that's roughly correct
and i the reason i was concerned about
this door here is i don't want to
really extend this any water like i
would have to be
two blocks wider if i put the redstone
behind the pistons like i normally do
but this is getting really close to the
tree farm below
and this tree farm is not complete
either it will probably still extend out
like at least up to here if i was to
guess which is
getting really close to this thing up
here
and they might interfere if i'm not
careful
okay sweet let me do some more stuff off
camera and we will
get the show on the road
yeah so for these window things i went
inside each of them and i dug
uh up to the surface actually went up
the surface
and dug down to be technically correct
i'm going to leave the top uncovered so
you can see the rain falling down like
this
i like that and i'm just going to go up
all these
and replace the dirt and stone and
gravel with the stone brick here
just to polish it up i got iron on the
door now i'm
i'll show you really quick how the
wiring is
i think i'm going to leave this door
very very simple
so all it is right now you got the
piston here and the one below it
redstone wire
next to it then block
redstone torch another block
and then exact same on this side
wire runs between the two redstone
torches and that's how you
can open and close the door
so i'll probably just run a lever i
think i'll just have one lever on this
side of the door
to open and close the door
okay so it's been about two or three
hours i've been working on this
uh since i last updated you so i felt it
was time to
give you an update it's overdue uh
most of that time was just me running
around i had to go to the nether to get
more glowstone
got three more stacks now silk touch is
awesome for that
last episode was stage one
of project pokemon here stage one was
exodus so
today we're working on stage two which
is settlement
so we're just building a little place
for these guys to
stay which will be in here
got a little drop set up for them still
have to make it safe somehow
i'll either put water up up here or on
the ground
for them to fall into don't know what
i'm going to do with this room i think
i'm just going to keep it really plain
this episode just to get it done
and then later i'll probably improve it
and of course the side project we're
doing here
is what i'm calling the six wise men
we're going to try to collect one of
each of them
so there's the librarian there's the
priest
blacksmith uh the butcher
villager and farmer those are the six
we're trying to collect
i think we only got like three different
types
from that village we uh we liberated so
gonna have to find a few more villages
to complete the collection here
and these guys i'm just going to push
down
this tube here i got all polished up
got a safe drop and when they're down
here i'll remove the water
and uh yeah should be pretty awesome and
then finally stage three
of the project is uh minionization
so once we get them all settled
then we will put them to work
in various rooms as i get them complete
around the cave here and i might also
make them
run through tests and stuff like that
too i don't know
it's all for uh good fun
another thing uh delaying this right now
is i'm trying to figure out what to do
with this door i was
thinking of having a fancy locking
system for it
but i don't know
this episode's uh taking a long time to
make so i'll probably have to rush this
end
a little bit and come complete it some
other time
well i made an attempt at that room
there i'll let you guys see it
tell me what you think uh
this is it we got lava lighting on the
sides just a
small tiny room to hold them for now
um got a little
safety water drop here which i'll
probably cover once they're down here
and this will just be flat floor
also have a safety above with that
glowstone around
to give a little bit of light to the
ceiling
i don't know not entirely happy with
this room to be honest but
let me know what you guys think i'll
probably be
most most likely i'm going to be
changing this room
to a different theme and i might even
make it bigger
but maybe just for today i'll leave it
like this
and i'll get your feedback on it
yeah okay
i think um i think i'm just gonna
quickly hook up a lever to this door for
today and uh
maybe next episode or something i'll
make something a little more fancy
uh just so that we can get the guys down
here because i've been
wanting to do that
yeah so i got the track all laid for
them i think we're about ready to move
them in
this is what's above at the surface
above all those holes
you've got these little buildings uh
i don't know what you call them i guess
stocking stations or something
just so it's not a hole in the ground
that you have to push them down
it's a little a little bit
this is the main one to the the main
room for all the extras
double doors are really weird
with this patch
if you click here the left one opens
i don't know very strange stuff
got a little axis on the back in case i
have to get up for some reason
so many creepers have blown up in this
area like unbelievable
number every time i was working on this
it was at night
by chance and it never went well
okay and once we push the guys in we
have these levers here
and just flip that door closes so no
mobs can wander down and our light comes
on which shows that
we have collected them
okay so i think we're ready let's go
let's go
get our newcomers
i don't know if you guys saw this but
check out all the ender damage
i got on the surface of my world here
it's
just random blocks missing everywhere
random blocks placed everywhere
it's really annoying
one of the reasons i want it to go in
the cave is because that doesn't happen
nearly as much
the only way to really prevent it on the
surface is to torch everything
or replace everything with blocks they
can't move
either way it's a lot of work
okay this is where we have kept them
let's hope they're
all here there's 10 before
i'm curious to see if any got out of
their carts
i hear something walking
hello
that is a zombie or else they're really
mad at me
oh he did get out no no
no
you know what me firsters or me lasters
you're stuck there you're gonna be the
last one
uh they all got out
wow
hmm
this is gonna be tough it's hoping at
least a few would still be in
it's okay it's okay
there you go it's one
see they won't be able to get you can't
make them get into my carts unless it's
on a track
there we go and that guy
is free he's trying to get away
okay i have to go catch some z's because
it's getting dark
there's no way i'm doing this at night
no way
all right guys you're free to go
so last episode i kind of asked
where i'm getting my promotion from
recently and a lot of people
have said it they found my channel
through pyropuncher
or paul as many of you know him so i
just want to say thank you
to paul or pyropuncher for all the all
the shoutouts you've been giving me
i really appreciate it
and of course uh other people have been
helping too like you know
co-star he mentions my name quite a bit
avidia a good and beatable oh
i almost don't want to name names
because i'm gonna forget people but
i'll i'll do my best here and uh
cilantro gamer gives me mentions quite a
bit
uh armitage and
obviously there's more but especially i
want to give a thanks to doc jam he
mentions me
all the time all the time
so i really appreciate it buddy me and
dm are really close on youtube
but he's he's got a pretty big channel
now so promotion from him really helps
me out too
oh what are you guys doing
is he free no i keep thinking they're
free
i should do a head count too
i should have installed a buddy system
before i started this
wait you know who's not in the car is
that stupid idiot
that wanted to be first you you just
love causing problems
get in the cart
ah and he's fighting me he won't even
turn around
maybe maybe i should introduce them to
guys below would you like that
you better cooperate then
you know what i needed to bring was a
fishing hook
uh he still didn't go in the cart come
on
get your butt in there
um yes no no come on
yes yes yes ah finally
i'm gonna smack him
he deserves it oh you
ah okay give me a minute this is gonna
take forever
all right i think i got them all so
let's do a little count here
one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten
i felt like i just skipped counted one
two three four five six seven eight nine
ten nope that's right
awesome seem to have lost one of the my
cards so
i only have one furnace minecart here
and off we go woohoo
it looks so awesome can they make it up
the hill that's a steep hill
the furnace minecart doesn't do a whole
lot it just prevents them from going
back that way
the real thing propelling them is them
pumping against each other
i think
come on almost there
almost there
oh oh seriously they can't get through
leaves
i didn't know that i thought they could
there you go
this is so awesome oh this is so
this project's fun i like it
all right we
are here we have arrived
i gotta check uh the wikipedia to figure
out who is who now
i know the white guys are librarians
okay i got it figured out we got six
farmers here
uh two librarians and two butchers
so mostly a farming village i think
i think they're the most common guys
um welcome everybody to the man cave i
will just get you guys settled here
first and then i'll find
something for you to do later so
i have chosen you to be one of the six
wise men
that's right where are you going
oh it's just gonna be a nightmare to get
him in there
it's okay it's a
it's a privilege it really is
just calm down he is excited man
big day for him i guess okay yes
let's go let's go this way i need a
shotgun
don't go in there no
that's uh the cow suction thing
if he gets in that water stream he's
going down
as i think uh no villager
wonder what villagers look like i think
that's farmer okay
mr wise man here you go
oh
can't tell i think he's just jumping i
think he's fine
ah he's fine he's fine
okay that's one wise man in let's uh
let's try to get another one here
librarian
come on oh they just get so excited when
you let them out
usually they're pretty docile
no no where are you going and they
always go the
exact opposite way they need to go
don't go near the water don't go near
the water don't push me in either
oh boy so i've been getting a lot of
people asking me to play terraria
again uh i've actually
have been playing it but i probably
won't be
doing an lp for it because i'm not very
good at it
and i don't think it's a very uh
fun game to watch compared to playing
type thing so
oh you're so close but yeah i've been
having a lot of fun playing it again
okay now now you can walk get out of
there
before when i was playing it i didn't
even kill the first boss the eye of
kachoochu or whatever as uh z stew calls
him
but now it's like i finally get the game
i know what to do
and it's a lot of fun for me now
let's uh okay that's two wise men
i gotta get out of here or this is gonna
be a nasty scene
let's make sure this guy's still alive
excellent okay i'll uh i'll collect some
of these guys off camera
and go catch some catch some more z's or
zeds or whatever
enjoy your stay thanks for coming
first on in
whoa have fun
oh you can get in without track
interesting
oh wow this guy cooperated
you're the last one buddy thanks for
coming
enjoy your stay
awesome all right everybody settled in
that worked out pretty good no
casualties
they were a little resistant
but overall i think they're pretty happy
so we got our butcher we got our farmer
this guy always has the most epic look
on i don't know why
it just seems he just seems cooler
than these other two for for some reason
i thought this guy was gonna be the
coolest but
nope he just shook his head nope
okay uh i did not hook up the door
properly yet
i'll have to do that some other time but
if i'm ever gonna get this video out
today i have to
cut corners so
yeah these guys they seem to be doing
okay hey
hey no what do you think you've owned
this place
oh dang it oh dang it
no no no no you guys do not understand
the situation here
hey
no don't think you know what's going on
here
wow you guys are gonna die out here you
know that
it's not exactly safe
oh man okay this is a
gonna be a lot i think with this room i
need to set up a way
so that they can't actually make it to
the door
because this is a this is a problem if
they all run out when i open it
come on
okay i think there's what happened to
the white guy
did he he probably killed himself
already
did he he didn't find his way up here
did he no
hmm all right give me one moment
i found him he made his way to the tree
farm he's just checking things out i
guess
i'll have to somehow get him back up
there
okay i managed to get him back up here
he's really not cooperating though
i'm gonna put him to work in the potion
room
i think he wants adventure
oh that doesn't work does it okay you
gotta try get in there before it closes
on you
yes
okay this is your new job oh what
because it's stuck on a loop yeah
so enjoy yourself uh you will be in
charge of the potion room
meanwhile these guys will hate you
because i've given you special
privileges that they didn't get
okay one two three four five six that
guy was the seventh and then we have
three
three of the wise men over there already
so we got it done everybody settled
awesome i am going to end the episode
here because i am exhausted
pushing these guys around
so much work okay thanks for watching
everybody
i'll see you again next time