[Music]
hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode so I found this hat off
of a mob and I just realized like I
might be crazy here but doesn't this
make me look Russian like I got the mask
as a face warmer and I have the fur the
fur hat that they wear a lot in Russia
totally I think so yeah especially if I
dyed it black or something I think we
got a winner
anyway we are at the gold farm guys we
are at the gold farm let's get the
zombie rate going on here they come you
can watch them appear right there I
notice that's where they spawn Oh as a
little guy okay okay oh good so I have
okay there's more than night okay there
might be a little more than next panel
here okay okay we're going down oh
they're down here too okay tell you what
I'm gonna heal I just happen to have
healing potions
did I start saying whatever what I meant
to start saying oh man they're climbing
the ladders even guys you see this fool
what is this oh now he comes down oh man
so yeah you guys are gonna think I'm
crazy but I have an idea for a project
today that's not gonna make a lot of
sense to you but I have this awesome
gold farm here right the thing is
let's do this I press the button right I
use this thing all the time like out of
everything my world
the last like oh you gotta be kidding oh
there's even more down here now
coming through we're good
everything's fine what a disaster I
usually don't do this at night because
this kind of thing happens but ever
since I built that gold firm with docum
on the minecraft server I've wanted that
gold farm that gold farm is so awesome I
tested it out with the snapshot I'm
using it it still works amazing I
haven't died dead here where is my food
so today I'm gonna build that second
gold farm the problem with this one not
that it's a real problem but the XP I
have to collect the XP after I kill
these guys and that takes a good minute
to to usually then I end up trading
zombie flesh I usually waste like 10
minutes every batch of these guys I kill
here
the thing about the one I built on the
minecraft server with docum is it is
fully automatic you can go afk you need
that gasps tears from it and you get no
XP though that's the one thing about it
so they both have their advantages the
one the one I want to build today though
is extremely simple it's only about
5,000 blocks I need about a thousand
rails and that's pretty much all it
takes so since I've done it before
though I'm gonna do mostly soft camera
just because I want it I'm gonna set it
up but by the wither skeleton firm up
above it and we have a beacon there
already saw pasted and all that good
stuff and I guess I will see you guys
there once I wrap up here and get some
gold together for some power rails and
I'll see you a little bit here let's do
something chanting - before we take off
I'm just gonna put books in I don't care
what we get I just want to use up these
levels before I lose them like like I
tend to do respiration fire protection
perfection three oh man so many books oh
that's it what do we get unbreaking 3
that's good fire r-spec to smite for
garbage respiration 3 is good that's bad
so so not bad and nope Oh a fishin C for
respiration 3 is really good most of
those were pretty junky though
okay guys so I'm just about to get
started here just getting my things all
together and sorted out I'm gonna build
it the bottom out of stone bricks and
light blue clay
I need something hard that won't get
blown up by a gas so I figured that'd be
good we are right above the wither
skeleton farm by the way you can't see
it but there is some beacons like right
next to us here I don't know why we
can't see them like literally three
blocks away from us
they oh you can just barely see the beam
you see that little the line go in there
you can't see them too well than another
when you get high up they blend into the
background somehow but yeah where matter
where there's Stilton farm we have speed
to strength to jump boost regen
resistance all the goodies I'm gonna
build a 35 by 35 square I'm not doing a
honeycomb shape no sir it's about a
thousand spawning spaces it'll be about
I should it's more like 1100 which
should be plenty and so I'm gonna frame
it with stone brick then I'm gonna put
the blue stained clay in the middle and
then I'm gonna put rails on top of that
and then another layer on top of that no
oh wait the face not gonna be enough is
it are you kidding
one block short oh this game such a
troll cool so that's first layer done
and spawn rates are looking good I'm
gonna put a rim all around this thing if
I can these guys are gonna be in the way
like crazy though
okay so little updates the construction
is going well I'm about halfway through
the rails and I needed more power rails
so that means more gold farming which
means more enchanting let's do it
what are we gonna get this time I think
I had 59 levels well I saw looting there
I liked looting efficiency is always
good Oh another one knocked back we're
gonna run out of inventory space oh
that's it so what did we get this time
bane of arthropods efficiency three
knock back to looting to knock back to
efficiency for power for flame one
efficiency for power three yeah I would
rate that so-so so there was a couple
good ones okay guys so we're gonna take
a quick break from the construction here
I had to come here to get some some
rails I left here I'm pretty much using
up all my resources on this build it is
insane which I expected you know it
takes money to make money right I might
have to rob a beacon to which I don't
like doing but it'll be worth it so
while we're here though let's let me
just show you what's going on so there's
been a few changes I extended the
walkway here and I really like the
Spruce walkway I love it
might add in some other things to rough
it up a bit maybe some grass poking out
in places or who knows but because it's
all one color right now but I love this
sort of random ish flow it's got going
to it this this area's a bit plain
though I also built a custom tree this
is like my second custom tree the first
one was the the one that didn't turn out
too well it grew eyes and and tried to
eat me
this one looks looks a little bit better
I like this one it's a bit rough in
places but I didn't spend a lot of time
on it either just basically threw leaves
at as quick as I could
I put a bit of a root system to it that
actually looks pretty bad now that I see
it from here yeah we're trying to go
with like a lush build here that's
pretty organic looking so the ruins oh
my goodness you guys did not like what I
did here for the most part so much
hatred against the end stone I couldn't
believe it I really think I I might just
have weird tastes but I really think n
stone looks good with green the yellow
and the green goes so well together in
my opinion but not many people share
that apparently so I tried changing here
I put some nether brick a lot of people
a lot of you guys weren't too happy with
the whole thing though so I'm probably
gonna have to rethink what I'm doing
here which I'm not doing today by the
way don't don't you worry yeah so here's
the thing I wanted to do this style the
ruins because I thought it would be easy
I thought it would save me time that I
could build something that's like I want
something that looks organic that that's
not symmetrical that I that each thing I
build is gonna look different basically
which this definitely accomplishes and I
was hoping it would be quick and easy to
build I just throw a bunch of blocks
down doesn't matter if it's messy
because it's it's wrecked it's ruined
but no everybody's telling me I have to
build a proper stretcher all perfect and
nice whoops I killed it it's trying to
point there we go yeah I got to build a
structure all nice and then I
very carefully destroy it and and make
it look like it's liked it was wrecked
and and weathered and so basically I got
to build the structure tear it down
that's not really what I want to do
that's the opposite of what I'm trying
to do that's that's extra work I don't
really want to I want like I want to
build a lot of stuff really quickly
basically and I'm gonna have to rethink
of how to do that because I don't think
the ruins at least that way of doing
them is gonna work anyway
let's head on back to the build
all right cool so things are going
really good here guys I am over halfway
done and this is a tough half to putting
down all these rails so many rails so
yeah that's that's the main cost of this
whole thing you have I have about
thousand rails here and that's like 16
stacks and also we're gonna get neat
about a stack of iron blocks to make the
iron golems later but then nothing but
gold from there on out down below nice a
nice blue color I don't I don't know why
I even bothered you're never gonna see
it I'm never gonna see it it's so dark
in the nether you can't see it when you
come up the ladder anyway but yeah I got
levers all the way down in three spots I
feels pretty cool when they're all lined
up like that all right and now I'm gonna
test out the carts I'm hoping we can get
away with just one minecarts these guys
are all in the way though it has to make
the trip there and back think within
five minutes for this to really work
if it takes longer we will need to
minecarts and these guys are kind of in
the way now don't really want to anger
them but sometimes you need to fine as
long as I got this strength boost that
helps a lot alright cool so second layer
I decided I would make out of this white
stain clay because I have a bunch of it
from the Mesa biome that's already white
and in the nether I want something that
stands out nice and bright so we will
put this over top and here let's let's
test up the head here we'll throw some
stuff on top and make sure it picks it
up through the blocks otherwise we're
gonna have a lot of trouble and I'm
gonna feel really dumb that I wasted all
this time on something that doesn't work
alright
oh I may as well remove them they'll be
in the way otherwise so I'm gonna
continue on here guys looks like it made
half the trip already that felt like a
minute or two so it'll be really close
oh this is not gonna end well for me
take you all on I realized it's probably
easier to place the blocks going this
this way instead of horizontally and
yeah much quicker much easier
[Music]
Oh huh not again oh I dodge this is my
dog [ __ ] right to the face
wait he just disappeared on me what is
this
did you see that he just vanished see
out here no aha it's all done guys it is
done I am very happy to be he finished
it this was quite the project was a lot
easier when I did it before with Doc coz
there was there was two people building
but all in all it didn't think all while
to take a couple hours by a couple hours
I mean like four or five but it went
pretty good compared to the other gold
farm this one was much easier to build
so this is it this is it - look at all
these beautiful zombie pigmen in there
they're delicious rotting corpses and
their beautiful golden what exactly does
a gold come from where do they hide the
gold I know they have gold swords anyway
so this is it we are going to get our
iron golems up and running here they
will do the killing and then as
it's always scary it looks like things
are still good though yeah I think we're
fine well that's gonna be a funny
sheet-iron Golan if I do that okay so
yeah as oh and good we're getting
zombies actually kind of wanted them I
figured we would get them yes as as we
set the stuff up maybe I'll explain a
few things about how this works
so this farm does not work in 1.7 I'm
pretty sure I haven't tried the latest
like 1.7.10 but it doesn't work because
the zombie pigmen will kill the iron
golems which isn't good because then you
got to either heal them up or replace
them which costs tons of iron in the
snapshots though for some reason the
zombie pigmen do not attack the iron
golems anymore they have new AI which is
probably the reason for that and also
the zombies don't the gas don't and the
magma tubes all of which get farmed in
here will not attack the iron golems
that might change in the future though
so I don't exactly recommend other
people build this farm you can if you
want you can see we also get XP from it
which is kind of cool least I think we
do I don't think we did before so I
think that's a new change with this
current snapshot I'm using although it
might stop now that they aren't a grow
or something yeah that one didn't drop
any or did he
oh yeah you're still dropping okay
that's good if I want to pick it up but
for most of the time I have to stand up
on that platform there I built and while
I stand there I will automatically just
get gold essentially oh yeah I'm like
man you guys are doing a good job they
killed all the Pigman why why are they
so efficient it's cuz none responding
while I'm down here so maybe we'll just
get a few of these guys going and we'll
go up to our little hideaway there and
watch things happen
apparently zombie pigman also break down
wooden doors which I did not realize
that's something new I learned today
because they shared the zombie
characteristics I guess they don't
always do it though just occasionally
alright so now we can see them doing
their job zombie Pigman spawn super
quickly
you thought gasps here and there
although it's not as quick as I thought
why why is it taking a while yeah I
guess that's about right we are way up
in the nether here we're at like 250 so
that prevents any land below it like I'm
above the bedrock layer that prevents
any mob spawning down below in the
nether so they all will spawn within the
trap here yes very good they don't
actually go after the gas they only
attack them if the gas is in between
their target pigment is the way it works
they're doing a pretty good job keeping
things under control I may be a little
too close here still I never actually
measured that's probably all the golems
we need actually alright anyway so as
that goes on let's head on down
of course we have that hopper minecart
running below in its zig-zag pattern and
that's picking up all the all the drops
as it goes by and I changed it so
instead of doing a zig zag bat it just
does a straight line back and goes here
and when I built this I made sure I
could take advantage of the Southwest
rule here with the track so when this
minecart comes by it will go this way
towards the unloader is that because I
killed a few I hope we don't get swords
from this although if we get sorts we
get gold ingots we're gonna be bad
either yeah so this is a basic unloader
we got a comparator up to a torch and
that powers this block and this redstone
dust which controls this this power rail
you have to do hopper and then chest
below it for that to really work though
if you do hopper hopper it doesn't
because this comparator doesn't turn on
now looking pretty good so we'll maybe
also i will i built this by the way i
started building this at y 224 it
doesn't matter too much what layer you
build it as long as you afk high enough
that stuff isn't spawning down in the
nether below and I will upgrade the
unloading station here - oh it's
unloading right now so picked up a few
things gassed here pretty cool let's go
down I want to show you where this is in
my world just in case you were curious
because I never showed like getting here
so the these are the four beacons they
change color depending on your height in
the nether so they're really red here
and down below this is the hole we made
in the ceiling a little while ago up at
the nether fortress
Oh usually I just enderpearl down and
this is the wither skeleton farm and you
can hear I'm running around somewhere
it's pretty funny like just like going
back and forth like collect supplies and
then going up there to to work on
building I had to make like five trips
back and forth between here I got four
with wither skeleton heads so we're up
to eight again the main reason for the
gold firm up here by the way is to make
beacons I want lots and lots of beacons
so I'm gonna use the gold blocks for
those and also for power rails if I ever
need power rails for things this will do
the trick nicely
oh no look what look what I found here I
heard some zombie pigmen grumbling when
I was on the nether sealing here so I'll
have to probably slab out this cave it's
really really close to the roof and my
farm and I might get slightly better
rates whoa no no there was a hole there
okay here comes a minecart we're gonna
do a test to your guys I have an idea
you see there's no gold ingots no gold
swords or anything that's a rare drop in
the minecart right now I also checked
the ground here there's none on the
ground anywhere so since we're getting
XP from these iron golems I'm pretty
sure it's because I own them and they
count as mine so if I have my looting
sword selected while I afk up here I'm
guessing we're gonna get rare drops and
extra like lots extra gold nuggets and
stuff from from the mobs as well so I'm
gonna let them do their thing for a
little bit here
maybe next time there's no gas if that's
possible we will hop down there and
check if there's anything rare on the
ground or in the chest oh is this it is
this it
kill that gas so I can go check thank
you I've been up here forever and
there's been a guest the whole time so
lots of oh look I see it already
Goulding get on the ground you would not
be able to get that if it was just the
standard kill so they're counting as my
kills and I guess it's kind of hard to
prove though if I'm getting the looting
effect
um is there more than one guest here
here that would prove it now it's just
one just one hmm let's see
little guy pretty sure I'm getting the
looting effect though look at all the
iron ore the gold ingots on the ground
just by having the looting sword
selected while I'm up there which is
pretty cool okay you know what this
should actually be pretty easy to figure
out now that I think of it cuz zombie
Pigman will only drop at most one rotten
flesh and one nugget so if we see a
stack drop from one of these it looks
like more than one has fallen
that means the looting sword is having
an effect
it looks like it's only one each time
yeah so I doubt it is actually yeah okay
so looting sword not doing anything I
thought it was GRU for a moment there
because we were getting so many rare
drops but I just saw just killing so
many that it's it's happening okay good
to know another reason I wanted the
zombies to spawn is because I'm pretty
sure we will be able to get a zombie
villager out of this and convert it into
a villager and get our cleric over here
so we can trade them rotten flesh
somewhere otherwise I got a cart one out
here and and somehow get them up in the
sky in the nether does not sound like
very much fun so yeah that might come in
handy okay here comes the minecart guys
there's another problem with this I just
realized oh it was fine this time a lot
of the times though this Mike Kurt will
pick up a bunch of gold swords like
right away and it takes up all the slots
and then it doesn't pick up anything
else off the ground so yeah that's a
problem for sure the only way to really
deal with that is to have like I'm
guessing you would need about ten of
these going at the same time then you
got a deal with like them crashing into
each other and so I've had another idea
on a possible way of dealing with this
we are gonna take all the drops we want
primarily so we're gonna take nuggets
gasps tears I guess zombie flesh gold
ingots of course are really good and
probably don't need magma cream I think
the only other thing we get is gunpowder
yeah so
I have made like an injection type of
system here all these hoppers we got
five hoppers one for each slot in the
the hopper minecart and we're gonna
force it to pick up one of these as it
passes by so it'll pick up one nugget
one gold ingots zombie flesh one guest
here and one gun powder and then as it
makes its trip and pick up up to sixty
four of those on its way and hopefully
that will deal with the problem okay may
need to mine cards because I think I've
seen it come back with over a stack of
Nuggets before and I can't create I
can't create two slots for the Nuggets
because if I put nuggets in this one and
nuggets in this one it's just gonna put
two in one slot in the minecarts anyway
just thought I would point that out as
well alright guys so that is going to do
it for today's episode I hope you
enjoyed it but we do have a comment as
usual and I have picked out and it says
I wonder wait did I I might have missed
part of the comment I wonder no now I
should check our row we'll roll with it
here how many times have you died in
total in your LP world uh-huh so I don't
know exactly as far as I know the
statistics are not super accurate and I
believe they were reset again recently
by the way I afk dat the farm for just a
little bit to see if it works and we
already have a 21 gold block profit and
when I never short on iron guess what
happens so we can rebuild our our
beacons at the man cave thankfully so
let's check out the statistics here um
again I don't know when these were last
reset because before I believe the
statistics accumulated throughout
different worlds and that one off
totally and then I think they got reset
and now they're bound to just a single
world so from whenever that reset was I
think this is accurate 14 days compared
to day 4450 according to this just quite
a bit that I don't know how much time
that actually is though because each day
can be a different length the video and
if I sleep and if I make a and all its
stuff so time since last death was 4
hours ago I did die a couple times while
building that's all though I think the
death was when I was here i teleported
through one of the portals and ended up
at the gold farm here and the zombie
pigmen were angry at me and they just
instantly killed me when I came through
the portal anyway I'm getting distracted
there it is 54 54 deaths since last
reset that's fun looking at these though
distance flown to 17 lots of sprinting
lots of crouching actually distance by
Pig 0 ah items dropped damage dealt
180,000 0 player kills what's going on
here junk fish 0 86 yeah and I don't
know how accurate this stuff is but it's
cool to see anyway used items
Oh die I was like there is no way I've
gotten that much squid ink but maybe I
bet you that's mostly bone meal right
there it's like uh uh I don't think so
oh here's a good one
275 creepers 1,500 skeletons under 29
spiders 1,200 some bees 900 slimes 160
gasps that's quite a bit actually I bet
you a lot of that was from oh we should
test that next time to see if the iron
golems add to my count here I bet they
do 27,000 zombie pigman 17,000 Enderman
pretty much eighteen thousand thousand
blaze five that 500 magma cubes only 18
bats oh come on thousand cows uh-huh
anyway got lost looking at the
statistics there but I thought it'd be
fun to check them so that is it guys I
hope you enjoyed like I said and I will
see you again in the next one bye bye
these came from zombie flesh by the way
these emeralds
[Music]