[Music]
so yes we're gonna start out today's
episode with a glitch here I was in the
end looking for more shelter shells
flying I got hit by a shocker shots kind
of at the same time I ran into the
Shocker and when I hit the ground I
never liked when in the standing
position I'm stuck in flying position
which is kind of weird so I can like
jump while flying it's not taking up my
dear ability on the wing just being in
this position but I'm like gliding along
the ground and stuff it's weird I can't
look like move forward on the keyboard I
don't think now very graceful
I can almost do it do a barrel roll
they're not quite oh I think I almost
did it there I think so
oh very graceful very graceful uh-huh so
I don't actually know if I'm gonna be
able to get out of this position let's
find that out as we tumble towards the
void oh I'm actually kind of stuck now
yeah okay it got to be careful it's
actually really hard to fly in this
camera mode gracefully land on the
ground without without dying here
without looking at an Enderman oh I took
a lot of fall damage oh how we doing
here still at 145 okay okay um it's a
little weird like this is the first
person to you if we go along it's almost
like we gain momentum look at this look
at this uh-huh up to a certain speed is
kind of like the max we're not actually
flying though like I can't use the
fireworks oh okay
how would I do what I do what I do
run away can I run away I jump off the
edge I won't be able to fly I just
realized I doubt my ability to fight
this guy look at the coordinates in case
I die okay okay I guess we're gonna have
to try it
hello please don't kill me okay I'm I'm
I'm getting this guy man oh man I'm
excited
where'd he go mm-hmm Oh taking damage
taking damage okay let's not do that
all right I can't really think of
anything else to do with it so I'm gonna
try to take off the wings now see if
that fixes it No okay goody oh man well
I might have to kill myself then oh snap
okay how do I fix this then I guess I'm
gonna try real AAG now wait wait wait no
I'm on the ground okay everything's fine
all right everybody good stuff good
stuff so we did it we got our shocker
shells we went on two trips to the end
there for a grand total of how many
chocolate shells did he throw yet we got
about a stack and a half in so all we
needed at 48 to make 24 shelter boxes
for our our mastermind game here that
we're building and now we got a really
cool cogeneration system oh yeah so
since last episode I worked on two major
components to our game here I'll just
show you those real quick so the first
one we were working on the code
generator here and now we can actually
see it working so check this out press
the button
breaks old code generates a new one we
got green green red purple oh yeah
go again green oh that's not orange
that's yellow red orange oh I don't
think I'm colorblind blue green blue
purple so you see it's working pretty
good
got a nice little code generator here I
think using chakra boxes was a pretty
good idea look at that green green green
orange man three greens what are the
odds so it's really important when we do
this that all six colors are in the
dispensers here and that they don't jump
between dispensers they have to say stay
separate that's what we're using the
trapdoors for it to create a wall like
we looked into last episode Spencer here
you see all six were in here before it
shot out the one it shows so it's
choosing a totally random code which is
important aha so basically this goes up
to some Pistons over here this is part
of the shutter so at the start of the
game we're gonna move that button there
- probably the platform and we're gonna
press that to start the game and that's
going to first make some Pistons come
down you see it's closed right now
that'll close the shutter there so we
can't see what the code is right now is
these alternating oh you press it again
it'll be open so you can actually see
the code there so that closes at the
start of the game and then it also
activates this line of pistons which
breaks the chakra boxes those fall into
a hopper a set of hoppers that needs to
be unlocked so that sends power over
here to our hair and there's some
hoppers underneath uh-huh so it unlocks
the hoppers so they can pick up the
shelter boxes and then those go into the
dropper and then we also have to send
power to the line down here which makes
the chakra box to shoot from the dropper
up to the dispenser here and then we
activate another line
up here to shoot the chakra boxes out of
the dispenser to generate a new code so
there's actually a lot of stuff going on
with this this little bit over here
oh yeah and check this out I thought
this is kind of weird or interesting if
you have a trapdoor like this then you
go to open the chakra box it can't like
I'm right-clicking you can't open it
this is in the way which which makes
sense you flip it and then you can cuz
it's out of the ways that also makes
sense right
I thought that was kind of cool but like
not everything does that like if we have
sand on a trapdoor like then when you
flip it down it doesn't fall even if you
update it right I don't know I thought
that was kind of kind of weird kind of
cool anyways this does one other thing
but wait there's more if you order now
now so we have one extra function here
we want to be able to store items in the
chakra boxes these are gonna have the
concrete powder in so the yellow chakra
box will have yellow concrete powder
blue will have blue green live green
concrete powder so on and so forth right
the locker the lockers the hoppers are
locked so that the items don't flow out
of here but every time we enter an input
in our game we want to refresh the code
down downstairs at the ice there so that
it doesn't despawn on us because we were
worried about that if we press this
button it allows one item to flow from
the chakra boxes out of there and then
we're gonna send that to the ice and
that's how we're gonna refresh the code
yeah you know we're gonna do it guys
we're it's it's happening here all right
I'm gonna be dead serious with you right
now
you like that long pause there that was
to build suspense uh-huh let me tell you
something guys some of you you were
probably dozing off already oh you might
have even had an eye roll in there oh I
can't believe those doing redstone again
I roll next video oh let me tell you
something
you might not like redstone but you will
appreciate
my redstone here I spent hours on this
right hours even if you don't like it
tell me you appreciate it because let me
tell you something I'm no dummy I know
how YouTube works guys I know I should
be making five-minute videos or less on
a wide range of obscure topics and then
like dumb down the information spoon
feed it to you
there's this game called minecraft it
has redstone in it
redstone turns on and off then title the
video I can't believe this redstone
project exists don't tell you what it is
though not entitled no I you have to
click the video to see what it's about
right and then I have a thumbnail with
my Kakashi character here with his jaw
drop through the mask
eyes popping out of his ax his skull
here in surprise amazement at the
unbelievable redstone projects and like
a question mark in the shrinkin I or
however you say it's that's the trick to
getting views on YouTube guys but I'm
not doing that I'm going against the
grain I'm trying to explain this device
to you how it works the details of the
redstone cuz I'm not trying to treat you
like an idiot guys no I want you I want
you to feel something I don't know where
am I going with this I should have
thought this through my point is guys I
realize being the next level youtuber
that I am that these redstone segments
you get a little bit long sometimes they
can get kind of boring if they run on
for 5 minutes or whatever I know I know
so when I have to do that when we have a
long redstone segment I need to break
them up with some random
something to get your reengage
revitalized for the next redstone signal
are you guys ready yeah you're feeling
good now okay here we go my last other
major components I added on to the game
here we won't get into to dip too much
depth here but this is it over here
basically we wanted a removable floor to
the game so that's when it fills up of a
concrete powder with all our inputs we
can just clear it easily at the end of
the game without having to like go go
with our shovel and break it alright so
ideally we wanted a floor that doesn't
look like Pistons or that's not ugly
right so
if possible we want to be able to have
whatever block we want here and we can't
we have cyan clay here right now the
whole floor and we have to be able to
drop the concrete powder or in this case
the sand through the floor using a
redstone device and this is the device
here okay so we got some double
extenders there which can reach the
block up to here and it's kind of a
weird thing so let's just see it working
here press it once it does that the
floor is not back in place press it
again it does that uh-huh but we still
got to do a little bit more with it cuz
after we drop the concrete powder down
here we got to break it into items and
then like collect it together in a
Chester or some storage that we can
access easy so we'll probably just drop
it on some slabs
if you drop concrete powder or sand on
slabs it breaks alright
but then after after we do that we have
to decide like do we want to use water
streams collect together hopper chains
we could use like a hopper minecart to
run underneath the slabs and pick them
up so I was just kind of thinking about
that if we wanted to use water streams
we could probably do something like this
we got the slabs here with the water in
now do you guys know possibly a new game
mechanic you haven't looked at if you
drop concrete powder on on a slab here
with water does it turn into solid
concrete's it doesn't spoiler but if
that slab wasn't there BAM solid
concrete just like that so this idea
would work but my concern with doing
this is you have the water sound playing
constantly and that could get a little
bit annoying so I kind I don't really
want to do that plus the whole mixing
water with redstone projects is never a
good idea so we'll probably go for a
hopper minecart that runs underneath
here and then hopefully takes all the
concrete powder and delivers it to our
starting platform here so after after we
again it collects all our play pieces
and brings them back to us up here is
the plan all right so let's check this
out one more time make sure it breaks I
am just like that all right that's good
by the way with this I had a little bit
of a problem trying to get everything to
fit you'll notice like the stuff we
built before is like right over here and
we have to make sure the redstone from
that doesn't interfere with our double
extender thing here and I found
something out kind of interesting while
doing this that I didn't realize this is
kind of a trick you can with do with the
double extenders you have one observer
facing down at this piston and basically
when this piston extends the observer
detects that and then this observer
detects that this observer detected that
it powers this block so when this piston
is here it gets power at the right time
to extend even further that way you
don't need like a timing device to you
know figure out when to activate the
second piston kind of does it all on its
own the thing I found out about this
though after I had it all designed and
figured out apparently if you have a
block above that a block above a piston
it gets in an infinite loop like this
uh-huh so I had to redesign the whole
thing but that block is gone it's fine
kind of an interesting mechanic so I
thought we would hop over to the ice
farm here as well today guys I've been
working on this little by little between
episodes and it's kind of at the point
now where it's basically fully
functional it's just missing like a
collection system and a couple other
niceties or would be cool to add on to
this thought we would do that together
here don't get it though isn't it
beautiful oh my baby my my own creation
here like if I if I made an art project
this is what it would look like mm-hmm
that regular geometry beautiful the
perfect rectangles kind of looks like a
welcome mat maybe you know you know that
you wipe your feet on look that's what
it reminds me of or maybe some tire
tread I don't know
I'm quite the artist though aha so yeah
this is pretty much fully functional
just to show you again how it's gonna
work you basically here make your way
down and then when you get to the end of
it step on my pressure plate and
actually all the suspension there's
water hidden in here and welcome which
is ice on the edge of the leg
we're watching right now and see though
it's pretty good it takes a long time to
get down to them and here we stepped on
the pressure plate here and that
refilled it so now all the water is
going to start freezing to ice again so
this is all salted water which it's
pretty cool um let's go check this out
so right now this is what's happening
it's the ice it falls off the the ledge
here and it's just sitting here so we
either need to like put water stream
here I'm thinking to push it all towards
one one side of our ice farm and then
collect it together in a chest or
another idea oh oh I got a few on me
here my other idea is maybe like we
could try to make this into an afk ice
farm is an option but honestly I don't
really use any afk features of the farms
I build I don't like to just leave my
computer running with Minecraft on I
usually just like to to get something
quickly and actively and actually play
the game to get stuff you know so if I
did make this an afk farm like we could
do that just have the water screen here
pushing us along as we break the ice
kind of slowly going along that's one
option but I think we'll just put the
water streams down lower here and I'm
hoping like the ice will be able to fall
between the crack here with the glass
into the stream below here although if
we do this I'm just realizing now it's
probably gonna fall on that ledge oh
it's not gonna float like it might land
over there and I think if we use like
stairs or something this the glass will
connect to that right so I'll have to
think about this a little bit I'm sure
there's a way though yeah so there's
actually probably quite a few things we
could use to do this we can't use stairs
though look at this glass panes connect
the stairs
that was changed a while ago before they
didn't but now now they do but we could
use like trapdoors you get a flat flat
area here it doesn't connect or even ice
or probably glass and that kind of stuff
would work too I think we're gonna go
for ice and we'll just do a small test
here to see how well it works I think I
set it up over here yeah so the point of
putting the water stream down lower is
so that I don't have to walk through it
while harvesting ice because if I gotta
walk through it that water is gonna be
pushing me and it kind of slows you down
a little bit especially if we don't have
depth Strider on then we can't even use
the farm this is this is now fast we
move through it then so I kind of want
it lower so it's not a it's not a factor
it's not an annoying thing we have to
deal with as we're using the farm
so as this harvest one section here and
see how much of the ice actually falls
down here and kind of see how it groups
together like if we can just get away
with having one water stream kind of in
the middle here would be ideal looks
like most of it fell down there is a
little bit let that landed on it here
though and actually none of it landed on
the ledge but we're safer got to put the
ice here that's the idea we're gonna
fill that in okay we're gonna do a
little bit of a bigger cast here so I'm
going all the way down just to be a
little bit more certain where we're
going to be
I don't want to settle on something and
then find out it doesn't work so looks
like most of the ice does fall down some
land it here let's see how much ice we
pick up or at 57 we got two pieces two
pieces landed there the rest of it looks
like it fell down Oh a little bit more
here grouped up 57 64 who has actually a
big chunk there we got we got 18 hmm
yeah maybe it's a bad idea to do it this
way cuz if we if we have the water at
this level we don't have to worry about
that oh yeah there was something I
really wanted to mention about the ice
firm here there was there was an
interesting suggestion in the comments
that I tried out we're using the
dispensers in the farm like I've said
many times so that we can have ice
freezing on both sides so it starts on
the side with the trapdoors and it
starts on the side with the dispensers
instead of just like starting on one
side and slowly making its way to the
other it freezes like almost twice as
quick doing it with the dispensers here
the downside is we have to have all this
redstone to control it but you guys
suggested why not get rid of the
dispensers use the new water lodging
feature and just have slabs running all
along the side they're full of water
right that way water the water can still
freeze on the side but you don't need to
have any redstone controls or do
anything complicated or spend all the
the redstone and iron and all the
resources to do this right there's a
great idea I tried it out though and
interesting game mechanics again does it
work like I thought it would or you guys
thought it would if you have waterlogged
slabs like something like this this
water block in the middle will never
freeze even though it's in a cold biome
and it's got the slabs beside it's in
order to get ice you can't have water
blocks next to the water block you're
trying to freeze
and apparently the game sees these water
log slabs as water blocks they never
they can't see dice as long as we leave
us it'll never happen so I thought that
is kind of interesting because as we saw
with the concrete powder there
if you drop concrete powder into a water
log slab it has to make a decision like
does it turn it to concrete's or does it
break it asked the decides because it's
it's a block that has the two functions
right has to choose which function to do
and in that case it chooses the slab it
breaks the concrete powder in this case
it chooses the water and it doesn't it
doesn't freeze here while if this was
just a slab like if that was there then
this could freeze but if the water's
there can't oh yeah there's one more
little detail about this farm I don't
think I mentioned before the reason why
it's on a zigzagging pattern you notice
that it's not like perfectly in sync
with each other there's a reason for
that actually the idea is when we get to
the end of one of these chains like for
this one we'll be walking this way when
we get to the end here we step on the
pressure plates they'll probably be a
block here stop us from walking any
further to the left but then we got a
change directions here we got to go
forward to the next section we don't
ever want to move our mouse cursor while
using this farm so we move forward and
then we start walking right and that's
how we get to the next section you get
it so we walk left forward and then walk
right now there's a little extra device
I would like to add to this farm and as
this experimenting with it here we're
ideally we don't want to have to walk
forward either we're gonna try to get a
slime block launcher mixed into that so
let's say we're we're walking left we
get to the end of the section and then
it pushes us forward and then we start
walking right so hopefully we never have
to press the UP button on our keyboard
just left and right to zigzag through
the the thing make it a little bit nicer
if we can pull that off but anyways guys
I think that's gonna do it for today's
episode
problem with those those big projects I
do too much stuff off-camera not enough
on camera not enough variety and stuff
so we're gonna hopefully cut down on
them once we finish the few that we're
working on hopefully not doing many big
projects even though I think they're
really cool they're really interesting
they just take a lot of time get back to
the more simple more fun stuff coming up
here soon in fact I think next episode
we might even look into the snapshot
just for a bit of a I change out maybe
play around with the new features the
illah Jers the pandas all the cool stuff
might be might be good unless there's
some reason I shouldn't update let me
guys let me know in the comments if you
guys know anything that might be missing
but says I mean like bugs or things like
that common as they says does etho ever
do anything with flying machines it
would be cool to see him makes some new
stuff with them let me tell you
something when it comes to redstone
there's two things I kind of avoid you
may have noticed flying machines is one
of them and like any of those big slime
block walking contraptions oh man I
can't get my mind around them I know
they're just like simple tricks lots of
simple tricks collected together and a
big moving machine but like where do you
start it's hard to it's hard to get your
mind around it to begin with but also
big doors I never really gotten too big
like four by four doors five by five
doors ten bartend doors the most amazing
door ever I never really got into that
kind of stuff either just find it really
confusing not a lot of fun I don't
really like condensing redstone and
making it all fancy I just like trying
out unique ideas with it I guess
moreso not really the the technical
aspect of making it all perfect and
fancy AHA anyways guys that's it for
today so hopefully you enjoyed it thank
you for watching as always and I'll see
you again in the next one take care have
a good day
bye bye
you
[Music]