[Music]
welcome back
everybody this is etho and we are
having some fun in our let's play world
again today i
i've been doing this thing come on
nope i like to go out during lightning
storms in the game now and like just go
up in a tree or something
and just stare out for where the
lightning
strikes and then i'll go check that spot
and i think one of these times
i'm gonna get a supercharged creeper
like i think the odds are pretty good
because even even right here there's
quite a few creepers around
whoa come on couple more lightning
strikes
please
uh thunderstorms don't last very long in
this game and then i bring a
a name tag with me so if it ever does
happen i can
name the creeper or trap him name him
and then
he shouldn't despawn and i'll have a
supercharged creeper in my world
um oh where where
i missed it
usually i don't i'll go up in a tree so
they can't attack me
while i watch oh man
i'm in trouble i'm in trouble there
where where
dang it no
there right there let's go check that
spot if we can
i'm really low on health now from that
and they're still chasing me go go go go
i think it was up here we had a
lightning strike
i've been wondering does lightning
strike in deserts because
it doesn't rain in deserts i'm not
healing
like where these creepers are right now
felt like where it struck
oh right there perfect that's perfect
when it strikes that close
because you should have some creepers in
the area
and if you're lucky it'll hit one of
them
nope no creepers there
well unfortunately we did not get a
supercharged creeper today oh hello
but i'm gonna keep trying that it's kind
of like uh storm chasing in minecraft
uh except i i chase lightning oh that's
not good
i'm not doing too hot here we'll use a
stair
[Music]
we got him um yeah i think the odds are
pretty good of actually getting a
supercharged trooper doing that though i
just have to
kind of luck out a bit on it uh
so i'll show you around again today i
did a little bit of work on a few
different things
so first off uh last episode we worked
on the slime farm we added a tool switch
for it
and you can hear one dying right now
uh i think he's in one of these holes
sounds like the farther one over there
so he's drowning that it seems to work
be working okay
i had one get by this thing i think he
went diagonally
off like the edge of that corner and
into this the stream
he bypassed the hole but overall it
kills most of slimes and it's a lot
quieter around here
which is really nice
and they're dead nice uh we also started
working on the spider farm here
and good news i got that pretty much
well it's partially set up at the moment
uh
64 hoppers
for each of these that's like oh that's
so many
so many hoppers so much iron that's like
uh
it was over a stack of iron blocks to do
all this it's crazy
but i think it's the simplest way of
doing it and in the long run it will
work out the best
uh we have only 32 string collected
so far i wonder if i
i'm not going to check them all i wonder
if i
made it so some of them didn't link
properly
but yeah they spawn up at the spawner
there and they fall down
something i wanted to test last episode
but we never got around to it is
if they would fall through a film of
water like this
and it turns out they do
so i was hoping to have like a switch
that we could turn the water off and
and make them go through this part of
the the spider farm
but uh now they just fall through like
it's not there
no matter what height they spawn it i
think one got through i hear him
up there what another slime got through
i think so
yeah i hear him up there
uh it works pretty good though it's rare
it's very rare if they get through
uh i also worked on the lab let's let's
leave these guys alone
worked on the lab some more that is very
very very close to done
humongous project though it's taking
some time
what i've done is i got the redstone
basically all set up i haven't fixed
this door yet but
uh let's see i added in item frames here
to show what ingredients go in
what's uh what chest or what brewing
stand so like for example
if we follow the line here this is for
making
uh night vision potions and invisibility
potions we start here
with an awkward potion add that that
makes it a night vision then
we extend it with the redstone
we can invert it then to make the night
vision potion and invisibility potion
and then we also add a splash
effect to it and i can i can grab the
potion in
any one of these chests like at any
stage of the brewing which is cool
so i've done that with uh quite a bit
this is for making speed and slowness
potions
uh this is for making instant damage
potions this one here
this is for instant health i have i have
an extra one of these
so they just go to this end slot and
nothing happens which is fine
we got regen over here this one is going
to be making
for making strength two potions i'll
have to take a strength potion from this
one
and bring it here for a second stage if
i want that
this one is for weakness potions
start here and it goes down uh this is
for
this is the same as over there but i'm
going to use this for making speed 2
splash potions
and finally we have fire resistant ones
here so
pretty cool i haven't set this part up
yet this is for making the awkward
potions and we need to distribute them
um but i did get
this set up this is like a master switch
for the whole thing
if we flip this it turns it on
and then crazy lazy stuff happens uh
there's
i don't want it running all the time for
sure because i notice
quite a quite a frame drop when this is
running
but we got the hopper timer pulse
extender
pulse creator here and then it goes to
these two wires
lots of redstone i'm out of redstone
again
but uh should have this done very soon
oh yeah i didn't really uh
really come on uh i didn't really
explain this too well but
right now all the string is just
gathering to one of the corners in the
hoppers i want to
make it go to a chest and then have a
storage mine cart that fills up and
brings it up
to the surface here or to a
higher part in our cave and drops off
all the string there somewhere
and then sends the storage minecart back
down to get refilled
that way i don't have to go down into
this nasty pit to pick up string when i
need it
and when we get enough string we should
be able to finish up the gold farm
i think although i need iron now
because i used it all but for today i
think that
the main project i want to work on is
this area
here we should work on this a bit
uh first off let's try to
define the shape of this room a little
bit better we have this thing here
we should match the shape of this but
like if we go up here for example this
is what we're
we're trying to copy have a three wide
grass path and then wood on both sides i
think
so like for here it's easy
just count out three and we want wood
here right
um we gotta shape this cell
uh let's go does it look bad if we do
this
i think that's too narrow yeah i think
we need to go out a little bit further
before we start doing that
all right but yeah we'll work out the
walkway
uh these chests i think i might move
today you know what i really want to do
people have been telling me for a long
time to make like a horse stable
and i think i'm going to put one of
those down there
so um
maybe yeah let's try to work this out
actually so
the idea is i want to be able to bring
my horses down here
and then have like have this like a
parking
lot almost to have a two wide
door entrance i can i can ride in with
the horse
ride in and then the horse gets locked
up
and when i press shift i can walk out
without the horse being able to get out
and without the horse suffocating or
anything like that and then i want to
make it
easy so that i can just right click on
the horse
door opens and i can back the horse out
real real simple
one thing i've learned already uh when i
do this
this is not enough head room i hit my
head if it's only three high
when i get off the horse uh maybe we'll
go
go up to the surface so and just work
out a little design for it
is it night oh it's night okay one sec
yeah so let's try to design some kind of
stall for
parking horses i was thinking something
like this is probably about
all we would need uh
because they just need like a two by two
space oh hello uh
you know it goes day and it's really not
safe around here
i have so many trees in this area this
creeper is always
uh the main reason i haven't really been
using horses as much as i would like to
is because they're a bit of a hassle to
to to get going and to get off
because if you just leave them wandering
they take off like they'll go
100 200 blocks really quick and you'll
lose them like on the mytrex server
people are losing their horses
all the time because you just hop off
and
they wander you can turn around 15
seconds later and they're gone and you
have to go find them
it's pretty crazy so if i set up like a
little parking stalls every
so often my world that would be really
cool uh so a horse
i don't think can get through that
just gotta figure out oh which which
side is it this side okay so they can't
get through that for sure
uh let's try go a little bit higher
all right so they can't get through that
either so they're over a block and a
half tall
and they should be able to get through
this yeah okay
so i think um
actually you know i think the best way
of doing it making like a door for them
is just have one block like that they
won't be able to get through that on
their own
like have a piston come up out of the
ground or something that that pushes the
block up
if we get off the horse we can still
walk out of that
and then we need to make it so that when
we hop on the horse that block goes down
ideally
if we can do something like that um
that would involve doing using trip
hooks though
i call them trip hooks i don't tripwire
hook
uh so i just
i wish you could make these a little
more compact i think we would have to do
something like this
get these like this
and if if this is
tripped make the piston go down
yeah well no that doesn't work because
how am i going to get the
horse in here if that's up
man this is a tough problem maybe i got
to use a t-flip flop or something for
this
i'll mess with it for a sec here yeah so
t-flip-flop is definitely the way to go
with this i think it seems to work out
pretty good uh had a creeper blast just
about
killed me very quick coincidentally
after talking about them
uh so check this out
tripwire goes to a sticky piston pushes
the block up
that converts it into a one tick pulse
which goes to another sticky piston down
here if you power
a sticky piston for only one tick it
will leave the block behind
so it's like a t flip flop and
check it out so i hop on the horse
block goes down from that stays down
until we return block goes up
hop off well i i hopped off
into the trip hook so something we're
gonna have to do with this is make sure
i don't uh
get off on the sides here so as long as
i make it so
there's no two block high space i should
be
able to prevent that from happening
let's try this try this again
alright so now we shouldn't spawn on the
sides
ride out return from a long journey
goes back up hop off the horse walk out
perfect so that's what i want to do the
only thing
oh i did not press shift i i swear
why did that happen that was weird
um the only thing i want to make this
tileable so i can't have all this
redstone to the side so i think
i'll try to run it to the back here and
also
maybe bring this in one block because we
only need the string
one block wide not two like this
and yeah
all right so we're gonna put a bunch of
these
i think like i'm gonna try and make like
eight of them i think
down in that room let's just go back
there
and i think that'll be really cool so
i'll be able to keep a stock of horses
uh like a storage room for horses
basically
in this little area um
yes over here so i'm gonna have to move
all these chests
out of here man
let me show you how much stuff is here
all this i'm gonna bring an ender chest
here i think to speed it up
man
this used to be my main storage room
this area here for the longest time
before i built that
that shutter one up there by the furnace
room
um now i've been using it for bulk
storage basically
oh yeah and i did this by the way check
it out so
that means the walls can go on the
outside of this wood
anything at the wood or inside we don't
want to
put any walls and also we can hide
lighting
using pistons kind of like we did up
here
so underneath each of these pistons is
yeah i can break it it is like a pumpkin
or something so that's
that's how i'm lighting a lot of my base
with that little trick
so we'll do the same down there and that
should allow us to get rid of a lot of
these torches
oh man that was brutal that took over
half an hour to do
oh it's crazy uh and i was i was
efficient about it too i had an
empty ender chest here i emptied my
inventory
just just pick up the stuff as quick as
i can
run up these stairs uh this is where i
brought all this stuff just over
to uh this area here i wanted
something i want to build sometime is
like a place for my bulk storage
like this stuff um but for now i just
put it out of the way
somewhere i can't really build or that i
don't really plan on building
and it's all in these chests
but i was like even doing like this
trick where you double clicked and
it fills your inventory instantly that
was a lifesaver
but it still took a long time
even with the speed two all these high
efficiency things and it was a big job
anyway that's done uh we can start
building our little
horse horse stalls or horse stables
whatever you want to call them down here
um okay so i want to have a path
here for sure uh those horse stables i
think are gonna
take up one two three four just for the
visual part of it
and then redstone is gonna take another
one or two blocks
in the back so we're pushing
we're get like if we if we put it here
uh it's going to come pretty close to
this path
so we'll either want to move it over one
more to the left i'm not sure
but yeah uh
i guess actually okay here's how we're
going to start this we're going to go
down
half a slab or a full block actually
um let's see
i want to put the next one here or here
i think we'll go
here i think that's going to work out
better in the long run so we'll go down
a block
we'll set up grass down here i think
we'll make the path
only two wide instead of three like
normal
because i plan on putting
um oops wrong pick i plan on putting
like an elevator to the surface at the
end of this as well
to get the horses out real quick
and that's going to be an even number so
we should work with even numbers for
this part of it
okay so
this will go down we'll have a the log
staircase thing that we usually do over
here
and here this will meet up
this will be taken out of this will be
dirt like usual i guess this should be
wood though
this gonna look weird i don't know we'll
find out
okay and then this will be wood
okay so that's that's gonna be our
little road for them
and then all the noise
i am so sick of slimes i think you know
when they changed it so slimes could
spawn below level 40. i thought it was
the greatest thing at first
i hate it oh
man that drives me crazy
because before i was they would only
spawn below level 16 when
i first started this build and now
they're
they're everywhere down here it's so
annoying
um okay so
i'm aiming to put eight of these stall
things in so this will have to go back
quite a ways
all right grass will spread get rid of
all this
okay so where should we start the first
one um
let's see one two
maybe we'll put the first one here okay
so it's going to be
this wide and i think we got to leave us
a one block space between each of them
so
this is gonna get big isn't it
just for the first wait wait no i did
that wrong
okay so one block space
second stall starts here so that just
for two stalls
all four stalls oop
i have arrows in the eyes now so it
shoots flaming arrows and it scares me
every time
um
yeah so it's going to be for four stalls
at this this length
so far and i want to do do it like this
we'll go up three blocks
hopefully we don't run into anything as
we're doing this
and i was thinking have
have it opened up so we can see like if
we're in the stall i want to be able to
see the horse
to the right and left the bus if there
is one if possible
get this up and fence at eye level so we
can see through
i might even take the fence out i'm not
sure and have air space
but i was thinking of doing that
[Applause]
on all the sides
like that all right
and when we get off the horse we won't
be on top of here because it takes up
all the space
which is good that's what we want
alright and maybe we'll put glowstone or
something behind this
back wall side
now as far as the redstone goes
uh we will have to get rid of this
actually for the trip wire
and this one
i'm running out of stuff here
so this is supposed to be this too
okay so that there
tripwire uh this has to come out
up to here because it's only we will fit
one string in
which is the minimum
and this is not a solid block below it
so it should still function
all right so that should be it's um
horses are wider than one block which
works out really good for this build
because
no matter how i enter this thing i'm
gonna hit that trip wire
just because the horse isn't uh like if
i if i had the horse all the way to the
right on this side
uh i still would touch the tripwire
because i won't be
flush against this wall the horse will
make me kind of like this
oh okay i think it'll work no problem
um and
then
[Music]
let's do it this way we'll connect to
the drip wire on
this side i almost feel i should
flip this around i'm not sure
oh okay i'm a little disorganized today
and rambling a bit just bear with me
we'll figure this out
uh let's make this come down one more
like this i don't want the redstone to
go in front of the fences here though
um so maybe we'll go out one more block
this way let's actually
put our first monostable circuit here
um okay
like that and then we need a repeater
going this way
peter go to a block and then
down like so
all right and then we'll run that uh
underneath
here i guess make that go down
all the way to the front and then we'll
put a piston under this side
right here for the door
so oh i wonder if i should move this
forward one because now we have two wood
blocks there ah it's fine
uh i'm losing it guys just bear with me
um all right
okay that will come to there that will
trigger the piston
and this should all work now of course
i'm going to want to clean this up
but yay
and we'll need something
to hold the horse into so we'll need
that running across
sweet and then we'll run them
all the way down
yeah so the plan with this is to dig
this out a little further i want to have
four of these on each side so four here
four
here total of eight and uh
that'll be a good level of storage for
the horses i think
and then at the very end of this i want
to have like a water drop
that i can ride a horse down from the
surface and just drop down into the cave
and also have an elevator
that i can be riding on a horse and ride
the elevator up
to the surface quickly and i got a
design for that all figured out already
that is compatible with
riding horses uh which should be pretty
cool now um
i guess that's gonna be it for this
episode though i'm gonna
i'll work on this and get it done it's
just repeating what we did basically
so let's get to the comments for today
uh first comment
hey etho is there any chance you're
going to play
uncharted territories number three i'd
love to see you play it
uh that's most likely going to happen
i've played uncharted
territories one and two on my channel
and i love that series that is
amla is the maker of that
of that map series and he hasn't
disappointed me yet i
i really love the maps he makes so i'm
looking forward to number three it just
came out
and i'm hoping it's awesome
i'm i'm guessing it is uh because he's
only gaining more experience as he makes
more and more and also
the number of features in minecraft is
increasing
every map he makes so hopefully he
topped himself again
number two was awesome though so
i'm going to wait until i finish ruins
of the minecrafters
number two with paws and beef and then
once we're done with that series i will
either start playing
uh uncharted territories number three
single player or with
i might ask paws and beef and see what
they say but either way it should happen
in time um
next question feed the beast what
happened
why are you not doing it
so we had the new uh map come out on
vanilla minecraft we started on the new
map
and oh yeah i can fix this i
i got stuck on on the wrong side ah darn
and basically
that's where i wanted to play everybody
was playing on the new map
i wanted to play there too does this not
work oh wrong spot
uh so that's where i've been and i have
i i've had little desire to play feed
the beast and said
instead because you know new map is
exciting and all that that's where all
the people are
and yeah but uh
like a week ago or so i started to get
the urge to play feed the beast again
and unfortunately
there's been an incident on the server
where
there a prank has pretty much
crashed the server it is extremely laggy
for anyone that can log on
and i tried to fix the the problem
by going to the spot where the prank is
and cleaning it up
but no i crashed and i can't log in
anymore so until that gets resolved
uh there's not gonna be any feed the
beast and hopefully it it gets
it gets fixed soon i'm not really sure
the way it's going to be dealt with
either we'll have to roll back
the whole server or that chunk or
find a way to clear entities or
something but hopefully we can get back
on feed the beast and get
back to recording i wanted to uh
play around with the red power frames
before we lost that
uh ability because it sounds like red
power is not getting updated
and i thought that was like one of the
things i was saving
because it seemed like it was going to
be a lot of fun but
i should i should indulge myself in that
and enjoy it
before it's gone so hopefully we get
feed the bit feed the beast back soon
anyway that's it for today guys hope you
enjoyed as always
have a great day and i'll see you again
next time