hello welcome back everybody do you know
what time it is do you because I don't
know that's why I keep a clock on the
wall it is
oh it's evil time darn it I shoulda
known that so guys last episode we
worked on the Nexus storage room here a
little bit and I enjoyed it quite a bit
we got a lot done we got the automatic
sorting and storage working on it and I
think we're going to continue it again
today um so here's what I want to do
we're going to focus on making this
thing more practical today and looking
at you know ways of making it actually
convenient because if it takes us 30
seconds to a minute to request an item
out of this thing we're not going to use
it very much honestly so we're going to
look at a couple ideas on how we might
be able to get it down to like five
seconds like to enter the code and
request item if we can do that in five
seconds this would be amazing not only
would it be an awesome science
experiment but it'll actually work
uh-huh all right everybody so I just
stopped into a creative world there for
a second to experiment with some
building styles for the control panel
the terminal whatever we're calling it
the thing that you enter the code to
request an item with and I came up with
something I like so we're going to build
it together here first this is the very
center of the Nexus right here this this
line so let's maybe go a few blocks back
here save some room for some redstone
because we got to connect all the the
rows together still and I haven't done
that yet maybe this is far enough away I
hope don't want to go too too far yeah
let's start here okay so this is what I
decide to do guys we're building this
just so we can visualize it Toofer
for later today for the ideas we are
going to do the 8 lever thing this was
something that was discussed and I want
to address some of the concerns with
this ok so what we're doing to request
an item we're going to have 8 levers on
this thing let's get them going here and
different combinations of this will
request different items basically you go
2 times 2 times 2 times 2 times 2 times
2 times 2 times 2 you get 256 different
possibilities and there's 256 different
items in the nexus so it works out
perfectly depending on the different
combination they'll get a different item
now this was discussed and you guys
suggested maybe we should do a different
type of inputs because this isn't super
convenient right we have 8 different
inputs we could condense it down to 3 if
we did an item frame system we're not
doing this by the way I just want to
bring it up because you guys mentioned
it you could have like you know items in
these and depending on how you rotate it
you can get eight different outcomes so
if you go eight times eight times eight
I think it's 512 so we could reduce it
from 8 inputs down to 3 that should make
it better right well I don't think it is
actually I think there's two main
problems with doing that um maybe
shouldn't have torn it down already it
seems like it might be more convenient
let's actually select what you want you
have to you have to rotate this up to
eight times well with this you just
quickly right-click it and you're done
you know I can switch probably three or
four levers by the time I do a full
rotation with one of these the other
thing though is to actually represent
what this is at is a little bit
difficult this is basically on or off
yes or no black or whites you know this
you would have to maybe use a number
between one and
eight and it's an analogue sort of thing
that doesn't actually have a good way of
representing what it's on right now so
all in all I don't think that's a good
idea
because we got to store the codes and be
able to reference them somewhere and
it's going to be easy to convert in our
heads and this is basically the easiest
thing I think but let's go ahead and
finish up what we're going to do here I
got to get into the habit of building
and talking at the same time a little
bit more thank you for all the responses
on the last episode guys it sounds like
what we should do like I talked about
spending too much time on stuff and the
consensus I seem to see in the comments
was that we should maybe do more stuff
on camera like build on camera a little
bit more and that kind of thing if I
could build and talk at the same time I
would be so happy I struggle though you
know you might notice sometimes I'll be
building and then I'll get into
explaining something and I just totally
stop building like I can't do both at
once here let's explain something else
here so I'm going to have a lever in the
middle and this is going to be like an
easy switch for this whole thing this is
going to activate the clock that will
start pulsing and requesting items from
there so every time the clock goes it's
going to request one item basically and
then when we're done we flip it back up
and then it stops but we're also going
to have buttons around here that will
request specific numbers of items like
if we want a full stack exactly 64 or
something I want to set up to do that
too and this will just be like an easy
on off you know longer it stays on the
more items we get from the thing I think
is a good way of doing it and I'll
probably use this the most just because
it's nice and convenient alright so I
did that wrong
I think I had stairs here and terrible
oh I missed okay yes
and then slabs on top all right and this
looked pretty cool when I did it before
I think let's clear a little bit of land
here I want to get some slabs some slabs
I don't know why I said it like that and
just do like a pattern like this on both
sides and I am unfortunately out when I
did it before I put courts behind the
glass here let's try it let's try do it
with the courts and let's try do it with
some sea lanterns I brought those that
might be better then we can get some
actual light from this too which would
be good let's see what we like more okay
hmm I'm not sure what do you guys like
more the sea lanterns or the courts I
almost like the courts more just because
it's cleaner okay everybody so this is a
look I decide to go with I hope you guys
like it
we'll go with a different floor though I
just put this here because it's better
than grass right for right now I hope
now let's talk about what I wanted to
talk about okay so we need a bunch of
codes like a code for each of the items
we need like the item identifier in the
code after it so originally I was
thinking about using a book we could do
something like this for example where we
have the code and then the item name
right so if we wanted to get steak from
the system its 0 1 0 0
1 1 0 1 1 1 0 1 all right so already you
can tell there's a little bit of a
problem there I have a short memory
uh-huh and then what we do just flip
this down we could get steak and then
flip it back up and when it's done or we
could hit a button either at the top
left or top right like if we want a
stack of steak they'll probably be a
button for that you just hit that and
then the items will get delivered to us
haven't decided how I want to do that
either they'll pop out of the floor or
fall from the ceiling
nearby here or maybe we'll put them in a
chest and there'll be an option to send
the items in the chest back to the
overflow chest and then they'll go back
into the system if we don't take them
out maybe but this obviously has a few
problems so I think the best way of
displaying information in Minecraft in
the most condensed possible way is
actually Maps so let's try this out
because the map is 128 by 128 pixels
that's a pretty high resolution and what
did I do with my item frames I think I
got rid of them let's grab an item for
him real quick
and I got a sleep here too probably
yeah okay so when you put the map in the
item frame it doesn't get down steeled
or anything it actually keeps the
resolution 128 by 128 so we could for
example have item frames all along the
top here or somewhere nearby
and have the map there and bam look at
that all the pixels you can see every
single one uh-huh so we can draw stuff
set up an area somewhere where we draw
out the items and then the code for them
now keep in mind guys this is not a
great example but it does kind of show
how this could work
terrible color choices but you can see I
got purple and white over there
we can see it pretty clearly on our map
but I would want to make it a bit bigger
I think but we can see white and purple
dots on here we could use that as a code
probably white and black though or
something for some reason I got the
white as off and the purple as on and we
have our exact same code for the stake
that we had in our book here right so
then we would just need an identifier
next to it like either in text the word
stake or we could try to draw the the
stake icon here next to it so we could
have like a bunch of identifiers with
the code next to it all the way down 128
by 128 that gives us if we divide it by
16 that's 8 pixels tall for each item we
would have free if we split it in half
like a line down the map here with 16
items on this side 16 on this side
that's 32 we would have we would only
need 8 maps so one here one here here
here here here here here that would show
us all the items in our system and the
code for each of them readily available
you just walk up and look at it since
everything is arranged in groups it
would be pretty easy to find stuff I
think and within the screen we would be
able to see everything we need
uh-huh so I think that's a powerful way
of doing it it would be a big pain to
set this all up but I think it's the
best way of doing it so I think that's
what we'll go ahead with judging you
know I feel like I'm a reasonable guy to
be honest but there's just way too many
of you there's like 10 of you in our
village we don't need 10 purple coats so
you're going to go back to school and
you better do well
get in there get in the building all
right let's try this out oh hey yeah
find the seats now he's stuck in a
corner darn it I saw this guy got in
here somehow is a leather worker but I
don't think that's the cheapest leather
price so you are out of here
Bubba you failed the purple coats still
here but this is a problem I need you to
go here can you do that for me I don't
want to hit him that makes the big guys
mad um good I was alone we don't have
any villager police right I think we're
good
we're cool let's get out of here so I
want to go check out the poppy farm here
I haven't looked at it in a little while
but we got all the hoppers and stuff we
need for the Nexus which is why we built
this in the first place so now what do
we do with all the iron that that's a
extra by-product to the poppies we get
ah that's the question what do we do
with all this stuff I think what we're
gonna do is save this we'll still keep
it separate from our normal iron but
we'll use it to make beacons in the
future so we have two stacks of blocks
er we almost have enough for a full
beacon base because I got I got 12
beacons just sitting here and I can't
use them because I don't have enough
blocks to do it you know so I think
that's what we'll do in the future with
all this dirty iron and start setting up
beacons around our world we're going to
head back over to the Sand Village here
though sand sandy city let's see I think
what I want to do
the man cave is over here we got the
path maybe what we'll do is just plan -
let's see maybe at this arch over here
well tear this out and we'll plan to put
a gate here that we can walk through um
I wanted to make what what are those
called a portal portal palace or you
know the the fence gate castle gate that
opens up I would love to put one of
those here Berta oh man I was way off
guys way off it's portcullis portcullis
I had to go check it was bugging me so I
looked for some tutorials on these and
to my surprise there wasn't really any
slime block ones like I thought there
would be I thought you know slime blocks
came out that would make it really
efficient but no maybe I just missed
them so I'm going to use an older that
doesn't look good I don't like the shape
to that I don't like it when it's like a
V you know um maybe we'll smooth it out
a bit more yeah I'm gonna use an older
design I don't know if we'll actually
get to building it today though the two
flats maybe oh maybe I could do it like
this and then do a stair here oh no I'm
bumping papers on my table here I've got
such a mess I got to clean it up yeah I
think that's better okay so we could
plan to have a date like this and then
we'll have two towers on both sides and
I think that would be pretty cool I
played around with I don't I don't think
we're going to build this today though I
don't have time but I played around with
the wall here a bit - I think we're
going to put dark oak maybe behind these
these little things here and uh yeah we
could put fences in front I played
around with that just to give it a bit
more depth and then for these like
archway things I'm going to
put the sandstone I think we could also
do something like this we got to keep
the Birchwood at the top though because
of this unfortunately but we could also
put stairs like this if we want a little
bit more detail but that might grab your
attention too much yeah I almost think
that's better
just just a flat wall alright maybe
we'll take a moment here to visit the
old stronghold base we haven't been here
much lately you guys don't know the
story behind this place we used to spend
a lot of time here and I basically just
took too long to build it wasn't happy
with the stuff I did I kept redoing it
and that was probably a mistake the game
changed a lot of things didn't work
quite the way I wanted them to anymore
and I specifically want to check out the
silverfish farm I'm curious if it still
works like in the past you used to need
50 levels to enchant something so I
wanted to have a silverfish farm running
all the time here that we could get XP
from then they reduced it down to 30 and
now today we basically don't need XP
let's see now if I remember right there
was a way to make this trigger or did I
break this one day and I never fixed it
I wonder oh you know I almost remember
doing that there supposed to be a piston
somewhere I can update this is over here
or do I put them push the button I
killed them what is there any way we can
resurrect this guys and and make it do
something cool in the future that's what
I'm wondering because I love the
silverfish farm but we never really did
use it we had some fun with it but we
never actually put it to use for
anything
doesn't look like they're going in the
blocks okay I just gave this a look over
and there's for sure some redstone
missing there's a piston back here so
this block pops out so I think there was
a torch there and I'm guessing a piece
of dust there or wood that might short
that out wait no that's probably right
there's some missing down here too so
I'm guessing maybe I had a repeater here
and then a piece of dust and hopefully
that fixes it I don't know yeah because
I spilled some water one day oh they're
falling out and I didn't know how to fix
it oh oh you just went in a block just
one in a block and it did something do
it again do it again come on come on I
know you can do it we almost got this
working again I think the only problem
this this wire has to turn on to
activate the stone generator and we're
not connected to it anywhere I'm
guessing I had it like this before but
like you can't send redstone down
through a stair unless it was different
in the past I don't understand what did
I do here does it make sense we could
try this just like solving a puzzle a
little of the past that might do it
come on do it again one more time oh man
we got two in a row there
two in a row guys for some reason this
is weird actually
it's like reverse now oh man
okay so in the past you have to walk far
away from this thing for it to work just
trigger it again and it seems to work
when I'm up close to them now like you
have to be think 16 blocks away four
from them for them for them to enter
into a block and now I can be right next
to them for some reason but yeah that's
working I might have to adjust the
timing but it's working now that is cool
yeah so if you got any fun ideas for
what we could do with the silverfish let
me know op the top of my head I'm
thinking maybe that arena we're building
if we could send them there and
incorporate them into the fight somehow
that would be cool uh-huh anyway let's
get to our comment for today it says hey
etho if you spend most of your time
building use mcedit to build for you but
when building the initial part to copy
work out the resources required and and
every time you use it to make a section
throw away that amount of blocks aha so
this is in response to episodes taking
too long and I don't think we're ever
gonna do anything like that I think that
would change the series too much if we
started using third-party programs to
build for us and I should probably
clarify something it's not that building
like actually placing the blocks takes a
long time it's the designing of the
building that takes the most time and
running back and forth collecting things
so hopefully when we get the storage
room the Nexus up and running that'll
help a little bit yeah I don't think
we'll will ever do that but thanks for
the suggestion but with that I think
we're going to wrap up our episode for
today guys if you have any ideas for the
things we've done let me know in the
comments I do I do check them and I will
see you in the next one
take care have a good day it still works
bye bye