[Music]
hello everyone thank you for joining me
again today
we have to talk very quiet we're in a
crisis situation at the moment
there's a there's that green thing
looking at us i'm gonna take them out
very quickly
wow
oh
oh well i tried
okay now we can talk um
i thought for the beginning of this it
might be fun to
pay a visit to something i built a long
time ago
that we never really visit even when i
did my world tour i forgot about uh
about this thing because it got replaced
and
it's just not really useful anymore to
me
but people are telling me i left some
stuff here so it might be worth checking
out
i can't even find anymore you know what
i'm talking about
there's one of the spawners over here
i don't know how many of you remember
this thing but uh
no haven't been here in months
there's a chest that's worth taking
let's see
how do we get down is the question
is it all sealed off
oh whoa one
two three skeletons over there
wow um
i should have planned this before maybe
i should have came here before i uh
because i don't know how to get in
it's been so long must be
i thought it was down here but it's all
sealed off
probably for a reason maybe
oh there we go how did i miss that
that's a good sign seems to be working
still
we'll just turn this down for your
benefit
yeah so we had a bunch of iron picks
here by the look
by the looks of it take that
efficiency two unbreaking three
fortune two breaking three
one two and one one
three oh uh
two three one that's not bad either
yeah so there is some stuff here oh yeah
that's all full cool
this is
oh yeah you know with this one we never
did get it to a one-hit kill we always
used
stone swords on it too but it seems to
be working
just fine with the new spider ai
that's cool
although did have trouble with jams
before too
you can see they're having a hard time
getting in it now
cool okay well i'm gonna head back there
i might grab some of these pics
and i will see you in a little bit
alright let's get into it so for today
i thought it would be cool to do some
stuff around here again
uh this is just an idea i had a few
minutes ago actually
i want to start working on a storage
room for this
this area here a mini storage room i've
talked about this before i just wanna
have a few chests around that have a
little bit of all the materials i might
need
when building stuff around here so i
always thought i was gonna put the
storage room
in here this is just a rough storage
room at the moment
which is actually where most of my stuff
is
in this world although i do have a few
stashes
uh like one in the nether
one in the stronghold one in the end
uh the branch mine there's a bunch of
stuff there too now
but yeah i want to
get rid of this stuff here and have a
proper storage room somewhere around
here
but not like uh where everything is
stored just
little bits of all this all the things i
need and i've worked it out on paper and
i figure
for the storage room i can organize all
the items in minecraft into about 18
chests 18 double chests very
comfortably i think have a decent supply
of all the materials without
having trouble organizing them so
i'm thinking first of all
we will work on this quarter circle type
thing i wanted over here
storage room i'm thinking will go
in this wall somewhere we'll have to dig
it out
and i also want to have a bridge from
from over here to over there
would be cool too
so that's the general general plan for
today we'll see how much we can get done
so first of all let's uh
work on this a bit i think i want
regular wood maybe and
three wide staircase
like that to get up and then this will
continue with the regular wood
and we'll have to shape it kind of into
a quarter circle
somehow let's see
it would be cool if it kind of over hung
a little bit too
and we'll just try shape it
freehand here um
do that that
so it goes two then one then one then
two
let's see how close that looks to a
circle
i did that right right
um yeah that's right
let's see how it looks from down here is
it overhanging too much
maybe of course we'll probably end up
shaping that too
okay well let's just say that's the
shape for now
then this will come up to here we're
going to put fences
around there too
see how that looks
so the bridge will probably
uh go out from here to there
so yeah right here
and we'll probably make it three wide
would probably be good i'm saying
probably a lot aren't i
what's that doing there
bridge will go out
extend this out how's it slicking
i don't know what i should do with the
floor here if i should make it out of
wood
or grass
i almost think i shouldn't use grass for
it
yeah that'll be good
you know what i could do is i could put
the half slabs underneath
to kind of hide that wood texture
okay well we'll just leave that for now
um this will come up
should this be planks
i wonder probably right
okay i will
put some wood over here
i'm probably gonna have to skip some of
this because i'm not talking very much
i'm in deep thought
all right yeah i don't know
i was thinking maybe make it go up two
blocks like a two block high stairs
but uh i think one block might be better
after all
and then if you're up on this stairs uh
or on the stairs over here you have a
nice
overlook too
okay so i'll mess with this floor i'll
try grass first i guess
and see how that looks
okay so the grass has mostly grown here
and i'm actually liking it quite a bit
it's
it really brightens up the area when you
have grass on the ground
and it makes it a lot easier to do
things like
this i'm just experimenting to see if i
like it
this glowing tree here um
because we got to light up this place
and i don't want to use torches like
i've said before
so that would be one way of lighting up
this corner
we'll see how it looks from below here
and over here
that's not bad
okay so that's one possibility and then
i was thinking maybe having a line of
leaves against here so it's not so
i don't know not so much
wood exposed and put pumpkins underneath
that will take care of lighting up this
side
let's see we'll try it um
i don't know if putting them one deep is
enough though
might be a little bit too obvious
although i might not want to go here
be cool if i left that so the lines
together
you know what i mean so the wood the
wooden line doesn't get broken
if i have a leaf here because otherwise
it has to
go diagonally like that
i will try to put these a one block
deeper and see how that looks
i'm i'm starting to like using glowing
pumpkins a lot more than i used to
they're pretty handy and they're so so
cheap to produce too
yeah we don't want that there oh
skelton right there
they keep finding their way down there
now that never used to be a problem
oh actually we don't want to use our
good grass blocks
you get those with silk touch by the way
because i'll probably have people asking
get rid of those see how it looks
then over here maybe we'll put flowers
or something i don't know
it's not bad it is a little bit dark
over here in the middle
still
um could maybe put glowstone
that's weird it doesn't let you place it
on top of fence
we'll use torches for now
all right so if we do keep this tree
here
we might put the storage room in front
over here and
possibly extend it out to over here
but the bridge should go should go right
here and we'll probably make it
a four wide bridge after all so
that would mean have a two wide gap here
that's that would be over here where it
would
continue again
kind of thinking out loud here
so let's just let's put a fake bridge
here just to see how it would go
first of all
it would extend out
and then we would maybe
do fences all along like from here
for the two sides
and possibly put half slabs underneath
them
it'll have to go down what is it two two
blocks or one block here
this won't be soil it'll probably be
wood or something yeah i'll have to go
down two blocks
hmm might be tough to do
by the way the plan with this was to
make water go
from here to down here and go through
this
tunnel and you could free
flow a boat through there and you could
possibly get off here
and i was thinking of maybe making it go
further
down over this way and come out by the
slime farm
area somewhere that was the
the plan from long ago it might need to
rethink it a fair bit
but we should try get that going too
sometime
okay so that might i think that would
look
pretty good but how are we gonna make it
go down two blocks is the next question
or make that come up two blocks
not sure oh
another thing i wanted to check out is
do vines grow on pumpkins because that
would be a
cool effect too oh they do
interesting
because usually i cover them with leaves
but you could also use vines that yes
to make them a little less harsh
okay well i'll mess around with this a
bit more off camera and we'll see how it
goes
okay so i've been working on the bridge
a little bit and uh it
seems to be pretty good let me know what
you guys think of this
i have the logs on the left and the
right here and we're going to run
fences whoop
over top these like so
both sides i was thinking
of running fences like to the ceiling
every so often too
and make it look like it's suspended
from the ceiling this bridge
that might be cool and we'll be able to
hide some lighting that way too
probably up higher
um yeah so that
that will do that and then we can make
this go down
these are the upside down half slabs
over here so
it looks cool from below or at least i
think it does
because the logs stick out a little
further than the half slabs
which is cool uh on the side
it looks decent a little
a little bit flat but
it's pretty good i think let me know
what you think
um so that will come over to here
and then we'll
just switch it so the half slabs maybe
go
like that then and then we have a nice
gradual
type thing
whoa i'm just destroying everything
we'll switch these to planks not often i
do decorate
decorative stuff like this it's a nice a
nice change
or at least i'm enjoying it
yeah okay so this
actually won't come out that far
we will make this at least two wide
so that we can walk along here and we'll
probably
have a rail here too
uh and we'll make it merge with this
this wall over here
somehow
yeah i'm gonna have to protect this
bridge hill because it caught fire
once already from from this lava so i
need to put something underneath it
or otherwise it's going to catch fire
like these logs here caught fire from
from that
but if i put soil underneath or
something
it should be fine
i'll just do that temporarily anyway
i don't know or half slabs or something
gotta have something otherwise it's
gonna go up in flames and probably burn
all that too
okay what else were we gonna do here
this will eventually be a staircase over
here
trust me i i'm getting really tired of
jumping up that
it is a quite the mess
these mushrooms won't be everywhere
either once this is all done but over
here
would be cool or i think it would be to
have flowers and
some tall grass maybe a few mushrooms
just so it's not a big plain green
grass area actually with this one i made
it so that the logs come out like that
so we should probably
change this one so it matches
yeah it looks better
and it might be worth checking out if it
looks
better if you put a fence there too oops
yeah i almost like that more
that's pretty good so we'll do the same
for this one too
yeah so many decisions man
every little thing you gotta think of
three or four different things you could
do
and figure out which one you like the
most there's a lot to it
does this look good
i think i almost prefer it not joined
yeah so over here i changed it a little
bit
as it is too wide now there will be a
rail of some sort over here
and don't know exactly how that's going
to work yet
or what's going to be over here or how
i'm changing this
elevator or a lot of other things got to
be figured out yet
but i do like where i'm going with this
it actually expanded the base quite a
bit too
it's a lot of extra walking space here
uh we'll have to get some more lighting
and the storage room will be over here
not well i kind of know what i want to
do with that so it's not going to be
very big
like i said 18 double chests is all i
need
i'll probably put 20 just in case i
forgot something
which i could either do
five sets of of chests that are four
high
is one way or
or we could do four sets of chests that
are five high to make 20.
yeah if you're wondering what's down
here
this goes to
hmm where does this go
that's a good question all these caves
kind of come together
yeah down here this is where the old
slime farm was
which is disabled i don't know if i ever
showed you but i disabled it with half
slabs
both layers
just so that the other one gets more and
yeah all right
we're doing it we're finally gonna fix
this leaf block that's been missing for
i don't even know how long now
accidentally broke it one day and
haven't
gotten around to fixing it um
yeah this has been going pretty good
thanks for all the suggestions
about last episode about the floating
island i got some pretty good ones
uh some one of the suggestions was i
should get rid of the dirt on the bottom
of the islands and
have it stone and then stick some
coal and iron veins in it to make it
look a little bit more
like cut out of a minecraft world i
thought that was a pretty good idea
one day i said i should have the vines
come down
and then stop at like a melon block like
a
like a watermelon use that as a stopper
so we could have the vines however long
we want and then
have them connect to a melon block so it
would look like
they're producing fruit kind of i
thought that was an interesting idea
i might try it out see how it looks
and people said one guy said enderman
can teleport
64 blocks uh x and zed
and 32 blocks y like
uh in any direction that's uh
it's a little scary
but people said if i put a curtain
around the enderman farm
the ender ender that uh
they won't be able to teleport so some
things that we will probably get into
another day
but i definitely did read your
suggestions and i thank you for them
oh yeah what were we going to do here we
were going to get rid of the pumpkin and
replace it with
a glowstone just because
i don't want the face
i really wish there was a a blue light
in this game that would look so cool
because these like glowstone and the
pumpkins
are very similar in color
and yes i know i can use a texture pack
but i wish they would incorporate
different colored lights in vanilla
minecraft
alright so cool hmm
try to think of how we could incorporate
some water over here too
but i'm not really sure it would
probably look
good if we had a few vines coming down
somewhere here
like like here for example
every so often and they would come down
uh to the leaves there that would
probably be cool
yeah i like that bridge that looks that
looks really neat
anyway i guess we will call it an end
for today
thanks for watching leave your
suggestions in the comments
and i will definitely take a look at
them
um this place is coming together it's
just taking time
and that's that's okay
all right okay anyway thanks for
watching see you again next time
take care