[Music]
hello hey how's it going everybody this
is
etho and welcome back guys to another
episode of our let's play series here so
today guys today you're in trouble you
are in so much trouble I have been
reading the comments on the last few
episodes and I know what you've been
saying you know what everybody's been
saying since the 1.11 updates yeah yeah
that's right
rest in peace Nexus you know you know
the top comments on the last video right
now you know what I've been dealing with
you know what you've been telling me so
so the Nexus that took a century to
build is overshadowed by an enderchest
Thomas MC I see what you said there and
you're right
to an extent to an extent guys there is
one thing though that the shelter boxes
can't do like they are so amazing let's
let's be honest here they truly are but
one thing they can't do is they don't
have they're not gonna be good for
storage like bulk storage right bf best
friend
I want this goin just so we can see it
working because we never see it working
hardly on video so yeah the Nexus fear
has been like my bulk storage room guys
this is where I drop off lots of stuff
if I get a thousand ice from our ice
cube farm you know I drop it off here
instead of just leaving double chests
around the world shelter boxes as we
kind of saw in the last episode take
about five minutes to get each one the
Nexus has 256 items and like just to get
256 chakra boxes would take forever so
yeah one thing I realized today though
that is a bit unfortunate I thought each
item in the Nexus had three double
chests of store
isn't that what I did I thought that
that's what I did but no it's only one
double jest there's like a hopper a
double chest a hopper and then a dropper
so it's it's kind of like three chests
worth of storage for each item I thought
it was way more than that though you
know
so yeah the Nexus has a lot of problems
to be honest but it was a great learning
experience for us it's always going to
have some merits like I'm gonna use it
for storage I'm gonna change the clay
because I I don't like it now now that
I've seen it for a little bit here and
the Diamonds will probably get changed
but guys I have a plan okay are you
ready for this
over the next two to five years we are
going to design and build the Nexus 2.0
using shelter boxes top-of-the-line
impressiveness here the ender shelter
box is gonna come out in Minecraft 1.16
probably in three years so then we will
start building the Nexus 3.0 that's
that's the 5-year plan all right so
let's get to it tear aha so guys I have
been working on a little bit of a secret
project here this is the Nexus 2.0 or we
might be calling it the Google box
question question or if you guys have a
better name let me know in the comments
but basically this is a shocker box
storage room I asked myself if I was to
build the Nexus now how would I do its
what would it look like how would it
work and this is it basically alright
guys so here's the thing about this
storage room I know when you look at it
here it's not super impressive right
it's pretty plain pretty basic simple
keep in mind I just like to hand this
out today I tried to get it done as
quick as I could so there's more stuff
we might be adding to this later and
this room is just a mess
excuse the mess I'm sorry about it we're
actually in the man cave
now you might recognize area this is
where I got that skeleton spawner and
all my mob drops purge was here because
I haven't put it in the Nexus yet but
yeah this thing is actually pretty crazy
this is probably the most complicated
redstone project I have done to date
believe it or not even topping Wilson
although Wilson and the Nexus took
longer but yeah let's let's give it a
try here we'll do a little demonstration
so in the middle here this middle row of
chess this is our search basically you
might recognize this from the Nexus we
have one of each item it's not totally
filled up here and it's got a few items
in right now and on the right here this
is kind of like our disk drive and the
chakra boxes are like our one key
storage cells if that makes sense so we
can put a bunch of chakra boxes in here
like four hundred of them or more it's
very easy to expand on this infinitely
if we want same with over here Mojang
add more items to the game we can just
add more chess really easy with the
system over on the side here I've
prepared a couple chests with items
inside already I'm gonna put those into
our our system here huh some of these
yeah some of these are empty still we'll
grab one of those two just to show you
they work so basically all you got to do
if you want to store items in in the
storage system is drop them off in this
chest here nice and simple okay we got
to empty purple ones they're the recipes
have items inside and you can see pretty
random items let's say for example we
wanted to get some dirt out of the
system we have 23 dirts 39 grass blocks
like to access the shell car box you
gotta place it in the world right and
you would have to like look through all
the shelter boxes in the system here the
great thing about what I've done here is
if you want to find dirt all you got to
do is look at it here in your search
press Q
that throws the dirt into this hopper
over here and now what it's doing is
it's going through all those shocker
boxes in the system and checking if any
of them have dirt inside if they do then
they show up here which is pretty cool
and let's say there's more than one
color box with dirt like let's say I
take these 23 out and I need more right
the project I'm working on takes more
than 23 then all I got to do is step on
this and now I can get 64 more and that
was all the dirt we have in the system
so no more showed up here
and then after you go through the boxes
here they they return back into this
chest so that is pretty cool so yeah
that's the basic idea of it here it's
really weird storage system right like
most storage systems are very very
structured you have a certain number of
chests certain items go in certain
chests and once they're full that's it
this is like chaotic and crazy if you
want to add items to the storage room
you can just drop them off in the chests
right or you could just place a box here
and start filling up up with stuff - the
last thing I built on this was this
little squisher system so there's a
couple kinks I still got to work out one
problem I'm not liking right now is it
gets stuck in this hopper here so I got
to step on this twice but I'll probably
get those all refined later but yeah
that just added torches to the system
you can mix and match items and chests
you can have you know 20 chests of one
item you can do whatever you want really
and also like these are really easy to
move so you could like pump them into a
storage minecart and move them to
another one of these systems somewhere
else in your worlds
do you like mobile storage that way and
oh man my mind is just exploding with
awesomeness oh you know I should have
kept one torch darn it so I don't have
that my system in now if we would search
for torches it's going to go through
these and it
pick out the magenta one it goes through
these in a chaotic way as well like to a
certain extent it goes through them
whatever is first here but then it also
goes through droppers so it randomizes a
little bit and as soon as it's found it
shows up here so sometimes you get more
lucky than other times and it shows up
sooner than other times but yeah pretty
cool stuff let's do a couple more things
here another thing about the system so
let's see do we have it I think one
chest at glassing let's search for glass
the last thing we searched for was
torches so that search item should come
back in this chest there it is right
there so it dis cycles through them they
end up in the bottom chest first and
this one then this one this one they
fill up as they go huh
pretty cool I guess this gives you a
chance of pulling it out too
the other thing is the hopper below this
is locked so if you wanted to take this
chest with you you can do that too it's
another option and then bring it back
later if you want
oh yeah and hopefully you guys don't
mind but today's probably gonna be just
a Show and Tell episode a little bit of
an odd oddball episode usually we we
build stuff together but I mostly just
want to show off the system so yeah got
a lot to talk about still okay let's
keep going here you might be wondering
what's on the left here absolutely
nothing this is just there for symmetry
right now but it might be used later for
a feature I have planned kind of an
afterthought I had was it would be cool
if this only showed the items in the
system not just like everything you know
so if I can't make that work with this
middle chest I might make it work over
here well show one of each item in the
system you know could be a cool thing or
we might have empty chests go into here
or something of that nature I'm sure
I'll get used for something though we
haven't really seen the Redstone yet so
let's get this running and we'll try to
catch it in action search for bones I
suppose
over over here was a pretty good view
and see there's two sets of Pistons
doing things there and then there's also
a bunch of item elevators going on to
get the items back to the top of the
chest to raise this Manion barely sees
these item elevators this one over here
is for that the item filters though the
the middle chest stuff this one over
here is for the shocker box main oh oh
well oh oh no we might have a problem oh
no really
mm-hmm wonder if that has to do with
piston translocation I'm still in 39 see
there's a chance it might work in the
next version oh snap I don't really want
to update though kind of seemed like it
came out of this item elevator here
there we go hello what oh I'm gonna have
to watch that video back just to see
what happened there it definitely came
out item elevator right like somewhere
around here maybe because I put a piston
here that might have been a mistake
yup so I just double checked and it's
definitely the Pistons that are causing
the problem so I think I'm just gonna
wait and not fix that problem cuz if you
didn't know in the 40 snapshots they
have removed or changed or fixed or what
however you want to call it I'm gonna
say removed piston translocation a lot
of people consider it a bug I saw it
more as a feature but there's a chance
this will just work in the next update
I'm not gonna update though because it
is buggy from what I've heard yeah like
oh my a lot of my elevators in this
world are gonna be broken because they
got rid of piston translocation so I'm
not super happy about that to be honest
yes it'll fix this one
a problem I'm having but I could just
redesign this and move the piston over
kind of a small thing or I could have to
redo a bunch of stuff in my world
fix my zombie pigmen farm and Mojang
anyways so yeah let's look down below
here the bulk of this thing here is the
search engine the search engine is like
a seven by seven by seven box of of
redstone hoppers Pistons and and stuff
like that its job is to go through the
shocker boxes check if the item matches
the filter if it does then it goes one
into one chest if it doesn't it goes
into another chest so it splits the
Shanker boxes the way it does that is
actually pretty tricky stuff though
let's see if I can set up an example to
show you all right so very cool guys so
we're gonna be looking at a couple
tricks here I used to make that system
in case you're interested so I'm sure a
lot of you are familiar with item
filters like we have here concept is
pretty simple if the item you throw it
it matches the filter in the hopper can
pick it up so we don't have glass in
here it's not picking up the glass but
if we throw a ladder at it that can go
inside because that's what we're looking
for
likewise if we put a shocker box on top
of here it combos pretty well spruce
wood is not in the filter so it's not
getting pulled out but if we put ladders
in the chest or if it had ladders in
already then it will pull the ladders
out right so what I do with our search
engine I give it time to allow one item
to pass through into the filter if it
does I know the shocker box has the item
we're looking for alright so that is the
first step the second step is we need a
way of changing the item filter which is
actually a really trivial thing to do
surprisingly I thought that is gonna be
hard
do what you got to do is just queue up
another item like a slime block
slime ball so from that middle chest
whenever I throw an item in this is
basically what it's doing it it goes
into a queue and then I unpowered this
for a moment like so and then it
switches so it's no longer a ladder
filter it's a slime ball filter right
the tricky thing is like getting this
out of here afterwards but we're not
gonna look at that not right now anyway
yeah so the basic gist of the whole
system is we have a dispenser that
receives the shocker boxes if there's
any inside the dispenser o'clock runs it
makes the shocker boxes get objected on
top of the hopper all right we keep this
powered until we want to check for an
item so we just flip this real quick we
can see one one spruce wood left the
Shocker box into the item filter so we
know this has spruce wood in and then we
break this I had another like hopper
over here to pick it up just so
simplifies things a little bits yeah we
break that goes into here and then it
goes into another dispenser a different
one and we place it again basically do
the same thing again the reason we do
this in two steps is just so it's faster
all right but at the second step what we
do is we use a dropper to replace the
item we took out of there so we took one
spruce wood out we need to get it back
in some way otherwise every time I go
through the search you'd lose an item in
one of the chests right we got to get
that back into there and then we break
it again and based on whether or not we
detected the item we're looking for in
the filter we send it one way or else we
send it another way and to do that I had
to use hopper junctions which is an idea
I've never thought of or used before
let's see
it's actually really simple as well but
basically you do something like this
right and you want to keep this powered
over here at the junction right so if we
put dirt through here it's gonna go to
the left hopefully no I
oh no I'm powering the wrong one got a
power this one down here okay
so now using redstone we can choose
which way the dirt goes pretty easily
because it pulls down before it goes
sideways is the idea so this will
because it's powered it can't pull down
so it's gonna go down to here if we
remove this so then it can start taking
them and it doesn't go here so you can
control which way the Shocker boxes go
using that trick as well okay so we're
back at our system here guys I'm not
gonna go through every single detail
with the redstone but I will show you
those main concepts how I built them
here now that we understand them so this
is our first dispenser places the
Shanker box that hopper over there is
the item filter and the piston breaks
it's afterwards yeah if we checked here
this is our item filter on the side here
is the cue to switch out the item and
you see we got a bunch of hoppers below
that is a hopper junction to get that
item out of there and then who can we
find our way through here it is very
very tight over here yeah over here is
the second step so this is the other
dispenser with the dropper to put the
item back in that we took out and then
the piston breaks it again pushes it
over to that hopper there and can we get
through here yeah so again we have a
hopper junction so if we found a match
if the Shocker box matched the item
filter then we unpowered this redstone
torch here the items goes or the Shocker
box goes down into this item elevator up
to our our thingy there otherwise it
goes to the
here and back into the main loop into
the storage boxes yeah that is how we
separate them uh-huh all right guys I'm
losing my voice here unfortunately I'm
kind of out of it I've spent too long
building this there's not going to be a
tutorial on this
I've decided just for a couple reasons
mainly because like when I built this
from creative into our world here it
took me an hour and a half I knew what I
was doing it like I had the world on the
other screen as copying it blocked
four-block hour and a half to build this
so that means the tutorial would be an
hour and a half and nobody's gonna watch
an hour and a half tutorial also while
building it I made a bunch of mistakes
which you guys will too if I make a
tutorial and then I'll have a bunch of
Rage comments oh this doesn't work you
wasted my time
because even in normal tutorials you get
that and this thing is like pretty
tricky to build so what I would do
instead if you guys really really want
to see this soon I'll try to get a world
download up and then you just copy it
out of the world or check it out in the
world or do whatever you want with it
but yeah it's gonna be too tricky to go
over every little detail I think so yeah
just kind of wanted to show it off today
hopefully you guys liked it and we're
gonna end the episode a little short
today
so let's do the comment of the day it
says heyyyyy so how often do you eat eat
on eat out am I losing my mind
eat out on restaurants and what do you
think about it I love your videos keep
up the good work I probably go eat outs
once every week to once every two weeks
I would say I really like eating out
actually I love I love like different
foods trying new stuff lately I've been
on a pizza kick there's a great pizza
place by my place which I've been going
to every week cuz I love it so much but
I know like fast food and that isn't
good for you so I try not to do it too
much and also like it's expensive in
Canada
in the u.s. fast food and restaurants
are a lot cheaper but in Canada like
it's it's $10 at the minimum for me to
eat out a fast meal like cheap stuff at
a good restaurant like it not even a
good restaurant but like a sit-down
restaurant a cheap one it's probably 15
bucks at least it's a bit of money you
know if you do that too often it adds up
so yeah I like doing it but I don't do
it SuperDuper often aha
so guys hopefully you enjoyed our builds
here thank you for watching if you have
any ideas on it let me know in the
comments and until next time take care
bye bye
[Music]