oh not gonna lie to you guys I've been
doing that for about five minutes
straight year I don't know why I find it
so funny today it's like I've seen it
before but I I never really paid
attention to how it just that goofy it
is okay like you walk you walk forward
it looks normally you know leg goes
forward and backwards forwards backwards
same with arms but if you walk backwards
the body it turns sideways and he he
starts to taking his legs and arms out
sideways ah okay enough of that enough
that just looks so funny all right
it started out by the way I started out
as parking mice practicing my spin jump
because I did that the other day when we
went caving with Michael and B thought
it was hilarious so I've been trying to
improve ah it's really hard to do though
especially in this camera angle okay the
idea the idea behind the spin jump oops
let's get get to this it's easier doing
it this way idea behind the spin jump if
you guys missed it you jump and then you
gotta do a full 360 and try to land
going perfectly straight the straighter
the better so it looks like looks super
graceful you know now ideally also like
that time I kind of see I went too far
left that time it's gotta be straight
you got to land straight and ideally you
don't want to do it like super quick you
don't want to do like that you know that
was a what was that for 80 I can't I
don't know what's a turn and a half I
forget but when you do it what was I
going to say when you do it you want to
smooth motion so you just you just
finish
and when you land you know smoother the
better anyway enough goofing around
let's let's get to it here so I was
working on a sheep farm I think I got it
finished more or less also like to get
stuff out of an enderchest
at the moments I used to have one up
there but since we redid the sheep or we
since we did that room up there I got
rid of the ender chest so now the
closest one is all the way over here
which is ridiculous so I added another
one I was having trouble before trying
to find a spot that it didn't stand out
like a sore thumb you know and what do
you guys think it's right over there
very sneaky very sneaky we got our
crafting table there
although hindsight now I would probably
just put the crafting table there if I
thought of that originally but oh you
know what we could put an anvil there
but uh all right we found a place for an
anvil finally see I got this dealio here
it's just the it's not much to it wire
running underneath and that goes to two
Pistons the center is right here I'm
going to be able to get out of here
Center is right there let's try to get
some light you see one piston there the
other ones over there so those come up
when we go over the pressure plates and
the water stream ends just short of here
so that's the items won't be moving at
all guaranteed when they pop up so I
think that's going to work I haven't
tried it yet and we get out of here well
I did try it I'm not going to lie but I
didn't break the ice so there was no
water flow so I had to cancel that
recording and start over that's why I
had this all done when I
started here because it did not turn out
well oh boy okay
let's share some sheep I switched over
just just this one to the half slabs oh
yeah
those eggs man shears one problem with
this room though I got to say like since
I got all these multicolored sheep in
order to put all the wall away I'll have
to open every single chest drop off like
two ol it's not convenient at all it's
kind of one of the problems with this
farm I'm not going to lie is it looks
awesome with the rainbow coloured sheep
but as far as practicality goes ideally
you would want them all one color so I
may eventually just start dyeing them
whatever color I need and I'll keep this
as a reference in case I want to turn it
back to rainbow but yeah let's try it
out make sure this still works
now with the half slabs yep yep sweet so
the items should have flowed here by now
let's go over this and what'd I do wrong
oh okay I did too soon I guess sweets
All Right see ya maybe ideally I would
like a mane drop off chest for all the
wool but I don't know uh these eggs man
I gotta fix that it's so annoying have
eggs all the time all over the place B
I'd say this is good good and done I'm
really happy with how you know this
whole part of the this whole part of the
cave turned out like I really like the
storage room really like this furnace
room this bridge I love this bridge and
it looks good with that
what I'd still need to work on is this I
need to put some lighting along the side
and get rid of these torches so there's
that sheep farm like the sheep farm like
this room that still needs work the only
thing that really bugs me about this
part of the cave is his door it should
have been in like two blocks and it
would have been perfect these eggs man
everywhere but yeah this is definitely
my favorite part of the man cave it's
it's like we kind of started in this
part then we made our way to this part
so we had more experience when we built
this but this book this parts cool too
it's just a little bit more plain I find
let's get some chat going oh yeah so
yeah with that in mind the kind of
finishing up with this area really happy
with how it turned out so far I'm still
going to make little tweaks and stuff to
it of course there's more details and
like I said little parts need to be
worked on yet but overall it's pretty
much done and with that in mind I kind
of want to start expanding out somewhere
else in our man cave here this area here
is also pretty much done although it
needs a little bit of love yet
especially like once we get to this
point here like I still need to do
something with that big blank wall there
and everything around the tree firms
pretty much empty so
yeah we could start expanding up this
way and we we might but I had my eye on
another place today to kind of walked
around my cave a bit the undeveloped
parts so obviously there's this part
here which we need to do and I do plan
on doing that but I think we should go a
little bit further to this area around
here start working around here on the
cave I like the spot it's it's got a lot
of elevation changes and it's fairly
wide open in most places so I think we
could do a bit with it and as we build
here we'll start working our way back to
this area I find it's easier to
transition from an area few to go beyond
it and then come back because that's
kind of what we did the tops there and
then we came back and finished up that
area
I am pretty happy with how that turned
out so far with that in mind I'm
probably going to do leste structures
like it's not going to be as cluttered
it's going to be more pathways and trees
and that kind of thing more naturey
I hope but I do have a plan for a
structure here I want to build a
mushroom farm I don't know if we can get
to it today it's going to take a long
time to clear out this land it's going
to take a long time to clear out this
land so I don't think we can do it today
but I want to build a brown mushroom
farm this open area here and I started
laying it down torches like lines it
should start about there from here to
here I figure I want to make it to brown
mushrooms wide so there's seven seven by
seven so that would be 14 wide and I
want to make go three Brown mushrooms
back so that would be 42 blocks that way
well I was convenient are awesome okay
we got it cleared out maybe we can start
it today Wow
who would have thought oh wow this is
weird I have a lighter on me too that
how did that happen
all right yeah so we're going to build
it here um clean this up I don't I
actually don't have a lot of time today
just setting that up to cup forever so I
don't know how far we're going to get
with it but it's going to have 16
mushrooms and got to clear out clear out
this land I want the floor to be I think
at this level here and I think I'm just
going to use brass flooring and see how
it looks and we'll add some pattern to
it but yeah oh boy this is gonna take a
while
okay oh there's more there's more tea
and where's my ender pearls the amazing
pearls actually you know what guys I
want to talk to you about something too
well a lot of things but the thing that
minds at the moment I want to start some
more fun projects in my world
you know like stuff that doesn't really
have a point to it it's just purely for
fun it's not a farm or anything like
that like in our old world we had lots
of that stuff we had the cannons we had
the secret project which never really
turned out so we don't talk about it
anymore
we had the Rube Goldberg machine which
also didn't really work that well
because it's vanilla and very hard to
set up that kind of stuff but you know
it's things like that we we did cool
things like that all the time so I have
a few ideas in mind but I want to get
your input on to it too if you guys have
some good suggestions I would like to
that maybe do those some things I'm
thinking of obviously there's a trivia
game which I've wanted to do I actually
thought of a really easy way of doing
that and I might do that for like it at
Gd a simple way of doing it not a
redstone version I might do that for the
next download that might be the Easter
Egg which hopefully like I said it's
coming out soon I also thought about
doing a shooting range of some sorts
possibly using boats and something that
really caught my eye recently although I
might do this on the minecraft server I
don't know is a Fe discos sonic map I
don't you guys saw that but he set up
like a race in Minecraft and I think
that could be its own genre itself in
Minecraft like you know we have race for
wool on that I think racing could really
become a big thing if people set up Maps
for it although like he's got cool like
TNT boosts and that kind of thing I
don't really think I could do all that
much of that in vanilla minecraft but
something like that like at a race track
or a parkour track or something like
that could be fun
oh what a mess I'll get back to you guys
in a bit
whoo that is a big space isn't it that's
gonna hold 21 mushrooms very nicely um
Wow I'm actually a little bit shocked
honestly like sure took a little while
to set up but I did not think I yeah I
cleared out this much space so yeah 12
mushrooms we will put them too wide um
yeah I miscounted but it's going to work
out fine instead of starting the firm
here we're going to start it to where we
blew up yeah so starting around here I
counted it's about 35 blocks that will
hold 10 mushrooms 2 wide 5 long and I
think we'll do it that way and we might
put in 2 or 4 red mushrooms or something
in the back but the main focus is to
make a brown mushroom farm and I'm going
it's gonna be pretty square of a room I
would say like much much like this but
the floor is not I never intended the
floor to be down this low the reason I
blew out so much is so I would have a
crawl space to do some redstone wiring
the actual floor is going to be up at
that level there so I'm going to fill
this in a whole layer of dirt will have
it a too high crawl space which will
make things easier for me when we're
when we're doing other stuff I'm going
to do a little bit of redstone but not
it's not anything crazy oh I'm sorry
guys I didn't know I didn't know
I just realized it does like man I
haven't seen a mob and so long what the
heck is going on I was on peaceful this
whole episode I've been on peaceful just
feel terrible now it's alright well
we'll live with it
all right so we're gonna lay down some
dirt here and maybe talk a little bit
but one thing I've noticed this is
probably going to be a problem probably
going to be a problem
yeah lots of Peter then it goes to
desert so if I'm doing the grass thing
it's not gonna look good I don't think I
would like to use mycelium since the
mushroom thing but I don't have any yet
so maybe we need to go find some
sometime soon or the other option of
course
just don't use grass don't use my
sealant use something else so we might
do that - I don't know but yeah I hope
you guys are enjoying the FT b-series
feed the beast
Oishi so far the response I've done is
pretty good on that so I'm happy thank
you for being so kind everybody and yeah
I'm pretty much addicted to that I think
it's going to be a regular series from
now on era at least I can't see myself
stopping play it's not playing it does
that make more sense and stopping
playing it I can't see myself not
playing it unless for some reason it's
boring to me which I don't foresee
happening anytime soon that's kind of
what I expected
with playing mods that's sort of why
I've resisted for a long time so that
figured it might corrupt me and Enix in
a way it has I have very little desire
to play on the minecraft server now I'm
hoping that passes but I think it's a
accumulation of a few things I have a
let's play series this so I get my taste
of vanilla minecraft through the
yes and on the minecraft server not many
of the guys have been on that
everybody's on feed the beast server so
it's a lot of fun playing on there you
know because that's where everybody is
but and I'm sure sure that feeling a
change after time I'm gonna try record
an episode on minecraft tomorrow but
yeah I'm really enjoying the feed the
beast like more than I was expecting I
thought I knew all about mods in
Minecraft like I I saw the quarry's
before but like all this stuff with mass
Raiders and that industrial grass stuff
I never saw before and Twilight forest
never heard of that before and lots of
this stuff the real craft thing and just
Greg that all of that stuff I've never
seen before so I I'm having a lot of fun
with it and it's neat four things you
can do and it's I'm really impressed
like for example the factory I released
an episode I think today today I'm
recording this thing I was going to
build a factory and I've been playing so
much I'm like two or three episodes
ahead in my recording so the factory's
actually built I can't wait for you guys
to see it because I I think it turned
out great I had a lot of fun building it
and I just I find myself just logging in
to watch it work because it looks so
cool so yeah it's cool and you can build
something in Minecraft and feel really
proud of it even though it's probably
not even that significant like compared
to other things people have built I have
no idea but for what I knew about things
and what I did I thought it turned out
great
so yeah just having fun with it um
well what'd you guys think the ceiling
is going to get lowered one I should go
get a mushroom a brown mushroom just
make sure it can grow here
pretty sure ten but I've I don't know I
always have trouble growing mushrooms
now okay brown mushroom will you grow
two tries but it did so I think you can
actually force them to be shorter I
think he has lows 5 blocks tall that one
six let's try and make a shorter one
here you got a block above yeah that's
what we're going to do we're going to
force them to be short like that so that
we can reach them easier that's my main
problem with growing them you know just
randomly is you get the tall ones and
then you can't reach them you have to
kind of go up top and it's not
convenient it's my problem so that's
that's why we're making a farm down here
I think they'll turn out pretty good we
can reach nice and easy you did all
right oh it's a slime chunk so I think
it's time to read the comments for today
guys oh dang it there's another one I'm
gonna die oh okay question for you I so
would you ever consider hosting a
minecraft server I would actually like
to build and play in a server with you
messed up smiley face I have considered
it before and what I concluded is no I'm
not going to be hosting any minecraft
servers I'm afraid
it's a lot of work and a lot of stress
and it takes a lot of time to do that
kind of thing
like even goood like managing us mine
crackers he's he's got to put a lot
extra time into doing that and we're all
we're all good like we cooperate and and
help try to help him out but it's still
stressful so for me to do that and open
it up to the public and and get tons and
tons of people wanting to join that's
not gonna happen I'm afraid I have
considered like setting up at an event
server like something that's not up all
the time but maybe once in a while get
the viewers together for some fun and
games but even that's I've I've been on
servers where people have tried to do
that and it's usually just the chaotic
mess and not really a fun time for
everybody or at least that's how I feel
and even people like streamers if you've
ever watched somebody stream where they
try to get a game going with their
viewers it takes a long time people get
very impatient and it's gets chaotic and
yeah it could be fun but it's not gonna
happen I don't think I'm afraid I'm
sorry it okay alright so I think that's
going to be it for today guys will I
survive oh yes I will live to die
another day
alright take care guys thanks for
watching
you