hello everybody this is Ito and welcome
back guys how's it going I am in the
middle of some speed mining here I'm
trying to collect redstone oh speaking
of which ah yeah oh oh we're good we're
good
I'm all out of torches so I have to
probably stop here but yeah I've been
collecting lots of stuff down here
trying to get more materials ready for
the Nexus project a lot of you guys seem
excited about that so want to try make
some headway on it today again there was
a spawner down here actually kind of
surprised me got a saddle from it but
this area was generated a long long time
ago so there's no chance I can get
nametags or horse armor or anything like
that because it was before that time
before it was possible anyway so we got
we got a bit of stuff collected here
though maybe three stacks of redstone
blocks maybe a little bit more also need
lots of iron we need over 750 hoppers
for the project so that's like oh I
don't know that's over what is that
through don't do math on camera either
big mistake there
3,750 did I do that right let's hope I
did
if I can't do it with my fingers I
shouldn't do math when I record because
I can't concentrate enough to do it ah
yeah look at it look at it it's so
beautiful
so this is 8 by 8 by 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 13 14
Tawes 14 stacks redstone or not counting
what we got today as well
but this is what we got from previous
speed mining adventures and I am going
to fortunate and that might be half the
redstone we need I don't know we'll see
how far it goes the big thing that's
gonna hold us up though is the iron
shortage but will will make some
progress today the main thing I want to
do is just try to get one side done so
that we can see how it's going to work
and then as I get the materials we'll
build the rest of them I'll build them
off camera or something we'll work it
out it'll get done um but this would
take a while
just how many chests I will fill with
this or how many stacks there will be
total I'll show you after it's done
Booya check it out this chest is full
and then we have all this so it works
out to eighty three stacks plus 46 and
another one almost eighty four 5358 dust
aha I gotta go get some packed ice
though too for this project so that's
what I'm gonna do next
all right so here we are um originally I
was just like I was harvesting normal
ice and I was going to use that instead
but all the ice is for the water streams
for carrying items and it's going to be
right next to all the redstone so if it
melts its gonna wash away all the
redstone so I want packed ice because it
can't melt
this is a safety thing because I know
I'm going to do that major headache if
it happens oh yeah this stuff what when
I first came out oops
when I go to my languages volume when
the Pat dice first came out you could
not mine it instantly like this but they
changed it this is just efficiency for
oh it's so much fun oh yeah I remember I
came here and I spent like 20 minutes
mining out one of these and it's like
nope I'm done I'm out of here okay
everybody so we got some stuff together
here we can get working on this I want
to show you today how we're going to do
the rest of this storage room or the
rest of these storage units I guess
there's really not a lot left to it
actually we did the redstone last time
and I explained how this bit systems
gonna work mostly you guys seem to get
it which is great afterwards I was like
did I explain that well I'm not sure I'm
kind of bad at that but majority of you
seem to to get what I was trying to
explain anyway so that's good I did make
a mistake though last time I had like a
line of redstone below like where I just
broke those blocks and somebody pointed
out that if these repeaters turn on and
they power these blocks they're going to
power the Redstone below so they were
not separate so I move that off to the
side here now they are separate I've
also wired up this second line of
pistons here the second bit to the
system and it seems to work good so when
I pull this they all extend or retract
and they switch between either this
dispenser in this one or this one in
this one um that's what this this line
of pistons does that was a little tricky
to keep separate so I got like a line of
redstone here goes to this block but it
does not connect to this wire instead it
goes through and then it's like yeah
it's a little messy
but it's good and then it powers it here
and then this is wire oh and I just
cracked everything now I think I had
wire here anyway so let's get to it
let's build I guess we'll start at that
end maybe I'll skip the night because I
think it's just about dark so here we go
let's get to to the building that might
make a few mistakes just be patient with
me but we're going to have that on top
right I had pretty much everybody
convinced I was going to be using
hoppers for the main item transportation
like have hoppers going sideways to
these droppers you can do this you know
it'll these droppers will put the items
right into the hopper and then they'll
carry it but no we're not doing that
because hoppers are expensive and they
also cause a little bit of lag each one
so I would rather use ice streams for
moving items around and people were
wondering how I was going to do that
because really the ice streams need to
go here because items are getting shot
out but we are struggling with space a
little bit with this design we have to
compact things as much as possible and
we have to do a trick because of that we
have to put the blocks right by the
hopper or the that's not a hopper
dropper yeah
and items have this tendency to go
upwards when they're inside a block so
they're going to go up into the item
stream through the block but we have to
make sure it's solid around it otherwise
they'll just fall out somewhere so we're
going to build it up like this and tell
you what I'm just going to run down a
little ways with this so that we can get
a little more distance with it I guess
alright so I haven't figured out exactly
what this is going to look like when
it's done like the actual storage room
but I figure we'll have a column here of
some sorts so I'm just going to build
that and this is what we're going to
attach our signs to for holding the
water in place so at each of these we'll
just put a sign
and they'll have to be a block of some
sort over here so I'll just put glass
for now all right
and I brought some normal ice we will
use a little bit of this just to get
water tada
and another one here all right so let's
try this out of course we use I I sin
our water streams because it moves items
really really quick and in order for
this storage room to be really effective
we want to get our items as quick as
possible otherwise like we won't we
don't want to order our items and then
be waiting a minute for them to arrive
we want them as soon as possible
and it looks like it'll take maybe and
seconds 15 seconds to travel from here
the farthest distance to us possibly um
just judging from this test here so
let's try this out maybe we'll put some
items in here this is something I made
sure to test quite a bit because I was
worried it wasn't going to work
tell you what I'll just put a dropper
bra I'll leave her here you see the
items popping up there that thing going
here did it no sometimes it's hard to
tell what they do they they don't drop
drop in the proper place all the time
but yeah it seems like it's 100%
effective no items on the ground out
here note we're good
ah-huh so we are gonna have some extra
storage above these hoppers as well
let's get these in and this is what we
connect our item filters to which we
will set up in just a second just give
me a second
I'm almost done okay and just like right
into the chest like this that went into
the chest right you know any little
mistake I make with this is gonna be a
nightmare to define probably when I'm
all done I'll be like what did I do
wrong it and then I'll find out oh one
of
offers is facing the wrong direction or
something stupid um yay I'm blanking a
little bit right now I think I had
blocks next to these like that yeah I
must have and then we use comparators
and then we do the other hoppers going
into those and then then I think I had
those going into a block and this is
your classic item filter I guess I don't
have nearly enough space hollowed out
here oops
I thought I did hey let's get some light
get the light in here alright so I think
then we go down one and then another
step down this is your classic filter
I'm sure you're familiar with it if you
do redstone stuff like this um although
it might be easier if we do put the
repeater in first I will optimize how to
build this later I'm sure after doing it
a few dozen times I'm sure I'll figure
it out the best way they're supposed to
be repeaters here though I know and then
let's put our blocks back and redstone
dust all over here so when the the
signal travels two blocks it powers the
repeaters and then those go two blocks
here and then torches and I was worried
no I did make a mistake darn it see a
lot of stuff I haven't figured out
totally but what's gonna happen here is
it's gonna power the piston below darn
it so I gotta move all that
I was so careful it's hard to be
compacting with your space because like
torches can power a lot of stuff you
don't want it to and I just found out I
have to change it a little bit yet but
then there was supposed to be packed ice
above here I'm not sure can I open the
chest oh I can't darn it another flaw
that is using regular ice before that's
what happens when you change things last
minute now what do i do do i teep teep
at normal ice and just be really careful
with the torches or what I'm not sure
now I think that's what I'll probably
have to do uh-huh
anyway looks like there's a few changes
that need to be made but anyway that's
the general gist of the whole thing I
basically just have to repeat this
pattern all the way down and like 15
more times that's going to be the bulk
of the work and where the majority of
the resources go but what we did we have
the lower item stream here this is to
retrieve items out of the storage room
to get them to us then we have this
other ice stream this is to put items
into the storage room to automatically
sort them and to do that we use this
filter thing this allows us to choose
what items go into what chests so for
example if I did this the signal is
going to go over two blocks for a little
bit there and now it's only one block
and this is all the items that get stuck
in there so if an item tries to go over
top this hopper that doesn't belong just
bounces off and keeps going down the
stream but if you throw stone in it'll
accept that
aha and that goes into the dropper below
into storage I'm going to be using the
trick the zip crowd used they aligned
items against an enderchest and I think
that allows it to pass both on the ice
here and on the hopper so it gets the
speed boost from the ice I can still get
picked up from the hopper I believe is
the way that works and one other thing
this these trapped chests here actually
activates the droppers below so if I
want to come into the storage room and
get items out manually I have to take it
from the dropper not from these these
all the items from these chests will
flow down though into here otherwise
they'll get shot into the item stream
but anyway that that's about it let's go
do something else and I'll work on this
more later and fix the interference we
have and yeah now there's something I've
been meaning to bring up with you guys
for a little while here I want your
feedback on it um but this nether hub we
have here I know it you know it's it's
not very good is it
no it like I built this a long time ago
still doesn't have a ceiling in the main
room it's a sandstone and purple wool
that was the theme I went with these
don't work anymore
I built this tunnel thing a long time
ago too and it's pretty plain in my
opinion as problems with zombie Pigman
spawning on the tracks and all in all I
think this area needs a total redo so if
I'm wrong correct me but otherwise I we
need to pick a style of what to redo it
like I was considering maybe doing it
using this new prismarine stuff like in
this type of style with another brick
dyer writes the sea lanterns or maybe
doing it like I did my nether tunnel on
the minecraft server last map with the
cyan clay stained glass
futuristic look but if you have ideas as
well don't be afraid to suggest them I'm
want to do in nature look though I don't
think because I tend to do that a lot we
want variety so just thought I'd bring
it up let me know I think it would be
good to do a overhaul though and really
we haven't built much here so it
wouldn't be too tough to do that's my
horse he's got the moves listen to these
sounds just amazing uh why are we here
why are we here
well very good I'm proud of you keep
that it I've been having people asking
me about the horse project here and I
wanted to address it so how have we made
any improvements the answer is no I hate
to admit it but I haven't really been
here much because it's become very
difficult to get a better horse now but
also our setup here is really
inefficient I have to like come to this
village so I have to go out of my way
like even if I'm at the Nexus there it's
it's quite a walk to get here then I got
to find the golden carrots and I got to
breed them and then the baby ends up in
one of these little fenced areas and I
have to take all the other horses out
because he's mixed in with them and then
I got to feed them to grow them up I
gotta find a saddle then I gotta take
them over to the jumping thing there to
test them out then I got to bring them
back and get all the horses back in and
oh my goodness that is why there has not
been much progress so we're gonna make
things more efficient we're gonna move
the horses like two of the best ones
anyway not all of them Fisher just two
of them to buy the man teeth so that
they're nearby to an area where I'm
usually at and I'll set up some golden
carrots right by them and just try to
make it a little easier yeah so I think
something like this would be pretty good
this is just outside the man cave
so I'll be around here a lot and I got
some dispensers set up with golden
carrots hit the button we get to got
saddles in here snow slabs if I want to
change the jump height checker singer
thingamajigger I don't know and do this
the ones that haven't been tested won't
have a saddle I think is the way I'll do
it so I'll just leave them be I'll let
them grow up and when we get like 10 to
20 in here that's what I'll try I'll try
them out because right now very rare
that it's an actual improvement so I'm
guessing it's not worth checking every
single one right away
all right guys so a little bit of a
shorter episode today unfortunately it's
4 a.m. did not have much time to record
today and now it's super late so I got
to go to bed here losing my voice but
let's get to the comments it says Ito
who is your favorite character in Super
Smash Brothers I always do that but I
say Brothers Bros Brawl I'm going to say
in melee first because I played melee
first I didn't play the n64 one though I
played as Foxx in melee and later I
found out that is a top-tier character
actually so I guess I chose wisely in
brawl I play as meta Knights mostly I
like the quick agile characters even
though they don't do much damage in like
a one verse one situation I just find
them a little easier um although I tend
to do badly when there's four people
playing because they just throw around
these big punches and it's hard to like
stay alive anyway second question
ESO you seem to be very good at maths
although part of that thought maybe
because I'm terrible at math oh oh all
this got me wondering look what kind of
student were you in school did you get
higher grades and other students
what were your worst subjects and what
we're
your best I'm guessing you were very
good at computer things anyways keep up
all the awesome videos I love every
single one of them every single one
reading comprehension not high on my
list so I never actually took a computer
course I wanted to but never really saw
one that look good
worst subject was math that was like
there were times when I was getting
sixties in math like it was pretty bad
all my other subjects I did can a 70 80
s sometimes 90s I would say best subject
was the sciences I liked biology I liked
chemistry although they were very
difficult subjects I felt I felt they
were my better one so I guess although I
probably got a higher mark in like
social studies that type of stuff
English is probably my second worst um
yeah just because I hate writing um yeah
I did okay at school I guess the big
thing that I always failed on was the
tests like I would always be the last
one writing just struggling to get
through it and usually that's where I
would lose most of my mark I don't know
why I'm so bad at writing tests but it's
just one of those skills I never learns
um I'm better at like problem-solving
and like logical thinking type of stuff
which I don't know if that's really
something you're graded on in school all
that well I don't know that's sort of
where I excel in thinking stuff I guess
I'm quite the woodsman - mm-hmm all
right so on that terrible note it's
again it's 4:00 a.m. so that's probably
why I can't speak too well right now I'm
going to end this episode thank you for
watching guys I will see you again in
the next one take care have a good day
bye bye
you