[Music]
well hello again everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode of our
minecraft series here how you doing
welcome back to the blaze farm so last
episode guys we worked on this dual
blaze farm
we redid a couple things like we got rid
of the conveyor system down there
and replaced it with a slime block
launching system so they get
shot up like that but it has a couple
problems as you can see
so if they if they pathfind towards me
if they see me
they get that flame on them and then
they start
trying to get me and it it messes them
up because they're supposed to land in
that
that tube in the middle there right um
so we got a few things to fix on this
mainly i think we're just gonna try
build some glass tunnels for them to go
through
that will block their view of us um
whoa and we might need to do other a few
other things to fix this
up but yeah to begin with we need glass
so let's go to oh oh
no
i lived i was gonna try to do a
transition thing but now i
i don't have enough life to do it
wait a second it's gotta heal up a
little bit okay we're gonna no no no
yeah so we are totally out of sand and
glass in our world guys we're just gonna
farm up a little bit of it here at the
desert
and then we're gonna make some glass
tunnels at the blaze farm to see if that
will fix
most of the trouble we're having there
um i wanted to tell you guys something
too if you're wondering what's up with
the modded minecraft
series i am having a couple technical
difficulties with that
i decided to try update a bunch of the
mods right i do that from time to time
occasionally i have some trouble with it
but
usually i've been able to fix it this
time though
oh it's it's been a disaster
i i've downloaded like 10 different
versions of forge by now and i
i spent three hours on it today just
trying to find some version of forge and
the mods that will work together i just
can't get it to launch
and trying different versions because
sometimes the mods kind of depend on
each other
sometimes like one one version of a mod
will work with one version but not
another version so you gotta find what
works with what
and there's no like site on the internet
that tells you
you know what what is compatible and
what isn't so use
it's all trial and error and it takes
like three minutes to launch
modded minecraft every time you you want
to and then it just crashes and oh it's
just
frustrating so i i gave up on that today
and just decided to do a vanilla
episode instead i'm gonna try just
downgrade everything get it back to the
way it was and hopefully
we can get the modded series back but
for right now it's just not working at
all
all right anyways let's let's head back
to the blaze farm
okay so we're just about to finish up
building a glass wall here
and the blazes are gonna be behind it
and we'll see if this makes things
better here
all right just a couple more blocks
there and there good that should do it
so we're going to turn this on
okay turn it on so that's all covered by
glass there
and all on the sides as well so they
should hopefully not see us at all now
oh here comes another one oh he got
stuck
is it because he ran into that pigment
okay those guys are going in good good
just watching it for any any errors that
happen so the pigmen
getting in the way was one already got
to make sure no other mobs can get into
our tunnels here
oh there was another air
that's a problem why did he get stuck
here
okay okay this is kind of bad
okay i'll tell you what guys i don't
want to lie to you i am having trouble
with this
this is a disaster i've been tinkering
with it off camera for a few hours here
uh i sort of fixed most the problems
that
that were happening from there and in
there but
i'm still having huge issues with them
not falling in that little one
one block wide gap there and there's a
behavior with blazes i didn't realize
when i started building this
something new that has changed in the
game
let's see if i can make it happen here
it seems whenever you damage these guys
uh they sort of all attack you as a
group then like they gang up on you
not just the one you attack but all of
them
let's see if we can trigger it
now it didn't happen there maybe it's
when they successfully hit you i don't
know
they'll all shoot at once though when it
happens
no and like even the guys in here will
try to attack me even though they can't
see me
um i'm not sure how it triggers exactly
[Music]
oh there we go i think it just happened
they all fire at once when it happens
now these guys are mad
in there they shouldn't be able to see
me
oh it's when they hit each other that's
what it is because now they're trying to
attack each other
oh if that happens though they all just
start floating out
all over the place and it's a huge mess
uh might uh might need to think about
this a bit
aha okay everybody so here's the deal i
decided
we need a new plan what we had there
wasn't really working out too well uh
for one thing i didn't like the way it
was looking like we had blocks
sporadically placed
all over the place we had uh slime
blocks that were green
and like ice that was blue it kind of
had clashing colors and it just looked
bad
and it was very finity it wasn't
functioning well either
so i decided we need a new method here
so i went with the minecart system
instead
and already does doesn't this look a lot
cooler i decided to do the
purper blocks and sandstone that a lot
of people have been doing
i think it looks pretty cool here um
so yeah let's let's see this new system
in action
here if we can it's not totally done yet
uh there's a couple problems with it
still but it's working a lot better than
that slime block thing that's for sure
so first thing that happens
uh they fall down here in front of this
dispenser
eventually there they come when they
fall through there they activate a
tripwire
and then that activates the the
dispenser here
right and they get sent off on their
merry way
up to the top there to the drop off
point in the middle
and then they fall down into our killing
chamber which is where we want them
uh this dispenser setup though is a
little bit special
because if we had for example two blazes
fall down
we would have an instant problem because
one would get stuck in the trip wire and
this wouldn't activate again
so instead we have a clock that runs
here whenever there's something in the
tripwire
this disables the lock on it and then
the clock is free to run
and it keeps running until there's no
more blazes in the tripwire area so it
doesn't get
jammed up if there's more than one
there's a problem here we gotta fix yet
though
see how they're building up because the
old system had a clock that would clear
them and i removed all that now
all right so they go up here up this
this rail line to the middle
and then there's a little bit of a blaze
clearing mechanism here
i had to finish with this a lot i got to
tell you guys one thing do not
use activator rails they are a nightmare
i was trying to eject them with an
activator rail at first
and after i pulled out a few hairs i
decided just to switch to a cactus to
break the minecart
and then we got hoppers there and there
to pick up the minecarts
after they break and then the blazes
gets ejected
in front of that piston and then that
one push pushes them over to the side
and they fall down the middle
and that happens on both sides
the most part it works pretty good
there's just the odd problem
such as that i don't know why that just
happened
um eventually like if minecarts jam into
that one it seems to
to fix the problems somewhat
but we might have a few jams in the
system still
[Music]
funny funny enough the right side seems
to always be the one that has problems
before it was the left side uh anyways
they fall down there
let's see if we can uh go
up there we'll just turn this blaze farm
off for a second
it is very dangerous here in the nether
these guys can kill you in like two
shots
oh okay wait for him i filled up
oh he stopped right by me
how do you do that i filled up that
tunnel with glass too so there's
hopefully no chance of anything spawning
in there and getting in the way
um okay they're bouncing around there
oh okay
i'm trying to do this without cutting
but we might need to just cut here and
let me clear them
it's a real pain whenever this happens
there's one down
whoa i just want to show you guys what's
what's built up here i just broke some
redstone
oh and they attacked each other no
what did that do are they flying all
over the place
yeah they are look at this if they ever
hit each other it's just this disaster
they go crazy
okay i'm gonna have to leave and come
back and let them despawn one second
yeah so i'll just show you guys what's
up at the top here with uh the shut off
for right now
so at the top here this isn't finished
this tunnel should be enclosed with
glass as well so
nothing will run on the track and get in
the way like no zombie pigman
um they come up here though this is like
a fail-safe method as well
instead of having a a curve junction
here
i have it just going back into a block
that way if for some reason the minecart
tries to reverse it doesn't go all the
way back down here and gets stuck in
this
uh glass tunnel area it'll just bounce
around at the top here
uh goes over a detector rail this
triggers this piston first
after seven delay and then after nine
delay
it triggers this one so they go left and
then right and the blaze falls down that
little
that little hole there one of the things
i didn't really
realize at first that was giving me a
lot of trouble is
don't put anything
like in the third block blazes are only
two blocks tall but if you put something
in this third block area
um what happens is like as they eject
from the minecart they don't eject on
the ground level they're a little bit in
the air
and if if you have blocks
like up here they'll be inside those
blocks for a brief moment before they
they fall down so if the piston tries to
move them
when they're in those blocks like when
their heads just grazing them
uh the piston can't move them so i had a
little bit of trouble getting these
pistons to actually
move them where i want until i got rid
of the the ones i had up here
all right yeah the minecart though it
runs into this hopper
or into the cactus and then falls into
the hopper
and then i have a pickup system to grab
all the spare mine carts they go into
here
and a storage minecart comes by if
there's
anything in these hoppers
it shuts off that power rail there until
the minecart is fully loaded or until
this hopper is fully empty i should say
then it'll take off again
another design choice i decided to make
here is i made each of these pickup
systems separate instead of combining
them together i
i kept the side separate that way uh i
don't have to worry about issues like
with one side getting all the mine carts
and one side having none it's just
each side has a certain amount and it
stays that way
but then the minecarts storage minecart
comes down here
and unloads the minecarts it picks up
into the dispenser again so it does a
full loop
and since i put another rack in there
that's where it is so i
only got five in each side i think
that's enough
though uh-huh and
let's see what else so
gotta do a few changes around here that
when this used to run on a clock
it would activate this every so often
now we have no way of triggering this
maybe what i'll do is just
hook it up to this clock see if that
does anything to help speed up the blaze
farm because right now we have a lot of
blazes getting stuck at the bottom here
and no way of clearing it because i
can't put pressure plates this low in
the system
all right just run it up like that maybe
see if that does anything to help it out
um for some reason that one blaze got
stuck up at the cactus here
we saw before i don't know what caused
that or how to fix it
maybe i could try adding more power
rails
like one here here and here
all right very cool so i've done some
more changes guys i
redid a lot of the the stuff up there
because it wasn't quite working
i got rid of the regular pistons i use
sticky pistons now with a glass block
attached
and they all kind of fire together now
you see that so it just smooshes them
into the middle there
they're doing this thing now though
where they're resisting the cactus you
see that like
they would go up to it and then they
like bounce off of it
instead of actually having the minecart
break
which is a bit of an issue this is going
to trigger soon got to really watch this
crusher system i'm trying to get it
working perfect
okay so it automatically triggers on
itself when there's 41 blazes
that signal gets to five one of them
just died two of them just died three
oh so that happens because they take a
little bit of damage from this uh blaze
cone thing
it's not quite perfect but you'll notice
one thing important here even though we
lost a few blazes from that
uh and the signal went down to four we
still have this
block preventing the full health guys
from mixing in with
the low health guys so it's still
separating them even though we lost a
few
and now we should try this out
uh yeah so one of my concerns here
is the xp orbs landing on the iron
pressure plate
might actually trigger it again
which kind of looked like it happened
there i don't think there was enough
lasers to do it
i guess let's kill these guys
okay it's not supposed to release that
until i pick up the xp
which it didn't happen the first time
there so i might need to fix a few
things
this time it waited for me to pick up
the xp before i let the other ones down
so that's good
so we're getting close guys this is
almost working ideally
um then once we get it working perfect
we gotta
sort of give this area a nice little
redo
try to party it up if we can with these
nice purple blocks
let's see if we do something like that
i'm thinking we leave this visible up
there right you have like a
the yellow around it and then a ring of
purple
and then maybe we'll do similar to what
we did with the tracks where we have
yellow in the middle purple on the
outside
let's do that behind here where we have
the yellow
and then purple
oops oh i don't want them to see me i
hate it when they go out of control
because then i gotta
reset them all
all right good none they're really
spawning right now because we're too far
away
gotta be very careful with this pick
okay good good purple line down here
i'm not so sure about the placement oops
of the lights here either
i want to have them because it's nice to
see how close is to uh being full
like these lights here i'm not sure if i
like them or not
oh yeah i like that with the purple
that's cool um
maybe if we changed it up a bit got rid
of some of the yellow like if we change
this
to the purper half slabs might look good
also i was considering maybe changing
out some of the sandstone with purple
blocks as well just to mix it up a bit
maybe get rid of the old glass and use
the new
stain colored glass
well i got some more stuff done on this
guys we're gonna watch it again to see
if i got the crusher working this time i
added a bit of a delay on it so
hopefully
it waits for us to pick up the xp before
it lets the next batch down this time
i've i've done some work on the design
as well so we got purper blocks on the
ground here
got rid of the old glass with the gray
stained glass here
and did it on the sides as well i think
i like that more right
i threw down some stairs and slabs as
well in the corners so it's a little bit
more rounded looking
instead of a square because we didn't
have upside down stairs when i
built this originally decided to try and
add that in
and i ripped out that room up there
hoping it would
fix the issue where they they don't want
to run into the cactus but
it didn't it so yeah
and it kind of opened up the area a
little bit too but we're going to have
to
add a different roof into here i want to
polish up this area
this time instead of just leaving it all
netherrack like we did originally
never really did finish this area the
first time
and i didn't like that i don't like
netherrack we gotta make it look good
right so possibly as a background color
i'm going to do
cyan clay possibly i'm not sure though
how would that work is there anything
important over there i wonder
i'm scared to break stuff like i want to
break this block
that was a mistake no
darn it now i can't see this either okay
one sec
i messed it all up
okay here we go come on okay pressure
activated
gotta make sure this thing works
properly it's the last thing to get
working
uh so that looks pretty good that was
fine
so it's supposed to wait for us to pick
up the xp
before it lets down the next load right
oh
no didn't work
okay well i think what's happening is i
throw the splash potion it kills all the
blazes right and then
the iron pressure plates able to pop up
because there's no entities on it for
that brief moment
before the xp orbs are able to land on
it again so i've added in like a
threshold
room for air sort of thing here so it
weights
seconds as long as the xp
orbs land on that pressure plate within
that time
i think it will work this time we'll try
it out so we'll see what happens
how close is this to activating
we are at one okay i'm gonna wait a
little bit for them to build up
okay it's going it's going come on it's
gotta work this time
i just want it to work so badly let's go
get a splash potion real quick
i should make it auto eject a splash
potion too so we just pick it up and
throw it
okay no
it's still messed up come on maybe it
needs to
wait a little bit longer i don't know
i don't know it's it's giving us trouble
though
so it turns out there was a repeater
missing last time so we'll try it again
that kind of matters
all right come on the last thing
if we get this working it's working you
know
no i let him down again i don't know i
don't know what i'm doing
all right well i guess we'll finish this
up another time we got a few things left
to do here i want to build a special
enchanting station for this
and maybe a potion brewing system i have
an idea for one
that works in the nether which would be
a pretty fun project
also going to do some more netherrack
removal
i think i do like the cyan clay for it
let's try to figure out how to finish up
the ceiling here maybe we'll do it like
this
and have it go all the way down
let's fill this in open my out i'm out
okay something like
that uh needs a bit of work
another thing the the proper way of
entering here
instead of going through that nether
fortress maybe what we'll do
is build a tunnel down this way and have
it connect to that other tunnel we have
got to be careful we don't fall off here
this should open up to that area
if we go far enough
i think maybe upwards okay we gotta go
up a little bit
yeah there's the tunnel so we gotta try
connect to that somehow
from here that way we'll have a proper
way of getting to it as well
all right so we're going to finish up
today by trying out the coarse fruit
farm again
i'm just harvesting all the seeds i
don't think it was quite
fully done growing now that i started
so we might not get as many seeds as we
should here but
we'll just make sure the the water
system works and everything so here we
go
bam
oh it's happening this is really laggy
it's like oh man it's not working
all right so everything's flowing down
here the idea is everything
should make it to the bottom before the
water shuts off
so it's on a timer right now and also we
got to make sure
everything gets picked up by those
hoppers
okay that was the last of the items and
the water's shutting off now that's good
that looks like it worked out okay yeah
let's check if there's anything
on these hoppers or if it picked
everything up
looks like you got everything okay so
these should be filled up with stuff
what about this one here yeah every
single hopper is
full
aha oh except for that one
okay so there was a little bit of space
left if uh
if there was a bit more coarse fruit or
stuff it would have been fine
very good so that did exactly what i
wanted to do so i'm happy to see that
let's grab these um so let's get on to
the comment for today it says i kind of
wish dinner bone would introduce seasons
into minecraft so the leaves change
color slash disappeared slash appeared
but i know that would be super difficult
yeah seasons would add a lot more
variety to the game that's for sure
especially in survival minecraft it
would be nice but one thing
i think maybe the reason they haven't
done that besides it being a big
job to introduce it is because
a lot of people play this game in
creative mode they just like to build
things
that look good you know and it might not
work out so well for them if uh
the thing they build is constantly
changing as a seasons update you know
like they'll build something and then
they look at it later and it's covered
in snow it doesn't quite work out
perfectly uh i would think like even in
terra firma craft for example it looks
that has seasons like it'll snow and
then the snow will disappear and
it leaves change color and all that if
uh if you're trying to build something
it looks
way different in the winter time and
if you just want to try build stuff that
looks good and you don't really care
about the seasons it would be annoying
and they can't just add an option to
disable it or that kind of stuff because
it just makes a lot more work for them
so i think that's the reasoning behind
not doing it
but it would uh would be good in some
situations for sure
anyways let's uh let's call it here for
today guys i hope you enjoyed the
episode if you have ideas for the blaze
farm please let me know in the comments
and i will see you again in the next one
all right take care thanks for watching
bye bye
[Music]