so how's it going everybody this is Ito
and welcome back I checked out the
comments on last episode I made two
mistakes with this build we did last
time and if we're lucky we're not too
late
let's find out first mistake I put wood
by lava so there is a chance things I've
burnt down or started to burn down yep
so we had some wood overtop these
hoppers and that's a big no-no I don't
know why I did that all right
ah the other thing a lot of you guys
keep telling me is putting blocks over
top of hoppers doesn't actually do
anything like it doesn't stop the
hoppers from checking if there's any
items to pick up so I've mostly been
doing it just to cheap items from
dropping into the hoppers but just the
common thing to do is to put furnaces
above the hoppers to help prevent leg
now this is kind of a I don't know
people have actually tested this I'm
very curious because by doing this we're
making it so the hoppers don't have to
check if there's items so that should
reduce lag but we're also adding another
tile entity the the furnace here which
causes a little bit of lag so is it
actually reducing the leg overall I have
no idea but I'm gonna do it all right
where did that would end up I just would
win it would have went into the garbage
so it should be gone
the other mistake I made though is I
never put in the filler block so this is
what I did I just put like one not one
item in these last four slots and the
item filters no no no no no you're
supposed to put some other type of block
something other than what you're trying
to filter out and a couple of you guys
got caught that so thank you it's going
to fix that here at whoops
because otherwise if the hopper totally
fills that like with raw fish here
it's gonna mess it all up all right you
know what guys I don't want to just keep
wandering I want to figure this out for
myself no the true answer here so I
decide let's hop into creative world is
putting furnaces over top of hoppers a
good idea or not let's see what it does
to our tick rates so what I've done I
placed down 150 by 150 thing of hoppers
here in a super flat world with nothing
but sandstone all right so that's 20
2500 hoppers total that has a lot of
hoppers what we do is we press shift and
f3 that brings up this little pie chart
here and that purple on the pie chart is
our tick rate our current tick rate as a
percentage of what's what's taking the
longest to process here what we're going
to do is look up at the sky I turn the
clouds off and everything so nothing
should be rendered right now that we're
looking up so it should give us a very
consistent reading on what our actual
tick rate is hopefully and I got nothing
going around going on on the background
on my computer really that I know of so
that won't influence it either so it
seems to have stabilized at about twenty
point five twenty point six percent is
our current tick rate now what we're
gonna do is go to the corner here oh and
we're gonna put put furnaces over top
all these hoppers and see if that raises
or decreases our tick rate it should
have some effect though for sure all
right so what we got to do 'is do a fill
command at our current position and 150
and 150 out from here
minecraft furnace good it's going to be
a giant leg spike while it does this
awesome yeah I did that right good so we
got a furnace over top every single
hopper and I'm actually going to reload
the world i reloaded it after replacing
the hoppers too just so we have a
consistent result here okay it's just
about got the whole world loaded here
you'll notice like the the chunks with
the hoppers and the furnaces in they
loaded a lot slower than those sandstone
ones out there so there
wait a bit more intensive but yeah we
got the world loaded all around us same
thing nothing's really changed here
we're going to look at the sky and just
see the difference in the tick rate as
it looks right now it seems quite a bit
higher doesn't it
we're at 38 39 % and it's pretty much
evened out it's not changing really
right now so 39% from 20.5% so putting
furnaces over top of opera seems like a
bad idea to me it seems to have made it
almost twice as worse tick rate on the
server so yeah don't do it
I don't think and now we know better
alright guys so let's get to it here we
started this armory project last episode
what we're trying to do first off is to
make an armor stand switching machine
sort of thing here
so basically armor stands are going to
fall down land over here and then we can
switch between them by pushing a button
or something is is the plant for this
thing um so let's go back up get out of
the way go back up okay
very first thing we got to do here is
set up like a PEZ dispenser minecart
thing and check this out I found a spot
in the man cave here one of the most
difficult things is finding space for
stuff but behind this little garden
thing I dug down and it seems like we
could maybe have a bit of vertical space
here we go just a couple more blocks
forward though we're gonna run into
Wilson Wilson is very close he's just
over there so there's maybe I don't even
know how thick this wall is it's
probably only two or three blocks thick
then right let's just mine this to
figure it out because I'd like to know
how much space we got free yeah he's
right over there and oh and this is
going to be chopped away - oh that's
overhang right there yeah we don't have
a lot of free space that is for sure but
we'll try to sneak in a minecart thing
right over here maybe
alright so the plan is let's go this way
a little bit more and maybe right in
this spot we'll put down our sticky
piston and our slab so the minecarts are
going to stack up on top of here
I don't like activator rails how did
that not push it down there I took I
don't know make no sense man a date that
date no make no sense okay I think I got
to figure it out here I just have to add
an extra rail between the curves section
here and activate a rail because there's
this issue in the game it's kind of
annoying whenever you like go around a
corner with a minecart
like it when it's on the curved section
of the track it also activates the one
in front of it so activated rails and
detector rails get triggered a little
sooner than you want a lot of the times
so ya just need an extra spacing so yeah
check it out basically got like a little
thing here track to bring the minecarts
up to the top of the PEZ dispenser
it goes up and then they fall down on
top of the stack it's just a little 2x4
windy rail thing here so far and then
they drop down there alright and when we
press the button here better work this
time good I think we can get rid of
these two now ah and armorstand falls
down there minecart falls down here
okay let's fall down here so basically
our armored stand oh it's not really
going to face the right way though now
is it
I never been thought of that it's like
facing sideways we want it facing us
hello never even considered that okay
that's gonna be a pain to fix but
basically when we go to switches
armorstand with the next one
what we got to do is then bring this
empty minecart by to pick it up picks it
up and then it's got to bring it to the
top of the PEZ dispenser stack and
that's our complete cycle so I got to
connect this to that open-ended track we
have up there all right check it out
guys so we got our armor stand here and
we're going to address it I'll put a
helmet on this one press the button down
comes next one and you might have saw
that minecart on the right there falling
down so it gets into position we give
our pants to this one and I really like
the effect like this is the best part of
any redstone thing like when you have an
idea a lot of times there's a lot of
details I can get in the way of your
idea actually coming out the way you
want it to but this is exactly what I
had in mind you know I was able to pull
it off so I'm very very happy with this
build this is exactly what I wanted and
it works and we can see it working now
it's great so yeah we can cycle through
our different armor collections or
whatever kind of a cool effect I liked
it one thing I got to watch for is I
can't press the button before the
minecart actually lands there if I press
it as quick as possible I could
potentially mess it up you see how it
takes micro a little bit of time to fall
down the reason for that is just because
we got a little bit of a jumble with our
track here I need to shorten this track
if possible but ideally I want this PEZ
dispenser set up like over here we can't
do that because of the our man cave
getting in the way so I had to put it
over here made the track longer which
makes it a little longer to reset than I
would like but other than that it's
pretty much perfect I could add some
safety mechanism but I can just try to
remember not to press it to play for too
oh yeah and I'll just show you guys how
I finish this up as well in case you
want to build something similar to this
yourself I was worried about the
armorstand rotation which way it was
facing turns out it all depends on which
way you place it at the start so if I
place it that way it's going to be
facing us if I place it this way it's
going to be always beside ways getting
ejected from the minecart doesn't
actually rotate it like I thought was
happening so that's good that was a
simple fix yeah so got the button here
basically that just goes down to this
block right this block has a torch on it
so this is these Pistons are extended by
defaults it also goes off to our power
rail here which is currently unpowered
so when we press the button makes
minecart move goes underneath the
armorstand or gets dropped here and goes
up to our Pez dispensers so I added this
line in here this goes up and kind of
connects that thing we built earlier we
do have room for a lot more minecarts
here too if we want to add more and
let's see I added in a wire here to
connect to this piston from the button
down below that is just over yeah so
from from this wire here goes through
this block over here and then up up to
that that piston there and that's pretty
much all there is to it
so we can fill this in nicely all the
way pretty sure
good I want my stuff back you mean my my
helmet all right now we got to finish up
the looks this thing okay I think this
is the shape we're gonna go for guys I
like how this looks
it's symmetrically pleasing and yeah so
this is an armory so we want to be able
to store our armor our our armor our
armor I have a hard time saying like our
and our you know like our and our close
together I always say like our and are
kind of the same thing it just happened
there anyways so it's for armor it's
also for tools though so what we're
going to do we have these six chests
probably do some item frame things we
got our tools here so we do like sword
maybe over here swords I them as well so
it actually shows the nametag above and
kind of see it
I got bows we got fishing rods let's put
the fishing rods opposite of the bows
over there and then pick pick axe and
shovel I usually group the pick and the
shovel together more so so let's do it
like that axe is kind of a weapon so
we'll put it on the right side weapons
on the right tools on the left I liked
it
alright so this is where I'm going to
put all my enchanted tools and enchanted
armor alright guys so we go down the
stairs here turn to our left and buh buh
buh BAM so try the green clay thing out
here what do you guys think of this do
you like it - do you not like it
yes no maybe I'm on the maybe fence with
this bill that it's like it's okay it's
passable I fall down again uh uh I'm not
in love with it you know there's
something about it it's not it's not
there it looks very convoluted like
there's too much stuff going on on this
clean clay surface I think that's a
mistake we could either switch over to
wood what happened there
I don't really want to use wood I don't
know why I just we use wood all
throughout the man cave here I'm trying
to change it up a little bit you know
maybe we'll try red clay still has that
smooth surface problem but it might look
better and I also gathered together our
tools we have a few bows quite a few
swords most of them are garbage Joe
likes mite swords arthropod swords I
don't know not that many axes laying
around not many shovels laying around
but a whole ton of picks got a little
carried away with these so I tried doing
this double double chests little thing
here where we put spruce stairs over top
problem is we can't do it over there
because we got the rails in the back so
I think maybe that was a mistake so
we're gonna switch it back I think and
also it makes it look a little bit more
at chaotic which I don't I don't want
because it already looks too crazy
mm-hmm okay well between the red and the
I thought I just heard a creeper between
the red and the green I definitely like
the red a lot more I don't know about
you guys
also since we used red here in here it
makes more sense for sure so I'm gonna
leave at that for today we'll go do
something else now all right so lately
guys I've been spending a lot of time in
our nether hub here doing various things
like The Guardian firm stuff and also
I've been building these tunnels these
ice tunnels recently I just added in
these lights up here because it was
really dark without them I think that's
a good addition as well I usually I
build these like when I want to watch
what I want to watch TV or something you
know I'm one of those type of people
that just can't watch TV and do nothing
I have to do something else so usually I
play like Minecraft in the background
and I will
I will do stuff like this because it's
one of those things you don't really
have to think about you just got to do
it and it's like a nice little casual
thing to do so I've been building the
tunnels and stuff lately though spending
a lot of time in here and this has
caught my attention again we built this
like ice pet or this packed ice thing
here nobody's ever liked it right but I
didn't know what to do with it so
recently I had the idea of using maybe
purple glass we're gonna try out purple
glass here and just see what that looks
like I think it'll fit a little bit
better than the packed ice and maybe
above it we'll try put see lanterns or
some some type of lighting if we can
make that work might mix in some purple
blocks with this as well we will see
yeah I've been watching a Fresh Prince
of Bel Air though I restarted watching
that I haven't seen that show in like
ten years and it is awesome really
enjoying it um I I was thinking about
this too like every episode we do the
comment of the day every now and then I
like to ask you guys questions and my
question for you today is what are your
top 5 favorite sitcoms of all time let
me know in the comments I thought about
it for me first place I think I have to
say Seinfeld really like Seinfeld but
it's a close very close game with a
theme what's the word contender there's
there's a word very close contender with
Arrested Development I almost want to
put that one first because that shows
just so good but Seinfeld's first
wrested development second not the
office offices third and fourth place I
would say Malcolm in the Middle
he's a really good show too and then
fifth place I'm not so sure I think I
would say either King of Queens mostly
because of Arthur um King of Queens
maybe Fresh Prince of bel-air I'm really
starting to like that show they're not
starting but like really getting into it
again and like the first few seasons of
friends were pretty
good - hey you walked right in front of
me this guy yeah so here we go guys that
is what it looks like now I think that
looks a lot better I like it a lot more
suits the area much better and I did try
putting sea lanterns throughout the
whole thing like behind the glass there
but it didn't look very good I think
because uh sea lanterns have those lines
on the edges and it just makes like a
crazy checkered pattern sort of thing so
I just put a couple of them on the
outside to light it up and the rest of
that is purpur blocks now and I think
that's how will I will keep it oh yeah
check it out guys we finally got our
farmer villager I never since we built
that pumpkin farm I've been trying to
get one finally got one to be born here
there's like a zombie sea to kill like
ten ten villagers today got a bunch of
babies afterwards and this is our guy
unfortunately though it's 11 for one
emerald we wanted to try get eight for
one that's the best trade I think it
goes up to 1200 for one so it's not the
worst but it could be better for sure
now the problem is I don't know how to
get these guys out of here because
whenever I try to like nudge them they
just run back okay I thought that was
hollow underneath I guess not
ah right where we want him oh oh no
that's stupid villager pushed him out
okay you're so close go to school we got
them in the school okay I'm gonna block
that door so we built like a way of
getting villagers up to the surface here
it's supposed to kill them but we can
also use it to transport them hopefully
it still works a little bit further yes
okay we got him so what we got to do is
push him into the water and I think
there's air spaces throughout it so it
should not kill them and I think
I'll try some ahead of him here I
thought there was a way up to the
surface but I don't see any light right
now does it now go up to the surface oh
it does it does right up to a tree Oh
interesting
okay so the villager should get up here
any moment good pick him up in a boat oh
he got away oh man get back here
he's running away no all right we got a
corner room I think I actually have to
get out of the boat to get him okay we
got him cool good alright so if I break
the boats do you go in the next one no
not quite if I nudge you oh that works
oh that's cool so you don't even need to
use slabs and that kind of stuff to get
them up a step here you can just put the
boat at their head level and though
it'll work alright get a bridge the gap
here Bob up up up we're almost there
just a little bit further
ba-ba-ba-ba oh he's doing that thing
where he's in the corner and you can't
get him out of the corner I hate when
that happens they really need to like
make a leads work on villagers like
seriously such a pain moving these guys
even with the boats all right we got him
in we got him in awesome yes success we
got our farmer in place at the pumpkin
farm how's our stock doing just about up
to four rows that's not that impressive
actually I guess I don't spend much time
here all right let's do some trading
though so this this will be pretty nice
you take a stack of pumpkins and trade
how many am rooms we get here oh I
didn't see if 55 would be five yeah so
we had five emeralds each time if it was
eight pumpkins we
eight emeralds each time well anyways
guys it's about time to wrap up the
episode for today's so here we go the
comment of the day brings up a good a
good point here says etho you should
totally make your own resource pack
without the droppers making that
clicking noise we built the Guardian
firm last note last episode and the
clicking noise was bugging me maybe
change it to a softer sound or make it
less loud you can all you can also
change some annoying textures for
example make the lava look like actual
lav instead of molten cheese why did
they do that I still don't know it
looked better before use it to get rid
of or change small things you don't like
yes that's an interesting point like
there's a lot of things I don't like
about the vanilla textures or the
vanilla sounds most of them are pretty
good but some could be better Oh
snowballs like the Lavin for example why
did they make it more orange it used to
be more red and looked like it was
blowing a bit better but they changed it
now it's not as good but when I play
this game in this series I try to keep
in mind it's not just for me
if it was just for me I'd probably use a
texture pack or try it out at least but
it's also for you guys and the more
things I change the more difficult it is
to light understand what's happening and
also it removes a lot of the challenge
oh man that activated again removes a
lot of the challenge out of the game too
I kind of look as a challenge trying to
make things look good with the manila
textures can be a bit tricky because
like they've been released over the
years and they don't always synergize
well with each other you know and some
of the some of the blocks really need to
redo like diorite granites
andesite I think look terrible if the
texture was changed found them it would
be a huge improvement but in certain
cases you can make it look good so it's
a good challenge same with the sounds
it's a challenge trying to make things
quiet like red
stonestep sometimes you want to use
redstone to do things you can do with
pistons just so that you don't hear the
piston sounds and it has a big effect on
what I do here so I kind of want to keep
that especially if you guys try to mimic
something I want it to work for you if
it works for me
you know anyways I hope you enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and I'll see you again in the next one
take care bye bye