[Music]
these guys so angry right now I see my
donkey wandering around out here they
must have let him loose somehow I go to
put him back and then I come over here
get out of here and they trample my
wheat unbelievable so outraged right now
no I'm fine it's not a big deal so
welcome back to everyone this is ESO and
we we have special plans today I've been
planning this for a while actually we're
gonna do some exploring totally missed
them he's trying to come up to see me
that was cool he like bounced off the
wall there we're gonna do some exploring
today I I've been wanting to do this for
a while now cuz 1.7 is out I did your
exploring a few episodes that go well
he's probably 10 to 20 now once they
added the new terrain generation but I
deleted all that stuff and loaded a back
up so I still do not have any of the 1.7
features in my world here and definitely
gotta do something about that I
especially wants to find a Mesa biome
and get the two new saplings like that's
a must we need to do that for sure so
let's that's what we're gonna try to do
we're gonna go try get some of the new
stuff today we're going to just have
some fun exploring I really like
exploring in this game but I don't do it
often because it doesn't take long like
in ten minutes my world size just
increases dramatically when I'm
exploring and I try to do the world
downloads but now I don't know I I wait
I wanted to do it like do this exploring
thing after I released it so I released
the world download a few days ago and
even even though I didn't do the
exploring before had in the world
size was still
two big I think and no website seems to
be able to host it without crashing or
or anything so I don't know I tried my
best to stay within this area but it's
still not good enough so I think in the
future if I do a world downloads I'm
gonna have to cut some stuff out of my
world and just release the important
parts of it so the plan is we're gonna
go 500 blocks out in the nether here and
that'll be like 4000 blocks in the
overworld and that'll start a whole new
area for us to to check out no matter
where I go I'm gonna get the borders
from the 1.7 terrain changes so I
figured it'd be best just to go far outs
and try not to connect the the previous
generation with the new generation not
that it matters too much but mister here
that'd be best and this is the portal I
have prepared but before we go through
it there's one thing I want to do I'm
going to switch my world into amplified
mode like I talked about because it
seems it seems like a really good idea
to do that to be honest like I don't
know everything in amplified worlds this
looks so amazing and when I did explore
like a while ago there with the 1.7
changes I saw a lot of neat stuff but
nothing really outstanding like I want
to build their type of generation it was
a lot of snow biome stuff and nothing
really stood out too much so I think
amplified is definitely the way to go
and I had a lot of people asking me how
am I going to switch my world to
amplified I will try to record that now
and include an episode so hopefully
hopefully I can show you rates now so
here it is okay so this isn't normally
what I do in my LP episodes but I'm
recording my desktop right now and I'm
about to change my world into amplified
and to do that I have made a backup of
the world I have downloaded a program
called NBT explorer which allows you to
edit NBT files which is
what minecraft use to use this to save
most of its data and the one I am
concerned about this might LP world here
ethos LP the file I'm looking for is
level dot dot which saves the general
settings for your world basically
there's 24 entries in its open it up and
we see all these different data entries
the one I'm going to change is a
generator name I believe is the one I'm
looking for right now it's default you
can change it to super flat to large
biomes and I'm gonna change it to
amplified so how do we edit this I've
never used this program before but how
hard can it be
edit it take that you there we go oh oh
let's drag this over edit string so it's
a string data entry and I'm going to
enter amplified which is oops one of the
settings amplified hopefully this all
works okay generator name amplified save
its save all modified tags and we're
done so let's head back over to my LP LP
world and here we are for some reason
the last three seconds of that clip got
cut off yeah so hopefully this works I
tried to find a guide on how to do this
and was unable to locate one through
Google so this is all me hopefully I
know what I'm doing
should work I think you would think you
think there'd be tons of guys on how to
do this but come on amplified we're in a
cave darn it
the cave that y21
does that mean we're an ocean no its
River River taiga no I hate tiger it's
all I see is taiga ah man okay so this
isn't quite the amazing view of
amplified eyes hoping for when we when
we got out of there
tell you what now I'm entering a speech
you dig straight up and just
double-check make sure that works if not
I will maybe load it back up and try
something else
I think I saw a tag for world type too
so I hope I got the right one there I
looked I looked on the wiki like under
the development guide there like the
structure of the leveled on that file
and I'm pretty sure that's the tag I
needed to change holy smokes
so if there's an amplified world I might
have to dig up a couple hundred bucks to
get out of here in which case I should
probably stop recording okay I'll be
right back okay we're about y8e here and
I've reached the surface so this is it
is it an amplified world is it's an
amplified world
let's wait we're definitely on a
mountain it regardless
no that's looking pretty sweet
I think it's an amplified world ohm and
and this is why I changed cuz even a
taiga biome looks amazing ah yes this is
gonna be so cool oh let's go take a look
around so I might have a little trouble
recording this initial exploration video
I'm not sure it's a lot of work on my
computer not only does it take a lot
more processing power to render these
amplified worlds but takes a lot of
power to generate the world and to add
to that I'm recording so those are three
big whammies on my computer right now
dude it's so cool
cause it's awesome yes floating islands
I mean if your computer can handle it
why would you not do this this is how
every world in Minecraft should be I
think we were talking about
maybe doing on minecraft but I think
some people have computers that can't
handle this kind of stuff so it would be
a little problematic I think but if it
works in my single-player I definitely
want to do it it's actually a little
smoother than I thought it would be
here's the thing like my mancave you
guys don't realize it but that place has
terrible frame rates like because of all
the redstone devices and stuff it is
just brutal recording they're even worse
than here I think oh my goodness I love
its best decision ever
oh and trash no please no I think we're
good cool cool
I brought a bad just for this special
situation where it becomes nighttime oh
the keys still broke into it here's the
thing I've had this Cup this keyboard
for over 10 years I love this keyboard
and I do not want it to switch even
though it's got a broken key now oh I
love this keyboard and I don't think
they make them anymore
it's a BenQ something but the keys are
like really weird on it they don't go
they don't press down very much it's
almost like a laptop keyboard but not so
quickie I guess so here's the problem
when I look down from a high place I
don't think it's gonna generate too much
down below until I'm actually down there
so if I'm moving around a lot we're
gonna have a little bit of that I'm
still on my old computer here - is the
thing I haven't transferred over I'm
about at that point where I should I've
just been lazy about it cuz I got all my
programs installed and it's ready to go
I think now oh but just haven't made
that change yet oh so those big leg
spikes are from the generation for sure
okay and there's still gonna be flat
spots in that so it's not like like this
is Plains biome they're still going to
be
well another big leg spike from the
generation not too bad
oh this is so cool even a Plains biome
is amazing wait that might not be Plains
so oh you know it's doing it the lava
flowing I think is causing a lot of leg
yeah for sure
it's fine we'll just sit here for a
little bit enjoy the sights oh boy okay
I think it stopped okay
it's Jerry on so we got a few missions
here I brought I probably tons stuff
with us with us in fact I was going to
make a map I should do that already
let's make a map we'll plot our journey
here a little bit
does that crafting bench look weird I
never noticed that before the sides are
different this side is not the same as
that side I always thought every side
looked like that I am not very observant
apparently okay okay map time here we go
very cool and we will zoom it out so I
brought some paper just to do that
zoomed out very cool let's do it again
I think I'm gonna go all the way out
well maybe not maybe three levels that
still feel pretty big maybe I'll go one
more time here so I brought some saddles
I want try find some horses we want to
keep an eye out for places to build
possibly in the future although honestly
I think pretty much anywhere is gonna be
awesome
okay this is that's zoomed out far
enough I think now I brought silk touch
shovels for podzol if we find it and
silk touch pick so we should be good
here let's go and I'm gonna leave that
crafting bench
and this is so cool the flowers I might
take some of the two two tall ones with
me I brought my enderchest to you I'm
excited for this yep
very cool some people said don't switch
to amplified if I decide later it was a
mistake I can always switch back to so
don't worry I think the main concern
people had is it's hard to get around
and amplified which it definitely is but
I think that's part of the fun of
building bridges and all that kind of
stuff paths converting a wild terrain
world into something you've conquered
sort of thing I think there's a lot of
fun to me like by setting up rail lines
and all that stuff maybe okay excellent
how high up are we were at 140 so it can
go way higher even as the crazy thing Oh
big leg spike yeah we're loading new
stuff now again man
that is sweet I'm gonna try it stop
recording for a second just see how
quick it loads in
I've only moved like 50 blocks here just
outside of that taiga forest we have
just a regular forest here and cool
overhanging lots of waterfalls nice
little lake here pretty cool I like that
Wow
man is this another 50 bucks here just
another amazing sight so so cool
something I'm really liking about the
stew there's lots of mobs around during
the day even because there's all these
overhangs everywhere this area
especially is crazy because look at that
oh man holy smokes
hey isn't that just mines mind-blowing I
think from as far as I could tell the
caves are pretty much the same in
amplified worlds
oh yeah which over there holy smokes
ah but more snow up ahead I'm not liking
that mmm rosebush I got lilac and rose
bush now this whole episode is just me
going like oh my goodness
so beautiful whoa you little bugger I
did not expect that and that's what
makes it fun that's whether this game
needs his mom's that come out at day to
like day mom's yeah best worst idea ever
ah man look at this like it goes all the
way around there's just so many oh yeah
I just keep repeating myself but it's
this it's this really cool no puny
that's three I just say and do this
three out of the four two tall ones I
got now and my map I just wasn't working
before there's a bug in the game where
if you shift click the map out of the
crafting screen it doesn't actually do
anything so I had to drag drag drop it
out and and I got this it's a report on
bugs already though so don't worry about
reporting it
nice very nice
ah yeah I guess this area was a flower
forest I just went a little further here
so we got flowers all over the place all
up the hills Wow
oh man oh just non-stop drooling here I
haven't seen any horses yet though once
again that was the problem I had last
time I went exploring I didn't find any
horses I thought it was a glitch maybe
like I guess this isn't horse train that
was I was in the plains for very long
I'm sure we'll find some oh yeah flower
forest and amplify is very very nice I
wonder how big the thing goes bear
takedown coordinates in case I want to
come back here yeah it's it's a big
flower forest Wow and this is why I need
to stop recording yeah okay I'm gonna
stop again we got the rendering issues
again okay I found another area in the
flower forest here that has a pretty
awesome view yeah did they change they
must have changed the slow camera it
looks different it's doing something
weird it's like it's stretching the
image somehow maybe that might be my
speed potion doing it I don't know
especially I like I like over here and
there
I'm not sure why but when I saw this
area right away it reminded me of the
Goonies
you know when they find the pirate ship
in in the side of the mountain like
underground and then the walls of the
the cave open up and there's all the
waterfalls yeah very cool I really like
what the water does in amplify train
like it since it flows such a long ways
down it it hits more things on its way
and it just it it becomes more unique I
guess usually if you have a waterfall
it's it's like a one by one stream that
flows down usually and it might split a
little bit but nothing like like this
kind of stuff
turns out swamp land is pretty flat
though by the looks of it I found a
swamp here looks almost I I think it is
probably identical to normal generation
ah boof Tower is very cool and more tyka
coming up OK in a surprise there's
horses here is this is this Plains why
is there horses
this is Plains okay so they must have
come from there ah yeah is this walking
through the swamp and there is horses so
let's see I think I tamed one of them
already yet might have been this day
let's see what he's got to offer 14
hearts that's very good I'm not super
fast decent jumper not bad I don't think
it's worth coming back for him though
how about you are you amazing Oh easy
he seems like a fast guy when they take
off like that when you hop on that's
your first warning we've got 11 parts
come on
I know you're gonna be amazing horse I
can tell already stop the resisting
arrest
don't make me taser you aah
one of the horses around here died - so
I got some leather I'm gonna have to try
make a book for the comments this
episode on the bill here I need a squid
in the chicken yet and I just have you
haven't paid for already come on man
stop resisting I should have brought
some food for these guys there we go
excellent I know you're gonna be fast I
can tell already oh yeah not bad not bad
ah I think not super fast though it's
pretty good jumper oh yeah uh well maybe
not yeah what is it
I guess that's four blocks tall right
yeah so he's like three in something
okay let's keep looking not usually a
fan of tigers but I have proof of this
one very nice look over here also
amazing we got nice flat plains down
there
so there's definitely places you can
build like big structures if you really
want there's lots of flat areas oh I was
trying to aim for that the top of that
darn it I missed where are we now where
are we close
I have no idea where I am now I thought
I was down to the plains okay we are at
the plains dude I don't know I almost
think my world's running fast now does
he seem like he's moving quick to you
guys maybe not I've known like it seemed
like the Sun was moving quick and a few
other things but it could just be my
imagination
all right so still have not seen too
many of the new biomes yet just the
flowered forest is really the only new
thing I've seen and this episode is
getting long I was hoping to see a lot
more but there's just so many cool
things catching my eye hmm all right I'm
gonna look a little bit more and then
we'll probably have to end it
Oh on a squid yes and your squid ah
excellent
I just need a chicken yet so much to see
that's a little time I mean it just gets
better and better I just spotted a
village in the plains here let's go
check it out it looks like it's a pretty
decent one oh it's gonna have this
blacksmith and everything nice secluded
spot for these villagers I could live
out here that's for sure this is awesome
hey guys you you have good deals
sharpness 2 for hmm kind of a ripoff if
you were to ask me oh that's good and we
got excellent I actually need I'll take
that all right
very cool
right picked yeah so I've heard villages
didn't even why actually I've seen it
I've seen them spawning the savanna
biome so there's there's other biomes
liyan spawn into now I would love it if
they spawned on hills though but it
would probably be pretty glitchy thank
you all right well it seems I have hit
quite a bit of ocean I would explore in
here check this out though
that's the beaches for me they go way up
high on the on the mountains it's pretty
crazy
this mountains is full of holes
everywhere Swiss cheese Mountain trying
to ride my boat around it's a little
difficult it's all the glitchyness but
haven't seen any of the new biomes yeah
so we might have to go quite a ways if I
explore too much here I might just
delete some of that from my world so
it's not so big but we'll see because
I'm already I I just know something like
a thousand and six thousand we started
at like zero four thousand so I'm doing
quite a ways already more taiga have not
seen any of the hot biomes yet like the
jungle savanna deserts much like I had
trouble on the minecraft server I'm
having that trouble here too oh I
thought those a 2x2 spruce tree for a
second
hey guy hey uh yeah
check out this die guy this is so cool
nice waterfalls nice overhangs goes a
million miles into the sky I've got
wolves everywhere
I really like the ferns in these biomes
now they look pretty cool and sleet goes
quite a ways back to like this let's go
check it out real quick I can't seem to
find a chicken anywhere oh man I can't
find a chicky I need a chicken to make
my book to do the common thing and I
just can't find one anywhere it's
driving me crazy
mmm very nice Wow you go a little bit
further here and hopefully find a
chicken oh this is very good this is
very good guys this means we may
actually find whoa Mesa somewhere
because we got a deserts so warm warm
biomes probably Savannah's around here
might be a Mesa for really lucky and
jungles should form around here as well
and I saw a village out in the distance
oh and a pyramid yes I would not I
didn't think I was gonna see any
pyramids I figured they'd all be like
buried a million miles under the
mountains and another blacksmith take
that pretty cool hey get out of the wall
yeah it's not good for your health and
you just move out of there 8ball but
farmers where's the librarian librarians
are my new favorites
nope the librarian nope doesn't look
like it oh right well anyway let's go
check out the pyramid I did find my
feather so I can end the episode pretty
quick here yes I do want to take a look
at this we might do a little more
exploring next episode and then make our
way back and I'll probably do a ton of
exploring by myself just to find all the
stuff I wanted to find Boop
all right what do we got you got iron
Gold's very good I still have quite a
few ender pearls that shaken I can go a
little bit further here ah emeralds I'll
take it mm very good
Oh power three unbreaking 3 that's a
good one and breaking books are very
very nice to get and the main treasure
is under the ground
excellent I'll probably need that to get
out actually I hate throwing Gunpowder
away but sometimes you need to well as
expected just outside of the desert
biome we found a savanna biome I don't
think it's too big of one but maybe I
can't see the backside over there so I
got my tisha saplings indication wood
and we got that really need to find the
dark oak saplings yet though so we saw
quite a bit today I think we're gonna
have to end the episode here though and
I did manage to get my squid and my
chicken in my channel and we have and I
was able to make one book so here's our
comment for today hey etho do you have a
favorite team that you haven't played on
your channel if so team you be expecting
a seat if so can we be expecting a
series thanks uh well I play games here
and there that I don't put on my channel
I always try to have like one one other
game besides Minecraft at least that I
play whenever I feel like just doing
something else so of course there's
terraria which I've been playing with
ZCO and having a blast with that game
but another game I've been playing and
haven't been recording lately his
Scrolls
believe it or not smashing Scrolls turns
out it's a really good game I like it a
lot actually it's very addicting too and
I'm not just saying that because it's
Mojang I actually legitimate
legitimately like the game so that's
that's pretty cool so yeah I play
Scrolls every every so often I like to
just play a game or two and then I'll go
do something else usually and yeah so
that's my that's my current team besides
terraria so I think I think we'll leave
it for there for today I think of all
the places I I saw today flower forest
was very nice I think that was my
favorite not sure about you guys but
that was my my preference so if we were
looking for a building spot I think
that's my pick personally anyway what do
you guys think next time we'll do a
little more exploring then we'll
probably head back and oh yeah this is
hopefully I don't have any trouble with
this but I just realized when I speak in
the comment here that apparently I've
had another instance of Minecraft open
this whole time and it was me in my LP
world so if you don't know this you can
join like a single-player world more
than more than once so you can have your
same guy like in in the nether and one
in the overworld and and even have them
together and that can cause the game to
crash and I've had that happen and I've
lost a lot of what I've done so
hopefully what I've explored and all
this doesn't go away when I want to end
it here today but I think it's okay it
hasn't crashed yet and I've done a lot
so be careful
be careful you don't open the same world
twice and have two instances going
because it's not really made to handle
that I think there used to be a
protection to stop that from happening
but yeah it's definitely weird anyway
that's it for today guys thanks for
watching and I will see you again next
time bye bye
[Music]