[Music]
do you guys know what time it is
let me show you it's it's etho time it's
so stupid so I I have like all these
Easter eggs sitting around my world
alright
you know this clock it's been here
forever I didn't know I named it like I
totally forgot doing that and today I'm
going around the man team renovating
things and I saw that and it gave me a
stupid laugh uh-huh so remember when we
change texture packs here I said I
didn't like how you could see the stone
through the leaves so one thing I've
been doing here is replacing all the
stone with green terracotta so that it
looks a little bit better it's such a
subtle thing such a minor thing but we
hit red stone boys hit red stone that's
why you put red stone on stone bricks
you know everybody asks why why do I do
it so that you you don't do that but for
some reason I didn't do it there hmm
red stone there red stone there okay
just that one spot
yeah so I've been changing all this out
with the green clay so that it looks
green through the leaves you know some
minor little thing change this all out
and I guess we're gonna prepare that red
stone I think that's our nighttime song
our daytime song over there go check it
out yeah so this we broke this right so
it must have been here but that doesn't
make any sense
oh I think it was so that this red stone
doesn't point at this block cuz if it
does it messes this up uh-huh yeah so a
major renovation on the man cave today
but it's gonna be barely noticeable like
a lot of it is very subtle things like
look at this for example this has been a
dispenser forever but now in this
updates you can shear sheep
automatically by putting shears in a
dispenser so this doesn't eject them
anymore so we gotta change it cuz it's
broken
put a dropper there instead and
everything is back to normal just the
way we want it
uh-huh yeah so we'll just run through
the man cave here real quickly I'll show
you some of the subtle changes that have
occurred like for example we got a stone
cutter over here by the window now
because kind of like crafting tables and
enderchest it's just some machine we'll
probably use a lot so kind of want to
want them around every so often in your
vases I think the big thing though
remember we can't shine lighting through
Pistons anymore so we had to hide a
whole bunch of lighting through the
Manteo that's the big change it occurred
here so I got a lantern there one of the
big tricks I used is I found out you can
shine lighting through compost bins for
some reason so this glowstone wasn't
here before right
it only seems to work with composter
though like it doesn't work with the
Stonecutters you can't shine it through
like enchanting tables anymore but these
for some reason hopefully they don't
change that but remember we used to have
Pistons like all along the wood all over
the place right those are those are all
gone now I've hidden lighting in a few
other clever ways like behind paintings
and pretty much got rid of all the dark
spots I think in our man cave now added
a painting here with lighting behind and
I abuse the compost thing all Lots and
they're kind of all over the place and
even with those you can use them like
for walls and it's actually not like a
bad looking texture right so we got
three compost bins here and lighting
underneath kind of cool kind of cool
added some extra decorative things
around the place too like we got a
bamboo shoot there now and just very
minor subtle things added a lot of
lighting above here because we used to
have pistons all on the floor got rid of
all those had some bushes in here
more compost bins hiding lighting and oh
yeah one one other big thing up over
here we didn't have any leaves here
before and I added them in and put
lighting underneath them and again
another compost bin okay
is this so good so easy that's about it
couple changes over here too like we
have a dark spot here forever and it's
gone finally because I hit some lighting
under the leaves here well you know what
guys today is finally the day where we
finish building the Nexus you know I see
the comments don't think I don't see
them every every so often it's like etho
are you gonna finish building the Nexus
it's a bit of an eyesore doesn't look so
good you should finish it today's the
day it's gonna happen not just kidding
we're actually starting a new project
today right by the Nexus so we have like
this big grass field here and I kind of
want to build a village here a few
episodes ago we did that thing where we
renovated a village mostly because I
wanted to get an idea of how the
villages work but honestly I wanted to
build a new village from scratch and
that's what we're doing today so this is
the block scheme you guys are wondering
if this is a joke or if I'm actually
gonna work on the Nexus now we're not
working out of the Nexus we're doing
this this is the block scheme I want to
use so dark oak wood with brick four
walls and prismarine for the shingles on
the roof I think would look very nice
and some path blocks oh look at it guys
it's a winning winning color scheme I
tell you what's I've been wanting to use
it for a long time and we're gonna build
it I just starting around here we want
to make it so we can connect it to this
path that comes by here and then
probably around here is where we're
gonna want to start our first house and
kind of expand out this way yeah so the
plan is let's grab our dark oak here
Wi-Fi start building
it's really hard to build while talking
I gotta tell you guys this but I'll try
yeah so like kind of like we figured out
before we want to do that chimney thing
so if a villager goes to their house at
nighttime we want to have a campfire
emit smoke from a chimney or something
so that we know they're there we got we
want to hook redstone up to this village
will do that sense this idea where we
can see how many people actually live in
the village
how many villagers I think would be a
cool idea I think about maybe building a
bank here where we can deposit emeralds
and they like keep track of like if
we're in a deficit period or four we're
gaining emeralds
you know if I'm spending them quicker
than we're gaining them sort of thing
probably do some minecart stuff in that
as well with this and yeah well just see
how this goes anyways one of the big
plans is to make the buildings go
forward so instead of going straight up
or going to the back they go forward
like they're leaning over top of us is
gonna be one of the keys to our design
here we'll start changing up our build
here so I want to build weird houses - I
don't want to make like standard boring
houses I want to make this kind of
strange a little bit like our steampunk
village in our modded series if you
remember that kind of go for that sort
of feeling let's do like a a window
steel thing there with flowers maybe
we'll do mmm some trapdoors
uh-huh I'll do most of this off-camera
don't worry no we don't want those ones
I accidentally crafted them yeah we want
these ones we'll put those underneath do
it like that's I brought over some sweet
berries we'll probably be using these a
lot I think they look pretty nice get a
couple of those there and let me do a
bit off-camera and we'll see how this
goes
ah which one of those describes it I
think I think who is the one we want to
go for I like it I think it's pretty
good so we just had like a little
fragment of a building me an idea of of
what it might look like the scheme
working together you know I think that's
pretty good
I like it so we're gonna we're gonna
stick with that and you know we'll
change it up a little bit like we're not
gonna always use these blocks we have
some freedom to change them around a lot
of the terracotta actually works with
brick I think so we can change up our
colors a little bit and all that I think
I'm gonna add an archway here so I want
to be able to walk underneath the
building kind of and like connect up to
the path there maybe he's the next plan
so we're gonna do something like this
and bring this over to about there we'll
do that on the other side and maybe like
up to here we don't want to overthink
this either too much like we're just
gonna build a kind of on sway you know
we're not gonna measure everything I
think this is an even number even you
know we don't care about those things
we're just doing it although that
doesn't line up is that a problem it's
not a problem guys we'll make it work
we'll figure it out all right so then
we'll mirror it on this side we want a
little bit of symmetry with the build
but not like total right all right so we
got a little bit more done here and it's
it's looking pretty weird but that's
fine you know weird is good von sway is
the way they're gonna be more like
complexes I think like multiple
villagers per building so it's gonna be
one of our entrances here I guess and I
think we're gonna hang some banners from
that thing look pretty cool
and I like we're trying to keep a little
bit of symmetry alright cuz it's nice on
the eyes when you have a bit of symmetry
so I want like the roof to end over
there on the other side but like how do
we what do we do now like for this part
of the building
it's what I'm trying to figure out I'm
guessing we're gonna want this to come
over like I did a curve here I made it
come out this way a bit so it's not like
a totally flat building either and we'll
probably want this to come over like to
here or something and then start turning
back this way is what we're gonna aim
for so with that in mind the roof can
either go down or we might make it go
like curved up and like that sort of
thing I think we might go like this and
then put a balcony here and like a door
over there to go out on the balcony
because I'm not really sure what to do
with the section now to be honest it's
like it's weird right we'll figure it
out though okay well this is a little
different for me this is probably the
first time I did like a roof section
before the building like we don't have
the building and figured out underneath
there usually you do the building and
then you put the roof on at the very end
right but I wanted this continuous line
effect with the roof cuz I think that
looks cool so we got like a
stretched-out s over here and then I
added on this piece over here I think
this looks really cool actually we could
copy this and use it on other other
buildings we make as well I think it
looks pretty neat one thing though I'm
starting it at the finicky stage like I
put some red up there I'm not sure I
like the red I tried putting brick up
there like I'm like placing blocks and
removing them check him out placing them
trying something else you know the
really slow buildings stuff I might like
that more actually I'm not sure okay
that worked pretty good actually so we
did the white clay thing at the top
there as well because even though this
is an asymmetrical build we want to
create patterns so it'll probably do a
lot of the roofs like this where we have
the white clay at the top like that
and it's an easy way of filling in space
and I think it looks pretty nice adds a
little bit contrast to the build having
a different color there I love that
sound yeah so one of the cool features
we want to add to our village to each of
our buildings is a fireplace so that
when the villagers go to bed at
nighttime
we're gonna activate some redstone
that's so that smoke will come out of
the chimney and we can see that their
home really easily so we want to build a
fireplace on each house to do that the
only thing is I usually build fireplaces
out of brick and the whole building is
made out of brick right we want it to
stand out and have some contrast so I
think we'll do the fireplaces out of
stone brick even though it's not a super
exciting material it'll it'll stand out
at least right and hopefully look pretty
nice uh-oh and we're starting have some
problems here so I think this side of
the house looks great I'm very happy
with it but then when we go over here
now that we've added the fireplace it's
pretty dull it's pretty plain I don't
know maybe I lost inspiration it's not
done like we still have a lot of stuff
looking out at the top here but I think
this is shaped good like the fireplace
I just don't like how it looks so maybe
we change to different material a nether
brick or something I'm not sure what to
do with about that side of the house but
I did do over here as well
what we did is we just copied that
initial tower we built and like mirrored
it and connected them all together put
like a weird middle section in here one
issue I'm finding is we're using a lot
of brick like maybe too much so I wanted
to add some different materials in the
middle and these are mushroom stems by
the way they look pretty nice right
really like those I did something you
should probably never do here though I
mixed like fence windows with window
windows the glass ones don't do that but
if you do bonds way it's okay all right
that's the trick in here this is our
inside fireplace and I'm okay with this
all right we had an option we could have
just put like I can't fire in the
fireplace and not did the flame you know
but we did both we have the flame and
they can't fire behind there so we can
see the smoke from the campfire still
and I think that works out okay yeah
like I want to keep the campfire
underground if possible that's it down
there so that'll be easier to hook
redstone up to it if it's at this height
it'll be a little bit harder because we
need to put a piston above and then like
how do you hide the wiring to the piston
you know it's it becomes kind of an
issue ah let's see what else we gonna do
here let's go up this is nice so I like
doing a little bit of building every so
often we did acacia wood for up here it
goes good with dark wood I think dark
oak throw in a window sure we got a door
here so we're gonna have a second floor
to this building which means we need a
staircase to go up maybe where do we put
it maybe like here upwards all right
something like that we'll plan for that
kind of like over here how is it gonna
go up and then we'll have to see how the
villagers handle it so the probably
second floor is gonna start right around
here all right let's do a little
comparison here so for the interior
floors to the house we could go jungle
wood jungle planks we could go Bridge
planks or I'm thinking oak or spruce
which one is it
which is the best jungle is a little bit
too close in color to the brick I think
I don't really like that so that's out
spruce doesn't really go well with the
brick should I say that I used it in a
few places no it looks great with the
brick birch is too bright I think we're
gonna go with oak
mmm-hmm changed my mind you know what it
is I think there's like a lot more black
lines than the old planks now like in
this this new texture pack and I don't
think I like that like I used to be a
big fan of oak planks but not so much
anymore
sure go mushroom blocks maybe we could
even do like this style if we want now
we should probably stick to these okay
so this is taking a little bit of time
to get this done but we're getting close
I won't be able to finish it today
though it looks like it's just one
building like we want to build a whole
village which is gonna be a bit crazy so
again we did that thing over here I like
how that looks
we'll probably use that several times
throughout the village we're gonna put
like a staircase to go up here to a
second floor and then we might connect
the two buildings together at the top
here because we definitely can if we
want to just mess around with acacia we
might go for oak upstairs I'm not sure
but I do like the mushroom blocks
downstairs I think that looks pretty
cool they're different enough from the
brick I think where they they look okay
we can throw carpet down and stuff as
well it'll make it look nicer but yeah
one last thing we'll do on this together
and then we'll call it for the building
I think we'll add another entrance down
here let's leave that three block gap
and we will plan to put it like over
here something like this and then we'll
do the blue tile roof down here as well
I really like how these look they they
make it a little bit of a change to them
with the texture pack change and I think
they're even better now like I like them
before I think they're even better than
they were all right
maybe we'll do one of those all right so
let's try to just a few more things here
before we wrap up the episode a couple
quick things so
let's check outs first off the poppy
farm now that we've updated I think this
is all the iron we're gonna get not that
I would ever use this higher no no no
definitely not guys if you guys don't
know the initial plan with this iron
firm this poppy farm was we would only
use the iron for building the Nexus and
we did then I kept using it and it's
like just been barely able to keep up
like this is pretty much all the iron we
have left I think we have 32 blocks or
something in our ender chest still 33
that's it that's all our iron couple
beacons with some iron and I think and
that's our total supply so we're gonna
need to build a new iron farm soon
because I am almost certain this one
doesn't work anymore thing is they're
still making changes like I saw in the
next pre-release there's new ways of
farming iron golems so I might need to
wait a bit on that but we're gonna run
out iron very soon and then we have big
trouble
Oh somebody stole my watermelon oh I
think it was an Enderman can you place
these floating in mid-air I don't even
know oh you can I didn't know that yeah
there was a melon under here before it's
gone so there's also a couple other kind
of big building projects I worked on
since last episode nothing exciting but
we can check it out real quick tear so
the red sand making building here wasn't
done for the longest time I've had like
a big hole in the wall over here like
none of this was here before so I copied
over that side to this side and now at
least this building is done even though
it doesn't work anymore
it's nothing worse than like a bill that
doesn't work that's not finished and I
don't want to tear it down you know it's
just like nasty so at least it's
finished now
also the pyramid been whole humming
about this for a long time like some of
you like it some of you don't some of
you have told me to try add more color
to it and I think what we'll do is we'll
finish the design to the other side it's
like it's it was just this side done and
now I started copying it over to the
other side so like all this wasn't here
before
totally finished the top layer like all
this is is done now
so that's cool Oh crazy sounds so yeah
we'll finish the whole pyramid and then
we might make some modifications later
to add more color and and change up the
design a little bit to make it nicer if
we can all right everybody well I think
we're gonna finish up our episode here
for today the same way we do every
episode with the comment of the day
which says a etho are you planning to do
a new playthrough of terraria with z
stowe as the new 14.4 update has been
announced Oh thinking about it really
thinking about it
I actually message Z still quite a while
ago and said AZ stow you want to play
Terraria
other world when it comes out with me
yeah you want to do it he said yes and
then I got canceled and I actually
haven't talked to Z stuff since then
it's been quite a while but you know if
he's down for it maybe could be fun I
don't know though is a lot of stuff
actually coming out in the 1.4 update
like the bay thing that excites me about
that is the master mode it'll be more
difficult but as far as I could tell
like I only saw one new boss so I don't
know if there's actually a lot of like
content besides like decorative things
not too sure but if you guys want to see
it let me know in the comments it could
happen
we'll see we'll see but yeah anyways
hopefully you enjoyed today's episode
thank you for watching as always and
until next time take care
have a wonderful date
[Music]