you're looking at that slime aren't you
it's cuz it's the only thing on the
screen that's right hey hey everybody
this is etho are you guys all ready to
sing your ABCs d e f g h i j k l m n o p
q r s t u v w x y and and and said oh
yeah I had this idea the other day I was
wondering if I could represent all the
letters in the English alphabet within a
3x3 block space in Minecraft and this is
what I came up with and they're actually
pretty clear you know or I think they're
pretty readable I especially like the R
R is very cool
so yeah if you guys need tiny fonts for
anything in Minecraft this is probably
one of the smallest ways you can do it
and actually like place blocks to do it
that I would share it hope you find this
useful for whatever on earth too you
have to spell out and
yeah well that brings us to our world
here today and you know I'm in a
building and terraforming mood today I
think we're gonna take a break from
redstone or at least I think we're going
to so this has been a scar in my world
for a long time this big hole here that
keeps getting bigger and this is where I
got a bunch of sand when I first started
in this world and then I moved on to
another place that I don't mind wrecking
but this is really close to the man cave
so what we're gonna do is we're gonna
try fill us in as much as we can today
if not all of its and I'm just gonna do
one pick of dirt like so all the way
through and then we might have a room
underneath or at least light it up or
something I don't know it I kind of like
this area for testing because it's a big
flat area but we would like to be able
to walk over it so I'm gonna try to
collect all the soil I have together and
fill this baby in and actually the best
way of probably doing this is to go out
in rows like this then every 3 or 4
blocks do that so that we have something
to actually place blocks against when
filling it in makes it much easier all
right well it's going very well here
we're just about got it all done I have
to go for one more load of soil and it
will be enough to finish it there's just
this one area left but it's gonna look a
lot better I think in this area this is
however deserts so this grass is going
to be like that color not not that color
so
what do you do we'll get used to it I
prefer like desert grass over sand to be
honest all right these sheep I've dyed
them this color for the build project I
have planned for today we're gonna work
on that library I think and I'm gonna be
I'm gonna try and mix up some weird
colors together and see how it goes it's
a style I've never tried before you need
cyan wool didn'ti clay possibly quartz
blocks and a lot of stone bricks and
stuff and we will see how that goes but
we'll get to that pretty soon I'm just
gonna finish up here and then I got a
transition this - I've been aft here for
good 30 minutes or so let's check out
how the grass is doing it's almost all
spread that's good oh man look at the
grass so that's a big difference isn't
it it's not bad once we grow like Paul
grass like with bonemeal on in all that
a little bit one thing I noticed though
when I was working on this there's a lot
of mobs spawning down below and let's
let's just go check that out real quick
yeah there's a lot of moms old ding okay
I've had brighter ideas in my day and
I'm tempted to make a mob system like in
this area to like not a drop one maybe
like one of the old mob evader styles
cuz I really like those and the spawn
rates are good most cities must be lit
up I haven't even tried to light them up
and it looks like make sure I was aft
for a long time here but it was like
this even before then oh oh that's not
gonna do it I think I give them a
passage up yeah they're on top of me I
think beginning all they did didn't look
at that alright anyway I went I'm gonna
get out of here actually let's go
together about that forever water it's
kind of chanted though I'll clean this
up later we're gonna get out of here
we're gonna go over to our library area
attempted to go there to pick up the
tracks and stuff though how bad is it
it's pretty bad maybe if we ender pearl
it will be a terrible idea we gotta try
it though oh there's a skeleton here
darling I don't see any of my stuff
where is it did you blow them up after a
couple up
or did nothing get blown up nothing got
blown up okay never mind I want to see
you guys
quick filaree quick quick excellent
we're gonna go which way is it up over
to the library area over this way I
believe my bearings are rights we're
looking for that floating island again I
don't have feather falling boots I got
to do some big enchanting again because
I do I don't have any work pics I'm
using that fortune 3-1 which is a bit
wasteful up there we are going to build
the library not on the floating island
we're gonna build it on the mountain so
we'll have more space to work I think it
was up there I had my eye on let's see
let's just check this out real quick
yeah right here this is it I marked it
with a torch so what we're gonna do
let's I think we're gonna level this out
a fair bit
it'd make a nice big open flat area to
work and we'll we'll build it with the
front facing this light towards us and
if we need more space we can clear out
more of the mountain as we need to
because otherwise like I would like to
build on the floating island there but
it's just not big enough let's go check
that out one more time it's over here
wait I thought it was over here this is
it yeah and it's not really flat this
thing either be a bit hard to shape well
I think I got a nice little area
prepared here to begin with we'll need
to clear more line for sure
and flatten the area a bit I've been
placed in Kabul as filler and just
covering over but this this will get us
started we can work on the front at
least and I marked this as our center
and I believe I got all the blocks
transported over here that we'll need
there was a zombie villager by the way
that spawned up here and he had
protection two thorns one I was like
fighting him and I started taking damage
done that kinda surprised me because
I've never seen that before they can get
thorns on their on their gear and yeah
yeah one of the materials were gonna
build with is quartz I just want to show
you something I kind of clued in to a
little while ago which I'm sure other
people have too but this is really neat
quartz blocks on their own they're so
pretty
they're awesome I love them it's a great
addition great block but with with the
pillar quartz block and the chiseled
quartz block
especially the pillar one though you can
do some pretty neat subtle patterns with
it like for example
one side like this is what the pillar of
block looks like so you got the stripes
on the side but this is really neat like
it has almost like a woodgrain like like
the logs have this this square look on
the top so hopefully it's not too bright
on YouTube we can actually see what I'm
talking about here but you can make some
pretty cool patterns with that better
you know they're nice and subtle or you
can for example late them sideways and
come up with a ton of other patterns as
well let's just check that out real
quick they're a bit of a pain to place
but you can do something like this for
example
and you know on a large scale that would
look pretty neat but anyway library
library I don't know how to build the
library really I looked I did a Google
image search for libraries and nothing
really stood out to me like I gotta
build this so we're probably gonna make
something a little weird here and that's
just oh you know what I never grabbed as
my wool I'll be right back so what I'm
kind of planning with this is like
staircase entrance with an archway over
top you know I love my arches and like
two big windows one on the left one on
the right with like support columns and
that sort of thing I want to try to use
a clay for around the windows I've done
that before and it looks really good and
maybe maybe a path yeah let's do the
stairs out of quartz so we will have a
path that goes up to the library and we
will start that I guess just over here
I don't know exactly where's the best
place for it but this will do yeah this
was courts actually wait let's do that
pattern get a pattern going um we'll
just do the checkered one I like that
one whoa oh I don't know what happen
there is just I like clicked once and my
game froze and placed a bunch all right
so I am I don't usually use wool in my
builds but you know if you have just one
color it can do a whole lot especially
like I like building with stone bricks a
lot and like gray color stuff and if you
don't have one thing with color and it
doesn't really work so that's what I'm
hoping the rule is gonna do and we're
gonna try carry the blue or the cyan
we'll look throughout the build so let's
let's try put it around the outside here
which actually works good because if you
think about the mountain grass is sort
of bluish tinged so maybe that maybe
this isn't a terrible idea
it's it's gonna be a weird library
alright arch let's do the arch going it
will make it go over top here or right
mmm
foundation how about a foundation let's
how does it look if we do this get this
top and I feel like we can't have the
wool on the ground though so if we do
that
hmm maybe maybe maybe let's maybe move
this arch back then okay uh see I'm
tempted sometimes to plant stuff more so
in creative and just copy it but I'd
love it on the other hand then there's
no spot Nate spot I'm not gonna be able
to say the word spontaneity no that's
not the right way of saying it
oh why can't I say that word I know what
the word is I just can't see it now
how's that look let's get a stair here
one there and then yeah we'll make a
quartz staircase that starts going up
here where should we start the actual
walls to this thing it's the next
question hmm maybe this type of arch a
little smoother
yeah that's better okay the windows and
the walls let's let's start those ah you
know what I kind of think we should move
that arch back one more like over here
one second all right we can always
adjust it again later if we need to but
what I've tried before and creative is I
had like a stone brick slab in front of
a clay block window and it looked really
cool like let's just do this let's maybe
one more we'll try that so you have like
clay blocks running down but you can
only see the top half like that and
we'll have maybe let's the strike courts
for this as a border we'll probably have
to change that though or like a
transition to the clay block one two
three four run along the top as well and
then we'll put these slabs at the top as
well then what I would like to do is
kind of have overhang balcony type thing
above like what I'm placing right now if
that works out kind of like that and I
also used this stuff to hide the clay on
like the vertical clay blocks a little
bit like like that okay and window
windowpane we will put over here getting
close to the edge of the world here
I might not have enough space for this
build will see and yet let's just go
take a nap here quick nap power nap and
yeah I guess I'll just build this
building one side and then at the time
and then do the other side off-camera
cuz it'll just be a copy okay we'll move
or we'll put this here how far do we
want it to extend like I wanted one it
calms as well actually if we brought
this out one more block that might be
better and have like that there make
this come up and then the block there
and we'll do that every fourth block to
break it in two three wide sections I
felt down where's that over here we'll
try this out a little take a step back
and to see what it looks like and if I'm
getting too carried away with one type
of lock let me know like I might did a
little overboard with the wall or
something as I'm building this I'm nuts
I'm not really good at judging looks of
stuff okay that's cool and we'll bring
these slabs out a bit more like so and
we should go maybe one more column I'm
going to extend this a little bit more
off camera one second again alright well
I tried putting these stairs in front of
the wall for the foundation and that I
actually really liked
the look of that so we're gonna keep
that this Court's it's definitely not
working so we're getting rid of that I
tried stone brick it's it's kind of okay
I also wanted to try these stone slabs
although I'm kind of scared to introduce
a new type block but when you got so
many different ones maybe it doesn't
matter anyway let's just see what this
looks like maybe maybe maybe the other
idea I had is bear with me this might be
a bit crazy
instead of having stone brick there we
put wool there give it more color make
it stand out quite a bit more although I
think then we have to put some more
slabs in front of the wool to hide that
yeah that could be cool let's let's try
this out let's put some more slabs or we
could move the columns back as another
option that way you only see half of the
wool block if you see the full wool
block on the top it doesn't look right
hmm maybe maybe okay staircase let's
work on the staircase some we will I
made the court stairs already I think
what we should do is have a mix of the
stone stone brick stairs and court
stairs and we'll start it maybe here
yeah we'll try there first no let's
let's move it back one more we'll start
it here and it will go up kind of like
this let's get some ease this is all
experimental if we don't like something
we can change it I know that's that's
way too close we got to move that back
okay and then we're gonna put the quartz
stairs in between one stair back sort of
thing like that so pretty cool okay
let's just take a step back and see what
that looks like yeah I like that
maybe I'll miss a little bit more off
camera here
see where that gets us okay well I did a
little bit more here and I duplicated it
on the other side we'll probably have to
leave it at this for today we got a bit
done anyway now I tried I tried
mirroring this at the top and I think
that's too much wool now
possibly one thing we could do is use
quartz blocks at the top there see we
got to get lighting in here somehow
other things so I thought about putting
glowstone there but then we need block
thickness at least up there cuz I wanted
that to be like the balcony or the the
an area you could go to look down you
know and this works if we have like a
half slab here it can cover up
everything we have here and if we walk
forward we don't fall off we even have a
better view actually so could be a good
idea anyway if you guys have ideas let
me know hopefully you don't think it's
too hideous I have weird tastes I
actually like this build but that's just
me so far anyway okay let's go read some
comments just one really quick question
for today everyone he says you should be
able to put books in bookshelves triple
exclamation mark oh my goodness like
nine books each perhaps
so there is a trick you can do you can
push a storage minecart into a bookshelf
and then when you right-click the
bookshelf block it accesses a minecart
and you don't actually see the minecart
you just use Pistons push it into place
that's one way you can do it the reason
why they wouldn't do that normally in
Minecraft like the downside of of them
doing that is then they gotta save it as
a tile entity in the world file which
you know increases data and all that and
most people use it for decoration so if
you have hundreds or thousands of them
in your world that's that's a big
overhang you know for something you're
not actually
so that's that's kind of the reasoning
behind it I believe but anyway that is
all for today everyone thank you very
much for watching I will see you again
next time