[Music]
do you have a plain
boring wall in your world somewhere i
got the solution for you check this out
oh man bam get windowed
you can never go wrong with windows
no
so welcome back everybody this is etho
how's it going
guys what's going on what's new
go get your snacks oh man guys i tell
you what i have a problem
i'm probably not the only one that does
this but in minecraft
for some reason we have all the space in
the world right
we can do we can take up take up as much
space as we want
but when i do redstone for some reason i
always try to make it as compact as
possible
and it's very difficult to do that
sometimes especially with this stupid
thing right here
oh my goodness i finally got it worked
out though
yeah so this is it this is a solution to
the whole thing i know i said i finished
the redstone
to this project in creative
a long time ago but i meant like the
sorting system this part here i didn't
think
i'd even think about this part like i
didn't think it was going to be that
difficult but
oh man yeah i thought it i thought it
was going to be the simple part of the
the whole thing but no
i did not think that through too well
i'm not going to attempt to explain it
either because we can't even look at it
it's all
there's not enough space to walk and to
check it out which is a problem because
i have to
try to copy this and i can't see what i
did even
so that'll be fun but the good news is
we got to figure it out we know how much
space it's going to take to work
uh which means we can get on with
building this thing
and actually making some serious
progress with it which is cool
you can see i figured out how wide i
want the walkway to be
for the for the two tunnels so there'll
be a tunnel here and they'll probably be
one about
20 blocks or so this way um
so i guess maybe we'll start off today
with a little montage of me
building and then we'll probably go do
something else
so here we go
hmm
stone stone stone
torch
stone stone stone torch
stones on stone torch torch
torch stone stone stone stone stone
stone stone
hopper stone hopper stone hopper
redstone dropper dropper hopper hopper
dropper dropper hopper hopper
hopper hopper dropper dropper raw pho
copter
all right guys so there we go a little
building montage
i had someone in the comments say i
haven't done that in a long time
which is true i used to do those like
every episode and then
kind of just forgot about them so if you
ever wonder what goes on behind the
scenes that there's a little bit of
insight for you
all the block placing um so we got a
fair bit done here that's probably all
we'll do for today we'll just keep keep
working on this little by little and
eventually we'll get done
big project oh my goodness this this
spot here is for the redstone
baby zombie go away oh wow one shot
um there'll be another tunnel starting
here kind of
like this would be the tunnel
like right here um this would be the
left side of the tunnel and then
there'll be a right side um so we have
to clear out all this stone here
still um what else what else i
experimented with the looks again
still trying to figure this out i'm
having trouble with it i wanted to see
what the colored clay would look like
next to the sea lanterns and the blue
floor here
and the quartz it might
work what do you guys think of that i
would not do the floor like this we
would
we would want more detail of course than
that but
the whole line thing here does this work
do i need to get rid of the lanterns
maybe let's try without them
oh man i put them all away let's grab
let's grab green here i wanted to see
what the colors looked like next to this
floor
if there's any that looked really bad
because
it's a blue floor maybe there's some
colors that don't go with that too well
but it's it's not too too bad i don't
think
what am i doing take these out was this
not still touch
oh it's not oops okay
do that so we could just have a straight
line too
i don't know someone suggested i put uh
colored beacons like maybe one here
and then one here and then when we look
down the tunnel
we'll have a rainbow effect of the
beacons going all the way down i think
that's
really cool idea if we can do it be a
lot of beacons though
um the reason for the color codes
i would like to include these to help me
memorize where stuff is in the storage
room
just like one more extra memory trick to
remembering things
uh currently one of my other plans is to
hopefully
oh which fell down uh
we'll use these levers to sort of figure
out where stuff is
in the storage room like there's going
to be a top and a bottom floor
so maybe one lever will decide is it top
or bottom floor
there's going to be two tunnels so
another lever will decide is the left or
the right tunnel
there'll be a left and a right side for
each tunnel so that would be another
lever then they'll be the
first half second half and then first
half second half of that
and yeah basically if i know where
something is
in the storage room i'll be able to
figure it out without
i heard some glass break or something
what was that was that in the game
all right i got distracted but anyway if
i know where something is in the storage
room i can
i can figure it out with the levers
without having to reference anything so
that
that's this one more trick we will
hopefully use
and if we get enough tricks like that it
should be pretty easy to
to know what code to use to get an item
without having to always check a book or
something which is also probably what
we'll use
so guys maybe we will do a few things
around the man cave here for
for a little while this window that we
we put in that sting
what i did is i lowered some of the
redstone that we had there originally
man i looked at the redstone it was so
bad
what was i thinking back then like did i
not know what i was doing
uh but i just made it a couple of
changes to it now we can actually see
into this room before there was this
you see that uh the stone bricks there
that was running all the way across
and there was like no view but i lowered
that
um this entrance is such a mess i still
don't really know what i want to do with
it
but i think for sure we're going to put
in at least one more arch
so let's just go ahead and do that
let's see do that and
i got some oak here i also made a couple
other changes
um in another spot in the manatee which
we'll go check out
oops and i want to try to add some more
detail to that
tunnel we have with the brick
oops oh man placing stairs so difficult
why why is that all right let's see
yeah i can't place blocks period all
right
is this okay is this too close to the
stairs does it need to be taller
it feels a little close to the stairs
yep that might have been why i didn't do
it before we could raise it
a little bit more though
okay so i moved it up one more block
feels quite a bit better
with that extra space um still might be
too close though
horsey horsey come here we gotta try
this
can you fit your big head through this
thing
oh wrong way actually i guess it would
be
my big head wouldn't it because i'm the
one that's gonna get hit
all right we can go up no problem going
down oh i hit my head darn it
hmm that might not work
here i guess we'll do this too we'll go
along with the
stairs and
let's put stone there
okay and then i'm going to put leaves
kind of like we have here this will be
like the last section that we do like
that
oh man what did you guys do what is this
i don't even know i heard the the piston
going on this over and over and over
like the slime was jumping on it
somehow they glitched out the water like
crazy
oh maybe it was just a visual glitch is
it broken
no it still works okay
that was weird um
so yeah we got leaves here now i put a
beam on this side as well
we have a slight problem
uh this wall if we take these out
it's only one block thick here so
might have to do something special on
this side
but i think this looks quite a bit
better a little bit more finished
looking
uh we'll put some flowers or something
down here they're doing it again
guys stop it
please stop it uh there was this one
patch where these guys stopped spawning
and it was like the greatest thing ever
now they're like annoying me again all
the time
because they spawn all over the man cave
here
perfect conditions for them um
people always wonder what what i do with
the comments at the end of the episode
they're supposed to go to the library
but for right now
this has been the permanent spot pretty
much
and i think there's a couple more back
here
and is there yeah they're in there too
and i think there's some at the library
as well
um we really need to finish that but i'm
not super happy with how the
building looks so i'm not sure i almost
want to just
redo it from scratch but i don't know
don't know what to do with it um yeah
let's go down here
this is what i oh wow
and these guys are all over the place
how did he get down there
he must have jumped from the stair here
over the fence
because i don't think they can jump over
the fence normally
yeah over here is where i work today
go across the bridge all this grass i
put in
put some stairs over here kind of worked
out
around this waterfall i don't know if
i've ever shown this waterfall even
but from the mushrooms up here
i made it so the water goes down and
then we'll try to make this place look
nice too
oh um
yeah this is this is uh
elevator and potion lab wire axis so we
have a little room here
where we can go to get to the redstone
which is something i like to do
makes it a little easier if you ever
have to do maintenance this is all the
potion lab wiring down here we have a
way to get to it now
instead of just like drilling through
the floor that's kind of nice
uh we're going to head over to
where is it
um i guess we'll have to go through the
floor
there we go shortcut um yeah we're gonna
go over here and work on this room a
little bit
this room is pretty much done in my
opinion the only thing i thought about
today though is maybe it'd be cool if we
started adding
just a little bit more detail to the
walls this is all
stone if we had like some stone bricks
throughout it it might look cool
so let's just try that out just like
randomly mixed in every
so often
all right so let me uh let me work on
this actually you know what i also
brought andesite i wanted to try
where is it there it is it's in my it's
in my hot bar
could do both or
um not sure which i like more
ah they're actually both pretty good
yeah maybe we'll use both then
ah you know what on second thought now
that i see it it kind of looks like my
walls have chicken pox
so that's that's not so good that's not
gonna work the andesite i don't like
um i'm gonna try stone brick though
andesite and the stone brick didn't go
well together so we have to use
one or the other i thought andesite
might be better
but now that i see it i don't like it
too much
but it was worth a shot alright
yeah stone brick is a little more subtle
isn't it the andesite has that sharp
white line
on it which makes it uh stand out a
little too much i think
you know what like i do like it here
it's it's not bad
but something i've kind of learned from
doing this
when you take it into context with the
rest of the room here this is a really
highly detailed room and when i see this
with the rest of the room it's just it's
too much
it's too much detail sometimes it's
better just to keep things simple
because it just detracts from the rest
of the details
i would rather look at the leaves and
stuff than
the walls that aren't really all that
special
i was just thinking it's been a while
since we last updated our map here
i'm curious if anything will change on
it most of stuff we build is
either underground or outside the area
here but
i know we've done stuff on the snowflake
so let's try that out oh
that's the gold farm up there right
oh yeah that looks different now um see
the library i'm pretty sure has changed
this is the library up here oh
[Music]
really and it's gone
darn it where'd it go i really wish
stuff didn't fly out of item frames like
that oh it's down there
all right i have to be very careful i
don't end or pearl here either i'll hit
the
map all right
did i not look at it
pretty sure it doesn't look like that
anymore why is it not
updating that is weird
all right i'll put it back because
there's all that
wood and stuff to it now like
yeah like this should all be filled in
here i don't know why it doesn't update
um okay there's also the
mob system down here i believe that
would be
i think around here
what is that between item frames it must
be
oh no i can't oh there we go
oh no change
let's try this one um
oh i think that's the cactus farm on
there now
up here maybe
or not what is that that looks very
strange i can't even think of what that
would be that must be the cactus farm
right
all right let's try to get another one
come on
oh same one
why is it partially buried though i
don't get this
okay that is the the mob system you can
see that that wasn't there before i
don't
think okay there we go i don't know why
but it only
partially updated originally but when i
held in my hand for a while here
then it's uh it fully updated
so you can see how much bigger the mob
system is on here now
and also that's the full cactus farm it
should be a square
for some reason there was trees there
before
which means if we take this one out
is this going to update it wasn't until
i started walking around that it did
oh yeah there it goes
where it started anyway very slowly
is that all that
just this tiny little bit of white
appeared i guess you got to hold it
for a while oh and that down it goes
[Music]
huh oh yeah it's very slow
i guess no here it goes here it goes
it's not until you get closer to the
chunk it seems to update
oh man oh man right before our eyes
stop chasing me spider you're wrecking
the reveal
oh oh i'm like a tourist here i'm not
watching where i'm going
oh man look at all the snow too all the
snow wasn't there before
it was until this was before that update
where it snows on mountains i guess
whoa okay
cool
oh man this is awesome guys check this
out get on the horse
down it goes get off the horse up it
goes
some people say minecraft has bad
physics no no no
look at this calculates your weight and
everything
it's like a scale
all right everybody so we're going to do
one more thing here today this
this should be pretty fun i keep putting
this off though because i've been scared
to do it we gotta fight
with 15 withers today
oh man we need beacons like we don't
have any extra beacons around even at
the nexus
like i would love to get a speed beacon
over there but we just don't have any
because i keep putting this off
but yeah let's do it this is probably
the safest place to do it we're on top
the nether
by the gold farm and the wither skeleton
farm actually it's right up there
i'm hoping they don't shoot it but we'll
see
um but yeah over here is where my
my speed 2 beacon is my strength to
regen and resistance too so that should
make this a lot easier
i don't know if this makes it better you
guys said it did so we'll do it
turns the nether into hawaiian punch
mode though
might be a little bright um i just saw
this guy spawn i gotta be careful
if that was a gas things would have got
pretty bad here
all right i think we're ready though
let's see how this goes i'm hoping they
fight each other
more than anything all right three
two one
okay okay this should be fun this is
back up a little bit
maybe not towards the gold farm maybe it
will go sideways
oh man there is so many bullets flying
my way okay let's
see how we do i bear eat too
so i can reach in uh it seems like the
armor is holding out
pretty decent so we'll we'll go in
oh man oh man oh man
okay we're still okay
i'm trying to get them all mad at me so
that they start flying around
that way they'll fight each other i
think
this is the plan oh yeah yeah look at
this this is what i want
i think i might have to hit each one
we're a little bit low
let's get this guy they're all just
oh my goodness last one okay
oh they picked me up there they picked
me up
this guy yeah he he's like dead and i
haven't even hit him once
he's he's already in uh sword mode
that's good
so as long as we keep moving around
they'll pretty much kill each other i
don't want to go outside of beacon range
which i think i just did
let's go back oh man how's it going guys
so nice of you to get right in my face
like this
[Music]
i know you like me a lot but a little
bit of space would be nice
all right we got two stars i'm gonna
stop and eat here
maybe he'll all right let's try finish
him off
how's my armor oh no the pants are about
to go
okay this could get bad if my pants
disappear
was that it oh no that's not it there's
still a couple
all right let's grab what stars we can
that's 10 stars should be five more
they don't explode so that's good this
guy's like
full whoa holy smokes
all right well i might have to do this
old-fashioned way
i think he's the last one though
oh man he's really hurting me too
without my pants it's not the same
all right come on guy fight me fight
fight me like a man
got him good it's 11.
don't see any more of them around it
looks like our ladders took some damage
i'm gonna go up there and inspect the
gold firm just to make sure it's okay
um oh here we go here we go
14 good there's one more
should be one more somewhere here
can we find it please tell me it didn't
disappear
not that it would be a huge loss we got
14 from that that's pretty nice
um
not seeing it all right i'll look around
we should be able to find it though
kind of strange i looked around like
really pretty
thoroughly and i could not find it so
somehow it disappeared
i'm hoping a wither didn't like run away
and it's like still out there somewhere
but i wanted to check the for any damage
on here
because we did the fight right by it
looks like it's okay though they
don't really tend to shoot upwards
yeah i think we're okay still all right
good good and all the glass is okay
double checking my iron golems have
pretty much all died
from like magma cubes and zombies
killing them so i'll have to replace
them soon
but that's after a lot of use with this
thing
okay everybody so that's gonna do it for
today but we do have a comment as usual
it says hey etho just wondering did you
think about using
item frames and comparators to control
the nexus
one item frame now has eight possible
orientations so you'd only need two of
them
plus two levers or you could use three
of them and no levers
um that's instead of using the eight
levers like i'm planning
downside definitely is fitting in all
the comparators to convert your signal
from octal to binary
if it if it is even possible it is
possible
would be really sweet to use that
mechanic though so there are uh
certain benefits to it you would only
need three item frames instead of eight
levers to control what item you're
requesting
downside is uh takes
it might be a little more difficult to
rotate the items and is just to flip the
levers
it also becomes more confusing
and less efficient when you're you're
going from an octal system to a binary
system
and like with that mental trick i have
in mind of
of uh keeping track of where items are
in the storage room compared to uh
the levers like you can you can position
items according to the levers um
wouldn't be able to do that if we used
an octal system so there's
there's some benefits to both of them
but yeah anyway we'll look into it more
as we get closer to that
i also had somebody ask how i underlined
the text in this it's actually very
difficult
i think maybe european keyboards are
different but with
with mine um what i have to do i have to
go to
wordpad i press alt 21
21 on your num number pad
hold alt press 21 that makes a special
character appear that looks like uh i
think it's a
european dollar sign of some sort i i'm
not sure what it is
and then you press n after that and that
underlines it
so that then when you put any text after
that then it's going to be underlined
um but for some reason i can't do alt 21
in the books
themselves i have to copy paste it and
it's pretty annoying
kind of wish i never started doing that
but oh wow
uh everyone has had that i think pretty
much and i
i just i'll just continue with it anyway
that's going to be
it for today guys thank you for watching
have a wonderful day
and i'll see you in the next one take
care
[Music]
bye