[Music]
hey how's it going everybody this is
Ethan welcome back guys to another
episode here in my single-player let's
play world I have some bad news
Wilson I've kept Wilson alive since last
time but I just checked him and he's not
doing so good right now it's not doing
the best in fact we kind of have to
hurry this is a bit of an emergency he's
on his last legs oh he's still alive
good things that one one health and he's
sick oh what's clicking oh that's just
the loss I was worried it was Wilson
come on Wilson
you can pull through this Wilson oh hey
I was worried there for a second
alright come on get some food in you get
some food oh his weight you know he I
was checking on him and he was fine he
was doing fine
then I left to like cut down some trees
for a little bit and I did a little bit
of building and when I came back he must
have got sick again like as soon as I
left cos he was almost dead when I
checked them come on guy come on
you can pull through this believe
believe he's he's at like half life
right now it's just about just about it
half life it looks like man this guy
he's he's a lot of maintenance to keep
going I can tell you that all right
let's get a little bit more cookies in
him try to get his weight up definitely
need to do a bunch of tweaking for this
guy because there are a few things not
working quite right
I don't know can we leave him and give
him one more cookie I think Oh that'll
help that'll help a lot his weight went
up to three so as he is right now his
health should start going up a little
bit but I'm gonna have to keep a close
eye on him so I was working over here
just really quick let's go check this
out I am been trying to decide on what
to do with this area so I got some of
this wood path going around now tried to
do a little something with this I'm not
quite happy with it yet this is our
elevator to the surface and I changed
out the ground here with with the slimes
oops I did and now it just broke it
alright let's try this out okay so you
run in whoo come out of the top and I
have it now so I don't have to jump when
I get to the top these are half slabs
your sign just walk forward and try to
do a little something out here I'm gonna
want I want to tweak this a little bit
too I kind of ran out of leaves
unfortunately this is a desert biome
right where this thing is so it's hard
to make it look green I know when you
want to go back down is bounce and
bounce and I got to do the the inside of
the walls here the stone and that kind
of stuff but it works pretty good now
let's try let's dig Zenith for a ride
here
oh yeah works great oh did I hit my head
on something or was it the tree I think
it was the tree oh yeah then when you
want to go down
oh I walked too far forward I go up to
there that thing there uh-huh I really
want to set up a horse parkour thing
with like these slime blocks because I
think that would be a lot of fun all
right
anyway did that this chick Wilson one
more time uh-oh its weight went back
down let me give a mistake even though
he's not hungry this thing is not down
straight right now I can't get his
weight to stay up which it should be
easy to beat to do that so with this I
think what I'm gonna do I put half slabs
down in this mushroom farm and I've
talked about ripping this thing out but
I think what I'll do instead is just rip
out maybe up to here like everything
from here to the right this way take
that out and that should give us plenty
of space here to do to do more stuff
around here and this mushroom farm does
not need to be this big so I think
that's a good move and then we'll still
have it rather than ripping the whole
thing out oh this guy then he got sick
again like right away Wilson you have to
get better get plenty of sleep okay okay
I fixed the sensor too now so oh look at
that guy he's super happy
I fixed the sensor so his happiness can
go back up again all right I'm gonna
give him one more steak excellent okay
so destruction construction is a lot of
fun let's do some destruction although
these half slabs probably will block
most of it
but yeah although I don't really want
that to break either man maybe TNT is
not the best way of doing this because I
got redstone nearby but we'll try it out
let's do a little bit good perfect
look at that okay he's back up to 2 but
I don't know if he'll make it all the
way guys he's getting sick so often he
got sick twice since I showed that last
clip I have to like check on him every 5
or 10 minutes otherwise he's he's gonna
die for sure I have to pretty much baby
him at this point this looks a lot
different though doesn't it's very open
to open in fact it it needs to be this
needs to be closed up somehow so we
should put like an entrance here I think
to the mushroom farm and make it so you
can't see into it because it just feels
feels like in situ much like it with it
like that there should be a wall here at
least then maybe some stuff in front of
this um let's see but yeah I got some
mushrooms I wonder if we could get a
mushroom to grow here think about
mushrooms you need so much space for
them they're kind of a pain ah I would
like to have like 2 or 3 mushrooms in
front of the mushroom farm but let's see
we need a 7x7 no we don't have it I
don't know I don't think we can do it
7x7 oh it's because of this shouldn't
have put this down let's go get some
more bone meal and I think I have some
how we can grab some from here go ahead
and do that oh yeah
this seems to have stopped burning by
the way in the latest snapshots the lava
has been fixed don't have the fires
going out of control anymore which is
good
Wilson you're still fine very good okay
so let's try this again
yay let's see I was kind of hoping for a
taller one maybe we should try get a
taller one that's like a really really
short mushroom does it have enough space
to get taller I don't I don't know if it
does yeah let's try this one more time
at the right spot yep nope
who's there yeah darn it they can get
they can grow taller can't they I'm
pretty sure they can I try one more time
here big mushroom come on start it okay
we'll live with it I think I need more
ceiling space but there's two blocks
from the top it should go at least up
till like one before the top of the
ceiling I think all right we're gonna
try to get a brown mushroom here please
work oh it did work nice alright and
we'll trim that according to how we want
later I guess entrance was here it like
grew through the entrance amazing okay
yeah I think that'll be fine like that I
had an idea that I'm gonna try out here
rather than having the grass and the
ground here I'm gonna flood this sort of
will make let's make some like walkways
above water I think would be a lot
cooler I really really do not like this
color of grass at all so instead we're
gonna make like a that pure sort of
thing not really appear though but
that's sort of that sort of walkway
connecting it all this together so we'll
have it go here I just believe that
three wide all the way up to here and
then it will connect to they're
connected this oh and I'm out of planks
so basically anywhere I have grass here
well almost anywhere like we'll have the
water H out like this
and maybe like this and like maybe here
take this all down at least two blocks
and then have water all over the place
here and I think that'll look pretty
cool mm-hmm so something like this this
is what I had in mind I think this is
pretty cool I actually really like this
bend in the walkway - I was worried
because the staircase doesn't line up
with that door I thought it was gonna be
really dumb looking but I think that
actually makes it better it gives it
more character just cool so we're trying
to make like a swamp here is our goal
and what we will do is flood underneath
here we'll have to of course protect any
redstone we got this is for the elevator
and this is for the door the door still
needs a little bit of work to maybe able
just do that for now yeah okay and then
we will build up mmm some like retaining
wall I wonder if we should go in one
block that might look better so I got
some and the sites love this stuff we
will use that maybe some chiseled mossy
oh wait this is chiseled this is cracked
uh-huh so let's try do some random I
guess we got cobble - we could use
and stone look at look at all these gray
blocks it's so cool so many choices and
it's gonna look terrible because I'm the
one doing it but there's lots of options
maybe I won't use the chiseled stone you
polished again polished cracks yes
that's not terrible as where it is a
little too chaotic but it's not terrible
um that and some cobble Oh
actually we we hit the end here anyway
so we're gonna do that I noticed
something really weird today I never
noticed this before I was adjusting my
my speaker's because apparently my
minecraft sound was way lower than it
should have been so I could barely hear
the game and it was really frustrating
me so I in here really clearly now in
the game and I noticed if you got
headphones especially you'll you'll pick
this up but if you walk left on stone
for example you hear the footsteps in
the left speaker if you go right you
hear it and the right I never noticed
that before the stereo audio for that
but here's the thing though if you do it
on grass its reversed you walked to the
left and you hear it in the right
speaker walk to the right here in the
left very very interesting and then
planks I think it was the same on both
or it sounds the same to me on both kind
of cool
ah so let me do these walls and then
we'll flood it hey I got the walls done
and ice is in place ready to to flood
down here I got rid of the mossy brick
because it was a little too crazy even
still I think it might be a bit too
crazy but you won't really see down here
anyway I've put a lining
cobblestone slabs over here to make it
look like it's holding up the the dirt
which is a little weird but it it kind
of makes sense I guess I don't know I
like the way water looks when it goes
underneath the block site when it goes
in at least one so that's why I did it
this way all right beautiful let's see
what this looks like from up here now
hopefully it adds a nice level of depth
oh yeah that's pretty cool it might be
too deep though hmm I wonder if I should
bring the water up one more block here
yeah because I didn't account to the
fact that the half slabs are half a
block let's let's bring it up one more
I'll get rid of this junk yeah I think
that's a good plan oh yeah I like that a
lot more with the water raised up of
bits very nice very cool okay there's
not enough water I find though so I
think what we'll do is we'll try to make
the water come out this way as well and
have like a walkway here on the edge
with maybe some fences now maybe I won't
do the fences yeah we'll have the water
come out this way maybe go down here and
have like a cool waterfall going over
there I also feel we need the water to
come from somewhere over here so let's
that's a really nasty looking wall over
there isn't it so let's let's try to do
something with that
try build it up into a waterfall sort of
thing if we can because this is like a
main thing you see when you're coming
towards here you see this so it'd be
cool if it looks nice
let's build it up with dirt I think
maybe try get the water to fall here
where are those slimes I think they're
they might be under here I've gotten a
lot less slime since I have slapped that
thing it's so much better all right yes
water will come down here we kind of
want it to cascade down but we want it
to flow down to two here we don't want
it to spread all over the place either
let's build this up maybe like that yeah
build it up building it up mmm okay we
can try this here I'm gonna protect the
wiring here before I do anything oh yeah
because we need the wall to come up all
the way up to here oops I got to put a
ladder here - because if I fall in
there's no way out especially once I
change over here alright let's see what
this looks like let's get a water stream
take out this redstone we don't need it
anymore water stream comes down here and
[Music]
it's still okay hopefully this spreads
nicely oh that doesn't work do I have a
bucket no I don't how can I break this I
guess we'll do it this way this is a bit
tricky today we're gonna break it and
then place a block come on can't even
reach it
oh I missed darn it Oh didn't I place it
that's not a place to second one okay
hey let's let it settle then we'll break
it again oh that spread a lot didn't it
I wonder if that's too much I kinda
didn't want it to get right next to the
door here maybe I can just manually fix
it yeah yeah that looks weird I don't
know about that
alright anyway the other idea is I think
I want to stream just coming out of the
ceiling over here
let's get another water block we'll put
it right above here yeah okay
same deal do it quicker this time very
good okay so now when we come down the
stairs what does this look like that's
pretty good I like that yeah I think
that's good I might try to make this a
little smaller this waterfall I feel
like it's it's too big ah yes so I made
a curve a little bit now I I like that
more I think that's better I also have
started to bring the water out this way
we're gonna we're gonna end up to here
today I think is what we'll do so the
ice is in place let's break it's get the
water going very cool oh you know what I
got put get the ice all the way over
here to do that and it'll need another
one over here
perfect okay so let's join the two
together the two sides I only made the
water one deep over here because I think
that's it I think that's all it needs
really okay hop on up
and I wonder that maybe I'll just leave
it like that for right now how does this
feel this is good I almost wish I had
one more block like this way where I
could have water I feel like it needs it
it needs a little bit more water over
here but I'm liking that I think that's
a much much better improvement to what
we had before it's kind of different to
it it adds a lot of color to this area
compared to the the nasty grass we had
here so we're also gonna be doing of
course like some some like greeneries
kind of stuff might try grow some trees
here get some vines going that kind of
stuff I think I'm gonna do that another
day and of course the roof needs a lot
of work and and some of the walls and
stuff need to figure out what I'm
putting over here but I like that a lot
more so that's that's cool Wilson our
friend unfortunately oh he died poor
Wilson I tried I tried to bring him back
I got pretty far with them considering
like he got sick around that time and
he's just been cleaning the life from
there to there
I left him for I think ten minutes at
one point and he must have got sick
again and died I don't know I came and
checked out him and he was he was gone
so that is the first run of Wilson I
should almost make like a Wilson
graveyard somewhere to remember all our
Wilson runs the idea though is not to
like it should be difficult to get him
to live a full life
so I'm kind of glad it didn't make it
all the way to the end because it was
challenging keeping him alive
but we will make lots of tweaks to this
thing before we start him up again I
have a lot of ideas and I I know what to
change now so that was a good run
but anyway guys I think it's about time
we get to the comments for today's
episode so I picked out one and it says
etho what's the most Canadian thing
you've ever done the most Canadian thing
you've ever done that is a good question
a very good question okay okay I got
something guys so there's one time as
like watching some Canadian hottie on
television and I noticed the fire and my
wood stove was about to go out and my my
log cabin was about to get very cold if
I let that happen so I had to go out and
get some more firewood so I put on my
red flag jacket and my snow shoes and
went outside into the pine forest but
before I left I also grabbed some maple
flavor to Canadian bacon to chew on as I
walk towards the trees and while I was
watching to find a nice tree to chop
down a grizzly bear jumped out of the
bushes and started to attack me to get
my my Canadian bacon and we wrestled and
then after a while I was like sorry we
can just share and and then we we said
sorry to each other and we we made up
and we shared the Canadian bacon and I
chopped down a tree and we were best
friends and it was amazing thanks for
watching everybody
bye bye
you