Aoh, oh, no new enterporter for this episode,
everybody. Oh, I broke the streak already. We
were doin so good we discot the the one we did last
episode. Aha, yes, I've been building the
enterporters mostly off camera, but I thought
to day, let's try build one together a bit here.
Ah cause we gotta design a new one so I ought to put
an interporter of a stupid enterman. I ought to
put an interporter in the mantaviere, I'm
trying to decide where to put it and ideally I
want it over here, though like this is the area we
we spend the most time in in the world. I think how
could it be if we had an anterporter like Raiden
here? Well, we can't really do that because
underneath the smelting room there we have the
tomagotci pet. We got the creeper face with the
portal behind and there's a bunch of red stone
behind this, there's not enough space to do it.
Really, unless we do something kind of special
with this one Bcause. there's no room below
this. There's no room besides this. That just
leaves above. Now. the question is what is above
this melting room. You might wonder. well, um,
fun, little fact, I think this is my first
cracking table furnace and wooden pick we made
in the series. Here, we still got it in the exact
same place we left it, so I don't really want to
move. That tit's kindo like an hostalgic thing
for me. But then Ah, we got this water pool we got
deal with. We gotta fill this in so it doesn't
leak. And then I think if we dig down around here
somewhere they'll take us right to the smelting
room. I'm goinna guess maybe around here. let's
find out. Nope, that's amiss. Oit's. moreover,
here. Yeah, at's one of our shockers, okay,
Good, Yeah, so we have some space above the
smelting room that we can take advantage of, but
the thing is, interporters are loaded by
throwing the pearl down, usually into the
bubble Com. So that that's our challenge. Weget
a design an interporter wher wethrow, the
interproll up. And yeah, that's a little bit
tricky because we want the enter pearl to sit in a
bubble column in order to make a bubble cull, you
need a piece of sold Sam below, so we can't just go
underneath that and throw it in ecause. Then we
hit the soul sand right, so we either got to move
the sole sand out of our way as we throw the inter
pearl and then put it back or we need to push the
interparal into the bubble stream somehow, and
I think we're going to go for the second option,
pushing the inter pearl into the bubble stream
will probably be a little bit easier, but either
method we choose here, We gottor somehow detect
to when we throw the endor pearl, and
unfortunately I think trep wires are really the
only way of doing that. Um, The problem with the
trippires though is, Uh, they don't always
detect like stuff passing through hem, like, if
you throw it here, those lights then turned on.
it passed right through he the trip wire but if
you get the distance just right, Oh, that's one
that works. Ok. Wol. If we go up a block, Um, then
it'll It'll detect it that time it passed
through. I guess at this height might be what we
end up doing then, not really sure how much water
we need here. so let's jus fill this all the way
up, and then we'll figure it out from there so
that will be solid water above the sole sand, and
then we'll have one water source at the very top,
so hopefully this will be downward flowing
water for we're at, and that'll sow down the
intercrowl a little bit quicker. Let's see if we
gat the roof here. Oh no, we don't okkay. good,
cool cool. So that slows it down really good. and
then we just have to push it into the bubble
column. Oky, Well, I took me a little bit of trowl
in air here to get the distances and the timings.
all correct with this, but I think it's pretty
consistent now. so he put a piston at the top of
the water, so that the interprols moving the
slowest at the top of the inter pearl arc. We push
it to the left into the bubble column. That way,
it's a consistent. and Ah, it seems to work like
every time, which is great. So then it says,
Suspended at the top of that and we just got to
activate a piston to the push it back to the right
out of the bubble, calm and it'll fall back down.
so just for now, I tot is for this piston pushes it
over and it should land right back into our
smelting room, which, which is great, So yeah,
the timing is four Redston ticks here. so he
said, a little ladder from the trip wire, and the
again, the spacing on all this matters a lot. So
we go one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight blocks to this wole sand, and then we have
six water blucks above that and that pistons at
the fifth one, we've got to have another water
buck above it. Otherwise the water will have a
horizontal momentum to it and push the
interpearl into the wall. Oh, Snapper's all
right, everbody, so after a bit o time here, we
got it installed in the ceiling like we wanted
to, so we readed the roof in the smelting room, Um
just put some blast furnaces in here for a bit of
variation. It looks maybe a bit weird. Still. I
may make some more adjustments. You know what I
forgot is H. This room's actually on slabs, so
that really affected the interpearls passing
through the tripwires. I had to change at
distance, so we have. I think four and a half
blocks of space before the trip fire. Ah, but it
works like every time, which is which is
awesome, so we throw it up. It gets set in place.
We have a button here, the teleport to our next
station and throw down. We can tell port back. It
does take a little bit longer, because this is a
special one. We make it fall through the water
instead of activating instantly. So it's a
little bit lower than our other interporters,
and the really cool thing about this is now that
we've added that station in the mancave, we have
a complete line that passes through. like all
our important builds, From the mancave to our
strong hold base. we can go right to our end
portal that we'll want to make some more branch
hops to other things like our coarsefruit farm,
probably to the libraries to other places like
that, but uh, the main area is covered now, and
uh, In order to mate this better, I standardized
all our interporter station Celets, other
thing I've been working on here, so we'll
probably have like four buttons along a wall.
This wild get filled up with interprols, so we
get one every time we tell Te ports. and then
there'll probably be some signs tat they wer
Thes lead to sort a thing, pretty simple design.
I know some people mention I can use things like
item frames, and Likhe choose a station that
way, but we really want this to be quick and
simple. Um, and buttons are probably the best
way of doing that or pressure plates, but I'm
worried slimes will spawn and step on our
pressure plates when we don't want them to, So
that's why I went for the buttons. The other
thing is, I had trouble triggering the trap
door. finding a good method for that, so we were
doing something like this before where we had
pass it through an observer, then it W'll go to
the trap door sort of thing, and it does that
quick flip like we want it to, But the problem is
it does it on both the powering and unpowering,
so I came up with something pretty cool Here. We
got like a sticky pist, thin, Um, just a really
simple thing, but it only activates when we want
it to, so not on the powering, only on the
uncowering, and it still does the quick, flip,
like we need. That's perfect. That's what we got
at all our stations Now awesome. So it that the
only thing let to show you really is just how cool
this actually is. So we. we'll take a trip from
the mancae to our stronghold face and checked
Thi outers so awesome and look at this, sir,
we're at are and portal. Just like that. we
wantta go back. Oh band super quick. I heard a
indermight. I wonder if antermi, tere goinnt be
an issue Wit this. Actually, I didn't think
about that too much and we're over at Santy City
and this one again. This is the slowest one. but
it's not too bad, right, amazing, so we
travelled like fifteen hundred blocks. E. Yep,
yep, so I'm gonna be adding more on to that. An
future episodes ins is going to keep getting
better and better when it's alreadyi supr,
awesome, so I I'm really happy, with how that
turned out actually over at the Guardian farm.
Remember last episode we started a gelt farm.
This is mostly just the fill up the space we had
here. but saih, you know, I didn't have a kelt
firm in my world, so it's kind of nice. We'll be
able to get this Li bit easier now. and uh, I
actually kind o like building with killbox.
Surprisingly, they're They're a bit tricky to
use. but if you can use. them, in some situations
it's the only way to get that dark green colour.
Ah, and these are pretty much fully done. I would
say we got a pretty satisfying way of harvesting
them too. Is it? The button here goes all along
like that? Then you see the celt float up to the
top and then at the very top it like fundles over
the wall and ends up over here. I didn't do a
collection system for this because I don't know
what we're putting here. Am figured we'd
somehow tie it in. so just for now all the kelp
ends up on the ground here. Al just pick it up in
chalters. Probably um, and yeh, then it's free
to regrow And you see, I added some sea lanterns
in the back there as well, and we did another one
on that side. This was an actually a huge
project. This wis a bit. these are big walls.
We're dealin with yer, and let's do this one more
time, cause it's so awesome. I love it. The way
that works is we just have a chain of observers
that run over top of sticky pistons and you's got
to update one of the ends here. It goes all the way
down, su per simple, and I should probably show
you the collection system as well, just in case
you're curious. It is not fancy at all, though,
Ah, basically the telt grows over here and then
we have water source blocks at my head level here
and then there's no water source above the
netherwork and then trap doors stop the water,
and then we have one watersource block ere and it
is a big staircase that goes all the way down and
all the kelp lands in this and funnels to one
spot. Ah, just hate it, curiosity. I wan't try
something here. I'd never use horses any more,
but during the world tour we found out that. Ah,
this migh not be broken. Now, look at that All
right. We can get horses out of the mancube
again. That's pretty cool. I get some firework
rockets and this guy is not as fast as I was
hoping. waitit. Alway's got the g. That's one of
my villages. Why are you on the surface Et in the
water, Buddy. Ah, he's dead. He had the. he had,
the. Uh, my horse frinly, the diamond ping ono on
his clothes. So he had to harvest some sugar cane
here, and I was hoping the horse would make it
easier, but he makes it hofper actually alight.
So it turns out horses do not like lilipads. We
just figured something out. We didn't know a
kind of Ah. That's something weird to them.
Well, that was fun, but I kina remember why I
don't use horses, so let's let's return em and
see if this still works that Ye didn't take
damage awesome, Ok, cool. go back to our horse
table. Oh, they're They're kind of weird
onstairs to, aren't they? Now? look atet hu.
aha, yeah. so empthing oult is Mob System is one
of my regular jobs. I tsouwh was overflowin on
gunpowder, so gotta take care of that. A zombie
flesh gets treated to cheef. How, and the bones
always go into the bambooslurifto. keep that
fueled. And then we got the arrows, which go to
our courstrer farm and the gunpotder gets
converted into rockets and t nd t constantly, So
it's been a little bit time since my last episode
of this. It's not because I've been lazy. Not not
quite. I did the start playing mine craft
dungeons, and been playing among us in some
other games, so I've been taking it a little bit
easy, but I've also been doing a massive grind
project since last episode, so we started this
wither skelton firm. Last time we did the one
layer. I have since installed another two
layers. We got the upper and lower with the
piglins in the middle. so I had to farm up more
wiahther roses to get that finished up. And the
big thing though was finishing a slabbing the
area. It's not totally done. There's still some
caves I haven't found yet, but uh yeah, it's like
all done now. Pretty much. Ah, just went adown, I
did the perimeter and then Ah, I was like Okay,
Why is this still not working too good? Ight, I
still warn't getting to me with ther skeltons,
And then I found an area over our hair kindo
hidden away up and behind. I had to slab all this
section here too, everything above. Um, if you
have a big flat spot, it's a lot easier just to
span Lavan in it. That'sh I did for a big portion
of this, but yeah, I. think, I got most pol ey. I
think I be careful though, in case you forget
about it like where you put it, Alf. Yeah, we get
some up here to who Ows a cos cott Aha. Yeah, so
ethobe Slabbin got a lot of it done, But that's
not all. We also need a place to kill the guys and
to gather them and all that stuff right, So
started setting up something here as well is
walk up to Im. Hit him with the sword, nice and
simple. a, I didn't do the dog thing, though, as
its kindo lazy to do that, but every so often this
pushes hm. yether it took up to oclock, and then
we got a drop or ele it Woe laughed down there we
got drop her elevator to bring the drops up to
Esorting system. We got bones, three things for
bones, one for coal, and then the withere
skeltonheads, it gathered there, and uh, you
see, the rates aren't perfect, the definitely
not too bad right, but the rates will get a lot
better as well if I can find a few more of the
caves. I know there's a bunch hidden in the lava
and up in the ceiling that I need to slab over. And
then the rates will get even better, but ah, yea,
they're not bad. So the the cool thing about
this, Of course, we got unlimited beacons
Basically now we got fuel for smelting, but we
mainly want the farm for the bones whither
skeldind farms produce an insane amount of
bones, and I feel like bones and gunpowder are
your two base ingredients in the scheme
performing all the other things, So I wanted a
good source of ones in my world Here and now we
finally have it. There's one more kind of cool
thing about this, though, as well up above the
Witherskelton farm is the Goon farm and that guy
over there. Ah, so yeah, we got our besalt
farming thing here. Um, Ana bunch is stop right,
So that the thing is when we use our wither
scelton farm. We also collect iron
automatically from Lhe goon farm. Oatsolful.
Wow, Oh, it's overflowing. Uhoh. Okaysa, good
to know, so we cin get iron as we get to bones and
stuff as well. All right, so we're goin t take a
moment now to stop by the crimson. Keep. what do
you guys think about this project, by the way, D
you still like it, but you want to see more of it or
you'e kind of bord of it. Um, as much as I like this
nether update. I do worry that it's not really
that fun watching stuff done in the neather.
Still, I don't know. Itis is a just kind of a
feeling I have. but Ah, I do have more ideas with
this if we want O work on it. Saim more. The thing
we're going to do here, though, is that finish up
the Magma cube farm, we didn't have enough with E
roses for it, and I farmed a few extra so that we
could fill in all these missing faces. Ah, this
is the worst part about with the roses. You can
never tell if you miss the spot because theyre
all like in different positions. I think we got
em all now. Oh, it is a thunder storm. yea, Okay,
this it. this is your chance. 've been trying to
do this for weeks, you get the stupid mushroom up
here. Let's see if hopefully this doesn't kill
him. Dhon't want O hit you hard. but it's not
thrown in the sike. I don. If wer really quick, we
might be able to make it think it's over here.
Han, We got a mooshroom There, Go through the
Pordal. Oh, it spawns us under camps. No, Yes, we
dinit ground mushrooms and cortullya, but if we
need em, we go mo so in terms of like farming
resources, and stuff, the main thing we need in
our world. Like more than anything is
villagers. We have this underground village.
It's graid and all. I use it all the time. but the
villagers do die here. Unfortunately, it's not
like a foolproof thing, so we need to get
something a bit better. Um, Ooh, I got a
breakfast, don't i yo ogto break it and he still
stuck. Get out O there. Okay Dariol. Oh, he
finally got his trao stock to kill, put that back
and I didn't get the divilent sine Okay, we're
goin to go to the nether. So the planis. we're
going to make some kind of villaer breeder in our
netherhub, so that when we need these guys
anywhere in our world, Ih, we'll be able to get
them and transport them through another. Not
that one you won't go through in the mancat,
right, so I got knock yo out of that. You won't go
through, out of a mind hirds, Okay, that's not
Ea. You can go through. Go ahead. The more the
marrier. nobody wants to go through my portals.
This is isn't e word denote Okay. It looks like I
can't send items through either, which is
interesting. So think as the chunks aren't
loaded here or the portals not conneced
properly. Oh, it connected over hers. It is not
the right place. I mean it is the right place, but
it's not the place. it normar ten and now Ay now
that I actually made a portal they'll go through
Be good or you regot one guy. So if you're
training a villagers, throug raport. I'll
probably the easiest thing to do is just to do
this around it. That way they will stay near the
portal and not run away. They won't run across
tracks. O. that works really good. We just try
get em there. We go. O. k. now, I' got to figure,
out how to get them where I want them. Oh man.
okay, so this actually worked out really good.
Were really close to where I wanted them to go.
Actually, I just dug out a little thing Her.
We're going to push em up. push them up. E. All
right, made it to go round the corner. and this is
exactly where I want them to go Stup here. And now
we are above our netherhubb. is the netherhub
over here, so we're going to make like a an area
here for breeding villagers, and then we can
drop them down. Yea so ol of our tunnels have
tracks, so we can just drop em down in a mine card
on a track. They won't take all damage. Or maybe
we'll use a boat or something and we'll be able to
asend them anywhere we want them to go in our
world, Allright. Then the plan is to pig out a bit
of an area here and it can take a bit of time. to,
get these guys breeding, so let's get that
started right away. I got to be so careful with
this. I have definitely accidentally Rand lick
beds before in Anether, and is the worst thing.
Ah, oky, so I'll have to set up a bunch of beds, a
bunch of work stations. I guess let's mus put the
lectrons in front of the beds for now. It's night
time All right, So they shore to count Den is
sleeping Now it's great. they'll be able to
breed in the morning. I got get the some food for
these guys, though I'm out O here. This isn't
exactly the best place for the Sgab. but I've got
our farmer guy over here for right now, Om, an
just one to make sure he doesn't escape or get
killed, So we're going to buy a bunch of bread op
of him to feed to our new cillagers. Here you go.
Don't that sound like a baby? We got a baby, Ha,
right so it's workin, but anyways,
unfortunately, that's probably as far as wi'll
get on that project today, because I am all at a
time. I have actually spent way too long on this
episode. Lots of grindy stuff on this this
episode. Ah, but yeah, our infastructure in the
worldis getting much better, which is great,
but let's get to the comment of the day it says, Do
you ever go back and rewatch any of your videos
like, the speed challenges, for example, do you
think you would be amused as to how your thought
process was for certain things? Now being years
more experienced, I am sure your viewers would
love to see an up to detd speed challenge of some
kind, reviving the old days. Aha, yes, O,
typically like I don't rewatch my videos
sometimes, Il, I'll see some stuff, Um, A,
mainly like the videos I find more interesting
to rewatch are like the Team Canada stuff, cause
eh, younoeg me interacting with other people
and I find it interesting. I all. I'll be
rewatching it. My memory is not quite perfect. I
remember most stuff, but they'll be like. Okay.
what am I going to say next? in this situation
I'll compare, like what I would say nowadays,
tho what I'll actually see in the video and a lot
of times it cattes me off cars like oh was not
expecting that or sometimes they'll be like.
Oh, Hit was a little bit snarki. You know,
Isabet. I was a bit immature back then. you know,
probably wouldn't have responded like that
Nowadays. that's kind of fun to see that, but uh,
generally I don't really watch my videos. As far
as speech hallenges go. That's like an old
series I had where I would try do a certain task in
the game as quick as possible, like a start from
scratch and go to the nether kill aghast as quick
as possible or early. I think one of my better
challenges is I tried to brew all the potions in
the game as quick as possible. I godlike really
likey o. Matt. Run an it in like thirty five
minutes or something. I remember. I was pretty
proud of that one. Um, but I haven't touched the
series like since then, Ah, speed speedriting
an mind crafters become more popular. Those who
maybe it's worth the thinking about T again, or
like, even hardcore mine craft people are more
interested in now, So it could be fun. I have been
wanting. That may be start from scratch in the
nether. That something haven't tried yet since
it's been possible. Ah, and that might be fun.
but uh, yeah, nothing definite anyways.
hopeully, I's enjoyed to day's ef fiso. thank
you for watch an I help you, Ave a wonderful day.
Take here byebye