hello how's it going everybody this is
Ethan welcome back guys I've had enough
of this I keep putting this off finally
going to put in a lava blade here I
don't know exactly how it's supposed to
be done but I'm going to try it so I
think this is my plan I'm going to put a
sign here sign here alright
because what keeps happening I keep
putting it off and then they fill up
this this spot and I got to blow them up
with TNT and usually I do that when I'm
in the middle of something and there's
like I'll just put the lab will aid in
later and then I come back and there's
tons of them here um there's actually
quite a bit here though still I wondered
can I do this with them down in here I
want to try put a sign like two blocks
below the one we just placed oh I did
get it okay can't do that all four sides
mmm Oh aha okay and got it good and
final one right there good okay so now I
think I can place lava in between we
made a sign sandwich here alright
and look if there's any drops left after
I do this
I hope I did this right that looks
pretty cool all right oh yeah I see
stuff Oh
but I might not have placed that high
enough let's just go down let's look
what did we do exactly so the lava was
here that's three blocks up I think
that's right right got 32 iron from that
so I'm gonna put hoppers down here I
guess to pick up the iron and we should
be good
uh-huh and there we go now start it ah
all right tell you what guys I'm gonna
do this and then we will are you serious
let me out of here there we go finally
bump bump bump bump bump bump bump
does it work looks good
I was worried he's going to swim in it
but he goes right down that's good
got the hoppers in there and it's gonna
be okay yeah he died cool and there's
iron sweet so I'll just add some chests
down here and it should be good that was
right there so let me show you our iron
supply over here um we still have a ways
to go to fill in this chest up but I'm
too excited I want to get started on
this like for realsies today I think so
we're going to head over to the Nexus
and start setting up some stuff there
okay I'll see you there alright guys so
here we are at the Nexus let me tell you
what's going on here so I've been doing
some digging we're going to move this
stuff down to this level so that we can
do some staircases down into the storage
room last episode we started setting up
these face plates there was a bit of
confusion as to why I would have just
single chests at the bottom here and
I'll tell you I'll tell you what's going
on so this is the big secret this is the
the goal the feature that we're trying
to achieve with this storage room the
main challenge here I'm going to sleep
really quick keep you on suspense so we
do want to have an automatic sorting
system like you drop items in a chest
they automatically go to where they
belong in the storage room alright the
other thing though let's go back I
didn't have enough time to start it last
episode so I just put chests here these
are actually supposed to be droppers so
i deceived you a little bit the other
goal of this thing though is to have an
automatic retrieval system so you can
request items out of the storage room
without having to go into
which is going to be complicating
because there's going to be 256
different items in here how do you pick
which one you want and how do you get it
out like you can get items out of a
chest using a hopper and a and a dropper
right but how do you pick it so that is
that is the big challenge what we're
going to do we're going to be setting up
some kind of thing like this at the main
command room and depending on the
different combination of these levers
each one of these is like a bit so
there's 256 different combinations you
can do depending on how these levers are
arranged like maybe some are down some
are up and you would select which item
you want that way out of the 256 then
hit a button for requesting that item
they'll probably be a few different
options for how many items you want and
it's going to send a bunch of pulses to
the proper dropper down there we'll
probably also have some kind of chart
over over here explaining which item is
what with the combination because
there's no way I can remember 256
different combinations and what item is
what so we'll need some organizational
system to it too um but I'll tell you
what I'm going to start moving this
stuff down here and then I'll show you
how we will be able to control the the
droppers and there we go so I cleared
out some more space got these droppers
in place this is probably their official
position now there is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 of
them 8 times 4 is 32
that's 1/8 of our total storage room
over here and I am going to show you how
I'm going to start wiring up the
retrieval system so how we're going to
do the binary the bits so yeah it's
basically yes or no
we trigger this dropper or not and the
easiest way of doing that in Minecraft
that I found is to use sideways sticky
pistons I think I think some of the more
like computer redstone guys might know
more about this than me but this is how
I'm going to do it and I decide to space
these three blocks apart instead of just
one so that we can have more details to
the build like aesthetic details and
also it's going to make the redstone so
much easier and efficient because I can
get rid of like eight repeaters per
section or something crazy so I kind of
need to like make a circuit board almost
so much redstone is going to be involved
in this so these these sticky pistons
here are all part of one bit one of
those levers over there this is like the
high bit or the little bit I forget what
it's called exactly but there's going to
be 128 for this bit the next bit there
will be 64 Pistons in the next one 32
and 16 it gets progressively less it's
like we're building a pyramid type of
thing I don't know it's hard to explain
basically we will have a row of
repeaters then the next bit would start
somewhere here not exactly sure how to
do it maybe like this and this it
doesn't really matter if they're not
exactly the same timing I do have to
make sure I don't set my repeaters
longer than one tick though and I can't
use redstone torches when I when I do
this as sort of a limitation that we
have to follow because I'm going to be
using a rapid pulsing clock to get the
items out of here and if it's a long
delay on that it's going to take forever
to get our items so we have to make it
as quick as possible um I think we do
something like this then
and yeah it kind of makes a pyramid so
here let me show you if I power this
it's going to branch off to the right
only because that's where this block is
if the block was or if this bit was
active it would switch to the left and
it would go to here and then it only
goes to this dropper because the block
is not over here right so here I'll put
up a cobblestone and I sin how about
that so oh yeah so if I click this only
one of the four droppers are going to
get activated it was that one there if I
extend this cobblestone gets triggered
if I power this it's going to switch to
ice like that ah so the other thing we
got to do underneath all of these we
will need to connect the one of those
levers hmm tell you what I'll do it off
camera the eye I don't want to spend too
much time on this today I want to do a
few other projects but I thought we
would just kind of look into it a little
bit
aha so check this out guys when I pull
this lever now it does this but uh so
this isn't super complicated redstone or
anything it's actually really simple
it's gonna line the redstone running
underneath each of the pistons and
depending on if this is powered or not
it switches between the different
droppers right it chooses which one to
pick and for this first line there's 128
sticky pistons then the second line 64
32 16 and it just chooses which branch
to take as we make our way through it
right so to actually connect this to our
control panel very simple all I got to
do is connect one of these bits to this
first line of sticky pistons is like
right to this all you got to do
the second lever up there I would
connect to the second line of sticky
pistons let's get our ender pearls this
one here where there's half as many and
half as many past that so it gets easier
and easier um and yeah by doing that we
can choose exactly hey guy
exactly which dropper we want using
those eight levers up there um but I
kind of used up all the redstone I had
on me and even though we've collected a
bunch over at our at our area there our
Nexus Fund I think we should do
something else today okay so we are
going to did you do I don't know tell
you what let's go you guys that you guys
wanted me to set up some scarecrows
maybe we'll do that so we'll head over
to the the windmill over there alright
so I got some pumpkins I got some
leather let's make maybe one full outfit
I don't know if we should use all the
pieces but we'll try them out and a hats
alright so I brought some straw I don't
know if we'll need it and I was thinking
what should we put the stick scarecrows
on and maybe a fence would look good so
I'm going to try that do that and that
good okay
let's go oh no I didn't make the armor
stance whoops
alright and just make a few quickly and
that's not the recipe is it no what did
I do wrong again
Oh move it up there we go sweet I
haven't made too many of them yet I've
been distracted by all kinds of things I
wanted to use them more so maybe we will
put one now let's put one over here so
and I don't want to jump I'll trample it
crops let's see if I just place it
straight on it
ah I fell through darn it
and I'd yield the crop and it like
jumped off somewhere did I get it back I
think I did okay we probably need a
block then and I'm gonna have to trample
him there we go
now if I drop it is it gonna stay oh
that's not good it's floating um dad
pumped you in chest piece for sure right
how's that look probably shouldn't be
floating right I'm not sure um Oh
that was spooky let's try pants just to
see scarecrows usually have pants don't
they I think they'd do maybe not
um it looks kind of goofy okay how about
this
we'll give them a red plaid shirt and
blue jeans ah that's what I think of
when I think it was stripped row anyway
there's lots of different types though
and we'll sit him on a hay bale maybe
and see what this looks like do that
okay yeah I like that more I think yeah
yeah I like that a lot more mm-hmm
so I made three of them this guy this
one and
where's the other guy oh he's turned
around he's over there they're pretty
cool I like them good suggestion
everybody that suggested them I like it
so next up I'm going to attempt to make
some custom trees along our path here
which is something I don't have a lot of
experience with let's see I will maybe
build one I'm going to build one here to
start off with just like short 2x2 trees
and hopefully they turn out good this is
tougher than I thought I'm having a
little bit of trouble but I'll keep
working on it
it's a little thin on the side I'm
hoping if I just BAM leaves around it's
gonna look good it might be a bit of an
optimistic outlook but I guess we'll see
cuz either supposed to be branches and
yeah I guess we'll see what it turns out
like and there we go guys that is the
finished product that is how I'm gonna
leave it get it leave it leaves ah ah I
had a bit of trouble building it I
thought it was going to be easier than
it was about I guess it's one of those
things I'm going to have to practice and
I added all these little droopy leaves
on it because it looked pretty pretty
flat without them from a distance I
think it's okay I tried to build it up
quite a bit it's it's like hundreds and
hundreds of blocks man I can't believe
in it looks so small now that I see it
with the leaves it should have probably
been at least a block or two taller but
yeah anyway it was a good learning
experience I added a bit more to the
roots as well
try to make them kind of crazy-looking I
thought I was going to be able to build
like three and 15 minutes or something
no it's like 1:00 to at least half an
hour and I'm all out of wood and pretty
much out of leaves now so we'll go we'll
go do something else now oh man it is
time again guys to play our new favorite
game Oh bah operation population
annihilation that's right not just Greek
food so pick your guy who do you thinks
gonna win I'm going to play legit this
time no armor i starved myself so I
won't recover how so I'm a I'm unworthy
contestant here I have the same amount
of health as these guys they are so loud
stop humming in my ear
alright so take your pick we have a
fisherman and a farmer that are the same
color I try to always pick guys that
look different but sometimes can't be
helped so take your pick who's gonna win
here we go oh oh not looking good for
the librarian haha oh man they're all
going down oh oh that guy's doing good
over there all right did we lose one
note we haven't lost one yet they're all
hiding against the walls Oh Oh might
lose the butcher here oh no I got hit oh
one guy down was that that was oh I
gotta pay attention
lost another guy there and if I get hit
again I'm dead
oh no I walked into it yeah started can
we watch can we see who is there's too
much fire I can't see there might be a
flaw with the game the cleric is still
alive I can see that
I think the cleric is going to win
because he's the only one I could see
all right tell you what we'll try run
back
oh I'm I select here good we might be
able to catch it darn we missed it
oh no oh no no no no okay I'm gonna say
the cleric on that but I'm not sure so
unfortunately that is all the time I
have to record today guys so let's wrap
it up with the comments says ESO what is
your favorites non minecraft game and
what games did you grow up with or light
in your childhood oh man best question
ever I could talk so long on this but
we'll have to hurry my favourite game as
a child was Commander Keen I played all
six of them and the dreams awesome game
awesome game I played fill the jungle
lots cosmos what else was there I pretty
much got into video games when I was
four or five I think I got my Nintendo
when I was six or seven like a regular
Nintendo then I got my first computer
when I was eight paid with it or paid
for it with my own money
it's like 100 bucks or something at 286
44 megahertz I still remember the stats
on it it's so funny 40 Meg hard drive
oh yeah um was there jazz the Jackrabbit
um maniac mansion sent a max oh then I
could get into console games I don't
have a lot of time no this I could talk
seriously long time on this maybe we'll
move on to my favorite non minecraft
game so I would have to say ah that's it
stuff I really liked Mario Kart 64 a lot
but if I was to I think probably I like
Super Smash Brothers Brawl a little bit
more though and it's a more current
theme so I'll go with that Harvest Moon
series also a contender I also played
the worm series a lot when I was like 13
to 17 I played worms Armageddon and
worms world party as my introduction to
online games and oh man but anyway I'll
leave it at that
yeah you can ask me again later I'm sure
I'll talk about it more so that that is
it for today guys I hope you enjoyed our
episode if you have any feedback feel
free to leave it below and have
yourselves a good day take care bye bye
you