hello everyone how's it going you
probably can guess what I've been up to
here looking on the Enderman farm spent
another hour to on it today I extended
it out further
I finished the third ring
I replaced the watermelon with orange
wool I got like the look of it
I tried green wool and it was had too
much contrast it's really stood out so I
tried orange and I think I'm going to
keep orange I might just for looks
change this inner ring with orange and
then the very outer one with orange - I
think that might look cool but no
urgency on that so it seems to be
functioning really well yeah getting
good rates I added it up today and just
the second let me check my calculator
432 spawning spaces so that's that's
good it's not a thousand like I wanted
but it's it's not bad I think I'll
probably keep it at that possibly make
it one more ring yet but this seems
pretty good and I thought about it a bit
more too and I talked about maybe making
this into an optional XP farm or have
them Auto kill from falling further by
raising and lowering blocks with pistons
not going to bother with that I'm just
going to make it into a straight XP farm
and nothing more
because I can't really see myself just
sitting around here trying to gather
ender pearls I get so many of them as it
is I don't need to wait around for more
I got
I think three or four double chests full
now and I just barely finished this so
that's what we're going to do I have to
raise this up one block that means that
whole area that I have outlined that's
about a 40 by 40 square so I thought a
quick way of maybe raising it would just
be to flood it all with water and then
pour live over top to make smooth stone
so that's what I'm going to try here and
another nice thing about doing it that
way is it will get rid of all the
torches really easily so here I go
all right I got it flooded now I put
water along this side and that side and
that only took me about two minutes or
so which isn't bad for 40 by 40 area and
I added that up and that's about 25
stacks cobble you would need to to fill
this all in one block high which is a
lot these guys if they fall down all
that way and as soon as they touch the
water they teleport and they have full
health - the water damage so all those
guys pretty much have full health in
front of me so keep that in mind if
you're playing or messing around with
these guys they teleport instantly when
they touch water and here we go this is
what I was waiting to do I love doing
that oh yeah
let's getting them all that's so cool
all right so we got it all flooded now
Chain Reaction flooding now we got to
put lava on top
these guys are having a bad day I don't
know how this is going to work out and
it'll probably I'm guessing it'll take a
long time for the lava to disappear I
should probably start at this is freaky
probably start at one end and I'm
working my way back to the other and I
don't think don't think I put it
directly on the water so I'll have to
put and how about you this MA better
turns down a bit more just to start it I
need something to put it on oh let's see
I guess all I'll do one of these oh yeah
that's fine spread spreading yeah good I
got to do that all the way long that'll
replace all the water with
it's milestone I actually don't have a
whole lot of cobble to waste on this
kind of stuff I used a lot building this
this bottom platform and all the all the
pistons I use down there they take quite
a bit of cobble too so I don't have a
ton for waste but I guess I got to do
this for a while here so I'll see you in
quite a few minutes once I get this all
done so I'm getting close to about half
ways done filling this place up it's
going to take the lava a long time to
disperse when I've done this but it
seems to seems to be working okay I got
that pretty decent pattern going I'm
just juggling two lava sources to give
them time to spread that's the main
thing of slowing this down as lava
spreads so slow but you're just kind of
going along as curious to see how how
quick this would be and it's pretty
decent I think it's comparable to the
amount of time it takes you to actually
place the blocks but it's definitely
faster than the time okay it takes to
mine the blocks cart them here and then
play some hoops not date okay I can't do
that again I did that once already and
I'm down to my last two lava which I
need so you could do this like if you
need to convert an ocean around your
area into land like you don't want the
ocean there you could do you could do
this get rid of it pretty easily
and pretty quickly it's pretty fun
watching the Enderman die I got to say
it's my favorite part of this whole
thing but anyway I'm going to continue
and I'll let you see it when I'm all
done here
so I got it all finished I think it took
me maybe 20 to 30 minutes to do which
isn't bad for 1,600 blocks that's that's
pretty good time lava seems to be
disappearing pretty quick to take
another 5 10 minutes it'll all be gone
and I only spilled in two areas over the
edge which is not bad
I was pretty careful there is a few
water spots left though that I need to
fill in and now all the guys that land
on this pad will be one hit one hit
wonders it's good yeah so I can move on
to the next stage I have a pretty good
idea for how I want to do this
Enderman farm now which we will probably
be able to try out today I'm going to
build a a fence area I think where I
have outlined all around here I'm going
to put a fence that is like this all the
way around this square and I'll be able
to pass through it but they won't be
able to pass through it to get me and
then oh I did spill a few more places
and then we will hook up the our
automatic system for hopefully
harvesting them we'll see if it works I
have a feeling it will though so if it
does this farm is going to be absolutely
awesome
aha enchantment time fifty levels of
Enderman death it's beautiful
we're going to do a pic here excellent I
love it can never get enough of those so
that in ermine farm is going to be
awesome I'm just going to say that we're
going to do a few more things to it yet
so I'm going to head back there I just
had to pick up a few things here and
I'll let you see how it works all right
guys here we go
fences up these guys are all neatly
together here all one-hit wonders they
seem to fill up this area really quick
too which is awesome and just to test it
out I made a little area here with a
covering over top so they can't get me
and I've just been looking at all them
and this works amazingly well very good
XP farm and generally by the time kill
them is more there to take
please there's just so many of them and
you could throw splash potions here too
so I'm really happy about this but we
got to automate this further at least
try so I brought powered rails with me
minecart track mine carts we're going to
set up a rail here that goes back and
forth with my mouse cursor set at a
specific height that gets them
aggravated and I'm hoping I like them
all come towards the side here as they
as they fell down and collect together
kind of like they're doing here I will
probably have to put a roof over top
here though they like to teleports on
top of it and if I leave this area they
they're ready to attack them so needs to
be three blocks wide or so safety and as
far as looks go I'll probably not keep
this as an official look of it I might
replace this with grass I don't think
they can steal grass if it's directly
below them but I could be wrong I think
he has to be at least level like if that
was a grass block they could take it but
if it's below their feet I don't think
they can so we might be able to use
grass or some colored wool or something
we'll figure out a pattern I don't use
color wool very often so if this looks
strange to you I tried my best I'm not
that good at making patterns and
choosing colors but anyway we're just
trying to get the function of this going
first and then we can make it look
pretty afterward
this like I said this end area is sort
of like my skyblock survival in my LP
this Enderman farm is going to be the
center whatever I build here I might
build some farms and stuff around this
thing probably put some trees down try
and make it look nice as the LPL
progresses into the future of course not
not all in a row or at once here so I'm
going to work on this some more and I
will be back all righty so I installed
the rail line which will make me go back
and forth on this track this is just to
test it out first we can work it
perfecting this later like for example
this roof I will take damage getting out
of the minecart so I might replace it
with half slabs or glass or something
this is three blocks wide this fence
thing above me so that they won't be
able to attack me from the side where
the side and now we're going to do our
first test run here I can't remember if
I said or not but the official name
we're going to go for on this thing is
as you guys suggested the ender ender
the ender of the Enderman the ender
ender good name good name I like it and
I missed it today I just got to get the
cursor at the right height make sure our
volume is not too bad so this will take
us back and forth there's a limit to the
number that will track me though this
might be going too fast
not maybe not ones in the back might be
not sure hmm I think it's going too
quick how can I slow it down your way I
could use a furnace mine hurts to push
me instead I know the track that XP Hey
right stop he's working pretty good if
you move the mouse cursor really slow it
seems to track a lot
definitely having trouble with a
minecart stop explosion see there the XP
orbs doing it or the girls okay so you
get pretty much everyone I go across if
I do it walk this right
awesome farmer I love it
levels are going up the XP seams get
stuck out there to those all to come up
with some we're dealing with that can't
just walk out and get it I guess but
okay another thing I want to play around
with this idea of splash potions so I'm
going to grab some I have four I brought
with me here and I'm going to let this
fill fill up again although it's pretty
much full already
we'll try check around a few of them
around and see how they do yeah I
brought four of these things with me
just the regular instant damage ones and
I want to throw them sort of randomly at
these guys and see how many I get I
think these splash potions have a
diameter of about nine blocks so they
teleported they did hey Jim a try was a
bunch of them in front of me I think the
limits like 25 will follow you at a time
that's about the most we will get
actually I should see if I can get tons
just following me
oh well that was a weird view you can
see the guy above going crazy so I would
like to find a way to keep them from
getting on top there I could maybe put
water that would kill them Oh get more I
chant Wow
how many more can I get here some of
them might be becoming an aggro at me
yeah I'm in a limit here whoa
doesn't kill him Christine
okay I don't know what else to do here
today
yeah I've been gaining levels like
unbelievably quick here this is this is
amazing
really happy with this farm more
enderpearls than I'll ever need this
rail line though it does work like it it
really does but the problem is it moves
quicker then the Enderman can walk so
the even though they're tracking me they
they leg behind and I can't hit them I
can deal with the issue of its stopping
by simply creating a bigger buffer here
like I can reach way farther than one
block so I don't need it this close but
then I have the issue of the XP getting
stuck on the pad you know I think the
best thing to do here is just to do the
manual look around method except setup
in the center so that these guys one
thing won't do you spawn because as is
right now standing where I am the ones
in the left and right back corners there
will be spawn because it's it's a
40-block square the mobs despawn if
they're 32 blocks away from you they can
so I'm gonna try that out I'm going to
set up in the center and see how it goes
it might the only problem about setting
up in the center is you have to do of
360 range of motion to get them all but
over here it's more like a 180 okay I
did something a little bit different
here I put half slabs on the ground and
made this three high I definitely don't
recommend that they can actually
teleport to where I'm standing and get
me they also do this weird thing for
some reason where they teleport away
when I look at them say humans got me
yeah so I'm gonna make this to hide get
rid of the Hat slab but we'll see if
it's any different all right let's try
this again this is two box high like we
had around that outside there that's a
fence I should be safe and hopefully
they don't do that teleport away thing
the advantage of being in the center
here is that it should be easier to look
at them I would think it makes a big
difference if you go slow almost like
you have to look at them for like a
split second before they will get mad at
you
maybe I don't know if you just do this
like really quick you might get the odd
one but generally they don't get mad at
you unless you go slow and pretty much
any every single one it's managing to
deal with that I seems like doing it on
the edge it's a little easier to get
them together though a little smaller
yeah I think I like the edge more just
because of the 180 mu 360 here makes it
more difficult to lick them all let's go
a little bit smaller yet oh just a
little bit see if we're still safe
now it's only a two by two protection I
have here very good something looks like
we're going to be able to do another
enchantment I'll probably I'm guessing
I'm gonna be enchanting a lot of stuff
between this episode in the next one so
I'll probably want to play with this
quite a bit
slow yeah I like it on the edge all
right well I guess I'm going to head
back we'll do an enchantment walks I'm
15 and in second gear there we go and
that will be the wraps for today so
let's head back and here we go and do an
axe I was thinking of maybe enchanting
some diamond shoes but like to try get
feather falling because I heard that
ender pearls don't causes much damage if
you have feather falling or protection
on your armor so that would be very nice
but I just you only need to do like a
level 20 or 22 enchantment on the boots
to have a high probability of getting it
so I'm going to use the 50 levels on
extra place when we lost and here we go
ah that's so sad so very sad well on a
sad note tragic we're going to end this
episode thanks for watching and I'll see
you again next time