[Music]
hello everyone this is Ito and welcome
back guys how are you doing today
everything good hopefully everything is
good you guys warned me not to use
command blocks in my let's play world
and I thought it would be a good idea
maybe you were right things got out of
control here pretty quick no no no the
reason we're in this creative world I
just wanted to show you two really
simple and fun command blocks you can
use if you want to blow something up the
first one here is a redstone clock that
activates 20 times per second it's
really simple and then this one here is
the thing that places TNT below my feet
so if I activate it with that redstone
block anywhere I walk we summon some TNT
below us and if we ever want to disable
this we can put another block by it and
then break this one otherwise if you
want if you try to break it it won't let
you but anyway so this place is TNT
below your feet and it lets you do these
trails in the sky which are pretty cool
because when you activate this it
follows a chain for forever pretty much
as long as you make it go and it's just
like an ongoing chain of explosions
which is pretty cool you make them for
shapes in the sky and fly around if you
want you can see some sometimes it
doesn't always did it all because I'm
also like goofing around with these
SuperSpeed boots may make me run really
quick and play some fast but when you're
ready to blow it up go ahead and do that
and you make it chase you
all right let's try run all the way down
oh man oh it blew up the commandblocks
good well not the command box the
redstone anyway just a fun little thing
I thought you might enjoy let's go ahead
and okay right let me let me get this
right this is gonna be the greatest pun
ever yeah that's the one we want let's
hop to oh I can do better I can do
better guys let's hop to all right let's
play world so everyone today we're gonna
be doing something pretty cool I think
I've been looking forward to this for a
while and I think I think today's a day
we are going to be starting our new base
we've been at the man cave here for a
long time and we've been finishing
things and making things look nice and
that's been great and all that but I
think it's time we venture out and and
made me start building somewhere else I
love that we're not by any means leaving
the man cave behind here or anything
we're gonna be going back and forth and
we'll probably work on things at the new
base and things over here and just break
it up a little bit have a little more
variety so I think maybe the best way of
doing this let's head out to where we're
gonna put our new base which is at that
flower forest in the amplified terrain
we found Oh what was it like 20 30
episodes ago now I checked the video
today thankfully I saved the coordinates
there it's at like zero X and negative
five thousand Zed so it's a little ways
out I think our nether track will take
us partway there as Oh we'll head out
there and then I'll go over the plans
for the new base because we're gonna be
doing it a little different than like
what we're doing here all right so this
is actually pretty good we have a rail
line that goes about halfway here
and then we had like this path that we
can walk the rest of the way except for
about a hundred blocks I had to dig more
my shovel has silk touch by the way
that's why I'm not using it I need a
piece of Flint which we just got all
right so this portal this is from before
I think we've got some horses out of
here before that's why I had that block
there so I dug all this just now
unfortunately I did not bring torches
always planning ahead this goes about a
hundred blocks give or take and I think
this is where we need to be so hungry so
hungry
this was like negative 625 629 whatever
then it goes down to about zero and I
believe this is where we need our new
portal so let's go ahead and set that up
I brought an enderchest with us I'll
need a piece of iron did not think of
bringing a flint and steel though woops
that's fine we'll just put it over here
so yeah
I had to improvise there cool so I
pretty sure this is going to be the
flower forest we'll check it out go
ahead and break that and we got to find
a specific spot where we're gonna start
out - there was a lot of good looking
places here so it might be tough man oh
I'm gonna be sad if this is all snow now
please tell me this is not snow this is
the area this is extreme hills okay so
we're just right by the biome apparently
mmm guessing we gotta go this way
wait maybe it was like negative 50 100
it might be this way actually we're off
just a little bit
yes so the reason why I've decided to
start a new new base I want to dedicate
this new base to the slime blocks I want
to start having some fun with those I
haven't really done anything with them
yet usually when something like that
comes out I try to incorporate it into
what I've built already had a few ideas
but overall I think the mancave might
just be a little bit too too finished if
I'm to say that there's not really a lot
of space to squeeze any extra like slime
block devices in with what we got built
already and also since we're underground
in the cave it does not work too well
for the slime blocks because they're all
about like launching you around and
launching things and there's not enough
space in a cave but this biome here this
is perfect because we got all this
vertical Heights there's layers it looks
amazing and one of the reasons people
have told me they don't like amplify
terrain is because it's hard to get
around in it which is perfect absolutely
perfect that's exactly what I want I
want it tough to get around so that you
have to use the slime blocks to get
around so that's the plan we're gonna be
we're gonna be dedicating the area to
slime blocks and and having fun with
them basically so let me look around a
little bit this area looks pretty nice
but I want to specifically find a spot
oh why am i I'm lagging uh this is the
end no we're fine but I'll do it back
all right so well these cliffs are
pretty tall aren't they just gonna take
a little while to get used to
oh man
yeah I think this is the cliff I'm not
sure everything looks the same around
here I'm not used to this area I tried I
think I tried to enderpearl up there and
I missed I owe ya I think that's the
tree I landed on maybe no no oh no maybe
it was this one oh no where's my stuff
there's my stuff yes oh I was scared
quickly quickly I've been in this area
for quite a while
gonna pick it up quick Oh enderchest my
tools I get my boots got my boots
awesome oh that was a close one that
area we saw at first I think that is
actually where we're gonna settle down
it it looks really cool and there's
cliffs all around it I think it's I
think it's pretty much perfect I've
looked a little bit here but I think I
like that area the most so far all right
I'm gonna double-check make sure I
didn't miss anything
yeah this spot right here doesn't this
look amazing especially I think this is
the place right there this cliff in
particular is pretty incredible there's
so many different layers to it we've got
all these little overhanging areas
there's some floating islands we got
waterfalls nice trees down below there's
even more of those overhang areas nice
dark spots and there's another big one
right there
we got this really cool formation here
it's like a tall narrow cliff with a
flat spot on top which is pretty cool
let's see what else do we got there's
another overhang down there clouds are
in the way though can't really see it
got the flowers everywhere lots of water
everywhere it's pretty nice
the question is though if we go over
here is it not gonna look good because
this is the spot that looks good yeah I
think this would be okay
like I think we should build on the
nicer-looking area because then when we
go back and take a look at our base it's
gonna look really cool it won't look as
nice when we're at our base though
because like this cliff is not quite as
cool as the one we're on right now but I
think that's the way we should do it
anyway
man all right I'm excited we need to
figure out a spot to put our chests
maybe maybe let's venture over here like
a little works spot with a bed in that
just to get started and then we'll try
to settle in a little bit better as we
as we're here for a while oh we can see
snow over there and we got to be careful
with that maybe let's check out over
here there was kind of a flat flat area
here by a waterfall I think maybe not
it's pretty hilly around here I want up
high is as my starting base just because
it'll be easier to find until I get used
to the area yeah this is pretty good
look at this
yeah nice flat spot snow over there we
won't really build anything here I just
want to put my chests here okay everyone
so I am starting to get pretty settled
here I brought over a few things I set
up a little base camp we got a portal to
go back and forth a little easier and
now we have to start building or
planning and it's it's it's making me
wonder where we should begin it's tough
when you got nothing to work off of
I think top priority though it is really
tough to get around here the way it is
I'm going through enderpearls really
quickly so we should focus on ways of
getting around that's sort of the focus
of the whole thing to be honest just to
have fun
didn't launched around and that kind of
thing so I want to do slime block
launchers I want minecart setups I want
eats roads and boat things and and
elevators all over the place is what
we're gonna be going for to begin with I
want to try a boat launcher see what
what do we need here sticky pistons
might need these a let's just take all
the redstone stuff yeah okay
do we need obsidian just take a little
bit of obsidian too just in case all
right so I am wondering if we can
possibly make a way of getting from this
Hill to down over there you see where
the the trees are there those two trees
it might be too far we got to get used
to like what's possible and not possible
with these slime blocks I kind of wish
they would launch you like twice as far
as they currently do there they're cool
and they're awesome and everything but
they are somewhat limited I feel with
the way that they're implemented
currently I doubt they'll change that
though so we'll have to just get used to
it
all right so to make a boat launcher one
a dispenser here to supply the boat you
need water above that which will wait on
doing I suppose and let's put glass
around here no we don't have glass how
about what should we build this out
let's see you stone for now because we
might be moving this and basically water
will be here we want this this one
launcher here will we'll shoot the boat
upwards then we want one that shoots it
sideways out this direction so we can
hopefully make it to the hill the reason
we're doing a boat launcher by the way
is because I think we'll get a little
bit more air
time that way to actually launch a boat
maybe we will put a button over here
like this so you'll be in the boat
sitting over here and when it when
you're ready to go hit the button and
you'll get launched off right and I've
done this before you have to go I think
two blocks up I have trouble making it
work just one block up sometimes it
would and sometimes it wouldn't so
there's a two block space between the
two alright and how do we do this I
think we can go here let's put a
repeater down oops oh I'm doing redstone
on camera what am i doing I'll skip this
in to show it to you because it'll be
quicker that way okay so I think we are
ready to try this thing out and see what
it does it's just a very crude setup
right now I'm not gonna polish it up
unless it works which I kind of doubt it
will because that's a far far distance
isn't it that's not like ten blocks
that's like 40 how far do you think that
is from here to there that's that's
pretty far we might need to set up a
second launcher in between or some other
trickery I don't know so the launcher
thing is here that goes to this block
there's a repeater down here at one tick
that has a there's a redstone there
comes up the staircase to this piston so
these fire or one tick apart to this
bottom one and this one here so we're
gonna do a dry run first
I had a dropper here too you guys may
have noticed which I replaced with the
dispenser I always mix those two up okay
so it's the boat going
yeah yeah made it no doesn't go too far
so I didn't hold up as I'm in the boat
though another give us a little extra
distance I'm fully expecting to die here
that's why I put all my stuff in a chest
but let's just see how far we can get
with it we go this mode I'm not sure
what the best mode is might be easier to
gauge Oh No we are short maybe 10 blocks
oh we actually hit the water that's
actually kind of bad I wanted to die
oops
that wasn't too bad I regret taking my
enderpearls that was a waste maybe let's
go one more time yeah that wasn't too
bad so we could do things like have
floating water in there too
like if we need a bit of an extra runway
alright just hop in we'll go this
perspective this time woo oh it's it's
pretty close awesome I like it that's
pretty cool I wonder hmm you know if we
built like something here that that
brought it forward like 10 blocks or so
like so that it was at the same height
but like above us here then we could
almost certainly make it wonder if we
should do that
okay so I think I want to try this in
here I don't know if we'll actually keep
it but it's it's an idea we should play
around with it this is a midair launcher
at the bare bones of what you need
basically this would allow us to bridge
the extra gap but if we liked this idea
we could potentially have them all over
the place and we can we didn't bounce
around in midair
and and chain them together and do do
all kinds of things but they might look
a bit out of place
we have water there to break the fall of
the boat so it doesn't break when it
hits something the pressure plate on
obsidian there
you need the obsidian so let the slime
block doesn't move it we could also
change this to a watermelon or something
I think sticky piston and redstone wire
down there so let's go and try it out
I'm wondering out if it's gonna beat it
to hit that target or if it's even in
the right place but try it out here see
how this goes we can move it if it's not
right woohoo oh we can't see oh is it
too far it is too far by like four or
five blocks whoa that was interesting
I bet the boat broke before we hit the
ground like just before so we didn't die
from it lavas gonna get me not you I
moved it let's see if we can do it now
again it's probably gonna be pretty
tough oh it's still darn it okay so I
moved this one forward two blocks
instead of that one I figured it'd be a
little easier and since we're just doing
this for testing it doesn't really
matter okay let's try it out
it's close oh we did it
no that looked really cool though I
gotta say even though it was a fail I'm
pretty happy with that I can't believe
that actually worked first try
well not first try but first try with it
actually setup right oh man so close all
right so yeah what we're kind of doing
just to start off here is the an idea of
some of the devices we could build to
get around and get used to like the
trajectory and how far they go I am very
curious actually how far that is this is
maybe will try to check it one more time
here
this is 590 okay I think we got one boat
left how far does it actually take us oh
I wasn't even aiming whoops 51 27 so
that's 37 blocks yeah okay oh I didn't
see the why we should keep that in mind
too but I'm sure the why is it least 40
50 bucks down I'm not sure I'll have to
check that well that's gonna do it for
today everyone let me know what you
think about the base idea and if you
have any suggestions for it don't be
afraid to suggest them leave a comment I
do read the comments and hopefully I'll
see it and yeah we're gonna be building
firms and that kind of stuff at the new
base too so there's gonna be a bit too
it's not just transportation only
there's gonna be a lot to it and the
firms are all gonna involve slime blocks
it's it's gonna be kind of like you know
that feed the beast season where I had
the minecarts jump in between the
islands we're gonna be doing a lot of
that kind of thing
- silly not really efficient ways of
doing things but just fun fun ways of
doing things is what we're focusing on
and as we get more situated there I'll
be able to build things quicker and yeah
anyway here is a comment for today it
says etho I was wondering if you ever
thought of posting something like a
first-person shooter or third-person
shooter or anything besides the sandbox
game have you ever tried a shooter in
the past I also think it's pretty ironic
that you named your pheasant nuggets in
your terra firma craft series and beef
named his horse nugget in his life in
the woods series keep making boss videos
and I'll keep watching
oh poor nuggets why do you have to
remind me of Nuggets it's okay we got
nuggets - now he's gonna live forever so
I haven't played a lot of shooter games
I have mixed feelings about them that
some of them are really good some of
them yeah I don't know I used to play a
third-person shooter called Transformers
war for Cybertron I like that game a lot
that was a really awesome game I got
really good at it too like I would like
to claim I was the best at it but I'm
not gonna do that I was close so I was I
would say I was top 50 at least I played
it so much eventually though the
community kind of died out with it and
somehow people figured out some hacks to
it like some some exploits in the game -
yeah I don't know it never got fixed so
the game kind of got rekt that was cool
the thing I don't like about a lot of
shooter games and I'm a noob here by the
way so don't don't get mad at me if it's
a stupid opinion but from what I've seen
there's a lot of quick deaths in them
and I don't like that like it's pretty
much you see the guy before they see you
and you can kill them I don't like that
kind of thing I like gunplay like where
there's a lot of back in the fore back
and forth where you have to react to the
movements of
other guy in war for Cybertron there was
a lot of that like you could instantly
kill people do in certain ways but a lot
of the times these pretty epic battles
would would happen that would last like
30 seconds to a minute where you're
fighting this guy and you're like flying
around the map and getting health packs
and just trying to stay alive and yeah I
don't know I like that style a lot more
than the quick kill method a lot of the
games use I don't think I would really
post anything on my channel I don't know
I find when I do play those games
sometimes it they just they make me feel
mad there are certain games that's like
provoked different feelings in you and
RTS games they make me feel really
stressed because they're so competitive
shooter games make me mad
games like minecraft and I don't know
these games just make me feel good
that's what I play and that's what I
like the post anyway that is gonna be it
for today guys thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next one bye bye
[Music]