[Music]
hey hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys
go get your snacks i just had uh death
by chocolate
which is a chocolate cake with whipped
cream
and chocolate pudding raspberries all
mixed together
and oh man it's so good so good that was
my snack for today so
go get your snacks let's have a good
time today's a good day because
that's right the snapshot is finally out
we're on 15w 31a the first of the 1.9
snapshots
and i'm very excited we've all been
waiting for it for so long
um i'm gonna get the nasty stuff out of
the way first
okay so i do not recommend you update to
the snapshot if you
are on a survival world like me it's not
ready yet there's a couple issues with
it i crashed already if i go
through this room i'm gonna crash so i
have to
stay out of it for today
and it's a bad crash it corrupted my
world so
be very careful make a backup if you do
try it
also there's some frame rate issues with
the snapshots
or maybe wait a minute i just reset my
computer and it's all fine now
huh okay maybe uh maybe there was
something wrong with my computer
but i'm pretty sure the crash was
minecraft related anyways
what we're going to do today i don't
want to miss all this new exciting
content so we're
going to have some fun with it today
we're going to go to the end we're going
to check out
the dual wielding look at this and all
the other fun stuff and then afterwards
i'll probably
load the back up and continue playing
1.8 until that
these snapshots seem stable enough to
use in our let's play here
so let's get to it dual wielding
look at this if you hold f it switches
between
goes into that new bar so we actually
gained an inventory spot
and we desperately need more inventory
in the game
so that's kind of nice um
you cannot push the tilde key to
select the this new special slots
i i thought they might add a shortcut
for that but uh it doesn't seem like it
because that's to the left of one on my
keyboard
which would coincide where where my
shovel is right now
uh but dual wielding so if you have
a shovel and a pick
left click does that right click does
nothing okay you can do it you can use
the right click
so this is the new path block as well uh
if you right click on grass with a
shovel it creates it
and apparently mobs don't spawn on it
which is kind of cool i don't know
i wanted to do a couple tests with it
all right i'm not used to the dual
wielding yet
if you have wait a second if you have
blocks
grass and soil right click does that
left click is your punch still okay so
it's if you have a weapon
or a tool and a block i think
yeah right click places the block left
click uses a tool
aha very interesting very interesting
so oh
if we put a torch down here
this is the crafting table switcher by
the way
all right let's do this place a torch i
want to see if light passes through
these uh
new path blocks so right now we're at
block lighting nine if we
till it stays the same okay
so light doesn't pass through you don't
seem to sink down in it i thought you
would
and as far as i can tell it doesn't
really change color with the biome
either
if we still touch it do we get it no
turns into dirt can we do that to
uh podzol i wonder
oh we're gonna load it back up
afterwards so it's fine if we tear up
our world a little bit here
no you can't right click on uh podzilla
all right
mycelium no can't right-click it on
with uh mycelium so it's only grass
blocks that turn into this
it actually suits the mantis kind of
doesn't it
all right so let's get to the main the
main topic here the main thing we've all
been waiting for
the purpose of the patch have they fixed
the boats guys
i haven't heard anything about them i
didn't see anything in patch notes
or what so i don't know
they rumored that they were gonna fix
them and maybe even seat two people
and uh
hope it's true oh it still breaks darn
it
so the next thing we're gonna do guys
we're gonna head into the end and check
things
out there that's where most of the new
features were added
in this snapshot so i got geared up
going to do a dragon fight probably here
i brought some clay just in case she
doesn't spawn i sort of
don't think she's supposed to be but i'm
not sure uh there is a way to summon her
with clay right now
and also wanted to try out these these
are the new spectral arrows that's the
recipe for them
so i guess you get two from it two for
one yeah that's what it is
oh no oh because i ran out of glowstone
i see
takes a lot of glowstone these are not
cheap
stack of glowstone uh that's a little
bits
for how fast you go through these do
they work with an infinity bow though
here let's get these both on our hot bar
to see
32 and 64. oh they do
um i'm pretty sure the texture is
missing on them that's why it's purple
right now
to be added
yeah it works very cool so that allows
you to see
uh what you hit through blocks it
creates an outline around them
be easier to track whatever whatever you
shoot at
i may as well leave the rest these
arrows here
and there's a few other arrows they
added but i don't think they're
craftable right now
all right so let's do it let's go into
the end and just see what we see
there is a dragon oh i wasn't sure
i wonder if the portal got moved
portal's still there
pretty sure oh yeah dragons flying
around
that's crazy i didn't do the dragon
fight with the beacon
um or my beacon's gonna get destroyed
here
she's uh she's doing something there
weird
the ai got changed a bit so there's a
few more attacks
i believe are the crystals back
no those are all broken okay
well let's get it on here
it's been a long time since i did the
dragon fight
oh she shoots fireballs now
that's cool she is still really hard to
hit
and she isn't charging at me like she
does she's like swaying all over the
place
huh the fight might actually be uh
more difficult if i can't get her oh
here let's turn the sound down it's
probably pretty loud
oops music
yeah let's get that down a bit oh is she
charging
there goes the beacon kind of stops
oh that's the dragon breath want to see
what this does
okay it does uh does a little bit of
damage
i do have pretty good armor on though
this makes it really easy to shooter
though
just kind of sitting there
and the spectral arrows are not working
on her at all
i'm noticing
oh there got a hit
it's half down haven't been charged once
yet
so maybe she doesn't charge anymore
man none of these are hitting it's so
far away
she's a lot faster now too it seems
[Music]
like how quick she's zipping around so
she must uh
fly around for bits shoot fireballs oh
yeah
and then she does that dragon breath
move and that's probably when you're
supposed to hit her the most
dragon balls didn't do a whole lot of
damage either though
okay down she comes oh she didn't stop
what invisible fireballs
okay work in progress guys
oh she's landing yeah
landing and
there was something in that chest that
isn't rendering apparently
oh snap they're all mad at me
it's all good guys it's all good how did
my spectral arrows hit them
did they not teleport
[Music]
wait a second no he teleported
it's kind of strange because he can't
shoot an enderman with an arrow they
always teleport
but somehow i marked them
what are these oh it says water bottles
yeah potions aren't really working right
now that's why i didn't bring any with
me
or the textures aren't
okay let's finish her off i'm gonna get
a second portal
oh i fell in my uh my mind over here
and
i'm close and personal oh yeah
uh i think the fight actually got easier
i like how she stops now
yeah another portal spawned very very
interesting
is let's double check if this one's here
or not
oh i see bedrock still it might be here
yeah so we actually have two portals in
the end from that kind of cool
so if you have a pre-existing world you
might get a
a bonus portal when they finally finish
all this stuff
that that dragon fight was was pretty
easy though i hope they make it more
difficult
maybe more fireballs getting shot at you
or something would be cool
because i was just kind of standing
around much like the
the original dragon fights so
could use a little bit more difficulty
scaling i would say at least on hard
mode
um let's uh should we go through no
let's not go through not yet
there is this thing over here
i think she's supposed to drop a dragon
skull somehow i'm not sure how you get
that maybe you can't get it
but i've seen uh pictures of a dragon
skull dragon head
i thought you got it by defeating her
but i didn't see it fall on the ground
anywhere
anyways yeah this is the uh
the new thing the big thing that was
added you're supposed to throw an ender
pearl into that
got it and did it
work i don't think it worked
it turned on for a second right let's
try again
oh bad throw yeah you gotta get in that
one
one by one block up there
it's actually a pretty tough throw
although i guess if you miss it doesn't
matter
are you supposed to throw several of
them or what
man here i'm just gonna stack up
i'm a i'm a cheater a throw isn't
working for me
oh that's trippy it's actually like
reflective or something
oh man i changed my keys today guys i
changed sprint to shift and sneak to
control
i reversed them so now i'm like walking
off ledges and stuff
i haven't adjusted to it fully yet
oh that did something this time okay
here we go yeah
oh baby so now there's multiple islands
in the end
and this is one of them look how many of
these plants there are holy smokes these
are the
coarse plants okay
what is the tool oh
uh you harvest them from the from
uh the bottom up
let's see if the axe is the right tool
oh yeah it's the axe
so it's just like chopping down the tree
and it just breaks all the way up
very cool uh you're supposed to be able
to get
a seed maybe from it i'm not sure i
think the top thing on it is the flower
yeah do we do anything for this oh yeah
we do
chorus flower so this is what i i think
you plant to get a new one you just put
it on the ground like that
and over time it'll start growing these
work off of block updates similar to how
reeds grow and and that kind of stuff
oh it grew already wow that was really
fast
and then when it's done growing this
flower turns dark
so right now it's kind of white um
eventually
it stops uh stops growing
can't put torches on it okay
i'm going to take this back with me i
want to see if it grows in the overworld
or not
we're going to engage lawnmower mode
here
chop them all down they break so easily
it's so much fun
it would be really cool if you could
grab these like with silk touch
like this actual block and then place
them together
and then when you finally do break them
it breaks a whole strand of
of whatever you place you know what i
mean like you could
arrange them however you want and then
when you finally break it
the whole structure breaks in this
domino like fashion
because it's a really neat effect but
like if you could put water on top of it
and then break it all and the water
would all pour down at once
that would be kind of cool
so with these plants you can do a few
things they're pretty important
you can not do that oh you know what i
think you gotta smelt them first
i think that's what the trick is uh
endstone also has a new block
that you can craft the end stone bricks
so you do a two by two looks like you
get four for that
and yeah they look pretty cool
i do like that that's a nice a pretty
nice texture to it oh they break fast
oh look at this
compared to that and break way faster
it's like normal stone i think
you can almost instant mine it not quite
oh maybe you can maybe you can huh
i'm not sure it seems like it stopped
there
one of the times but uh the other time
there it broke them all
all right so there's also
[Music]
apparently fortresses that spawn in the
end now i'm looking around for one of
them right now
might have to hop to one of these other
islands
i believe it's infinite now in the end
if we do an ender pearl throw what are
the chances it's gonna work
oh it was short let's get a little
closer
almost hit the island with that
there we go perfect oh
just about fell down there
uh yeah it just keeps going here oh
there's one right up there
okay that's where we gotta go i see one
in the distance i brought
four stacks of stone oh and i gotta hold
control i just about ran off the island
hold control we're gonna bridge across
to that and check it out
all right so i i bridged across here all
the islands seem to be pretty much
at the same height like i didn't have to
go up or down at all
it's perfectly straight from that one to
this one kind of cool
and we are on this island this is this
is the new fortress
and i gotta say that looks really cool
man they did a good job on this
the new purple blocks i'm a i'm a big
fan of these
uh what are they called perper or
something they gave them a really funny
name it means like purple and swedish
i believe yeah look at these
they break not quite as fast as the end
stone
end stone is instant mine with the
efficiency five here
there's purple glass in here yeah perper
these uh these fruits by the way if you
eat them you uh
just randomly teleport like an enderman
oh and
yes these are the new uh shulker mobs
i think that's what they're called right
oh i got hit
if you get hit you start floating around
and then you can save yourself with
these oh that
that wasn't very safe just about died
from that
uh teleports you to the ground though
when you eat one of these
which i am very curious wait a second
before we
go up the tower oh
oh no they got me again
oh snappers can you enter pro while
you're
oh yeah you can so if you get stuck in
that you can just ender pearl down
so you don't take fall damage i am kind
of curious
about one thing with these flowers
if you're if you just jump off a ledge
for example
can you eat one in midair
they take a long time to eat gotta go
higher
gotta go higher okay let's try this
again i'm gonna start eating before i
fall
oh i
hmm i kind of took fall damage right
oh weird i actually went higher
i was on top of that pillar and i ended
up up here instead
not what i expected
oh okay yeah that teleported me down
this time i didn't take fall damage it
took no damage at all
so that is pretty cool if you ever fall
you can just eat one of these
in midair and it'll save you
i think i i would like to try it like
falling from a very far distance and see
what it does
but yeah let's go into the building here
let's check it out have some
fun and just see what it's like
all right first floor is clear
good still okay this is getting a little
trickier up here
this is like the parkour section
oh and it splits off okay we got two
directions here you can either go this
way or this way
there was a new light added to
these things here i don't know if you
can craft them
i really hope you can because uh they're
pretty cool
kind of they got like sparkly effects to
them
and i've seen people making like
staircases out of these stuff
already you can kind of place them like
this
all the way up and then if these are
solid blocks like this you can just kind
of walk up it oh
maybe not maybe not i thought you could
let's try this oh yeah you can so if you
do that you you
make it like a staircase which is pretty
cool
um oh i didn't even see him
he was just right there there's another
one yeah there's another one hidden
there
oh and he got me
i want to kill one of these guys and see
what they drop
can i still touch you can't still touch
them
oh do they not drop anything
oh they don't
i thought at least they would drop the
chorus blocks but i guess you don't get
anything out of them
or else i got really unlucky with those
two
all right let's go uh let's go up over
this way
what would these purple blocks look good
with i wonder
emerald blocks for sure if you want
contrast
oh oh oh
we're going up yeah i've killed three
now we haven't got any drops from them
oh an ender chest in here
oh got hit again i'm going up higher
there's actually stages to the building
though so if you do get hit you can just
go up to the next
next step pretty much and you'll be fine
i think they're still trying to get me
up here can we poke a hole through the
floor oh you can
protection for respiration two
unbreaking three that is an insane
helmet
and i just threw it away
let's go back down for it
emeralds gold iron helmets
some pretty good loot
all right and did he teleport he must
have just teleported there
right
yeah still no drops from them um
[Music]
okay let's go up here ender pearl oh
that hurts
that hurt quite a bit
okay that time we got it i gotta be
careful i'm i'm pretty low on health now
uh this is this is kind of a special
building i believe it's got the banners
on it
i'm not sure if the shulkers respawn or
not
i suspect they would in
oh in the area defined by the fortress
kind of like the
the mob spawn in nether fortresses and
that kind of stuff
all right we're about to fall i thought
maybe not
that that time seemed to last longer
all right and
oh let's go to the top of this one this
seems to be
like the capital tower or something it's
got the banners on it
oh and we went past it we're still going
up
oh yeah there's a boat over there that's
the special one it's
actually got a beacon in it
all right we shortcutted the whole
building
is there nothing in it at the top here i
just not
there's lights there's lights that's
kind of good
i really hope you can craft these
i'm not sure i didn't see a recipe for
them though so i don't know how to
if you can right now oh
all right nothing at the top of that
tower
and let's keep going down
i just realized what it is it's a face
it's a face isn't it that's these are
the eyes
and it's like a derpy face it's got like
derpy eyes over there
that's the mouth and he's got some crazy
hat on right
i think it's a face a funny face
okay can we do this by enderpearl i'm
going to aim high and at the
ladder in the middle i don't think we'll
overshoot it but you never know
okay we just barely oh just barely made
it there
you sir leave me alone
oh he got me
oh is this a beacon up here or is it
down lower
must be down oh yeah it's down lower
okay so it's just shining up here
so yeah this is shaped like a boat oh is
that a special
oh no this is a normal block right
where is the difference
i want to go down let me down all right
wait a second let's compare that to the
other ones we got is it a different type
of block
we have two of those it's the pillar
ones okay
uh can go down here there's a brewing
stand
instant health 2.
oh in a loot room
oh baby some obsidian in here
oh oh wow
yeah these enchantments are pretty good
on these actually
gold look at this another great helmet
oh snap well that's better than
my current legs let's put these on
and i did put on that other helmet we
found
so there's a beacon here that's a really
nice reward i think that means beacons
are infinite right like
i don't think there's a limit to these
fortresses you can just explore the end
and get all the beacons you want here
and iron and stuff so that's pretty cool
if you enjoy exploring the end then
there's definitely a reward to it
which is nice and i think that's about
it though
yeah this is oh no no
my reaction times today are not very
good i just ran
out still getting used to this shifting
control change
instead of sneaking i'm running
but it's not that high up at least we
survived it
that's pretty good and yeah that's the
changes in the end guys i'm gonna grab
maybe a couple more of these flowers i
wanted to try grow them
and just see if we can grow them in the
over world i don't think you would
really want to though because
look how much end stone we got here
if you want to farm them this is a place
to do it
all right so to get back i think we just
have to throw an ender pearl back
into this thing and they'll take us to
the island again with the ender dragon
i've only seen two of these
like looking around here i didn't see
any more of them so i think these are
the only two
you get and they basically let you
transport through your
your dragon islands the normal one and
then the infinite
islands we just saw there with the
fortresses on and stuff i think is that
the idea behind it
so we're going to head back to the
overworld and just wrap things up here
for today i do want to try a couple
things though
where did we kill that dragon oh yeah
just over here
okay there is a chance if we did get a
dragon head it might have fell
in the portal and maybe got picked up
that's the egg uh let's
i guess let's try to get this egg grab
it
anything special happen with it that's
just a normal egg
so they're going to introduce a way of
summoning the dragon
like to re-summon it all you want right
now
what they just did is a temporary thing
you have to build a creeper face to
summon the dragon which is a bit crazy
i don't know why they don't just have a
special button they press or something
to do it but
apparently this is the way they do it
when they're
when they're testing things out i think
it's just a
creeper face like this and then eyes
oh i did it again i'm not holding the
sneak button
all right let's do this
and you got to build it out of clay
and yeah that's it
there there she is so she came back you
can dress you can summon as many as you
want and i think you can
have more than one at a time too but uh
we're gonna get out of here
before we die
oh the portal's gone
oh snap you devious you devious thing i
wanted to
hightail out of here is this one still
alive
yes haha i fooled you
all right that works
[Music]
and we're back in the the overworld here
so i want to do
just a couple more tests this episode's
getting a bit long
but i want to try grow some of these
plants
so i'm going to make a little in stone
garden for them
the new skeletons are pretty cool here
they are causing a lot of lag though
you see that speed jump um
[Music]
boom well that we saw him for a second
anyway
oh here's another one yeah they have a
draw animation now so it's no longer
randomly guessing when they're going to
shoot at you
it's kind of cool they seem uh quite a
bit smoother
in general
they still shoot pretty often i don't
think they do
the same like when when you get close
they shoot more often than when you're
farther away
can i not get off my horse oh there we
go
took a little while
yeah definitely a bit of lag with him
right now
um
yeah they don't they don't shoot super
fast anymore when you're up close to
them
that's kind of kind of different kind of
cool
changed that up so let's try plant some
some of these plants there we go
cut off and
you have to place them on end stone it
seems i tried placing one on the ground
doesn't let you can't place it on dirt
so it's got to be end stone and we'll
just put a few down here i don't know if
they need light or anything
oh yeah the skeletons are a little laggy
just a little bit got warped back in
time there for a second
let's just put some light down and see
if it matters or not
as far as i can tell you don't want to
put blocks beside these uh like when
they were growing in the end there i
tried that out
and uh didn't really work out too well
oh yeah they do grow look at that oh
that's awesome so if you want to make a
farm
in the overworld you can
you would have to bring the end stone to
do it but it is possible
so that's kind of nice i like that
well anyways guys that was pretty cool
we got a new adventure in minecraft
always nice
to get new content like that
and the blocks look really good i like
the new end stone and the new purple
blocks
i was just thinking those purple blocks
would probably be nice with sandstone
and sandstone is a really flexible uh
style block as well so
you have two types with stairs and slabs
you can do a lot of stuff with that
maybe even these prismarine type of
blocks would be cool
yeah lots lots of options with it i
would say uh
purple's one of those colors we haven't
really had much of so it's cool to get
to
get that in the game anyways i'm
rambling here let's get to the comment
of the day it says etho
you should try replacing the ice streams
in the nexus with
with stairs so damn just showed in a
video
a trick to make items flow faster in ice
creams if you put a stair over top the
ice and then have the item flow on the
the lower part of the stair it goes like
i can't remember what it was almost a
time and a half faster though
the only problem is in the nexus
we have space limitations
didn't really design it with that in
mind so right below the ice
is repeaters and redstone and stuff so
we can't actually do that
for the the main bulk of the the nexus
here only like once we get to this point
could we
could we do something like that when it
falls down here
and then over here we could do it so
might
might do something like that if it's uh
if it's going to speed things up it's
definitely a good thing to have because
the sooner we get the items the better
with our our setup here
so we're going to try optimize this uh
once we get
the time to do that next episode it's
probably going to be a nexus episode i
want to work on this again
uh so we'll check out whatever i do with
it
and uh yeah
had fun today hope you guys enjoyed it
i'll see you again
in the next one take care
bye bye