arrow in the knee maybe no okay hey
how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back to another
episode in the comments on the last one
oh man I had a stare somebody said
Zenith died and I like went to my
computer well I was at my computer I
loaded up minecraft right away and I had
to check it out he's fine he's good
because I left the door open here last
time and don t died and I would have
been so sad if Zenith did but he's good
he's okay
this guy took down a wither man for him
to like die because I left the door open
would have just been pathetic so guys
today maybe to start off with today we
will go to the nether I'm trying to do
some tidy tidy up work with the way
things run around here this portal
network thing whoops this seems to work
okay but there's a bunch of portals that
interfere with it that I can't control
right now and the majority of those are
oops oops are here these portals at the
gold farm I'm gonna have to add a switch
to these to turn them on and off if we
can so probably try to rig it in such a
way that we have a dispenser like right
right at this block here that with the
flint and steel in it and be able to
ignite it and maybe on the other end we
will have like a lab a budget that gets
put out and it extinguishes the portal
so let me try to get that going and I'll
be right back and it is pretty much done
here I'm just putting the final lava
bechet's in and then we can try it out
only took an hour which is probably way
more time than it's ever gonna save me
to like light the portals and extinguish
them manually whenever I want but you
know that's a comment I get a lot you
spent how long doing what that's gonna
save you one minute or two minutes of
time no that's that's not what minecraft
is about minecraft is all about trying
to make cool things right and if it
saves you time awesome this is this is
like two birds in one stone type of
thing the goal is to make something cool
as gold farm as cool right but what
would make it cooler is if we could turn
it on and off easily right so that's
that's sort of the point to this just to
try to make something better basically
and if it saves time all the better but
what what it should do one of them is
out right now this is the light them and
the wire is running down the middle here
to do that and then the one to
extinguish it it's all being controlled
by this thing this is this generates two
pulses kind of in a nasty way but it
does it it could have done it better but
I kind of wanted to keep it symmetrical
generates two pulses and then it goes to
the edges of the portals to the lava
buckets with displaced
and out they go did you get them all ooh
that looks good
cool let's try light them all again make
sure that works whoa
fell down the wiring awesome yeah that's
good that's exactly what we want I think
it got them all cool all right so those
dispensers that light it are like where
I said right here let's just steal one
of these for right now I'm gonna hook up
some controls to this one as well I just
want to show you something for for like
a month or two now if I ever leave the
nether to go back to the man cave this
is where it takes me inside the zombie
pigmen farm like in the cage and if
these guys are ever in here with me and
I have to get out well let's just say
I've died many times because I either
like try to break my way out and then
I'll hit one of them and then I'm dead
instantly pretty much so we need a way
of turning this one on and off too and
maybe the one above yeah there might
have been a reason I never automated
this now that I that I've tried I had it
all set up here put the laven and the
the flint and steel and all that it was
ready to go and then I found out that it
it was stealing it because below the
dispensers where I need to put them is
the hopper timer and when it runs it it
steals anything we put in the dispensers
and I am NOT moving this thing because I
had such a hard time getting this all to
fit before so we'll just pass on this
one I think although I just had an idea
let's try this out
there was a portal I used to use fire
churches on and I would like shoot them
from the corner here I'm wondering if
this trick still works or not
nope nope I think it was in the corner
maybe it wasn't
let's try one block up maybe it was a
little higher because that would be
really cool I basically just can't put
the dispensers where they were there
they can be anywhere else probably you
see the squid there I'm so tempted to
name this guy I'm not sure if you would
live though or not if you would
suffocate eventually oh it does work
still okay is that consistent do I have
a yeah let's do this it's funny I say
extinguish the portal with lava that
makes a lot of sense you got to put out
the fire with the lava oops
yes he's pretty consistent not nice as a
flint and steel but it works I'm gonna
name this guy I want to see if he'll
live or how long he'll live for okay I
got the name tag and he's still here so
I dub thee asta Dukey who this portal
stuff is taken taking it out of me lots
of redstone lots of like dealing with
tight quarters and stuff but we got it
worked out pretty good here let me show
you what's going on now so I showed you
these ones this middle portal wasn't
hooked up before it is now we got the
lava one there and the flint and steel
so I hooked that up to these buttons as
well if we want to light it we hit this
one goes down the chain here you saw
this one just got lit or you saw the
particles hopefully and those all get
lit sand then we'll do the the lava and
if we're quick they'd actually see it
happen here I hit the wrong button
I gotta get some signs on these or or
maybe I'll make one wood and one one
stone
but yeah you see how the lava it got
shot out and then picked up pretty
quickly there so that's good if what do
you want to do how we can leave these
off actually let's go up here now
there's another portal up on the roof
it's all really really complicated
there's so many portals and they all
work differently with each other since
this one's above the nether ceiling you
can never actually go from from here to
to its but yeah that that one takes you
to here this is up at the top of the
gold farm we hopped down that's what I
use when I want to harvest this you see
I got all these slime blocks right in
here
the fireball trick did work so I added
in two more buttons and basically if I
hit the left one portal goes out hit the
right one and it lights it and you can
see the this is like just vertical
redstone basically I cheated there's a
sticky piston pushes the slime blocks up
and then there's a redstone block at the
top which goes to another sticky piston
and you can do a chain as high as you
want doing that you only have 12 blocks
so per section but yeah if you hit these
activates support up there because I
want the two in sync with each other and
this elevator has really been giving me
trouble today
it's fine now but if Mike I'm doing
other things on my computer like if I
have it's fine it's good it seems to
take longer to shut down now - I think
some of the redstone wires have crossed
in places unintentionally this is off
right now this one must be off - right
yeah let's turn it on now if we go up it
should be on up there - right again the
app I'm watching videos in the
background this elevator doesn't work
because it's laggy and Pistons they'll
just drop you through if it's laggy same
with on multiplayer servers but it's lit
up here now there's also controls up
here if you wanted to do it manually
that clears it this one lights it and
you kind of get the idea so this will
take us now to the main entrance in the
nether hub because we shut the portals
off - up at the top there and and they
won't interfere with our portal Network
anymore which is great if we want to go
to the stronghold base we got to set
this to 10 which it's at
okay go in the portal it's gonna close
behind us you hear the piston go oh we
left this one on oops
hey just for demonstration great kids
this should take us to the stronghold
portal hopefully oh this stupid ones
still here - ah it would have if we
didn't have more portals interfering
this one's gonna take us to I think the
city and farm area yeah I should just
break this one honestly alright
you die now okay okay everyone we are
going to run through a little test now a
little scenario and try out the portal
network for real now because we did that
stuff at the gold farm we only want
those portals on when we're actually
using it so right now they're off I turn
them off it's really easy to turn them
on though because we we set up all that
stuff today just press two buttons and
you're good but now that we have those
working we can actually use the portal
network as well the way I intended to
but they were interfering with it for so
long I haven't used it really so we're
going to run through the test here a
little scenario to make sure it works
let's pretend we have to go to the
stronghold base to pick something up and
then go collect some sand at the sandpit
and then return home to the man cave
okay so first stop number 10 stronghold
base have 10 dialed in on our thing here
press the button go through there's a
interment somewhere should take us to
the man cave yeah we have to go through
one more time
stronghold please yeah very good okay
took us where we wanted to so we got to
pick something up here right but we're
going to be going to the sandpit after
and we know that so we can set this to
eight which is the sand pits press the
button let's go pick up our thing
at the strongholds get here we are
we need sandstone okay let's go get sand
now should take us to the sand pits
portal yeah very good
and we're going to be returning to the
man cave afterwards there's no sign here
there's no oh there's no chart we go is
nine wasn't it pick so that's oh man
eight nine okay let's go get our sand
the sand fit is like six hundred blocks
away from the man cave by the way like
where we are right now so in that frame
of mind that is pretty cool because it
would take you like two minutes to walk
here but thanks to the nether oh no it
didn't close that's not good
sometimes that happens it doesn't close
behind you properly hopefully it doesn't
happen a lot
otherwise this might not work out too
well now we're still here we turn this
on right nine one two five nine yeah
there might be some bugs in the system
to strike one more time so convenient it
oh man go on please work see it it's
sending us here but the portal is off
let's go check if this one is on at our
main hub because I'm not sure put these
back yeah and now I'm confused
is it on oh it is on
see this is where it's supposed to be
taking us but it's keeping us there even
though the portal is broken oh boy mmm
not sure what to do about that maybe
I'll try this some more off camera okay
it does work I watched the video and I
forgot to hit the wood button for two of
those times the last time though I did
hit it and it failed I'm not sure what
that was about but I've tried it some
more should take us to the sandpits
portal which it does okay now we want to
go back to the man cave after this which
is again nine hit the button this time
go to the sandpit get our sand all right
we got our sand let's head back to the
man cave this is what we have trouble
with
I hit the button this time for real okay
good yeah I don't know what the deal is
with that but did a full full round-trip
this time which is good go through it is
the man cave and we are home so that's
kind of the way it'll work it seems like
a lot of like rigger rig Amaro to it but
I think once I get used to it it'll be
pretty good and we are traveling huge
distances there each time so that is
pretty convenient
kitty no titty Bad Kitty you stay out of
the water I don't know if this guy's
teleporting to me properly he is
randomly teleport to me one day oops
kitty kitty no don't drown okay come on
teleport to me he's not gonna teleport
to me this jet is so weird I wanted to
bring him along but I kind of regret it
now
you're 10 you get to you get to the land
at least okay we're just going to sit
set you down there you'll be fine I'll
call the Coast Guard for you Oh with
that throw so guys next up oops I didn't
mean to do that now I'm gonna ender
pearls next up I've been meaning to do
some more stuff on this village here our
villager village it's been neglected
lately still got our good librarian yep
oh but I've used up the trade we really
need to get a farm in here somewhere so
that these guys can harvest their own
wheat and then make it a babies you know
on their own and I don't have to watch
it was that the cat do you see that
flicker I think the cat tried to
teleport again
that wasn't a no it's not they speak or
the speed beacon or anything is it
which doesn't reach here I might have
put the speed beacon in the wrong place
I just realized I'm not getting the
speed effect from the beacon replace the
other day ah oops alright anyway so
where shall we put our our wheat we
could do like a big pool of water here
with with wheat all around might be cool
we got this big open place or we could
save this for like a tunnel that goes
somewhere this area mmm man one of our
villagers get just got killed while I
was in here in the Red House somehow
zombie got in there and killed them do I
have any apples I see a weakness potion
in there Apple Apple man no Apple there
darn I wanted to save this guy but it's
just a weight low it may be in this
chest no no no don't hurt me maybe this
one yes we got apples in here
okay and the weakness potion oh it hurts
you jerk
how are we gonna trap them alright
good good I will save you
I want my blacksmith Becker or whatever
you were alright you come get me right
here perfect hopefully that didn't spawn
a bunch of zombies nearby because when
you attack zombies sometimes they spawn
let's just check out what's going on
here I'll come on dude there was an iron
golem in here and the zombie killed
somebody in this building and you just
watched and let him unreal I think maybe
yeah I bet this was this was the Kazi er
somehow a zombie spawned in this cave
and it was close enough to the ground
that he was able to fall down and get
the guys so I should block this off this
is our new guy here he became a
blacksmith again pretty cool how neat
would it be if if maybe blacksmith
villagers interacted with anvils or
something kind of like the farmer guys
like how they go in harvest crops like
if you put down an anvil somewhere
blacksmiths guys would interact with it
and maybe make special tools or
something and and use up the anvil over
time that would be pretty neat oh yeah I
was thinking of maybe having a jump pad
but these guys will probably just kill
themselves on it so I'm I'm gonna get
rid of it
it's just a thought though I'm gonna
save this area for as some sort of
tunnel after all but maybe we can put
some farmland like going down this hill
that might look a little better than the
stone we have currently let's try it out
switch it out and we will see what it
ends up looking like Oh
I haven't decided yet if I liked it or
not I'll have to look at it for a while
I think our farmer villager seems to
have died though I was hoping he would
come by and we would see if he would
harvest this or not but yeah he's dead
he's gone so I I fed the villager some
bread and hopefully they give us a
little baby farmer that will tend to the
crops never tried carrots instead the
thing about wheat it's got that yellow
color to it and I don't think it's very
good here while carrots and potatoes
they are nice and green here's our
common today for today by the way it
says etho have you ever attempted to
make a minecraft mod if not what would
you make the mod about also how did you
get so good at redstone works so a long
time ago maybe too well I get sprouted
in three years now I did attempt briefly
to make a minecraft mod I didn't get
very far with it though I was attempting
to make a terrain generator that
replaced the one built into Minecraft
and I was trying to do it in such a way
that you could create your own biomes
this was like right after biomes
originally came out wanted to be able to
create your own biomes and specify what
types of blocks were in it where they
were replaced and what rules guided how
they would get placed like maybe dirt
would be placed on stone like it usually
is or maybe mycelium or whatever other
blocks and then I wanted to make it so
that you could imports mcedit schematics
as structures and then dictate what
rules guide where those structures spawn
like maybe there's different height
levels and they have to spawn on certain
types of blocks and yeah I want a lot of
variety to it and then I was going to
try to to
- what was I going to say and have like
settings that would control how big the
biomes were and like what biomes could
spawn by other biomes and and you know a
lot of that stuff is in the game already
now but yeah I never got very far I
didn't like NBT file formats and I was
trying to make an editor for it and it
didn't turn out too well had trouble
with it um anyway redstone redstone like
a lot of things like some people say
they're not builders in this game
well that's because you have to learn it
and same with redstone you got to learn
redstone um it takes time the more you
do it the easier it kind of becomes and
you pick up tricks along the way and
sometimes you have creative thoughts and
you come up with new tricks and and
that's pretty much how a redstone works
it's not that complicated once you once
you get into it and you just pretty much
copy-paste different designs that you've
used before over and over and as you get
experience with it you don't have to
reference how to build certain redstone
devices you just kind of know it off the
top of your head usually and yeah not
too difficult
give it a try anyway that's it for today
guys I hope you enjoyed today's episode
and I will see you again in the next one
bye bye there was a hole here - by the
way I think that's where they actually
got in
you