hello everybody how are you doing today
I just wanted to share this with you
I've been doing a lot of of caving since
last episode this is my second big run
all this stuff I was just about to head
back with it and I saw this and I
thought I just had to share it with you
giant natural lava waterfall let's go to
let's go a little closer here I'm going
to see it up close and there's a chest
next to it too which is pretty cool
that's awesome
nothing I've ever smoked I've ever seen
one that big in like not in the nether
that was natural pretty cool yes I got
lots of iron now lots of diamonds again
and redstone supplies are up again
should be should be pretty good
let's check the chest oh nice wide
opening here you I'll take that let's
let's see over here Wow is amazing
huh slime up there go beast
oh this sword is awesome anyway I just
wanted to share that with you cool area
I found and I'm going to head back and
we'll probably start building or
something well I had a pretty nice
surprise when I exited here uh check out
what's outside something I've been
looking for for a long long time here
snow finally found some snow so I'm
gonna head over there and get at least
two blocks and we can have infinite snow
I've actually been wondering about that
in the new snapshot we have the jungle
biomes with my LP world here am I gonna
get the jungle biomes like if I generate
new world or is it just not going to be
possible period unless I use an NBT
editor or something let me know because
I've I've been hearing a lot of mixed
things about that and I'm not sure
exactly what's going to happen I would
like to have the new features but I
don't know if I would be willing to
cheat just for them cool all right we
got snow we are a long ways away from
home
well about a thousand blocks not too bad
and I will have to ditch I'll give her
the torches and grab the have a full
stack here maybe good okay I'm going to
head back and I'll see you guys there
okay we're back and my unbreaking shovel
over here is about the break so we're
going to make us a new enchanted one
here let's see how efficiency for hmm
so-so
alright we're going to do one more
enchantment here a bow I was doing some
editing so I left my game writing near
the tape spider thing and here we go
level 50 failed oh there we go I wonder
why I didn't work the first time I
clicked power 5 mm okay I wanted to
flame one but it's it's decent okay so
I'll give you a little update on the
resource situation this is a this is
where we stand now doing pretty good I
think I'm going to start making Diamond
armor sets instead of using iron just
because now that I think of it iron is
really useful but diamonds my tools
don't wear out fast enough for the rate
I get it so there's nothing else to
really use it on so I should be using it
for armor instead of my good supplies my
iron which would try to keep running out
of now and that I want a lot more of so
that's probably what I'll do soon maybe
I'll try do level 50 enchantments on it
as my redstone supply will grab some of
this
and we'll grab some gold gold blocks and
let's head up to where the door is going
to go that we were planning had some
good suggestions for it I ripped out the
wall looks a little bit weird right now
but I think when I polish this area out
it'll look pretty good it's just a flat
stone slab at the moment I put the grass
here glowstone I don't know if I'll keep
the glowstone there it's kind of nice
and this wall on the right will be
removed slightly too so the fence gate
or the fences don't attach like they are
here okay let's let's try out this door
here so people suggest that I should try
sandstone and gold instead of like the
nether brick and iron that I have at the
potion room down there
since we're going for a warmer feeling
in this area without the constant use a
constant use of stone bricks try we'll
try something different here so it would
look your frame would be like this and I
have been looking on YouTube for I did
search for different doors people have
made and apparently there's like 4 by 4
doors and 5 by 5 doors I am aware of CNB
Minecrafts 3 by 3 door it's really nice
he's he did a good job on it and also I
saw a Minecraft addict also did a nice 3
by 3 door but I will still do it my way
is a just funner for me that way so this
is what it would look like but yeah
people made like 5 by 5 doors and it
takes just like 15 seconds of Pistons
moving around or putting the door it
looks really cool and the wiring is
crazy I guess this is what it would look
like
okay it's different that's for sure
might be good I don't know let me know
what you think I think for this episode
I'll keep it like that
while I build it here and I'll have to
do mostly soft camera probably so like I
said I want that the middle wants to
retract first then the corners and then
the sides so that's all aim for here and
I think my Pistons going and I'll give
you an update after I've worked on this
for a little bit I got it pretty close
to working properly now it's a lot
easier to build in that spiraling door
that's for sure a lot quicker to some of
this redstone will need to be moved
here's a here's what it looks like at
the moment I'm having a few issues
that's opening that's closing so closing
is working perfectly exactly like I
wanted it to like spot-on opening
there's one issue with it
few if you watch a bottom ones that's
the way it's supposed to work but then
if you watch the top ones you'll see the
bottom one retracts first for for the
middle but at the top one the corners
retract first so it doesn't match and
that's all has to do with the way the
repeaters are positioned with the
Pistons so Pistons are below these
blocks I'm sending power into the blocks
with these repeaters and the wire here
and down below the way I'm doing it is
slightly different and that's what's
causing it a little bit of variation I
think so down here I have the repeaters
going directly into the Pistons I think
I was to do that at the top it would be
perfect but then it might look a little
strange
like the repeaters that have to go down
lower which would mess up with my
doorframe whoops so I'll try move them
and see if that would fix the problem
just out of curiosity
yep changing that around has fixed it
for sure so this is what this is how I
wanted the door to function just like
this that's opening that's closing
working perfectly now only downside is I
have this overhang here which I can't
get rid of what the way I have this but
I've realized the reason it was a
behaving inconsistently is because the
wiring was powering the Pistons
diagonally so that causes weird effects
if I raised the repeaters even higher
like before I had the repeaters at this
height did I fall through the block or I
walk off there that was weird
I had it like this ah but the repeater
or hmm how did that work it's very
strange if you send redstone power
diagonally to a piston it causes
inconsistencies so I was to raise the
repeaters one block higher that would
fix the problem I think as well and then
I could get rid of this overhang so I'll
do that nice thing about how this turned
out the middle of the stairs aligns
perfectly with this walkway here so
don't have to walk to the side to get
away from the water streams and
something a lot of people commented on
as I should put two half slabs over top
the water it's definitely something I
was going to do when I originally made
this but
then you have a problem because the way
I did like a trick to get the redstone
wire on these dispensers and the game
will not allow you to right-click the
dispensers if there's wire on it it sees
it like like a full block so you don't
have line of sight through that is to
the dispenser so the only way to
actually open these or to access these
dispensers is from the sides where the
water is so I can't cover these water
streams otherwise I won't be able to
fill the dispensers that's the way that
works anyway still don't know what I'm
going to do here I'll definitely clean
up the walls I'm not sure about the
floor though it really won't match if I
do sandstone it's raining again this
wiring here I will change around a
little bit so that I get the moment I
can't cover this without going up one
block so I'll probably move it out one
more and leg okay I think it's done I'm
done messing with the wiring here I
think yeah it'll have to do so works
exactly like I wanted it to how I
imagined I'm happy about that all this
wiring can be covered now I've changed
it around a bit so that flat ground here
probably could have done it a little
more efficiently somehow but I'm done
messing with it today this is the way
well these are the delays so this the
middle blocks are at two all the corners
are at four and then the sides are at
six that's the total delays torch delays
so right below the lever is this wire
that's the middle one it's at two then
these corner ones the bottom corners are
four goes off to the right side here so
the wires at zero and four then five and
six and goes to the piston on this side
it's at zero here one two and there's a
repeater takes it to six and that's the
other side but at this point here it's
still at two and it goes up to the top
and I just did the overhang on the other
side I did try to bring it up and it
seemed like it was going to work but the
wire would have to be a little bit
sloppy so I just decided to simplify it
here so it goes it's a two at this point
then it goes this would be for this one
would be for wait what
yeah that's right I want these at four
and this would be a 2 oops
so that's the wiring and I I made it
sure that I could have a flush wall here
if I want so I have space to work and
that's the door the golden door so let
me know what you think of it if I should
change the block types now's the time to
say I'm not going to mess around with
this room today until I get your
feedback on this on these sandstone and
gold I don't really care too much how
this room looks mainly this outside is
what I'm concerned about and I don't
know if transitioning from grass to the
sandstone is good either
usually I like to do wood but it might
look a little funny if I have wood here
I could do if people don't like the gold
the golden door I might change it to a
wooden door or something I don't know
just ideas come check this out this is a
this is my spider eye collection full
full full full full full full full full
full that's I was trying to eat spider
eyes so that I wouldn't run out of space
in my dispensers and I have so just
through a chest down here and I'm
starting to fill it too
yeah I got lots of spider eyes I I'm the
type of person that can't throw anything
away even if it's garbage I just have to
collect it okay so we got to figure out
a locking mechanism for this I don't
know if I'll do it today I was kind of
thinking of maybe doing reads a weird
read system so maybe have a read on the
left side and a read on the right side
and at the very top have a bud switch so
that to open the door you would have to
break to the left and the right read
that would trigger the piston and the
door would open and then when the reads
regrow maybe it'll close the door I
don't know could be interesting that'd
be one way to make a timer for the door
that that's really well and all that
wouldn't be simple just an idea
something fun to do mmm
what should I do now
it's like 1:00 a.m. here so I'm trying
to decide if I should just wrap this
episode up or start working on a walk I
feel bad I feels like I haven't done a
whole lot in the episodes lately you
know I kind of have I don't
see maybe do something here ah my games
lighting again I gotta clear my
harddrive
I got like 90 gigs left still
transferring files over the new one here
what should we do at the bottom of these
stairs
need some lighting or something because
this is dark doesn't look good oh yeah I
never fixed that oops
okay I'm wasting time here I'll think of
something all right so I'll probably
have to end the episode here because
it's getting late very late and I have
to get up very early tomorrow just lost
track of time today we played a race for
wool that took a few hours red stones
verse brute we did a rematch just for
fun that went well
red stoners won again but it was a close
close game I don't think anybody
recorded it I didn't so don't expect to
see video of it but it was mostly just
for fun and also tonight
I got pranked on mine crack you got me
yep got me good took me about an hour to
clean up that mess and all I recorded it
too so they'll be footage of it so I'm
not going to spoil it this doesn't seem
to be burning it's good let me know what
you think of this if I should rip it out
do something else I was talking about
doing an information board there before
but I don't think there's enough space
to include everything I'd like so you
should probably build it somewhere else
and I anything I build here is really
going to block the view so if I have a
whole bunch of signs and stuff it'll get
really big yeah and this isn't burning
because it's a taking advantage of a
trick with fire if there's no air spaces
for
fire to spread it can't spread and so if
you have fire in the middle of something
it will do a three by threes you can
only set fire to three by three areas so
the fire here would be the middle block
and all these other blocks are solid so
fire can't spread to them and it can
spread to blocks one one block below
itself so these again are all solid and
four blocks above which is also all
solid so there's no air spaces for it to
spread to so it it won't or at least I
don't think it will
ah my teams aren't so bad here not
better it's better okay so if these
pressure plates or these pressure plates
weren't here this catch fire is there'd
be air spaces but seems to be okay
anyway I'm gonna end it here thanks for
watching guys give me your feedback and
I will see you again next time