hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys once again to our let's play
series how're you doing
I'm very happy because I have just
finished up our gold farm here that
we've been working on the last couple
episodes at least I think it's done I
just moved all the torches off the
platforms kind of evenly spaced them
around the place on the sides there and
now I'm just doing some like final
touches to this and also testing it out
I've been up here for over five minutes
and brought some carpet with me I was
going to put it over top here yeah it
still haven't got a new Mouse yet so I'm
double right-clicking all the time ah ah
that's the is there anything in here
still there's actually quite a bit of
stuff isn't there alright let's break
these this is what I was using to store
the items well I built this I do want
those slime blocks what etho makes gold
farm and then throws away the gold it's
okay we're gonna be getting lots of it
guys
don't you worry so I set up a gold
collection system now we'll go check
that out
let's see you first before we hop down
is there any problems hole is there any
problems we can spot right now I am
seeing like the zombie chicken jockeys
the Pigman chicken jockeys are getting
stuck on the trapdoors you see how he's
just like spinning around there there's
another one over there maybe I need to
actually try replace those trap doors
with glass and see if it works
but then other than that I don't see any
problems on the actual spawning
platforms so let's go down here
I am worried some of the XP is getting
stuck places so let's really watch for
that
there are a few items popping out of
here like there's some XP there let's
see if that will get picked up next next
round here because this is all very
experimental I don't know how good
Pistons are actually moving stuff also
I'm getting some zombies stuck here and
I'm not exactly sure why oh yeah good go
okay so it's not a not place it's
getting stuck so we have one hopper
clock that's controlling this whole
thing right now so it goes from one arm
to the next arm to the next arm and then
the next one and it restarts the cycle
every time are these guys just like
falling down and not dying I wonder
let's try see how many hits they take to
kill their two hit kills yeah so they're
probably not falling quite far enough it
might be when this piston extends if
they land on it for a brief moment then
they don't die I should have built this
all one block lower probably than it is
but yeah let's go down here other than
that I don't really see too much trouble
aha so I got all the gold going in here
zombie flesh in there it's working
pretty good dressed for the moment I'm
dropping the garbage items into a 1x1
glass chamber there I plan on putting a
lab in though to destroy them but you
can see all the gold swords and stuff in
here
I'm just looking at if any gold is
getting through and I don't see any
yeah so basically the way we got this
working guys we actually pick up the
items at the very end of each of the
arms here and then I use the hopper
chain to bring them to the center right
they meet in the center here and
converge I have a ring of hoppers here
they pull the items out of the hoppers
you see how it passes over top of them
pulls them down they go into here then
they pass by these three item sorters we
have item filters so we have gold
nuggets gold bars and zombie flesh
anything that doesn't get sorted goes
further on into that dropper over there
and that's going to be the void items
that we shoot into lava so if any items
are in in that dropper then this clock
runs and shoots them out umm I'm not
trying to keep an eye out for any backup
happening and so far it seems like it
might be a little bit too slow to handle
all the items um so I might need to set
up two sets of item filters to deal with
all the items because it looks like it
might back up currently yeah other than
that I think this is a pretty good
system
all right guys very cool so we pretty
much got that gold farm project all
taken care of now so we're gonna move on
to something new today and you might be
asking Etha what crazy project you have
in mind today well I am going to rebuild
the planet Earth and all the cities in
it had a one to one block ratio so one
meter in earth is one block in game here
no I'm I'm taking it easy today guys
we're gonna make another word farms
we're going to keep it simple I've been
doing a lot of big projects lately we
did the Enderman farm zombie Pigman farm
nether warts seems like a nice change
it's fairly simple
and with the 1.10 update we have two
blocks nether wart blocks and red nether
brick that require nether wart to craft
them and currently this is all I have as
as far as the nether wart farm goes this
thing here and this
here these work pretty good like I've
I've been using these for a long time
and they've been able to keep up with
our potion brewing no problem press the
button every so often get the nether
works replant it and that gives you a
little bit of profit we got 21 from that
so pretty simple um but we want to
mass-produce this stuff right there's
not really a lot you can do with nether
word in this game it's one of the least
liked automatable crops in the game some
interesting things you can do like if
you use fortune on it I believe you get
more so I got a fortune pick here we had
21 now we have 26 so we got five we got
six that time four five if you don't use
fortune I think you get two to four they
have to get to their right three three
and I think four yeah so could get a
little bit more if we use fortune but I
don't know if it's really worth it I
think we'll just make a big field of
nether warts one thing I had in mind
let's see if this works
if you there might be one way to
automate it a little bit easier if you
click on the dirt block does that plant
oh it doesn't
oh darn I was thinking like you could
have a bunch of soul sand down like this
if you click on the nether wart in front
of you it would plant it that looks like
you actually have to click on the on the
soul sand because I get if you use a
redstone for example it'll place it or
if you place it on the dirt it places it
on the soul sand I thought it would do
that as well but I guess not I guess
because it's a crop and not a block hmm
any other ideas
oh yeah you can't grow this stuff with
the bone meal so yeah we we really can't
do much with it
where this gonna make a big field of it
I think okay guys so I got a plan now I
thought about for a little bit we're
going to expand the man cave into a new
region today off this way towards the
swamp we haven't
really built anything underground we've
done a little bit above ground over here
just a little bit of decorative stuff
nothing too much if we look in the
ravine down here you see how we got the
birch wood and spruce that is actually
the tree farm in the man cave if we go a
little bit further on here though like I
think past this point there's nothing we
haven't done anything underground or
above-ground here really um so we're
going to start expanding out to this
region we're going to build the nether
work farm underground probably it's
going to take a fair bit of space and
then above ground we're going to try
decorate it some more one thing that
we'll probably be doing in this area you
can make some pretty cool-looking
mushrooms using the new nether wart
blocks so once we start amassing a ton
of those we'll build lots of these
probably different sizes and shapes I'll
try to do a sample one here though
yeah bone blocks work great as the stems
and then let's kind of do something
round it out
I also saw on the reddit some people
were growing jungle trees and then they
change the leaves with this nether wart
block and it looks really good it looks
like giant mushrooms
wait isn't on uh-oh they changed it Oh
weird that's really weird because you
used to be able to harvest it with your
axe right and now in 1.10 you can't
uh-huh anyways so kind of smooth this
out really sure what I'm doing I guess
let's go down ooh
AHA there we go
that's my sample mushroom for you guys
so maybe in the future we will plan to
transform the swamp area into like a
mushroom forest we'll have like big
mushrooms little mushrooms try to make
it look rundown and and creepy and
whatnot I don't know we'll see but for
today we're just going to build a nether
wart farm underground probably in this
big flat spot and then connect it to the
man cave probably at that tree farm area
so gonna need a fair bit of space I
guess I'll just dig down
and try to make a big area here and then
we'll get to it I guess okay guys so I
got a dual beacon set up now with that
haste - and speed - just to make the
school a little bit quicker and I got a
path to go down here and this is
probably going to be about the center of
our farm right around here I got a seven
by seven thing of soul sand down right
now not exactly sure what we're doing
but we're probably going to be
harvesting this the nether wart using
water streams it's probably the easiest
way of doing it um and I think we'll try
to collect all the nether work together
in the very center here so we're going
to be making a big plus sign probably is
the plan so water streams will push the
nether work to here so we can probably
go at the most since water streams only
travel eight blocks maybe let's do six
blocks from that center hole there yeah
let's try six blocks around the border
of the soul sand here I'll probably put
the red nether brick I think that'll
look pretty good with this alright cool
so this is probably what we'll do here
we'll test it out in a second but first
I gotta find these spiders man they are
driving me crazy and yes I just said
spider-man oh really okay I know where
we are this is the old old dual cape
spider farm is over here right
underneath okay mmm can't really shut
this off mm maybe I'll just have to live
with it then all right let's uh let's do
one of these babies while we work on
this nether wart firm cuz I'm not
breaking those spawners
or we're lighting them up I guess okay
let's go up here throw a torch in there
so I got to test out the water streams
now make sure they
you wash the nether words to the center
like I want so probably
let's go up one more block right yeah so
basically let's do this I got some ice
on me is it gonna be able to push
overtop the nether word here let's see
or does he get stuck it does get stuck
okay so we can't have anything fancy at
all man
no fancy borders or anything this has to
be soul sand all the way through here
okay so let's try this again our goal is
to get all the nether wart to the center
hole right so if we have one stream
going there and another stream on this
side I keep placing like two two blocks
when I only want to place one definitely
getting a new Mouse tomorrow because
this is getting really frustrating okay
yeah this looks good I think that'll
work out pretty good uh-huh
so I've done a bunch of digging here
guys bunch of building I think we pretty
much got the nether wart part of our
firm done here and I really liked how
they look when they're all bunched
together like this too it's pretty cool
so this is the plus sign shape I was
talking about so we could go up step by
step as high as we want here as far out
as we want but this is probably enough
in other words I would say each of these
steps we have is a seven by seven so
like one of these things from there to
there is seven by seven that's 49 plants
so we've got eight eight of those step
things so that's about 400 and then this
middle parts probably probably at least
100 if I was to guess so that's like 500
plants I think that's good enough if we
get three on average which I'm not sure
if that's correct but I think it's about
three and we got to use one to replant
that means we're gonna get about
thousand each harvest um oh got some
lighting issues here too uh I think a
thousand is pretty good though it's only
that's not even two stacks in other word
blocks but yeah it's it's good I think
so I'm gonna put water buckets in
these dispensers on each of the arms
that'll wash all the netherwart
to the middle then we'll probably pick
it up with a hopper or something and put
it into chests and to actually replant
the nether wart I I don't think there's
any way around it I have to go and like
place it manually there are some designs
that use minecarts that movie around and
you just hold right click which worked
pretty good too but for for mass
production I think it's just easier to
do this all right so do that and now we
also want to decorate the farm as soon
as I kill this fool mm-hmm
I probably won't be doing much of my
redstone on this red nether brick right
it's like invisible on it but yeah we're
gonna we're going to power the
dispensers in the back like that I put a
thing of the brick over top of it's this
area here around the farm is going to be
a path that we can walk walk around what
block do we want to use for this I have
a couple ideas we could try mycelium
let's pick our favorite here mycelium
might look good grass because this is
going to be part of the man cave so we
might want to keep this grass theme and
the dark green looks pretty good with
this red brick I think the other option
is to use bone blocks I would say which
also probably looks pretty good if we
just did a three wide path let's see
what do we want to do definitely not
mycelium mmm let's put some more red
brick on this side for the walls I plan
on using magma maybe we'll put these
down too just to see which works better
with them I plan on using these magma
blocks for the walls and maybe some
brown clay or maybe bone blocks for the
walls as well do two to this stuff
doesn't hurt you could touch it on the
side it's only if you step on it right
yeah okay cool oh man that breaks
quickly I forgot it's an instant
okay yeah brat brown clay where's this
gray clay it is great okay looks really
good with this stuff now which do we
prefer with that the green works with it
but the bone I would create a real real
big contrast if we use the bone maybe
we'll stick with the grass then oh yeah
check it out now we got all the grass
blocks in I think that looks good I'm
really happy with that actually now that
I see the whole thing done I think it's
a good choice now check this out on the
wall I was just going to do like a 3x3
thing of this this what do you call it
again make my block ah maybe we do an
arch it's a man cave we got to have
arches right maybe we do an arch of this
stuff that goes all the way across to
the other side would look really good
and I'm also playing around with the
sandstone the red sandstone I never use
this stuff but it goes really good with
the Megane blocks as well and not too
bad with the red nether brick so I got
on the ground here I tried using it on
the wall I'm still trying to figure it
out exactly but I think we're going to
go with something like this and then in
the very middle here I thought it'd look
cool if we did what you might call it
what's the word
oh no it's escaped me skylight I think
your skylight is what I'm looking for
right in the middle here do a big
skylight because I think we're pretty
close to the surface actually how far do
we got to go up to hit the surface
that's right there it's right there so
maybe we do like a glass skylight over
here we'll put the the clay as a border
around it as well maybe like an octagon
shape or something like that well I've
done some more building here guys and
it's really coming together I'm loving
this block theme we got going on here I
think it's pretty cool
very interesting I've never built
anything quite like this before so these
red nether brick blocks they're pretty
cheap they're not a problem bone blocks
are fairly cheap but the ones that
really seem expensive now that I've
actually done some building like this is
my first time using the Magna blocks and
I've used a little bit of nether wart
like on that mushroom and stuff those
are expensive and these magma blocks are
actually pretty pricey too each one
takes four magma cream yeah that's
that's a lot so I have ran out of magma
cream I even afk dat the blaze firm for
a while I might have to do some more AF
game to get more but I got about half of
this done now I did a skylight over here
in the middle seems to be collecting
slimes from the swamp area but of course
we'll do some terraforming out there so
it's not going to be a big circle out of
the land or anything like that it'll be
evened out I'm sure and I think I got
the water budget hooked up here too
let's try that out which side was it
over here yeah over here okay so
basically all I did it's very simple it
just ran a wire from here goes out this
way actually I don't know if I finished
it now that I I see that it goes out
over here there's a repeater back there
powers this wire goes on to the next one
yeah there's some of these you're
missing it's gotta have those blocks
there to work yeah if we if we put a
button here and press it should activate
this all the way down yeah that one's
good that one's good sweet oh you know I
was worried about this actually some of
the nether words bouncing off off up to
the edge here mmm
I wonder maybe I should raise this by
one block then but it doesn't look like
we have any dead zones in the water
which is cool everything is getting
washed to the middle and after we'll
probably need a hopper clock to actually
to time this and then after a while this
will shut off and then they should all
disappear again cool and then just go by
replant
so you see how dark that red nether
brick is in the middle there if we put a
torch here it should save the lighting
right these magma blocks still save it
if I'm not mistaken yeah so if I just if
I want to light it up that that's cool
you have the option of making something
lighter or darker I think I want it
lighter though right oh yeah I think
that looks a lot better
aha so these kind of function is lights
too which is pretty cool but yeah
anyways we got a lot left to do on this
actually like I got to figure out some
lighting for the soul sand area might
have to hang something from the ceiling
to do that I'm gonna have to afk at the
blaze farm for at least an hour probably
get the rest of the magma cream for this
um figure out entrances and figure out
how I'm do where I'm putting the
redstone controls all that kind of stuff
we got a good start on this though but
we'll probably have to wrap up the
episode here for today guys I've
actually recorded this over a couple
days so I have a new mouse now I went
shopping today and clicky clicky
oh I just want to hear the clicking not
actually look at that it hopefully
that's not too loud of a clicking I
tried to pick something quiet but it's
really hard why do they make mouse mice
Mouse's mice so loud I don't get it I
guess like everyone I tried clicking
it's super loud and I don't know people
must like that
but I would prefer quiet mouse for
recording for sure but had trouble
finding one um oh I really don't want to
do this I got a do it ah this is the
nasty parts of working where I'm working
here there's water up above and actually
these magma blocks they sizzle
constantly if there's water on them it's
kind of interesting did not know that
before yeah anyways let's get to a
turret the comment of the day says etho
what did you do before you made
Minecraft videos bump-bump um uh well if
you mean what did I do
on the
those lab channel YouTube channel I have
a surprise for you a lot of you guys
don't know this but before minecraft I
actually get this uploaded about
probably about 30 videos of a harvest
moon 64 playthrough with no talking no
commentary it was all annotations like
whenever I had to explain something I
put an annotation in it was basically a
speedrun of the game back before I even
knew what speedruns were and that was it
each video got maybe actually did not
like as bad as you would think like 200
views or something 300 views up probably
on average for the videos so some
somebody watched him but then back in
the day in order to become a YouTube
partner it was rumored you had to get at
least a thousand views on each of your
videos if any video had less than that
you could not become a youtube partner
so a common thing was for people to
delete all their really bad videos so I
deleted all the Harvest Moon videos and
you guys missed out on them except for
later I did another playthrough which
was very cringe-worthy
but that still exists unfortunately um
hmm but yeah anyways and even before
that get this I did something else I did
a couple tech videos on on game
programming like I was doing experiments
with game programming and I was
uploading my results of like making a
not a 3d engine but a 2d engine that had
3d capabilities I figured out and an
algorithm that allowed you to do 3d and
2d and it was kind of cool and now that
I've said that I realize it probably
doesn't make much sense because I
probably contradicted myself there but
you would understand if you saw it kind
of made sense actually 2.5 D let's say
that
but anyways let's wrap it up here guys
if you have any ideas on this new region
we're working on here on how to make it
look cool please let me know in the
comments or any ideas for our another
word farm here but until next episode
thank you guys for watching as always
take care bye bye