[Music]
hey everybody this
is etho and i tell you what guys this
is living this is really nice the goop
is really warm and the air is real
cool oh it just feels feels so cozy
in my little hot tub here
what you gonna do he coward
he coward all right
i am kind of wondering something though
kind of wondering what happens
to the stuff that goes through this
portal
i don't really know to be honest
because you can throw stuff in i think
mobs can go in but where do they come
out
because you come out wherever your your
spawn is set
where do they come out though
all right you throw that there
got still not picking it up
still not picking up so it actually went
through the portal somewhere
do you think it actually came out though
i honestly don't know so if you're
waiting for an answer
uh i don't have one i mean i'm guessing
it either got destroyed though or
comes out at the main spawn of the world
right [ __ ]
i bet you could if they actually came
out somewhere i bet you could get a
whole ton of them through here
really easy
actually i just saw did i see the dirt i
threw when i came through i
i don't know i'm gonna have to watch
that back
yeah so this is the main spawn point of
my world
and i don't see the items anywhere i
know a chicken went through too when i
was goofing around
and i don't see a chicken anywhere on
the surface
so that just makes me think they get
destroyed whatever goes through that
portal
that's my guess who knows i'm sure
somebody
will tell us so
you know what uh being here has given me
an idea of what i want to do
for today's episode or at least part of
it
uh i really like this area like i think
it looks awesome
but there's a few tweaks to it we could
make to make it even better i think
and one of those is to fix
or to adjust the water a little bit like
for example over here definitely want to
take that out so that the water flows
all the way through
and we could actually take a boat around
here
so that's one thing i want to do i think
this this area here would be
oh hey hello
i think this area would look really cool
if i put a cover over top too
and made it look like this mountain
joined with this one
and there was a passage through
oh we actually got a gold piece nice
cool uh so let's take this out
just a lot of minor tweaks could make
this place a whole lot better i think
actually what i should do is get some
ice
all right
okay i wonder how hard it is to
make it look like a passage through here
you know when i started this world i
always thought i was going to go this
way
into the mountains because these
mountains are pretty cool
but i ended up going that way instead
just the way it worked out with the
stronghold being over there and
everything
but eventually we should go this way
okay uh i guess i'll just
play around with putting some dirt here
and see what it looks like
oops
yeah we'll use this as a guide i think
we should go make it slope like
this and gradually up
and then for the lower part we'll make
it kind of arch
like that
yeah that's what we'll go for and we'll
make it go
from maybe here
see what what height are we maybe from
here
we don't want it to look too man-made
though
we'll have to rough it up a bit and
we'll make it come out
we'll make it go up to here
so from here
to here
all right well i got some shape going
here i'll tell you the strategy
i'm using to shape this i don't know how
effective it's going to actually be
but i'm just picking the lowest point of
the two sides
so for example the lowest point would be
over here
because the point would be way up there
for that side
so i just went straight across from
there
but if you get to like here for example
uh this side is the lowest point
and this one goes up to there right
so i just just did that all the way down
as far as i wanted it to go and then
i'll have to
or the the way i plan on shaping this
now
if it's a flat wall like this it'll be a
steeper slope
or or like over here so i'll be placing
more land
to help make up for that and i'm gonna
shape the top
first got to get some soil over here i
don't
have i've used it all somewhere i don't
know where
but at the stronghold i have a lot more
i'm gonna shape the top first so then
we'll shape
underneath and i think it'll be okay
that feels that feels pretty cool
yeah you know what this is actually
going pretty good i think
i i was a little worried starting this
how good i would be at it
because it's it's fairly random trying
to do this
and random isn't my specialty
usually everything has to have a purpose
but really all this is
all i'm doing with this is averaging the
landscape out which
isn't too hard even for someone like me
just to do with their
their eyes
um it doesn't have to be perfect either
which is always
nice
but yeah landscaping is one of those
things i tend to avoid usually
just because i don't know it takes a lot
of time
a lot of resources usually and
it's not like you can move mountains
around in this game
it would be cool if you could but yeah
that takes a lot of tnt
and a lot of prep time to do something
like that
and you know what i always thought would
be cool
is if there's a quick way like we have
tnt that's a quick way of destroying
blocks
and there's creepers and and all that
stuff be cool if there's a quick way of
placing blocks in this game too
somehow but i don't know how
you could get that to work i guess
in some ways there is like if you pour
lava over water you'll get
you'll get a stone which is cool
but it's not like you can
put 64 blocks of something into
a furnace type thing put some tnt and
have it
blow up and make a a 4x4
cube of the material you put in or
something like that
i don't know
doing large scale terraforming is very
difficult in
survival that's for sure oops
see how's this looking pretty good
uh this should probably join a bit
better
yeah i'm happy with how that turned out
that's that's the top side done
still gotta do underneath but i think
that looks pretty
pretty good
uh one thing i want to do yet though is
just
try to make it a little more natural
you know if you plant a tree or
something on top of it it really doesn't
look like somebody
built it and grass does the same thing
kinda
uh yeah sure
okay so now we have to do the bottom
side
and i sort of started started with that
i made a base
like we did above and it's hollow inside
woohoo i might fill it i'm not sure
um but yeah now i just have to average
the bottom side so make it go
arch shaped
and i think it'll be okay
well what i'm finding is doing the
underside of this thing is
much much more difficult and i think
it's because of
two things really the first one is i
can't reach anything so i have to make
scaffolding
and the second thing is i don't have a
difference between the two walls there
they're the same heights because i went
straight across unlike above there was a
difference
and it made it easier to give it
character
with this i kind of have to just throw
in my own randomness
and like i said i'm not good at that so
probably won't turn out as well as the
top parts
okay guys i got it mostly all
done
slimes slimes everywhere
and uh let's go for a ride through it
it didn't turn out perfect but you know
it's it's pretty good
the underside oh that was a nice boat
ride the underside was really
tough to do
here we go so just a little something to
add character to the land
cool okay let's do a little bit more
terraforming
there's a spot over here where the river
seems to brush up against this pool here
but it doesn't connect too well
so let's let's make that a bit wider
so that it's easy to get a boat through
uh-huh much better much much better
so the next one i want to do is a a
bigger one
uh i would like to make my own river
that goes
at the base of this mountain i'm on
right now that kind of follows the
bottom of it
that will go from here
cut through there and then
see let's hop over here
there's gonna be a lot of blocks
involved with this one
yes it'll come through and go
around like that
then in and then connect with this big
pool water here
because this one's all on its own right
now
it would be cool if it was connected
all right let's see
it's going to be hard to see where i
want to go
when i'm down here it's easy to see from
above
uh i'll probably make the river about
five between five and ten wide
yeah so go through here
um through here
take out this tree
shouldn't be too tough
all right here i go
okay so the strategy with this one i
just cut a
pretty thin path all the way through
uh where i wanted it to go like what
shape i wanted to take
and now i got tnt running all the way
down i think if i light it
it should make a five wide or so
area for the river with a nice
nice shape to its nice depth and
everything
so let's see what happens
[Music]
so far so good
it's cutting pretty deep i'll have to
widen the top i think
although it was mostly stone there
there's a ravine
i think that would be good
and excellent
so let's go check out what that looks
like from above now
yeah all right i think that'll work
so with this i'm going to
probably put a layer of leaves
and then water above that and then take
out the leaves
i think that's the easiest way of doing
it
that's pretty good this looks so cool
okay never ever record with an open
bottle
near your mic because last clip was
reverberating very very badly from that
even though it wasn't even close to me
it somehow picked it up
it's the second time i've done that now
but yeah i'm just going through here
with the leaves
it's i'm using leaves because they're
the probably one of the easiest blocks
to get in this game
either leaves or netherrack i would say
um and also when i clean these up i can
actually use shears instead of wasting a
diamond tool on them
which is good it's going to take me
about six
years or so to remove these
so yeah i'm gonna connect it to there
then i got to put ice on top or or water
buckets i'll probably use iso just
because it's easier
i also went through and just cleaned it
up a bit too because there's a few
random blocks places i didn't want
and i may as well block this too
and yeah so in places
the wall is a little high
actually the water is going to be at
this level so it's only a one block
height
but if i want i can try smooth that out
too
just a lot of minor minor tweaking here
and there
i got the ice running all the way down
i'm kind of curious to see how it'll do
how much water will actually cover this
area once we break it all
and the water is driving me crazy
because with the
latest snapshot
the water can push you around really bad
and you can't get out of it sometimes
even
so i'm having the water push me as we go
here
seems to be working yeah it's filling it
filling all up
it's so hard not being able to fight the
current though
okay then i have it coming out here
let's make it to make water come all the
way to the edge there
see like i can't i can't walk up to that
ice block or swim up to it i have to
actually ender pearl
yeah it's that's working pretty good
this won't take long
very very nice
all right guys are you ready for it
check it out
that is a very convincing river it's
hard to believe that was man-made
so it started there
curves very nicely could use a little
touching up yet
but
goes around very gentle curves to
it
the tnt gives it a nice level of
randomness too
and yeah
oh i missed the spot
there we go so let's uh let's test this
out
because it's meant for a boat so let's
make sure we can take a boat through it
it'd be cool if at some point i get it
so
all the major locations in my world you
can get to by boat
yeah moving full speed here no problem
will we be able to get around here
oh man just grazed it just grazed it
that's so cool it's a nice ride
this is the other spot we were working
at
i gotta slow down a little bit there i
think
very cool our overhang
comes out to here
that's cool i like that
so for that river we just made i i'm
gonna try to get some trees running
along it too i think that'd be cool
and some vines hanging down maybe some
vines in the overhang there
um this here i think is a pretty big
swamp
pool most lily pads are gone out of here
this is where i've gotten
just about all the lily pads in my world
from this pool
there's still a few left i guess
and beyond here i think we went
exploring
beyond here once a while ago
think
but yeah um i think i think that's
gonna be it for today a little change of
pace terraforming
it's not something i do every day uh i
hope you guys enjoyed that
let's go read the comments and see what
you guys have to say
check it out guys this is our comment
for today hey etho are you going to
consider doing other
game let's plays i loved your harvest
moon 64. let's play
and i was devastated when you stopped
playing it
i had also enjoyed your terraria
episodes there was only two
i and many others would love to see a
let's play of one of your favorite games
you don't have to do this if you don't
want to but i myself and maybe many
others would enjoy it
if you do so well that's a good comments
that's a good comment brings up a
subject a lot of people wonder about
um well first of all let's address these
harvest moon 64. i stopped playing that
because i felt it was getting very
repetitive and it was becoming harder
and harder to make episodes for it
so i just let it go um
i have had an urge to play that again i
would not post it on youtube though
because i would run into the same
problem i think
but i might stream that if i play it
again
uh terraria i recorded two episodes the
third episode
i had my mic muted and just lost a bunch
of footage and that kind of wrecked
thing um but
i i have considered playing other games
in fact i was going to
i was going to do a faster and light
let's play but
so many people start playing it i decide
not to
maybe maybe when it becomes
retro or forgotten i'll play it
and there's another game similar to dot
i've been wanting to play
and i probably will do that too sometime
um but in general i'm i'm still happy
playing
minecraft so i don't want to get away
from that and people
like it's still a popular game so i
don't see the need to
but a a let's play of another game once
in a while would be good i think so
i'm i'm keeping my eyes open
it's a little more difficult for me than
some other people though because i'm not
uh partnered with anybody on youtube
like no
no game networks like not machinima or
ign or any of that
and not that i can't get partnered
that's the different subject but i am
not partnered which means i have to be
more careful with
copyrights
whoa with copyright stuff
so i'm a little nervous like posting new
games
on my channel because i'm worried i'm in
trouble for that
for not doing my research or
you know not knowing i wasn't allowed to
post it to her
or something like that of that nature
but yeah maybe maybe one day we'll play
something else
no promises though in fact actually
this one this is like a lot of the games
i like
oh i'm talking for a while here a lot of
the games i did like
or that are among my favorites would not
make good youtube series like
one of my favorite games ever was worms
the worm series worms armageddon
primarily um and that doesn't really
work for youtube
because in fact you can just download
people playing that game
like replay files of it so why would you
want to watch it on youtube
you know unless maybe if i was playing
with someone else and
we were talking together but
yeah it's not so easy playing other
games sometimes
anyway talking way too long here i'm
going to go on thank you for watching
guys i'll see you
next time