oh boy hey everybody how you doing I'm
okay well not really I there's something
about this tree farm the creepers just
love it
in fact a few of the signs have been
blown up already and they keep coming
back for more
the tree farms not don't shoot their
tree farms not done yet I'll hopefully
get around to doing that soon I figure
once I finished figuring out all the
donations stuff I will put my world up
for download once this is done here so
all the signs will be ready and it'll be
nice then ah yeah this is what I did
okay we knew it was going to get fixed
or at least I knew it's happened I
decided I'd let the wild do its thing
I let the cows and the wheat fight it
out and it seems like the cows are the
winners it's their territory now yeah so
I have upgraded to minecraft beta 1.9
pre-release 6 I call the guys I hate to
say it but I called it they did a
pre-release six and it is a great patch
shell lots of improvements to the game
lots of bugs bug fixing which is
important there's a few new features
like they did some stuff in the end to
actually win the game now the dragon
boss fight there are a few new bugs in
the game like doors the wooden doors
they don't function properly you have to
I think there's a pressure plate out
here you have to use a redstone
circuitry or whatever to open the doors
that will probably fix the next patch
I'm sure
yeah so I was using pre-release for
before I never did do the pre-release 5
because I didn't like how the water and
lava mechanics were working I shouldn't
reject if that was fixed either mmm well
I suppose we can find out quickly here
this is I think this will work anyway if
I take from the middle of here yeah it
seems to be fixed well I guess we should
do a proper test here let's do the plus
sign
I hate spreading false information
sometimes I do that too it looks like
it's not yeah ok so infinite lava is out
of the game now that's good I didn't
like that and hopefully I'm sure the
water streams are fixed now what else
what else I noticed just before I
started recording here if you go to your
options there's new new options here you
can turn clouds on or off particles this
is a nice feature if you're having lag
issues if you go on minimum you see no
particles come from the torches anymore
if you go up to decrease particles there
you can see particles from the portal
over there although it's not quite as
many as if you are on all there's a lot
more now so that's a cool feature to
have like that
I'm just off shaving right now looking
for some redstone and I came across this
pretty cool ravine it's really wide it's
got water coming down both sides and I
can't even see the end of it so this is
pretty cool
very tall awesome
fight fight fight fight oh yeah Oh
beautiful dodge another one
you got a horrible aim man right in
front of you aha found some redstone
finally and so why am i looking for
redstone besides you know the obvious
reason that I need some because I read
in the patch notes that the fortune
enchantment increases amount of redstone
yet now and I want to see if it's true
or not because normally you get four or
five from redstone wait I think that's
six is it six it's six awesome not much
of an improvement but it's that's four
blocks now how many did we get
twenty-two not quite six on average five
blocks we got twenty eight so that's
just over five on average I was hoping
it was going to be like lapis you know
when like twenty can fall at once but oh
well it's an improvement
that's what that's what counts I don't
know you notice how quick I mind it too
a lot of blocks now you can mine quicker
hey hey which is a nice improvement I
keep having skeletons follow my head
over here so I'm wondering if there's a
spawner up there I want to check it out
very carefully nothing there could be
higher little creeper over there hanging
out Oh somebody came from somewhere yep
there he goes nah cower and wait
yeah not what the deal is I found a few
skeletons up here and I know a ton fell
down but I'm having trouble finding any
spawner oh hey oh no no no no and that
is how you actually win minecraft I
couldn't tell if that was one or two
skeletons it almost seemed like to
probably a bad idea to do this but no
wait where where am I Who am I what's
going on these guys only have one hit on
them I don't
now they're still pretty tough though
two hits dad was just one skeleton I
gotta go back up there I got to see what
the deal is okay so I came up on the
other side this time and I think we got
to get over there that's where the
skeleton was I don't know I just feeling
a little crazy right now because I
survived that double-team I feel almost
invincible so I'm going to do I'm going
to try something I normally would never
risk and I've never really done parkour
in Minecraft before so this is my first
attempt whoo-hoo-hoo
beautiful I didn't work
okay let's try find a spawner so many of
these wooden plank ones yeah it must've
just been a coincidence I don't see any
skeleton spawners don't hear any unless
they're waiting to ambush me or
something yep nothing okay let's do that
here I don't know why but I just want to
try to hop across that creeper now for
some reason a fight Jen that would be
awesome these abandoned mine shafts are
just so much fun
oh yeah and I want to say thank you to
everybody that left comments in the last
episode that that was that was just
great really upbuilding get all that
positive feedback and so much of it too
it's close to 2,000 comments it's
incredible much appreciated everybody
I'm coming for you oh he brought friends
again look at that guy
he thought he could make it all you name
it I don't think you took damage even
now whoa blew your cover how can I get
him there's no way I'd make that jump
this is it crazy attempt of the day Oh
didn't quite expect that but that that
turned out pretty good actually
okay enough goofing around let's get to
business here home sweet home
I should probably point this out to
these glowing pumpkins or just temporary
placeholders for now I want to use only
glowstone in this whole tree farm so I
will have to go get a bunch more I
should show you this place in moody it
looks so much better
oops that's not Moody or at least I
think it looks pretty cool yeah
yeah and what was he going to say I
heard a rumor that the fortune
enchantment works on glowstone I tried
that today it does not so that is
nothing but a rumor if you've heard it
it's not true false rumor that's what I
should say and I have a plan for today
just what guess what you'll never guess
so I'll just tell you I got seal touch
that's right we got silk touch finally
what I've been doing I've been leveling
up to level 20 and then I been upgrading
my iron pickaxes to try to get it
there's about a seven point one percent
chance of getting it at level 20 on an
iron pick if I remember right I think
it's about seven point one percent and I
think on my seventh or eighth pick I
finally got it so pretty cool the reason
I'm doing it on iron is because no blue
shiny rocks these are these are my three
picks I don't know this this world
there's something strange about it I
cannot find any shiny rocks anywhere
it's like the only ones I found so far I
think you've been in chess and abandoned
mineshafts they're just very rare
redstone - it seems to be more rare than
in my old world I'm not sure why I hate
strip mining but I might end up doing
that eventually just because I'm having
trouble anyway what I want to do even
though a lot of you probably know
already what silk touch does I want to
try use it on a few different blocks and
test some things out here so hopefully
you find this interesting I was just
thinking it would be cool if you could
use silk touch on a zombie turn him into
a place of a block and then when you
place them he comes back to life or
something
or comes back to death whatever you know
what I mean okay first thing cobwebs and
this will take a long time so I'll be
right back
nope that's a no for cobwebs I've heard
some people say that the tool you use
matters oh great this is the second so
like you would need a sword to get it
from cobwebs but the thing is you can't
get silk touch on a sword so you can't
get it from cobwebs you might need an
axe for mushrooms I'm not sure okay that
was not silk touch no works with a pick
awesome and he comes out yes so it works
on mushrooms that's confirmed you guys
know me I gotta try it out on vote of
course see what happens
nope kills it pretty sure it works on
all the ores get coal blocks that way
really important I'll be able to get
redstone ore box which is very useful
for bud switches because you can cause a
block update on them by walking on them
or by right-clicking on them so that's
pretty cool I want to see the double
half slab thing just gives you one now
yeah okay that's that's been changed I
want to try it on spawners even though I
don't I thought I heard the creeper even
though I don't plan on using it if it
works even I know it works on glass oh
yeah glowstone glowstone it works on
glowstone so I think I should probably
mmm
when I go to harvest glowstone I should
probably bring my silk touch with me
because it'll save some pieces otherwise
I think it's I'm going to check right
now yeah I checked then the range is you
get two to four glowstone dust if you
break glowstone arm ly so if you use
silk touch there's definitely no loss
and the other day I saw one of these
guys teleport down here in front of my
eyes so when they walk in the water
above at the surface they seem to
teleport down to my teeth so doesn't
matter how bright I have it I don't
think I'll be able to stop that from
happening I thought I heard fire from
second ah the main reason I want silk
touch though is for the grass grass and
ice blocks would be best very cool
don't know where there's any ice now you
still I hate those guys it's like they
don't they leave you alone for a minute
and then they come and get you yeah so
this works on grass that works on ice
now it's using it on grass is going to
be really helpful for me in this cave
for spreading it further and also I want
to do something else with it yeah I
almost forgot I want to try silk touch
on the spawners so this is silk touch
because now it's changed so it's true
don't work anymore
it was unintended behavior that you
could move them around and place them as
pig spawner so they finally fix that
unless they fixed in pre five I'm not
sure now anyway well you saw it there
doesn't work in three six
I wanted to try it on a portal piece
here to see if you could do that it
doesn't look like it's possible to break
it even nope okay that's a no you know
it's really strange I've taken a lot of
abuse with this armor and it has like no
damage on it it's kind of weird that
even when that creeper like blew up
right in my face only took half a heart
damage I don't I don't know what the
deal is I'm on hard or and I was on
heard wondering if it's a pre six issue
or I don't know normally I just fly
through my iron armor but maybe that's
because I was enchanting it and there's
some bugs with enchanting I don't know
something's off here though that's all I
know that's the one thing I know
something's off anyway we're going to
the nether again today hope you don't
mind here's the deal we or we're going
to start a base oh I don't want to
teleport gee that's why pretty this
get out of here yeah I want to start a
base here man
thought there was some type of bridge I
love that it's fun
there we go problem solved
want to start a base in the other
because that I went into brewing potions
and stuff but to do that you actually
have to be in the nether for the nether
wart to grow so oh yeah I never did
finish with the spawner I swear if that
zombie pigman goes wacko on me right now
I'm going to lose it they always do that
to me they just turn all the sudden okay
that should be fine yeah so we're going
to start a base here and that's why I
wanted this grass and hopefully we can
find ice is I'm pretty sure hopefully
this is still in the game and have grass
in the nether gate what's the deal
million torches there
well thanks for the rod yeah I pretty
much used all my torches up on that and
they're still spawning so I'll have to
deal with it another day yet the grass
is spreading here I tried and it's
spreading nicely which is good so yeah
I'm just going to avoid that for today
so we will be able to have grass in the
nether and if we find ice will it be
able to have water
I believe if that's still in the game
uh-huh
so let's let's just explore this a
little bit we got to find another wart
looks like there's closed on the head
and I wanted to give a shout out to
cilantro gamer that was on his twitch TV
stream today he streams about 40 hours a
week and he I stopped by his his show
today and he let me on his show is
pretty fun and doc him came online and I
got him in the show pause and pause was
there Forks what is it
Fork see Fork see sorry
for butchering your name was there too
and a lot of other cool people lots of
fun you guys see it is on bright don't
have any torches sorry and we found
nether wart awesome
so yeah shout out to shout out to
everyone they're having a lot of fun
doing a multiplayer stuff and I got some
news about that as well
goood has invited me to join a server
his minecraft server and that's where
dude be the lower is there pause and
pauses there
some other cool people like badge and
vintage beef etc etc so don't know
exactly what I'm going to do there
I'll probably record some espy stuff and
I check this out stuff mine so quickly
now in pre-release 6 it's cool this
place seems really dark though so I'm
yeah I might start up a occasional
series on the minecraft server I'm not
quite sure what angle I'm going to take
with it it might just be sort of like an
SMP version of my LP but probably won't
be nearly as regular as my LP that's for
sure my LP always gets top priority with
anything I do so unfortunately that
means my CTM survival map is kind of
haven't I got stopped seeing kind of all
the time I haven't done a whole lot with
that recently just because having a hard
time getting LP episodes out into every
day not that I do it every day but like
getting a video of it every day I've
been having a hard time keeping up
recently mmm so that's about it hey
think we this is an area - I should
probably stop exploring this because you
might not be able to see I'm not sure
and yet I continue to do it anyway why
not yeah so that should be fun
dead end okay I'll probably call it an
end for today we'll start setting up a
base here sometime it's not going to be
anything huge but I just want to get
some stuff going in the nether make it
nice and we should try to find a snow
biome soon too anyway I'll see you guys
again next time thanks for watching