[Music]
good greetings everybody this is etho
and i've had a few people ask me if this
still works the cave spider
xp thing here because a lot of people
are having trouble with the new mob ai
since the 1.2 patch and they're behaving
slightly different now they're even more
difficult to work with
this is uh this is kind of working
and kind of not working mostly not
working they're getting jammed in places
in my uh
piping and stuff i've i'm finding
and this spawner down here i'm not sure
if it's working at all
there's one further that way which i
think is working a lot better
but over here well maybe it is i don't
know it's hard to tell
without being able to see
it might be because there's a light on
down there it seems pretty bright i
don't know
um i'll have to take a look at all this
and maybe
do a little maintenance try to fix it
they seem to be getting stuck
above the 15 block drop way up there
once they fall down though they seem
they don't have any trouble getting down
here
and before when they were there they
would kind of jump around all the time
and climb up sometimes now they're just
very
very nicely just sitting there waiting
to be killed which is nice
once you hit them though they'll climb a
little bit
but once you stop hitting then they fall
back down so
yeah one place i know they are jamming
is over here
that might have been from the
renovations i've done though i could
have
broken a sign accidentally or something
possibly
and yeah what was i gonna say oh yeah
this
this seems to be working okay um for let
you we might see a spider come up
there we go uh even though they're
trying to get to me
they can't fight this current still with
the spider elevator here
so that's working really well it's just
in some of the
piping that goes
well here for sure and i don't know i'll
have to
look at it someday but not today
let's go do something else
all right so just really quickly here
we'll talk about the branch mine project
a little bit
not too much you're probably getting a
little tired of it because we've had two
in a row about it
but uh this is the situation
with the minecart stuff um
i need i don't think i'm gonna set up
like a cart system i think i'm just
gonna make it slow
i carry the cart with me or have
dispensers with carts in every so often
and then when uh you wanna ship stuff
back to the
the main hub there you just put it on
the track and then push it manually
i don't think i'm gonna bother with
buttons and
and launching stations and all that just
doesn't seem
overly practical with this because it's
an expanding mine
and could cause problems so i need all
the carts
to be able to make it back to this main
hub on their own so
if we do a cross thing like this
it goes that way unfortunately so we
can't use that trick
um so what i would like to do or i think
what will work
is if we get rid of that
and do
no got to do it like
this we'll make a cross
type thing and
get rid of that that and that
so that we can form
like a little loop here
but we don't want it to connect back
together we want it to go
this way
how do we do that keep doing the same
thing over and over
um yeah i don't mess around with
minecraft stuff
all that much
there we go i think that's what i want
so then these will just go like this
and the card is going this way it will
do
that if it's going from this way
back it will do that and
if it's going from this way
it will darn it oh we were so close
hmm does it work if i
switch it it probably probably would my
mouse is acting up again i am so sad
i might need to get a new one again soon
oh that totally
was bad oops
um okay i'll redo this one sec
i guess having it switch doesn't work
either it was like this before
now we have it like this
just keeps going around and around on
that one
same with that one but i believe this
one goes
yeah so i have to do something else
so i've been uh i've been messing with
this
and it's turns out to be very difficult
very challenging
i am not having much success here i
thought this idea might work
just do a standard cross like this
obviously if it goes this way it goes to
the main hub like we want
then this detector rail would cause it
to switch so
instead of going straight that way this
will switch
pointing it to the main hub like we want
and you would think it coming from this
direction would go straight as well
should right it does
the problem is now we have a four right
cross here
and this detector rail does absolutely
nothing
it doesn't matter if you power this uh
it won't switch
once you add that this piece here
so this idea is not working either
and i tried it with a detector rail or
something besides
your standard rail hoping it might be
different but no
so yeah i'm trying to do this without
making a big mess of the track
and without having any raises or drops
in it
i wanted to keep it pretty clean if
possible but i'm not
doing too well here
all right i finally found a method that
works here i went back to using that old
ring style
but i also stuck in a detector rail and
just the power rail here to keep it
going in case it gets
stuck going around and around
and it works so this way
it's all good um this way
good now come back
and this way
is also good so that does what we wanted
to do
i had to do a little bit of wiring
underground here though
right below the detector rail is over
here
goes to the torch and then powers
oh right
oops it's like that didn't make any
sense
there's a torch hidden behind there
which goes to
the junction
all right and this uh this torch here is
just
to power this so i had to be careful not
to send any power below or have any
torches below this
this one here because that would cause
it to join with this track here
which we don't want um and i also tried
with the power rail to see it going max
speed when it enters this
intersection see if it goes the right
way or if it gets stuck going
in an infinite loop or something and it
seems to be fine
it'll go around a few times sometimes
that's the most i've ever seen it do it
usually it's one or two times
from that way other ways don't seem to
have as much trouble
so good got it figured out
and i forgot to mention but this does
work if i'm riding the carts
not just with empty carts which is
important
because this will be for me getting back
to
the main hub here
that way works this way has the most
trouble
but usually it's not bad sometimes you
get stuck going around
the ring one or two or three times
before it lets you through
all right
okay so i got a bunch of track laid down
here we're gonna go for ride
um and i wasn't really planning to spend
a lot of time at the branch mine today
it just kind of happened so sorry about
that
hopefully you still found it
entertaining
um i really enjoy this project i don't
know why
it's i guess it's because i don't really
ever do anything
really repetitive in this game usually
and this is a really relaxing
thing to work on i guess
and i really like the way it looks i
don't know
so i got these at the intersection
it's there's a power rail right there
then it skips
every odd one and that there's six of
these and
then i have them
uh over here so normally they're eight
blocks apart
here they're six blocks just the way
this works out and then it goes back to
eight
up until the next intersection
which is going to be right here and
it works really well if there's empty
carts
it kind of slowly chug along like that
so that'll be good for the storage
minecarts i'm hoping
they're able to make it all the way back
if there's unloaded chunks i'm not
quite sure what the story is with
minecarts and unloaded chunks
i'm pretty sure they'll work but
might have trouble if several carts
are sent back into the same unloaded
chunk i'm not sure
but anyway for reals this is all we're
going to do with this today
i'm going to go to do some i'm going to
do something i don't know what yeah
all right enchantment here efficiency 4
okay
so i really hate to do this to you guys
but i'm going to make you watch me
grind xp for a little bit here uh it's
because i have something important to
talk about
and i don't want you to be distracted by
what's going on
by any pretty colors or anything i want
you to really focus and listen to what i
have to say
um mostly going to be talking about the
ultra hardcore series we did
so we all had a ton of fun doing it
it was a blast all eight of us really
thoroughly enjoyed it
and we're talking about doing a season
four sometime soon
we got it all figured out pretty much
and i'm really looking forward to it as
well i know it's gonna be
a lot of fun again um
and we've been getting great support
from everybody too
people even made a minecraft subreddit
just to
comment about it and share their
thoughts and stuff
different things which is great getting
good support
a lot of people have said it's their
favorite minecraft series ever
which is just great oh voice crack
sorry just great just great
okay um
there is a bit of a touchy subject i
need to bring up though and i don't want
to talk about it
but i feel i need to i really do
the whole good hates
etho or pause hates etho or fill in the
blank
hates etho has to stop it does
please stop please please please stop
um i know a lot of you are kidding when
you say it
or at least i hope you are it's quite
clear when they said it that they were
kidding
good was laughing his head off when he
said it and pause
kind of said it because we told him not
to i think
but in the comments people keep posting
pause hates etho specifically pause
people have kind of forgotten about the
whole good thing which is great i
that's kind of why i haven't brought it
up yet is because i don't want people to
remember
but the thing is it's not going away or
at least not for pause
and even though most people are doing it
to be funny i think it's causing
a mob mentality or it's fueling
it's fueling the mob of haters i should
say there's people that
legitimately are harassing paws
about it and it's it's just got to stop
um and
with regards to the ultra hardcore
series
episode 3 like episode one and two
everything was great
but then people started dying uh when i
died
in episode three paz got over a hundred
dislikes
on his uh on his video because he killed
me
and that's ridiculous seriously
i don't know why people did that um
and it's gonna cause problems if it
continues which is why i'm bringing it
up now
to hopefully stop it for season four
we actually joked around about it before
we started recording that
uh poor poor whoever kills etho in this
because they're gonna get
so many hate comments we were joking
about it but it actually did happen and
that's kind of sad
um please stop
uh good has actually
been harassed like outside of the
internet from it and
paz just constantly gets
he hates etho comments and
just stop i don't know how else to say
it
uh yeah it's fueling haters
and it's not good and even
even if it's not a bad comment for a
commentator to read the same thing
over and over and over again in their
video comments
is really depressing like
in my episode three i had to read the
you should have used the lava bucket
hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of
times and it was
it's the first time i've hated reading
my comments usually i love reading my
comments
and uh that episode it just put me in a
terrible mood
i hate to say it i actually didn't even
record that day
because i was in a bad mood which is why
you didn't get an lp
episode yesterday um
yeah which is another thing i want to
bring up
i got so much flack from dying people
obviously i made mistakes
in my opinion if you die in the game
it's because you made a mistake
and there are things you should have
done differently and
the idea is you learn from your mistakes
and i was pretty much aware what i did
wrong
uh right after it happened but in my
panic
i did not react very well
and i'm worried about season four
because there's a good chance i'm gonna
die
and good chance other people are gonna
die or do things wrong
and i really hope you guys are nice
about it
doc has gotten quite a bit of rude
comments
and in good's last episode he's gotten
some rude ones because
he's kind of fortifying himself
and he doesn't know how other people
played it you got to keep in mind we
don't know
what all eight people are doing in this
we only have our perspective while you
guys can see
everything and
he was going for the long haul in it i
was too that's why he's going for the
netherward first
um and people are giving him a hard time
because he's just kind of
building himself up making himself
strong while other people are out
fighting
and that's that's not fair for that
either
doc got a lot of hate for making
mistakes and that you got to keep in
mind he was playing in the middle of the
night
dead tired and uh
i don't know i just hope in the next
season you guys are a little bit nicer
about things and i especially want the
hate etho comments to stop because it's
causing problems
i don't want it to get to the point
where uh
people choose not to kill me because
they're worried
like against their better judgment to
attack me they might choose not to
because they're worried people will
respond with hate and that would
actually influence the game
it's a game there's going to be winners
and losers so
let it happen don't uh
don't be mean please and if people make
mistakes
it's not like you can't comment about it
but do it in a nice way or in a joking
way or something don't be like you suck
i had so many people saying you suck or
you're an idiot you're stupid i had some
people say some things i'm not going to
repeat
i actually had to or i chose to ban a
few people just because what they said
and that's something i rarely do but
if you call me an idiot and you don't
say why i might ban you
i'm sorry especially if i'm in a bad
mood from reading all the
you should use the lava budget comments
um
yeah that's my rant i'm sorry i hate to
bring it up but
please be nice i love you guys
just uh yeah
don't want any problems in the future
okay
all right one more pick here um
oh yes finally oh it's been like
20 or 30 pics that i haven't gotten silk
touch and i've
just about used mine up i don't know why
i'm having such a hard time getting it
again
because usually when i do it there's at
least a 10
chance of getting it and i never seem to
and i only actually only have two good
picks right now that i can use
two efficiency picks so that's why
i'm kind of doing this too um
yeah i hate to do this but i'm probably
gonna have to end the episode here
because
i have a project i need to do and i
really shouldn't even be playing today
but
i wanted to get something out so
i will say goodbye for today and
hopefully we'll get
some quite a bit of stuff done next
episode
we'll see what happens okay
see you guys thanks for watching