Hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode I realized something I
always start the episodes like in the
exact same spot in the man cave
just once I thought let's go somewhere
else let's go to the potion lab because
this thing is actually really cool to
watch and we never come up here
I actually don't make potions very often
because once you make one batch they
last forever it seems but I've actually
ran low on instant health potions
believe it or not from the gold farming
and you can see I'm back up to 50 XP
levels because I was doing some more
gold farming we need power rails for for
that minecart thing I'm doing at the
amplified terrain so yeah if you guys
have been keeping up with the Minecraft
development you will have seen something
really exciting has happened I've talked
about how they're working on the ocean
stuff recently and it's out the snapshot
is out the ocean updates
well the start of it anyway from what I
read today it sounds like Jeb and the
team are planning on possibly adding
more structures to the Hey whoa little
guy Oh 50 levels ah darn it
that little guy just I have no pride now
he he killed me so quickly and I
couldn't defend myself but yeah they
Skelton totally lost my train of thought
now it's stupid zombie yeah so today I
think we're gonna go check out this new
ocean stuff
the underwater temples that have been
released and there's new new blocks
there's new enemies there's new I'm
really excited about the sea lantern to
be honest I think that's possibly my
favorite thing that was added with
addition to the enemies of course and
from what I've read it works in existing
worlds which is an exciting thing
especially for future patches because I
think that means they found a way to
technically add more stuff to worlds if
it comes out later in the game so that
means your worlds will probably be able
to survive patches better in the future
is what I've understood anyway if they
continue to do that so I'm going to try
find an ocean I think there's one out
past the stronghold and I got to get
geared up apparently the enemies are
really strong so we need better stuff I
haven't updated yet either I'm going to
make a backup of the world before we
head out just in case there are some
serious issues with the snapshot you
guys should always do this yourself make
a backup in case something is not the
way you liked it too you can always fall
back on that and yeah I guess we'll get
ready for a little adventure here I have
I actually don't have very good harbour
because I never bother with armor blast
protection protection - oh this will
come in handy
respiration 3 aqua affinity so we can
see underwater better I'll have to get
some night vision potions and there is a
new enchantments that came out for boots
that lets you walk underwater quicker
which is why I had 50 levels I was
hoping I would get lucky and get it but
now stupid zombie alright be right back
well first time this has happened to me
but the snapshot does not agree with my
world I downloaded it I started up my
world and repeatedly I was crashing so
we will have to do the ocean stuff
maybe next week or in two weeks when
they get more of the bugs ironed out
with it I was able to create a new world
no problem but something my existing
world here is not agreeing with it but
we're going to go do some exploring
anyway we are going to go check out the
ice spiked biome we tried to get there
last time and we had some trouble that
was not a troll by the way a lot of
people thought I was doing some fancy
video editing or something and making it
look like this was taking me out to
about 80 thought 80 thousand blocks out
no that was that was legit guys there's
some issue which has been reported by
the way so don't don't worry about
reporting it yeah this the portal is
taking me 64 blocks instead of eight
eight blocks per one blocked in the
nether which is kind of interesting I
tried making a new portal just a little
ways out over here and it looks like
this one's gonna work though so we can
hopefully find the ice spike biome today
we're in ice mountains over here we had
to get to like 2800 so we should be
fairly close I think this is all new
terrain here I haven't checked it out
yet and I've never seen the spiked ice
biome in the amplified terrain either so
I'm curious what its gonna look like if
if the ice spikes or somehow amplified
to or if it's just the terrain we will
see hopefully we don't have to go too
high up it does say mountains though
doesn't it yeah this may take a little
while I'm gonna dig until I see the sky
and then we'll be back well we didn't
have to go very far just a little bit
further here and we have hit the sky
guys woohoo red mushroom in a snow biome
what is going on Oh are we on the verge
of a border to another biome that's
weird there's grass here ice Plains so
we got to go out this way
you have speed potion so we should be
able to get there pretty quick that's
weird there's there's actually grass
showing ah oh oh they are amplified I
think that that's not my imagination is
it that thing's going way up to the sky
Oh
let's turn clouds off here they should
be off I don't know why they got turned
back on whoa
it's not all of them no it's just some
of them let's be careful too here let's
let's go forward whoa
getting a lot of lag it's just
generating the terrain right now look at
this overhang we got going this is this
pretty crazy and I like tell you you see
this we've got like snow layers all the
way up there's there's a layer there
there's a layer there another one there
pretty cool let's go explore a little
bit it's very um it almost looks like
dripping water that froze in mid air cuz
it's not all connected oh look at this
lake man oh uh that's okay I was
recording I had I think I had our
coordinates save time I was worried
there we might get lost and not find the
portal deck but we should be fine and
that looks crazy
look at that hill that mountain over
there that 100 getting lots like that
one is pretty weird it's like it curls
to the left and then it goes right it's
like a corkscrew almost going up oh man
this would be this wouldn't be a bad
place for a bass really not that we're
looking for a place but this is a pretty
nice biome huh I feel like we should go
this way this is where it gets crazier
there's another big mountain and back
there so while we're here I'm going to
click some of this too I tried in a
creative world like having haste to an
efficiency 5 on a pick it did not let me
instant mind it instant mine it so I
don't think there is a way to hey guy oh
all they hit each other whoa
all right let's keep going Wow
yeah it's pretty cool out here I'll give
this view very nice and there is an
awesome mountain here - it's like an arm
coming out of the ground and then the
hand at the top there
there's also ocean here it looks like I
haven't found much for ocean so when
that is out or when we do check out the
ocean snapshot we may come back over
here and when I said they get added to
existing worlds I meant like existing
chunks you visited already so even
though we've been here the structures
should generate when we apply the
snapshot with the ocean stuff in which
is a really neat feature
okay everyone so we are now over here at
our new base location that was it for
the spiked ice biome it wasn't very big
actually there's only one or two really
cool mountains in it and then that was
it but I did bring back some packed ice
which we'll probably be using soon in
the future but now today I have finally
come up with a plan for this place a
building theme possibly maybe we will
see we'll try it out today though so I
think we're going to start construction
around this area I really like this area
here there's a lot of potential for it
because we got like overhangs and
there's a lot of height here we can go
down we can go sideways if we want go
through the hill if we want four tunnels
and yeah so and we also have our future
storage room right over here too which
will come in handy I would like to get
this thing running I know if he's
noticed but there was some tracks laid
out there but I have a lot more tracks
to run you see one over there um like
3,000 blocks long at least so our theme
for our new place is going to be ancient
ruins I thought about it for a bit and I
think that'll be a good one
I kind of want something fairly random
ish you know that I can just this build
and not have to think about it too much
and this hopefully will will give us
that feeling
the thing is though I also want to
include wood colors with it too like the
Browns and maybe even a little bit of
colored clay and that kind of stuff
because if it's just gray blocks gray
and green it oh that's what happens and
it's terrible ah sneaky little creeper I
did not hear him at all not at all
so glad I set my spawn here wow there's
a problem right there cuz it's six
percent no wonder I couldn't hear him
oh I do kind of like oh iron oh I do
kind of like this about this new area
there's actually the risk of getting
attacked by mobs which is which is cool
I didn't really have much of that in the
man cave and I miss that because in
we're gonna fill us in by the way in my
old LP world with the storage room and
all that I used to get attacked by mobs
all the time and then in this new world
that never really happened much and
there was no random like it's funny when
you're watching somebody play Minecraft
and just out of the blue at creeper
blows them up I always liked that about
Minecraft videos and that doesn't happen
to me too much anymore when I play so
maybe this place will be different um
although I think it was this episode
already
oops hopefully that didn't mess things
up I bet you it did yep that's gonna
wreak a lot of things
darn it doesn't wash pressure plates off
though it went over the lava I'll snap
you're gonna have to be really careful
with water as we're working here well
okay guys so we got that flattened out
pretty good here next up we're going to
make a tunnel here that's sort of in
this shape I want it fairly epic you
know if it's just a 3x3 tunnel it's not
it's not too fancy that's what I brought
the tnt for I would get out of here so
much like the man cave we are going to
try build with the shape of the terrain
but we're not opposed to like making a
little modifications to it like this
hopefully this isn't the problem
actually maybe we almost need to do it
up higher
wait a sec we'll put a few down here
that's like the exact same it will put a
few up higher do another row over here
umm yeah we're going to be making some
adjustments to the terrain to our liking
and I always enjoy finding excuses to
use TNT even though it's probably just
quicker to use hey speakin hopefully
this is controlled enough oh wow
it didn't even activate the lower one
really I got so much TNT now guys I love
it yeah I was that was almost overkill
putting them so close together alright
so we're going to have it slightly
raised here as well that way when you
walk out you kind of look down on the
terrain here so actually this height is
pretty good I would say I'm going to
switch one of those beacons over to
haste to so then I can clear this a lot
quicker then over here I kind of want to
level it out and make a circle around
this place and maybe we will oops blast
out this lower middle part into a giant
pit I want to see what's down below here
oh let me get our torches ready I'm
gonna jump down and just see what's down
if we were to blow it all up with TNT oh
yeah yeah I think we should do that
because this is just like a that it's a
dead end otherwise there's nothing
really here yeah we'll do that did you
know my favorite part of construction is
actually destruction it's true because
destruction is awesome
all right so yeah it's going to go like
this
I want this overhang filled still though
and then we will have like support beams
on the very edge holding the ground
above us up you can see that cow is
about to have a bad day any last words
poor little cow here let's light this
one first I might have a bad day too
this guy's dangerous
all right and we got to take out there -
I didn't send a TNT up for that this is
the big one though there let's what's a
good angle to view this from maybe we
want to get far away from it's sort of
but still see it let's go over here
we're good good all right I guess we
need more how let's see how far down is
it or maybe it doesn't even go down here
maybe it was just in that forward spot
was it just forward oh I thought I fell
there might just be if we go forward we
might have a lot of blasting to do
oh there it is over here okay so all
this is solid then that's kind of bad
okay here we go again
get me out of here
all right I want it to like come out
words kind of like this wall is doing
right here where it it comes closer and
then it forms that overhang feel to it I
want that all around here so this wall
here is not good because it's perfectly
straight so we need to like bring the
top towards us a little bit more and
like the bottom out this is a three by
three by three of TNT how did that do
out we broke into it over there yeah so
this whole pillar like all this has to
go to get the pit I want a pit that I
can like hop down to a lower level here
really quickly and then we will go out
this way okay
one more run run run run oh we got lunch
Wow ah we might need to do that one more
time yet we're just about to the ground
though this should be the last one
I hope all I'm not far away
yeah that should be good that should be
good they're cool
and I noticed over here it looks a lot
better too if we go like on this pad
here when we look this way now you got
this light over there before it was
completely dark and you couldn't really
see anything and it didn't stand out now
it looks pretty cool like that so this
is starting to come together pretty
nicely here I did some more terraforming
off-camera
just manually shaping things try get
them flowing a bit nicer so I did this
tunnel room I mean I have another tunnel
going this way and that's going to
connect to the opposite side here so
instead of going straight through this
pillar it's going to come around and
connect to there a big thing I've been
spending my time on is shaping this does
the TNT is nice because it can blow up a
big area quickly and it has a certain
randomness to it that you probably would
never achieve if you use the pick but
the downside is it makes a giant mess
and there's it's very rough looking and
yeah so I've basically smoothed out the
whole thing as best as I could here try
to add some depth to it and we have like
the overhang feel to it then I wanted
you can see I've even thought about
adding layers partway up which will put
grass here and yeah just just for
variety there's a way to get to an area
here that you can't reach any other way
actually so this is just kind of cool
behind me
Owen ah darn it but yeah there was no
way to get up here so it's kind of cool
to have a way up here umm what else what
else added oops
I'm low on health I gotta be careful oh
and he's got an enchanted boat let's go
let's go
added a slime pad just temporarily until
we decide what we want to put down here
I have a feeling we'll change this out
to a big pool of water but we will see
ok we're going to try something here I
am wondering if we can slime jump our
way up to there if we if we jump from
here so let's see if we can do it whoa
Oh nope not quite let's see where are we
I think we are short at least ten blocks
wait where did we land I think we landed
there and I wanted to get here so yeah a
little bit short okay guys so another
thing about this pit it looks pretty
plain right now it's nothing but gray
and we got to change that so I'm
starting to add some grass on here and
also I think every so often we should
have like bushes growing out the side
with leaves hanging down or that kind of
stuff just to give it a little bit of
riding color this is what I wish I could
fly man would make it so much easier ok
let's do that
trying to get look like it hangs a bit
and yeah we'll just go all over the
cliff add the grass and we'll see what
that looks like oh yeah look at that
that's that's so much better isn't it I
like that a lot more stinking Enderman
though they're gonna wreck it all this
divot time and all that grass is going
to disappear you got to add some flowers
and some tall grass and that to it yet
but anyway we will probably have to end
this episode here I did not get to
building any of the ancient ruins it was
going to have like a staircase going up
here and then like balcony or whatever
type of thing then maybe a tower
here and yeah but we never got to that
today if you guys have ideas for ancient
ruins please let me know and if you have
screenshots or video of some cool
ancient ruin you've seen in Minecraft
send it to me in the YouTube PM or on
Twitter or something and hopefully I'll
see it I tried I looked around today a
long time for good like examples of it
that I could get inspiration from and
honestly I didn't see a whole lot it's
almost like maybe I was searching the
wrong thing it seems like one of those
things that a lot of people should
definitely be building but I had trouble
finding any examples honestly but anyway
here is the comment for today that I
picked out it says hey etho why don't
you check out space engineers I think
you would like it Luke the science guy
so I have checked out space engineers I
played it quite a bit I was addicted to
it for like two or three days right I I
had a hard time like getting my episodes
out those those couple days and if you
don't know space engineers you can get
it on Steam it's a sandbox space game
where you you mine asteroids and you can
build spaceships from like the metal you
you collect from the asteroids and it's
pretty cool there's not really a
objective to it it is a sandbox game
much like Minecraft but I've been very
tempted to make a series on it actually
and I might in the future we'll see I am
worried I don't know exactly how I would
do this series so that would be
interesting because there is a lot it's
like a very drawn out game it's almost
better for streaming than it is for
YouTube unless you cut a lot of it but
anyway that's it guys I hope you enjoyed
today's episode and I will see you again
in the next one I want like a launch pad
here to the
like shoot you over a fence and then
you'll go down anyway see you guys