Hey how's it going everybody
this is etho and welcome back once again
to our let's play series so check it out
I've been working on the nether wart
farm here and oh my goodness I like it a
lot you know I had my doubts about these
new blocks the nether warts the red
nether wart bricks and the magma and the
other nether wart blocks but now that
I've actually used them and see them
here I really really liked it and I was
a little bit sad
that I was having so much trouble making
these magma blocks like the make using
the magma cream is a little bit
expensive and then I saw you guys
comments it's like oh yeah you can find
it in the nether can't you so I went to
the nether I grabbed a whole bunch of it
and yeah we didn't use it a lot in
building cuz it's actually very abundant
in the nether I was surprised yeah
pretty much got the whole thing done
here in the middle I decided to just do
like a ring of magma around there try it
immediately it connects to the skylight
we got in the middle here as well and I
had to hang some lights for each of
these sections here just so the nether
wart wasn't totally dark so I got some
hanging lights going on and I did the
thing where you put glowstone right next
to the magma blocks and then they retain
the light from the glowstone so actually
even though it looks pretty dark in here
this is a bit of a darker theme right if
we look at our lighting levels this is
actually totally lit up like nowheres
does it drop the light level 7 where
we're standing here so that is pretty
cool we're not gonna get any mom spawns
on the grass here or anything yeah let's
try this out now right let's let's
activate this I haven't done that yet so
here we go press the button see if any
wash up on the sides now that I raised
the size a little bit as well good looks
like everything's getting washed in the
middle it does take it a long time
though right because it's on slow sand
so I think the items move slower right
that seems pretty slow like the wins way
in the back there still haven't made it
yet so we're gonna have to leave the
water running for quite a while whenever
we do a harvest here but yeah it looks
like it's gonna work pretty good
nuttin seem to have landed on the grass
area here uh-huh
but I don't have any oh it's still
didn't finish Wow
yeah it takes a really long time then
still don't have a collection system set
up we might do that today among other
things here now we're gonna do a quick
little test here just to see the
difference it actually makes I got soul
sand on one side dirt on the other water
in the middle so they should go at the
city exact same time as each other and
dirt is done and soul sand so sand is
done so yeah that's that's quite a bit
slower for sure okay guys so I want to
set up a hopper clock for our water
stream thing here because as it is right
now in order to use it we got to press
it once to turn it on to harvest all the
nether work wait for it to finish and
then press it again to shut it off if we
use a hopper clock we just have to press
this button once it'll time how long to
keep the water on for and then shut it
off automatically so it's a little bit
cooler a little bit easier and usually I
would just do this off-camera but I want
to give you guys a quick little hopper
clock tutorial here today because even
if you guys know how to how to build one
of these and you've used them before
there's a chance you don't know how to
use them to their full potential because
by making a couple little adjustments
you can actually change what it does
significantly I'll just show you that
real quick so this is the the classic
design here with using two sticky
pistons redstone dust over there and
there and then depending on how many
items you put in the hoppers here it
affects how long the timing is so right
now it's gonna bounce back and forth so
it's like a repeating timer it doesn't
stop if you want to stop it you can
power you
redstone dust the pistons the hoppers
the block here there's a lot of
different ways you can shut it off
and you see it stopped until you release
that again that's pretty cool now most
the time though you only want it to go
once you don't want it to continue going
so you can make it work with just the
redstone pulse like this switch one of
the sticky pistons to a regular piston
and then like if you send a redstone
pulse over there it'll go once bounce
back and then it'll stop right that's
pretty cool
now you can get oh yeah also they're
affected by block updates as you saw
there so because I broke the redstone
dust it activated it one way you can get
the power out is to put like a repeater
here and then when the block goes
forward it'll send the signal to that
but also if you put a repeater on the
side with the regular piston on the
block here look at the difference that
does so you notice how long that one's
on compared to this one this one stays
on for the full cycle so that if you
want to use it again right afterwards
you can if you're getting the power out
from here and art for our case here
because I want to turn the water on and
then off afterwards
two pulses what you can do is just put
two redstone dust like that and then
when it cycles back and forth you see
how it goes off and on so that's pretty
much all we got to do here and I figured
it's probably about two stacks of items
we have to put in here let's just try
this out for now shut off good and it's
done yeah so it only goes once and it
sends a double pulse on the output
cool cool so that seems to be working
pretty good now let's figure out how
we're gonna extend this room because as
it is right now there's actually no
proper entrance or exit or connection to
the man cave
creeper found me all right which way
where did we as are here yeah okay so
this is the closest side to the stuff we
got built over there so maybe we put the
entrance over on this side then let's
see if let's see what happens if we dig
this way and go down a little bit if it
will connect to the man cave because I
think it's supposed to yeah let's get
some torches going to or do well do a
little bit of planning here what what
paths we're gonna take is this something
I built yeah its first wood I was right
here oh man that was a lot closer than I
expected actually
maybe we don't want to go here then
maybe we should take one of the other
sides because they're a little bit
farther away yeah we'll be able to do a
better transition maybe if we pick that
side over there for our path man I just
found the light level 7 spot I've been
noticing we've been getting like
creepers and skeletons spotting in here
and I decided to check it out and yeah
it looks like there's actually a few of
them there's one here there's one here
one over here do they go all the way
down this spot over here seems fine it's
it's more over here I guess oh how do we
deal with this we'd either have to put
like a light over here or maybe what
happens if we lower this one more does
that solve the problem oh I think I got
rid of a few of them but yeah there's
still one one or two here I'll have to
think about that I guess I thought we
were all good but now we're getting an
Enderman down here but yeah here's the
plan
I decided let's make a fairly big room
over here this is where we're gonna
actually
like store the netherwart in chests that
we get from the farm here so we're gonna
make the ice-cream go off this direction
this is where we'll have the button to
harvest the crops and that kind of thing
crops I mean in other words and then off
on this side is where we're gonna
connect to the man cave so I been
experimenting here with the tunnel I'm
not quite sold on it just yet it's a
little bit on the plain side but yeah
basically it's gonna come down to over
here and I tried to line it up with the
staircase so we'll be able to go
straight through here and we'll also
want to probably refine this area a bit
better and he'll go up and to the right
here I think is pretty good and then oh
yeah people are telling me I should
build a bridge across the netherwart
here I thought about doing that but
maybe I just got to get better at the
bow jump because that works too and then
off on this side I'm thinking about
going up to the surface then have a way
out over here it does go right next to
the beacon we got set up though so I'll
have to move that first now in there's a
little blocks I hate you so much
everybody hates you here let's let's
start doing the ice cream though so
basically okay that's that's the spider
farm over there basically what we're
gonna do is have packed ice running this
way and then it'll eventually go to an
item elevator and hop into chess and we
might also want to sort the nether work
just in case other items get mixed in
with it
could you can cream ice cream ha ha okay
guys so we're gonna take a little break
from the building get a change of
scenery here and I have an idea for a
challenge I'm gonna I'm gonna pose this
challenge on you guys see if he can do
it I'll try it out myself here this is
the killer wither while flying challenge
okay so the rules are pretty simple you
have to do the whole fight while flying
if you touch the ground once you lose
and also know I'm not gonna use any
beacons or notch apples for this fight
and we'll see how it goes
I got two bows one of them is my flying
bow and one of them is a power five bow
and something is wrong with my mouse
it's jumping all over the place
okay hopefully that doesn't happen
during the fight heat up here I think
we're ready to go so let's take off and
I've got to shoot that pressure plate to
start it miss miss oh no that was a hit
okay yeah I don't know I don't know what
I'm doing here
this might be really dumb he's about
ready and oh right off the bat got a hit
and that's about it okay
yeah top priority here is just making
sure we don't touch the ground because
then it's over that was pretty good
that was dude it's almost three nice all
man four hits in a row baby that's what
I'm talking about
oh and he's in he's in sword mode
I missed no sword mode actually is
probably going to be very difficult
especially if he starts moving now that
I think about it he's chasing us that's
good I think but he's recovering so fast
and he's flying higher than me I'm not
really sure what to do about that buddy
yeah he's flying higher than me every
time every time I try to get him here
that might be a flaw with this I got a
hit I got a hit oh snap okay I'm gonna
do it strength potion time
this is the real deal I want him to stay
on me here it's it's so stupid no I
think I came across a pattern here
though Oh
losing altitude losing altitude guys if
we can keep him stuck on me no he's not
on me now I lost them oh my potions
gonna run out I only brought the one now
I missed we need him back on us I think
it would have been possible there if I
could have kept up that pattern because
I was able to hit his feet while I flew
by oh he actually hit me with a bullet
man oh he's angry yeah I can just I can
just barely hit his feet as I go by
there okay but I'm struggling to stay in
the fight here already he went on
something else now
darn where'd he go I need to keep him in
the air I totally lost them
I'm really struggling fighting well
withered here where did he go
seriously I have no idea must be off
this way oh he's over there yeah he's
recovered a lot gotta get back up when
our strength potions gone I got one
eight-minute one but it's not the
strength to where to go somewhere my
inventory there it is okay okay let's
get them back down to half we'll try
this again I don't think I'm gonna
succeed in this fight though especially
because I keep losing em no seriously
he's like gone
so we're here somewhere did he go into
the trees all he's over there darn it I
don't think I'm gonna be able to get him
out of there if I don't get him out of
there it's over oh I was a big mistake
oh okay I'm bailing I'm bailing yeah I
failed it was a good attempt I need more
strength potions of to finish it I think
and a better location okay guys so we
are back at the nether wart farm now
doing some things here I think I solved
the lighting issue we were having kind
of maybe but not really
I've seen some rumors in my comments
that these magma blocks are a little bit
glitchy at the moment so you'll see the
light level says 9 8 and 9 and I'm
almost certain it was higher than that
before I saw people were saying when you
leave the chunk it resets or something I
don't know how much truth is to that so
now it's 13 all the way down and that
gets rid of the light level 7 problem we
had also I added a little bit of a face
plate here on the end of of all of these
I think that looks kind of ok breaks it
up a bit more mmm yeah something very
strange is happening for sure I left the
area and came back like I let the chunks
unload it still says 13 here where we
just updated but a lot of these other
ones either overtime or whatever have
have lowered in light level so maybe
when they receive a block update maybe
it decreases I don't know this is my yes
and like like updating the lighting
around here isn't changing it either
it's not lowering it so I don't know
something very strange though for sure
anyways worst case scenario we'll just
put a little stone
glowstone on the opposite side of the
magma block and that should fix it long
term over here I did set up the item
elevator for the nether warts so
basically we got the water stream and we
just thought we fell down
we fell down can't see anything now okay
we back up good yeah the water streams
over there so it's bringing all the
nether words to the very end here into a
hopper into the item elevator just using
droppers we got a little clock system
that detects if there's items in there
and then ever it runs and staircases up
to each of the droppers and lets go back
up so now if we activate the farm it
should shoot a bunch of nether word out
of the top here
oh yeah and to activate it I think what
we'll do is maybe put a button right on
these droppers yeah let's do that
we'll do a wooden button maybe right
over here shouldn't interfere with
anything else besides the item elevator
yeah we'll do that and then let's run
this over so that I'll go to the the
hopper clock there and I think I got the
right timing on the water now ah that
looks so cool when I harvest some it I
really like that they like the nether or
kind of jumps along as it goes looks
neat okay and then from the top here
we're probably gonna run some more
hoppers over to the other side here and
then into some chess so maybe one two
three four five six seven how far off
how far away do we want to go with this
maybe just over here okay so when this
hits zero hopefully it'll start working
now this is still powered by something
well
I messed up somewhere let's go back down
this is oh I left the oops that redstone
block is not supposed to be there I did
that for testing to see how long the how
long the redstone wire could reach okay
so now it's shooting out the top good
okay yeah netherworld goes up into the
hoppers branches over to there and then
back down into the chests so they should
start funneling into here nice and we
got plenty of storage with five double
chests should be good
aha so I'm just taking things over
making sure this is working properly I
detected one problem here it's producing
more nether work than this hopper can
pick up at once so that stuff will
despawn if we just leave it a simple
trick if this ever happens to you when
you're making a farm is just to add more
hoppers so that adds five extra storage
spots so they were to go into this one
first so we for interrupting this
episode but here's a short word from our
sponsors hey there
do you play Minecraft with your friends
do you want to kill your friends of
course you do
introducing the sand slab by ethos slab
yeah this is actually a really old trick
guys I thought show it to you today
though just in case you've never seen it
so if you're playing on a server with
your friends and they see this there's a
good chance a lot of them won't know
what it is because it's not something
you see every day but curiosity kills
the cat right yes so they'll probably
walk into it to try stand on it see if
we can stand on it and then they'll fall
in I'll show you how to do this it's a
you can actually make a really simple
trap this way what you got to do is have
a bunch of fences down because fences
are a block and a half tall what happens
when you drop sand on its is check this
out it actually kind of just hovers
there it's a floating sand entity not a
sand block and you can do it this with
gravel with red sand and VLEs I think
dragon eggs all those sorts of things
Oh actually whoops I was gonna show you
how to make a trap was it I totally
forgot what I'm doing here dad let's get
this back down so yeah you can just put
like live in there or something will
work out pretty good and again since
these are not blocks it doesn't destroy
the lab but when it falls on it
kind of like that and it looks really
jumpy right now but I think once you
leave the chunk and come back then it
smoothes out all right guys well
unfortunately I have ran out of
recording time here again today so we're
gonna wrap it up but we made some pretty
good progress on this I got the main
look of this room figured outs start
expanding got it functioning and we
goofed around a little bit today too
which was fun try out the challenge see
if you can do it I think if you flew up
high in the air it would be a lot easier
and just like glided your way down as
you try to do the sword attacks it's
probably the way to go with that but I
was the guess but yeah it's fun and yes
we do have a wither loose in the world
now here's the comment for today it says
how about name the swamp mush whomp
mushroom + swamp makes mush whomp pretty
good I like it I think we'll go with
that right uh-huh
and actually I have a question to ask
you guys today not to finish up here I
see a lot of people in the comments I
don't know if it's like old people
coming back to the channel or what but a
lot of people seem to want me to start a
new world I don't really want to start a
new world personally but like if I do I
know I'm gonna mean nostalgic and miss
this world and all that kind of stuff
but maybe what we do go off to a new
area in the world and abandon all our
items and start fresh and then like be
able to go back and forth and like just
leave the items from the new area at the
new area and the areas the items for
this area over here you know don't mix
and match them might be an interesting
experiment to try outs but I want to see
what you guys have to say about that I
know some people don't like watching
restart as well but could be fun
I don't know thought I'd bring it up
anyways we're gonna wrap it up thanks
for watching I hope you have a wonderful
day have any ideas let me know and
until next time take care bye-bye