hello everybody thanks for joining me
again
and like i said we are going to be
building something special today
something new
it's going to be another xp system and
you can probably guess by the title of
this episode
we are building what i'm calling a
silver fish factory
it's an idea i had a couple weeks ago
played around with it a bit in creative
mode and it's actually really cool
um i'm making it mostly for the fun of
it
i still haven't worked out all the
details on how
to do it it's actually very complicated
oh there goes our bane of arthropods
but yeah we're making an xp system
there's lots of different types of xp
systems you can make in this game and as
far as getting xb
quickly goes i would have to say blaze
farms win
because they have 10 xp each and if you
find a dual
blaze spawner it's really tough to beat
enderman farms also give a lot of xp if
they're set up well
and then a good average farms are like
the zombie ones in the cave spider
spawner ones those all work pretty good
too
but these silver fish they have i was
thinking about it and they have a really
neat property about them
they can hide in blocks
there's three types of blocks they can
hide in regular cobblestone
smooth stone and then these regular
stone bricks here
just just these type not the mossy ones
or the cracked ones
and that's really no this isn't killing
them
okay i have to stop using that sword
that's really interesting because
it makes it possible to store xp inside
of blocks basically because these guys
will hide in blocks after a certain
amount of time
um i actually wanted to check to make
sure
or to see if they will do it while
aggravated
at me let's help this guy up
he's mad at me oh no
he no now i'm mad at him
yeah these guys are quite the fun
fun treat to work with probably one of
the most annoying mobs in the game
i'm just trying to see if they'll enter
these blocks while mad at me
normally they do when they come into
contact with them
relatively quickly if they're not
aggro at you but it doesn't seem like
they're doing it
while aggro
yeah okay so
they can't be mad at us which means they
can't have a line of sight to us
okay yeah so
silverfish spawners there's only one per
stronghold which means it's not going to
be
a very quick xp system like it's not
going to be good rates
compared to some other things you can do
these guys only drop 5xp
but since they can be stored inside of
blocks
um it has a unique property where you
can
actually like if you afk at a normal
spawner system you have to deal with
lag issues and possibly crashing your
game
if you have hundreds and hundreds of
mobs
building up in them and then if you walk
away they just disappear that's it
but with a silverfish system you can
store them
and then cash them in whenever you want
type thing
which is pretty cool so i'm going to
start working on this pretty quick here
i'm just gonna
get my stuff together and we will get
started
okay so the first thing i'm gonna do
here is get rid of all this lava so i
don't
walk into it again or anything like that
we'll need it for
later too and i
don't think the portal needs it to be
around i hope
pretty sure it doesn't
and grab that so we got six buckets the
rest i'm just going to fill in with
it's going to kill it oh
before it kills me nope nope too late
guys man they're so
bad
uh i can't really shut down the spawner
too well either
because they i read the wiki and it said
light level 11
or lower they can spawn from the spawner
uh we'll probably test that ourselves
just to check
in a little bit here
fill this in
yeah i would definitely die today if i
didn't do that now the big problem we
have is just
portals in the way
we could remove it and this would be a
lot easier to build then
and it would also work better but
this is also my only portal to the end
that i have
i wasn't able to locate any other
strongholds yet
so oh it did go out
nope one thing i didn't want to come
here
uh okay i'll be right back
okay i made it back here and i've
started making a case around the spawner
like i usually do
um it's gonna be that eight by eight
thing
spawner is below this block here
and goes out four blocks this way from
that
and three blocks this way numbers get
lower
this direction so that's how i figure
that out
um and that thing with the portal it's
just a visual thing
you all probably knew that um but you
can see it from on top and not
from below even though it's there
so yeah i'm trying not to
break this portal here if i can help it
i would get better rates if i did and
this would be a lot
easier to do if i did but this is my
only portal i know of
in my world i've tried finding more
strongholds but i haven't succeeded yet
i haven't looked really hard but i have
thrown pearls around to check
and haven't found any new ones
a lot of people say there's more than
three per world but as far as i've seen
so far i haven't seen any evidence
suggesting there's more
not saying there isn't but i haven't
seen any proof of there being more than
three per world so
i don't want to risk destroying one of
these portals if i can help it
and uh so that means i'm gonna try and
make my case around it
and just incorporate it inside and see
how that goes
so i will work on making the
8x8 case and we will probably install a
lighting system to this
once we figure out the exact light level
we'll make sure it's
11 or lower like the wiki says
so i will check back in a little bit
here and once i make some more progress
okay i'm having silver fish problems
my flint and steel broke so i've just
been hitting them
just to get rid of them all i want them
all to break from the blocks
and this reminds me of something too
while playing around on spellbound caves
like just for the fun of it i found out
a little exploit you can do in the
skittering mines
if you have diamond armor a regen
potion and one of those flaming battle
signs
you can keep hitting the silverfish in
that area
and hundreds and hundreds will just
swarm around you and they're all a
one-hit kill
and xp will just flow like
like water like as quick as you can hit
the mouse button
you'll get xp from them kind of like i'm
doing here it's just
filling up the room this is kind of what
the mob system is going to be like
only hopefully it'll be better even
i got most of them out of this room
and i am going to get back to work here
i found a new air oh look at it oh it's
beautiful
no they're gonna push me in the lava
creepy enderman back there
mm-hmm
okay back to work all right as by the
enderman farm i decided to level up to
50 since we were so close
and here we go doing a pick
decent i like those not going to
complain about that
so i've been playing around with the
lighting here and i'm still having them
spawn in the middle
uh even with torches all around pretty
much except that side
i think the only way i can actually make
a lighting system for this to turn it on
and off
is to replace entire ceiling with the
lamps because they'll be light level 15
and this would be 14 13 12 and if these
guys need
light level 11 or lower to spawn they
shouldn't
should be spawning at that
so that's probably what i'll end up
doing
these guys man um they don't seem to be
spawning around the portal
like i kind of thought they would spawn
above it and below it but that doesn't
seem to be happening
at all although it might be because of
the lights
but even before that i never noticed it
so yeah i'll be back when this is
replaced
it's a little bit expensive but i
definitely want an on off for this
because these guys are extremely
annoying
all right so that is definitely doing
the trick now we're not getting any more
spawns
this is an 8x8 ceiling so that's 64
lamps i had to
put up here but there's no real way to
avoid that i could
probably have less if i was to put some
in the walls of this but then the wiring
becomes more complicated
and i just don't want to deal with that
because i'm not exactly sure how to
build this yet
so the simpler i can make it the better
ideally when this is all done we want
this as dark as possible in here to
maximize the spawn rates as well
so we need to cover up this these portal
blocks because i think they let light
through
and we can't have them outside like this
or else
light will pass through into the
spawning room here we want it completely
sealed off when this is done
and i'm going to replace these this wood
i've put with sandstone i think
something
non-flammable and we can't use a stone
cobblestone or these stone bricks
because
uh the silverfish will hide in them and
we can't have that either
i could use like the the cracked ones or
the mossy ones but uh they're more of a
rare block so i'd rather use sandstone
and also there's something very unique
about these
silver fish spawners as well even in
high light levels
even in high light levels they can spawn
on stone
just stone i don't think cobblestone
works
um at least i hope they did
do otherwise i just lied well maybe put
a few more
increasing chances
don't know why it's not happening
come on so the only area they can spawn
in here is
these first these uh three layers here
this one this one in this one
nothing below nothing above the spawners
the spawners in between at this layer
here
yeah they're not spawning when i tried
it before in creative it worked
unless that changed they really should
be spawning by now
um
don't know what the deal is oh there we
go
oh that's because the light was blocked
out though that doesn't count
um yeah i don't know why that's not
working now
anyway i'll show you the wiring
for the lights it's very simple
might be able to do a little better yet
just an outer ring
here and then little branches off here
for the corners
otherwise they wouldn't be lit and that
pretty much covers the whole thing
okay so i'm going to finish this up i'm
going to replace it with sandstone and i
will be back
oh yeah one other thing i was going to
show you is that mobs will spawn at
light level
11 or lower i just saw it
i had only four places with lamps
missing so
it's only four blocks in this area
within the spawner that they can spawn
uh with a light level of 11
and everything else is 12 or higher so
they they can spawn
at light level 11 or lower it's
confirmed the wiki is correct
okay i'm back again and i have learned
quite a few new things here
the case is done pretty much i just made
a little viewing window here so i could
see
their behavior apparently
these guys have the same property that
spiders have where they will
are not property but behavior where they
will track your player
through blocks like without a direct
line of sight to you
um that might cause problems won't be
too big of an issue but as soon as you
get a little ways away from them
they start to wander around so if
if they're tracking like they were
before they won't enter
the stone blocks i'm pretty sure which
would prevent this all from working so
we need to make sure we
are it looks like it's only eight blocks
so one
two three four five six
seven yeah it's about eight blocks
wait one two three four five
six seven eight um
maybe maybe like nine
nine or ten so it's i don't think it's
quite as far as spiders
tracking ability uh
the way i'm doing the spawner i'm
dropping them down
let's see spawners at that level there
one two three four five blocks
that's so that these guys are out of
range of the spawner so that it'll keep
spawning
more so more than six will spawn
and after a long period of time this
room would just fill up
with hundreds of them you can see the
lights are off
but there's still light in here and
that's my next major
problem i've realized apparently that
end portal
emits a light level of 15
so another reason i want to destroy it
but
at the same time i need it so
i'll have to probably encase it with
blocks
but i'm going to first try making a
backup of my world here and
maybe destroying some of the blocks see
if we can
and possibly make it smaller
and i'm going to try silk touch on it
too i don't know if we can actually even
destroy
the frame but we're going to try it
um
there's something else i was going to
show you i know it but i can't remember
now
oh well
okay remember now i was going to show
you them entering
the stone box so we're going to turn
this on
stop the spawning and we're going to go
in there
and get our butts kicked i only have
my uh pants on right now
hopefully i'll be okay
i need to make a new set of armor i
guess
okay yeah so i'm just going to put down
some blocks here so we can observe the
silverfish entering them
uh that's one there these are the three
types
they can enter them if they're directly
below too so if we put one
like here they'll be able they'll be
able to enter that too
okay so we're going to turn this back on
and it hopefully won't take too long
have to be away from them though
so it's kind of random it's like when
they make contact with it then
quite often they'll enter the block
or if it gets in their way when they're
walking
that guy just walked over him but he
didn't go in so they don't always do it
but
uh
if you have lots of them walking around
it's going to happen for sure
come on guys
any day now
also i want to give a shout out and a
thanks to
premier pixel who has made me a new
uh there we go he entered the stone
block
right there who made me a new channel
background new image
for that with the new layout that i'm
forced to use now
all youtube pages are required to use a
new
channel layout so i'm sorry if you don't
like it
but you're going to have to get used to
it because i can't can't use the old one
anymore
and i want to say thanks to the mr
schizobel who provided the old
background
which served its purpose for a long time
it was a great background and even
though it's retired now
it had uh had good use so thanks mr
schizabel
for that as well so we can see
i think yeah they entered that one
that one that one
i must have missed all these not that
one and not that one
hmm
they can though not when they're
tracking me okay well anyway
the portal i have to do something about
the portal oh
ladybug just landed on me ah
that was distracting okay one sec
oh yeah and if you make one of these
make sure you put a glass block above
the spawn or two otherwise that will
happen
it'll get stuck up there
and he won't come down
unless you do that okay so i made the
backup
we're going to try see if we can destroy
this
might not be able to it's something i've
never tried we're going to try silk
touch
nope indestructible
try the actual portal
also indestructible okay i read
something about maybe
being able to wash it away with a bucket
water buckets we'll try that too
um and if that doesn't work we'll just
have to
encase it with blocks and take the hit
okay
nope that is not true
whoa open my water that i didn't place
it there did i
i must have okay um
yeah we're going to be encasing it then
we will lose a fair bit of space in here
plus side is we can remove the lamps
above
and we'll have an easy way to get back
into the portal
but we will lose some spawning space
which means spawning rates will be
decreased slightly from it
so lower xp rates
here's another update for you guys i
have been busy here
i have in case the portal
that has reduced the amount of spawning
space by about
a third so there's two thirds left or so
it's going to lower rates but we'll have
to deal with it
on top here now we can get into the
portal actually
just down here
i'll probably adjust that yet make it
look a little better
then i've started making a little place
for the silverfish to fall in this
this line here to get them a little bit
more compressed
and then they're gonna come to the end
and fall down
here and i think i'm going to
put water along this wall here i'm not
sure if water's
better or not as far as
getting them to that spot there because
they fight the current really
aggressively but
doing this will ensure there's no other
mob spawns in here
so that's one of the main reasons i'm
doing that
then for down there i think i'm just
going to put a half slab so we don't get
any mob spawns
and it will still be a block and a half
so they won't be able to jump up
and out of here
um this will have to be moved i tested
this
and silver fish are taller than half a
block
so they would not be able to fall down
there
i guess now we can
actually do this which is awesome
yeah okay uh i'm using so much sandstone
on this but i love sandstone so
may as well
okay so i am going to get this
and
let's see we're going to put glass along
here just for now while we're testing
this so we can see what they're doing
hopefully um
yeah i'm just gonna try to turn it on
see what happens here
the silverfish go down already oh he did
because they're tracking me they just
bee lined right to the wall here
yeah so it's nice and dark in their net
excuse me it's nice and dark in there
now that i got that
portal encased
these guys it really doesn't matter how
much damage they get
while i'm processing them here in my
factory
because once they go in the block their
health will
get reset basically so if they have half
a heart and they
enter a block when they when you break
it they're gonna have four hearts again
so it resets when they get recreated
um okay i'm going to shut that off
we're about to do we're about at the fun
part here
uh just give me one moment and i'll be
back
actually i should probably explain the
idea to you a little bit more before we
advance any further here so what we have
what we've built already is a way to
spawn silver fish
we can control when they spawn using our
lighting system
and then the water stream and their
pathfinding will bring them all to this
one spot
here they all concentrate here
so beyond that in our factory we need a
way
to get them into the blocks the stone
cobblestone or these stone bricks
so that we can store their xp
and basically we're going to need lots
and lots and lots of blocks
because this thing's going to spawn an
infinite amount
of silver fish so ideally we want an
infinite amount of blocks so
the way i thought of doing that is just
to have
a smooth stone generator or cobblestone
generator whatever you choose
to create an infinite amount of blocks
for them to
hide in
hello they're having a party over there
i blocked this area all up so that
creepers can't get here
but they can still look um yeah
so i was thinking there's two good ways
of doing this really uh one would be to
have a room of cobblestone generators
um creating big like 12 by 12
slabs of smooth stone
that spider can get here and then
let the silverfish loose in the room and
let them wander around
and they'll randomly enter blocks and
uh then when you start the chain
reaction of
hitting the silverfish and making them
come out of the blocks
the slabs will get full of holes and
then the cobblestone generators will
create new blocks and make it all solid
again to restart the process
that's one idea that's the easy way of
doing it
there's mobs everywhere oh yeah and when
you break a block
that has a silverfish in or when you hit
a silverfish
and not kill them the game will check
a 10 by 10
area all around them like all around the
sides of the silverfish and a five above
and five below five blocks above and
below
the silver fish for any more silverfish
blocks and if there's
any in that range
then there's a possibility of them
coming out of other blocks
so in that way you can control uh where
they come out of blocks so you could
potentially set up rooms like if you
wanted to control how many levels you
gain
from breaking all the silverfish blocks
takes 4 625 xp to get to level
50 from level zero that's
would be 925 blocks you would need in a
room
to make that happen because each
silverfish is 5xp
so you could have several rooms fill up
and then every time you want to get a
level 50 enchantment you just go in the
room
uh make all the all the silverfish come
out
and you'll go from zero to 50 that way
and just space the rooms far enough
apart where uh breaking them in
or killing the silverfish in one room
won't affect them
in the other room i'm rambling a lot i'm
sorry
but the way we're doing this one is a
little bit different
this is the second idea i had
this is more controlled we're gonna make
the silverfish fall on this
sandstone here then where this glass
block is we're gonna
have our infinite line of smooth stone
from a generator
over there
and we'll put a bud switch next to this
smooth stone block here and it will
detect when a
silverfish enters the block and then it
will
tell the generator to create a new block
and it will push
silverfish block away and
put a fresh new smooth stone block
in its way for more silver fish to enter
and every time that happens
it will keep creating a chain of
silverfish blocks and then we can
clump them together in like big 12 by 12
by 12 cubes
at the end of all this so that's the
plan that's what we're trying to do here
it's very complicated actually and
getting this timed rate is going to be
very difficult
as i've played around with this before i
had a lot of trouble with it
okay so i think we're ready to build on
some more here
the next step to this is going to be
probably putting the
cobble stone generator smooth stone
generator
if i say cobblestone generator i mean
smooth stone
use that word inter changingly or
whatever
um i think this is a good enough
distance here if i remember right
i have built this before but i'm going
by memory
uh and i played around quite a bit with
different
ways of making the generator it's really
important that it's quick
and i was having a hard time making one
that could quickly produce blocks
came up with this design it's pretty
good it's not perfect
but it seems to do the trick not too bad
and it has a
safety to it as well if if it ever
glitches out where it doesn't
uh or where the lava flows through the
water
it's able to correct itself because it's
uh two generators into one
oh i'll be able to explain a little
better as we build it here
um so lava goes above the piston arms
there
and another one over here
like that lava will go right there and
right there okay
and then we need a place for the water
the water goes to the left and right of
this piston here this is the main one
that pushes the block
let's see we'll just put that there for
the water
i think we can use glass for this if i
remember right
just so we can see what's going on um
water will go there flow down one block
so we'll put another one like that
yeah if it can't keep up this thing is
going to jam
up and stop working so we need a very
quick one
or else we need to really regulate
the rate that silverfish blocks can be
created otherwise
it will get ahead of itself
okay be careful the shovel
i'm so sad you can't pick up glass
blocks with silk touch anymore that was
uh they're really nerfing silk touch you
can't pick up silver silverfish blocks
with
them ir or ice they need to
get that stuff back that's why silk
touch was so awesome
okay water there water there
lava above
i think it's safe to put it now
yep make smooth stone
pistons push it to the middle we will
need
to put furnaces on both sides of these
two so that
uh the pistons can't push each other
one of them will be dominant over the
other one
um so
we'll we'll see when it's set up here
okay furnace over here
not that it really matters we have a
wall behind but if i move that
i want it to work still and one
over here okay
it's taking shape
put that there and
i think that's it that's good okay now
we need to wire it
um
i'm refreshing i wonder if i can cover
that i think i'm able to
like i said i'm building this from
memory so i might make a mistake
uh we can put sandstone over top
here
so we need to run a wire to that arm we
probably
actually need this to be sandstone
and one over here
okay so i'll wire this and then i'll be
back probably take a few seconds only
minutes maybe hours i don't know it'll
take a little while
not overly exciting
there seems to be a real party up there
now we got two creepers and a skeleton i
don't know how they keep
getting there so there they must really
be tracking me
it's amaze the new ai is pretty amazing
yeah i think this is all ready to go
here so yeah there's going to be a
dominant
piston because both these pistons get
activated with the same delay
so the game has to decide which one gets
actually gets pushed because they can't
both
push to the same block but if this thing
is running so quick
that one of these doesn't have a block
anymore
the other one will still push it and
in that way we can have two blocks being
created
at a time up to two and it
it'll create a smooth stone a little bit
quicker than if you were just to have
one
and i got a button here the middle one
is set at a
two delay i think that's the way this is
supposed to be
i hope
okay maybe we'll push it a few more
times
heard the sizzle
so that's what i mean when i say the
lava overtakes the water
if that happens no smooth stone gets
created
and if you only had the one that would
be it the thing would be jammed up
but if you have two
it allows the block to still get pushed
by one of them
and the lava gets cut by the piston arm
so then it is able to fix itself
on the on the corrupted one
so that's good and we are making smooth
stone nice
okay so the silverfish will come down
here they can enter from the side of the
block
so that's that's all good um
next thing we gotta hook up is the bud
switch
yeah so the bud switch goes right on
this block here this is next to the
silverfish chamber
in here so
sticky piston put a block on it
and that will extend to
um let's see
i think that's where we want it be a
redstone torch
and then we need it to reset
so um
if there is a repeater
oh dang what did we hit
oh there it is gotta be really careful
these tools they're too good
way too good okay put that there
repeater i think we want the repeater at
one
delay as low as possible
um that will go to a block
and we need to invert the signal
so we'll get one more of these
i think over here
and then
i'm going to run that signal to the
piston
i keep doing that
ah so hard working in this cave
everything's a mess these my good blocks
too
yup okay where's my wire
so we can grab the power from there and
run it over
to the piston we want it diagonal of the
piston
so that whenever block gets placed next
to it it updates
and does that okay so that'll send out a
pulse
and now we want that pulse to go to here
so that it'll activate the cobblestone
generator
so we're going to start another path
over here
um
can you place redstone on yeah you can
okay that might be a good idea
i think we can do it with no or not too
much delay
i think if we do that it'll work so
let's see if it makes a smooth stone
when we update
yeah awesome
so that's going to happen every time a
silverfish enters a block
so technically i think this is all ready
to go but it's not going to work at the
states
for very long and that's the next thing
we have to deal with
let's see what should we do
we should test this to make sure it
works
uh when i was playing around with this
before i was doing in creative mode and
obviously
things that are a bit different with
this we'll have to
keep our distance otherwise they'll be
aggro at us
and they won't enter the blocks
unless they're not tracking you now i
almost think he's not tracking me now
it's hard to say
let's see uh
and it might take a while before it
really starts going that once the
concentration of silverfish increases
they're more likely to
touch that block there and then enter it
might be tracking me i can't quite tell
there we go
and there we go so these are silverfish
blocks now
pretty cool huh
but it's not gonna run for very long
like this it has problems
all right so i'm gonna try to
demonstrate the problem with the way
this is set up right now why it won't
run
for the long term like several minutes
or hours
we have about 21
maybe 16 silverfish in here they're not
able to enter the block right now
because i'm standing
next to it and they're tracking me this
is a
stone block there's no silver fish in it
yet
as soon as i back away they'll be still
be able to enter
and they'll all enter really quickly
that's silver fish and that is also
silver fish
so they beat the bud switch basically
they're able to enter the new stone
block before the bud switch
resets and it is able to detect them
and there really is no way of dealing
with that
because the bud switch needs a certain
amount of delay to work
the signal needs to be inverted and you
also need that
repeater so two delay
is the minimum for a bud switch like
this i'm pretty sure
and the silverfish can enter basically
instantly
so this is a real pain
to sink and this is where i ran into
trouble
when i was uh playing around with this
before in creative mode
that's about as far as i got with the
project
and this is where it gets interesting
really interesting
the other thing is we need the
cobblestone generator to
not be activated overly quickly either
otherwise
it won't be able to keep up creating
blocks and it will jam up too
so cobblestone generator needs a
delay bud switch
has to be timed right otherwise uh
silverfish will enter the block and if
you delay the cobblestone generator
uh the bud switch will also activate
when these blocks get pushed
so it'll get activated twice
so that's another problem i played
around with the
t flip flop mud switch and uh
i basically had same problems
can't keep up with the silver fish
entering the blocks
so we need to add a new third delay here
we're going to have to put a piston
underneath
where all these silver fish are
and we will have to hook this up to the
bud switch as well
there we go so that
um before the
the new stone block
gets pushed over here before that
happens
this needs to extend and once the bud
switch is all ready
and waiting to detect the silverfish to
enter then this can retract
so that they are able to enter it that's
what we need to do
with the redstone yet and
uh i'm guessing
i will probably do that another day
because this episode's getting really
long
but from this point
as far as what what we do with these
blocks we can
hook up some smart pistons and uh
move them to other areas and possibly
clump them
into several different rooms uh we
should be able to control that pretty
easily
yeah i'm going to do one more test run
here
with me standing at a distance from the
get-go
because when i did it before i had them
all concentrated and that's what jams it
up
with this current setup so let's see how
long it will run on its own
with the steady spawn rate
okay here we go i replaced this all with
glass so we can hopefully see what's
going on a little bit better
i'm curious to see how long it takes to
actually fall down
and we will have to get far enough away
where they can't see us
you can still see me for some reason hmm
hey
i wonder if they can see farther fused
glass
now he's doing his own thing
okay problem is i might be too far away
for the spawners to work now
i need to try to get a little bit closer
yeah okay it's going so those kind of
wander back and forth on there
eventually they might fall down uh
and they do like to fight the water
currents if they're not tracking you
it's just what they do and he seems to
want to go back
up now
okay i skipped ahead here and we still
haven't had a single one fall down there
yet
there's uh about 20 or so
maybe a bit more we should probably use
a water stream there then
because they don't want to fall down on
their own it seems
unless they get pushed so yeah
gonna put a water stream in
here's our next attempt seems to be
working better that's for sure
we might have to lower that drop
i hate to do it but they seem to
try to jump out if they fall down back
into the water stream
which would definitely be a problem
or maybe we could try to use a half slab
there let's see what happens
see he fell down then he jumped back up
oh oh that was actually pretty good
uh ideally if we can make this work so
that
generally there's only one in there at a
time in that concentrated chamber
the better it seems to jam up more so if
there's a lot of them
but it looks like they're stirring a
bunch up now
hmm there we go
yeah i like the concept of this
farm i don't know how good it's actually
going to be
to be honest i just think it's really
cool
but i it would be really neat if i had
my storage room above this
and it was running constantly and
every now and then you would just check
to see how many blocks have gathered
together
and it would be a pretty good xp farm
and right next to the end portal that
would be cool too
yeah yeah it's working good relatively
good i
i'm pretty sure after a few minutes if
if this could keep running it would
eventually jam up
uh i think it does keep up with the rate
that they spawn which is good
it's very important
whenever we have you know 17 there was
there's always going to be a few around
um they're one of those mobs that's hard
to
make go where you want they
they're fighting the currents
but yeah i think i'm going to end this
here today and we'll work on
maybe improving it later there's a lot
you could do with this yet lots of
different ways you could set this up too
if we can't get this way to work i might
try that other
method i talked about with the the rooms
of
full of hundreds of blocks and we just
let the silverfish
run around and do their thing
but i like this way because you know
guaranteed every one of those blocks is
a silver fish that's what's cool about
this method
it's a lot harder to make it work
i think we've hit pretty close to the
end here
is that silverfish yep
so jam
or maybe it might have been too long
there i can't tell anyway
i'm gonna say goodbye for today thanks
for watching everybody
and i'll see you again next time