[Music]
hey welcome back to everybody this is
etho are you guys doing today I am doing
fantastic yeah
I'm still off on my adventure here
checking out the amplified terrain
looking around trying to find the last
few things I need on my list and long
and behold I almost did not see this I I
was like I ender pearled right into it
but yeah Mesa biome unreal so lucky I I
was really shocked I found one I didn't
think I would and it's really close to
my spawn actually it's only about 3,000
blocks out maybe a little bit further so
I'm gonna set up a portal here and I'm
going to take it all down all this clay
is gonna be gone even though it looks
nice it's going to be destroyed oh yeah
so unfortunately though even though I'm
really happy I found a Mesa biome it is
a really small one or at least its it
might be deceptively small it looks it
looks like it's pretty small though um
but I think I think there's a lot of
clay here actually it just doesn't look
like much because it's like very
vertical there's gonna be clay in here
all the way down to y 64 so yeah there's
there's probably a lot here and I just
don't realize it but I'm gonna keep
looking around maybe I'll find another
Mesa because we're still in the dry area
and I'm about getting ready to head back
and do some build in here but I also
want to find the dark oak saplings so I
need to find a roof what's it called the
roofed forest out whatever it's the one
with the mushrooms in it you know what
I'm talking about but yeah this is
really cool I'm glad I found this very
cool and it's right next to yeah maybe
we'll check this out
it's next to a desert so that means I'll
probably be getting my sand from here
from now on too because I'm guessing
it's a lot easier to collect sand from
this kind of stuff than my other areas
although okay so there's tons of
sandstone it's thinking I might be able
to do the torch trick but maybe not so
it looks like it's mostly all sandstone
hmm
let's go over here I was hoping I could
just put a torch down and like 30 blocks
of sand would just fall on it but I
don't think that's actually gonna happen
I'm running out of ender pearls too so I
gotta head back soon where did we go
okay so yeah it looks like it's not much
different than a normal desert actually
because if I put a torch here like
that's not that's not anything yeah darn
it be really cool if you could get like
40 or 50 blocks the sand falling on it
every time but a good place to get
sandstone anyway so I'm gonna keep doing
a little bit more exploring and I will
turn you guys in on any other important
discoveries I make such as this one
woohoo there is a lot more to this this
Mesa biome than I thought I I climbed
this hill cuz like down there this is
all I could see was this hill the top of
it I didn't think there was more to it I
thought we went back to the desert over
here or something but no no it it keeps
going here so this is awesome okay so it
must have got yeah I kind of I guess it
kind of gets narrow oh maybe not I think
it was all that grass down there that's
threw me off it looked like the biome
ended but it just keeps going and going
and it looks really weird I don't know
if I've seen this this must be a oh it's
nighttime a variant of the Mesa biome
because there's like grass and stuff
here it's nighttime I tell ya night
night good night
bedtime bedtime time to go to bed
morning alright so that was a reference
to force versus zombies by the way let's
go check this out is this part of the
Mesa or is this something different
Mesa plat to plateau F okay so there's
actually grass here trees very very
Brown trees as you would expect ah yes I
am very happy okay so I got enough clay
to last last four days forever basically
come on tree I really hate that when you
ender prone you get stuck in a block
like that oh okay oh yes oh yes keep
keep going never stop chances are I'm
not gonna find another maid Mesa biome
honestly I don't do like after this
exploring here I'm not really planning
on doing that ton more I didn't find the
2x2 taiga forest whatever its called yet
with the podzol and I need the roof
forest and once I get those two things
I'm probably close to done although
there's also the packed ice I could get
from a snow biome but I wouldn't mind
finding that too and then then why don't
we get all those things we're like done
exploring for a long time probably
because we got plenty of building
potential a lot of building sites we
found that would work out great so we
don't really need to look for more and
that is a huge Mesa oh that's cool
that's like it's like a cannon almost I
bet that's this is probably different
from okay so this is just regular Mesa
oh maybe not something usually like
between biomes there's a river that will
split them
or like it it'll go down then it'll go
back up like that but it might just be a
river running through man I think I saw
some of the red sand down there too like
where we started there so I think I got
that Wow
holy smokes it's huge absolutely huge oh
and it keeps going very cool
just keeps going and going that's over a
thousand blocks long I bet oh what's
going on here seems like there's a lot
more grass still plant Mesa plateau
plateau F I always say plat 2 keeps
going woohoo
so if I want to build in a Mesa biome it
looks like I'll have opportunity to do
that too there's plenty of space here
cool cool anyway we've seen it let's go
let's go do something else here alright
so I walked to the very end of the Mesa
biome and it is gigantic it is I'm at
ex- 438 I think we started at an ex-
2,000 or so so it's over 1,500 blocks
long and then I started seeing this and
I'm like what that doesn't make sense
III didn't think Mesa biomes could spawn
next to like the pine forest stuff taiga
and then I look over and what is going
on and yeah so I guess this is where
this is land I explored previous to this
update I hit a wall here otherwise it
would have kept going for sure and I
might go down there and just check if it
continues on the other side or something
if I just cut a line through there
somewhere but out this way is ocean by
the looks of it I'm sure it goes like to
the right and
I didn't check that is one like that
these two directions east and west over
here we have one of the new jungle
biomes that's from that's amplified
terrain
so let's this let's just head over to
the other side I'm curious to see I'm
guessing it I explored a lot before
otherwise the Mesa would probably
continue on the other side here got
wolves nighttime and these walls even if
I wasn't an amplified terrain I would
still get those so that's not the cause
of them it's just because there's 1.7
generation in an old world here yeah
must have explored all this before okay
so I I ran across the line there I
wanted to see if Mesa would show up on
the other side here and nope we got
jungle huge huge jungle walls but this
is quite a ways out so we're at like x0
the generation the old generation went
for quite a ways actually so too bad
jungle biomes look pretty crazy we might
hop up there and just check it out I
think I see yeah so melons and that can
spawn outside of the biome kind of like
I saw this the pine trees in the Mesa
there where they didn't belong so this
is what amplified jungle holy smokes
that terrain looks like I'm getting a
lot of lag in here for some reason see
there's a leaf blocks doing it like all
the leaf blocks or I also saw there's a
huge lava and fire starting so that
might be what's letting me to you uh-huh
pretty cool though I like it probably
won't build here if I'm getting this leg
though okay I got to show you guys this
area this is really neat I haven't seen
this kind of generation before it's a
Mesa biome
I the thing that caught my eye it was
the red Santa is gonna come down here
and harvest some but it's like in the
ocean too it's really cool there's all
these little Mesa islands around there's
like floating islands like lots of them
and you got a great view of all the
layers I don't think I want to risk this
area I I'm hooking up the portals to the
Mesa area and by the way that's why I
came back here yeah this is a very cool
area because usually Mesa biomes it's
just like it's all dry there's no water
around so the fact this one's in the
ocean kind of really neat oh that view
that view such delightful scenery arch
number one arch number two arch number
oh no it's not complete that's almost
arch number three over there hey just
about look at the Mesa plateau plateau F
yeah check this out it goes on for quite
a ways and it looks really cool I like
it I think I like it more than the Mesa
I advised to build because it actually
has hey guy it's got the the dirt and
the trees and there's also clay in the
side of the hills I think it looks
pretty good actually I like it so many
of these guys all over the place there's
really just the incredible amount of
cool things to see I love exploring it's
so much fun so this stuff here this is
right next to that Mesa plateau F that
stuff this is just Mesa plateau and it
looks like it generates the same way
that stuff does except instead of soil
it and grass and stuff it puts just
orange clay on the top of everything you
see how everything has the orange clay
on top and then there's no trees either
obviously then we got more of the F
stuff over here
there's
also a Bryce cannons type of generation
for Mesa or sub terrain I guess it's
called sub sub biome but I haven't seen
that yet that's like the rarest biome I
think oh this is it I just like I
stopped recording for a second there
this is it this is my Mesa Bryce but
what's different about this that's
really cool so I got all them the Mesa
biomes I'm all out of ender pearls man I
want to explore I I don't really know
what's different about it can you spot
the difference because I'm not sure I
can
all right so I made a quick stop off at
the man TV and got a whole ton of
enderpearls again forget the speed
potions I I found I used it very little
because most the time you have to jump
around and an enderpearl around speed
potions not too useful for the amplified
and this is only four hundred bucks out
like in the nether it's really really
close to my my home which is great
Beatrice fill up on ender pearls if
you're exploring and amplified as you
won't really need to be potions all that
much so this is by that Bryce
Mesa biome I looked and I guess there's
two more mesas there's the mountain
varieties so there's Mesa plateau M or
mountain and there's Mesa plateau FM or
forested Mountain come on guy let's see
there was a really cool area where was
it I think it must be through here
creeper no it's like all these arches oh
no no all these arches and it's just a
really cool area I think this is it yeah
so up this way with some more of that
Bryce stuff I think yeah this is it
Bryce I think what Bryce does is it has
a lot of this kind of stuff for me and
it's maybe and like that but I don't
think I have enough of the biome to
really see what it does exactly this is
really weird it like cuts off there I
think it's floating but I haven't
figured out exactly what's different in
the Bryce um yeah I love all these walls
and little caves out this way let's just
look at this - I like this area a lot
because it gets really flat
you got the walls and the caves all
around us and then over here it's some
more of that forested area and it's
really really flat around here actually
that's pretty cool pretty cool
nice nice area alright but anyway we've
seen enough of Mesa I think unless I see
another really cool thing next clip is
probably gonna be from when I find a
roofed forest if I if I do find one oh I
just found a very nice Plains biome here
up above cloud level looks like it goes
a little bit higher yet that's what I
had off this whole time it's the clouds
I turned them on just now and if you're
if you're in an amplified biome you
definitely want clouds uh-huh check out
this lava fall over here and like a cave
there mm-hmm I'm sticking close to the
taiga biome I want to find the mega
taiga yep
that is definitely extreme hills because
we're already at y100 where I'm standing
goes way up cool area I really got a
kick out of this I was just walking
there's this random Water Street I could
not see where it was coming from for a
long time it finally loaded in there's
tiny island floating up there and water
coming down for over a hundred blocks
probably another island up there finally
found some horses and donkeys and stuff
there's quite a few out here there's
some down there I saw there's some more
in the background up over there this is
like the only horses I found in all my
traveling and I believe this is where we
were last episode by the flour forest
area except I think I went right that
way and tried to avoid the taiga last
time so this time I'm gonna go straight
this way but I'm gonna check out these
horses maybe we'll find some good ones
alright check this guy out he's pretty
good he's fast
he's really fast well not SuperDuper
fast but he's I think he's a fastest
horse I've found in this world that's
good he's got 11 hearts nuts not the
best jumper though but definitely one of
the better horses I've found I've been
here for like three or four Minecraft
days now just checking out all the
horses and and the donkeys trying to
tame them all it takes a really long
time to tame these guys if you don't
have the the wheat or whatever to make
them like you out of all the donkeys I
think the best one had 14 health and out
of the horses I think this guy is the
winner
he's got 12 hearts really fast I don't
feel it as fast as that other one
actually he's not that quick now that
I'm riding him am I on the right one yes
is the right guy I think you jump over
four blocks oh so that's pretty cool
maybe it was just I might be better
after all he's got less hearts I think
it's what is that nine nine hearts he's
much quicker actually but he can also
jump four hmm yeah I don't know I
actually I really liked how these horses
look at the light pans brown ones but
I'm not sure it's worth bring him back
maybe I'll ride him for a bit until I
can't go any further I think I found him
this is the best horse like I've checked
50 horses today I'm sure out of all of
them I think this guy's the best he's
got 13 hearts he's fast when the clip
clops
make start like playing over top each
other I don't even hear it that's a sign
that you got a fast horse sometimes it
even be hard to tell in game when you're
riding around and he can jump three just
above four blocks
I really wish he could jump four
oh yeah he's pretty good so I was
exploring and I just saw this huge dark
shadow there and it's like okay looked
up waited for a bit nothing nothing and
then finally a giant giant island all on
its own there very cool there's even a
tree that's just like on a single dirt
block way out let's see if we can see it
from down here yeah look at that that
tree over there
it's like floating it's awesome
but I've done a lot of exploring I think
I've explored everything out this
direction I've hit the ocean on all
three sides it's like a peninsula goes
to about negative 6000 before the ocean
and no roof or snow spiky snow biome or
anything like that I think we'll have to
go a different direction
if we want to find that stuff so I'm
probably gonna head back in I'll just
have to look for that stuff some other
time too
- exploring episodes is enough for sure
we'll try to do some building next time
but I'm on my way back this guy he's
he's really good I like I was worried
with the mountains and everything he was
gonna be a pain to get around but he's
actually making it easier because look
look at this I can just run up this
stuff no problem well it's a little
tougher to explore now that I'm
recording cuz it's lagging anymore but
whew a lot more yeah he can get around
pretty good takes a little bit of fall
damage here and there but whoa whoa oh
boy
that lag but yeah he's he's really good
hmm I was getting around pretty good
with this guy until I started hitting
this kind of stuff with the sheer walls
and I can't see if I can get down here
oh I think I can
think I chan we can do it it's really
tough
oh you stay in so much damage now it's
crazy I wish I could put him in my ender
chest oh man yeah we're good trying to
take any more damage
he heals so slowly down the floor it's
gonna take like an hour to get back up
the full you can heal him if you got the
right food but I don't have any with me
how far are we we still gotta go four
thousand blocks holy smokes
oh and more of the crazy Hills ah darn
it mmm this is a yellow moment okay I do
really like this guy I don't want him to
die but Yolo Oh Oh what was he at 200
that was a bad jump my bad all right
well I've given up I can't get him
through this stuff is his way too hard
and he's healing way too slow so I'm
gonna try the nether and I haven't been
able to check what's on the other side
of this yet so hopefully he survives I
have a feeling I won't be able to return
if I go through so want to push him
through first
alright get a pic ready don't be dying
don't be dying yes okay he's right where
I wanted to be in this tunnel maybe
let's expand this a little bit yeah you
go forward perfect so I think you'll be
fine here I just gonna make this wider
alright let's see if we can get him back
now I brought a secret weapon that
worked on him and here we go
still only one wide in a lot of places
and this fall probably killed I think
those guys were bumping them maybe well
yeah I hope you guys enjoyed that little
adventure I don't go exploring too often
this game that was pretty fun founds
found a lot of cool things saw a lot of
neat things the Mesa biome was the
highlight for me I can't believe I found
one of those and one that amazing is
just awesome and so close to home it's
like gonna planned it better those
things are so hard to find so I did not
find the megataiga with the pond soul I
think that's the one with the podzol I
did not find the spiked snow biome with
the Pat dice and I did not find the roof
force roof Forest should be pretty easy
to find make it through what else I I
wanted to also find what else was there
I was hoping to find a mushroom biome I
still have not found one of those but
yeah anyway we did we did good I was
happy with that I'll probably do a
little exploring on my own just to finds
the roof forced at the very least
because I need I need that new sapling
the dark oak and we got we got ourselves
a new friend here this guy's really good
as much as I like Zenith Zenith is like
my my trophy horse I want a horse that
can actually ride though this guy's
gonna be good what oh I was over in
comparison to Zenith maybe let's just go
for a little ride with this guy that's
not that bad either though can tell he's
a little slower it's got 14 hearts it's
my my morning tune by the way I think
you can only jump two blocks yeah so not
bad not bad at all excellent so we've
made it back home to our lovely man cave
love this place
I don't want to not ready to leave it
even if we build somewhere else we'll
still come back here and work on it I'm
sure so I got a comment picked out for
today says what happened to speed
challenges I really like them I like
them too
I haven't had a good idea for one lately
so if you guys have ideas for speed
challenges don't be afraid to recommend
one the idea is I should be able to do
them within 30 minutes and also don't
want them to be too easy but not too
tough and a little bit of luck is fine
in them but not too much type of thing
it's hard to find a balance and a good
theme for them but if you guys have a
good idea let me know and I will do it
for sure
this thing here I have worked on this
too by the way this is my old old
enchanting room I set up a long time ago
and it's always a kind of incomplete to
me so I decided I add in like a little
arch type thing to complete the look of
it and I've added in a bunch of droppers
with all the tools in so if I ever want
to enchant something steady hit a button
and I'll get that item so simple little
addition but I think it finishes that
off pretty pretty well but yeah thanks
for watching everyone
and until next time I will see you later
have a good day
bye bye
[Music]