[Music]
hey what's up everybody
this is etho and yes we are finally back
once again with another let's play
episode uh so sorry about that guys i
took a few days off here
and actually i have not even tried out
the new snapshot that added the parrots
and
the other fun stuff the new crafting
system so i just uh
i just installed it i i just uh like
looked at the patch notes and was
reading up on it
and yeah so i'm kind of excited to try
it out here
um so that is what we're gonna do to
begin with and then we'll get to
some other some other projects probably
today so here's the new crafting thing
huh we got a book over here
how does this work exactly let's say i
want to make a furnace
mine stone
advancements not achievement
advancements
okay look at this
this is my first time seeing it this is
actually
pretty cool um
okay so if i want to make a furnace it's
it's not in red
oh that's pretty sweet showing all
you can shift click wait a minute why oh
it used up all the cobble i had aha
yes yes very cool stuff so i was uh
i was reading the reddit on this and
some i saw some people were actually
kind of upset with the new crafting
system like it took
took away the whimsical nature of not
knowing the crafting recipes from the
game
and i thought that was uh kind of
funny because i always hated that about
minecraft how
how you can't see the recipes like if
you're new to this game
to me it seems like a really big design
flaw not having the recipes in the game
because if you don't have an internet
connection
uh you pretty much can't play the game
if you don't know the recipes right so i
think this is a great improvement
personally okay and also
we got parrots guys parrots in the
jungle
i think i tried uh a test world out here
and in an old jungle i was not able to
find uh parrots this is like the closest
jungle to our
base and i thought we would just check
here
if we can find any not seeing any right
now so i think i'm gonna have to go
make a new or go explore new terrain to
find the parrots aren't i
then bring them back okay i did not
realize
they totally replaced achievement so
it's advancements now only
but these can be edited with json files
like for custom map makers
and then do whatever they want here now
so that's kind of cool
let's see if it opens up a new tab when
we go in the the nether like we have two
tabs right now
advancement made enter the nether i
think there's one for the
ends i was just reading reading about
this
let's see let's check it now no i didn't
make a new tab
it just unlocked it here somewhere
entered the nether yeah we just got this
one
okay i got a couple more thoughts about
the crafting system here so i've been
messing around with it
pretty familiar with it now i guess if
you're a new player you're going to want
this
unchecked right and this will show you
uh recipes you can't craft like you
don't have the ingredients for but it's
a good way of discovering
items in the game that you don't know
about right but for
us experienced players that have played
for years
probably leave this checked all the time
because you don't need that information
and it cleans up the menu there is a
search bar so if you want to
narrow down your search you can that's
going to be really nice in modded
minecraft later when you have hundreds
of items
it'll make it real real simple to make
something
and what i would like to see changed
like right now if you left click here
it'll it'll fill in the recipe that's
nice
but every time you left click here
nothing happens i would like it to
increment so you left click goes from 4
8 12
16 and if you right click it'll subtract
from the crafting here i think that
would be really nice maybe
if they added an option for your scroll
wheel on the mouse to add and subtract
would be cool too
we do have the shift click though for
doing the full stack
which is good um and i would like them
to add an option to use the control key
to do something here so
right now if you want to craft something
you have to click here and then move
your mouse
all the way over here click again to
pick it up
what would simplify this a lot is if you
could hold ctrl
left click and then that'll just put it
in your mouse like this right
every time you control and left click
it'll it'll add on to it
and go 8 12 16
or if you hold ctrl and shift it'll do
the full stack
and just put in your mouse reduce the
number of clicking and moving the mouse
around a lot
and make it a lot quicker aha that's my
two cents on it
that was not a torch there we go okay so
what we gotta do
uh we're we gotta get to minus 725
in the nether here and minus 125
which is going to be this way i use the
admits program to figure out where
a new jungle is going to be in our world
here um
instead of just free roam exploring
because my world's over i did in size
now
i don't want it to get any bigger if
possible so
we're just gonna home right in whoa
right right in on the jungle here and
hopefully it'll be there
um i guess i'll just put it over here
actually
minus five seven eight two minus one
thousand
thirty three yes it worked
whoa gravel falling on our head all
right
okay so things are still pretty laggy
here i let the game load uh the world
for a while
uh but things are on fire and stuff so
it's not gonna be super smooth
but we might be able to check out a few
things like look at this area this is
pretty
sweet got cliffs all around us and
these two sides are kind of connected
together
nice flat spot in the middle here
i love jungle biomes like so much
the best grass color and usually the
mountain formations are pretty cool in
them too
and the trees look nice and yeah i kind
of lost the portal already though it's a
good thing uh
got it in the video or i would be lost
here forever
oh there's a planes over here too
still looking for that donkey guys i
still have not found a donkey it's like
they don't generate anymore
um not seeing parrots though
which is a little concerning i thought
they would be like all over the place
i don't know though like they spawn on
the ground right so they're probably
hard to see oh is that one actually yeah
it is
okay right by the cat
does the cat kill it uh
[Music]
looks like the looks like the parrots
after the chat actually
all right guys so i've been going around
the jungle here looking for the parrots
and i got
really lucky i think i got one of each
color like
exactly one of each uh they're pretty
hard to find actually i
just found this guy here though so to
tame them
you feed them cookies and sometimes it
works
sometimes it doesn't this guy's a little
bit more stubborn there we go
so now he's he's tamed and he'll
teleport to us kind of like wolves and
and the ocelots do you can tell them to
sit down and
they make all kind of cool noises and
they're really neat
and they actually make good pets because
you don't have to worry about them dying
so much like
if you tame a wolf they're always
falling off cliffs and stuff
these guys they're pretty good
and if you get far away from them like
that you see this teleport right to you
so it's pretty nice you can attach leads
to them though it seems
so if we if we connect them like this
they'll kind of follow us around
and i did
also manage to use the fireworks with
them too
but just once so you can
do something like this and they'll go
with you
kind of like balloons so that's a that's
a good way of doing it if you don't want
to tame them for some reason you can
still move them around this way
but if you tame them they'll just
teleport to you okay let's see if we can
get a parrot on our shoulder in midair
here
let's go land oh yeah we got him we got
him okay
that's pretty cool so yeah the parrots
do ride on your shoulders too which is
another neat feature um
as soon as you jump they fall off
they seem to like like they fly towards
you to actually go on though which is
cool
oh there's a witch down there i want to
hear what the witch sounds like through
these guys
a zombie here so if there's any uh
hostile mobs nearby they mimic the sound
which is pretty cool it's like a warning
system
they'll they'll let you know there's a
guy nearby before they get to you
probably
so they're only making zombie noises
right now
if we go by the switch though they'll
probably start making which sounds
i don't want to get too close though
oh they're making creeper sounds oh
there's a creeper right there
oh did they get oh don't get my birds
okay let's get out of here before we
lose them all
i like that what that laugh though the
witch laughs
i also found a jungle temple here
uh in this chest there was i think six
gold
and i have not checked out back here
though
two gold in a saddle all right
how does this work again like i never i
never find jungle temples
that makes that go out
does that do anything oh you gotta do
this and then that's
okay that retracts the block why do you
want to retract the block
what so this piston moved the block from
here
to here what's what's the point of that
then you can fall down here i guess
interesting okay oh i guess that's how
you
actually you're supposed to find it
right instead of digging through the
wall
gotcha okay let's get out of here okay
we got the green guy on our shoulder
here let's see if we can get him through
and hopefully this goes okay because
it's gonna be really hard to get any
more parrots
one two three four five
we got the green guy over here
okay a little bit of a tough part here
again uh we lost the duplicate gray guy
i think
or white guy might have burnt up i'm not
sure
it's actually pretty pretty hard to move
them through the nether
oh no no no because like they can land
in lava pools and stuff
oh i just about died um
did they all teleport back
no we only have the blue guy here one
guy's on my shoulder
uh oh uh oh come on where are the other
three
no no where did they go
oh no
i didn't fly over any lava did i
i was so careful the whole way and i
just messed up at the end here
maybe if i move a little bit more
they'll teleport they might be dead
already
i'm not sure what happened to them
yeah i only see the two now ah
we have to we have to get in here
possibly they went through that portal
when i when i went near here
yeah that's what it was guys they
actually went through the portal
so i gotta get you out of this minecart
somehow without killing you oh
uh oh are you on my shoulder you're on
my shoulder they do that all the time
like
i think they disappear but they just go
on your shoulder and you can't see them
then
good good
perfect all right we got them in
position
let's try this out
[Music]
[Laughter]
oh that's great
[Music]
worth it took me about an hour to get
them here but it was worth it guys
that's great
and they stop right away when you shut
it off
awesome cool so i think that about does
it
for the new stuff added in the snapshot
guys so we're gonna get to some other
stuff here we're gonna do some building
today
a little bit short on some building
blocks though so let's head over to our
mesa
clay station we haven't been here
together in a long time but i do use
this area
a lot i go here all the time
and it looks like it's empty again
yellow
we need some gray and we need some of
this uh
light gray stuff so there's lots of that
here this is brown though right not gray
so i'll probably have to craft the gray
um
i think that's about it here okay
kill the mob oh yeah
great clay that's what we want right i
think that's the one
awesome all right i think i got all the
stuff i wanted to collect it together
here for our building
uh what we're going to do guys is
hopefully make a building for
our super smeltery because right now if
i want to use this thing it's a real
pain
got to like jump around on the chest
here and then like jump across here and
yeah we need a floor and stuff for this
building uh this is gonna be a bit of a
challenge though because of
like all the functional stuff is gonna
be in the floor there's nothing in the
walls
and usually i use the stuff in the walls
like the functional parts to help
decide how to build my stuff you know
i'm not good at building just like
freestyle
but uh yeah these are the blocks i
picked out so i think we're gonna go
for this for the flooring primarily
uh nether brick for the borders these
are kind of some odd colors
uh compared to what i usually use i like
to use like wood and stone
nature themed stuff so this building
might stand out a little bit i'm not
sure
and also we're gonna need some kind of
glass color to go with the nether brick
so i couldn't decide either purple
magenta
or pink i really don't like pink though
but it might be the best suited we got
the most purple honest though so that's
probably what
we'll go for and finally for the walls
uh just in general we're gonna use this
gray clay stuff
so i think those colors all kind of work
together that's that's the plan here
let's get to it
um so when i asked you guys what we
should do for this building the number
one
thing that was suggested is we we make
it so we can still see the rail stuff
down there don't cover it up totally
so let's start with that
first i'm going to just put a rip
rim a trim something
around the chest here to get us going uh
this is the very
center right so this is a good starting
point
and then my plan is to maybe put glass
over here and
let's just see what this looks like
here let's let's do this actually give
it a bit more variation
so if we're standing here out of our
peripheral peripheral
vision can't really see that but i guess
if you look this way you'll
see it you can't see the rail stuff when
you're looking forward here
oh well i i think it's fine still let's
go maybe
five blocks across here and then i want
to put in a window this will help me to
figure out how the building's going to
go because if i got nothing
in the walls i don't know what to do
usually so
we'll go up like four blocks or so
and we're out of glass already oh man
okay let's let's carry this on here
build up the trim and then probably
have this go forward a block and come up
like this
all right one two three four one two
three four
and then i do have some stairs on me
we'll try to curve it
because i like my arches you guys know
that
and then it's gonna be oh it's an even
number here right
so let's just connect it like that
yes something like that will work out i
hope
um let's fill in the floor a little bit
here with this clay
let's see what that looks like maybe
just run it solid here so we have a big
piece of it and not just the
like if we put another nether brick
border around this chest i think it's
going to look
uh too much nether brick you know oh if
we do this though we can't open this
chest ah man trouble
actually let's just test this out
because i think they fixed this right or
they changed it
so if you have chest over here
hopper over there and stuff in here
going into there
if you cover this up does that stop the
flow
with a solid block here
oh it still does darn ah
okay and then it starts again
okay so we have to put something above
that
oh wait does it still flow into here
this is still going down yeah it still
flows into there it doesn't flow out but
it flows in
that's weird and now it's stopped again
huh okay so what is what's it doing over
here it's flowing
in and then flowing out so
yeah we still need to put slabs above
actually i was just trying this out some
more and it might only be a problem if
you're using a double chest because this
single chest is covered up
but the items are still flowing out of
it they're flowing in and out of it
so if we turn this into a double chest
it might just
stop no it didn't stop
recover that now i think it's stopped
yeah now it's stopped
now it started again okay interesting
yeah so i just uh put some upside down
nether brick stairs here
so this should all work fine still and
hopefully it's not too much nether brick
um now i think what we'll do is work on
this middle part this is going to be
tricky because we got all this redstone
stuff here i don't know
how well we'll be able to cover this up
without breaking it you know
i think we'll put some stairs here this
will keep this in the middle yeah that's
good
and probably gonna have to throw a slab
in over here
and let's let's bring some more of this
uh this pink stuff
light gray forward here does this cover
up any redstone i think we're still good
over here we'll be fine too good um
yeah i kind of want to get rid of this
over here though
hmm well let's just do the best we can
for right now
so what i wanted to do was use fire
as sort of a decorative thing here i
think we can get rid of these two pieces
put puts another rack there
do it like that and i want another piece
over here
i'll probably just have to like redo
this this elevator a little bit
because all this stuff's in the way
yeah let's try it like that i think
that's the shape i wanted
so we'll light this and just get an idea
of how that feels
kind of that incrementing fire look
i like it i like it a lot we'll put a
stair
above here
i wonder if we can get rid of that too
this uh this thing's not going to work
afterwards is it
even after like we we try to fix it it
might not be possible to do what we're
doing here
i'll have to mess around with it off
camera probably
okay can we put this here
probably not probably not let's just get
it the way i want it to look though and
then
i'll i'll try compromise later with it
okay that has to go
okay so i just did a couple more things
here got fire there and there now
i think that looks cool and we added in
a trim that goes around the fire
which is a little bit wonky i think
because there's corners
there and there but if we didn't have
those it would be a perfect triangle and
that might look a little weird too
i don't know maybe i should have rounded
this a bit more
but it's fine we'll live with it put
some brick in over here just for
variation
and i want to put some torches at the
front here like some fire torches
maybe like right in the center
here we'll keep them fairly short too so
we'll light the fire here
and then let's try put some stairs
around that
like so and i think that'll be good
so i think it's far enough out of the
way here it's not going to block our
vision
yep i like these a lot actually these
torches here so we're going to leave
those in
and then the last part of this guys is
we just got to fill in the walls here
all these empty spaces
with this gray clay and hopefully that
looks okay
i'm gonna try curve it in kind of like
an igloo too i think
uh the outside of this building is going
to be another challenge though and i
think we'll save that for another day
because i don't know what to do with it
at the moment but we'll curve this in
like an igloo
and then probably put in a glass roof
too so
i have trouble building roofs and that
would be a nice easy thing i'll let
light into the room too
so let's let's see how this looks after
i finish shaping it here
it's always good to take a moment like
when you're building does this side
match the side
uh i think they're okay i think we can
continue here
[Music]
i don't know what do you guys think of
it it's not super epic or anything but
uh it's a little bit of a different
style than anything i've done before so
it was
it was a good uh fun fun build for me
anyways
uh let's go ahead and sleep here real
quick so we got the skylight in the
roof by the way so it's gonna let light
in you don't have to put torches on the
ground or anything like that
the fire probably does light it up
fairly decently at night actually
but there will be some dark spots i know
um so we got our window here to look
outside
this is gonna get filled in with grass
this hole here and then we'll be able to
look down at the minecart stuff over
here so it's like a
a window down below and a window outside
two windows in one
we should change out some of that stone
brick there or the stone with the
clay or something that looks a bit nicer
and
all in all i think this will be good as
long as we can get this elevator working
with these uh
changes i've made but i'll try that out
another day
and put a chest up here mixed in some
nether brick slabs like
underneath the clay here just because it
looked pretty bad without them
i think this this makes it a lot nicer
aha anyways let me know what you guys
think about it i think we're gonna call
it here for today though so let's do the
comment of the day
[Music]
all right here we go guys says when is
the next world download coming
i really want to replicate the super
smelter
so i'm trying to do world tours and
world downloads every 50 episodes now so
the next one's going to be
probably episode 500. i think we did it
on 450 last
it's gonna be 500 for the next one
these guys are like really going nuts i
don't think this guy's dancing as much
right is this like swaying back and
forth
these ones are like really
they're really going for it if you start
the song
how did i do that i think if you start
yeah when they're not near it and then
you bring them towards it then
or no if they're they're not sitting and
then you start the song and then make
them sit down
that's how you do it anyways guys
hopefully you enjoyed today's episode
thank you for watching
as always and until next time
take care bye
[Music]