[Music]
comes aground
whoa let's try to see how close I could
cut it welcome back guys to another
episode of our let's play series how're
you doing today I'm doing great guys
I've been out of here for probably three
four hours already actually I've been
raiding the end cities like I said I was
going to but a couple of you crazies out
there you wanted to see me do the whole
thing okay
I'm not going to show you everything
because like I said three four hours you
don't have that much time in the video
but I'll give you a little taste of the
experience what I've been doing here so
let's head on over to the end and
shouldn't we walk together you know I
don't walk together with you guys very
often let's do it
oh and my walk I mean fly right into the
well alright guys so yeah I've come
across a couple tricks while doing this
one of the big problems I was having
with the end cities is I would go you
know exploring generating new terrain
and then this is not the right tunnel ah
I'm very good at locations but then you
know I I find another end city ten
minutes later and surprise surprise it's
the one I raided already and that kept
happening to me cuz I was just kind of
chaotically exploring the end finding
new cities and then it's like wait a
minute where have I gone where haven't I
gone I'm not sure anymore
it all kind of blends together after a
while and especially if you guys are
playing on servers this is going to be a
problem for you
like how do you know what in cities have
been rated which ones haven't been so I
had one of those moments so oh yeah
kind of moments it's like they made it
so Maps worked in the end I forgot about
that and then I remember is like this is
the greatest thing ever so check it out
this is I totally zoomed out map so it's
2048 by 2048 area and you can see pretty
clearly on the map there's the purple
clusters there those are the N cities so
I've been using a map while exploring
here and this is great because it shows
me where I've been so I can totally get
perfect coverage of the area and not
miss any cities but also I know I've
I've explored these three now so I don't
have to go back to this location so that
is the way to do it I think here I made
another one as well oh you can dual
wield maps next level craziness year so
I've been to about 7n cities already I
got to make a new map for a new quadrant
now so also I brought some item frames
let's see how they look in these if we
put these in here I'm done with these
ones I've explored all the cities bam
and bam pretty cool so that's our main
island over there and then the void area
over there then all the new island stuff
over here so what I figured out like I
don't use maps too often so I wasn't
really sure how they work to be honest
the first one I made at 0 0 and then the
other one I think I was negative x and z
let's try make one over here see you if
I do this correctly see if I understand
it now so it will right-click look at
our map here it's our of our island
let's see what happens now when we zoom
out so to zoom out you need a crafting
table and a bunch of paper let's get our
paper here
all right put your map inside takes 8
paper to zoom out one level I didn't
think you can do it four times boom boom
boom
maps are a little bit glitchy right now
uh have I gone all the way it says
unknown map now Oh mm try it out oh it's
working I think four four yeah that's
totally zoomed out one problem maybe I
don't understand this because this looks
the same as the one we got already
because the islands at the top left like
the one on the right here okay so I
still don't understand maps it seems but
I think I know where I went wrong I
mixed up my directions so the top of the
map this way is north which is the
direction we're facing now so I think we
need that way and that way on the map
let's try that out
so let's go to see I thought I made one
negative negative X and Zed but I guess
maybe not let's try make one over here
then oh and see if it fills in the
missing quadrant here alright the thing
I found out though is the maps
auto-align their borders which i did not
know before i thought you had to be very
careful where you created the map but as
long as you're within the area it seems
to auto-align everything which is nice
so let's see now no it still got it
wrong maybe I could go farther this way
I don't really understand maps are hard
sometimes
let's try go farther this way we want
the island to either be at the bottom
right or bottom left did we do it right
bottom left that's good right that's
what I said bottom left maybe I was just
too close to 0-0 maybe goes a little
ways away
alright guys so after I get my map here
what I do is I fly around the border of
the map kind of spiral my way inside to
uncover all the terrain here oh we just
passed over a fortress apparently and
when I do this I go pretty high up in
the sky
I went up to like a thousand and then
that way you can have a pretty good
downward angle as you go here get some
nice momentum otherwise if you fly near
the ground you should go too fast I find
ah whoops wasn't watching my health one
of you there you are there you are
found ya aha I will take that from you
and we do this and we will try to get
back I looked in that Enderman I looked
at an Enderman I don't have a good armor
I looked at more No all right so we are
supposed to get to minus 324 and like
1200 or something hopefully it's not
gonna be over the void like on the right
way yes I am okay good we want it to be
over a big island like we're at right
now oh I just saw some items fall I
think okay okay there's hope guys
there's hope uh scared of some of these
oh no I'm still on the same island can I
take you sick items raining from the sky
I was at 600 like up in the air so this
is pretty far woo hoo okay man how far
did this stuff scatter is the question
like it's gonna be all over the place
it's my water bucket very nice
some books oh here's a big cluster of
stuff okay
Oh some of it is pretty close to the
edge hill okay it looks like we
recovered a map my axe
oh snap I kind of regret bringing all
these arrows now I wasn't sure how many
I would need though okay
got my pick two picks sweet steak yeah I
bet you some stuff did fall over the
edge here right no way I'm gonna get
everything back shovel nice
oh my helmet shulker box recovered boots
I got my boots I got my bow ah dude I
found it I found it my wings and my
sword er up here oh I'm so glad I
thought of that is like oh well then
it's like wait a minute they bet I
landed on the course fruits oh man I
feel like I've cheated death here this
is great I don't know why but I've
really been second lately haven't I I
like I just died two episodes ago to
that wither and lost all my stuff if
that happened again today oh that would
have sucked but we're good we're all
good I think I got everything important
back I didn't notice anything missing so
let's uh let's talk about these
fortresses for a little bit uh first
thing like I've raided a few of them now
the boat doesn't generate at all of them
I think it's about 50% of them from what
I've seen so far anyway the boat is
where you get the lighter wings of
course the big thing though is the
shelter guys right like the main reason
I'm doing this is to get the shelter
shells these guys this is really
important they don't spawn in they
generate in so with the the fortress
they generate in which means couple
things number one you you can figure out
where they are pretty easily after you
do this a few times like there's always
one guy guarding the polite row wings
here they always generate in the same
spots and you can figure out their
patterns cursive vanishing you get some
really good loot in these chests so I
gotta say like look at that unbreaking 3
and many that's great that's wonderful
sure makes this fun
it's it's a really viable way of like
getting started like if you're in a new
world and you want some good gear I
would really recommend just like rating
these fortresses instead of like trying
to enchant it it's it's great doing this
and you gets cool stuff like dragon
heads and all kinds of stuff but yes
because the shocker dudes don't spawn in
I don't think there's any way of making
the farms like if I kill them all here
they're not coming back they're gone
so this boat typically has three of them
or always has three of them I think
there's one guy here always one guy
inside the room and then I think there's
one on the side here yeah right over
there at the top of these towers there's
always one which is pretty easy to miss
because there's nothing up there you
usually go for so like up in there
there's going to be one there's going to
be one over here let's go check that out
I highly recommend you bring ender
pearls as you do this so yeah you see we
got one guy up here there's always two
guarding the entrance and the reason I'm
telling you this is because you're going
to like want to raid these as quickly as
possible get all the shelters as fast as
possible and it helps to know where they
are so you don't miss any of them and so
you can get to the quicker okay so check
this out this is the best room in like
the whole in city here it's just loaded
with the shockers you get lost the
shells Oh sometimes they do teleport
it's annoying so what I like to do is
let them attack me with their levitation
thingy then I kind of flip my way up and
attack them on the way here all right
what kind of loot we get we got some
gold ingots fire protection for
unbreaking 3dep strider 3 that's nice
efficiency 5 and mending oh snap Chris
vanishing 3 and 3 aha
all right so what do we got here one two
three four five so really none over
there yeah six seven eight nine ten I
can count to ten no we have ten ten
cities in these four map areas so that's
4096 4096 and if you - avoid area here
I'm guessing you get probably three or
four every 2000 by 2000 area and here we
go guys this is the big moment
let's check out the loot all the loot I
got from the rating here all the N
cities so in total I think I rated 9n
city's brand new ones I didn't go back
to any of the ones we found previously
when they first came out so this is all
brand new loot and I also spent about
five hours doing it so nine cities five
hours probably wasted 30 minutes from
dying in there as well so yeah I'm
guessing about 30 minutes to locate and
raid each of the cities on average which
is a fair bit of time when you when you
think about it and here we go check out
this box so this is how many shelter
shells I got in total plus made six of
these boxes so that's twelve more that
averages out to about thirty not thirty
thirteen bring brainfart there thirteen
to fourteen shelter shells per and city
um yeah so you're gonna get out seven of
these boxes every thirty minutes or you
know let's let's just call it one of
these every five minutes so you can get
thousands of these it's gonna take you a
long time though so they're pretty
expensive
unfortunately so today's episode also is
kind of a momentous event in our series
here it marks a special day because from
here on out I am going to be carrying an
ender chest with me at all times and I'm
pretty excited about this so I got it
cleared out as a lot of you guys know
because you can put shelter boxes in
ender chests it is like crazy Opie and
amazing so basically you can fill it up
and the great thing is you can dye these
colors as well so I'm going to have a
red stone chest in my ender chest it's
going to be red you can diet
and also name it I believe now let's try
that out
redstone red stop I spell good oh come
on come on oh come on what there we go
I had to look at my keyboard there we go
I pride myself at being able to type
without looking at my keyboard but there
I failed so yeah I can carry just that
crazy amount of inventory with me at all
times now which is great
on one hand though it does kind of over
overshadow some of the cool storage
gizmos you can build with chakra boxes
cuz you're not gonna be able to top this
it's just too good like and if I die
that doesn't matter because it's an
ender chest all my stuff is still gonna
be there so that's pretty crazy so yeah
what I plan on doing is kind of going
through my storage room here like I have
things categorized right now so I'll
probably have a plant box it has like
one stack of everything in a bit of all
the food at least the kinds you need for
breeding I'll have in there it carries
some stone with me cobblestone at all
times bit of wood dirt you know gotta go
through everything here make sure I have
one of each each of the clay colors and
now whenever I do building is going to
be crazy easy because I usually waste
like five minutes every time I need an
item I'll have to go run get it and then
come back then I'll be like oh I should
have brought this with me as well and
I'll have to go back and do it again now
I have it on me at all times but anyways
guys I think that's going to do it for
the exploring for now let's do some
actual building and designing now that
we got our stronger boxes we can have
some fun here so not only did I do the
fortress rating today I spent about an
hour in creative building and designing
and like trying to perfect a box loading
system which if you don't know box
loaders and unloaders are going to be a
big thing with this update so we'll go
over the concept of that here and I'll
show you my design that's going to get
annoying
okay it stopped so no it did it let's
take my zombie pigman farm for example I
got tons the zombie flesh here tons of
gold and stuff that always smell I
emptied this frequently but you know
stuff builds up in these chests
previously if you want to have a bunch
of storage with your farms you have to
like do this continuous thing where you
have hoppers and chests hopper chest
hopper chest and keep expanding on that
now with the shelter boxes you can
pretty much have almost infinite storage
and like no area at all which is cool I
think we're gonna have to tear these
down oh I dropped it darn it alright so
you can see over here this is kind of
annoying I have to like pick up the
zombie flesh out of the chest here put
into shocker box and then I can
transport it easily the idea of a box
loader and unloader is an automatic way
of filling these up and then like
collecting them together and then the
unloader takes items out of here and
puts them into your system so if we take
my Nexus for example I could set up a
box and loader there and then drop off
20 chakra boxes full of stuff it'll take
all the items out of it automatically
sort it in my Nexus and that would be
pretty cool so yeah let's let's try
build a box loader here so I got rid of
the old storage we had here we got the
item filters ending up over there so we
had the gold nuggets gold ingots and the
zombie flesh let's try to make three of
these together here I got this down to a
three-wide tileable thing that means i
need to place these three blocks apart
from each other and this is kind of a
word I put my stuff I I first like when
I do redstone stuff I usually focus on
what I wanted to look like first before
I even do the redstone so for example
here I really wanted this to look nice
on the outside it's kind of a tricky
thing with these shelter box things to
have a nice looking interface because of
all the stuff you need to
include with it but I'm pretty happy
with how this looks actually so
basically we have one chest the bottom
here on top of these double chests is
going to be a hopper over here and then
on top of those is the chakra boxes so
oh I broke that under chest that was
here yeah basically on top of this
there'll be a shelter box at each of
these and then we go up one more or two
more like so another stair here and I
think I put it where I'm trying to like
do this off of memory it's a pretty
complicated thing but there's not a lot
to it so I think I can pull it off here
oh yeah then a double chest over here
and to hide this double chest what I
decided to do is put like stairs running
across oh maybe I didn't do it like this
I did something how did I do that that's
kind of yeah this is what I did
definitely alright so we have access to
all three of the chests here fairly nice
interface basically you drop off empty
shell core box is up here and then it's
going to place those over here you can
access these and take your items out if
you want even or put them in and then at
the bottom here is going to be the
shelter boxes full of stuff so it's kind
of a nice progress empty filling full
okay maybe it's not the most beautiful
interface but with some decoration I'm
sure it would look nice or maybe if we
built it out of wood but the big thing
here is I want to access to all three of
these Jes and that's what I was able to
pull off here so that's kind of nice
alright so let's start doing the
redstone part of this so we're going to
remove this temporarily all right so to
place the shocker box of course you have
to use a dispenser and that's going to
go on this side here on the right side
if you're facing this way and we want to
fill this up with empty shelter boxes
so from this chest our empty chakra box
chest we will run a hopper here into the
dispenser from there and that's the main
reason for these stairs just to hide
that hopper so it's not it's not ugly
there alright and to break the shocker
box that's a big thing place break
pickup you got to have all three of
those things I'm going to use an
upside-down slab there and a sticky
piston to push that down into it like a
so alright and let's see here what we
got to do actually that should probably
be a quartz block yeah what we got to do
here is the rest of the Redstone I'll
probably do on this is get a signal out
of the Shocker box we need to detect
when it's full of items right so we're
going to use a comparator over here
chakra box will be here will read that
signal and we need to do a subtraction
thing here so we need another comparator
on subtract mode and we want this
powered at 15 so 15 on this one and 15
on this one 15 minus 15 is 0 so that
will make this redstone torch shut off
when this box is totally full is
basically what we're going for here
all right Oh memories starting to fade
how did I do this I don't know um
Oh might need to pause I think I had a
repeater here I'm gonna pause yeah
probably a good thing I did that because
I would have got it wrong otherwise now
what we actually got to do here is to
put a server block right over here
detector side facing up and then we put
another block here and then the repeater
set at 2 and the redstone dust from this
torch here so basically when this box
fills up a stuff it's going to tell this
piston to go down break it but that does
not
date this comparator when the Box
disappears in order to do that we use
this observer block it sends a signal to
it and that tells this comparator to
shut off kind of a weird thing but
that's just redstone for you all right
so now what we want to do is tell this
dispenser to shoot out at another box to
take the place of the one missing
so from this redstone torch we're going
to run a couple repeaters here this one
we will set two for this one we will set
to three and then last thing we got to
do here is control the locking on this
hopper here so it doesn't steal the
items out of the Shocker boxes we just
want to pick up the box when we break it
so to do that um from from this block
here that the comparator is going into
we get the signal and we run it this way
I think we set this at three actually I
know we set this at three and then that
goes to this hopper here and that locks
it so no items we put in the shelter box
are going to go into that hopper all
right cool and that's the whole thing
here let's let's actually look at it
from a distance here this is hard to
figure it out that's not the whole thing
in order to fill up the shelter box what
you can do is run a hopper right over
here so from from that chest there I
would run a hopper down here so I just
about got this too wide it's three wide
though technically but we got a lot of
space here so it makes it easy to run
hoppers to it which is nice as well oh
yeah one other thing I like to do with
this is put a button over here so we can
Auto eject stuff from the dispenser nice
and easy but we should be able to place
the Shocker box here let's get a couple
of them in there empty ones empty shell
core box is go up here to place our
first one you can use the button we can
open it still because the upside-down
slab above it and you'll notice it
placed it upright so it opens upwards if
you have a block below this even though
the
spencer's sideways at always places its
upright okay guys so you can see here we
got our box loader connected to the
zombie flesh chest from our item filter
up there from the from the gold farm
which isn't really running while we're
down here so just for this test I filled
up that chest there with some zombie
flesh and it's funneling into here to
speed this up even further I'm going to
manually put a few more into here just
to get it to that point where it's just
about to switch over alright so just a
few more until this fills up you see it
breaks it places a new empty one there
that full one goes down into here and
it'll keep doing that until it runs out
of these empty chests so I load it in a
few from up here those go down into here
and we could have up to a double chest
of shelter boxes in here and a double
chest the full ones down here so that's
a lot of storage in a small area but
those are very expensive as we saw so
I'd probably only have a few in here but
there's potential to put more if I want
alright guys well unfortunately it is
that time again I was actually planning
on building the unloader with you
designing it together but that will have
to wait for another episode it seems but
hopefully you find that loader useful I
have a lot of cases in my world like a
lot of farms like even here for example
where I'm considering adding that in
it's going to be like some major like
renovations so I don't know maybe over
time I'll I'll get get to switching
everything over to that could be cool
but here is the comment I picked out for
today guys it says hey ESO do you ever
look that and wish you didn't switch
your world over to amplify terrain
that's a good question you know I
thought when I did that I was going to
have more issues actually it's been
pretty good honestly like yeah when its
brand new terrain and I'm generating it
and recording
it struggles a little bit to keep up but
after it's been generated it's usually
pretty good the second time you go to
that area as far as like exploring
though it makes it so much more fun like
there's a lot of amazing sights I see I
wish I could include them all in like
like that episode I did last time I saw
some really cool stuff but only had so
much time to show it and with the wings
it's a lot of fun flying through all the
tunnels and crazy overhangs and stuff it
makes so no I don't regret it I really
do like the amplified train still and I
love having the mix in my world so I got
flat spots where I can do building or if
I want I can go to the amplified terrain
it is hard to build an amplified terrain
I have found though maybe with some
practice you could get better at it but
I'm I'm not there yet I still need
practice but I'm working at it hopefully
you guys enjoyed today's episode though
thank you for watching hope you're
enjoying the 1.11 update as much as I am
and until next time take care bye bye
[Music]