[Music]
hey everybody it's etho today i had some
big plans in mind i was gonna change the
world
quite literally actually i i wanted to
do some building you see but the problem
is
i quickly realized i did not have the
materials to do the building i wanted to
do
so
what did i do while i ran off to go get
them so yeah it seems we are pretty low
on oakwood in our world at the moment or
else possibly i just misplaced it
somewhere and i can't find it i do that
a lot as well
uh but i also needed to get some azalea
leaves so i started growing some azalea
trees and chopping them down and then
oh it kind of hit me like
if people knew
if people knew they would call me out on
this they i i mean i'm being a sucker
here right um so i i started panic a
little bit after growing a few trees
it's like okay we got to make an
automatic farm and actually let's just
do a quick little crash course on azalea
trees here so we can get more familiar
with their
basic uh game mechanics okay so as most
of you probably know you can bone meal
moss and it will convert stone into moss
as well and that's also where azalea
trees come from the saplings
now you'll notice like some of these are
moss carpets some are grass some are the
actual azalea plants so i think it's a
15 chance
uh when it tries to create some sort of
plant it will choose to be either a
flowering or a non-flowering azalea
plant okay
but you'll see not always do you get
a plant growing sometimes it just stays
as air when you when you bone meal the
moss right so i think the actual rate
might be of one and nine is the number
i've heard the cool thing about these
trees is you can take stone from a stone
generator made out of thin air basically
convert the stone into moss and then
when you grow the azalea tree
it creates the rooted dirt underneath it
replaces the moss with the rooted dirt
so you're essentially creating rooted
dirt out of out of nothing now the
really cool thing about the azalea trees
is you can actually fully automate their
growth and harvest so what you do
uh bonemeal in this dispenser up here
does nothing so you need two dispensers
you need one below facing the moss
when you hit that one it will grow the
the plants on the top of the moss and
again that 109 chance that
there's going to be azalea plant in
front of this dispenser we got unlucky
this time we got an air block but if we
try again
oh yeah this grass needs to be removed
before it'll try growing again
okay
and the moss needs to be removed there
and
you know you got to get lucky to get it
to show up
oh not in the right spot
hey look let's just plant one there yeah
so what a nine chance it'll appear there
all right and then
you can hit that with the bone meal and
it'll grow the tree another important
detail about the azalea trees is they
seem to be very easy to grow like if you
compare them to oak saplings which were
like traditionally the easiest tree to
grow in the game one two three
one two one two three
you know
they grow very easily but azaleas seem
to almost
always grow the first time or second
time
one
one two a couple other interesting
things about these saplings is they
don't grow naturally you have to hit
them with bone meal and when they try to
grow they check a three by three area
above themselves for any blocks
obscuring their growth so if there's
brick
in a three by three area above them
no matter how many times i hit this with
the bone meal it will not grow because
these bricks are in the way
but
oh yeah and even if there's just one it
still won't grow because it's within its
area it's a block higher
or a few blocks higher it won't grow
but it ignores any that are on the base
level with the sapling so these ones
here are fine
and they'll be able to grow and the
trees tend to grow crooked and at most
they'll get five blocks tall
all right very good so now we know how
they work let's actually get to making a
farm for them right well not quite just
yet you see the plan is we want to
develop this area this cavern
and it's a death trap okay so what i
need to do actually
is like survive
and torch it up for just for now like we
might get rid of these torches later if
they're not very atmospheric but in
order to actually work down in this area
and develop it
i need to survive somehow
oh man
uh so yeah first step light it up now
thankfully with this update
we don't need as much lighting we don't
need to get to light level eight to stop
mobs from spawning we just need light
level one or higher we gotta get more
torches and i'm not really aiming for
perfection on the lighting here i just
kind of want it to be tolerable
i can deal with a couple mobs i just
can't deal with like 50 at a time
okay how's that look now that we got it
lit up did it ruin the aesthetics the
looks of the place a little bit
if i want to ever go to a new area and
develop it what i have learned about
myself
is it has to have farms or some reason
of visiting that area because if i never
see it i never think oh i should do this
and that to it and this and that and it
never gets developed right so we got to
put farms down in this area some reason
to visit this area
uh for example there is a geode here
there's a geode over there
and there's even a geode right up there
there's a triple geode here so i think
we should make this our amethyst uh
farming area another thing i would like
to do with this area is have a river
that runs kind of down the middle here
maybe a couple little waterfalls on the
way as well
and then we'll split it into two sides
so amethyst farming on that side and
then i think we're gonna put the tree
farming
right over here all right so let's get
to it here i think the first thing we're
gonna do is just kind of level out the
ground a little bit so it's easier to
work with and then after we're done
building the farm we can
rough it up a bit more in the future you
know
get it looking more natural oh what's
going on but i like never have space
my shoulder boxes are always full it's
driving me nuts probably because i'm
carrying like boats and tropical fish on
me and a random carrot yeah whatever
okay it might be my fault a little bit i
was looking at the vines here i was like
wait a minute how are they that color
because i think we're underneath the
desert right now and i think lush biomes
or lush caves
actually has its own biome color to it
despite like being in a desert up above
oh snappers all right guys let's build
our azalea tree farm and i actually
worked this out in creative already i
got it uh working pretty good i spent
more than the usual amount of time on it
so i figured let's build it together
i'll show you how it works
a couple cool things about it as well
and then you'll be able to build it if
you want to yourself so this is how we
start it
this is a sticky piston right and then
we leave one space for a wood log and
then this is going to represent our
stone line
coming from our stone generator and you
want to get to the point where the
piston can't push anymore
so this is 12 blocks long right and then
we're going to start setting up our
stone generator here
and basically when lava flows downward
onto water it creates stone
if water flows sideways into lava it
creates cobblestone
and i don't know if it's just me
but this was the hardest part of making
the whole farm to be honest with you
making the stone generator was a
nightmare
okay let's seal this up
the water can't flow out uh yeah i don't
know what the deal is with these things
like they'll work
you leave the area you come back and
it's the stone generator starts making
cobblestone though the water and lava
get out of sync with each other
and i just could not figure out
what to do about it until i tried a
bunch of different things and eventually
i just kind of stumbled on something
that works so what we're gonna do
is get a chain of repeaters here
[Music]
set all of these to four except for this
one we're gonna keep it one and then
when the stone passes by here from the
stone generator it's gonna tell it to
create another one at just the right
timing
all right
here they come
and you'll notice like as soon as the
stone gets created it gets pushed here
uh-huh yeah so this is kind of like a
double function thing it acts as a clock
for the stone generator but it also
seems to synchronize the water and lava
so that they don't produce
cobblestone on you even when the chunks
unload and reload
which was a huge head scratcher for me
so i had another big problem with stone
generators as well sometimes
the piston wouldn't push the stone when
the chunks would unload on me like if it
happened at just the right time or the
chunks unloaded right when the piston
was supposed to push it would ignore the
redstone signal it received and you
would find a piece of stone in front of
the generator
that it didn't push so my solution for
that problem is a countdown timer
where basically if you leave the chunks
and come back at just that right time
where it'll fail
uh this constantly refreshes the
countdown timer
until
the piston kind of messes up then this
will go off the torch will come on and
then it'll try push one more time and
yeah the goal of these safety systems is
we want to be able to run this farm
automatically like turn it on be free to
move around our world and not worry
about chunks unloading on us and
breaking the farm we want it to just run
all the time without like hey we're in
the area we have to turn the farm on
stay in the area for it to work and then
like when we're leaving the area we
gotta make sure we shut it off otherwise
it's gonna break on us
that's not that wouldn't be very good uh
so hopefully
what i figured out here we'll keep that
from happening
yeah so we go for six sticky pistons in
total each with a log in front the log
thing is a trick with tree tree growing
um
remember the three by three rule with
the azalea trees
when they grow here and they check the
three by three above them they ignore
logs as one of the the things that will
stop them from growing so this is a way
we can push
the tree that grows here without needing
a double extender with the the pistons
then we run our redstone line up there
and we're going to add one more slab at
the top here because otherwise
a log will eventually grow here and cut
the wire this prevents a log from
appearing in the spot right there are
you ready for the logic part of the farm
this is
the tough part of the farm okay
uh yeah i worked really hard at
compacting this i hope you appreciate it
even if you don't understand it ah
here we go okay so the goal is by the
way to get the moss to spread to this
block and then grow the tree on top of
it
so what we do is we bow meal the moss
with this dispenser it's facing towards
it right we also need to remove the
grass that grows on top of the moss
otherwise it can't grow anymore
which means i need a piston
i totally forgot about that part okay
that goes right on top dispenser breaks
the grass that spawns on top there
easy peasy right well then what we got
to do is we got to take the observer
this updates when the block moves right
and then it goes to
the block here with the redstone dust on
top
this activates both the piston and the
dispenser and it seems like the
dispenser triggers before the piston for
just update order reasons
then we take the signal from there it
goes across over this way also we need
to grow the tree that's here using
another dispenser
which is over here which gets powered by
this as well we also need to place box
over top of this stone here otherwise
this will convert to moss we need three
of them
because that's how far it extends to
now
what we got to do is take the signal
from here
and send it to there
while also sending the signal
back this way with just the right timing
so that this triggers more than once we
want it to trigger twice
okay and then uh what do we do here i
don't even know uh no i do know
i think we want three repeaters this
one's set to four this one at one this
one before so when this repeater updates
it triggers this and gets another pulse
to the dispenser growing the tree
what else oh yeah we want to get another
pulse to this one because remember
sometimes you get air
blocks even after you bone meal this so
to improve our chances of us getting
something to grow there we're going to
trigger it twice
using another delayed
pulse going to it and that's it that's
the tree farm so it should be able to
grow trees now let's give it a try here
we got these loaded with bone meal to
start this farm if it ever gets stuck
like if it runs out of bone meal or you
run out of tnt you got to break that
block right there
where the trees grow
and then we just send a pulse to this to
get it started again
all right yeah we got a tree farm did i
mess up let's find out
oh i got moss in the area here so it's
spreading everywhere oh my goodness
i gotta remove that
oh we got our first trees
uh-huh
so as soon as the stone gets pushed here
it gets converted to moss and then
a couple plants grow here
it tries twice oh there's another azalea
awesome okay so it seems to be working i
just shut it off for now we got a few
more things left to build here but this
is what it does it basically creates a
long strip of wood here
and uh the root of dirt underneath and
then we gotta blow that up and collect
it in a collection system so that's what
this is over here
it's uh five wide
we're gonna put water here
fill this up
and
it is exactly like the tree grows here
so it's a one
two and then a third block is where the
water is that travels eight blocks the
end here
and then we're gonna put another water
source uh it doesn't really matter where
i'll put it there
and then that's gonna go to
just a hopper for now
until i do something more fancy
uh hopper
it'll put the logs and stuff into a
chest so that we don't lose it
like so
and then i'm just gonna put a trapdoor
uh over here
all right so that should pick up the
stuff that lands in the water here
nice and easy
next up here we're going to set up a tnt
system for harvesting the wood from the
tree farm
and while building this farm originally
i had the tnt system up in the air like
most farms and i came up with a pretty
cool trick i think
um like normally you gotta drop the tnt
at least eight blocks so it doesn't blow
up the dispenser it comes from oh i
should not have placed this here
wait is that the right spot yeah that's
the right spot i think
okay i'm gonna just put a piece of brick
underneath there yeah check this out so
what you do you put your tnt in here you
put a stair on top water
and then when the tnt ejects here the
water carries it right to the end
and that way you don't need to drop it
you don't need to run redstone up up
there you don't need to shield the
redstone from the blast it's all just so
much simpler we just activate it from
underneath okay i just put a button here
so we can manually trigger and i'll show
you how it works so yeah up comes the
tnt the water carries it to the end
and the water shields the dispenser from
getting blown up as well
and then all the logs land into the
water stream and up in here and the dirt
okay so we don't want to trigger this
every single time a tree grows though so
we got to add some kind of counting
system for our farm as well here's how
we're going to do that we're going to
take the signal from
here
so whenever a tree gets grown this gets
triggered and then we're going to send
that down to a counter i'm going to put
two droppers
facing each other
like so we'll trigger this one by
putting a block above the observer will
trigger it that way
and then we're going to go down here in
the corner of our our water system
and put a comparator
pull the signal from here
then we put redstone here that'll go
back this way
and i don't have blocks
i'm gonna carry the signal this way
and then we're gonna add a repeater
set to four
this will go to
a i think i want a sticky piston here
with a block on top
no not a block i want observer yeah
we're going to set up a observer clock
here so you know how observer clocks
work they
oh
yeah if you have two observers facing
each other they constantly pulse
see how they're ticking like that so the
pistons gonna push this up
and then it's gonna trigger and send the
items in this dropper back to that one
our goal with this is when five items
enter this dropper we want to send them
back to that dropper to reset it and
then also shoot out a tnt here this is a
bit of a janky uh counter i made just
for this tree farm so it's a little a
little weird
uh put that in subtract mode and then
we're gonna fill this up with uh four
stacks of items plus sixteen
roughly
uh-huh uh if you do copy this uh counter
just keep in mind it will only work for
up to five items max count up to five
maximum
okay and sixteen okay so now
what's gonna happen is when we put
swords in here or an item that doesn't
stack five of them
it should reset where's my last one
i only made four apparently oh no it's
my inventory okay here we go
that pops up and then those items go
back into that one and it sends a signal
here right so now we're going to take
that signal
and send it over to the tnt system so to
do that
it just so happens those five swords the
signal reaches exactly to here
oh it's almost like i find that right
and then we we're gonna run a redstone
torch up here
target block so it connects to it
and then
our dispenser with the tnt is there we
run away
and then we're free to cover all that
stuff up and it doesn't look too bad
right pretty clean presentation to the
farm
uh
yeah i thought we're gonna get this done
10 minutes tops right
yeah we're still going here oh it's a
good thing we didn't uh design this
together too or
we'd be looking at 20 20 episodes on
this thing i think
oh man
don't worry you're gonna get an extra
long episode today guys um
i thought we're gonna get this done a
lot faster than we are i still want to
build some stuff okay so
you'll notice like moss is shooting out
here and getting collected so we can
either drop that into
water to collect it or we can put a
hopper we want to compost it we can
compost it
and then reclaim some of the bone meal
that way for the farm i actually want to
keep this moss and stuff it's creating
because i don't have a moss farm built
in our let's play just yet so i'm gonna
i'm gonna be storing this stuff for now
oh
all right
something like that should work and then
we wanna make sure
like
this stuff doesn't fly everywhere
so what we're gonna do i'm gonna have a
nice viewing window with glass here
we can put glass there but then remember
the three by three rule we can't put
glass here oh first first batch
uh because then it'll stop the trees
from growing so we can put leaves though
so i'm gonna put leaves there
just to keep everything contained
all right
and then we can cover that back up and
if we ever need to break that block to
restart the farm we can just put this
trap door break it and put it back
okay then
uh what else here yeah let's add uh a
system for the bone meal on this
so we can run hoppers to this dispenser
and
then a chest double chest
and then i think we can do hoppers here
we gotta run boatmeal to this dispenser
as well so hopper
chest and chest and this is outside of
the range of the tnt just barely
uh okay then
that will get another double chest here
and then a hopper facing into that
double chest here and they kind of meet
together and then when you fill
this chest with bone meal it'll funnel
to both sides and you've got a nice
storage
and you can add more chests if you want
more storage for that now remember we're
also making like moss and and seeds and
the the plants and stuff over here from
this uh one as well so
if we want to collect that we can trap
it with leaves here as well
they'll kind of stay contained that way
and if we put a hopper minecart
underneath that moss block
we can pick up most of stuff and with
that we are actually done building the
tree farm i just want to talk about a
couple quick things again if you want to
restart the tree farm if it stops for
some reason the blocks here you got to
break that
and then you run over here hit the
button
uh i think i might add a proper way of
shutting this down for right now if i
ever want to shut it down
this is why i do i just break a repeater
not the most fancy thing i wait for this
thing to shut off
and then i'm free to put it back and
it's shut down so this runs totally
automatically but there is a semi afk
mode you can use with it as well if you
want you can kind of stand inside there
and hold right click with some azalea
trees
if you want to grow them quickly you
know
oh that scared me
although i might be within the range of
the blast standing here
yeah this is a way you can get it going
quickly
doesn't always grow them it usually does
okay anyways
don't walk away
all right uh the other thing though this
is very important to me guys okay so
it's running it's working fine
i'm gonna leave the world
and rejoin it a few times and just make
sure it doesn't create cobblestone
because i tried very hard to make sure
it doesn't break when you leave the
world or leave the chunks
let's go here let's see if it's still
running
please
please don't be broken
all right still making still making
stone i'm going to try that a few times
why why
oh it failed to push this time and then
the the countdown went off okay and it
restarted
all right well i tried re-logging about
20 times here and this thing gets
triggered a lot actually i thought it
was only occasionally that was gonna
happen but no it's like almost every
time i join
uh the piston fails to push
not entirely sure why but that's what
happens and then this thing saves it
got cobblestone once
and i am extremely disappointed by that
i tried so hard to fix that problem
it's very rare it's happening but still
it is happening and it will require me
to break
like 20 blocks of the cobblestone to fix
it and the farm will stop working if it
happens so it's a really annoying
problem i don't know how to fix it so if
you guys know let me know all right
awesome let's move on here so we got our
tree farm built it's good to go
and uh before i can collect some wood
from it though i do need to gather a
bunch of bone meal to feed it
at some point i really want to build
like a giant massive uh
moss farm in our world to like
mass-produce bone meal but until then
this is my best source of bone meal i
want to take a quick little second here
just to talk about the theming or kind
of the lore of our world here so when we
look around the man cave right it's got
almost a clean look to it
like all on the path here it's nice and
clean there's no grass it's like
somebody's living here somebody's taking
care of it it's well manicured just off
the beaten path you know it's a bit more
rough there's there's shrubs and stuff
that haven't been taken care of so yeah
for this area underneath the man cave i
really like the idea of keeping it
overgrown like this like this was what
the man cave was before we conquered it
kind of idea and we're going to try to
develop the roughness a bit like we
don't want it to be so scattered and
undefined
we want to try to add some definition to
the roughness i guess is
the goal
uh the idea that kind of comes to me
when i look at this is terraria jungles
right
i'm really getting like a terraria
jungle
feeling for this area i want to sort of
develop that as the theme so for for
example imagine we set up a honey farm
like a bees nest or something
representing the
the bee fighting terraria right but
instead of like having these pools of
water we replace the water with honey
maybe and then like the clay with
honeycomb i think that could look cool
have it like dripping from the b nest
and then
inside is where all the bees are and
they're making honey and stuff yeah i
want to try pull some of the elements
from terraria and use them as our
decoration ideas for down here
so for example as well like you could
put heart containers in places you know
those those rooms with the treasure
chests in we could use
that as like some buildings for down
here and i want to put like a couple
random uh
it's very dark around here i want to put
a couple of random plantera bulbs down
here
as well i think that could look cool add
some pink to the train i think that
would look nice
uh
let's space this a bit more
actually
this is gonna be a big bulb isn't it
that's good we want like big elements
though right we don't want everything so
small it needs to be like oh that i i
know what that is it's a plantarity bulb
when you look at it kind of thing
uh
let's round that out
and i'm gonna fill this in with the pink
terracotta
and hopefully this looks cool we
probably gotta rough this up a bit more
and then
uh let's go up more
yeah let's go up one more and then we'll
do the
we'll bring it in a bit
how's that looking let's take a let's
take a step back
huh
that's not bad right
oh we could do something like that maybe
uh i did bring some leaves let's try to
decorate the bottom a little bit more
but anyways we'll probably have to get
more into that next episode i wanted to
do it this episode but uh timing yeah uh
because i also planned on doing some
stuff at sandy city here we're gonna go
through and do a bunch of upgrades to it
and hopefully try build another house
here
and uh just do a do a few things so
starting with the walls okay i've i
really struggled building these walls
like i wanted to add some color to them
i wanted to
do something with them besides just
having them all sandstone so i did this
green and wood thing and it's like okay
it's a little bit on the busy side
though um i've never really super liked
it still not super happy with my up
upgrade with it here i want like brown
sandstone or something i think is the
dream here but it just doesn't exist
but i like this more than uh
than this and i think it works better as
a background look it's a lot cleaner so
i'm going through here and we're
updating all the walls to the new style
sandy city has three of these gate
things around it and i still really like
them i think they turned out okay but i
wanted to add some extra detail to them
so i'm gonna put some
uh campfires
uh up like this and i think that'll be
good it'll add some animation it'll add
lighting
and just give a bit of life to the area
as well
be able to see a bit of smoke i'm gonna
do that on both sides of it as well like
we'll put them here too
i am noticing a couple odd blocks
missing every every so often as well
i've had a few creeper blasts over the
years that i've fixed and sometimes i
miss blocks when i fix it and uh yeah
there we go
all right so this path here is a mixture
of birch planks we got some upside down
sandstone stairs to get the textured uh
sandstone look and then there's some
smooth pieces and sand mixed in with the
path and since uh i originally built
this we have gotten this stripped wood
in the game i might try mix some of the
birch in
and we also have azalea leaves in the
game now and i think these are gonna be
huge like so so nice for any desert
build or savannah build um because well
you kind of got like two options you can
go for the the dry dying look to a
desert area or you can go for the
beautiful oasis look and that's kind of
what i want here so i'm gonna replace
all these uh leaves here with azaleas
we'll get a nice brighter green
okay a couple things over at the
blacksmith area here yes iron makes
sense at a blacksmith true true
it doesn't add any color though uh so i
want to put emeralds here it'll be a
jewelry
smith yeah and also i don't really like
the
red nether brick i think it just came
out and i put it here
and uh yeah it's a little weird
i'm a pretty big fan of the beehive
texture it works great as a flooring
material but it also
works good in a lot of other situations
they kind of look like crates a little
bit
so they're good for just like decorating
cities putting them around people
traditionally always use note blocks for
that but i think these work a little bit
better
okay so there's a spot over here that's
kind of interesting i think i originally
planned on putting some animals in here
or something i'm not sure
it's it's not doing anything right now
though i found out if we dig down here
it actually goes to a pretty good spot
in the man cave and we could probably
put an elevator to connect the two
together because right now there's no
way to get to the sandy city from the
man cave
uh-huh so we got the musical mushroom
farm over here and then if we go past if
we want to develop further this way
we can connect an elevator it'll go up
here
to sandy city so this is going to come
as a little bit of a surprise to you but
you know that potion brewing thing we
have over here that gives us night
vision uh
yeah i never actually finished it
oh i know i know it happens though
sometimes believe it or not sometimes i
don't actually finish things
uh i'm gonna
do a little tweaking on this thing see
if we can get it looking better and and
by not finished i mean uh there's like
redstone exposed and everything here
yeah it's not the not the cleanest look
so maybe we'll put some clay kind of
like what we've been doing with all the
houses here
get a couple stripes of clay here
just a couple of minutes of building
makes such a big difference it's crazy
uh yeah i like that quite a bit more
um what i want to do now is like we got
this tiny area here like it feels like
it's big enough i need to do something
with it but it's too small to really do
anything substantial so we might just
build another one of these
like market stalls oh i didn't want to
break that
over there
uh and just
fill in this area a bit with it
like one two three four
maybe we'll make come out here
and like throw in some bushes here
maybe get rid of some of these bushes
and put product back there
oh the inventory space guys i don't know
we need a solution to this soon
uh let's go up uh three maybe
oh no the white wall
uh i gotta set up a sheep farm guys like
we have a sheep farm but it's not a
practical one to use
oh we got some okay sweet
all right we've done orange we've done
red we've done blue so maybe green or
yellow for this one let me figure out
the shape of this thing before i
actually start putting the wool down
maybe like that well i guess it should
match the counter right yeah
oh snappers okay it turned out better
than i was expecting actually i didn't
even think of this but like we have
something to look at now when we're
walking down the alley here which is big
like instead of just looking at the wall
i think that's very important uh so what
do we sell here we sell watermelon blast
guys we got the watermelon floor
watermelon stock we're brewing up the
watermelon blast here
yeah
i put like a ring of trapdoors up there
to kind of look like it's tying
the yawning awning
awning right yeah
awning
to the wall right it's gonna connect to
it somehow um and then
yeah that's about it okay so
oh yeah i wanted to check this out let's
try die i gotta get used to like dying
signs different colors i'm still living
in the old ways guys
oh that doesn't work nope nope nope i've
said it before but i i really like my
inventory system for the ender chest
it's so good it's like well i i just
look in here and it's like okay choose
which one you want to use
i think we'll go for beet root maybe try
it out let's try grow it just to see
what it looks like
sure
yeah okay
and this doesn't block the path either
as we walk by so i think it's good no oh
we're we might be all out of wheat here
we got one more place to check
i like i like never raid this thing
there's got to be some here right
uh yeah okay that should be enough oh
tough decisions everybody the details
the details do we keep this here or
do we go for this i think this
thematically makes more sense right
we're trying to sell potions or or
drinks
maybe that's the watermelon blast right
there i think the the little guy looked
better though
maybe
i think we'll keep that though uh uh and
i know i'm sorry i disappointed a lot of
people i made a bad decision i would
switch back to carrots
i don't know what i was thinking
not my proudest moment okay uh we got a
little bit of a space here not really
enough space for a house i don't think
so we got to put something here that's
kind of small
uh and i'm thinking i want to have a
spot for llamas like a stable sort of
area and it makes sense i think they
would come up to the well to drink right
like this is where you would want to
have the llamas
so yeah let's just do this i'm going to
make a little feeding trough thing for
them here
actually let's do it like this
that and then we will put a
not that we'll put a wood block there
but i want to do it like this
have uh
this with the straw in and this one for
the water
what
explain
oh i know i know i i i see i see it i
see it i see it okay okay
that messed with my head though uh you
know what it is that's a stair so i
waterlogged a stair
i was kind of planning and hoping to
build a house here today as well maybe
in this spot uh would be good uh but
timing issues on this episode i think
i'll do it off camera and then we'll
just check it out afterwards
um but uh yeah i did get the little
stall here for llamas so we got a
stockpile of hay we got our lead ready
to go for them
fence gates now you can't put path
blocks under the fences and stuff that's
what i was originally planning on doing
but uh it doesn't work so i had to mix
in some dirt and stuff here
to make it work
i think it's fine right
uh-huh anyways uh yeah let me get to
this awesome all right everybody check
it out i've been building a way here and
we now have a brand new building
added to sandy city
it's a two story
uh let's see let's get a couple
different angles of it so it's kind of
like a fat t-shaped building
both on the bottom and the top it's like
another tee stacked on top of a a bigger
t below
and i think it works i think it's good
so i didn't do the interior i got a lot
of buildings i need to add interiors to
and i'll probably make a episode where i
focus on that um but my plan with this
one is i'm gonna use these barrels to
store dyes in i think because i don't
really have a good uh like bulk dye
storage in my world and i always like
run around looking for little scraps
here and there it's kind of annoying
so i want like a big storage spot for it
um and then
the thing is with that little t on the
top of the building there wasn't really
a good way of like
adding a ladder or a staircase in here
so i decided to do something kind of
interesting um we got the wall going
around the city right but there's no
real way to get up on the wall so now we
have a way
up on the wall for the security guards
right that work at sandy city they need
to be able to do their patrols
and they also need time to relax guys
right so i built them like an employee's
lounge up here they can get out of the
sun and and relax when they
get tired of walking around the wall or
something i don't know did something a
little different here too that i've
never tried before i use scaffolding as
a ceiling material and i actually really
like it i think it's kind of cool
right
uh-huh so that's all done and then
they're also we got like a little
walk-around area for them here so they
can go check out the city
on their patrol uh-huh uh-huh
and what else i did do the roof
oh man you know you spend half the time
building the building and then you spit
waste another half the time on the roof
right it's not even a full roof it's
like
it's like
a weird shape roof check this out it's a
very weird roof
now keep in mind it's a desert city
right so we don't really need to protect
against rain though we don't really need
roofs the roofs are for sunshine to
protect against the sun
but yeah we got a lot done on the city
here today it's uh coming together
pretty good i think maybe we build like
a little structure here for our ender
pearl thing and then maybe one or two
houses and that's it we'll be finished
with this um or even just one house and
maybe some outdoor thing like
like a park
but deserts don't really have parks so i
don't know
a desert park of some sort it would work
as well yeah we got this house here
didn't do a whole lot around here today
just the updated bushes and stuff
changed some of the trees around more
melon trees in the city i think i should
add one more stall like one of those
market stalls in this corner
feels like we've got a bit of empty
space there that needs something
uh-huh we got our crates around the city
we updated the blacksmith this is the
area we spent the most time in
i think we actually we should probably
add the pathing back here too that's one
thing i gotta do still add the pathing
maybe something over here is needed as
well
uh
maybe a
black market corner back here or
something i don't know
uh but yeah otherwise i think uh it's
come along pretty good here oh and our
elevator we need to build the elevator
still all right everybody well it's time
to wrap it up for today so let's uh end
our episode here with the comment of the
day which says
hey etho great video i was just
wondering is it safe to assume at this
point that the recreating the wiki
project
is a new nexus
and i think by that he means a a project
that's never going to get finished
uh yeah so the wiki project you guys
remember that uh
we went to the new terrain forts
started building a room for it and
that's about as far as i got with it um
so it was a project i was super excited
about
i thought it was a great idea
um was really looking forward to it but
it became pretty clear to me
that i was way more excited about it
than you guys were okay it's kind of
what it came down to and i'm not going
to spend an insane amount of time on a
project
uh that you guys aren't all that
interested in is is what it boiled down
to so at most i'll probably finish that
one room we started on it and maybe add
a couple more just for fun
but the other thing is somebody brought
up a point that i hadn't considered
about it as well like the whole idea of
the wiki project was to create like a
museum for minecraft to
kind of show off game mechanics and that
kind of thing and somebody in the
comments said isn't that already what
you kind of do
i would rather see you do it by building
new farms and showing off the new game
mechanics and farms and stuff
in an actual application than in some
controlled museum where we already know
the outcome and stuff so i thought that
was a good point that i hadn't
considered
and i ran out of brick here uh
and that's a good reason not to continue
it as well
yeah
anyways
hope you guys enjoyed today's episode
thank you for your feedback if you have
any please leave in the comments below
i'll check it out and that's it take
care have a wonderful day bye bye
you