[Music]
hello everybody
welcome back to ethos lab
had a very strange urge to uh
some mobs for some reason
that's what i'm doing
and for some reason this one area had so
many
so i thought i'd start recording anyway
uh with the work i've been doing on the
potion room i've been trying to collect
ingredients to
get the potion brewing a little bit more
look at all these arrows
wow get a little closer to
like the ingredients stocked up that's
when that's why i'm
hunting basically so i was looking for
gunpowder
um
and what else did i need i think this
gunpowder i went out to get some reeds
and it was nighttime and i just decided
to hunt for the whole night
and now i'm heading back
oh it's a party yeah this sword is
awesome for getting gunpowder
look at all goes quick um
getting it for splash potions obviously
should really crit them
so off we go again
i was collecting the reeds for the sugar
to make
fermented spider eyes mostly so
the reason i want those is for the
instant damage potion so i can stop
punching the mobs in my xp farms and
actually just
throw a potion at them to get their xp
because uh
even though i can one punch kill like my
spiders in that
uh it does take a long time to punch 100
mobs or 200 mobs
at once it would be much nicer to have
the instant damage potion so that's what
i'm working at
getting set up today just as a starter
here
and i've uh i wanted to try something i
never used my awesome axe
on the giant mushrooms so i want to see
how quick that goes
out of curiosity
because i need mushrooms
yeah it's instant but you have to click
if you just hold it it's kind of
takes a little longer
whoa i almost fell down there okay
all right and i also changed the door to
the
ingredient room here uh it's dark wood
now instead of sandstone has a nice
contrast to it i like it a lot and it
will better suit this area here the look
i'm going for
so nice adjustment
this room here i don't really care how
it looks to be honest but
i may i either got to convert it to
like stone brick or or else to wood or
something i don't know
it'd be a pain to well anyway i'll think
about it
and i will deposit our new ingredients
here
oh i did have some in there i didn't
know that
oh they're not all full okay
oh man i've been dreading this but it's
time
we have a very serious talk about your
performance this quarter
you have not been meeting the
requirements i set out for you
been here for days weeks
you haven't made me a single potion yet
i don't understand
what you do with your time all day
you're in here all day
what do you do
dude oh fine i admit my training was a
little bit rough
okay let's go through this again so you
stand here
pay attention stand here we're going to
get some
glass bottles
fill these up
you better be watching
all good then we get our netherwarts
hey come over here
put these in the oh we still can't shift
click them can we
i hope that gets fixed put these in
the brewing stands
yeah we may as well put the nether word
in as we do this too save some time
ah
all right very good i think you're
getting the hang of this finally
so that'll give us awkward potions and i
want you making instant damage
splash potions okay so the next things
you would add
are the spider eyes it's okay don't push
me don't push me
i'll show you spider eyes then after
that
add fermented spider eyes
spider eyes turn into poison fermented
ones turn into instant damage
and then finally add the gunpowder to
make it a splash potion
okay you got this
i'm gonna leave it to you now and when i
come back i expect these all full
all the chests okay good
okay i seem to have forgotten minecraft
running again
so let's hope this doesn't uh
wreck my world or something
just right clicked
stuff is happening
the potion seems to have worked uh
two frames oh here it comes big shower
of xp
you're enjoying the slideshow i am it's
very
very enjoyable
just hope it stops soon oh i'm getting
xp
yeah i think i might install a timer to
this thing because i keep forgetting it
running
so i'm thinking if i could set up like a
to 30 minute timer that would be awesome
so if i go afk for longer than
like 30 minutes uh the cave spider
system will just shut off or something
as a safety might be a cool feature to
add here
um two frames per second now
seems to being three
um this is a very
exciting video i probably shouldn't
record this
all right i'm going to stop it here it's
taking too long
well that's pretty frustrating but it
crashed my game my world
cannot play it so
have to load a backup this is what it
does and then eventually it blocks out
yep make backups guys keep making
backups and never stop
uh this one i only lost about an hour
of like gunpowder collecting and stuff
so i think just that one night and
some of the potions i made are going to
be gone and i think that
tree thingamajig that people don't
really like
is gone too so not a huge loss
i think we will recover just fine so
i'm going to get back to work
recollecting my ingredients for the
potion room and
i will skip all of that because you've
seen it already
okay this is a few hours later now and i
think i've recovered
pretty well from that crash and then
some
you get even more stuff now
i also went ahead and finished up this
room like i was planning
decided to go with a stone look it would
be
just because it would be a lot easier to
do so i replaced all the dirt and
garbage on the walls with uh just
regular stone
and the floor with stone brick except
for
where i had wire just uh just in case
ever gets washed away i'll be able to
see where it goes
and uh i was too lazy to change the
cobble with stone brick so that's why
it's like that
but yeah it looks a lot better in here
and i just kept like a little
i don't know what you call it when a
building has uh
this part way up the wall i don't know
trim or it's not exactly trim though
i don't know i forget the word
so this is nice i like it
up here i changed this a little bit it's
uh
ceiling's a little higher in here and
it's all squared out and
3x3 and delightful so
all is good and i
have made a few instant damage potions
and have been using them
i actually enchanted a few things off
camera sorry
i left my game running afk for a while
and uh i know what i want to build today
so we're going to go do that now
or what else i want to build today
because i already did this
i fixed this door more to more times
than i'd like to
admit uh but it's a wheat farm
a very cool wheat farm made by generic
bee
one of my buddies absolutely ingenious
idea
and it's been improved by a pear
squirrel so
i'm going to set it up next to that
skeleton
dungeon i found in the sand the other
day that way we'll have bones next to
the wheat farm because it's uh it's a
bone meal style
wheat farm okay so i'll get my stuff
together and we'll we'll head off
all right we're here at the spawner the
skeleton spawner i found
and i already started cleaning it up a
little bit down there
got my supplies didn't know exactly what
we're going to build this out of so i
brought a bunch of stuff
and um should get started
the first thing i'm going to do here is
encase the spawner and set up a
collection system for it so we can get
our
our bones going and i'll probably just
encase it with stone bricks
and that might give you a little bit of
updates on that
then once i got that going i will start
work on
the wheat farm and it turns out
this spawner down here this other
skeleton spawner is just out of range
so we won't be able to use both of them
unfortunately it's like two or three
blocks too far away
or something ridiculous so
oh well what can you do
i like that one over there because it's
near the surface
it's uh it's pretty rare to find them
that close to the surface
well not rare but it's awesome when you
do because you can actually build things
on the surface that use the mobs
so believe it or not i might actually
build something above ground
on this one and i am going to get
started here so
i'll see you in a few few minutes here
yeah so it's coming along well here i
got most
grunt work done and we're just about to
seal it up and put the
put the water streams in and stuff
lighting i'm going to put a lighting
system into it
uh the plan is to make the skeletons
kind of go up
and then to the right here
and i'll probably have the wheat farm
somewhere
up here too eventually i will probably
make like a building like a bakery or
something
just for the novelty of it and uh
these guys are distracting
yeah we'll have like a bakery building
or something here eventually
uh the skeletons will probably be an
xp farm or have the option of killing
them
or something like that i don't know
exactly how i'm going to do it but i
think we should head down
that creeper is still here though i do
not want him blowing up that spawner or
i will
have a hissy fit and i don't trust me
or i don't trust myself on these broken
ladders
or the fixed broken ladders or whatever
good okay so when i make these
mob systems i pretty much do them all
the exact same way
because it's it's the best way in my
opinion
so it's an eight by eight area here
uh to maximize the amount of spawning
space
and the spawning rates so
spawners over here will mark that
i've talked about this many times before
but
this wall here at the f3
direction is three blocks away then at
zero i have it
three blocks away one is four blocks
away
two three four and then
two is also four blocks away so one
one two three four away from the spawner
that is
so it's an eight by eight room but the
spawner can't be centered
in it because it's an even number so
that's the way that works
two of the walls are three blocks away
and two of the
two two of the other walls are four
blocks away so
yeah enough blabbering about that i'll
use glowstone for the lighting i guess
and oh yeah you'll need two
blocks of airspace below the spawner and
two blocks
um yeah two blocks above it as well
so this roof i'm putting on
is two blocks oops
or will be two two air spaces above i'll
just bring it closer so you can see
so one two
okay uh the lighting
how do i do this i'm going off memory on
this i think i put it
level with the spawner and
the fifth block in or so
or fourth block from one side and then i
put
the lighting back there do that for
oh this might be a little bit different
with the skeleton trap
now that i think of it because uh this
has to be two blocks high for them to
fit in here
it would go normally over here
i'll have to think about this i'll put
it there for now anyway
over here one two three four
stick it in there and
one two three four so this will
this will light it enough that light it
up enough so that skeletons won't spawn
when the lights are exposed like this so
we don't need these torches anymore
it's daytime anyway then i have pistons
sticky pistons that go
over here and when they extend they
the block they push will block out the
light from the glowstone
like that and it becomes dark in the
room when that happens
okay so that's the lighting and i'll
have to run wire on the outside to
connect them all together
next we'll do the water stream here so
this uh it's an eight by eight room so
the water ends up going
all the way to the very end here
it'll push the skeletons this way and
i'll have water
all along i guess i can go ahead and do
that actually
i think oh
you know i'm gonna put the pistons in
first give me one sec
i got the roof on it now and we're going
to be trying to get the skeletons to
this corner i think and
should be really easy to do pistons are
in place as well
so i'm going to go ahead and put the
water in i guess
put it against this wall we'll do a
stream all the way across
like that that will push the skeletons
to the side over here
um let me polish this up before we
finish this this shovel is pretty cool
efficiency the efficiency for one
i like it it's quick
okay we'll do that
and uh we said that corner so i'm gonna
put water over here
and then that will push the skeletons
that way
i guess we gotta convert this yet
i better hurry up or else we're not
gonna get to the
wheat farm today
okay i'm showing this because a lot of
people ask me how i do these uh
spawner trap things
all right so that will take them to this
corner and then we will go in one more
block
that's as far as the water extends and
this is where
we will go up and that will take the
skeletons up here up a mob evader
type thing so we'll
polish this up
so to do that we're going to take
advantage of the skeletons heights
them being two blocks tall and their
ability to swim in water
so how do we do that again i think yeah
put a pressure plate here
and then water above uh we'll need a
sign
here
put that there and you have two block
high clearance to get in there
so oh you know what
if we do that though then they will
push against here we can't have that
don't make a ton of these things
uh what should we do instead i guess
go down one block maybe and then we'll
go
this way a little bit
and then we will have another water
stream here
i guess we don't need to push him that
far really
refill that well
i'll make him go up here a little bit
aways from the spawning room
okay so now
i need a pressure plate here
uh give me a second i'll it'll take me a
while to do this probably
i really don't like being in this hole
at night
creepers can come down at any moment and
then they seem to be
always around
okay so all the torches are out of here
and you can see they're not spawning
and we have all the space utilized that
they can spawn in
so it's pretty pretty good here uh
they'll go to the side then this corner
they'll fall down
this stream will pull them a little ways
away
doesn't really matter how far uh i'll
put a pressure plate here to block the
water
could use a sign here too with this
block it doesn't really matter
i'll put a sign over here to hold water
as well
and then oh i hated that ladder change
so much you have no idea i'm so glad
they're changing it back
i actually died a few times from it
just because they're so messed up now
anyway
uh what we'll need to do here
or what i would recommend is to make
the the water you place here flow
towards this wall or towards
this direction because uh
if you just have a flip box there and
you just have a still water block here
uh you might have
well i might not know what i'm talking
about here
it's possible the skeletons might try to
swim up and then get stuck on the block
above
maybe
probably not actually
it's hard to see anyway to be sure
just remove that block then do this then
there'll be a water stream that pulls
them against this wall
so they for sure won't hit get stuck on
the block above here
okay
just a little trick
and this we will polish up and take it
up
okay so i got some bad news guys i have
started working full time again
so i'm not sure how it's going to affect
video upload
rates and everything uh
i'm really glad i have a bunch of that
oh
ooch i'm glad i have a bunch of uge
recorded
that'll make things a lot easier to get
regular videos up
and we actually finished that series up
now recording
so uh good figured they would run until
march before it finishes up so i hope
you guys enjoy it
we had a lot of fun playing that map and
actually towards the end of it we were
pretty much uh
just trying to kill each other
constantly this'll it was pretty fun
okay so got to fill this up with water
all the way
up here to however high we bring it
i think we will leave that skeleton
thing
at that point though for today
maybe i'll try to put the water in
yeah so i'm working full time
i'm not really sure what's going to
happen with that i'll have to try to
develop this
schedule to make sure i get my videos
out still
but please be patient if i am slow at
releasing videos and let's play videos
i do what i do i do what i can do but
you know it's not
fun uh staying up till 2 a.m or 3 a.m
making videos if
if that's not what you want to be doing
so i will try my best
but i'm gonna make sure it's still fun
for myself
seriously these ladders oh we can't do
anything with them okay i'm just gonna
leave that for
today let's start working on the wheat
farm
hmm i've been trying to figure out where
to put the wheat farm but i don't have a
whole lot to
work off of here so i think i'm just
going to put it over here somewhere
and i would have liked to build it out
of bricks but i don't have any so
i might try another brick don't know how
to look
so i think i'm going to build most of it
off camera
or all of it off camera just because i
don't want to take views away from my
buddy
generic b so if you want to see how to
build it yourself
uh go check out his channel and
or check out his video i'll link in the
description
of this video and also check out pear
squirrel too i would recommend
but here i go i'm going to try build it
and i'll show you how it works afterward
yeah i had another pretty close
encounter here
uh just about had a rage moment
still might nope got him
i should probably take a look around for
any more
uh it's just about done here or at least
the guts of it then i'll just have to
put some filler blocks in
i think we're okay so i'm gonna get back
to work
should be done soon
all right so i got it more or less
complete here uh it still
has the wiring exposed and everything
and this area is not
safe by any means i'll have to be very
careful about using it at night until
i turn it into a building of some sort
i put a piece of glowstone in the back
here next to the piston that you see
over here so it should
give a little light into the building uh
behind the wheat
and i knew you were going to come down
here
well let's get this over with so
the redstone to this was done by pear
squirrel
he improved it made it quicker smaller
more efficient that's what pear
squirrel does but the farm idea the
original
the design and everything is done by
generic bees so this is his baby
so he calls it his awesome automatic
wheat farm
which is it's a good name it's a good
name
generic b if you're watching i would
suggest nickname it the bread
maker that's my suggestion suggestion
suggestion excuse me the bread maker
it's kind of catchy
i think and it reminds me of a bread
maker because it's like a little box
you put your ingredients in and you get
your wheat or bread
out of it and it makes a lot of noise
like a bread maker too
so with enough
rambling here this dispenser here has
seeds in this one has the wheat or the
bone meal to grow the wheat
um what you do and i did install piston
here so if i want i can have that up
so the idea is it uses bud switches to
kind of control the wheat growth and you
shouldn't have any seeds or bone meal
in your inventory you just want one seed
to start out with so i'll grab that
hopefully this is set up
i think we're safe you just hold right
click
on the tilled soil over here
and voila
so it just gives you one of each item
and it keeps alternating and
it gives you about 75 wheat per second
is repair squirrel figured out
so it's very quick
so as i do this i should be
in range of the spawner so i'll be
having skeletons spawn and i'll be able
to get more bone meal and then when
you're all done you walk in
grab it and pretty cool
uh might be a few issues with it that
that shouldn't have been there
but overall it's pretty cool i like it
very unique design for wheat farm
um
[Music]
i had something else i was going to say
but i forgot it
oh well kind of been important yeah so
i'll probably end the episode here
i'm loving this new wheat farm though
it's very cool
and i will probably
start breeding cows more often now that
i got a renewable way of getting wheat
again
because i'm getting tired eating these
watermelons you gotta eat them
every like five seconds it feels like
i want some steak some real meat
uh yeah so i'll end it here thanks for
watching
i'll see you guys again next time