you're reading is everybody this is etho
and welcome back to another episode we
are in the stronghold right now and the
other day you know I decided I just want
to play in my world without worrying
about recording just to relax and enjoy
it so that's what I did I did a bunch of
resource gathering and I also did like
like sand and wood and that kind of
stuff and I also did a few minor
building projects like I've redone the
silverfish farm here it looks different
it's not totally done but I'd even a new
look still works the same as before
though I did not fix or not fix but
there's a few things I need to do with
it yet like I have a sensor here that's
supposed to shut it off when this fills
up which is not set up yet so if you
hear Pistons spamming out that's why and
I also need a proper way of hitting them
up here which I haven't set up but yeah
this is a new look turned out pretty
good I'm happy with it I like that you
can see the spawner in it now and you
can actually see them fall down when
it's running and I guess let's go shut
off the light and take a look looks
pretty cool when it start to read to the
top up here there's stairs outlining the
whole thing and I love how the stairs
connect now you can do so much with that
little trick you know just lots of
little extra details you can fit in
really good change I love in the new
snapshots like I'm so glad I switched
over and I plan on keeping up with them
but yet looks pretty good when it's dark
so since it's all half slabs it stays
dark inside there light can't pass
through half slabs but you're able to
see inside
pretty good and I have it set up so they
can't jump out at all so it's safe and I
decide to leave the end portal kind of
showing yeah that's a cool look to it
yeah it's the new silverfish farm and
remember the big mess underneath it like
how I kept falling and there's this
random blocks everywhere I decided just
to take that all out and just try to get
more structure more organized in this
place because it's a mess still I don't
favor show this but I put these on the
glowstone now and yeah just trying to
organize around here a little bit more
because it's been crazy I
I got chests everywhere I can't find my
crafting benches ever I don't know what
happens to those things but they just
disappear on me always yeah so on the
topic of getting more organized today I
think what we should do is work a little
bit on that storage room that we're
planning on doing up there I'll show you
what I've been doing I remember I talked
about organizing how I'm going to do the
chests in like a word document than that
I was about half done that may be but
now we got these item frames and I
thought a cool thing I should do or a
cool way of organizing it now would be
to set up like these walls of my
different groups so like I have an armor
group and just put all all things I want
chests for so I would have a chest
dedicated to picks a chest dedicated to
shovels axes swords
this stands for misc tools like hose
flint and steel fishing rods that kind
of stuff so we would have five chests
four tools four chests four armor and
then food some of this stuff gets is
going to be doubled up oh you scared me
some stuffs going to get doubled up it's
it's going to be like a large store
but not like SuperDuper large where
every single unique item gets its own
Ches like golden apples and regular
apples are going to share a chest you
know just but in general just about
everything is going to get its own chest
like I'll even have an old chest for
gasps tears really don't need one
because you don't get too many in the
world but yeah so that's what I'm going
to do and I want to play around with my
storage design again because we have to
change it we sort of planned it out
before but now that we got the item
frames I want to change it up again to
include them oh right right something
else important I discovered while doing
this the item frames they have a limit
on how far you can see them you see them
loading as I walk closer so I worked it
out and it's 20 blocks exactly I'm
pretty sure which sort of sucks because
our storage rooms over 40 blocks across
so if we're for over half way away from
the wall we won't be able to see what's
in the chess kind of sex I might know a
way of dealing with that because I do
really want to use them just I would
have I would have liked to be able to
see the item frames from the other side
of my my room though it's too bad
there's a limit like that um where we
going oh yeah nope not here still
getting used to my changes I because I
didn't have this staircase here before
and it's just temporary so before the
way we did it
we were planning something like this
where we would have double chests sort
of staggered in a checkered format like
that and then we're going to have
buttons below of the block type and then
a dispenser on the ground and then I
think we were going to do signs on these
on these stairs here
but yeah we got to redesign this so I'm
going to get my stuff together I think
I'm going to just skip doing dispensers
all together because it takes quite a
bit of space so yeah I'm gonna get
blocks together we'll try work out a
different design that will work with the
new item frames whoo-hoo oh and by the
way I didn't really explain this too
clearly but the whole point of these
item frames here is to organize them so
instead of doing it in a Word document
I'm doing it visually in Minecraft where
you guys can see it too
and then once I get it all organized I'm
I'll have everything here because I kind
of have to collect one of every item
which is going to take a while too but
basically when I get the spot set up for
them I'll just come up here and move
each of these item frames to where they
belong and this way I it's easier to
group them together because I can see
what stuff I want to go next to what you
know like for example I want tools next
to armor and yeah anyway let us design a
new storage area here's a good working
area I'm probably going to do it mostly
out of wood because just have that wood
color to them I think storage rooms
should be made of wood because of that
so we're going to go with darker color
too so yeah my idea is to have two like
two chests below then a beam with the
item frame on and then two chests above
because and still do the checker pattern
so let's just try to put that together
here something like this and then
we'll just use full blocks we're
actually supposed to use stairs for this
so we can open the chest because you
can't open the chest if there's a block
above it but we can if it's a stair and
the stair looks the same because I want
to undo yeah I think so right yeah okay
so you do that then chess and then the
next thing would be where we would have
the item frames so at that level going
all across and each vertical row is a
group and then we do two chests above
that something like this yeah I love how
the block kind of sticks out of the
frame that's really cool so yeah
something like this we could probably
improve this plate a bit though how's it
look if we do this I'll probably yeah
I'll probably want to use dark wood
because the overall scene of the storage
area is kind of dark so could do that on
our walls
it's hmm is pretty high up to reach
these so each item yet would yet two
double chests basically with this um you
know what we could do though actually we
could use half slabs in front like this
and go up like half half a block and
we'd still be able to open the chests
that could be cool and then do the same
for above make it look a little smaller
you know
maybe maybe come out another block like
that oh I think we are onto something
here now I really like this instead of
half slabs I did stairs right at the at
the edge here next to the chess you can
still open them but it gives us a full
block height here and above so this is a
great part about though the item frames
are at eye level now which I really like
what I would like to try - we're going
to perfect this and I'm going to be
really happy with it that's my goal we
if we were to do ah only problem if you
drop stuff in stairs like this you're
never get in the back unless you break
them that's pretty cool oh but we know
that won't work because we won't be able
to open the chests like these ones but
we could we could use spruce wood stairs
yeah let's just try this out we'll use
we'll use full blocks just to see what
it looks like but we could we could do
this with stairs later just to give it a
bit more color OOP that works alright
and maybe instead of like staggering the
chest like this I'll just do a flipped
image so the chest for the top part
would be here and just for this one
would be up here so reversed of what it
is
oh yeah I love it it's perfect this is
what we're doing I'm pretty sure that
looks really good very efficient like
space usage able to store a lot of stuff
a good visual on it really happy that
the item frames are at I hat eye level
here and they kind of stand out with the
darker wood yeah very good I liked it so
I flipped it it's more symmetrical
looking now with my groups I think I'm
going to always have to make sure I use
an odd number of stuff so that's this
side and this side are the same because
if you if you do an even number it looks
weird it's like that way and then that
way you know what I mean so odd numbers
either threes 5 7 9 11 s you know
vertical columns now I did have an idea
here though like we could do our walls
like this have have little sections like
this where we separate our groups with
the with the wood there or I'm thinking
maybe we do little coves in the storage
room so have a wall here one here one
here and then the entrance like over
here and you go into it and have three
walls of chests
type thing I said it type thing knew I
couldn't go to the episode without it 1
2 3 4 5 so yeah the next next one would
be here and we could do maybe 5 5 per
wall so 5 here 5 here 5 here entrance
here have an arch on the way in because
you know I lick my arches and maybe half
slabs for the ceiling
could put some lamps in the ceiling if
we want to have them stick out yeah I
think we got something going on here
guys
and then stairs OOP just want to get a
feel for it yeah I like how it's how
this looks we could also just thinking
ahead here for the floor see this would
be stairs and then our chests would be
here but for this we could do regular
wood I need more blocks oh I'm all out
Dart so I see what it looks like real
quick here yeah nope do it this way like
that make it go all the way around that
and then did it again and then again
chests here that's pretty cool I think
that's what we're going to do guys
I like it so with my project here I need
to finish organizing this once we do
that we can start building because we'll
know how many sections we need like this
each of these would hold 15 different
items let's go down below let's just go
down below for a sec 15 items yeah we
really can't plan too much ahead until
we know how many items or chests we need
total I would like them all on ground
level so they're easy to get to we could
have like one Cove
over there we might have to do like
three per wall like one there another
arch over there another one over there
and three over there three on that wall
this front we're going to do different
though so we might not have any chests
on this side I don't want it to be a
perfect circle room I want it to have a
bit of shape to it and then also I want
stairs that go up to a second level and
on that second level will have entrances
to other parts of the base like our
firms and stuff yeah got it planned out
mostly now so we can we'll probably be
able to build this pretty soon going to
have to go in pretty quick here though
it's getting late
short episode today I'm sorry I'll show
you what I've done with another hub
because I messed around there a bit too
okay here we are so I just all I did is
I put up some sandstone walls here to
see what it would look like three high
and then I have it sloping inward and I
have it all connected together like the
stairs connect together which is pretty
cool getting these lighting glitches
with them like these dark spots here can
fix those and I will just by breaking
the block above there we go
one thing though I'm noticing with these
sandstone stairs they still have a line
here like where they connect right there
but I guess it's not terrible
then what over and these things I'm
going to have like a little display
probably like I might put a wheat or
flowers or something in them just for a
little something extra and I also missed
around with the hidden wire access door
order here so I might do them all like
this but like this
just retracts the Pistons
and we have a nice little room here and
pretty much get to everything this is
the wiring below and I might make most
the room out of stone brick or I might
leave it another netherrack I'm not sure
not too worried about gas blowing it up
because I know there's a lot of
netherrack here in the way also I never
showed my cart launching system so when
you press a button piston goes up and it
powers the track so you take off then on
the way back there's this detector rail
when it goes over that the piston goes
up again but it doesn't power the rail
so if the cart should hit the the block
before it goes down and they'll align it
perfectly where it needs to be and
that's how I plan on doing that and then
I started digging out this tunnel which
goes as stronghold I think with my track
system I'm going to make it go straight
and then it'll branch off to the right
here for one destination it's really not
that far this is a stronghold portal I
also went a little further here and this
goes all the way to my sand quarry which
is where I would like to move the
silverfish that portal takes us there
and yeah that's about it for the nether
never did fix that silverfish problem
though too bad all right
alright let's end the episode with a
comment etho zombie villagers either
randomly spawn or become infected by
regular zombies
there are also baby zombies that are
young forever to get them get a baby to
get them get a baby villagers infected
to get a villager infected have a zombie
kill it's ah ha yeah the other episode
when I found one I had no idea that they
spawned randomly the zombie villagers I
thought they only could be created by
getting infected so that was a surprise
to me
just another joy of playing the
snapshots without giving the spoilers
but yeah turns out I think it's like 10%
or something chance that when a zombie
spawns they can become a zombie villager
and the other day I went out looking for
him as I trying to repopulate that first
village I found and I was going to cure
him i lured a Samba villager into one of
the houses blocked it off and I was
going to enter pearl out but he cornered
me and killed me and when I came back to
my stuff since they D spawn he was gone
I went because I was out of range and
when I came back for my stuff my armor
my enchanted armor including my feather
falling for boots and also my sharpness
like for sword was gone because he
picked it up and then he spawned so I
lost the ton of stuff from that that
sucked and on that note I'm going to say
goodbye thank you for watching everybody
and I'll see you again next time
you