[Music]
and though everybody and welcome back we
are starting out in the tree farm for a
change
I came here to to cover this up because
it seems to be working flawlessly I've
been watching it for a while
and I got a little bit of a surprise
that I thought I'd show you this is
meant for the big slimes but apparently
I caught a squid too which is which
means I think let's just go over there I
think what happened
a squid must have spawned in this little
bit of water here and unless it just
grazed the pressure plate went to the
corner and got picked up that's the only
way I could see that happening something
I've never even considered like what
would happen if the squid spawned in
there but it can handle them too so
that's good anyway nice I'm gonna show
you the sheep farm and I'm just gonna
finish this up all right so the sheep
farm project is getting close to done I
would say I did a little bit of tweaking
so one thing I did I came up here and
got rid of all the all the soil all the
grab all the ores I could see at this
top part here and replace it with stone
just to I know that stuff bothers me
even though rarely will ever come up
here then what I did is I added an extra
four repeaters at the back here to make
the water stay down longer so whole
bunch of repeaters here I tested it once
and the sheep seemed to be okay but they
might have started may have started
drowning a little bit I it was hard to
tell
before I tried again though I wanted to
get some of these to heal them up
because they might have taken some
damage while I've transported them here
because I dropped him down this hole I
didn't really have his only one block of
water in places so they might have taken
fall damage a little bit of a medic here
because I lost two sheep there I don't
know how or why or if it's gonna happen
again I don't want it to happen again
and one of them was a brown one which is
the worst of it all I should have thrown
it right at him but I don't have a whole
lot of the brown dye left and that's I
got some more I also just the front here
I like to look at that what I'll
probably do is put one of the buttons on
this block here for the master reset and
one on the other side for the for the
water system the sprinkler system - it
shortcuts
I feel like expanding here some more not
really sure I'm scared this guy he moves
so quick now that he can pretty easily
get out of here that's right when I open
that door he's still he seems to have
made a few potions though which is good
because I came here and it's like loaded
up now like he's he's actually doing
stuff good I thought I was gonna have to
let him go there for a while
cool you go check the chests over there
while I steep excellent he filled these
two or one of them anyway I noticed
all right so he'll the rest of these
sheep talking about other games I
recently installed an older game of mine
that I used to really enjoy called
Alpha Centauri hope I said that right
Kurt will correct me it's it's a old
turn-based strategy game
I used to love playing when I was
younger I I'm not really big into
turn-based strategy games or anything
but there was something about that game
that was just amazing and played it
again absolutely love it still now that
I'm older I can actually appreciate the
numbers behind it and the formulas to
calculate things and just it's still a
great game so if you've never seen it or
played it you should check it out even
though it's older it's still it's still
really good okay we will well we will
shear some sheep here I'm a bit of an
older gamer I don't there's a lot of new
games that just really don't appeal to
me and what I like to do is just put in
an older game that I haven't played in a
long time and then you know since I
haven't played in years it's almost like
playing a new game to me I the way I
feel
and there's thousands and thousands of
older games that I've played I've played
a lot of games in my life all right yeah
we'll try it you know what I did just so
that I change one of those blocks to a
wooden one and I put that torch there as
a safety is really watching sheep see if
they suffocate it seems to be okay
doesn't seem like that would be enough
time to set that you don't a mob I guess
we could try it on ourselves maybe no
it's pretty hard to stay in there oh you
know what we can do see when they make
that noise it sounds like they're dying
I see how how much just takes off of us
yeah that's not it close to enough time
so therefore they're fine with that I'm
pretty sure the other day when I was
shearing sheep I could have sworn I
double sheared them and I checked the
wiki today to see how many hearts these
guys have or to double check and they
got eight hearts but it said there's
this glitch that if they have seven and
a half or not not a tarts eight half
hearts so if they have three and a half
hearts so everybody if you left and
right click with the right timing you'll
get five wool from them and somehow I'm
getting none okay well I'm not doing
that because I just punched that guy so
if that still works you have to really
be good at it otherwise you're gonna
kill your sheep
poor guy do I have any more definitely
gives the blocks enough time to get
there now we should go heal them up all
right yes I did a little little
something fancy on the front here I'll
probably leave it open like that for the
front
I got pressure plates here to hold the
water in I don't really like that
because they make the clicking noise but
I don't know what else do you use hmm
that's the problem did the same thing at
the back here I plan on putting
something here I know I know what I want
to do here we might do it today but we
might not you know what I actually
wanted to do is check out the cave
system down below there I thought I
explored all the abandoned mineshaft in
this area but it seems like there's a
whole bunch more there than I missed
because that's what this all was before
I started building here this was
abandoned mineshaft like starting here
and everything through here was
abandoned mineshaft if you if you watch
the older videos around 100 you can see
how much it has changed since
yeah so I might go Taming here what I
want to do now is sort of get away from
wearing armor I think I'm just gonna go
around wearing boots booties and just
for the extra challenge to it and though
I'm gonna go explore the cave and maybe
include clips of it if anything
interesting happens actually you know
what guys I'm gonna take you caving with
me I was thinking about it and when I
first started this world I kind of made
a point that I was gonna try add more
diversity to this this world compared to
the last one because I had fallen into
the habit of totally cutting things out
of my LP like when was last time you saw
me caving for example or cutting down a
tree or anything like that I've kind of
fallen into that habit again I've
totally skipping stuff and I know like
people don't want to watch me cut down
trees for five or ten minutes you know
but a minute or two here and there I
think would really help to get people
more immersed into the let's play to see
how things actually came about yeah I
know that ravine oh and there just had
to be a little piece over there but
while we go teaming here we can talk
about the new patch that's coming out I
think it's the 1.3 patch lots of amazing
new features to it people are really
excited about it myself as well I think
the the main feature that everybody's
excited about is probably the sandstone
stairs and I know myself I actually like
expressed my happiness out loud when I
first heard they were coming out you
guys do probably but besides that
there's some other cool features coming
out too I tried out the snapshot the
other day I I just couldn't
I usually wait until the official patch
comes out like I know I try not to try
out the snapshots in creative mode
because I find that spoils them it's
like you wait for all these new features
to come out and then you just go
creative mode see everything and you
don't really experience it properly I
find but try it out the snapshot then I
did in survival mode just so I wouldn't
do that and it's pretty cool
a big change recently is the XP systems
difference you know I'm gonna take the
chests instead of going up to level 50
as you probably know you only go up to
level 30 now and it's no longer like
what's what's the word quadric turd
where it requires more XP each level you
go up it's now linear so it's the same
amount XP per per level and I tried to
find out what that is and I think it's
17 per level but I could be wrong so the
new tap is at 30 and it's 17 per level
that works out to 510 XP get maxed out
which is about a ninth of what it was
before so big difference there and then
on top of it something else that's
different is you get xp for mining ores
and even for cooking which i think is
really cool I like the idea of getting
it for mining ores it kind of adds an
extra level of fun to caving something
some extra reward to it you know I don't
think you should get it for cooking
though but for the caving that's cool it
feels like they give it to you give you
way too much XP though I'm guessing
they'll nerf it before the official
patch that's another reason why I don't
play the snapshots in my LP is because
stuff usually
doesn't get really bounced when it comes
out in the snapshots and oh no no my
tracks and also you know there's bugs
and whatnot trip wires coming out I
played around with that for a little bit
it's really cool definitely gonna be
using that in my map coming up as well
as the adventure mode if that gets
released where you're not able to break
your place blocks I'll definitely be
using that in my map main focus of the
map is going to be killing mobs and it
would make things a lot simpler setting
up traps in that if people can't place
or break blocks like I could lock people
in two rooms for example and force them
to deal with the mobs instead of being
able to run away and have things despawn
oh hello let's back up back up something
else I really like is the ender chest
that's coming out I a big flaw in this
game Oh check it out dude is ever since
like the game came out we've been
actually you know I'll - some other time
from there ever since this game came out
we've had the exact same number of
inventory slots for well over a year or
two years whatever it's been but the
number of unique items has come out
keeps increasing and there's like
hundreds of new items since the game
first came out so we kind of need more
inventory slots for all the unique items
because you can barely carry anything in
your inventory without it filling up you
know that's one of the reasons why when
I go to caving I don't bring
a bow and arrow with me usually because
it's that's two inventories slots that
get taken up Oh or just in general play
I don't carry one on me cuz I want the
extra space so with ender chests that
sort of doubles your inventory plus has
other cool factors to it let's see I've
been here haven't really been paying
attention to where I've been villager
trading looks cool I've had mixed
feelings about that when it first came
out it almost seemed like it was really
really easy to exploit like you could
trade ender eyes for emeralds and then
with the emeralds he could buy diamond
tools and pretty much anything your
heart desired so with my my ender ender
trap here I basically would have
infinite money no trouble combined with
my blaze farm which still isn't complete
by the way big surprise that kind of has
me worried it would take some of the fun
out of the game if you know everything
is just handed to you but with the new
update they've tweaked it again and I
don't think you can buy diamond tools
from the villagers I could be wrong you
can enchant them I saw but I don't know
if you can actually buy them galore man
but we'll see how it turns out once they
get everything balanced and figured out
what level are we at 43
so this cave I'm exploring here is
potential new building area too that's
another reason I want to show it to you
because it's my very well one day be
part of the the man cave
actually I'm gonna do you all right and
[Applause]
then we got the new randomly generated
structures which look awesome see what I
mean I like my inventories full I've
barely been saving it all here and I got
to start tossing stuff there's a bunch
of stuff I can toss but it's like you
can't hold on to anything with the
inventory space you have new gravel
texture so many things have come out
I've already started like I already was
at the point where I forgot what had
come out and when I was trying out the
snapshot extrema and someone mentions
what do you think of the new gravel
texture and I was like new gravel
texture what are you talking about and
then I remembered seeing it like weeks
ago and just completely forgot about it
yummy no there was something else that's
gonna say probably close close to the
end of our teaming adventure here or the
part all that you see I don't want to
like spend whole episodes caving but a
little bit here and there would really
help to diversify things Oh what was
that other thing I want to talk about I
can't remember now I'm gonna remember
right when I stopped recording
oh yeah the mobs they switched it to
like be like SNP and the mobs or glitchy
they lag in single-player now which is
the thing I like least about the patch
that's hopefully they improve it a
little bit the boats don't work the same
anymore they're really choppy it like if
you're in the ocean and you hold the UP
button you may eventually start going in
circles even like instead of keep going
straight it will decide to turn you
around which is really weird
oh I remembered what I wanted to say was
the half slabs it seems like wooden half
slabs burn now so there's a chance some
of the stuff in my man cave is in danger
you know I have all that lava around
some of that's being held in place by
half slabs I'm pretty sure all right
well I'm gonna continue here but I hope
you guys enjoyed this little change of
pace and we might do something more I'll
see how long this episode is well that
was fun
I did not go very much longer because my
my inventory filled up of course I it's
the coal that gets me but I just can't
leave it let's try out our new record I
know this one sounds terrible
add it to our collection I'm gonna head
back down there though probably because
I saw some redstone and stuff but we'll
probably wrap this episode up one thing
I'm going to do yet is hook up the
buttons to the sheep farm and that will
be it for the day yeah okay so let's
let's do this real quick we're gonna put
our buttons here and here I believe this
one will be for the sprinkler system and
it'll go up here and this front is not
done I'll put something to make it look
better and you won't be able to see that
stuff up there either when it's all done
but from this side I'll probably keep it
like this okay let's head up here we
will put this here as a safety otherwise
it will flood the Sheep as I'm working
on this and kill them up here and I'm
gonna invert it one more time yet all
right there okay
that's one done let's try it out we can
get rid of this very good oh I wonder if
I left a hole in the back there when I
went mining I might have made a mess
there I can't remember okay I'll check
it after next one we'll run the wire
down through here probably and can I do
this still think I Chen yeah that works
we will go through here hmm I guess down
through here is what we'll do take that
out I think that's one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten eleven
twelve thirteen fourteen fifteen it
might if I counted right that'll just
make it maybe let's try that one too
awesome okay so we got that done I'm
gonna call this episode good for today I
hope you enjoyed it
take care and have a good day
you