hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to our let's play series over
at the amplified bass you know I haven't
been here since the wings came out this
was all I could think about when the
wings were coming out and is like I
can't wait to try them here and then I
never went and I felt bad but here we go
woohoo I don't know how practical
they'll be but I'm sure yeah you can
definitely get places you couldn't get
before like you would never ever get to
the spot it's like nothing here it's
just a little flat spot it's kind of
cool so we can start incorporating those
at this base I tell you what we're doing
here though guys I recently watched like
a western movie western um and you know
like a lot of times in western movies
they'll have a scene with a mind like a
silver mine and a mountain sort of thing
is what as what I have in mind
we've done a little bit of building
around here but honestly it's nothing
too special right like there's no reason
I I don't have a desire to come here you
know that's that's the problem that's
why I never do anything here um this is
kind of whatever but if we gave this
place a theme it needs a theme instead
of just random building so we're gonna
go forward like a mining colony I think
like a little mountain mine silver mined
in the in the mountains not silver
though because there's no silver in this
game
oh no they're up there I wonder how bad
this is gonna be skeletons are so bad
like so annoying in these latest
versions of Minecraft I tell you I hate
them so much now like it's not like it
they make the game harder they're just
very annoying now well they do make it
harder
Who am I kidding um I thought I brought
my tea and tea I brought the Flint
yeah so we kind of got this this cool
cool area like part of the the building
is going to be outside in this open area
but a lot of it's also going to be
inside the mountain we're going to dig
like tunnels and stuff let me go get my
tea and tea and of course when I say dig
I mean T&D baby that's the only way to
go this is a really good way of doing
tunnels I found these two pieces do it
like that
sometimes you need to add a one or two
more if you place it a little too high
there and yeah it just digs a big area
now it's really good if we want to go
further just down to more pretty
efficient way of digging too like it
doesn't take too much TNT do that and
we'll have another big spot pretty
simple and then just clean it up so yeah
maybe to begin with here let's just try
to work out the basic look of our
tunnels how we want to do them the
mineshaft usually when I do tunnels in
this game I like to do these arches I
round it out it's kind of my thing you
know
but in mines like in the movie I saw in
like often in video games they have like
a brace I've noticed so maybe we will
try to mimic that I'll show you what I
mean
so usually oops we're going to mostly be
building out of wood too but usually
it'll go up straight logs you know like
so and then it'll cross over maybe or do
we even want to do that let's try it
cross over kind of like that so it's a
pretty straight look but the thing I
really want to try out here and also I'm
going to be building with dark oak
I never build out a dark oak I thought I
tried it like with the logs it actually
goes pretty good with them I don't know
why I never use it but we could do
something like this this corner brace is
going to be a key detail I almost feel
like this needs to be wider though I'm
going to maybe space it two blocks wider
and my plan is to then have the rails
system like down the
the middle like this will probably go
for a double lane instead of a single
kind of like this all the way down
aha yes so something like this I think
it looks pretty good I got rid of the
logs on the top and I just put in some
slabs instead got the corner bracing I
think that looks pretty mineshaft II
right ah the only thing though it might
be a little wider than I want now it is
pretty open in here but that'll that
would probably work out pretty good
because we're gonna fill it up with
little details like logs on the ground
you know dirt on the ground stuff like
that just so it doesn't feel quite so
plain and empty I got to get used to to
shift-clicking like or middle clicking
you know to select stuff I keep
switching out manually so let's try add
some more details maybe we'll do log on
across like this connected together
maybe we'll do one down the middle kind
of like that that does give it a bit of
an arch feel that might not be a bad
thing though I do like my arches oh yeah
let's middle click and then maybe one
more being going across here or maybe
one lower even let's try one lower and
compare the two mmm I don't really want
it connecting to this brace I want it I
think I want it higher up yeah okay let
me let me do a little bit more here Oh
actually let's figure out the floor too
before I cut again so I brought a few
blocks here that I thought would work
out pretty good we're going to use
mycelium maybe coarse dirts gonna be a
pretty big part of it and maybe
underneath the rails we'll try to do
some spruce wood just to give it some
more structure you know all right let's
clear out some grounds and then for the
walls I haven't really decided if we're
going to keep them stone or if we're
going to try to change them out with
another type of block like dirts or
gravel
let's do the floor first and we'll
figure it out okay yeah so down the
middle we don't want to make it totally
uniform let's see the middle is
here kind of like a pretty good amount
of spruce wood but not totally solid you
know kind of randomly span it a little
bit Oh ash is good like that not totally
random but fairly random okay and then
in these other spaces we'll put in some
coarse dirts actually this is bad
that's that's a that's making a pattern
we don't want patterns okay that's no
there's a skeletal horse and it's dying
we must go rescue it quickly quickly
yes get out of there
ah yes we're heroes oh wait did know
they didn't die are they fighting each
other they're fighting each other yeah
they fell they fell very far
did anybody survive that we got two
horses yes all right we'll check those
out later all right guys so we got a
pretty good basic look going on here
good start to it I would say um yeah I
think I'm happy with this so I did put
the mycelium down I tried mixing in some
mushroom blocks just for a different
texture and I'm trying to decide how to
do the sides here so I tried just
putting fences in front like in front of
stone then I tried in front of gravel in
front of course dirtier and other ideas
not to do the fences just like randomly
put stuff on the ground like wood or for
things like that I'm not sure what I
liked the most or maybe we could just
alternate a little bit - oh man did you
see it did you notice we did something
crazy here we went one to the left and
one down with with this tunnel design
now that's I know it's nuts it's not
perfect we're adding in imperfection to
the tunnel and I think that's going to
be a key to making this an interesting
build if we just did it
completely straights totally copied
every section here it's going to be a
pretty boring build in the end of thing
so I want to add little variations like
this into it and even like at the second
section here I was thinking it'd be kind
of cool if we add it in like a creek
that runs across you know and then like
they bridged over the water like a creek
from that side flowing this way might be
a cool little thing to do
just add a little more character to
different areas mm-hmm so something like
this is what I had in mind but I
reversed it so it comes down here goes
this way there was some redstone over
here so I wanted to be a little bit
careful about putting water in that area
we just bridged over top like so now
what we're going to do instead of doing
like tunnels everywhere what we're going
to do is have rooms every so often as
well so I'm going to open it up quite a
bit here got the TNT ready hopefully
this doesn't make a mess it's kind of
close to here OOP I think we did okay
there oh man
that made a big hole all right that's
good it looks like it goes up to the
surface here after all this tunnel like
this mountain
I checked out how far it goes and it's
insane it goes all the way you see the
opening at the end there like we're out
that Y 157 here there's just a giant
amount of land way up in the sky for us
to work with which is kind of cool but I
guess there's areas where it kind of
reaches outside like there okay so I'm
gonna maybe do a little bit more digging
and stuff here we should get a beacon
over here too that would be a good idea
yeah I'm gonna go get the iron to make a
beacon here I want to see if we can do
this portal trick to get back home
though so we're like minus 5000 Zed
right now let's see if it'll take us
back to near our spawn oh think it
worked where are we now - 600 okay so
it's like a rounding error it divides by
eight I believe
yeah it takes your coordinates divides
by eight I'm pretty sure and that's
where it puts you so we're not quite at
the man cave over here but we're pretty
close wait a minute I just found a witch
huts at 100 and minus 400 I think this
is pretty close to our base I've never
seen it before though aha I wonder if it
still works or if it's no longer
spawning them because there is a couple
changes in the game that might have
broke it okay very good so we got our
room taking shape here we've got a
little bit of space to work with try to
figure out what we want to do I did run
into some open area over here apparently
a lot of open area this is a really cool
spot too though like we might do some
scaffolding out on this on the side of
the mountain here that would be nice I
think ah but yeah let's try figure out
what we want to do here oh and I just
put that beacon up there for the time
being
find a better spot for it later okay so
I sort of want to dig like a little hole
down here
um maybe one two three four five five
blocks we'll leave from here and do some
things like this going up and then every
third one or so little do fences between
here alright and then down here this is
like where the holes going to be I guess
we'll start digging down we'll have
little pathways to get down here because
I want like tunnels branching off to
different places of the mountain here so
I want it to go down and then maybe
we'll have a tunnel that comes out lower
down on the mountain somewhere like down
there I don't know how that's going to
work out exactly but we'll figure it out
I also wanted to do a thing here like
where we sort of make kind of like a
covering over top this area here like
have it go up at this angle and maybe a
room up at the top there would be
nope
logs are too bulky here let's put put
some slabs in instead like us Oh awesome
so we got a couple more things built
here guys let me show you what's going
on so I did do this covering thing I
think it turned out pretty decently I'm
happy with it
ah it's kind of gives us a bit of a
sheltered feel like you don't want rocks
falling on our head you know um then I
was I was falling into that habit again
I was making things too symmetrical to
perfect and so I like move this log out
one block and then did this one kind of
want you to just so it's got a little
bit more variety to it same thing over
here experimented with another way of
doing like a retaining wall just doing
slabs instead of fences might be an idea
and then I was working on building like
a crane for like picking up the minerals
from down below here I have found out
I'm not very good at building these I
don't know I don't know what's the trick
to them I'm just like randomly putting
stuff together hoping it looks good
building is not exactly my forte as I've
said many times before but I like to do
it every now and then just for fun but
yeah then you do like the rope oh no we
want we want oak though yeah oak go down
and maybe around here we'll connect the
load to it so we'll just do like a three
by three half slab platform here we'll
load on some coal or or something make
it look like we're bringing it up
okay oops and then we'll connect rope
here the corners and somehow connected
to the middle rope um I saw a thing
somebody did once they like let's see if
I can copy it they had like a solid
block here and then I think they did
fence gates and opened it like that and
I guess they brought this up higher than
yeah kind of makes it look like it
connects that way you take this out yeah
I think that's kind of cool uh oh he
found me
he found me and down he goes so yeah I
got this thing done I got the coal on it
and I think that's pretty decent right
one thing I've been experimenting with
here you might notice the change
I've been putting oak Oak fences around
trying to get some more color into this
build up if this is the way to do it
like even this thing maybe I should just
change us back to the spruce right these
little decisions I have such a hard time
with and I keep going back and forth
back and forth it'll change this back it
was spruce originally I was like yeah it
doesn't look quite right and then I
don't know can't decide but yeah I feel
like we do need more colors in this
build as much as I love poopy Brown
everybody loves spoopy Brown right we
may be some Lowell would be nice like
some colored wool we try to incorporate
that yeah
also yeah I did some more stuff here too
by the way so I got the tracks
I made them run over here I don't know
exactly how I'm going to make them
continue one problem with doing a dual
rail like this like if we want to keep
that look going ah the platform outside
here is gonna have to be pretty wide
right at least three blocks wide yeah I
like this little entrancing we got four
I think that's pretty good and then this
is supposed to go down like spiral down
into the mine as we dig this
out it's going to be dug out quite a bit
more than what we have here Oh
invisible blocks everywhere but I kind
of feel like taking a little bit of a
building break maybe we'll go check out
those skeletal horses see if any of them
are are good I do have a saddle here
this is really coming along though I'm
happy with what we got done already yep
I found my saddle let's go check them
out I think they were by the beacon
there's the beacon down down there ok
good
whoa oh that's a creeper no no no no no
no no oh no that's not a creeper that's
a zombie zombie villager all right so it
looks like we got two that survived it's
gonna be really hard to test their speed
if we have nowhere to to run but we'll
check them out okay that's the main
thing I'm interested in how fast they
are I'm looking for fast sources all
this guy seems quick oh I wonder if you
could make this jump okay we're gonna go
how do we do this guys I wish I could
give him my glider wings that would be
amazing
if we go onto the tree not that far
we lost the hearts okay that's not too
bad there's a witch down there too okay
and now I think we're pretty close to
the ground yeah we're good okay
seems decent right can you do the jump
pad all man jump pads with the horses
that is awesome let's try to get them
all the way back up go forward oh you
didn't like that or that oh we're all
good okay guys guys decent I like them
quite a bit pretty fast we should like I
want to incorporate a lot of stuff into
this base I like we basically need
everything here we need an enchanting
table setup furnace setup horse stable
would be cool as we go here I'm going to
try to add that stuff okay I like you
quite a bit
oh this is not the place to test your
jump height though let's go outside okay
can you do three I think you can yeah
he's a jumper or she it okay let's try
four it almost seems like it could do
four
oh man it can do for this is a really
good horse 13 hearts - yeah
okay I'll go check out your brother now
oh I'm dual wielding alright and don't
die in the meantime I'll be right back
so his his brother was down right over
here
I love the glider wings around here I've
been using them a lot makes it very fun
so this is a twelve harder not as good
of a jumper this looks like a three
maybe even a two block jump hey same
thing we should be able to get down here
yeah quite a bit slower to this guy here
let's try something out here - I was
just wondering like you know how zombies
and creepers and all those guys they
won't cross rails now I wonder if that
AI also applies to horses I never
checked that out yet so if it does this
horse won't leave this corner I don't
think won't cross over the tracks of
course we might be staring at them for
quite a while do you want to leave yeah
it seems to be the same AI because it's
been close to two minutes now I've just
been watching hasn't crossed the tracks
hasn't moved at all ah we could try to
get rid of a track see if anything
changes yeah I moved right away has a
very weird walk uh-huh all right well
anyways we're gonna wrap up the episode
here pretty quick we're just gonna check
out the village oh yeah we got we got a
little baby butcher I fed all the
villagers at the very start of this
episode I gave tons of potatoes so
hopefully you got a bunch of little guys
running around Oh dad you see one ran
inside we're looking for farmers Oh
potential farmer right there for the
pumpkin farm because I've owned another
blacksmith I tried converting them two
more times and is like Fletcher and
Shepard I I wasn't able to get a farmer
so I kind of gave up we're gonna try get
a farmer from this village to be born
and then we'll move it to the pumpkin
farm and that one little guy might
actually be a farmer one in four chance
it's just the three little guys we got
right now but yeah anyways let's check
out the comments for today the first one
says etho please come back with Zee
stove in Terraria
I mean north of you guys exactly
I did quite understand this comment but
I think he wants us to play Terraria
again and I think the plan is I thought
the Z Stowe about it already we're
planning on playing Terraria overworld
when it comes out which hopefully will
be pretty soon I'm really excited about
that game and that should be pretty fun
ah second one says these golems are
creating way too much lag I'm going to
kill them off then proceeds to create a
huge lag inducing pumpkin farm now
actually here's the thing I I built that
pumpkin farm around block updates all
right so it only activates when the
pumpkins grow and because of that
there's no like redstone clocks running
or anything like that it actually
doesn't like very much because at most
you might have one pumpkin grow per tick
usually and it can handle that pretty
easily
the only time you really get a big lag
spike is when the daylight sensor switch
at day and at nights
little lag for like two seconds or three
seconds it's kind of bad but it's not
like a constant like aha anyways hope
you guys enjoyed today's episode if you
have any ideas on stuff to add at the
base theorem please let me know I always
appreciate your your feedback ah and
also let me know if you like the project
or not maybe I shouldn't spend too much
time there I don't know uh but I like to
do a little bit of building every now
and then so I thought that was fun today
alright well I hope you guys have a good
date take care bye bye
you