[Music]
hello everybody
this is etho and welcome back guys to
another episode
this is number 420
and you know what that means 420
420 graze it huh i think i got that
right
i'm not much of a mean guy i think it's
420 grazing yeah
okay
that's that's the best you guys get i'm
sorry all of you pressuring me to
to reference it that that's what you get
if you do a 420
the other thing then you turn into the
sheep here who
who just spins around like that you see
that
you don't you don't want to do the other
thing 420 graze it
yeah much better
right everybody so we're going to get to
it here i just made a pretty funny
discovery actually
i went down here i was going to check
how many perper blocks we got last
episode from the
the coarse fruit harvest we did the
furnace is still
running in here like i've been i've been
doing stuff in the world
since last episode i've built things and
uh
this has been running the whole time i
think it's just about done though
uh we got oh two rows
that's pretty good from i think that was
one harvest right
yeah that's pretty good uh we're gonna
have a lot of purple blocks more than we
know
what to do with them i think but if we
ever need more
we have a super awesome farm now to get
them
um let me just show you a couple things
because we had a couple problems at the
end of last episode just wanted to point
out some of the changes i made
i got a new crop growing here too we'll
harvest this uh maybe later
to try this out but i added in a timer
down here
why why can't i get down i'm too fat
okay
just a little hopper timer it's got 60
items in it so when we press a button
this is going to switch it's going to
activate
this redstone line over here goes up to
the water release
on the farm right over here makes all
those pistons go up
let's water out and then after those 60
items go through then
the pistons automatically shut off the
water
so it's just a single button press now
to activate the farm
and it waits long enough for all the
items to flow down into the water i'm
pretty sure
kind of tested it out a little bit but
it seemed to work i got rid of the
ladders
because those weren't going to work as
many of you pointed out and i
this is a button by the way i did one
more thing here too
i just added a bunch of hoppers uh
at the collection area here we had an
issue where it wasn't picking up the
items fast enough so
kind of a cheesy easy way to do it is
just to put down more hoppers
because now we have one two three four
five six times
five 30 item stacks we can pick up
like instantly and i don't think the
farm produces more than that
but we'll try this out towards the end
of the episode i'm gonna let this grow
we're gonna do some other stuff today
just to change things up
uh had an idea for a little building
project in this area actually
let's go towards the lake if i can enter
pearl right
oh yeah right at the lake perfect throw
i've gotten really good at ender pearls
lately guys you have no idea
all right so what we're gonna do here
just a really simple thing i wanted to
try out
it might actually make it look worse but
but we're gonna do it
quite often when i look at people's
builds that they do when like when it's
a finished
village or finnish city or whatever they
almost never leave
the water just as it is like they don't
have this gradual
natural um grass
to water type of thing they always like
build it up or do
something make it look like it's the
soil is being held in place or
reinforced from flowing into the water
sort of thing or they'll add
docks and and stuff uh if it's by the
ocean
and then like a fishing ship of some
sort you know they dress it up they do
something
to make it look better so i wanted to
try that out um
let's try this
all right just put some planks in the
back
okay if we did that all around
this lake is that going to look good i
wonder
hmm what do you guys think i i repeated
a few more times here just to get a
better idea if
it's going to be good or not i don't
think i like it
i don't like the oak for sure anyway i
tried changing it up with the
dark oak and spruce wood i like that
more
maybe that's what i'll do instead
okay we're just about done with it here
i'm gonna show it to you and then you're
gonna
judge it you're gonna tell me what you
guys think i want your honest opinion i
can take it
you can tell me it looks ugly it's fine
you know what like if
i say your mom is ugly you know it's
we have a connection we can we can tell
each other the truth like that it's fine
so don't be afraid um
we have that bond you know
i probably shouldn't have said that that
was a little harsh wasn't it some jokes
are funny
some of them are just mean that was a
little bit mean i take it back
maybe i don't all right so let's uh
let's go check this out so
what i've done i just went along here
with the spruce wood
all right and then i built this up a
little bit too like the land so it's
kind of the same level as the wood here
i want to do a little bit more to blend
it in but maybe uh maybe not today
but let's just take a look from a
distance to get an idea of what it looks
like so it goes all
all the way around pretty much from here
to over there i'm going to stop moving
the camera so you can look at it
and form an opinion all right i built a
little bridge here too
just that's where that man-made river is
that we
made a little while ago it goes over top
that
i like how it looks from this this side
right
or maybe it's ugly i don't know you
you'll tell me
but uh this side it needs a bit more
work
but i think it's an improvement
personally but i want to see what you
guys say see if you have any ideas for
what to do with it
like i don't know how to blend it in
better maybe
like bring the spruce wood out and sort
of randomize it a bit and then
mix in some coarse dirt or something
might be an idea but i'll see what you
guys say we could put down bushes on the
side of the path as well
kind of along but i don't know if that
makes sense or trees over here
we'll do something with it but give me
your feedback
uh i would like to build some sort of
building
maybe around here because right down
here this is how i access the firework
launchers
and i would like to do something more
uh polished than what we do currently
like right now to activate this i
go down here pull a lever and then go up
as quick as i can and by that time a
bunch of fireworks have gone off
if we had a building with a button in it
or something to activate it that would
be kind of cool
just a little a little thing over here
uh-huh anyway uh let's move on guys to
another project
i gotta tell you one thing gotta get rid
of this ticking noise
i got some items going in right now has
driving me nuts
like that that can't stay we have to fix
that next time we work on it
we might get we might do some stuff on
that today if there's time but first
by popular demand today we're gonna go
check out the blaze farm it's been a
long time
and last time i checked it it seemed to
be
broken they made a change where
blazes can't swim up lava anymore i
believe
was the issue but we'll go investigate
it first off
and uh if i can figure out how to fix it
we might we might do some stuff with it
all right this is something that really
needs to be polished up though like
currently the to get to the blaze farm
we have to go to this uh
bridge in the middle of nowhere i
believe down here there's a
lava you can fall in yeah it's it's not
very safe even
all right and then it gets an old
fortress
let's keep on moving it's kind of
hollowed this out a little bit it's
nothing polished or finished at all
and then here is the blaze farm the dual
blaze farm
okay go up the ladder to turn this
on i did something really goofy here
i believe this is like a big clock
and then this runs non-stop
i wasn't very good at redstone when i
built this i'll tell you guys that
so i probably could improve quite a few
things
now this is on yeah
there is a lava switch to shut it off
but it's on right now
light levels in this area
it's a little bit bright over here
[Music]
through the torch oh yeah
can't have a torch there okay
and then they go down this conveyor belt
it looks like he got
stuck there right
yeah so we're gonna need another type of
mob elevator
to get them up this little portion here
i don't know what to do with that trying
to think of an idea on the spot right
now it's not coming to me
uh slime block launchers maybe oh uh
oh if i could get one of those shulkers
over here and like have them levitate
that would be amazing
okay well i've looked at this some more
i got it shut off right now this is what
it
looks like when it's shut off the lava
comes down and makes it bright enough so
they can't spawn
uh it looks like there is no easy
fix that i can think of anyway so before
it's a little hard to see from this
angle they swim up this lava right
and then there was a block at the top
there that stopped them from entering
the the killing chamber here
uh yeah so
more lava would flow out that would make
them go up even higher
and then that would get shut off right
there on a timer no
oh then i think i had to hit the crusher
it's been a while that shut off that
lava yeah okay
and then this block goes back into place
the problem is
if we do like levitation with the
shulker
the levitation only lasts for a couple
seconds so they're gonna
float up to the top and then they're
just gonna start falling down so that's
not gonna work
slime block launchers we would have to
catch them before they
start falling back so no easy
fix as far as i can tell but i got uh
some plans if we want to do some major
remodeling here
formulated a plan good news is it's
going to be really cool the bad news
we have to destroy some nostalgic
stuff here so this conveyor belt thing
we would have to get rid of let's i'm
just going to remove a little bit of it
so we can play around with the idea
but i'm not going to destroy all this
just in case this doesn't work we can
we can just put it back okay so
they fall down here first thing i'm
going to do
is set up a slime block launcher to the
side
so there's going to be a
really the one thing i didn't bring was
slime
uh-huh there's actually some slime in
the chests up there so i got a little
lucky we haven't
had enough to make five blocks which uh
should be enough to get going here
anyway
so i'm gonna put put some packed ice
down over here
and make the blazes get launched to the
side
how far does it go i i measured this all
out in creative already so i kind of
figured out some of the mechanics
because otherwise this is going to be
really time consuming to do the trial
and error with the blazes
yeah okay so then we have another slime
block launcher going up over here
uh to get this going i'm going to put
some stan
sandstone over here and then
redstone break this stuff i feel bad
breaking this but
you know it it was annoying too having
this run all the time this
this way there's going to be no clocks i
don't like clocks i want to get rid of
them
if we can actually let's do it like this
yeah okay so there's gonna be a pressure
plate right over here
they changed the graphic on this too by
the way it looks super thin now doesn't
it
ow okay so they'll fall down when they
hit the pressure plate
yeah they'll get launched to the side
ice makes it slippery so they keep going
then they get to this one i'm gonna add
one more
pressure plate to the the dealio here
okay when they activate this
i'm going to make this slime block
launcher go up
and then another sideways one
uh probably around here
yeah so they'll get they'll get shot up
and then to the side
and it'll make like a nice little arc
should look pretty cool
uh let me do a little bit of finishing
here
you get where i'm going with this now
don't you this is either going to be
really cool or
it's going to be a big bust i'm not sure
what the blazes are going to do exactly
if they're going to cooperate or if
they're going to
like make this a royal pain in
in the booty but we will see the idea is
though they should fall down here
hit the pressure plate slime block
launches them sideways
uh they trigger another pressure plate
then this shoots up they shoot sideways
they'll do a
fly through mid air hopefully if they
don't like that if they try to pass
towards us then we'll need to put up
glass
to to stop that so they can't see us
otherwise uh
they'll fly through midair land on this
one over here
and then we need some kind of a backing
just so that they don't uh
keep moving they need to to stop
completely here
so otherwise they might go into this
block over here like one further
let's get rid of this put some sandstone
whoops
over here okay so they shoot up and then
this is going to push them sideways and
then this is going to shoot them up
one last time and um
then i plan on putting an ice stream
over here
i don't know if this is the right height
i'll have to experiment with this a bit
more
yeah they should go every time they get
shot sideways with this they seem to
travel about 10 to 11 blocks
from what i i could tell when i was in
creative
oh oh there's some wiring up there by
the way
that's that's what this is that's why
you use stone brick when you do uh
redstone guys
because when you're digging you might
accidentally run into it one day
that's the reason i do it
well if we're lucky it'll work there's a
lot of moving parts to this i realized
that doesn't work for me let's hope that
works for the blazes
and then uh there's a second step here
so there's another tripwire
right and it goes down to here and
activates after two ticks that goes
up and then also have some redstone
torches running up to the top there
to that one for the sideways i think
that's one
two three four five six delay i guess
and then one more repeater from off of
this
goes to there and then the blaze should
get shot
up into the left and then i made like a
little basket in the middle there
which happens to be right in the center
of the two sides
funny how that all worked out right yeah
so this is the very middle and this is
where my basket is so that's what we're
trying to get into right there
let's see if this works this works
this part works for me
boo perfect let's see if it works for
the blazes because they're another story
i'm a little worried because this first
part isn't working for
for me but in creative it seemed to work
for the blazes so we'll we'll see what
happens
okay let's go up we'll get this going
and hope for the best all right
and then we gotta redo the killing
chamber as well
okay turn this back on might take a
couple moments here oh right away
okay okay are you gonna do your thing
take him a little time to get down wait
a minute why isn't he down yet
is it possible for them to get stuck on
this i thought uh
i thought i worked out the details to
all that in the past
oh man oh no he was short why was he
short
see i can make this one why can't he
make the set one and he made the first
one but i couldn't make the first one
that is so weird
all right do we have any more
i wanna see if another guy does it here
i'm gonna make a little uh barrier just
in case
i'm influencing their pathfinding or
something
oh are they hitting their head oh that
might be what it is
okay let's shut this off for a second
i'm gonna remove a few more blocks here
okay here comes one i cleared out the
blocks
so let's hope it's
oh yeah right in the basket nice
oh that's awesome it actually worked
now how how consistent is it is the next
question
let's try to get a few more going and
then i want to try to remove this
this barrier so they can actually see me
and see if that affects their movement
ideally i would just like them to free
fly through the air
but if they pass fine to me might make
things a little different
oh actually i'm gonna go out just
because we can't see down there
so we gotta do the same on the other
side as well
and then in the middle there that's
where the new killing chamber is gonna
be
any more now one problem we might have
though is
if we're shooting one to the left and
one at the right and they meet
together at the middle at the exact same
time they might
bump each other and not fall down there
i'm not sure
we'll have to test that out too
this was a big problem in the past
because the only way of moving mobs in
the
nether was like mine carts and pistons
and we didn't have slime blocks and
packed ice in the past
i don't even think we had upside down
stairs when i built this before because
i didn't use any in the design here
so a lot of stuff has changed in the
game since uh
since i built this didn't have hoppers
and all that kind of stuff
okay that guy saw me he was on fire
oh yeah if they see me
we have trouble oh oh okay i'm getting
out of here
turn this off and run
very good so i got the other side hooked
up now both sides are hooked up
and should meet in the middle haven't
tried it yet
but i want to show you the plan for the
killing chamber we're running a little
low on time
so let's go through this pretty quick uh
they're going to fall into this first
part right what i want to actually do is
have a piston
around here do a sticky piston thing
all right so that what that can extend
and retract
to either allow them to fall through or
or stay there
then we're gonna have the actual tilling
chamber two
two blocks below that
and let's put this here for right now
okay so they're gonna fall into this
area here
then what i'd i experimented with this
in the creative world a little bit it
seems like it's going to work
what i want to do is grab some iron
i've never done this i wanted to do this
since they came out we're actually
gonna use an iron pressure plates
shocking i know they actually have a
purpose
believe it or not they're not just for
looks
you can use them for some redstone
things
so these detect entities right so the
more entities you got on these
the iron and the gold the farther the
redstone signal travels
so i worked out some of the the details
to this
to go from level 30 to level 33 to do
one enchantment
you need to kill 37 blazes
okay and
let's see can we do this let's try to do
this
okay so i think if i just
throw items on it it should do the same
thing right
okay let's get some redstone down one
two three four
five to show you what happens here
get the lights so we can visualize it a
little better okay so we're gonna throw
i have 50 stone on me right now
so it goes one block
and that is 25 30.
oh okay we might actually have to use
blazes
this is not working oh yeah it's only
counting as one entity when they group
up like that it's only one that's right
so anyways once we get to 41 blazes it
travels to the fifth block here so
up to here which is four extra blazes
than we need but it should be
should be fine we can calculate kind of
how many we need to kill to do
one enchantment and once this
triggers this iron pressure plate i want
this piston to extend to stop anymore
from coming down
they'll start grouping up here right i
want to automatically
trigger a crushing system as well
so we don't even have to press a button
or anything to activate it with this
design it'll all be automatic
cool so i think i got this up and
running we're gonna get some blazes
flowing here and we'll see
what happens
hopefully they don't see me it's gonna
put up a wall for right now
just so i don't mess up the results here
we're gonna have to tear this down
unfortunately
let's build it a little higher too
oh i'm out okay so i want to make sure
this left side works
first off um i'm going to try watch it
to see what happens if they collide in
the middle there too
that might happen this thing's kind of
in the way right now though
it's going down we're getting rid of it
i hate to do it oh yeah lava lava
travels fast i forgot
whoops oh man
make it stop travels fast and far
so used to the overworld this is like
you break it you
put a block in the place and it's gone
you gotta be really careful in the
nether
okay and goodbye you you were
good to us for a long time but you
served your time
and now it's time to modernize make
things better
or work at least this wasn't working at
all anymore
okay right side we know you work you're
doing good oh that guy saw me that's not
good
oh now he's attacking other ones and now
they're all gonna get out
oh left side left side is having some
trouble guys
uh oh i might have i might have done
something wrong over there
see if we can look at it without dying
oh okay okay reset
maybe some timings are wrong
gonna have to take a look at that
well i just did something really dumb i
forgot there was more than one lava
source and i fell in the second one
when i was tearing that thing down and i
am down half my life already
inside a tuba lava we have to try block
it
as quick as we can so we don't lose our
tools and stuff i'm gonna die for sure
though here
all right here we go gotta aim down
place blocks
quickly and try to jump out
one more oh i just need to place one
more no
no oh that sucks
no my gear all my tools
don't read me it was it wasn't
past its prime yet pick
on me my pistons the redstone blocks i
don't think i put back
oh i put them back okay i didn't lose
all that i lost a few repeaters and
stuff but
not the bulk of it
oh okay my big problem though is i don't
even have replacements from my tools
it's been a long time since i did a big
enchanting thing
and i've just been using up my tools
little by little so
i kind of had some old pics that replace
what we lost but i don't have a shovel
it's my best shovel right now
no efficiency or anything and it's my
best sword
and that's it i got some boots again
they don't have depth strider on
breaking so
we're hurting a little bit uh we're
gonna head back there
really quick here i think we can get
back and and just check that out
and then we'll we'll call it an end for
today we'll we'll do that coarse fruit
farm thing
uh another episode running out of time
oh maybe i didn't lose everything wait a
second wait a second there's some
food i see i see my redstone up there
oh my goodness
oh and oh and some picks my bow i got my
bow back
he's got my boots we can get those back
maybe slime okay wasn't as bad as i
thought
okay let's get back to it here the
problem on the left was they were
hitting the ground
and that was stopping them so i cleared
out some land there
hopefully hopefully we're all good now
the right side was working great
oh no
what happened there he hit the piston
and then went off of it
i don't even know okay
oh oh there we go
what happened with that guy i wonder
yeah that's good that's perfect uh
oh so they're trying to go
left so pathfinding is messing something
up
oh now we got in that guy's way
we're gonna have to fine tune this guys
we can't just let them do whatever they
want it looks like because they will
mess it up
all right so the way it's set up right
now if we get
41 blazes in there this thing should
uh automatically trigger
oh they did bump did you see that
no
oh yeah pushed in at least
oh okay there it goes the crusher
activated automatically
oh and i had it for too long darn it
but once once they all die like if i
threw a damaged potion on them
then uh the thing that stops them from
falling down their tracks as well
automatically so then
the next load will start to fall down so
that means i can have
like an enchantment worth down at the
bottom
and then they'll start to accumulate at
the top there
and it's not until i kill the ones at
the bottom that the top ones get sent
down
so it might be pretty cool we got a few
problems going on here though because
they're getting out all over the place
and i'm scared to uh
to move now that side got totally messed
up
so yeah got some work to do with this
but uh it's it's uh interesting change i
think
i'm getting a little scared we got
problems
we'll fix them next time let's get to
the comment for today
it says oh no item elevators are
not working in the latest snapshot what
are you going to do
with your builds ha the nexus
yeah so they're not the old test
elevators have some issues in the latest
snapshots
currently i'm using 15 w35e which is not
affected i'm going to wait a while
before i update uh i want to make sure
that's all settled down before i update
because i don't want to fix
my elevators in this world and then you
know they make another change and then i
gotta
fix them again so i'm gonna wait a
little bit for that to settle down
uh i got about 10 to 20 of those
elevators in my world that i'll have to
fix
but it's probably going to be as simple
as adding a piston and and whatever
maybe a little bit of circuitry i don't
think it's gonna be too complicated it's
gonna be a pain to go
around my world and do all that but
it's gotta be done so uh
that's the plan anyways hope you guys
enjoyed today's episode thank you guys
for your support
and i will see you in the next one
take care bye
you