hey everyone welcome back to our new
home here oh it's good to be playing
this game again properly playing
survival mode
I missed it a lot creative mode is cool
but man it's just not nearly as fun
somehow so I got the grass coming down
here it's gonna take its sweet time
though that's for sure
if I got a piston I'll maybe move it
manually but for now I can do its thing
odd yeah so this is our home we got like
all kinds of tunnels and stuff around
here it's great
that's kind of what what I want to do
first of all is check out some of these
tunnels like we got a big area up there
I believe that is the outside that light
there and possibly that light there -
although that looks like lava actually
so we should go check that out
that zombie up there has its own hangout
location a hey you're on YouTube right
now
they hide everyone might think you can
stay there ah yeah
so we claim this as our home now but
it's not officially my home until I
build one thing oh hey mr. Skelton
thanks for the bones and I'm going to
try to do that day if but we need some
lava to do it I have one thing I want to
build at least today but the majority of
this will probably be exploring and I've
been collecting the resources that we've
seen so far we're up to 30 iron we got
about a stack of coal or so so it's
going good we're getting started like
look at this every air
you just branches off to another area we
got like 10 to 20 tunnels in this warm
little waypoint here I like that guy
he's cool ok this goes yeah this is that
deep hole outside that we look down
before you get this I'm going to get
this stuff here alright maybe what I'm
going to do as well I'm going to get
some wheat growing down here we got to
figure out some way to get animals down
here it's going to be tough because it's
a steep drop and they'll just die if
they fall I will let's get our stuff
going down here
the general crafting table furnace the
allele stick some coal in here and we
wanna I'm not gonna say you know what it
is we'll plant our wheat the cave
idea was a big hit I'm glad you guys
liked it I think it's gonna be awesome
he'll take some time to get it going and
all that but it'll be cool
you know week going for our breathing
and all that sometime I want to grow a
tree down here just to see what it looks
like get a feel quite a few bones
already all right
how does it look underground I like I
like a lot let's do it alright what are
we gonna do now we shall go check out
this tunnel here starting wish I killed
them won't go too far I just want to oh
cool it opens up some more down here it
looks like yeah it's very nice I like
open areas like this as we can we'll put
stuff whenever we find an open area will
try build something add it like how big
this is don't make any jokes don't make
any jokes
there's doesn't seem to be any enemies
though okay um getting too far away I'm
going to get lost or something yeah I
wanted to find lab it today let's go
down that deep deep hole where was that
like this is kind of a deep deep hole
nice and open here lava back there gold
would like to find some redstone stay if
possible
oh the coolest is a ravine awesome and I
don't think it's the same one that we
saw its spawn this is a different one
remember when we first start in this
world there was that one in the swamp
biome you can tell by the water this is
not a swamp biome
Wow where is he I can hear them ah very
cool mine shaft up there we are at 24 by
24 cool nice open area here
oh there he is I can he can stay there
Oh Enderman
okay I'm going to do it today I'm going
to fight my first Enderman I still
haven't done it legitimately he's put
down a block so apparently their nerve
so they don't they only pick up certain
blocks from what I hear but I have no
idea how to fight them properly maybe
I'll help them come down come say hello
I'm making you a nice staircase no he
doesn't want to do it ah good clip oh oh
wow he does a lot of damage you need you
should really have armor when you fight
them cool
you got a pearl oh I want to try
something you know what it is already
yeah I'm gonna let my health recover
first though I haven't done this yet
either steam has so many exciting new
features to try out that hat Wow I don't
know if I just saw that wrong but it
looked like I fell down a deep hole I
don't know that was weird
okay here we go we're gonna do it oh
ouch
cool Ellen this is where we have torches
awesome Pro throw right there yup okay
so I'm going to collect some resources
and we'll check out some more of the
tunnels here yeah so just over here is
the giant two ravine right over here
nice and close to our starting area
there but I do want to check out that
deep tunnel we found and hopefully it'll
go down to lava and redstone which is
what we're looking for today mostly I
think it was just up here oh all right
we'll try again oh okay well they're
pretty easy yeah right here this is what
I want to go down
and we'll worry about getting up later
we got a pearl if we need to use it
Skelton down there oops
what are we at 28 now so we're just
about deep enough mmm it looks like it
goes down to the ravine as well maybe oh
there we go that's what we're looking
for I should have brought some buckets
with me yes we can make some okay how do
we get down though that's important
hmm well no this is like maybe it's spot
to go down
good spot for lava possibly hard to
reach them no hmm what's over here
hey okay that looks promising
hey I'm trying to look around dude and
you're shooting me ah ha first diamonds
and a nice lava pool perfect and
redstone oh it's a trifecta sweet okay
we will grab these two three don't you
go down there that's the hard thing
about doing diamonds there's always lab
and nearby Ariel that's for not bad not
bad
okay give me a minute and we will be
back yeah that was a nice little
adventure there we got lava yes I made
six buckets we got four diamonds 18
redstone and a bunch of other stuff so I
was good well I wonder happens if you
throw it in lava that could be bad
you're not careful it's making its way
very slowly yeah another problem my food
supply is low again
just slightly hmm Oh oh that's new I
think tells you how long you're poison
for that's cool yeah so we're going to
build our thing here like even though we
we've said this is our house that
doesn't necessarily make it our house
until we put our mark on it so that's
what we want to do now so I had some
stone cooking we're going to make
awesome blocks 40 of those and I think
we're going to put our mark right over
here let's see three six that would be
eight yeah yeah that should work nice
cut this out replace this with our
favorite block mm-hmm all right give me
one moment
there we go I built the frame already so
it looks nice
some people they add like little fake
furniture and stuff in there minecraft
homes to make it feel a little more
homey I do it a little bit different I
need one of these in my home this is
with the lab us for it hopefully it
doesn't follow me yeah very nice you
figure it out yet and maybe this will
help
what jumped a little bit close there a
little too close for comfort
something really freaky about a giant
wall of lava just a little bit freaky
mmm did I built this wrong no no that's
right just goes down though I believe
and this comes out yeah I think that's
right
that is right very nice I like it
yeah so I've officially claim my
property here I like its first thing I
built it looks good
I've just grew some wheat I got some
more lava let's plan around with fences
I'm thinking about lighting how should
we do lighting one idea is kind of
contemplating was using offenses because
I mostly want to light with lava if
possible just for yeah that's not that
pretty sure fences don't burn still I
never this it's annoying me and they
allow light through I'm fairly certain
yeah looks like they do let's try out
these fence Keats that's a little
strange
yeah I like the regular fence that look
good we'll put this back well now we
can't grab it can we yeah so that's one
idea
ah for the surface I know how I want to
do it already this is something I played
around with before maybe I'll show you
guys I'm gonna grab some shears
hopefully it's not dark out right now I
was also thinking about the Enderman
pearls how you can use them to teleport
now wondering how long it will take
before someone makes a golf course
indoor golf using the pearls because you
can throw them a long ways our grass is
coming down I think it'd be pretty cool
and S&P to build like golf courses
though it is dark
and every time you throw an ender pearl
chances a shot I saw like Yuna the
yogscast they had mini-golf where they
were throwing snowballs across ice but
now you can have like a full-blown golf
game in that simpie using the pearls now
we're going to do it one at a time
I'll keep shot way up and you could like
instead of having sand traps you could
use you could have lava traps and if you
throw the pearl in the lava it kills you
when you take an extra extra point or
whatever or you could have like water
pits and oh if you land in the water you
have a certain amount of time to take
your next shot of the Wrights you drown
and it's hard to see then I don't know
I'm just thinking about it could be a
fun new fun game in Minecraft
well yeah it's going to show you the
hedge think hedge lighting that's my
thoughts already light up those in it
we got just a little bit of time let's
hurry hurry I'm gonna grab some pumpkins
gonna make lanterns if I know how good
so with the recent changes you can do
these cool new lights not mess that I
messed it up 10 it's been a while why
are you messing it up I only want one
hole on home okay you put your
jack-o'-lantern in there or glowstone or
whatever for torches and then you have
hedges above actually looks better if
you put it deeper two blocks down with a
leaf above the surrounding lights
interfering them and basically you get
glowing hedges then with the new
lighting system and the fact that you
don't need leaves next to wood blocks
for them to stay alive they kind of
admit this glow and it looks great
even on on fast graphics it still does
the same glow let's do these torches see
like like it's glowing around here
that's from that one jack-o'-lantern I
hid and you can't see it so it looks
great oops and you can do that in trees
too if if you sneak up a light in a tree
it looks amazing at night the only
problem is the tree leaves die then if
you remove a wood block and replace it
with glowstone or something so you
basically have to rebuild the tree which
just doesn't make it worth it
but if you're making an adventure map or
something definitely a cool look having
glowing trees at night maybe I'll make
one just so you guys can see what I mean
I'm going to grab some more s'more leaf
blocks and I'll put it the top of the
mountain there so that you'll stay there
forever be cool kind of a terrible time
for rainbow oh well what can you do it
happens I'll give you guys a nice view
of the area though this is amazing so we
got we got six biomes all around our
starting position here we have this
swamp over here rain forests that's
where we've settled and we have the
desert which I will probably make a huge
mess of in the future getting sand looks
like there's ocean back there I can't
quite tell and then we have these
amazing mountains over here just amazing
huge huge area and it looks like they
keep on going quite a ways so yeah nice
nice starting position and right down it
there was our spawn we got the ravine we
haven't checked out yet and right on top
of this mountain here this very tall
skinny mountain we are going to build
our glowing tree
and I didn't bring a whole lot of leaves
with me so we're just going to do a
classic style
I suppose put our glow device there then
use a torch pumpkin glowstone looks good
and we'll build a five by five at it's
unfortunate you can't do this with
regular trees though because once you
remove the wood block to replace with
your torch or whatever though all the
leaves just start dying so otherwise I
would replace all the trees in my world
with glowing trees so they look they
look really good
yeah 5x5 rain is still annoying
sometimes I need to make a bed that's
that should be on my to-do list by three
and we'll top it off with a classic plus
side aerial the perfect tree
and it's kind of glowing around here
let's go check it out out from down
below if I survive this descent
oh yeah I forgot we got planes over
there that's the six mile yeah so we're
just missing the snow dilution biome and
the the pine forest one that's those are
only three we have to find yet and I was
gonna take a lame descent but I decided
we should do it the proper way
Oh No ah I missed ah
hey the good news is were right next to
spawn and that was my first death by the
way a little bit depressing
okay well my stuff then we'll look at it
if I can find it
oh yeah just I guess if you don't like
the rain you can always just live in the
desert because there's no rain much
nicer here check it out that looks cool
hey now if you if every tree looks like
that it's amazing
dang I just died a long died yet alright
for sandstone yes ok we're going back
home before I died yet
yeah so underground if I do any of this
edge stuff for decoration all I'll use
as lighting as well and all if I have
any trees for decoration I'll do the
glowing trees and other than that I'll
probably use lava and we need to try
we'll probably figure out some other
things you guys have any suggestions on
cool lighting let me know yeah that
grass is getting nice and getting down
here so this area isn't really lit up
yet now occasionally I keep getting
these creepers who think they live here
still so yeah next episode we are going
to check out some of these tunnels oops
I'm not healing light no I'm not oh man
yeah we'll check out some more of the
tunnels and then the mineshaft and we'll
probably try start setting this place up
and making it look nice nicer it looks
cool already so for today I'm going to
say bye bye thanks for watching