so we got about 1300 mobs there
unbelievable
just give us going up again
so normally in Minecraft when you have
such an amount of entities bad things
happen to your game but with the latest
snapshots they seem to not cause too
much trouble actually like I can walk
around no problem I can an open chests
and stuff no problem
they are moving very slowly because it
can't keep up as you would expect but
like if I'm not looking at them I still
get normal framerate and everything it's
really interesting and really cool how
this multi-threading works normally that
would just kill your game but I'm not
having too much trouble really let's see
what happens already kill now I think
the XP orbs are a different story
alright here we go oh
game game dying let them despawn once
they get through the death animation it
should get better particles are gone I'm
getting through 30 frames per second
here I don't see any XP orbs though do
you man look at all those goodies oh
there they come oh and there go the
frames all right well we got 70 levels
from that one killing spree there it
took like 15 minutes to collect
everything but the stuff doesn't despawn
because the games running slower in that
time so I've been trying to get depth
Strider on my boots I did get depth
Strider - I want to get depth Strider 3
though 2 is decent it seems like I'm a
lot quicker but that's because I have
the speed beacon here as well
so I want to see what three is like with
the speed beat in let's see if we put
that in protection for sharpness for I
just will do a book sure okay
lots of enchanting to do unbreaking nope
and braking nope we'll do another book
ah ah not really worth it
mmm do book again I guess so feather
falling that's not bad
mm-hm I always check for looting three
if there's looting three I take it for
sure protection three sharpness three
alright it's another book I'm breaking I
keep getting on breaking three oh here
we go yeah I'm taking that looting three
sharpness four very nice power for
projectile protection no yeah I'll take
that
come on depth Strider it's got to happen
alright let's just do the rest books
this is taking a while and efficiency
for is very good just about on the
levels come on depth Strider unbreaking
as good as well that's it we didn't get
it
darn it so these boots I got these with
the level 30 enchantment it was
protection three before but it was I got
it was protection three feather falling
for depth Strider to unbreaking 3 I
added another protection three book on
it to make it protection for so is a
pretty good enchantment actually but I
want to upgrade it just a little bit
more with the depth Strider excuse me
sir sir hello yes hi I believe you have
something that belongs to me if you
wouldn't mind can I have it back please
oh don't you walk away from me oh you
drop it in the lava when I tell you
he didn't drop it oh yes he did
it looks thin for now I didn't see it
alright cool
uh I actually wouldn't have found it on
the ground I totally missed it I just
happened to notice he was wearing it
because it was in the area I checked
already and I didn't think I didn't
think any wither skeleton heads dropped
but apparently he found one oh no oh
that redirects amazing Oh ladders are
gone we're gonna do some problem-solving
today guys
oh is it not gonna make it darn it
let me meet you at the top here okay so
here we are at the new gold farm and
there has been some pretty big changes
without way iron golems work look look
right there for some reason most the
mobs will actually try to kill iron
golems like they'll actually chase after
them and attack them before that didn't
happen and the iron golems would just
kill everything and not get attacked
back pretty much so now in the 30c
snapshot it looks like they still can
attack the zombie pigmen without getting
attacked back oh you see that baby
chasing after the iron golem though down
there um what's going for a closer look
yeah so we have to do something about
this because the iron golems are taking
damage over time here and eventually
they'll all die unless we can somehow
heal them right so we're going to be
using regen potions why is the tool text
behind these I can't read it we're gonna
try to use regen potions no here we go
he's like even creepers will chase after
iron golems and just explode on them
it's crazy
it's a chicken after them not you too
chicken come on they're good guys so my
plan this is what we're going to do I
think we should try to get a magma cube
on the roof here name them with a
nametag I'm going to use Uncle Leo
because I had that laying around and
when a magma cube is in the middle here
all these iron golems will will flock to
the middle and try to attack it but they
won't be able to reach it I believe and
then if I'm here in the middle as well
nothing else can spawn so it'll be the
only mob that they'll be able to track
so they'll all flock to the middle and
then we dispense a regen potion on them
and if we do that every so often that
should keep them alive and then after we
dispense the regen potion move myself
and the magma cube away from here away
from the middle up to there or something
on a rail line and then stuff can stuff
we'll be able to spawn here again and
iron golems will start tracking the
other mobs so that is the plan I guess
we gotta try to get a magma cube on the
roof that should be fun there's
something wrong with these guys they
just take it now all right I can live
with that um I'm just making a little
spotting platform at the top here and
hopefully we get a magma cube okay I
just had another idea though this one
might be way better I'm pretty sure the
only reason the zombies are spawning is
because there's dark spots in the nether
here so I'm lighting up all these little
dark patches where it's like light level
gets down to seven in very few places
but it does if we light all those up I'm
pretty sure the zombies won't spawn any
more and if they don't spawn these guys
aren't going to take much damage the
only thing that will damage them is the
magma cubes and
doesn't happen very often and it turns
out the plan works perfectly there's no
more zombies spawning in there I moved
all the lights out of the ceiling
they're in the ground now and I had to
redo it a couple times it turns out I
learned something new today those
zombies that spawn when you when you hit
a zombie in it like calls for
reinforcements that happens at light
level 9 and less so right now the
darkest spot in here is light level 10
and it goes up from there
so they can't spawn anywhere anymore
which is great and these guys should
stay alive much much longer because of
that I might try to change out these
glow stones with a block that gives off
light but doesn't take away a spawning
space I haven't tried those lamps the
new lamps if they work like glowstone or
not the sea lanterns if they don't we
can try maybe putting in just regular
glowstone lamps and I think those will
allow spawns oh yeah we got one we got
one finally oh that's awesome I made a
little spawning platform outside of the
thing here oh don't tell me I ain't an
apple are you kidding me just I pressed
right click I didn't hold it at all uh
yeah just a little tiny spawning
platform all these blocks here so that
when they attacked the zombie pigmen
there's a chance the zombies will spawn
out here because it's dark enough and
after a couple zombies here we actually
got a zombie villager and hopefully he
turns into a clerk so I can get rid of
some of this junk here no we got a
librarian we didn't get a cleric
like it takes a long time to get a
zombie to spawn after yet a zombie
villager is even more rare I just had an
idea to speed things up you can have
them
I want a cleric man guys useless to me
all right so he should be a zombie
villager again yes oh that's right he's
mad at me why are you mad at me I've
never done anything wrong you don't be
like that it would do that and hopefully
we get a cleric this time I didn't just
keep reroll in him and I ate the Apple
again are you kidding I clicked it I
clicked it I didn't hold the button why
does it keep making me eat the second
Apple nope got a Fletcher this time
still no cleric out apples out of
weakness potions I'll try this again
some other day yes because this is
taking forever let's go do something
else
yes let's check out how these lamps work
or they like glowstone or do they
function like a solid block do you put a
torch on it no you can't can you pass a
redstone signal through it no you can't
okay so it's like glowstone which means
stuff probably doesn't spawn on it let's
see we want fire resistant potions you
have to click in just the right spot now
the stair collision thing is weird oh
that's not in the right chest
it's over here oh there we go you get
some fire resistant potions now we're
going to go try get some some rabbits
some bunnies for our base we found some
last episode just by chance and I got a
portal out there now so let's see if we
can bring them home oops
that's exactly what the fire resistant
potions are for just to get them through
that so it's out this way
this isn't annoying at all oh man come
on stop there we go
also a lot of you seem to really like
the room I design last episode which is
really cool
glad you guys like it yeah I think it
turned out pretty good so as as I
collect more of these blocks I might try
to do something on a bigger scale with
them out where I dug that hole at the
Guardian farm and try decorate that make
it look nicer you guys said that these
change color to these ones depending on
what time of day it is I don't see
anything happening are you trolling me a
lot of people said though it must be
true
alright this is probably a bad path but
we're gonna try guide them down here
yeah might not work out too well and
it's not very far it's just about 100
blocks or so off the tunnel there should
bridespeople alright let's go let's go
let's go so I tried today on creative
also to to see if I could get one of
those evil bunnies there's like a 1 in
1,000 chance of them spawning apparently
I spawned like 2000 bunnies in and I
didn't get one I know there's a command
you could do to do it but I wanted to
try get it from a spawn egg and I just
couldn't get one so they are extremely
rare hey you want this you just like
froze oh that guy up there is coming to
see you too let's see
hey mmm
carrots whoa okay easy now easy
you want some carrots can I lead them
down lead a wild rabbit is it gonna let
me have to be tamed
apparently they run away like ocelots is
what I heard oh you can oh that's
awesome by the ears so cruel I just want
to get to oh I thought you broke off
it's confusing that there's two exactly
the same here did I get it no come on
come on don't run away don't run away
and then they'll just like randomly jump
right in your face
it's so funny alright guys let's go
let's go let's go let's go they're gonna
die in the portal I know it already
calling it already see what happens so
do I lose the leads when that happens -
I've never cuz I think I had 15 right
and now they're just gone
think I had 15 other there okay
come on guys very dangerous here very
dangerous can you fit oh look at this oh
yeah very cool okay they have gotten to
places they shouldn't be so I think I'm
just going to tame them cuz I have no
way of getting them out of here
that's the portal right there but we're
on the wrong side of it no no no don't
run let's get the hearts okay this guy
is what was that oh no really how did he
die oh man where'd the other one go I
thought he was tamed supposed to follow
me hey hey hey guy
are you not my friend here we go guy
come on through the fire in the flames
oh no my war mine wore off I think he's
still good
hopefully guy you can do it I believe in
you
okay maybe get the delete break I think
the lead broke alright I might have to
go rescue him guy is he trapped in here
I don't see him this portal is very
dangerous
Jesus gone did he swim up maybe what on
earth we just saw him and he's gone
he still had the particle effects I saw
them you should have been fine let's say
just wore off huh all right let's go
ahead two more rabbits okay how about we
refresh right away this time before we
go yay come on guys
yes oh they did it yes finally oops
oh I n I unhooked them stop with the
clicking that's right
come on so I'm gonna put these guys
uh-oh
don't tell me he died dude get out of
there yet
yeah get oh he's dying oh man let's just
do that for right now that was a close
one we almost lost them again all right
cool
so we're gonna put them out over here
the new area that we built oh man we got
bunnies we got buddies oh so cool I'm
just gonna lock them in here for now all
right well I'm having a bit of trouble
with taming these guys I thought I could
just give them carrots and they would be
mine and happy but I think there's a
process to it they have to do the slow
hop towards you thing that's it when
they get the smoke particles I see what
about you will you do it why are you
what are you doing to that fence gate
crazy rabbit I don't know what's up with
this guy
I think he wants out what if we open the
door what does he do I think you just
try to escape Garret mmm tear it that's
right oh he's doing it he's doing it all
he backed up at the last second get here
he comes again
it's got to be patient it's like an
ocelot man Oh Andy got the smoke
particles so now they should both be
tamed right
are you both tamed come on guys you're
killing me
make it the babies this is it this is it
come on brown bunny the white one is
tamed he's teleporting to me okay he's
not taking any more I think that means
he's mine Oh Oh finally yes oh it's a
baby only one I thought you were Bunny's
alright everyone so that's gonna do it
for today's episode but I do have a
comment picked out as usual this one
says a etho you say you read a lot of
comments so do you like reading books as
well and if so what's your favorite book
if you have one keep up the good work by
the way um so I don't know the name of
my favorite book but it was some
survival based sci-fi book I don't know
it is a long long time ago is this a
short like a hundred page book or
something where these kids are or sent
off by their school to some planets and
they ended up like turning into savages
and fighting each other it's not Lord of
the Flies or anything it was something
else I was a pretty good book though I I
like reading books but I don't do it
like at all like I've read May
maybe 10 to 20 books in my life that's
it I do really enjoy them but I enjoy
playing video games way more way more
than watching TV or anything else like
that so that is what I do
we're Zenith which one is Zenith oh
we're dizzyness go oh there we go who
had me worried there for a second so
yeah I I know there's thousands of great
books I would probably enjoy out there
but there are thousands of great video
games
I haven't played either so I I think I
prefer video games to me they're the
ideal form of entertainment and so
that's what I like to do but thanks for
the comment just a heads-up to everyone
I am going to be very busy this next
about a week or so I'm trying to record
a bunch of episodes ahead of time here
hopefully they'll help fill in the gaps
there might be a day or two missing
currently as I'm recording this there's
three days missing hopefully I can get
it down to at least two so if I don't
upload anything for a while it's just a
little bit out of my control hopefully I
get back to schedule soon though but
thank you for watching hope you enjoy
and I'll see you in the next one bye bye
you