[Music]
so
i had this idea i was
i was by the zombie pigman farm the gold
farm i was like
i wonder how well this thing works i
should try it out
how many zombie pigmen can i spawn
because i i figured
i'd probably be working on it today
you're good i almost hit you i'm sorry
i didn't mean it um i was planning on
working on
the gold farm today for the episodes i
kind of wanted to know
like is it going to work well is it kind
of a bad idea because it's an
experimental
and so i went up and i spawned a bunch
of zombie pigmen
and when i went to go check i
came in the nether i was climbing the
ladder and
it's a it's a big ladder so i was like
i'm gonna throw an ender pearl up and
make it go really quick
and i threw the ender pearl straight up
and
bam right into a zombie pigman
and it was like throwing a
rock at a hornet's nest the swarm of
zombie
pigmen that came at me
was unreal and now i'm pretty sure
we have to fight like some kind of war
here
to
to make this work the good news
oh my boots survive oh oh i picked them
up good
that's the main thing i want whenever i
die i want my boots back that's like my
best item i carry with me always
okay there's a few gold around
um so this should be fun
they should be mad at me still
oh yeah they're still mad
the good news good news bad news
uh it seems to spawn quite a few mobs
bad news
like oh yeah there's lots up there okay
so that's kind of good the bad news
though is we gotta
deal with them all now see there's more
stuff
up there
how
how's this gonna go
let's go to the very top
[Music]
and take him
no you don't great
they don't forget when you make them mad
they don't forget they stay mad
[Music]
okay maybe we'll go down actually
because there's some stuff here there's
lots of gold on the ground this this is
good
okay we got our pick
and you eat that
okay
man it looks like the farm's gonna work
good though so we're gonna go ahead with
it today i think
uh i'm in 1.6.4
and let me ask you guys this how would
you go about
exploring a 2000 by 2000 area in the
nether
oh there's a bow enchanted bow
[Music]
i wonder if that's any good i can't
remember what i had on me oh
darn it um
because i had to go all around my nether
to lower all the fortresses in 1.6.4
so that they'll create um the proper
file
and save it in my world oh look at my
sword
um if i didn't do that i just upgraded
straight to the snapshots
uh it'd be like losing all my fortresses
oh oh no no no
no no no no we're not doing this again
no oh i hit a block
darn it bounced off
oh i'm not even healing how pathetic
ron you stupid guy
can hardly wait till i get the sprinky
okay i think oh
he tried to get me but he couldn't i
think
uh i got a control of this though
um so i'll deal with this and i'll be
right back
i'm gonna kill the rest of the guys
okay i think i got them all but i'm a
little nervous being up here i
think i think i'm gonna watch my back
for just a bit until
things cool down i don't trust any of
them
um but yeah to answer the question
well it wasn't really a question it was
it yeah it was a question i asked you
guys
how would you explore 2000 by 2000
nether
that is a lot of space by the way i was
i didn't think it was going to take me a
long time but oh
man over an hour like two hours
with speed potions so the way i
did it i thought hey
don't i just go to the top of the nether
and
we got a nice perfect flat ground to
walk on
and i just ran and i ran in total i had
to walk like twenty thousand blocks to
load the 2000 by 2000
so it's it's a ton of uh kind of running
around
and basically basically the way i did it
i
i did a perfect uh perimeter around
the nether here i um
first of all i went to zero on x
and z then i went like uh
every 250 blocks i would run a line
from negative 1000 to one thousand zed
and then i'd move over 250 more blocks
on x and
run another 2 000 blocks and then 250
more 2000 more
and just did like a grid pattern
and i would stop at a thousand for each
of them so
my nether should be safe from
upgrading to the snapshot we're going to
check it out though in just a sec i'm
going to try to find
a fortress and see if we can get wither
skeletons spawning in that
and if they do then i'm going to upgrade
and then we'll see if
we still have them spawning and if not i
don't know what to do
because i really don't want to explore
it all again
i wanted to stop by the village here too
just to make sure this gets saved
properly when i
upgrade because i'm going to upgrade
this episode i think
uh holy smokes
they're doing that group thing they're
not i think they're looking at somebody
in the group
[Music]
huh hmm are they even gonna go after
which guy are they looking at
they're like hugging this guy here in
the middle
all right anyway uh let's go find a
fortress
okay so i think we're gonna use this
fortress here this is the very first
fortress i
visited in my world
and good news we got skeletons with our
skeletons even
so this is definitely spawning fortress
mobs we're looking for either
the skeleton guys or magma cubes or
blazes
but this is 1.64 so there's no surprise
they're spawning still
it's after we upgrade oh
there was another one uh that i'm
worried about so i got this beautiful
room here to see if something spawns
got a magma cube back there i'm going to
leave this area
update and then come back
and see if we have any fortress specific
spawning mobs to make sure it's it's
saved properly so
i'm gonna create a backup as well just
in case there's problems
so this is it we're upgrading to the
snapshot at this moment
be right back no no no no no
[Music]
get out of here all right guys so the
deed is done
we are in the 13 w38a snapshot
for 1.7 and it looks a lot different i
can tell already like uh
new rendering code came out with this
there's mint mapping now and a few other
um interesting interesting things
there's oh how do you say anastropic
filtering and you can change your render
distance to
more than it used to be let's try 16. i
can tell though it's like
darker in the background it seems um
but overall the new rendering is
actually pretty good
i find stuff looks a lot smoother and
also i think colors are more vibrant
with it
um but some stuff in the background
looks a little messed up
uh this is this is going to be
interesting though because i
i did use the 1.7 snapshot for a while
and i think
just the way that all worked out i might
have
oh good there's please i
i thought i might have went to the
nether jeering
use of it and somehow saved that in
with my world and i thought i was gonna
mess things up maybe
for this close fortress anyway uh the
reason
why you have to go and explore
everything again is because
uh fortresses and like which farms and
that kind of stuff
was determined by the seed
and that since they updated terrain
generation
structures were appearing in different
places with the new generation
so um which farm might not be where it
was before it might be in a new place
that you don't know so they fixed that
or created a fix for it by actually
saving it to file
and by going to that area it saves it to
file
so that when you update then it it's got
information that that's where it's
supposed to be instead of
where it figures it out when it
generates the seed i gotta figure out
how to get back here now
anyway we are in the snapshots
i have a nice gas ball over there um
i think we're gonna get working on the
the gold farm though so i gotta go get a
bunch of materials together
and i might do a time lapse of it i'm
not sure
look at the tracks like uh there's a
line there you can see it
the ones further back are dark and
as you move that that darkness creeps
back
um so yeah definitely some interesting
rendering
with the snapshot and of course there's
these
super secret settings which
change uh uh they change
filters and stuff which is
or not filters shaders this is a shaders
option
i think uh oh i never even noticed this
look at the
the hot bar the enchanted items that's
pretty wild
i think mojang are experimenting to see
if people have problems loading the
shaders and if it works out okay then
they'll probably
create some kind of support for them
i could get used to this all right
i'll be right back this was really cool
actually this is the inverted uh
was this inverted color shader so purple
becomes green and yellow becomes blue
it looks pretty nice actually
i like that
well i've been getting the stuff
together and crafting like a madman here
this chest here
this is our project chest so we're going
to be building the gold farm
that is a lot of stuff i've been saving
for a while to do this
there's not enough redstone here either
by the way but i have an idea of where i
could get some more
if we if we made it that far today who
knows how long this is going to take me
uh but we're going to try to as much as
we can
and this is 12 stacks of pistons that's
not quite enough but again
i got the iron if we get more redstone i
can make more pistons
if there's a shortage um so i'm going to
get to that pretty quick
i wanted to show you something though i
i was all excited about the snapshots
like
i wonder if my maps are connected here
because that was a new feature with the
snapshot the maps connect when they're
in an item frame
but they're not there at all
which has me confused and
curious so we're gonna check this out
and somehow all my towels ended up on
one side
why is there none over there i don't
understand that either that's another
puzzle
oh look at this you can see my icon
the white dots but the map is not
rendering
wow
oh that looks so much better
yeah that gives me that gives me
encouragement i want to finish my uh
my mapping project now i wasn't too
excited about before because it didn't
look that great
but now that's awesome
and apparently i think they render
pretty good too like they're not too
processor intensive
oh that looks so much better
oh i want to see the whole board done
now that is really cool
i like that okay so we'll have to get to
that sometime soon i'm liking the new
snapshot
i find it runs very smoothly too like
they made so many code
optima optimizations with the snapshot
and i can tell things are so smooth with
it
so if you guys have like frame rate
troubles when you update uh you'll
probably find the game runs a little
better for you
um but here i go
i don't know how long it's going to take
maybe i should do this in steps maybe i
should do all the pistons first and then
redstone then string i don't know how
big of a trouble the gas are going to
give me either
i might have to build a wall if i'm
losing too much stuff
but we'll see um
and i don't know i kind of wanted to do
a time
time lapse of me building this but the
nether might be too dark
to really get much out of it like
if things are moving quick and it's dark
and gloomy
uh it's hard for your eyes to focus so
i might just skip it but we'll see we'll
see how this goes
um let's head on up
i'm scared doing this now because i hit
a pigment before
uh but yeah this is the pattern i need
to copy we got
pistons running all along there's string
above those
there's redstone up here i think all the
blocks like the slabs are in place i
just have to put the other stuff
there so um
once i get into the groove of it it'll
probably go pretty quick maybe we'll
just try to
aside here oh this is good actually i
have this blocking in this place off of
and the speed 2 beacon is going to come
in handy for sure
because i can move quick while shifting
yeah i think the way to do this do the
pistons first
um then the redstone then the string
probably
and the trip wires because once once you
do this
where it pushes then it's it's going to
be tough
uh it's actually really quiet i'm on
hard yeah okay
cool so i will see you guys in a while
um until i get bored of this anyway
i'll either finish or get bored or run
out of time we'll see what happens first
um so i'll be back in a bit and then
we'll try to test this out and see
how much gold we can get this is not
like like once i get this done this
isn't the end of the gold farm i need to
make a healing chamber
and i might want to make some way of
transporting the gold
up above the bedrock so i can actually
see
how much gold is producing while i'm up
there because i'm completely blind
when i'm on top of the nether i don't
know what's gonna what's going on with
the system
oh i'm missing slabs
hmm okay so i didn't quite finish i
forgot put slabs there
on this side and probably all the way
down
so just a little update for you guys
things are going very well with the
build i'm in the middle of it still
but uh i decided to do
redstone first because the pistons were
going to be in the way if i did those
first
but then i did like three quarters of it
and ran out of redstone so i'm here
collecting
more this is my secret backup plan
in case i ran out this is my
unloaded chunk detector thing that i set
up a while ago
never ended up doing anything with it
yet
i might fix this in the future let's
actually leave this stuff
um but for now we're in desperate need
of redstone so i'm going to take this
and i'll leave the repeater zone in case
we ever want to repair it
this will give us more than enough to
finish because there's over a thousand
down here
and i guess
you know i've been breaking this stuff
for a while i didn't even get four
stacks yet
man um well i guess i'll collect more
and i'll
i'll get back to it
i did it i finished the whole thing i
can't believe it i did not think i was
going to do that today
um all the pistons all the redstone all
the screwing all that
tripwires everything it's all together
i gotta get a stinkin wall on this thing
though because
i got shot at by jazz so many times
and if the fireballs hits they
break a lot of stuff so
yeah i think i just saw a pigment fall
from it um
okay you'll notice something though like
from
from that height down they're gonna hit
the ground and they won't die from that
fall so we're gonna test this
now and just see what happens but like a
lot of these guys aren't actually gonna
die until we set up a proper killing
system for it
and i kind of think i might go for a
suffocation
thing uh just so they don't have to fall
24 blocks
[Music]
there's a bunch of them around but
they're like stuck in these little caves
i think
um and there are some refinements i need
to make to it like
i didn't i didn't protect the top so
some can spawn on the top still
i'll have to go through and fix that
might add some lighting
in the walls like i said
but let's go up this will be our first
official working test
usually i come up at a better spot
this will go here that works okay so to
test this thing
again uh the way we do that we gotta
climb this
ladder and notice
the e you see my mouse cursor the e here
that's entities
uh the first number is how many are
being rendered in our screen region
second number is how many are total
within the loaded area
so we have 66
total loaded most of those are probably
mobs
but then as we get higher they're going
to start despawning
because if they're over 128 blocks away
from us
they are going to
despawn pretty quick and
90. the thing is i've also noticed as i
get higher here it seems like
the number of entities increases
like almost like the maximum number
allowed
or the number of mobs possible increases
the higher i get here
because i thought it would go over a
hundred there
we get higher higher higher and now
we're at that sweet spot where
it's just the level i want they're
spawning really quick and then they're
despawning really quick so um
see we're at 246 think we can go down a
bit
i don't know what the the best height is
yet
but that's kind of why i want a
way of sending the gold up here so we
can actually see
how quickly it's running because at the
moment i have no clue i think this is
about the height we want though
and i'm just going to hang out here for
a little bit then we'll go down and
check out
how much gold is on the ground and if
there's
um just to see what happens here i guess
i don't know exactly how well this is
going to work again this is a
experimental gold farm
i guess we can probably go down
um and if you're wondering why i didn't
just make a giant portal
uh gold farm of some sort well
they didn't exist when i started this it
those just
came out and i think those actually got
nerfed so
maybe it's a good thing i didn't do that
um
okay so i'm gonna go back into the
nether from
from beneath again and we'll see just
what happens
okay we're going through here i don't
know really what kind of results i
i want or what i expect from this most
of them
most of the guys aren't even gonna die
from from this because they're not
falling far enough
um in fact even if i just got like
five golden nuggets that would be pretty
promising that's
the way it's set up right now
we gotta make a few changes to it um
okay let's look around there's one
some guys down here oh
two three so these spots they're falling
far enough where they'll die
i think i see one wandering around up
there actually
all the gas are gone too because we went
out of the range
there's another one uh that's nice
didn't hear again um that was really
getting on my nerves the longer you stay
in one spot in the nether the more gas
you'll get because they they take a long
time to spawn
and they don't despawn easily
that's promising one two three four
i think this thing's gonna run really
well if i
if i fix things up there's actually a
few here too
yeah i'm pretty happy with that
so it's not much yet but
okay that looks like they got the
pistons jammed
this design might have a few issues
actually
let's go up here
[Music]
yeah they're getting stuck on this stuff
oh i didn't put redstone here
bye-bye he found the one spot
with no redstone
yeah and there's a bunch of guys at the
top oh wait there's
i just saw a guy over there
no no no ah
okay well there's a few spots they're
spawning up there not falling so i'll
have to get rid of those
and i gotta clear a little bit more of
this netherrack too
like you can see there's a guy up there
that's that's wasting space where they
can spawn and not die
the walls on probably get some lights in
here lots of guys at the top
another one over there yeah i'm pretty
happy with that result
considering like we were only up there
for
less than a minute at the right height
so that was
pretty good to get like 11 nuggets from
that
too bad not too bad
all right well i'm gonna get the comment
ready for our
question and i will probably call it an
end for today
oh yeah by the way check this out this
is crazy after
after building all that just how much
redstone i had at the very end
eight pieces and four pistons is what we
ended up with
that is unbelievable if one or two more
gas balls would have came my way
would not have had enough to finish i
don't think or it would have been a real
pain to get more
um so that was that's crazy worked out
great
um oh there was there was actually a lot
of things i wanted to do when i update
to the snapshot
we'll probably do some snapshot related
stuff
next episode i kind of wanted to get a
lot done on that whole firm today too
let's go outside though for a sec
i think it just turned night
according to my bedtime song so we'll go
sleep for a second
very excited for the snapshot i still
haven't tried the fishing
haven't caught any of the new fish i
haven't tried brewing the
new potion haven't uh
oh there's a lot of things i wanted to
do
um next episode i'm thinking
[Music]
we might make a flower farm of some sort
uh but let's just make sure we can get
the new flowers over here
such a mess around here oh look at this
guy you blend in so nice with that tree
i didn't even see him
okay we got poppies instead of roses now
we got the yellow flowers
poppies and yellow uh-oh maybe we can't
hit them here
poppy's in yellow maybe wrong bile
are they biome specific
i am in the snapshot yeah hmm
tell you what let's go over to well i
don't think the swamp would get better
stuff
oh it does look at this we got the blue
flowers i love these
blue orchid awesome
i always wanted a blue flower in
minecraft like
if we could only have one that's the
color i wanted so that is awesome
i do really want to check something for
this episode too that fishing pole
is it in here
fishing pole where what did i do with
that
not there did i leave at the fishing
shack
let's go to the fishing shack
um man where did i
put that maybe it's in this chest
ah it is okay uh it does have the year
two so i got the leader two back once i
updated it
because it had unbreaking three last
last episode
that's cool okay so
uh here is the question
or comment for today says etho what is
your favorite slash
best minecraft experience
uh i'm going to say uh there was this
crazy absolutely crazy game of cluster
chunk
we played a long time ago it was like me
uh seth bling 3-2
unhost and uh
it looked like it shook there and
a few other people too and
the we did random teams that game and
actually the way it worked out
a lot of the veterans were on one team
and then me and like these
four or five new guys oh you can see the
fish go to it
i saw that uh we're on the other team
and i remember i was like this is really
tough for me because
i'm not very good at delegating we're
leading a team
so uh i kind of sucked it up
and and gave everybody a job and
tried to work out the game but anyway
the game went on
uh we were sort of at a disadvantage for
the beginning
there's footage of this too if you want
to see it i might link it but
uh towards the end things got really
crazy
where we lost our bed once you lose your
bed if you die you're out of the game
and we lost our bed
and a bunch of us were dying and then i
i went over to their side and i
managed to blow up their bed it was
cased in obsidian
and then they started
getting picked off one by one and it
worked out where it was just like me and
three two
left in the game with good gear on both
of us
and we had this crazy fight i
i lost it and oh
and they thought the game was over but
since i took out their bed i had my
spawn set and it worked out
to where 3 2 didn't have his spawn set
anywhere and i did but i had no gear and
he had good gear
um and
i'm rambling anyway if you want to watch
the game watch the game
but uh the way it worked out
um he was running to get my bed and if
he got it i would have been out
and he was at like this lower level i
didn't realize he could get across on it
and i was at this upper level
like 40 50 blocks above him
and i saw him running towards my bed and
i freaked out and i ran towards
like where he was going and as he
stopped like halfway on the bridge
and i jumped down and punched him off
knocked him off um there's like this one
once in a lifetime clutch moment in
in minecraft it was pretty awesome i'll
try to link it if i remember
and you can watch it if you want but
yeah it was a fun game good memories of
that game uh
also when i posted my first lp episode i
was pretty happy when i
when the comments were f weren't full of
you suck or
that kind of stuff i was worried uh it
was gonna get rejected pretty hard
so it didn't it went on and we're here
today still
that was another good experience
okay so that's all for today thanks for
watching everybody
i hope you have a great day take care
[Music]
bye