[Music]
greetings everybody this is etho
welcome back let's play some minecraft
so i do apologize it's been a little bit
of time between
uh now and my last lp episode i've been
a little bit busy
but hopefully i'll have more free time
coming up and i'll be able to get back
into
the routine of doing one of these every
two or three days
again i know a lot of kids are finishing
school now too so
congratulations to all of you that are
and those of you that are graduating
and hopefully your tests went well
and you probably have a few to do yet
actually
i'm not really sure it's different in
every location
um i have added this sandstone
rim all the way around the tree farm now
so that helps to complete the look a
little bit i had to mine out
all the way around and that's a lot of
blocks
i've also kind of worked over here i put
a little staircase here not
nothing nothing much i
played around with the lighting here
don't know if i'm going to keep this
these are these are glowing pumpkins
with wooden pressure plates on
i'll probably take that out i don't like
how it's sticking out like that maybe
try
rigging some lighting along the side
here or in the ceiling
instead but it's always good to
experiment with different things
uh this walkway seems to go over
the rail track not not too bad
i'll have to make this walkway kind of
curve to the left here because otherwise
it will go straight into this so need
some kind of wall here
and actually it might it might go to the
left and then go to the right also
because i wanted to have
some stuff over there when this is a
little bit more complete
but anyway what i would like to do to
start off with today
is work on the sheep farm some um
the back the back of the sheep farm i've
had a plan there's a reason i haven't
murdered these guys yet
i'm keeping them around
as you know couple sheep died here i
wanna have a way
of renewing the sheep if they die
so i'm gonna how should we do this i
wanna have two sheep at the back here
uh behind glass
maybe we'll go back at least one more
block
we'll have them have one like right here
and one more right here
and they should be able to breed through
the one block distance there
and then we have to hook up a mine cart
to
pick up the sheep bring them to the
middle here and when we
hop in the minecart or break it then
we'll have another sheep
running around here which we can move
wherever we need them
so that's the plan
so yeah glass glass display will
probably be right
there it's a good height for it
how's this gonna work
also with the water coming down we can't
have any tracks
at this level so i might have to raise
this one
well i'll think about it a little bit
and maybe get started and then
we'll continue on
now we're gonna try something here i
don't really expect this to work but if
it does
awesome because it'll be very simple i
got two sheep over here
i i leered them with the wheat uh we can
breed them if we leave this open
i believe yep a little bit difficult too
and they should pop okay so he pops into
that one
every time i breed them they'll pop into
the little sheep have this are the exact
same size as the
the big guys though so it's not like
they can fit through the one block
high adapter there's still a block and a
half or whatever it is
i believe it's a block and a half and
um we'll just put i'm just going to try
this
put that there get some more light put a
block back there
rail
um well let's make it let's make it
point the correct way at least
so if i put a minecart here i want to
see if it'll pick up the sheep from the
left here or if it's
just it'll or if it'll be different
every time or what's going to happen
i picked up the little guy that's that's
pretty cool
sorry guy
i might try this a few more times
because if that can work consistently
that would be a really easy way of doing
this
okay um maybe we'll go do something
else while i wait for them to breed
again
yeah i'm gonna work on this uh in
between while we wait for them to breed
a few more times
um i said i want to make this pop up
when the water
flows down but the issue is i can't just
simply hook this button up to
up to the redstone here because if i do
that when i press it
it'll come up but it'll go down in one
second so
by the time the water hits the ground
it's already down and does nothing
we need it to stay up for a long a long
time until all the water disappears
which will be at least i think it's at
least 10 seconds
15 seconds not an easy thing to do
i need a pulse extender for that the
issue
though is our delay
system is all the way at the other end
here
so what i could do is make another one
at this side
but big waste of repeaters
um and as the power goes through that
it's not a pulse extender it's just
a long delay on the pulse it still would
only be one second
um i would like i
could possibly do a t flip-flop i'll
have to think about it
for a bit but when i'm
what i kind of want to try to do is hook
up a bud switch here that will detect
when the water
uh disappears and then cause that to
switch back
so i'll just mess around with it a bit
see what happens
so i thought about it for a little bit
here and i believe
the easiest and simplest thing we could
do is hook this up to
an rs or latch with the little delay
we'll put it over here
somewhere and then
and then we'll also run
this wire here down to the other side of
the rsnor latch to shut it off
but we'll have to add a few seconds
delay not
not too much just enough to give the
water time to
dissipate after after these come back
down
and yeah that's all we really need
okay they are there look at that sheep
no sheep sheep no sheep i thought they
had died
i was worried uh might be breeding time
how long did it take me to think i went
to the bathroom too
nope not ready
all right so i've been doing the wiring
that's almost done uh let's
let's try this reading out again though
a couple more times make sure it works i
logged out of my world and logged back
in just to see if that would have an
effect this time
yeah i gotta i gotta raise these guys up
one more block
make it easier oh yeah let's take this
out too
little sheep is oh
see i always thought they uh came out of
the same one every time
based on the coordinates
i'll have to watch it again maybe it's
whoever you fed first
got the little guy again great
good job okay i'm gonna work on that
some more we'll probably do this at
least one more time
maybe i'll try nudging them next time
too see if changing their position
affects things
and that will lead you to the hole
right on okay let's try out these
buttons again i got them wired now
first test here this one is for the
manual reset and this one is for the
water system
the auto auto reset thing
and it goes up here and then goes down
the delays at the back and then it comes
back
and while that's going on it's also
going to go down here now
and that connects to these repeaters
and built into this is an rsnor latch
right here so it switches it
switches this to on and stays on
and then it comes
well we gotta go up here
comes back down this line with the delay
goes to here and i just have it
branching down
a little bit sloppy but it it'll work
to here than there
down and two repeaters i'm guessing it's
not going to be long enough and if
if it's not i'll i'll redo that wiring
voice crack whoa redo that wiring and
make it longer but we'll see how this
goes
got a little protector here
i'm yeah it's it's not gonna be long
enough oh pretty close
pretty close
um that might work let's try this again
and i think our sheep are ready for
another go
yeah that that'll work um
let's try the manual resets
excellent
you know what we can actually put some
repeaters up here too
so we'll put one here that'll make it
three
and that'll definitely be long enough
now for the water
let's go try this one more time if it
works again
i'll probably finalize this
okay so we'll get our wheat
so we picked up the little guy two times
in a row
oh yeah i was supposed to nudge him oh
well so we went on the right side this
this time and again we got the little
one
excellent so
i'll probably raise them one block
um
okay well let's i'll get my supplies
together and then we'll do this
um i'll i'll clean up that front there
too
and then we can try it without the guard
and yeah
alrighty so i got some supplies together
here and i've been working at
cleaning up this front part i did the
fence around the leaf lights type thing
up here too
like we have down here
i think we'll keep it
definitely a better way of lighting than
torches
how dark does that make it eight
yeah that's good um did it over here
man i'm getting lag spikes it's raining
um
oh i hate to do it but
well
close your eyes just close them
we're done with them though
um cover this up just for now i want to
try this water thing out
oh what
i must have cut a wire somewhere darn
ah
all right give me a moment i'll check
this over again
found it it's uh this block here is
cutting the wire
so we'll just we'll make it a upside
down half slab
there should do the trick
cover it up again try it again
so i got kate story the other day on
steam
i saw it was on sale it uh it's been out
for
i think a year or so i've always been
tempted to get it and
when i saw it on sale i definitely
decided to
even though i've i've played it quite a
few times in the past
i was in the mood to play it again and
on the on the steam one it has better
graphics
uh new sounds
and i think extra challenges too i
haven't played it too much yet
this is working excellent
that part's done let's go to the back
now
but yeah really enjoying playing cave
story again
i finished it in the past but i never
got the hardest like it's one of those
games that has multiple
endings and i never never beat it the
hardest way
so to feel like i completed it i think
i think i have to do it
do the final final ending on it
um with these guys we're gonna
maybe moving forward one more block
again
and that sort of want to try this
i don't know we'll put them here we'll
put them on top of these
stone slabs
make sure they don't escape
if i do this will you move
that um i don't think he wants to move
there we go
get him in like that we'll put that
there for now
then you can't see their face so
hard to know what to do
well let's try this we'll put stone
brook stairs in front
and then we can remove that
he likes it more okay uh we will have to
move this forward what i want to do
is put a dispenser back there
so that when dispensers can shoot out
minecarts we can just
press a button above let's make it wood
get that press a button above
and minecart will instantly shoot out
and instantly
pick up the baby sheep
yeah okay we'll move this one
that that seal him up
how's that looking
we could put these
then maybe
nope um
wait a sec
yeah like that oh he can get out he can
get out
now
oh no
no i didn't mean it get back in there
uh he he fought for a little bit but i
gave him a treat and he was happy
right yeah so
i do want to try something though i
think it'll look better with
upside down stairs i knew you were going
to do that
maybe
gotta do it with him too and get rid of
this
no no no no no no no no no no no more
treats
no more
yes that's that's kind of cool uh
do that let's try this out again
baby in the right we'll put the mine
cart in the dispenser
oh yeah well obviously that's not going
to work right now
oh no no
we just finalized it everything was good
hmm i wonder they must have just got
moved and it wasn't positioned right
anymore or something
i should have tried nudging them
all right i'll get them back we might
still use it this way i don't
i don't expect to use this very much if
ever
i also want to set up a couple chests
for extra stuff like i want some weed
around here
some shears maybe some health potions in
case i gotta heal these guys some dyes
etc etc don't wander too far
so we'll put one let's get this iron
i think i might have covered up some of
it i'll put one of the chests over here
um i want some lighting behind it
put that there
with a half slab and
here
hmm looks a little strange
that looks better with the chests there
so that's what we'll do instead
uh we'll put lighting underneath though
like that
i got the sheep back again he it's
pretty stubborn
i think if i position him right it'll
always work
but we'll we'll see
and then we will do this
it's annoying having one extra torch
constantly
entering your inventory over and over
again
yeah yeah that's good um maybe get that
back
and
oh no this has to be stone
and we will try stairs here
and this will be about done
all right
um yeah this almost looks too steep
try full blocks instead
messed with it a bit more came up with
this
i think it looks a little bit better uh
i don't know what happened to the sheep
here he just mysteriously disappeared
so oh well
uh when this guy grows up i'm gonna try
it out again see if we can get them
positioned properly so it always works
and there's a cobble block there that i
missed
it's gonna drive me crazy so
i could probably fix that
yeah that's no problem
but other than that this sheep farm is
done
for the most part we
will have to wait till 1.3 to get ice
for the collection system but this is
all we can do
until then and of course this will be
covered up and whatnot but
on to new projects i do plan on using
this a fair bit though
it's not just for show or for the for
the fun of it
uh it's going to be useful
that looks pretty good okay on to
something else
actually you know what i just added the
footage and it's longer than i thought
it was going to be
so that's the end for today
until next time we will continue on
uh it's nice to complete well kind of
complete another project until 1.3
is what we'll have to wait for and i
noticed a few mistakes with
what i did here so i'm gonna fix these
two
this should come around like this
and that's not gonna work so we'll just
get rid of that
maybe we'll do that and
we'll fix these ones i changed this i
like that a lot more
also there was one block over there i
missed
don't worry i fixed it
oh the sheep grew up too
this block here is fixed don't worry um
ready to breed
yes you are good
[Music]
if we find the right position it should
work every time like it was
i would imagine
ah well i'll keep trying
i'll get it don't worry um
maybe i'll yeah i'll mess around with it
in creative and see if i can
figure out a trick to it uh but
thanks for watching everybody see you
again next time
you