then detective hello everybody this is
etho you are watching evil and we are
playing minecraft again today I have a
lot of nether quartz now I went on a big
trip got a whole bunch of it we have a
lot of it I put some here you know yeah
so we went and got a bunch of nether
quartz I said I saved the stack here so
we could do a test real quick here just
to see how much we get from fortune 3
from my previous stacks I have noticed
it's been about just over 2 crystals for
each block similar to diamonds like 2.2
or something like that but we'll try
this out and just a little bit of a
warning today guys I am really tired for
some reason it's uh I don't know what it
is I had enough sleep last night but
just so tired and it's one of those
strange tiredness issues - like it's
it's my mind feels okay like I'm perky
and and waked that way mentally but
physically my body is telling me to go
to bed right now like I I got the chills
I got my eyelids are sticking to my
eyeballs for some reason my eyes I just
want to rub them constantly even right
now I'm like squinting because it's
bugging me so much I took a nap for like
30 minutes today and I helped a bit but
I don't know I'm still really tired I
might be getting sick I'm not sure but
yeah probably going to be a quicker
episode today just more of a talky one
so we got with what is a 64 calculator
time 1 128 plus 26 is 154 divided by 64
is 2.4 on average
that sounds about right so pretty good
and I forgot to check what our level was
I think we were no I can't remember I
think we were 17 you get a lot of XP
from the nether quartz it's pretty cool
oh yes it'll probably spun around and do
stuff simple tasks around our home here
as a 3-2 message me the other day
reminding me that jukeboxes don't do
updates anymore which is pretty sad I
saw that in the patch notes but I never
have I haven't actually tried it so
let's just check that out yeah lights
never changed oh how depressing you know
what I've always wanted in Minecraft the
ability to play jukeboxes using redstone
then I could have like 12 jukebox to set
up and set up a bit like a a track
changer press a button and you get the
record you want play I think that would
be so cool but oh well so I guess this
thing's kind of broken at least the
lights are on what else what else
oh yeah the nighttime song thank you
everyone for suggesting nighttime songs
for me I had a really hard time choosing
actually get some no blocks together
we're going to do that today I think
and there were about three songs I had a
hard time choosing between and I picked
the Brahm one I figured since our
morning songs kind of class classical
music it would make sense to have a
nighttime song that is too so I picked
the Brahm and it was a lullaby I was
thinking of actually but there was also
Zelda's song of time which I was really
tempted to use and I think there's a
Zelda lullaby as well what was that
that's broken what's going on no blocks
they do this weird thing where they will
sometimes it's randomly update if you
rejoin a world because it's still night
time let's just try this make sure it
still works
due to sweets
all right that still works I'm going to
work at putting in the night time song
here I'm gonna have to try it's bigger
than this one I think so I'm going to
have to try howl outta space here
hopefully I don't hit anything
you know I dad is one of these days I'm
gonna have to set up a better tree farm
I think maybe try find a way to automate
it a little bit better cuz my wood chest
is always empty when I need when I need
it the most
these no blocks they take quite a bit
and I got none around
where else let's go and cut down every
tree in my world one day that might work
- mmm night I'm making eyes heavy me go
sleep now no no me show you
nighttime sound now I got it done here
it's it's actually about the same number
of notes as the morning song I think
this is Brahms Lullaby vegan vegan lead
is what it's called I believe big THANK
YOU to Mickey Mick tours his channel
I'll try to like in the description if I
remember although I might forget and if
so apologies but he took the time to to
lay this out for me pretty nicely it was
a little challenging to lay out here
somehow when I was laying this out like
halfway through I added in an extra note
block which just made it's terrible um
to track because I had to rearrange all
these repeaters if I arrange them in a
certain way like if I if I try to change
just one notes it's not going to work
anymore because if these note blocks are
ever touching each other like if they're
adjacent to each other they'll both get
triggered by one repeater so I had to
play around with them quite a bit here
to get them this compact and I wouldn't
worry about this kind of stuff too much
except I do run a lot of stuff hidden in
my cave and I need as much space as act
I can get for that for future projects
but yeah it's done night time song here
it is again a big THANK YOU to Mickey
oops
oh my sound is up a stupid morning song
that's not the time what is the time but
I was doing something else
ah yes I think at night time this will
invert the signal and it should just
play but let's do that again since I got
my step and I'll turn this up a little
louder
it seems quiet to me for some reason
awesome I love that so I think the two
the two songs go together very nicely
they're both pretty similar and thank
you everyone else that's ended that sent
me your song suggestions even if I don't
use them here I might use them for
something else
so don't feel like you wasted your time
and even if I don't use it other people
are going to see it to most likely so
thank you like the song of time I really
want to use that for something now
sounds pretty cool from Zelda it's kind
of a shame people don't use note blocks
as much anymore I've noticed like when
they first came out everything on
YouTube was note blocks no box no blocks
and now not too often I kind of
understand why they're pretty painful to
set up especially if you're like me and
you don't know what you're doing but
once they are set up it I don't know it
brings a smile to your face every time
you hear the song and I want to show you
guys something by the way with this new
update they did something with the
textures I think they set it up in a way
that's you can animate them now which is
really cool idea like built into texture
packs I think people could simulate
moving leaves on trees or like
glittering ores or stuff like that
which would be really cool maybe
glittering sand you know really neat
stuff like that
but there's also a bunch of bugs in this
texture pad and one of them are in the
snapshot like a bunch of textures aren't
working correctly and one of the things
is we have this lime-green on the grass
edges so if you look up at a mountain
like this this is what a mountain looked
like in Alpha yep I'm pretty sure it's
exactly the same there would be no
difference if you switch because if we
don't see the grass if we just see the
edges that's what it looked like oh yeah
actually I was kind of just walking
around here this is a really nice
mountain isn't it very cool that might
be where we did that realistic caving
thing I think but check this out we got
this cool arch goes over oh pretty cool
that's a swamp there and I saw we go
check something out I saw a dungeon in
the sand I may have found it before I'm
not sure right there let's go check that
out go for a little exploring now this
is a new one I've never been here huh
that looks like a chunk err type thing
over there where am i I kind of got lost
oh I'm pretty far out I guess negative
700 almost huh
very cool all right let's check this out
where is that I lost it where is it
there it is two two two two zombie we
got one chest got a saddle not bad
huh cool alright I'm gonna snag this
mossy and maybe have a look around here
I'm kind of curious where I am
hey guy how's it going you want you want
this you want it yeah come get it come
do it I know you want it oh man they're
so smart now look at that what the way I
don't believe that since when I guess
you must have to have more than one
chicken following you
where's that other guy you're stuck
there Hey
don't be afraid I'm not going to hurt
you technically you're gonna hurt
yourself okay come on come here I want
to see something yeah Mon here we go you
two
all right you to battle battle for the
seed come on I know you both want it
who's gonna get it unbelievable I can't
even get two to kill each other there we
go come on oh oh you're the winner
enjoy okay yeah this is where I did the
realistic caving thing maybe we'll go
check that up too today they are still
going I brought another stack of tracks
with me and I went a little further down
here let's get the
let's get some coal I guess get the
carts actually probably won't take me
all the way going there this is meant to
take me back whoo oh yeah it's gonna
send me here no oh no this is right this
is wrong Oh danger I just will probably
have to walk yeah
all right we're going to go walk so I
went further here and it goes up mid to
the ravine this is where it gets crazy
down here
very steep borders the ravine and kind
of goes along the side a couple beams
across pretty cool and then over here I
like this part there is danger area here
then I got this wall thing which I like
and I think that was about it all right
I thought of something else I want to
try here I read in the patch notes I
can't remember what what patch it was
for it might not even be the snapshots
but that you can ride a minecart
into a portal now this is still real
loud it's not too bad so I'm curious to
see exactly how that works let's give it
a go here so I didn't go far enough
let's try that again
nope we can't try to get my minecraft
gun
one second got our minecarts let's go
back this is the village by the way all
right here we go again
I'm wondering what no I'm in the portal
I'm in the portal I'm not going through
so maybe maybe I read that wrong or
maybe it doesn't actually work too bad I
was hoping there would be a way you
could just ride through a portal with a
minecart and keep going on the other
side oh no no no no not this Oh No
uh I don't have any arrows to shoot the
cards I can't believe that just happened
can I move it I can't move it I don't
have oh dang how do I get out of here
now um can't break anything
oh wait I just moved right oh dang
through with my dick um dude guys I
don't know what to do honestly can't
break this I can't break that
I'm in the nether so my water but it's
not gonna work dude what have I done
I have gravel I don't even think I can
kill myself as a thing I can't believe
this just happened okay that's on I
place the block somehow that's good
although I did that before - I'm gonna
try figure out how to get out of here
I'm not sure relog relog is the trick
that was the first thing I tried and it
worked and my mind Kurt went through I
think so maybe only if there's no entity
in the karts
although won't it just keep going on a
loop there's my pick and the cart went
through again
let's try push an empty cart in not
ourselves let's not do that again that
could be cool - oops
go through oh it does go that's awesome
and the pearls don't do anything boats
will probably go through to double-check
I was worried there Isis thinking I was
gonna have to mcedit my world or
something to get free that was really
scary boat go through oh yeah it goes
through too cool so if you go through
the portal then it's like right in the
portal or is it off to the side and it's
kind of right in the portal interesting
I tried setting up some track on both
sides and it's a little strange the
track is on the right of the portal sort
of it always comes out or it seems to
always come out on the left side of the
track that place if we move this maybe
that will work but like even if I push
it through this way you'll see it'll be
on the left side let's try this too
just to be sure
see it's well I guess it's on the right
isn't it
never mind I'd be so cool if it just
came back through the cart birth and
came back on this track if it did a loop
yeah it seems or no let's that's
opposite side right what if we have
tracked everywhere then what are you
gonna do well let's try make it point to
we'll make it point there
alright here we go again come through
come back nope
let's got to go somewhere now is it
going to be on the trackers it going to
be even further away from the portal
it's inside the portal now ah didn't
budge at all okay so you can get you can
send carts through but you can't really
get them on tracks although a piston
might do it alright guys it is common to
reading time and this is a pretty good
one hey etho I was wondering I was just
wondering in fact have you ever
considered doing a let's play on
something else
some other game perhaps I mean something
made may be out of the ordinary for you
I know you've done something on don't
starve but have you ever considered
starting a let's play for an RPG kind of
games such as Skyrim never played it or
something something else or even one of
those older games like morrowind or
something similar
I did play Harvest Moon that is
technically an RPG never played
morrowind I've been watching variety
that game recently for nostalgic
purposes but I can't help feeling you
would do a better job well maybe that's
a person uh-huh I could probably talk at
least half an hour on this first of all
why do I play so much minecraft and post
that on my channel mainly I'm going to
go ahead and say it right out the bat
here minecraft is my favorite game ever
it's my favorite game
I still love playing it even after all
this time there's I don't I just it's
really enjoyable but I'm weird like that
I can play the same game over and over
again and not get bored of it in fact
for my game preferences I tend to
attempt to keep replaying games I've
played before like I might wait three or
four years after I've played the game
but then play it again three or four
years down the line if it was game I
enjoyed and half
with it again instead of like always
playing new games oh I prefer games that
have a high level of randomization in
them or customization or freedom to do
what you want in the game I tend to hate
games that are linear there are
exceptions of course especially if
there's a strong story element - it's
like this is what bugs me about new
games in particular I want to play a
game I don't want to watch a movie you
know what I mean sometimes some games
you gotta wait like eight ten minutes
before you can even play the game and
that is just frustrating for me or
there's this long tutorial it's like I
can just randomly push buttons and
figure out what to do it's not that hard
but yeah so a lot of new games kind of
frustrate me I find I do play new games
though but I'm very picky on them now
maybe back to the question I'm going off
off topic here so yes I would play other
games on my channel uh I don't feel the
need to though I'll do it if I want to
if there's a game that stands out to me
in fact like other YouTube channels so
they are actually switching to play
minecraft a lot of them especially the
big popular ones because this is where
the popularity is this is where they get
views so youtube wise money wise if you
want to be successful play the popular
game and the popular game is minecraft
that works out good for me because this
is the game I enjoy and I this is a
successful game so and I could talk
forever on this even on that subject
like a lot of people on YouTube like
people that do it for a living I'm one
of them they feel the need to start
playing other games for the reason that
what happens if minecraft just dies then
they're out of a job if they aren't
playing other games they have to
kind of customize their fan base to them
playing other games before that happens
and I kind of share different view on
that maybe I'm wrong on this but if
Minecrafts popularity starts to dwindle
I'm sure I will be able to spot it well
in advance and you know start switching
to other games then if I feel I want to
or need to but if you're switching
prematurely like if if you want to play
other games fine that's good for you
have fun you know I have fun playing
Minecraft so that's why I'm posting my
draft but one of the problems of
switching prematurely or trying to
customize your fan base is you're
actually sort of aiding in killing
minecraft I find because you know that
that's less videos you're posting a
Minecraft Let's less people are going to
see Minecraft Let's new people are going
to start playing minecraft and it's kind
of a cycle there but that's getting
pretty deep here anyway I enjoy playing
Minecraft I'm going to keep posting
minecraft if there's a if there's
another game that appeals to me I would
play that as well oh man another topic I
could talk about I'm an independent I'm
not I'm on a roll here I'm an
independent partner on YouTube which
means I have to be a little bit more
careful to on what games I play because
if I get copyright strikes I don't have
a company I can turn to to say get rid
of these for me or well usually they
just don't get on period because they're
protected so I have to be kind of
careful in that way and there's this big
grey area where I don't know what I can
and can't play legally so yeah that's
the other thing anyway I had talked
about five ten minutes on this I'm going
to shut up so thank you for watching
guys have a good day I'm gonna go to bed
and I'm going to enjoy it my mind is
still firing though but my body my body
wants rest
you