[Music]
well well here we are again
guess what guys silverfish are gone
not here anymore
where'd they go i'll show you
we've been waiting a long time to do
this
actually i'm going the wrong way it's
down here
so i kind of redid this i got a
dropper thing for them and when they
drop through
the portals right here and that works
very well
uh then when they come through here
there's this uh one high area for them
to fit under
while i go on top and i lead them down
here
i'll probably show you how this works
eventually but
we have no silverfish left but yeah i
get them
go all the way down here it works almost
just about all of them got here which
means there's a lot of them here
so i'm excited to see what's gonna
happen
see i'm wondering what kind of hole
they're actually gonna dig if
if it's even gonna work i don't know
because if they hit a cave they're gonna
fall down and that's gonna
do weird things or if they hit a lava
pool
or anything else like that you know
strange stuff can happen
but to get this going
let's just get a few of these guys out
here
i guess we got to find them there's not
as many as i thought
just one
there's one oop
i'm having trouble finding them
all right
oh this is going to be fun
this is going to be fun i tell you
okay get up higher
oh boy
get up higher much higher and then we're
gonna drop one of these babies
oh no they're spreading come back guys
dang it okay we went up too high
let's get them to follow us again
oh that's slime he's took my spot
okay this will work
it's not as many as i would have liked
but
oh that is so cool
i wonder how long this will take to do
actually now we go back up higher
i need a better way of finding them yes
and then they'll re-enter the blocks
hmm it actually takes them a while to
re-enter doesn't it
yeah i'm gonna try awaken them again and
just see what happens
might need to bring more of them over
here
come on guys where are you at there
should be lots of them around
and i'll never be able to kill them like
this because whenever they enter a block
again
and come out their health resets so
well unless i hit them like 16 times
like i did there
come on guys
yeah i think we need more of them here
oh
i think that's the problem
all right let's try this again just see
what happens
that is pretty cool though i gotta say
hmm
yeah i'm gonna try to bring more of them
here but this is a good start
this is a really good start uh maybe
next episode or something
we'll try this again with more
well guys what's new what's going on
uh i think the only thing i've changed
since last episode i went to the nether
i did some work on the hub a little bit
just minor things and around here i
started to organize a little bit with
these chests this stuff is not
officially in place so
i'm just playing around with how all the
items fit together
in their groups um
and that's really hard to do there's so
many different items
and the thing is it's like what i gotta
do is i gotta collect one of everything
which is
really challenging actually
but yeah i'm working that out
let's go check out the end see how many
drops we get that's what we got right
now
now i have been afk for a long time so
if i don't get
at least like a stack and a half of
gunpowder
and i know that stuff is despawning or
at least i'm pretty sure
did i yeah so something's wrong
something's definitely wrong it's gotta
be
hmm i wonder what the deal is
i'm trying to think of an experiment we
could do where we could
actually time how long
the world loads when we send something
through a portal
that would be tough to do because i
think redstone
behaves weird i'm not sure
i've done it before like i've had a
redstone circuit go
after i enter a portal and it always
completes itself so i don't
i don't know if it waits for that to
finish but
i don't think we could use redstone to
time it
um what are we doing today what are we
doing i don't know
what should we do what i kind of wanted
you know that's actually i'll meet you
there one sec
so we're over here now i'm just here to
get the coordinates so we're at x
540 just writing it down and zed
about 900.
y52 just in case we need it oops
i'm thinking about running a track from
here all the way to
over here which is at x
negative 245
and zed about 600
hmm that's uh that's a little ways isn't
it that's
uh uh 300 block difference on the zed
and 200 or about 300 on
the x as well that's a ways you know
what i should do with that
that purifier thing is set up another
portal system for it so we could just
have another portal here
one over there and then it won't be all
that far to send villagers
because what i would like to do is
fix up this village since it's the
original one
in my world here where i got villagers
from
and they're all gone all of them
so
hmm i guess we could put a fence around
it
that's probably what we should do just
light it up put a fence around it
and then get the villagers here and take
it from there
okay actually we're gonna set up the
portals first but we're not actually
gonna send any villagers
uh we're gonna use zombies as test
subjects as dummies
so wait
yeah i'll just pretend they're all
villagers turn this on
oops other way
okay and
are they simmering there oh man they
move fast
you see that they just like
i'm still in 1.4.3
where the water's messed up 1.4.4 is out
i just haven't updated
i didn't realize uh mobs are so affected
by the water too though
where are they oh they're all the way
over there
wait that's the right spot okay well
anyway as they get settled there let's
just try
set up the portal so the first thing i
want to check out
i wasn't sure what the final verdict was
on this in the game
can you can you send a mob in a minecart
through portal and have them
go through and if they go through do
they stay in the minecarts
that is what we're trying to figure out
first of all
so we'll just quickly set up a portal
and then we'll send one of these dummies
through
and we'll move this later if it works
all right i'll do which one of you wants
to volunteer how about you
you know what i never did set up this
isn't fully set up i just realized
i forgot
ouch how do i
move him yeah i'm not set up for this
hmm would be so much easier if it was a
villager
what can i do here to make this work do
i have any levers
no thing is i don't even see him yeah
won't let me push him
at all oh there's another guy in there
that could be why
um i guess let's try to get a furnace
minecart going
and there should be some coal here yeah
um
how do i push this guy i have no idea
i need a power rail really to start off
with and it has to be powered
just to give him a boost
we'll get this guys don't worry we'll
get this
okay now if we get
get him to move oh there he goes yes
see what i did there and
no go through okay hmm
oh there goes my item okay well that's
good to know
um we should be able to use mine cart
still though
maybe maybe we'll see
okay so i tracked it down and to set up
a portal for
that purifier i think we got to put it
over here
pretty sure and it's not that much
farther away from this one but that's
okay uh it's far enough where we could
keep them separate if we want
i have a feeling as my world progresses
here i'm gonna have all these past
paths through the nether through the
nether like one
paths for me paths for silverfish
then other ones for villagers and
all the different things you might want
to transport
okay so it should take us to the
purifier
if i figured that right yep and if we go
through
we should go through that portal
very good okay
oh yeah by the way uh this is what i did
in the nether i got all these
installed all these little center doors
wire access doors
uh-huh yep we got the problem uh
this this is the portal for the purifier
i looked where
i need to move the villagers for that
guy's glitching out
for the the village
and has to go about right here
but it would cut through this other
tunnel i'm supposed to make for myself
so yeah we got to set some rules i think
in my world to keep things organized so
any silverfish dedicated tunnel i think
should go
like five blocks below my tunnels and
like for me and any village or tunnel
should maybe go five blocks above
any of my tunnels like them like uh
my tunnels are at y 65 i think
i think that's what it is so if we go to
y70 or so
with the villagers that should be okay
you know what's funny this pig you guys
remember this pig
he's still in the well he's been there a
long
time he's getting all soggy
so if i figured this out right uh this
should link up
where i want it to in the nether
oh let's just put the portal right here
for now i guess
we'll probably move it later
and go right there
okay let's see what happens where will
you take us
what will it be like
yeah that's this is what i just carved
out that's good
and try it go the other way
sweet
yeah that's gonna work so with
silverfish
they'll follow you as a player
so you don't need mine carts or anything
for them
uh nor could you move that many with
minecarts
but the villagers they don't like to
cooperate and there's no
like bait for them like you can't hold
out a potato and they'll follow you or
anything like that so
what we got to do is set up a track i
think
uh this portal i'm gonna align the other
way
and
um you know maybe i won't get too fancy
with this
or not today anyway
i think i'll just get a track in here
real basic track
and just get it going
nope more trouble much much more trouble
if you've ever tried linking portals
together when you have them
uh close together in the nether it is a
real pain in the butt i tell you
so i tried one here didn't work tried
one over here
tried one over here and what it comes
down to is i can't have it up this high
so if i go in it takes us where we want
it to take us
here but when we go through this one it
does not take us back
through that portal takes us to the
other one
and the main reason is because this
portal
this portal here will always be closer
than that one even if
even if that one's in the right position
like x and z
this one is closer on the y-coordinate
because it's down lower
so i'm gonna have to actually move it
down to where it was originally
oh boy so yeah
and i guess what i'll have to do is make
it go
make the villagers go uphill and still
have the tunnel up higher
would be better i think
okay let's start laying down our fence
here
so with this village i think my first
priority is just going to be getting
life back
into it so
like this fence and anything
a lot of the things i build will
probably be temporary and if we want to
expand it later we can
i don't know if i'm going to do like
i don't know what i'm doing with it
basically i just want to get life to it
because
it it was a important village in this
world and it's dead right now
which kind of sucks uh
just trying to make trying to bring
more activity to the surface of the
world i guess like last episode we did
terraforming
this episode i'm trying to revitalize a
village
and just little things like that make
the the world a better place
i guess
oh man it gets really rough over there
doesn't it
but you know what guys i think i'm gonna
have to call it quits here for today i'm
i'm getting really tired it's pretty
late here
so um let's go read the comments and
we'll call it an
end of an episode until next time
okay guys here we go etho i notice
you seem to have some interesting tool
preferences
particularly with shovels and the way
you use them for wood as well
i just noticed the particles frozen here
uh can you explain a bit about your
preferences there
and also maybe touch on different
enchantments and their usefulness
okay so the whole shovel thing uh once
the u2 efficiency for efficiency
fi five on a diamond shovel i really
can't notice the difference in speed
from from like using efficiency four or
five
axe like a diamond axe so uh the shovel
only costs one diamond
diamond axe costs three um
it doesn't take any like it still only
counts as one use on the deer ability
for the shovel does
doesn't take any extra uses so it's
cheaper and also it's more versatile
because you can use it
on soil and other things as well so it's
there's no real point to using an
axe in my opinion
although i never did like do a speed
test like a proper one
uh where i was very precise with it but
just judging from my eyes i don't notice
the difference
so that's the reason behind that um
if you let's see what what else did he
say about other enchantments
uh unbreaking is extremely useful it
makes a tool last a lot longer so
if you have an unbreaking three anything
you might want to try combine it with
efficiency something
to really get a good tool out of it
and ps wouldn't it be neat if
mojang als added a wind noise that plays
while you
your move around in a boat and builds
or quiets according to the riding speed
that would be cool
i like little pleasing noises like that
as long as it's not overbearing
like the minecart noise um yeah that
would be cool
i'd be up for that
and i guess that's about it so thanks
for watching everybody
i'll see you later
[Music]