[Music]
oh
hello how's it going
um all right all right you guys caught
me i'm on a break
i'm taking it easy but you know what
sometimes in life guys sometimes after a
long
hard day at work or at school it's it's
nice to take it easy just
sit back relax get your snacks
maybe maybe watch some ethos lab
self-promotion uh but yeah i was
checking out the new snapshots with the
horses and all that uh it's trying to
see if they naturally spawn and
sadly it doesn't seem like they do
but regardless i've been having fun with
them in creative here
just goofing around with the patch the
snapshot
and i've come across this glitch that
i'm sure a lot of you have too
which is a lot of fun
[Music]
oh so funny
uh yeah i've been messing with this for
too long
so if you want to jump jump up a little
bit you gotta do
a butt clench to get your spring on and
then
oh i'm getting good at that uh
yeah horses are out and they look pretty
cool
um
nobody's gonna take this intro seriously
i should get out of f8
i wonder if you can sprint faster on ice
doing this
uh yeah horses are out they look pretty
cool
um i like them i know there's
been a lot of discussion some people are
unhappy about them something
some people think they need to be
modeled better i think they're off to a
good start i was
actually surprised how many features and
all that they added already with them
and especially the donkeys i really like
that
feature where you can put a chest pack
on them
and maybe use them as storage that's
something i've always wanted with wolves
like a little pouch you could attach
to their back or something so that they
would have more
more purpose to following you around you
know but
it makes more sense with the donkey uh
and horses of course
they're really cool anyway enough
goofing around
uh let's let's go into the real let's
play we'll get into horses
later when they're properly implemented
i'm sure so
here we go
[Music]
[Laughter]
all right guys here we are this guy
kill him with a shovel wait wait
no yes yes good we're back
so guys to start off the episode let's
work
on the mob system we're getting it very
close to
amazing just have to work on it a bit
more uh
last last time we worked on it we
pretty much had the sorting figured out
and i worked
on the junctions so they can all be
controlled with redstone
um what we need to do
basically is just we're going to be
dropping zombies down this hole here
skeletons down this one and then
creepers down this one we just have to
run a tube all the way up from these
so let's go ahead and do that
and then at the bottom of this we're
going to have dispensers with lava
buckets in that will
incinerate them get them down to one hit
and then like creepers we can kill with
a looting sword and get
extra gun powder or that we're going to
set up with a record firm
feature where if we walk
between between a creeper
no we don't walk between we walk on the
side of
a creeper a creeper between
us and a skeleton there we go how do you
say that
um then the skeleton's gonna shoot the
creeper and
the creeper's gonna drop a record
because he dies in one hit
one hit that's that's what we're going
for here
so let me finish these tubes and i'll
did i miss
no that's right and i'll get back to you
all right there we go so the tubes come
all the way down to the ground now
and i want the mobs to land on like this
level here
we'll have dispensers in the back with a
lava button in each of these
and i'm just running a line of redstone
back here to
to dispense and pick up the lava budgets
so this is a comparator clock delay
if this is powered
it does that pulse thing we only wanted
to pick it up
or to put it out and then pick it up so
to do that it has to power on power off
power on power off
and the quickest you can do that is in
four ticks one tick
off one take on one take off one take on
and then we need a mono stable circuit
to this
let's see what am i doing here let's
make it go up one i'm just laying it out
rough to start off with here
and uh we're gonna make a skin for this
afterwards
i'm just i just want to get the redstone
figured out make sure it works
and something like this just really
quick and rough
so i get a button
i like cat cat is a good record the best
record
dare i say
um okay yeah so i press this
that only go twice
yeah hmm
oh yeah that's what we want just out and
in
okay and then i
got three level budgets prepared i
actually don't have many records in my
lp world here maybe
four or five different ones tops uh
out of what is it 13 so a record firm
would actually be a nice thing to have
because i like listening to the records
i just don't have them and they're
spread out too like i don't have
four or five different ones here that's
throughout my whole world
um okay dare we try this
with real lava like that that's what we
want
so i'll burn the mobs real quick and
they'll burn for a while but i don't
think it will kill them
so that's good and now
all this stuff by the way is going away
we don't have to worry about it
we're going to make a new skin to put in
front of this
i i want to do it out of quartz but at
the same time i feel that might be
a mistake um i'm gonna go
back to the man cave get some quartz
uh hopefully i have quite a bit there
i'm not sure
if not i'm gonna have to go to the
nether and yet more and we'll try
come up with something cool looking here
or maybe
actually maybe we should just test this
out first
let's let's do that first yeah that's a
good idea
okay so we're going to turn the mob
spawner on
i'll probably have to sleep because i
think it's night time
let's head on down here how's everybody
doing
i'm doing good um
silverfish farm is still working uh
all right yeah let's go on we'll flip
the switch
mobs will start going through the sorter
i did make a new way of getting up there
actually let's try this out
uh just a temporary thing before i was
going up some vines but those were in
the way so i had to move them
okay how do we get over there
i'm a little afraid to try this but
okay now we have to get up there
good this is a switch
all right now they're gonna start going
to the mob sorter let's head on back
down
and this is like the first time we're
seeing if it works
all on its own with us nowhere near it
that's a good sign that's the skeleton
tube
skeleton uh that zombie
that's creeper over there
come on we're your friends though
you didn't see that that didn't happen
what oh snap
that's not closed um
okay do i
they're they're trying to get the
villager look at that they don't even
care about me these guys
looks like they're holding hands up
there oh
wow this really is not working
what is up with this
shouldn't be that bad
did i there's a creeper up there
oh you know what i never put i never put
walls on anything
that's the problem okay i'm leaving this
area
for a bit and then we will well i gotta
shut it off first don't i
and then we will come back and try this
again
uh there we go all right
be right back
yeah things are looking a lot safer here
now we're okay
i went and i got all my courts which
isn't very much but i think it's enough
to do what i want to do
we'll probably try skin this in just a
bit we just want to
maybe check this out first give it a
test
so let's go back up i finished the paths
the creeper path wasn't even open i had
a soil block
blocking it so even if the troopers
wanted to go to the right place they
wouldn't be able to
let's check it out now the sorting
machine wasn't perfected yet
i haven't perfected it um
and it doesn't really need to be
perfected but i think i can
improve the accuracy a bit but we'll
just see
how well it does here so far it's good
that's supposed to be zombie that's bad
zombie skeleton creeper why did the
creeper
go in there
it's all right come on any more creepers
where are you gonna go
and yeah like i said we're taking this
down making a new skin
let's give it a little time to run
see how it does
did we get a second creeper in there
that's not good oh
all right we got one in the proper place
finally
the issue i was having before is i
either need
to give the creepers more place to run
or
get a second cat up there or something
so they
go to the right place but yeah it's it's
working in general
so the next thing we should do is try
this fire thing out
very good oh oh yeah it's
killing them because we're dropping them
yeah let's add a water drop
like four blocks up
do i have any ice i do have ice
and a sign let's get some signs any in
here
no no crafting benches there's one
look at that guys i found a crafting
bench
and didn't make another one i'm getting
better
that was hidden too like come on i
deserve props on that one
[Music]
uh actually we only need three
oh but i don't have water started
no i have ice stuff i'm losing my mind
let's do this one more time
and i'm going to risk opening this up
should really switch it off let's get
glass
on our bar but for entertainment
purposes
okay that happened a lot faster than i
thought it was going to
um man
and now they're going to start falling
down okay
i hope you got a laugh out of that at
least
now i gotta rebuild i will be right back
it's rebuilt and we have a few creepers
in with the skeletons but other than
that
we got it right we got water above
they land as gentle as a feather
so the only damage they're taking is
like
half a heart i think when they fall in
the sorter
other than that they should be at full
health and the idea is this
should take them down to one hit
we don't want any of them to die we want
them to be down
to one hit possible
it doesn't matter if it's not exactly
one hits
but ideally that's what we want
okay that's good none died and they are
one hits
yes are they all one hits they should be
awesome that is sweet i think
zombies
yeah because they have more armor
they take they take more hits
that guy wasn't burned but yeah that's
that's good
that's good news oh you know i've never
gotten chain mail off these guys
this could be a first and of course not
all right so we might drop them onto
hoppers as well i still do have hoppers
um i'm going to shut it off though
before i try switch that
you know i saw this my first instinct
was that it was jammed or broken somehow
but no turns out the room is just full
of silverfish blocks already so that
didn't take long at all that's good
um we'll have to move those some other
time
but for now we'll just disable this
since they can't
enter any more blocks we don't want them
spawning anymore
uh now let's work on the skin for this
thing because
you know the glass tubes they work and
everything but they don't look the best
so we're going to try we brought some
courts over already
and got our quartz i made some stairs
and some slabs
and i also brought over purple wool and
cyan wool
and we'll try mix those in um
like personally even though i really
like the green wool like the lime green
i don't find it goes with quartz all
that great because
the the lime green is a really bright
color and the
quartz is a really bright color and they
just
they look really bright together but if
you pick a darker color like purple
or cyan it looks really good with quartz
um personally i prefer the cyan more
than purple
but we're already using that with the
library so maybe we should try the
purple
we're gonna do both and i'm gonna let
you guys decide what you like more
um all right here's the fun part
this is where things get interesting i'm
going to
like to start off with here i don't feel
i'm
the greatest commentator on youtube by
far i i
have trouble with it i'm usually i got
this problem where i'm very direct and i
don't
elaborate on stuff too well usually
um and that's just the start of my
problems
but yeah i'm going to try and prove my
skills here by doing something
i've never really been successful with
i'm going to try to
build something like and talk about
something else at the same
time like i can very easily narrate what
i'm doing like i'm placing torches right
now
now i'm looking at dispensers that's
really easy to do
but to talk about something else while
doing something creative or complex in
the game
very challenging it's like the brain
doesn't allow it
or at least not my brain but maybe with
practice it's possible so that's what
i'm hoping for here
and here we go all right
so subject this is what we're going to
talk about
um youtube youtube statistics
youtube is a very amazing site
like it keeps track of just about
any type of information you can think of
it's not just
views and likes on a video they keep
track of demographics like
the ages of people and gender of people
watching
videos and uh
the thing that's really interesting is
they also keep track of
oh man this is so tough
oh i'm having trouble already they also
keep track of minutes a video is watched
like
pretty accurately i'm sure it's not
perfectly
accurate like it's an estimate but i
didn't
for example go on a video and see
exactly when people
stopped watching it like when they
exited out like if something bored them
in the video i can see that and then you
know
i can learn uh you know false with what
i'm doing and all that
excuse me but the thing we're really
interested in here is one of the
statistics i saw the other day that
really caught my eye number of
minutes watched
on average per day
what do you think it is for me
well when i saw this i was like
whoa because it's pretty shocking when
you think about it
but on average per day
uh how do we do this um
i'm just keeping you on the edge of your
seat because it drives you crazy
i'm being evil um on average per day
it's about 10 years total minutes
that's like if everybody that watched my
video their total time was put together
it would be about 10 years
uh which that's a number to think about
really um of course after hearing that
the thing that instantly came to my mind
is am i wasting people's time because
per day 10 years waste of time
if it's wasted time that's that's quite
the detriment to
humanity um
if i wasn't doing this like even if it
was wasting time
that's what we're going to talk about
here we're going to define what is
wasting time
which is interesting because everybody
has their own definition of it
even if it was wasting time though just
putting this out there
uh i'm sure people would waste their
time with something else so i don't feel
too bad on that
but here is the real
question what is wasting time
uh a lot of people they feel wasting
time is
if you're not doing anything productive
like if you're working
you're not wasting time but if you're
watching tv you are
um that's that's a very common view of
it
and this is something i thought about in
the past maybe you have as well
uh let's make this like a pillar
see narrating so much easier
let's use the pillar blocks actually
um so personally my definition of
wasting time after
some thought is
wait a minute i
thought about this before see this is
this is how i'm doing this i kind of
pre-thought what i was going to say and
then pre-thought what i was going to
build
and i'm hoping you know with that extra
effort
it's all going to work out um
but now i feel the need to stop and
think uh
this is a real challenge yeah anyway my
definition of wasting time is if you're
doing something that's not of benefit to
you
or to someone else so entertainment i
feel is a benefit to you
with the proper degree like obviously if
you spend all day
entertaining yourself with something
maybe that's not the best
use of time for you maybe working a
little bit would be good for you
um or doing something else
you see where i'm going with this uh
and on on the topic of work always
not being a waste
man i suck at this on the topic of like
if you're at work and being productive
that's not a waste of your time
but if you're watching tv it is consider
this like what if you're working
you're making ten dollars an hour at
some job
but you could have another job where you
could be making twenty dollars an hour
you know uh let's pretend that job was
available and ready for you if you're
working those
ten hours for or for ten dollars an hour
uh then you would be wasting your time
because there's another job
available to you that you could be
making twenty dollars even though you're
doing something productive
i would argue you are wasting your time
you know what you know what i mean um
anyway uh i think i plan on saying more
on this but
it's an interesting statistic i'll put
it that way and it
it made me think uh what do you guys
think is wasting your time
how how do you define it um
like i said i don't feel entertainment
is a waste of your time if it's done in
in the correct moderation you know
everything in life needs to be bounced
this is getting really deep
all right i did something here it's not
much
but it's something i think i will
attempt to do the rest off camera
because it'll be so much easier
or should i try to keep going i could
keep going in there it's no problem
um i can't even find a crafting table
while trying to talk about something
else all right
half slabs actually on that topic
you know since i've started youtube like
back in episode
like 10 or something this is something
i've tried before trying to talk
and about something else and do
something creative or complex at the
same time and i've never really been
successful at it
and because of that i've i've watched
other youtubers to see if it's just me
or if
or if other people are actually able to
do that and i've never seen a good
example of someone
talking about something else talking
about something else and doing something
creative
or complex at the same time it just
can't be done
i don't think they can do something
repetitive in the game very easily
or like do something like caving in the
game
and talk about something else pretty
easily but not
building something
complicated all right
that's enough talking for me i'm going
to work on this some more i'll get back
to you in just a sec
and after all my rambling and blabbling
that's how it turned out i'm pretty
happy with that i think that looks cool
zombie skeleton creeper
still works that's good items should
fall in the hoppers below i
i imagine we might have to do some
tweaking i'm not sure
and this is the wool around here the
idea is
this is going to be floor level here and
then you'll go down
this little bit um
so i don't know if this is going to be
quartz over here or if we're going to
switch to something else like
stone brick i'm not sure
we have plenty of options but as a
centerpiece i think that looks good
and we should probably do some something
with the top of it too
later um let's go turn it on
see it working and then we'll try switch
it with purple
like i said we would
just to be an idea oh
oh no no no no i've done this before
this is not good
oh
when that skeleton fell my heart jumped
i need a ladder ladders would be nice
i can't enter pearl again i'll kill
myself
okay i'm going to climb up since we're
recovering and we'll end our pearl over
it's a little easier that way
ah but yeah thinking thinking about
wasting your time uh i thought about
some more and
after that twenty dollar an hour or ten
dollar an hour argument
you know i could technically i think
safely argue that
every moment of your life is a waste of
time
because there's always going to be that
opportunity
you're missing that you either choose
not to do or
maybe you don't even know about it like
for example i could be watching friends
on tv which is a good sitcom
don't get me wrong i like friends or i
could be watching
seinfeld my all-time favorite show at
let's say it's playing on another
channel at the exact same time if
only i had switched the channel i could
be watching seinfeld
but maybe i don't know it's playing
um oh it's nighttime that's why
that's a missed opportunity there that i
could have been getting better
entertainment for my time uh if i was
watching the show i prefer
you know there's always going to be
opportunities out there you don't know
about
that would benefit you more that you
aren't acting on
so technically i think every moment is a
waste of time
work but really
what it comes down to is are you
enjoying yourself
because that's that's all that really
matters if you're enjoying what you're
doing
you probably don't have to worry about
it too much
although you know there's that attitude
live for today
or or work for tomorrow what's the
better of the two
you know if you live for today you could
be enjoying yourself today
more more than if you're working for
tomorrow you know
and again you're not gonna get it right
uh either way because like i said you're
gonna miss opportunities and whatnot
uh you could work for your retirement
and then
die when you hit retirement and then
that sucks but hey you didn't know
um what was i gonna say
yeah really what it comes down to is
bounce
bounce uh
is probably your best best way of
gauging your life
keep things bounced don't worry about it
enjoy yourself this is really not
working now
why is there a creeper in that one
zombie all right
anyway i'm not too worried about the
sorting i i still plan on working
on that later um
it seems it looks good which i'm pretty
happy with
cool cool if you guys got suggestions
let me know i think we should go read
the comments though because i've
definitely
gone over time for what i usually aim
for
this episode so let's let's read the
comments
just about forgot but remembered last
moment
that's purple so let me know what you
like more
uh i think the kill switch for the lava
by the way it's going to go
that's all my courts left that's why we
can't do anymore
it's going to go over there
yeah i think that would be good
let's do a quick comment time here guys
uh one comment
hey etho i was wondering what episode
you started making the cave house
that's where we are right now could you
please put this in your next episode
because i'm sure other people are
wondering the same thing
thanks now go plays on minecraft
um that is a question i get asked a lot
actually and you would think i would
know the answer to it
but i can never remember if it's episode
103 or 104. i
i'm pretty sure it's 104. um
basically we ended the chocolates
island world and all that stuff because
the adventure update came out
and that made some very drastic changes
to the game
and broke pretty much everything i made
so i decided to make a new world
uh that lasted i think three or four
episodes
and then they made some other drastic
change and i decided to wait
like two weeks to stabilize things and
then and then
i started this world which we've kept
ever since
and i think it's okay i think we can
keep it for a long time
because now when they make patches it
doesn't seem to break things like it
used to in the past
which is good anyway that's all for
today guys thank you very much for
watching
have a great day bye