[Music]
greetings everybody this is etho
uh welcome back to another
minecraft episode today we are going to
be trying out the 1.3 pre-release
woohoo been waiting a long time for this
i'm still in 1.25 i haven't installed it
i've been waiting
to record it oh damn
seriously um
how have you guys been doing how's your
performance lately that's empty
okay you're doing good there that's not
bad
yeah okay oh very good you guys are
doing
doing all right i suppose what's in here
ah but yeah we're going to try out the
1.3 pre-release i'm going to make a
backup of my world
uh just in case there's some problems i
don't think there will be it seems like
it's stable now
and uh we're going to try out some
some of the new features today see if
anything got broken and stuff like that
and i just got back from a teaming trip
that's why i'm loaded
up to the deals here so here we go
making the backup
ho ho ho ho okay guys this is it we're
in 1.3 now officially
uh oh it doesn't say pre-release i
thought it would have
just says minecraft 1.3 at the top there
we got new f3 information
how do you bring up the
if you just said if you just hit f3 the
pie chart comes up but the
performance chart that was at the bottom
left isn't here anymore
i wonder what happened with that that's
cool
it has the feet nice uh y coordinates
separated now that's
something that could get confusing
before
so yeah i i don't have a whole lot of
experience with the 1.3
snapshots and that i for the most part i
skipped all that
but i do know a few things about the
patches
those guys are frozen
they're not okay i got worried they
weren't moving their heads or anything
it's not like they were looking at each
other does this work
okay all right
like with the there's been some piston
changes apparently i was worried uh
this door might not work or anything
using pistons
might be affected
okay uh let's kill this guy
see how bad the s p mobs are oh it's bad
it's bad
wow
normally i can punch an enderman to
death without taking damage
in single player he almost got me there
cool so the first thing i want to do i'm
sure a lot of you can guess it
after we unload our stuff here don't
want to risk losing it
and i'll sort it later oh yeah new new
texture for the cocoa beans
all right yeah so what i want to do
first
that get some of these um
still have not worked out the crafting
bench
issue i know what i want to do i just
need to do it
but for today i guess we'll just make
another one a loose one
and stick it
right up there why not
okay oh
why why is it taking so long to get
these it was such
they're such a good idea you know i've
wanted these for so long
so many people have
awesome straight up ones
very cool great addition to the game
now i can smooth out my ceiling no
problem
cool
i never liked how how this looked
uh with the full block i i wanted a
smoother transition but there was
no real good way of doing it before
when i was making the ceiling i
struggled with it for so long trying to
get it smooth looking and fluent
we go that's much better um
yes so villager trading i don't know
what the story is with that
i know i tried it out when it first came
out but it's
changed since then i'm sure
okay so i think he
is the one offer for bookshelves he
wants to
buy them perhaps
wait no he
no i need to buy him from him i think
they both have the same deal
boy what about these guys i'm curious
i'm just gonna remove the bottom glass
for now so we can test this
are you offering the same thing no he is
offering
paper paper for money
see i don't know what the order is i
don't know if
okay i think that means he's buying
wheat for emeralds
we can try that out we have plenty of
wheat
yeah so as far as the villager trading
goes i don't know if it's going to help
me a whole lot
because i have almost everything i need
in this world
for like the minecraft server and that
i'm more excited about it um
cool oh
oh i shift clicked
if i walk away will he get a new trade
yes
i don't want to buy those we got
millions of them
another trade
i think so
nope
yeah but the main thing i'm excited
about is uh
i think they sell glowstone last i heard
and also i think
fish cooked 12 cooked fish that's going
to take forever to get
and the other main thing i'm
i want is just the emerald emerald
blocks themselves
it's one of my favorite new blocks our
favorite box in the game
i've always wanted a nice green linton
block like the emerald ones
okay so i think the villager i want is
the blacksmith
i don't have any of those i'm pretty
sure
these guys are still alive
gravel and emeralds for flint
okay i'm gonna do a bunch of trading
then i'll get back to you guys
um
okay
ah
[Music]
uh
all right guys so i've done some trading
with our friends here and i've also done
some research about the offers
we can make with them and i got a lot to
say like
about the villager trading system i
could probably talk easily half an hour
about it so
i'll try to keep it as short and concise
as i can
um it's pretty interesting it
it's a good system i like the idea of
trading stuff
that you might not that like trading
stuff that has a value to it
that you don't really need maybe you
have too much of it like
i have over a double chest full of coal
which i probably
am not ever going to use so i like the
idea that i can trade that
for something more valuable to me
um like diamond armor which isn't really
that valuable to me because i have tons
of diamonds too
but you know what i mean
so the trading system itself is pretty
cool it does
make the game slightly easier because it
gives you another way of getting items
which is fine as long as mo yang
you know tried to incorporate ways to
make the game more challenging as well
like
this patch at least came up with one way
of doing that they increased the damage
creepers do
which is great so
yeah it's got to be get give and take
if you give you got to take something
too so if you make the game easier in
one way you got to make it more
challenging
in another i i feel but uh
let's just go over how the trading works
so
it seems you only get new trade uh
offers if you trade them the last item
so if i do that
there's a chance i might get a new offer
i don't think it's always he gets that
purple particle effect no he didn't give
me
uh like when i traded the bookshelves it
took me three tries to find
before three tries before he finally
gave me a new offer
this time i took two um
the thing that really surprised me i
didn't know this but
trade offers can go away too if you
trade with them
several times i think or maybe even one
time who knows
i want to check that out so we'll just
trade them
one at a time
the offer go away you didn't get the
purple thing
still there we can trade trade one more
time
i'm wondering if the offer goes away
when i leave the screen or if it can go
away
while i'm in it as well i think it's
only when i leave it
still there
and it's gone so three tries and it
disappeared
so that may be random or it may not be
oh and he got the purple particle effect
too which means
bye bye to the offer
okay huh what else to talk about so
some of this pretty sure anyway they do
the villager trading system it can be
exploited
they did a better job at this than i was
expecting when it first came out it
looked like it was going to be
extremely easy to exploit and now it
seems like
it's more challenging especially
considering the offer can disappear
one thing i want to try out too is if
you can trade charcoal instead of coal
maybe i'll make some and we'll just see
that first
actually this gives us a good chance to
try out our new furnace room and also
try out
getting xp from smelting
i have noticed a huge performance change
though with
this patch a lot of times my frame rate
while recording drops below
30 even which is bad news
definitely bad news the game is much
more laggy now
um so i might have to look into
ways to speed it up
but hopefully as future patches come out
they will continue to improve
performance it's like like right right
there
drop down to 15.
i got xp right away there that was weird
huh
oh i do have charcoal sweet
and i think that's enough so let's go
let's go trade with that villager
um it seems like you can exploit the
villager system as it is now
uh fairly easily though since the trade
offer doesn't disappear until you leave
the screen that means you
what you got to do is you got to go
bigger or go broke
type thing
while the trade offers there you want to
take advantage of it as much as possible
so
for example say i had thousands and
thousands of paper
i might throw it all on the ground where
i'm standing here
and and as i trade with the villager
more paper keeps popping into my
inventory and i can just
trade all of it in one go
instead of only like being able to trade
three times okay this is a charcoal
so you can trade charcoal for for
emeralds too
like before it disappeared on
two or two trades i can make several
trades as long as i don't leave the
screen
so yeah now when i come back it might be
gone
yeah because i just traded a whole bunch
and that doesn't add a new trade offer
you only get that if you trade the last
item which means
you might hit a point where you can't do
any more trades unless you go get an
item you don't have like
like pork i have no real good way of
getting pork so
it's possible i could use up all these
and
run out of trade offers until i can get
an item i
i don't normally have so there might be
some grinding involved in this
um out of all the things they buy
i made a list of it here they they buy
the farmer buys wheat wool
raw chicken and cooked fish the
librarian buys paper
books and written books the blacksmith
buys
coal iron gold diamond and the butcher
coal raw pork and raw beef
out of all of those paper is the one
item you can
get very easily like
like weed is fairly easy to get to but
you gotta plant the seeds
but paper you can have automatic
harvesting
no problem so that seems like the most
exploitable
trade and it's almost like the trading
system is designed like to be
exploited because like
most of stuff this is this would be a
terrible deal like i would not want to
make that
this is a terrible deal it's not really
stuff you would have
laying around that they're offering to
buy
for the most part like the librarian
who has paper laying around i don't who
has books laying around i don't
so you almost have to grind to make them
just so you can trade i don't i don't
know it's
it's a little weird to me it would make
sense
more sense like if they bought wood or
something something you have lots of or
cobblestone or
you know something that has a little bit
of a value to it but you might not need
and you might want something better but
less of it
yeah so maybe back to talking about why
it seems like the villager system was
meant to be exploited
uh in general their trades are a
terrible
deal like that's a terrible deal in my
opinion
and i'm going to use a blacksmith as the
main example for this you can trade him
four or five diamonds to get one emerald
and then if you were to buy
a diamond chess piece from him it would
cost you
16 to 18 emeralds so
that's like spending 64 to 90 diamonds
on a diamond chess piece so that's 8 to
11.25 times more expensive than if you
were to just make it yourself
if you were to exchange the diamonds and
then
buy something made of diamonds it's
it's a total ripoff um
so just making the odd trade here and
there with these guys is not
the best thing to do because this is a
good trade
in my opinion this is the best trade for
getting emeralds
but if i was just trade 19 paper or so
or
make two or three trades this offer is
going to disappear and or
and in order to get another good offer
back like this one
i'll probably have to spend those
emeralds i got just to make it to
reappear in the list again
so when i trade i have to trade big
get as many emeralds as i can
and that's the way this is going to work
so for me the best offers or the
the main reason i would use this is to
get redstone and glowstone
are two things a priest can sell some
other interesting things
are you can get by trading our glass
a bottle of enchanting but you would
have to spend about
two stacks of emeralds to get to level
if you bought bottle of enchanting to go
from zero to thirty
i can buy steak and cooked pork chops
you can buy
iron and diamond armor
as well as tools so
of all those redstone glowstone are the
most interesting and i would rather just
hoard emeralds and make emerald blocks
out of them that i can use for building
so that's how i plan on using the
trading
and i don't think it's much of an issue
for uhc what
the
huh that's a glitch
huh
weird i'll have to fix that later i'm
not sure
what the deal is um i got xp
what the heck is going on
oh i gotta relog this is bad i don't
know
oh
yeah relogging fixed that we're okay all
is good
um but yeah you can get xp from smelting
now i got xb before
when i was confused there because i took
the items out of the furnace
that's that's the action that gives it
to you
just got some and the reason
it's that is because you can't put items
into that slot if you could you could
just
put it in take it out put it in take it
out and keep getting xp from that
the only way to get it into that slot is
by smelting it
um it's not really
a liable way of leveling up like you get
some from it but it's not much like
and certain things give you more than
others like i think 10 cobblestone gets
you
one xp when you smelt it while iron
gets you a lot more
17 19 level 19
20 um
yeah so it's just a nice bonus
nice little bonus as it should be
okay okay let's move on here we talked
about that enough
uh another new feature is that items can
stack
together
or entities to help prevent lag
there's a test i want to do with this
i'm wondering if
when you throw a new item into the stack
if that renews the timer
on when it despawns so
i'm wondering like for example if i
throw one here and i throw one here
if after like three minutes or so i
throw another one into that stack
if that will renew the five minutes
despawn timer on that one
so that's what i'm going to do i'm gonna
i'm gonna throw one here
i'm gonna throw one here after
a few minutes i'm gonna throw another
one in here and i want to see if
if this one disappears way before it
ah they disappeared at about the same
time which
means if you have
an item down and another one joins with
it it
gets whatever timing the first one had
so if
if that was down for four minutes and
another item
joined together with it
like that then in another minute both
blocks will disappear so
keep that in mind
and one of the biggest features i've
been looking forward to with the 1.3
patch
is getting ice
oh that's awesome been waiting so long
for this stuff
can't make water in the nether with it
but you know what
there's so many other things you can do
with it anyway
the main the main use for ice is for
moving items around because
they slide you can move an item as far
as you want on flat ground
otherwise in a normal water stream you
got to go down every eight blocks and
it's challenging um so yeah moving
items around my sheep farm
my sheep farm i've been waiting for the
ice to complete it
and with my storage room area i've
needed
or i will need ice for all the farms i
plan on building there as well as some
of the decorative stuff
i want to do because ice also looks very
good
has a lot of unique properties you can
you can move quick on
it if you're jumping and yeah it's just
an overall useful block and i'm glad
it's
we're able to get it again in the game
in an easy way
okay guys so i'm actually going to build
something real quick here just a
temporary
temporary thing got my stuff together
uh the problem with taking ice like this
is it's going to scar the landscape if i
keep doing it
because this this ice is gone it's not
coming back
i removed the water and
the only way to get it back is to
replace the water and let it freeze
again
and same like if we take it from the
ocean we would take it off one layer at
a time
and it would freeze you could take off
another layer eventually though
you would get to the bottom and there
would be no ocean left
so before i get into the habit of doing
that i want to set up something
that will regenerate ice just something
real simple and quick
out in the snowy biome over here there's
a nice flat
spot up ahead right here
so i'll clear the trees and i'm just
going to make something
like a 16 by 16
pad for for creating ice
so this is what i've been working on
this is the ice tray
it's just about done i'm not spending a
whole lot of time on it i just want to
get it up and functioning and
probably won't even bother replacing the
grass with with this stone just because
it's
most likely going to be a temporary
thing
that'll tear down one day soon
it is a 16 by 16 so
that will yield four stacks of ice
every time these creepers
i'm scared i got no armor on and i
and it's like s p now
plus they detonate really far away
okay so those are all down so now this
one lever will control all these pistons
or one piston what's up with that
what's going on
i just tried this and it worked
oh it's sending power oh that's what oh
sending power back i made a loop here
okay i'll fix this
i'm gonna put water in these drops here
and it should be good to go
this is what i did instead it'll work
it'll work just fine so this is all
ready to go
i got the water in place all the pistons
are ready
it'll create an infinite spring in this
whole thing
uh when i pull this lever and then that
will freeze
and it freezes because this water is
exposed to the air
this water over here though is covered
so it won't freeze
close that and it's ready to go for the
next time once all this freezes i can
come in here with the
silk touch remove the layer open it up
again to create the new one
nice and simple and only took like
15 minutes to build
oh yeah also the glitch with dogs in
that teleporting is not
fixed in 1.3 not the pre-release anyway
because this guy just randomly
teleported to me when i was out in the
desert
i'm so scared of these guys now i
haven't had one blow up yet but
i know it's going to kill me
and now we are at the san quarry because
we're going to try something out here
too
in smp shovels work very quickly on
dirt and sand gravel a whole bunch of
stuff
you can shear leaves really quick in smp
a lot faster than
in single player before now
that single player is emulating a server
i'm curious to see if that
effect has carried over or not so here
we go
this is efficiency 4
it does sweet
yeah that's another thing i was really
excited about because
i do not particularly enjoy gathering
sand in single player
usually i would use tnt for it but if we
can do this now
it's gonna be awesome
so fast
and like look how long the shovel lasts
two it's it's so quick
and barely uses up the tool
and it's fun to do
cool wow man that took
hardly any time at all it's like two
three minutes filled up my inventory
so much sand i guess i never really
talked about
uh also while
while you're looking at this uh entity
items they
glitch out like they do in s p i think
that's actually above
or else below the sand
so you can walk right up to it not pick
it up
there it is uh
yeah xp for mining ores you don't get
very much
it's much like the smelting thing uh
it's just a nice little bonus
as it should be
you actually get more from the more
valuable ores like
it's not all the same coal i think is
the least and
as you make your way up to diamonds you
get a fair bit more
so now it's really a quick way of
leveling up either it's just a nice
little bonus
actually smelted five stacks of cobbles
let's see how much xp we get from it
we're 26
yeah so it's not it's not really a whole
lot
yes i wanted to try out the snow thing
just to make sure as well
and yep it's super quick now
that would have been so handy when i was
building the mob system because i spent
hours just harvesting the snow for it
took so long now
oh well i i may expand that thing yet so
this could come in handy still
and yeah i'm building i'm building with
the winter theme in the storage room so
i'm sure i'll be using snow blocks quite
a bit
yeah so we're running out of time again
i don't think we're going to be able to
try
all the new stuff out today there was
something else so really important i
wanted to try
almost forgot almost forgot
this is another really cool thing about
the patch
there they are uh
we'll make our enter eyes
and we will make our ender what are they
called ender chests
ender chest i guess that's it okay
sweet so can you put these between
regular chests
you can oh those are crazy
i think if you break it you get the
obsidian but you lose the eye
oh yeah that's what it is
no big deal okay so i want to try this
out i'm going to put some stuff in it
then we'll head over to the other base
um i don't know maybe tools
not sure what i would use it for mainly
gunpowder well
well i'll put some stuff in it oh yeah i
got all this i could
maybe move
huh all right
i feel like i should uh put the ender
chest in the storage room somewhere
um i was thinking maybe here would be
good
yeah like some something like over there
try patch it in somehow okay if we
remove this
and put that there and put our chest
down
it's the color though it's never gonna
look good
hmm
unless i bury it
like put it put it down here
dang i'll figure something out i guess i
don't know what to do
hey it works awesome
all right guys we've moved on to the
nether now we're going to try out the
blaze farm in just a second
i wanted to enchant some feather falling
boots
which is i think level 26 is what you
want for that now
um but it seems you can't get that if
you have your enchanting table maxed out
so
it's still there's still some benefit to
having a variable
enchanting table it seems
what will that do oh overdid it
how about now
um
[Music]
i wanted 26. that one would block out
quite a few books no it still won't drop
oh now it dropped a lot
too much oh
28 28
28 that's interesting it's stuck at 28.
okay maybe we won't block out a corner
24 24
25 oh man that is really specific
now i don't know if i can get a 26.
might not be possible
i don't know if the top ones work
anymore even they probably do
man 24
yeah i don't think i can
all right well we'll do a 24.
beautiful wow that's that's really good
i'm safe again so let us check out the
blaze farm there is a lot of pistons in
this thing and a lot of redstone
which has me worried it takes
i think 825 xp to go from zero to 30 now
which is about 5.6 times less than
what it was before before it was 4625
see that i thought would have messed up
i don't really need that i should take
that out
yeah the pistons aren't giving me
trouble like i thought they would
they seem to be okay still
it's probably only a select few things a
few glitches that don't work anymore
with them
okay so it only takes um what is it
about 83 get 83 blaze to get
from zero to 30.
okay i think that'll do it it's about 90
90 blaze in there so we will
do that and just the correction or
clarification of what i said
when i said 4625 xp i meant from
zero to 50 before that's what it was not
zero to 30.
but the new max level is 30.
which this should take us to if
if i figured everything right
probably 31 or 32
oh man did i call it or what
that's cool so you don't want to go over
30 really because
um it starts to cost more per level i
think it was three xp more
each level um
but yeah maybe we'll enchant a few
things and then we'll call it an
episode i need a new axe and
the thing is if you do a big batch of
blaze like if you were to kill
200 or 250 like i usually do
you can get the xp and then ender pearl
as it's swirling around
you you can ender pearl to get out of it
so it doesn't follow you and then you
can go back to its
pick up 30 more levels into pearl away
and just keep going back and forth until
it's all used up
all right here we go level 30.
that's very good i'll need a new one i
have to do another one that's useless
uh yeah so it's 17
xp per level up to level 16 and then
level 17 you need 20 level 18 you need
and it keeps going up three every time
every level
beyond that
oh man what have i done
okay um i went for a shower came back
we're at 373 i've never
gotten even close to this before
before i was afraid to go over 250
because i would run out of memory and
crash
and i corrupted my world once doing that
too
but i do remember seeing in the patch
notes that they
improved i think memory usage
and if you look it's barely going over
300 even
so we probably can handle a lot more
blaze now
thanks to this patch and
i'll just have to be more careful in the
future
even the frame rates not bad oh
now it is
[Music]
okay yeah that killed it we're getting
one frame per second i gotta
i think i gotta stop recording
yep okay i'll see you guys in a bit
two frames per second
it's beautiful
good good okay enough ender pearl ender
pearl away
the really nice thing is i don't have to
spend an hour trying to get the level i
want now
nice we can go right back there get our
xp
with plenty of time to spare because you
only got five minutes before that
despawns too
very nice very nice
oh so many plays
ah all right we'll do it
well we can't do it 29 generally we got
to get it
i'll have to get better at doing that
going back and forth
i'll take some practice uh let's do
let's do a pick
oh i almost killed myself i wasn't
paying attention
all right yeah i'm loving the new patch
i'm
i'm definitely glad i've upgraded
um of course there are problems that
come with it but i'm pretty sure
mo yang will spend the next
little while working at fixing all the
bugs they've introduced with the
smp emulation not bad not bad
so pretty sure it's only going to get
better from here
and i wouldn't worry too much about that
unless i'm hoping they do it like
without going
months before they fix it like
i don't want them to fix it in 1.4 i
want them to do
uh follow-up 1.3 patches within
the next couple weeks or whatever and
then start working on 1.4 with new
features
is what i'm hoping for
okay
uh let's do a shovel this is fun
wow now that i can get all these tools
so quick i can focus more on building in
less time on grinding
which is always nice
because i spend a lot of time just
getting xp in this game another four
but anyway guys i think i'm gonna get
going here this episode is very long as
is
uh thank you for watching i will see you
again next time
uh we're gonna do some building i'm
gonna try uh
finish up the sheep farm
and i'll probably do that off camera
and then just show it to you and i also
i want to do some exploring sometime
soon but i'm going to work on
building for the next few episodes
anyway
cool all right guys see you
[Music]
you