[Music]
no there is nothing wrong with your
speakers
oh i got you good i got you so good
oh
what's up everybody this is etho um
let's get this back up so today
i don't really have a plan for the
episode i'm probably just going to do
random audio ups around here trying to
make things look better
to begin with i wanted to switch this to
grass
and uh this is kind of a special episode
some of you have noticed i have went
over the 200
000 subscriber
number now and i just want to thank
everybody that
has subscribed and has supported me for
so long
since i've been doing youtube here it's
a still a lot of fun i enjoy it
quite a bit um
you might have noticed i've had more
time to play minecraft again and i'm
really
getting back into it and enjoying it a
lot
which is awesome so
to begin with i just want to thank
everybody
for your support um sheep farm
i had a great idea suggested in the
comments
of uh last episode
i had a problem with you might remember
i had pressure plates here to keep the
water from flowing
out of the sheep farm
people suggested i should make something
like that come up
when i when i hit the button for the
water
and that way it all stays in great idea
i'll i'll probably do that
but uh not today
not today we're gonna take a break from
the sheep farm continue it's another day
uh you know what else i wanted to do
i wanted to do this make a path from
the storage room up to the sheep farm
here's is
like another way of getting here because
otherwise you gotta go
around this little maze thing
nice to have more more options of
getting around
as i was cutting this out i found this
lava pool
which i've been hearing for a while now
but i just didn't realize it was so
close
so what we'll do
we're gonna have like a three we're
gonna make this much like the stairs
here where we'll have the wooden
half slabs and then the wood blocks and
the fence on top
so i'll play around with it a bit and
see see what we come up with
and this is what we get so i
used half slabs here
the advantage of using half slabs over
stairs is you can actually run up them
without breaking your stride which is
always nice
but the downside is you get a very long
staircase twice as long as
if if you use regular stairs so
do we do it this way or do we use
regular stairs is the question
um if we look at some of the other ones
i made these are regular
or these are half slabs but if we go to
this one i used the full stairs
otherwise it would have been would have
been huge
so with this
case i did the stairs because i didn't
want it taking away space from other
things
but with this this one we just made i
think the half slabs
are pretty good actually because there's
nothing else we would put there
so i don't think the huge staircase is
an issue
and it starts at a really nice spot here
too
so we'll do it this way i'm happy with
that
let's see it goes like this uh a big
question a lot of people had
is why by the way i filled in
the lava lake there i didn't want
anything catching fire when this is all
done
uh why am i not in season
[Music]
seven season seven
of ultra hardcore uh i actually said
this at the end of
season six when i died that i wouldn't i
wasn't able to record with them when
they did season seven
uh which is okay in fact i
was sort of one of the guys pushing to
continue recording if people can't make
it
to a season because when we were doing
the teams we had issues with scheduling
it
we had to kind of postpone it
for i think a week or two and that's the
problem you have if you have
a lot of people playing a game it's it's
just going to keep being postponed
because
not everybody is free at the same time
so
to me it makes more sense just to
have everyone play and if people can
make it great
and if not hopefully they can make it
next time type thing because
doc wasn't able to make it last season
in season six because he had to work
i wasn't able to make it in season seven
because i had to work and i couldn't get
out of it
uh and
that is just fine but uh
i did talk i did like join in the call
afterwards
so i heard what happened spoiled it a
little bit for myself but
i'm not going to write it for you guys
but it sounds like it was a very
exciting season so i'm looking forward
to seeing
exactly what happens i've seen the first
episodes i watched all of them
and really enjoying the teams things so
far
what do you guys think of this staircase
i'm looking forward to seeing how the
rest of it plays out it's going to be
great
uh for the next season though i've
talked about this i have i have a plan a
very
[Applause]
well thought out plan now in the
previous seasons i've just been
kind of winging it but now i feel like
something hit me in the head and i know
exactly what to do type thing
so i'm looking forward to playing it
again when i can
and actually you know what uh with
season
season six the guys kind of
i felt they gave me special treatment i
they they recorded that
one week after we did season five uh
just so that i would be able to join in
because otherwise
i would have had to work during season
six as well
so
yeah uh and going on with that
uh i said this is my 200k
special sort of type thing i just want
to say thanks to everyone
everyone on the minetrak server i have a
blast playing with those guys
we all do have a good time
make each other laugh thanks to good for
letting me on
um everybody gets along really well
which is what i like about it
and we have a good time
okay do we want now
yeah i like that um still never figured
out what we're gonna do here
this door is just sticking out
and i gotta be careful
oh that oh i stepped on the pressure
plate
i thought i wrecked a wire there
all right so i went through and i
chiseled away some more of the wall here
to make it so that the fences don't
connect to it
uh we'll we'll clean it up some more
once i
once i finalize this area still got to
do quite a few things to it yet
like we didn't do a front for this yet
or
we gotta build the the furnace room here
still
yet still i figure out how to use those
two words again
um we'll put
put a log here one here
oh i do have my axe equipped whoops
uh
do that i can see also that
these two don't match like the staircase
ends with planks here
this one ends with the fences coming out
one more block
and having the
the wood blocks instead of planks
not sure which is better
almost prefer this one
uh what else should we do here i wanted
to
cover well let's get some of this
one of these days i'll make a bigger
watermelon and pumpkin farm
i've gotten quite idea i've gotten used
to using the glowing pumpkins for stuff
although when the trading comes out with
the testificates
i believe one of the things you can get
is glowstone from them which is
awesome yeah what i want to do is i want
to cover these up
once and for all
still have to work out the lighting
because i like when i run through here
sometimes i fall in those holes
and they should really we should make a
way of getting down to the cow farm
over here come down the stairs go to the
right
and then these are these are the tubes
to get down
yeah that would be better
um something else i'm thinking of doing
let's go over here
today's a little gonna be a bit of a
quick episode because
i tried to i tried to record two
episodes today
i just recorded a long long minecraft
episode which will come
out after this one and i was not left
with much time to record this lp
so
it'll be a bit quicker today but what i
want to do
i need to improve the transportation in
this world
um i would like to maybe make
a minecarts track over here
this is a slime farm the big pad for it
have like a minecart track that goes
from here all the way to the end
portal with the silver fish farm and the
mob system and all other stuff we plan
on doing there
maybe we'll work on
improving this area a bit too
we'll run the grass and wood walkway
thing here
all right um i'll stop recording while i
do this
all right we got that done uh you can
see the grass is a different color here
i believe this is a
desert biome yeah
desert biome nice view of the slime farm
here
i would like to like have the minecart
track
right around like start right here
so it's out of the way you know um
and do the same thing i
did with the the mine shaft system you
know cut out the
like a five by five area
and run a tunnel all the way down i'll
probably blast it out with tnt
uh our z coordinate here is around 200
we got to go all the way up to 800
to around 800 to run the tunnel to
the other area there i think that'd be
cool to do
i'll try and do that today
if i if i can manage to do it in time
um oh
and if i have enough tv t i'm not sure
how much i have at the moment
but i'll i'll tunnel there and i'll rig
it with
the charges if i can and we
will hopefully get to see an explosion
today
uh and also we'll maybe we'll go check
out the the mine shaft project because i
have been working on that
uh continually i just haven't shown it
in a long time so
that could be fun too
okay guys so i have uh ran some more
grass here
on this side i don't know if i'll keep
this or not
um i felt like i needed it like it
bounced out the look somehow uh if if i
do
keep it i plan on replacing this with
glass as well
so it'll be much like this side uh
desert forest desert forest desert
forest uh
so pretty much all this way it's gonna
be desert grass
i got it rigged to blow here that took a
while actually
and i used up all my tnt only made it
about
halfway but we should get a pretty good
show here
won't be able to get much done today
though we actually
have to go to i wrote this down
somewhere
negative 450 x and 860
zed is our destination it's a long ways
very long ways it'll take another stack
of tnt at least yet
or still yet or still whichever
here it goes
oh yeah
see if we can keep up there i did run
across the ravine
oh good um let's get some blocks ready
because we'll have to cross here yeah
this is an unexplored review by the
looks of it
oh it's leaving without us
so yeah i'll make this sort of like the
the mine shaft with the the support
beams running through
it's actually blowing up maybe more
space than i want it to
must have been some dirt patches
it's a long ways very long nose
that's this is only half of it
oh something else i plan to do
is uh set up a nether hub in my
single-player
player world here like we have on the
minecraft server
get to different destinations that is a
really
nice way of traveling
[Applause]
to places quickly and it's a good way of
organizing things too
is that it that's it i came across a
cave system i haven't explored two
uh that's where i decided to stop i only
had five tnt left
oh hello
wow possible
dungeon
no just a whole lot of mobs
okay so i'm gonna pick up the stuff kill
some
kill some mobs here oh let's see if it's
enchanted
nope okay i'm gonna put this stuff up
before it despawns
and we will go go check out the mine
shaft
yeah so running back through that i
filled up my whole
whole inventory with cobble got a lot of
blocks from that
we will keep it sealed now until we
light it properly
a lot of people have been asking about
the bad and mine shaft they want to see
it again
so we will go check it out
and it's fitting that we do because i
plan on copying
the style i used in it for that minecart
tunnel we just
drilled halfway
this is where the mine shaft is
um i really like this mine shaft i think
it's cool
got our water drop
and i can't remember if i left any
i think i yeah i got i'm pretty sure i
grabbed all the redstone that was down
here
i'm up to one stack gotta get more
yeah i took mostly good stuff out of
here
soil that's all cobble
i think this is gravel
stone man that gives you like a seizure
if you see that
screen over and over again
um
let's see this thing's gonna be
uh useless i believe when the
actually kind of already it always was
useless who am i kidding
i've used it once i would like to use it
one more time though
at least one more time
uh
okay let's go let's go see how far this
extends i can't remember
i have not started digging out any of
these yet though
like i said i plan on putting up a sign
for the donators
i have to go through some of the
information and figure that out
it takes a long time to do that
let's try go to the left first
and this is the style i want to copy for
the other minecart tunnel
except maybe put grass instead of stone
in it since it's higher up and
connected with other cave
okay it looks like i started working on
it over here
and as we go through here maybe maybe
we'll talk about something
uh one thing i've been thinking about
is uh sickness
um i know some people that get sick
all the time it seems like uh
five six seven times a year at least
and i always find that kind of strange
when i was when i was younger i used to
get sick a lot more
and it was bad like feel like you're
dying
then maybe
probably three or four years ago i got
into the habit of washing my hands
a lot more especially before i eat i
always make sure i wash my hands and now
i find i only get sick once a year
maybe twice a year i think since i've
been doing this youtube thing i've
i remember only getting sick once and
that was around episode 80.
i've always kind of wondered what's
going to happen if i get sick and can't
talk for
two weeks or something like that but it
really hasn't happened
when i get sick it's it doesn't last
long
and it's not it's not really that severe
um i do get headaches and stuff
quite often but like sore throat
flu if i get the flu i never
i never throw up anymore so
i've been thinking about it is it i
think it
has to do with like washing your hands
it probably has to do with your immune
system
another thing i think that gets people
sick is uh having pets
around in the house but
this is all speculation from what i've
what i've observed in some of my friends
and whatnot
um but if you guys
find you get sick often i would suggest
trying to
make sure you wash your hands before you
eat that seems to have done the trick
for me
um and like i'm pretty careful about it
like if i touch my keyboard after i've
washed my hands then i'll wash them
again before i eat
even if i just washed them three two or
three minutes ago you know
um but anyway that's the mine shaft it's
it's
grown a little bit i still plan to
continue it
i'm going to have to
or what i want to do is harvest a bunch
of those
wooden half slabs because in the
upcoming patch people
have said there's going to be two types
the type that
burns and the type that doesn't the type
that doesn't you can only get
before the 1.3 patch so
i might fill up a few chests full of
those
they'll be handy to have around but i
gotta go get going here so thanks for
watching everyone and
take care of yourselves don't get sick
[Music]
you