[Music]
Jeff Jeff don't just stand there staring
at the camera you got to introduce me
man I'm trying to make a grand entrance
you got to be like ladies and gentlemen
I present to you the great etho gonna do
something like that
quick you're useless man you're you're
sighs well on the positive side of
things guys I finally know what I'm
gonna use this hole here for I got a new
position for you Jeff one that I think
you can handle you're gonna love your
new job why are you burning you see that
he was burning for a second there there
you go Oh perfect
Jeff buddy pal guy well done man I think
you finally found your position your
true potential in life has been reached
you're gonna do great there don't worry
about you he'll take care of the lab for
you I don't think you'll I'll notice any
difference well things will probably run
a little smoother all right moving on
oh yeah
you know we never did name our donkey we
should do that I just got back from this
huge huge caving adventure
so you got lots of good stuff lots lots
lots and lots and lots of iron which is
great I've got a bunch of emeralds like
the real emerald ores which is cool
found another name tag so we can name
our donkey and believe it or not I only
stumbled across one dungeon and you know
what was in it I was shocked because we
just found one of these I found out that
another silk touch one in a dungeon
which is pretty cool put those on some
shears to you I could not believe it cuz
what are the chances finding two silk
touch books in a row that's pretty crazy
alright so shears I might not use these
again unbreaking though I'm not sure if
they'll work on shears but if they do
that would be awesome and all right so
we're gonna name our donkey donkey yeah
ah there was it the anvil too bad I just
have to make another one for the silk
bed won't wait very cool
had a lot of fun caving though I I want
to go check out that stronghold sometime
soon to mate might do it today or well
we can't do it next episode because
we're doing that or next episode but if
we don't do it then we'll probably do it
after that I do have a project I want to
try out today which we'll get to pretty
quick here
can we name them what should we name our
shears hmm how about Edward skeezer
hands that work that works okay awesome
all right I do have some cobwebs around
here we can try it out let's go name the
donkey first we're gonna go back to the
nether today believe it or not like I
said I've been really interested in the
nether all of a sudden just like lots of
lots ideas with what we could do with it
ooh donkey
Zenith meet donkey awesome let's go find
some cobwebs down here to try these out
I've never gotten silk touch on shears
yet I don't know what I'm gonna use it
for cobwebs are great for timers oh
that's awesome
it takes an item I think about 24
seconds to pass through a cobweb so for
long long range timers they're really
awesome cool I'm not gonna use these all
up though if we get Adam breaking I
might put it on these let's head on over
to the nether though so the plan I want
to try and make a zombie Pigman farm or
at least started today and I'm going to
go up on the roof of them
today I always wanted to do it I'm not
sure if I it's like breaking some
vanilla code or anything because it's
it's you know it's not really intended
for you to go on top of the nether but
at the same time it's possible so I kind
of want to do it I don't think it's
gonna cause any technical bugs so as far
as I know so I think I think it's okay
to go ahead with it and we're gonna use
that feature with our zombie Pigman farm
let's figure out the exact center here
this is probably what else Center the
farm on okay negative 4365 just writing
it down and Zed 11 perfect okay I'm
gonna grab some netherrack wow that's
loud
let's maybe just turn this down a bit
today all right so we're gonna go up
right above here just on pillar up I
just is probably the easiest way and I
brought a bow and everything just in
case we have trouble this is where I put
the beach in by the way just above there
and I got to make sure we don't block
the beam to that too
all right so we're about eighty four and
let's keep going up this is gonna be
cool I'm gonna put a portal on top I'm
gonna put an ender chest up there too
and some other stuff so we don't have to
die to get back in this game like if you
ever get trapped on top of the nether or
trapped anywhere you can always kill
yourself with starvation by the way so
don't feel like you're stuck you will
lose your stuff but you you can continue
playing you don't have to get like a
server admin or whatever if you're
playing on a server to get you down
they were why 122 let's go away from the
beacon actually so I don't mess that up
I think we got to get up to or ideally
we got to get up I'm sure we'll find a
spot not there I want a nice this
doesn't look too bad I think I think
that might be a good over here actually
124 I think we can get up to 125 yeah
look at that so we can get one more
block higher mmm well I could ender
pearl into that I don't really want to
maybe this is first time we'll do it
okay on top of the nether whoo awesome
all right so what was the center 43
negative 43 I'm just gonna March it 11
so the beacon is directly below us here
I'm not gonna block it I'm just gonna oh
that looked bad oh that scared me the
cobble like went invisible there oh and
I lost my a speed oh I may have just
killed the beacon because I think I
raised the sky limit now
[Music]
okay so there are some side effects to
this it seems not to worry because we
can move the beacon up here and then
it'll be fine
yeah I didn't think it's gonna kill the
beacon all right I'm gonna put down a
portal so the way I'm gonna do this I'm
gonna build our zombie Pigman farm
underneath the bedrock like just
directly underneath it and then to use
it I'm going to come on top here and yet
just the perfect distance away from it
like I'll have to go up a little ways
like a hundred blocks up and then zombie
Pigman should spawn like crazy within a
circle area I think yeah where are we
gonna end up here I don't think I can
come back through this portal either oh
we're at the lumber
that's cool I didn't make this portal
here it created it just now go through
we'll probably end up at nether house no
oh uh this looks kind of familiar
how cool you relate it beautiful
this will take this back to the library
nope okay it's takes us to the forest
now I wonder if I had that disabled all
right
not again
okay so beautiful I'm going to get some
stuff together here and we'll start
working on that okay guys we got our
beacon moved on top of the nether here
we're getting their speed to sort them
good I want to talk to you guys a little
bit about my plan with the zombie pigmen
from this cold farm normally if you want
to build a zombie Pigman farm or a gas
farm or wither farm in the nether it
involves like clearing out over a
hundred and twenty eight blocks all
around you in the nether it takes weeks
usually it's not fun it's a big big
project I'm kind of cheating the system
here by going up on top this is very
similar to a sky mob trap which I'm sure
a lot of you are familiar with where you
build your spawning pads up in there and
then the mobs fall down but I'm doing it
sort of in Reverse I'm building the pads
below the ground here like right below
it and then they're gonna fall below
that as well and we're gonna be above
that the reason we're not just like
standing here and building our our
spawning pads above is because when I'm
standing here I'm still within range of
all the spawning spaces below the top of
the nether here if you look at the
entities you can see we have 61 mobs
lingering around down below somewhere
you can hear a gasps Steven so that's
not good and as we go up higher though
that's gonna disappear but something
else we're trying to avoid is this LC
coordinate this loaded chunks as that
increases the game has to check more
spaces to spawn the mobs so it it
decreases the rate they spawn but the
main thing we got to get rid of is those
mobs the 50 or whatever and as we go up
higher here Oh
mobs can only spawn or stay spawned
within 128 blocks of you if they're
outside of that range they pretty much
instantly despawn so as we go up higher
here you're gonna start seeing them
disappear we might have to get up pretty
high before that happens I'm actually
kind of surprised that the number is
going up I'm wondering what's causing
that now like 93 I'm thinking maybe the
max mob now is dependent on the load of
chunks I'm not sure now it's kind of
interesting in fact I'm gonna attest
that if I quit come back so I'll see you
gonna be oh yeah I have to get off this
tower I think for a ton load well anyway
let's keep going here is it 80 any
moment now we're gonna start getting out
of range I thought it would have
happened already oh yeah you can see
it's starting to drop now there must be
a lot of spawning spaces in the ceiling
but we're gonna be clearing out a little
bit of space still just not as much as
we would need to if we builds down below
and you can see as I get near the top
here that number the e is going down to
0 just we're at the top here
I don't think oh you know what it is I
think some Pigman spawned on the beacon
because that's the only place for them
to spawn so that's why we still have
like 10 or so loaded but you can see the
numbers jumping up and down really quick
because they're spawning outside of that
128 block range like if they spawn at
the bottom of the nether or anywhere
below the bedrock at this point they're
gonna instantly despawn on us so
that's that's the general idea behind it
and so if we create a trap like an area
where we want them to spawn where it's
doing that they're gonna spawn very
quickly on our our small spawning pads
and only in our trap so that is our goal
and as we get down here we'll probably
see a bunch of pigment I'm assuming yeah
look at them there's the only place they
could spawn was on the top of this
beacon and I think the portal there so
they spawn
very quickly ah man I messed up guys I
thought I read somewhere that beacons
like affect the whole chunk now
vertically if it's in the range but I
must have just totally got that wrong
because it only comes into effect if I
get within the 50 radius of it like it's
always been I just thought it'd change
for some reason so that means the beacon
is way too high and I'll have to move it
again somewhere but we messed up our sky
line so I can't put it back either I'll
have to find a new place for it but
anyway guess what we have to clear out a
bunch of space for the spawning pads I'm
hoping this does the trick it's
definitely not gonna be the most
efficient way or efficient most blocks
you can break with the TNT doing it this
way but it's it's a quickest way to set
it up so let's have some fun I guess
I'll do this let's break this as well
it's about a stack I had a stack to
start off with I got eight left right
now yeah
bombs away Oh what that do you oh it
blew up I thought it's gonna blow down
yeah well you know what that worked that
worked pretty good in fact if I just did
a couple more of those
yeah that would take care of pretty much
the whole thing mm-hmm so what we're
trying to do with this thing this is our
center point for the mob system right
we're gonna be way up in the sky at this
point here above the bedrock right and
then we need to imagine like semi-sphere
starting there and expanding out
depending on what height we end up being
the lower the better so we want to kind
of cut out a semi sphere here if we can
and then also we need to dig down as
well to give the mobs like a 24 volt
drop so that they'll die and they'll
probably land on hoppers and stuff and
get their resources collected or
something like that so if we cleared out
maybe maybe twice to three times the
space like a circle two or three times
bigger than that I think that would be
plenty so it just so happens and we did
it have some fun this is most of my tnt
supply oh no I did not have an escape
okay let's see what that did
let's even reflect our stuff oh that's a
nice big pocket I did see quite a bit of
our stuff when I died so I think it
survived mostly I supplied it quite
always pick over here there's probably
some stuff down there to see I don't
have my boots got the TNT back I'm using
my sword oh there's a little bit a
little bit of me left up there Oh what
did I get
just ender pearls oh there's something
up there war ender pearls there's a lot
of gas around out there oh wow yeah I
exploded this way too it looks like some
more ender pearls see some ladders down
there that's just gonna a I get my food
back now
we're gonna need that food okay I guess
we should go down just look from a
distance maybe there's something else up
there no yeah
my bad wasting time jungle wood oh
there's my food oh I don't like that
fire dang I bet you Atlanta isn't a fire
somewhere found my boots and my sword
excellent just in time too okay I think
that's everything
good news the flint and steel survived
which means we didn't keep going here
another chance to blow ourselves up we
have an escape path yeah I cleared out a
pretty good amount of space I'm happy
with that
netherrack is very low blast resistance
[Music]
respect the TNT whoa Wow oh I forgot
about that
[Music]
if you if you heard a Pigman like with
the environment I environmental damage
like TNT now or at least in this patch I
think it's a bug the Integra on you yeah
same with Enderman in that jerk
where's his friends now I'm gonna have
to be careful the whole time I'm here
too I've died so many times in the
nether lately it's crazy
come on any when I was wannabes of me I
see you over there
you're thinking about it alright so not
the greatest success rate so far with
this TNT stuff
power to a I think we're clear
got two more to go let's see if we can
survive one of them Oh water but its
water budget and it's up here I'm a
little scared to walk because they're
Pigman down there that are definitely
mad and maybe in this room yeah I think
we're okay
let's get her pic ready let's try this
again this is gonna save a ton worked
using the tnt like this not that takes
long time to break the netherrack but
it's just very convenient Pigman Pigman
check okay I didn't quite get the
ceiling like I would have liked I may
have placed these ones slightly too low
they were one or two box higher it would
be perfect guys thinking about it okay
one left over here
I love TNT it's so much fun
why didn't clear this room up too well
[Music]
nice Oh big open spot - ah left a big
chunk there it's alright I can clear
that most us up with the pic as long as
we get the bulk of it it's fine
although there's a big wall there - I'll
have to deal with so I went through and
cleared a little bit of land here with
the pick some of the corners I did that
one
I still go clear a bit more it goes
pretty quick and I also cleared that one
a bit still got to do that one and that
one and yeah the idea is just to make
this round you know we'll probably have
to put somewhat of a cage on this thing
too so gas can't shoot the spotting pads
I build and I just set up a little fake
spawning pad thing here to see what kind
of rates we get from this if we can the
problem is problem is it's really hard
to see what kind of spawning rates we
actually get because we're gonna be on
top of the nether and we can't just go
down real quick and check oh I hope it
in throw one I think we're good but I'm
gonna try a test here so I think we
should go maybe a hundred blocks up hold
that position for a little bit and then
leave the nether and I would like to see
a couple zombie pigman on that fake
spawning pad if there is there's a good
son that's a good sign that this is
gonna work out really well
and if there's not well maybe just got
on that year
mess something up so ceiling of the
nethers 128 let's go quite have enough
to finish let's go up to about to 28 to
30 or whatever okay numbers are bouncing
that's good hold this position for a
little bit I gotta be careful when I
ender pearl here if there's Pigman on
that beacon I might hit them
alright that's probably enough time whoo
okay so I'm gonna go out of here then
I'm gonna re-enter at the hub and go up
as quick as I can to check the pad all
right I'm gonna reenter the nether now
at the hub and since we're entering
within 128 blocks of those that fake
spawning pad I think should work out
okay as long as we get up there quick
cuz we're over 32 blocks wait so they
can be spun over time terrible throw ah
oh yes
you fell off man one two three four plus
that guy over there yeah that looks very
promising and look at all the other
Pigman laying around this area so as I
clear out more land and get lots of
spawning beds done I suspect this is
gonna work very well I'm gonna use a
piston pushers to knock them off the
pads I think and hoppers to clacks so I
think the idea is gonna work
it's just gonna
I'm gonna have to work on it and I'll
probably do a lot of it off camera
because it's a big project and we're
doing the world tour next episode guys
so look forward to that I think we're
going to go read the comments now for
today though and let's do it
I got a comment fit for today this is
based on last episode etho I think the
reason the nether village isn't working
might be because you're using
transparent blocks for the ceiling /
roof and so it doesn't count
as a proper house because I used brick
half slabs for the ceiling but that's
just my guess maybe try using full brick
blocks for the ceiling under the slabs
that you already had placed hope it
works
aha yeah I think I will try that just to
see just to be just to be sure whether
it works or not
after AF came there for a little bit
longer I did not have any baby villagers
running around the nether village so
this is one more thing to try it yes but
that's gonna be it for today guys
thank you for watching as always I on
the record this is not a good one nope
nope we're not ending it like that no I
gotta get some better records okay bye
bye
you