haha so how's it going everybody this is
ESO welcome back to another episode
bump-bump bomb so you know what I
realized today guys I never showed this
thing working we never tested it out
we're here at the Nexus every episode I
see comments what what is the Nexus what
what's this fool talking about the Nexus
is a giant storage room project we're
doing where we're trying to auto sort
items and then auto retrieve them from a
control panel is basically the ultimate
goal you guys seem to like the stripes
and the sea lanterns again so that's
cool going to change out the floor a
little bit might use these bricks but
less of them we will see but yeah this
side is pretty much all done we should
try it out this guy's been stuck in here
forever
I'm sorry she beat your time has come
let's make sure it works so because I
never actually tried it out so maybe
this is what we'll do we'll put one item
in each of these all the way down not
every single one just to try it we'll
put one there maybe one here let's do it
every every one of these things will
skip to the next dropper oh let's not
use the same item either okay and then
we're going to try retrieve them and
make sure it's all working properly
before I copy this all over and then
realize it oh no I I majorly messed up
I'm an idiot type of thing which I do
often
all right put cobble in there we got
wool let's put that in this one hey why
is that in there alright we'll put that
in the next one
that that made a lot of sense okay so I
tried to figure this out on Tamra it
took way too long so I wrote down my
predictions here on paper this and I
have like a little cheat sheet on the
combination I need for these five levers
so this is the first one second one
third one fourth one fifth one that that
controls five bits which is all that's
needed to make 32 different combinations
which is how many
droppers we have on this side uh-huh
so let's try this thing out I figured to
get that first item we put in we need to
have zero or or off on all of these this
is where we would send the pulse and
then it makes its way down the different
branches it's going to make it yeah we
got it cool all right the second one I
have this on and this on let's try it
out so the idea is we will hook up rapid
pulsing clocks to this line here and
we'll be able to request like different
combinations of you know if you want one
item or four items or 16 or 32 or a
whole stack that'll send it that many
pulses and should be pretty quick next
one is that and then we go switch over
here seems to be working maybe we'll
just do a couple more and then I'll test
it off camera because this could take a
while just want to show you it working
how and how it's actually able to select
between the different droppers
everything seems to work according to
plan let's do one more let's this one
zero one one good all right this was the
slime ball if I remember right Ariel and
that's about how long it takes items to
get your - it's not too bad a couple
seconds uh-huh anyway I just wanted to
show that I will work on it more later
I did some speed mining today we got
like four more stacks of redstone blocks
which is awesome we're going to make our
way over to the end
check out the musical note blocks again
have some ideas you guys suggested the
main suggestion I keep getting is that I
should try a different note block scale
for our note block wait a minute where
are my portals broken again see you guys
this is why we need to redo the nether
hub my portals this is not the first
time this has happened
where has it taken me this time oh man
why does this place seem so familiar to
me
this is so weird oh you know what this
feels like that dream I keep having over
and over guys every time I go to record
I have this crazy dream and this feels
just like it I yes the clay the clay
here I don't know why but I get this
feeling like I like people want me to
harvest it but I keep resisting like
it's wrong but in my heart I know I need
to to appease the people and then in my
dream I finally do it oh I'm scared this
feels all my heart is racing this feels
just like the dream I'm gonna do it Oh
oh no no this is oh man
Oh that just happened
okay okay we're getting out of here
crazy dream dimension I want none of
that seriously that was okay we're good
oh that was really creepy
I think we're yeah we're here okay so
we're gonna make our way over to the end
and the suggestion was that I try a
Penta pentatonic open hopefully I said
that right I was using a whole note well
that was scary she's still doing okay
still bouncing away we got to make like
hamster tubes for this guy oh so many
things to do
I want him like all over the place in
the nether though that would be neat
like if he he had his own little
playground type area but yeah I was
using a whole note scale with our
randomizer apparently that makes it
sound really eerie which is good for the
end but I'm curious what these other
scales sound like Oh as a cat I was like
okay too many strange things happening I
just heard some weird noise had no idea
what it was okay it's still working this
time last time I entered the end it
stopped for some reason
don't look crazy okay so what I'm gonna
do I'm gonna tune it according to what
you guys said and we will compare the
difference with what we have now
okay so we gotta tuned up here according
to a pentatonic scale there must be
several different ones where people have
told me wrong information I'm worried
now because I was looking at the
comments and someone told me to tune it
this way someone told me to a different
way and they they both called it the
pentatonic so let's hope this is right I
so it sounds like uh-huh
then there's three extra ones here I'm
just gonna put blocks over top so they
don't play any sound so be a little bit
less note Box playing here um let's try
it out see what's like it's also minor
steel major scale and probably more
Skills than we have time to try out oh
you know we gotta go in too quick wait a
second switches back to two sounded cool
so I think the idea behind is that the
notes are more likely to harmonize with
each other or the chords i intel already
it's more cheery happy you're sounding
that's pretty good I like that hopefully
I got it right I definitely noticed the
difference though um should we try other
Steel's we kind of did this last time
play around with it yourself if you are
interested it's really easy to set up um
I'll leave at that though that sounds
pretty good
all right it's moving on I just won the
game amazing yes I am okay hmm
so I'm at a bit of a loss here guys I
think our poppy farm stopped producing
poppies what good is a poppy farm
oh that's weird if it doesn't produce
any poppies well it's got poppies it
doesn't have something else I kind of
want um I think I left those in there
from before actually yeah it doesn't
seem to be making anymore those the
problem um we need we need more a lot
more I'm maybe a little swim up there
and just check what's going on if you
guys have any ideas let me know I don't
know much about these poppy farms it
doesn't look like there's any iron gol
I'm stuck up here though I heard that
maybe this two-by-two hole doesn't work
too well sometimes we get stuck if more
than one spawns up here but I think it
just totally stopped producing them for
some reason and then we'll see any still
get the villagers I hear the villagers
okay the doors are still here water
streams not messed up I really don't
know what's going on oh is that going to
be good oh just barely on the edge got
one two we need to end three four five
six okay seven eight one more side Oh
what No
are you serious how did they die did it
they glitch and a block from the chunk
loading or something one two okay I got
it I got it I got find the problem I
don't know what caused them to die which
might be an issue yeah we're we're short
some the doors aren't broken are they
everything looks fine know that yeah
this is one they died in did I forget
the roof no there's a roof here I really
don't get that there was at least two
villagers in there I'm sure maybe three
huh all right what we're gonna do next
guys oh I think they glitched into a
block or else I'm suffering from the
entity's disappearing issue I'm still on
the pre-release one I never upgraded yet
what we're going to do next we're going
to head over to here I just want to
scope out an idea up happy quite a while
the abandoned mineshafts oh man ooh
currently there's only one way in and
that's it sometimes I get stuck down
here is the problem
so cool this is where we we did the
donation signs and the mineshaft and the
cool rail line and yeah so I looked into
trying to make a path to hear from the
man cave let's just follow this I was
hoping to make a nice Road actually if
it's possible oh it's right at lava
level yeah that makes sense that's where
the diamonds are right I mean the red
stone the red stone I don't know what
diamonds are um comes out to here where
is here how do we connect here to the
man cave I did lots Oh easy
oh I should know my way actually this
this is a familiar area it is this it
I hear the note blocks going yeah this
is it right
goes up yeah okay here we are here we
are and this is the start of the man
cave
the lowest point on it so we might try
to make a nice road here and then then
we'll start expanding downward with the
man cave which would be cool okay so we
are going to try a little bit of a
darker color combo here usually I would
like to build in this style but oops it
is down at lava level and what is going
to burn there so we have to try
something else
I'm planning on putting the get on get
off departure arrival stage station over
here for it it's going to go like to the
right and then have to be an elevator to
go down a little bit and then I think it
goes this way all the way to the
mineshaft and be kind of out of the way
that way too but anyway let's let's just
try so I went the wrong way
here we go here we go oh man I am so bad
with mazes and that's like what the
whole tunnel system is here all right
yeah good because we got these sections
here with big lava pools I don't really
want to get rid of those I kind of want
to highlight them so I'm planning on
putting glass black glass over those see
how that works out fortunately we are
very low on building materials right now
so we'll have to deal with that like
we're out of glass we're out of clay
pretty much all right how does that look
I think black glass is pretty good
then in areas where there is no lava I
was going to put possibly this black
stained clay stuff oh but you know what
I think I wanted to put the glass over
top that still so this go down one more
like here then the glass would go over
top yeah I think that's right and then
on the sides I was considering using oh
don't mind if I do I wanted to try
nether break we got lots of nether brick
just laying around kind of want to get
rid of it because taking up space and we
don't have a lot of storage space right
now until the Nexus is done all right so
do that and then have like just a sec
unfortunately I'm running really low on
time I wasted too much time on that
thing I did earlier so we're not going
to get very far but I want to do this
and one of these maybe have pillar every
five blocks or four blocks
then like this something like that that
way it makes it feel a little bit more
spacious if you have the stairs over
here down the middle is going to put
black panes black beans and I think
stone slabs here I did not bring them
with me though let's do it real quick do
oh yeah okay and hopefully it doesn't
look really stupid with water going over
top this I don't know I haven't tried it
yet because it's going to be blue and
red but might not quite go together but
we'll see yeah something like that
okay everyone so check this out this is
sort of a rough idea of what its gonna
look like let me know if you like it
doesn't quite match the rest of the man
cave like the man caves more of a nature
themed area don't think it matters too
much because this is sort of its own
separate thing we're not going to be
able to see the two together so we can
really do whatever we want with this
tunnel but yeah let me know what you
think about it hopefully it doesn't look
bad when it's all done I don't have any
more materials that I'm gonna have to go
farm some and I think I'm just going to
call it the end of the episode because I
am outta time to record so sorry for the
shorter episode today I had a busy
weekend but anyway here is the comment
for today it says I was going to get
this game but it looks very complicated
I think he means minecraft why are most
games either over complex or too
simplistic aha you know what I think the
answer is the same to both those it's
because our attention spans are so much
shorter these days a game is complex
because we're not willing to put the
time into to figure it out and it's too
simplistic because game designers need
to make things simplistic for people
short attention spans so it's kind of a
is that a catch-22 I think
so um I find I have that problem myself
like I don't put the time into learning
a videogame or getting into it like I
used to like back in the day used to
spend 80 bucks for a Nintendo game you
play a Nintendo game now it's like
really people spend hours and hours
playing this thing compared to the games
we have nowadays yeah but you
appreciated the game is more back then
then then we do now there's so many
games nowadays it's really hard to focus
on one of them and when when I play a
game it's like you know I should play
this game instead all it or I should be
playing Minecraft err you know I'm
always thinking about what I should be
doing instead of this this particular
game instead of just enjoying the game
and sitting down and playing it and
having a good time I don't know with the
exception of some games of course some
games are just really really good um
anyway guys that's it for today I hope
you enjoyed the episode I will see you
again in the next one
take care have a good day bye bye