[Music]
hello everybody
snacks how's it going today get your
snacks
i was doing a little bit of mining
around with the strongholds we are
really low actually this
is at y17 found a spider spawner
that's what's in it not bad double chest
and then there's also a tabe spider one
right here this is really close to the
stronghold
so it's pretty good uh i've been using
silk touch when i
go mining around here because i don't
have a fortune one with me
and i like it because you don't use up
all your inventory space
as quickly because otherwise
to hold a stack of redstone blocks uh
would be
probably five stacks of redstone dust
you know in your inventory so it's nice
that way
really good loving the new ai for caving
makes it so much more fun
they can find you from miles away it
seems
and uh i was on i was playing on the
minecraft server the other day
caving and i got creepered at least
20 times within like five minutes
just one after another they kept coming
kept finding me somehow it was amazing
but i didn't record it unfortunately i
should have
okay so i thought this might be
something fun to do
these are all the blocks i got from
mining around that stronghold with my
silk touch
and we are going to break them all with
the fortune 3 pick and see how much
how much diamond and lapis and
everything we get so we have
16 diamond 25 lapis
115 redstone and 181
coal so i'll probably just show you the
the good stuff the diamond lapis and
maybe the redstone
very curious how much it averages out to
with fortune 3
and this is going to be very fun too for
me anyway because i need to keep all
this stuff
all right here we go
nice very nice oh look at all those blue
shiny rocks
creeper no
okay we got 32 so that's uh twice as
many diamond
it's two diamond per block with fortune
3 that averages out to
doesn't mean it'll always be like that
but with this uh test we did that's what
we got
lapis i'm curious about because it's
very
it fluctuates a lot how much you get
from lapis sometimes you get
like five and sometimes you get 25 it
seems
although i don't know the exact numbers
all right so that was 25
lapis right yeah yeah 25.
i wrote it down just in case i forget
look at some some of them have just tons
all right oh that looks so cool
[Applause]
got it all yeah okay so what do we get
here
four stacks and 56 so 256
plus 56 is 312.
312 divided by
25 averages out to 12.48
each 12.48 each each block
and finally redstone
uh maybe i'll just show you a few and
then i'll do the rest off camera
i want to say thanks to elle the
hedgehog he has made me a new
intro if you saw my last uh
minecraft video you would have seen the
intro there it's very cool i like it
thanks man he surprised me like he did
the first time he just said
i was bored one day so i made this for
you
use it if you want type thing and the
other day when i checked my private
messages
he did that again for me with the second
intro
just surprise here's an intro so
thanks man i appreciate it
and i'll probably use the old intro that
he made me for the lp still
and the new intro maybe for s p
tutorials and other stuff just so it
kind of averages out to
using both of them 50 50 so that there's
more variety with my intros because uh
i know a lot of people are kind of
getting bored of the
oh yeah look at all that redstone
of my uh of the other intro even though
it's a really good intro if you see it
over 100 times it might get a little
boring so
if i use it a little bit less from now
on i think people
will still continue to like it i should
say
okay so i'm gonna do the rest of it here
and i'll be back
oh yeah
[Applause]
alrighty so this is what we got from all
that
our 16 diamond got turned into 32
we got let's see we had 115 redstone and
that got turned into
671 and we had 25
lapis and that got turned into 312.
and this is the coal we had 181 coal
and with the fortune 3 we got 582
so i hope i'm pretty sure i got the math
right on this that works out to
2.0 for the diamonds per or
uh 5.0 five
points 834
for the redstone per ore and
lapis was 12.48
and finally the coal was
five 3.2154 not that the last ah
there we go so that should give you a
rough idea of what fortune 3 does with
the oars
the diamond here and the lapis we were
using a very small
sample size so it's probably a little
bit
more inaccurate than the redstone and
the coal
but yeah it's good to know that
the averages with fortune 3 uh
i have no idea what fortune 1 and
fortune 2 do in comparison
the wiki says actually i can't remember
what the wiki says
fortune 3 is supposed to add 120 percent
to your findings but obviously that's uh
doesn't seem right to me because you
only get one coal normally and 120
percent
of like plus 120 percent of one coal is
not three points you know
so i don't know that's so
that's what i found with this little
example though
oh yeah we're sitting real pretty here
now we got over three stacks of the blue
shiny rocks
and we have more of these things and i
know what to do with them i rarely use
them when building because i don't know
how to
make thing use blocks that match them or
that go with them i guess i tried it on
my
potion room door before but people
really didn't like how that looks so
yeah they're a tough one for me to use
got lots of gold
and tons of iron again which is great
we're gonna do
one of my favorite things in the game
make a stack of iron blocks
i don't know why i enjoy that so much
but i do we're gonna head off to the
nether today
a lot of people have been requesting
that i do which is awesome because i
love
doing other projects and i would do them
more often but people really don't seem
to like the nether or
don't like it when i spend a lot of time
there in a row
and that's our redstone so yeah we're
doing good here
uh i want to do some zombie pigmen
experiments or just i want to kill them
that's what i want to do
so we're going to bring that with us and
i got my potions ready already
so i think we're good to go here
okay here we are so the reason these
guys have me interested
is the new mob ai i'm wondering
how they react when you aggro them
like you know how they swarm at you i'm
wondering if when they're swarming if
they do
the intelligent ai or if they just run
off cliffs and
just be lying to you like they did
before
that's the main thing i want to try out
here and i'm also curious
what kind of drops we get how often we
get them
and i just want to get them period and i
want to get some gold
so here we go
i mainly want to watch you guys on the
cliff there
okay yeah they just b-line still that's
too bad
that would be pretty amazing if they uh
were really intelligent when they
swarmed you like that
no drops yet let's just kill a few
see if we can get a magma cream those
are really hard to get
oh yeah
not that i really need it because
i can make hundreds of them pretty easy
um so there's basically three mobs in
the game that give the rare drops i
think
we got the skeletons the zombies and the
zombie pigmen here give the rare drops
they give golden swords i think and
gold ingots and i think a gold helmet
maybe a few other things
oh did we get one
no darn
oh i thought i saw a sword drop
[Music]
i wonder if like i have looting three on
the sword i wonder if it increases the
chances of getting
the rare drops too
[Music]
so yeah we're gonna go to the blaze farm
today
uh i'm really worried it's
not gonna be working anymore with the
new ai because they can
see through glass a lot of the mobs
and i'm worried the blades are going to
be able to too
[Music]
and if that's the case they're going to
track me through the glass and they
won't
uh go down my conveyor belt
thing and all that that i have set up so
i want to check that out and at the same
time i don't want to because i'm worried
it's
all going to be broken and i've wasted
so much time on that thing
trying to get it right and now it might
not work at all
[Music]
all right i'm gonna kill this gas and
then we're gonna go over there
i'm gonna try to no don't run away
oh so close so close
one hits wow
this sword is awesome okay
uh i will see you at the blaze trap
oh iron ingot i got a rare drop awesome
that that made this uh complete for me
that was awesome iron is the new gold by
the way
yeah it's been a long time since i've
been here
many many weeks it feels like and
actually has been many weeks from that i
got
about three stacks of gold
nuggets we got one ingot and we got two
swords one was enchanted with sharpness
one
so that was pretty fun
good run so we're going to turn the mob
system on and see what happens i don't
know
i'm really worried
come on oh perfect 22
nice and we'll probably use those in a
little bit i killed three gas
each one dropped the tier with my sword
um hmm
oh that could have been dangerous
actually uh
where was the switch i don't even
remember i think i was just doing one at
a time
let's see what happens here
so we never did actually get the setup
fully
not so far so good uh one other problem
i'm going to have is they're
going to fall down there all that quick
because they no longer see those signs
as ground their path finding so they
won't freely walk off like they did
before
so i might have to put some pistons at
this top row too to make that happen
quicker
okay they're not tracking me that is
very good
hmm
oh my sounds not working okay i got to
reboot minecraft
i was having some video issues too
okay and that guy's coming up one of
them is getting suffocated i never
did tweak this so that it was working
perfectly
might be a little bit challenging so i
guess
i gotta put pistons around this top row
unfortunately i'll probably work on that
now
but they'll they'll come up here
and i gotta i gotta hook up a crusher
and i'll probably end up making it so i
can punch him to death or also use
splash potions to kill
i think that would be best but i gotta
make it sure i do it so that their stuff
won't fall
in this lava below otherwise i'll lose
it all
so i got that extra layer of pistons
added to the top here
there are six per side uh they're done
the
same way as the ones below this is the
pressure plate repeater
to block them to the piston and i have
to put the blocks in front of the
pistons yet i just wanted to show you
before
i did so you can see it
so when the blaze spawn up here they'll
get pushed down
uh the pistons blows get activated too
because uh they're directly below
[Music]
the pressure plates are diagonal to the
pressure plates and they get updated
it doesn't have much of an effect though
and i also got rid of the signs because
they no longer did anything
so no need for them so we're going to
put the blocks on
and we're going to give it another try
and be very careful i don't get pushed
here
all right you get the idea
so i am a little bit sad about uh
these pistons are blocking uh the
blaze farm here a little bit i really
like the way it looked before
and now um we got all these pistons in
the way
of the viewing area i may actually get
rid of the ones
on this side only which would lower the
efficiency a little bit but i don't
think it'll have much impact
just as long as i don't have more than
two blaze
up here within range of the spawner oh i
did it
i can't believe i did it all right
quick quick
that was scary
[Music]
he's override it it's about the only
time we'll get to
um what was i talking about
yeah i might get rid of that one side
just so we can
uh view it a little bit better let me
out of here
because originally i intended of sort of
having this is an area where you would
be quite often
and you could clearly see the blaze
spawning inside
and it looks cool with the lava coming
down and then below you can see the
conveyor belt which also looks really
cool
and i want to try to keep that look if i
can
so i may just get rid of this one side
uh i'm gonna finish this up i guess it
is finished right
yeah so we'll block it off and then we
will
let them spawn again and see what
happens here
and i took out a few blocks here
there we go
yeah so that uh king of the hill on the
ladders
king of the ladders that was a lot of
fun if you watch the last mine track
episode number 10.
yeah you can't see the blaze at all uh
we had a lot of fun doing that
just happened we didn't really plan on
playing that we just
started and we couldn't stop it was so
much fun
we actually played it for about it was
between two or three hours but i edited
the footage down to
um just under an hour there
all right now that's working and i left
this open
so i should probably close that
now i i was playing around with this
before and i know i never showed this
but i don't know if it's set up at the
moment
like i said i haven't been here in weeks
but i think what i was trying to do
here is uh cut the lava
oh right they fall down
i was having trouble with this i
remember so i have to activate the lower
one
and the upper one and then
now they're now they're up so
yeah because we gotta get them in that
holding area
if we don't have lava though they won't
swim up
and if we do have lava the items will
drop in it so we need to get them up
and get rid of the lava
so that seems to be
working okay
[Music]
and then any extra that come we'll just
wait down there and stay separate from
the ones we
crush here and then we can kill them and
then let
the other ones up by root
by doing that
yeah so this might be set up already
pretty good okay
yeah it's really hmm
it's really jamming up the conveyor
um just watching it a little bit here
it's it's only jams up if there there's
a bunch of them at once otherwise it's
fine
all right well i'll watch it a little
bit more off camera here
get a better idea of things
okay
yeah so i just remembered another
problem i was having with this
before um if i
do it the way i have it set up now
there's an issue where their feet can
get stuck
in that block that just extended
that happens if they're not jumping
so that's a problem because
if we try to crush them they're going to
be one block too low and they won't take
any
suffocation damage
um also there's no lava below because we
cut it off but
we can fix that by having a second lava
source just below the pistons
so that they'll continue to swim up even
when it's cut off like this
that's not a big deal but i think what i
want to try
is replace this block with a half slab
and then put another half slab just
below this one
like on top and then
uh use try see if
this block extending out will crush them
so they'll be half of half a block
below this one and their head will be
half a block above and then
i don't know if that causes suffocation
damage we'll see
so i'm gonna get rid of these guys and
we'll try it out
all right let's see how this works so
we're just going to extend
this half slab should push them up
nope no it's too bad
um
let's try it again
yeah all right we'll have to do
something else then
uh i'm gonna extend that glass
it'll definitely work if we extend that
first
i was hoping to do this with two pistons
though instead of three
and now i just want to see if this
crushes them so we do have a half slab
of
over there and that there's one there
and finally yeah
are they all getting crushed no i don't
think they are
that's very weird
it's happening like one after another
instead of all at once
that is really weird
i wonder why it's doing that
all right so that setup won't work uh
i guess i'll continue to play with this
some more off camera
it's getting very late here though so i
will call it an
end for today uh we might work on this
some more next episode
uh we probably will and hopefully we'll
finally get it up and running
and i gotta transfer those pistons over
to that side
and i'll probably get rid of this one
side of them like i said just for
a better view and then i gotta
fix this holding area up i could just
have it down below but i i want it up
high just for
the looks of it and this will be like
the main floor over here
i plan on doing another one of these
like holding areas
on this side and that will be for zombie
pigmen i'm gonna make a little farm for
them it won't be super efficient or
anything just
just something to collect them
one day but anyway
thanks for watching i'll see you next
time