[Music]
hello everybody this is etho
and we are in the end right now uh
remember i said uh i was having trouble
getting silk touch
i did like 20 or 30 picks in a row
without getting it
uh now i got four in a row
believe it or not and two of them are
pretty good they got unbreaking three
efficiency four uh these are unbreaking
three and breaking three
just got another unbreaking three ea
um there's the other good one and i
think i carried
the other two so-so ones back to the
main world
now i got four four new ones which is
pretty cool but i keep getting these
unbreaking three ones now and i wanted
to try
something this is a trick i heard
of where you can put them in the storage
minecarts
and then break it to get rid of the
enchantment the only other way i know of
getting rid of enchantments
is to repair
the enchanted item
all right so we put this in because i
don't want to waste the diamonds on
these things if that's what i'm getting
oh they must have fixed that glitch darn
unless i did it wrong i don't know
pretty sure
that's what you were supposed to do
one more time
yeah they must have fixed it too bad um
it's the only way to repair is to repair
it i guess but that's not
i don't think you can repair a full item
like this
i don't know they're useless to me
though
pretty much only thing i'd really use
them for is maybe netherrack but that's
it
anyway today's project is probably going
to be in the end here today
i we're not going to spend the whole
episode in the end but
i've mentioned before that i kind of
view this place as my
skyblock survival area
to me the cool thing about minecraft is
you
start in an empty world basically and
make
cool stuff happen awesome stuff right
you make it happen
out of nothing basically and here that
takes it to a new
extreme where there actually is
absolutely
nothing but air so
that's why i really like the idea of
building stuff in the end
it's just although it's not quite like
skyblock survival
but just idea of making something out of
nothing is cool to me
anyway so the vision i kind of see for
this place
is to have a bunch of islands floating
islands
some higher some lower uh kind of spread
out all over the place
and some bigger some smaller different
shapes and everything that's kind of
like what i
what i would like to do here or at least
in this area around the
the ender ender here um
and today we're going to see just how
feasible that idea
is we're going to try make an island i
would like them all to kind of have a
purpose
too the main thing i want right now
i have to walk this long thing
every every time i come here
because i gotta go this way and then
when i when i want to leave i have to go
all the way back here to the portal
um a lot of people don't seem to know
how i leave the end with all my stuff
once you kill the dragon a portal forms
and you just go through the portal
so it's pretty simple you get to keep
all your your levels and all your items
that way
but yeah what i really want is some type
of road i was thinking of doing an
eats road from maybe from
this is the platform you arrive on maybe
from here to
there to an eye to a floating island we
build
and at the bottom of the floating
islands i think it'd be cool to have
vines but
i'm a little scared of vines i gotta
admit we're gonna do
some tests with them today that's kind
of what i want to do right now
and just see how they work because i'm
not too familiar with them i've never
used them in a project before
so let's head back
see that's what happens you go through
the portal this was made when the dragon
was killed
press escape to skip the credits which i
have done every single time
and it takes you back to your last spawn
area
which is my bed here
okay i'm going to collect some vines and
we will do some experimenting with them
all right so i got some vines collected
here and we're going to do a few tests
uh i'm a little sad i've never really
used them for anything because
not only do they look pretty good
but like they're good for a visual look
but they're also
pretty handy with other functions like
with mobs mobs aren't able to see
through them or
you can use them as brakes to reset your
fall damage
ladders and lots of other stuff so it's
a really useful block and i've never
really used it before but
i was looking at the wiki and it says uh
one of the reasons i was afraid of them
before is because they spread like
wildfire
and apparently they still do spread
according to the wiki
um it says they can spread left right
i think up and obviously down i know
vines spread
infinitely down until they hit a block
or reach the bottom of the world
which is a concern of mine for these
islands because i don't want the vines
to go
down like hundreds of blocks i just want
them a certain length and then
stop growing hopefully which is
one of the challenges we're gonna have
to
be clever about here so
the wiki says as long as there's not
four vines in the area they will be able
to spread i don't know
what area it means like how
what kind of area checks but
should be able to spread up i think left
and right
and obviously down i don't know if like
that vine can spread
to the other side of this block or
anything like that
it's one thing i'm very interested in
and i don't really know what kind of
lighting conditions are required either
so we're going to set up a dark room
here and put some in
just to get a another idea of that
give it all these torches make it dark
oh we missed one oh yeah nice and dark
so
light level zero perfect
okay so we'll see how those ones grow
and then also
this is the most important test what
we're about to do here this is uh
this is how i'm going to control the
length of them if this works i hope it
does
i'm going to put a vine
in the middle of this with blocks on all
six sides
like that and my idea is
have it so when the vines reach a
certain length whatever length we want
make it so that they will be within rain
excuse me range of lava or fire and
catch fire
and then they'll burn up a ways
and then they'll regrow and keep getting
longer and then
get shorter kind of like a way of giving
it a haircut
every so often uh but the thing i'm
concerned about
obviously is that the vines will burn up
completely
which would suck because then you would
have to manually place them again
which i definitely don't want so
if i can hide them
like this and have them spread to the
outside
uh it'll make it so it's impossible for
the fire to burn it up but yet they'll
they'll always be at least one vine
there to
to renew the ones that possibly burn up
type thing
okay so i think uh
i think that's all i want to test so
we're gonna watch these for a bit i
might set up a few more
examples here too while i wait
and we're back here so
i've left the game running for over an
hour
while i sit in a little hole type thing
and i've come back
and now i'm trying to make
sense of everything here and i'm not
didn't quite figure out as much as i had
hoped but i did learn a few things from
this
so the one that was here has grown
uh it's able to pass around corners like
that
and it's actually made it all the way to
the back here even
so i'm guessing it went to the side and
maybe drew up and then
to the side again or something i don't
know but it has
reached the limit it seems because this
one's been like this for a long time and
it's not even growing down here
so it's like too many vines in that area
but i haven't been able to figure out
what the area is
i still don't know this one too it's
reached the limit remember we placed the
vine here
it's grown to the left and the right and
down on all three
but it didn't go around the corner and
it's there's none on the back or
anything
so that one's reached the limit too
this one surrounded everything and grew
down
all the way so it covered everything but
i didn't give it any more space to grow
this one i placed it right here just one
vine
and it's grown up it's drawn down it's
growing around the side
and yeah it seems to reach the limit too
so i don't know i really don't know what
the area is these ones unfortunately
did not grow outside of the box
oh they filled the box though that's
interesting
and i did another one over here
same type of situation
um then i right after i did that i
thought maybe since those ones are
growing around the corners here that
maybe
if i used a non-solid block like glass
that it would be able to pass
from that face to this side over here
but it never did
i'm still going to try one more thing i
want to try
with a sign there and see if
that vine is able to pass around the
corner to that that side
because that vine still wouldn't burn
if there's a sign here
and i did this where i have them
underneath
i had these two vines here underneath
and they did not grow up or anything and
i even put
a few blocks here to see if they could
jump from
from there to like over here and it
never happened so
yeah so i figured a little bit out about
it
but uh still gonna play around a bit to
really understand how these vines are
are working and what the area is
this one is just doing a fire test i
think it might
be better oh you can't place it i
thought you could place fines on vines
well maybe you need a block to place it
on first i don't know
i think it might be better just to use
water or pistons or something to break
the vines instead of fire i don't know
we'll worry about another day oh and
this is something i just did recently i
was wondering if it could spread
infinitely sideways like this
so i put down three it's spread one
block over here
and i'm just going to watch it a while
and see if it continues spreading
to the right and left here but we're
gonna head back to the end
and maybe start work on an island
hopefully
i'm running out of time though
oh and i forgot about our dark vines
over here they have actually grown quite
a bit
uh
so these ones over here seem to still be
growing
uh and same with these ones but this one
has reached a limit too so it hasn't
been expanding
for a long long time but these ones i
think are still growing
so again i don't know what area it
checks
i don't know because there's two vines
in the one block so i don't know if that
counts as two vines
or if it's still just one vine i'm
guessing it must count as two
so there's actually five vines in this
area even though it's three
vine blocks if you know what i mean
okay so we're in the end again here and
i am about to start building
the floating island their first one uh
i'm a little worried about this this is
gonna be a challenge for me i've never
built
any type of floating island or anything
i have no experience with it and i'm
worried it's gonna look terrible when
i'm all done here
but hopefully it turns out we'll see
and it's just it's a real challenge
building them i think
even though i've never done it usually
when
people try to build a floating island in
vanilla
minecraft it turns out to be
like one thick and kind of a big giant
square in the sky
basically uh it's really going to be
hard to shape it and it's going to be
if i do lots of them there's another
issue of running out of materials
i got a lot of soil with me here but
if it's not going to be just one thick
i'm going to use a lot of blocks
building it so
my plan for this is to kind of construct
a shell
and shape it out of soil
or dirt or whatever you want to call it
and then once i got the shape and
everything figured out in the size and
i'm happy with it
i'm gonna fill it with water and then
pour lava on top
one layer at a time same way i made this
pad here
i filled this all in with water and then
i poured lava
and it was a very quick way of placing
the blocks
and also uh very cheap
because i don't need to place or collect
a thousand
thousands of stone blocks to fill the
island if i do it this way
so we are going to be building departure
island
is our first one it's going to connect
directly
in line with the the portal to leave
here
excuse me which is at z negative
did i say z i mean that i'm sorry z
negative
nine and y
65 or so is what we want to be at so i
think i'll build it
a little ways away from our end or ender
here not too far away though
maybe
maybe around here would look good we're
going to eventually get rid of
of that thing here in this path i want
to be gone
and now is the challenge of
shaping it and everything maybe i'll go
up to
here make it about 10 thick or so i
don't know
um and i kind of want to make
an l-shaped island maybe
so i guess i'll just play around with it
a bit and see how it goes
all right everybody here is the island
i got it all shaped out and
got most of the shell complete for it so
that was the first layer down there that
i started on just kind of got a
the basic shape that i wanted and then
every layer i just outlined the same
shape
and went up so that's kind of makes it a
45 degree angle that
it expands wider
and then at this top layer i made it
expand two blocks
so don't know how that's gonna look i
hope it's okay
it'll be kind of 45 degree
anglish because of that but
makes it really easy to build if i
follow that pattern
and i decide to make the shell mostly
out of soil
or entirely out of soil i should say i
don't know if that's a good move or not
i could have used stone
for it or other things or do the bottom
out of something and then
decide something else i don't know
hope hopefully it looks good when this
is all done and then
once it's all done i'll probably have to
go underneath and
shape the the bottom a little bit so
it's not completely flat like it is
there
and yeah the torches are to prevent
enderman from spawning because they will
destroy this place in seconds otherwise
but they are also teleporting from down
there
to over here and they are
slowly trying to destroy it so i need to
hurry up finish filling this in with
stone
so that that's not as big of a problem
until i can figure out how to stop it
what i should do sometimes figure out
how far these guys can teleport because
there going to be a problem constantly
if i do this floating island thing
so yeah anyway i'm going to
grab some lava grab some water we're
going to do this layer by layer
as much as we can today no
don't don't steal
stealing is bad
oh man i'm so scared going down there
because i think
i'm always worried i looked at them
okay this is what it looks like from
underneath
and also when we shape the bottom we'll
put vines on probably and maybe figure
out a way to prevent them
from growing infinitely to the bottom of
the world
okay everybody so i've done two layers
already and it went pretty well
uh basically all i'm doing is putting
water down
making a lake on uh on the whole layer
here
and then we pour lav over top to convert
it to stone
and it's yeah it seems to work good it's
quick
uh the thing that takes the longest is
waiting for the lava to disappear
afterwards
but uh something i've been thinking of
doing is just put
pouring water over top the remaining
lava to convert it to
cobblestone i don't know
but yeah it's seems to be okay
uh if you guys have any ideas on how to
oh no no no no on how to make a floating
island
or ways i could do this better please do
let me know i am all ears
getting an organic shape is really tough
i'm kind of happy with how this turned
out just because it's my first attempt
but
it does look fairly symmetrical
which i kind of expected because i was
just copying the same shape over and
over again
um
but yeah if you have better ideas on how
to improve this
or not better ideas just ideas on how to
prove this i haven't
given any ideas on how to improve it
uh let me know uh
i am going to try to shape the bottom
though oh he's dead
so that it's uh fairly vertical and then
it'll get to the 45
degree angle spot so it'll go up quickly
and then
kind of round out and then near the top
it's
even wider so it'll create a
bevel shape hopefully and
yeah then i'll put the binds on and
whatever if they look good
okay so we got our lake now we're gonna
pour the for the lava
and it just spreads out like that and we
juggle it
really like this method i think i i'm
going to use it for a lot of things as
far as placing blocks
lots and lots of blocks quickly this is
probably
the best way of doing it that i can
think of
um
well i guess it depends what you're
doing like getting leaves and stuff
is a really quick way of getting blocks
too
and placing them whoa
but obviously we wouldn't want to use
leaves in this case
oh dance i did it
i hate when i do that
also um exciting news for me anyways
channels getting very close to 150 000
subscribers so thank you
everybody for all your supports and
what's it been over a year now anyway
i've been doing this
it's much appreciated and welcome all
newcomers
i'm just gonna get another lava bucket i
guess
um and hopefully not die
here
[Music]
yeah lots of new people it's cool
i probably won't be able to do a hundred
and fifty thousand
150 000 subscribers special this time
around
well i guess it's the only time around
right but uh yeah i haven't done a
special in a while and i feel bad about
it
but just been busy
with work and stuff so the only way i
could really do it is if i was to stop
making
videos for like a week or so to get the
extra time needed
and i'm sure people would not like that
so
probably best just to skip it this time
um with my work
it is taking a bit of time i'm just
i'm managing to get a video out every
day which i'm happy about but beyond
that
not a whole lot of uh extra time to do
more
and it's going to be that way until
about june and then i'll
pretty much have a lot of free time i'm
hoping
to really put out videos and
and do more stuff which i'm excited for
um let's talk about a few other things i
can't remember now
hmm oh i hate when that
happens i don't like make notes or
anything when i
when i record i just kind of get a
rough idea of what i'm gonna say before
i start and
quite often i'll just mess up
uh maybe i'll pause the video for a
second think
what i was gonna say
yeah i don't know nothing really came to
mind i think i was just going to mention
about my map because i had a few people
asking
uh what the progress is and i just i
haven't been working on it
i haven't had time really and i've been
discouraged to work on it because the
whole mc edit
issue and the change with the new
map formats from what i've heard the
mcedit
version out right now is
fairly buggy so
been just been putting it off i guess
but hopefully one day maybe
a few months down the line it'll
actually get completed
is my dream but uh
yeah i think we're gonna end the episode
about
here for today uh
because i'm gonna have to wait for this
lava to disappear i could just
pour water on it but then it'll convert
to cobble and it won't
be really clean
pattern or anything so it'll be hard to
place water for the next layer
so i think it's it's better probably
just to wait the five minutes or so for
it to
disappear
all right well i'll talk to you guys
again another day
and i don't know what project we'll do
next
i kind of want to get started on the new
base by the silverfish farm
but uh we'll see
so bye bye thanks for watching