lessons of life by eso lesson one is
this how people react to you when you
step into an elevator take a shower wash
your clothes use mouthwash and deodorant
it'll improve your life trust me because
I know oh I know I once walked into an
elevator and knocked a man unconscious
he had to go to the hospital they put
him on oxygen and he survived I'm just
kidding I'm picking a story up he
actually died in the hospital uh so
hello everybody this is Ito now starting
it starting episodes is probably the
toughest thing for me I never know what
to do um and they get so repetitive if
you always do the same thing uh but yes
welcome welcome everybody um what what
should we do today that's the next stuff
thing about starting episodes that the
main thing I've been working on pretty
much the only thing I've been working on
since last episode is the lab so let's
go check it out show you what kind of
progress I've made
oh I've put in a 3x3 door that's kinda
like the last thing I just did here it's
not quite done I don't have a switch to
open it or anything
I've never done a nice door like this I
thought it would be a fun fun little
experiment and yeah I kind of liked it
might do that um another idea I had was
to do what am I looking for this could
either do an ice store this is my switch
for opening it at the moment it's not
too good but it works I don't want to do
a nice store we might do something like
no no get it right get it right oh I
know what I need to grab I need it
stairs um yeah I've been working on this
this lab for quite a bit of time here
it's a very slow project
lots of finicky little details to it and
of course I'm using every single tough
to get Block in the game I'll just
reverse it
oops I placed I place the Box wrong um
this isn't going so well usually it if
this happens I just start recording
again and pretend I never messed up but
we'll keep going here alright put them
there there there and there
this this is another idea for the door
kind of like the the building I made on
mine track I have a door like this I
kind of like that too and changes the
courts but anyway let's go inside
the lab let me know what you guys think
of this oh boy so much courts so much
clay so much redstone so much iron and
every other hard to get Block in the
game has got into this build but I
really like it actually I decided to go
with red clay for the ceiling and at
first I started placing it's like nope
that doesn't work then I tried a bunch
of other things and then I decided to
give it another shot and did the whole
roof like that I don't know if it works
but I actually really liked it now that
it's all done I've gotten used to it it
might be a little shocking to you guys
but I think it once you see it for a
while you kind of start to like it I
don't know I really like it now that
I've been been working in here for a
while and we got lamps and stuff
lighting the way so we have no torches
and I think that improves the look of it
builds so much when you can get rid of
torches because you got an ugly ugly
thing blocking the view of your blocks
and then it has particle effects and
it's animated it's really distracting
from the build if you have torches I
find so for most my builds I try to not
use torches where I can not always but
most of the time so yeah we got to our
brewing setups here we got four of them
built so far and we're not done as you
can see we still have empty wall here we
actually need to build two more of these
threes three brewing stand setups like
this one need two more of those and I
think two twos and then we're done with
these brewing setups in total we have we
have a three over there this is a four
we have four fours that's second third
and fourth and here's other three so we
have two threes and four fours at the
moment we need four threes and two twos
total and in this Cove here I'm going to
use this to brew awkward potions and
haven't set it up fully yet of course we
got our nether word farms that we set up
last time which work pretty good I like
them and let's go get the other one you
want for this side we have another one
of these coves and for here I want to
place controls for turning the stuff on
and off for controlling all the Redstone
we'll put into this little area here
somehow and up at the front here I kind
of want to do something fancy but I
don't know what like of course we have
to put a few more of these but I was
thinking like stairs that go up then
maybe some ornamental stuff I don't know
exactly what I want to do here we do
need to expand like dig out a bunch of
this so that's what that buttons for and
clean it up quite a bit
and I'll probably have to take out some
more space still while I was over here
I've discovered a few cool things
rediscovered I should say let's head on
over up here yeah up here check this out
we're really close to a skeleton spawner
thing I made a long time ago right in
there is a skeleton spawner that's kind
of cool
so we'll probably try to set something
up for that because the building is so
close to it and if we go outside I think
we are pretty close to those glowing
jungle trees I set up yeah over here
this is where that's that snowflakes up
there so pretty cool I like where this
is going um I don't know if we're going
to work on this today kind of feel like
just dripping around today to be honest
and I got one other really cool thing to
show you guys oh that's this making all
the noise see I set this thing up a long
time I have no idea where to pick up the
stuff is it here I don't think I like
actually finished it in any capacity I
think I'm grabbing stuff through the
wall here so yeah it's it's not really
working at the moment yeah
pretty cozy I wish clay in quartz was
easier to get because I want to build
everything out of it now it's such a
cool block looks so nice oh yeah I got
these two icings here I want to stick
villagers behind them trap them in there
Camela kind of crazy scientists
experimental lab sort of thing this
entrance here though needs a lot of work
I said I want to bust up this farm quite
a bit change it up around because it's
in the way and it's spawning slimes and
do another
things yes I have a really cool trick I
want to show you guys today I think
you're going to like this one a lot
pay attention make sure you're watching
make sure you're listening because this
is really cool or I think it is anyway
yesterday I was playing with some of the
guys from the minute the midnight
society
which is like a group of us that play
PvP games together sometimes and in one
of our matches we stumbled across a
really interesting game mechanic and I
was trying to think how can I
incorporate this into my LP world in a
fun fun way you know that people are
going to like and I came what team up
with something that I think is really
cool so I'm not going to explain how
this trick works to you right away I
want you to kind of scratch your head at
first and try to guess how it works
because there's a few a few things you
might not expect to see with it
so first off basically people have been
wanting me to make a bedroom get my LP
world here for a long time and I've I've
been wanting to like a proper place
where I can sleep and set my spawn and
stuff that's not out in the middle of a
forest like I currently have and I can't
die over here and I found an awesome
spot so check this out we're going to
we're going to kill ourselves and
respawn in a bed I am NOT doing any
fancy editing with this this isn't a
editing trick this is actually happening
in the game so check it out
I took my boots off right yeah all right
so we respond and oh what what what is
this all right here here's the fun part
um I'm gonna have a lot of fun with this
I think whoa oh
den nnnn nnnn and then den N and N and n
and n and their dinner is so cool so
this is my new spotting place oh so so
awesome dananana dananana
uh every time I die I'm gonna respond
there when I when I'm sleeping at this
spot I can still change my my my bed
really easily and it and stuff like that
it's not a problem let's kill ourselves
a few more times here because that is a
lot of fun and I just set it up so I
haven't had a chance to play around with
it yet kind of waiting to start
recording before I did oh that failed I
never did finish this I know I said I
was going to and I will
I just haven't yet Dannan and then and
there and in it and then and then Denton
and then and then Denton and then and
then Dani
alright let's let's do it one more time
at least and then I'll explain how the
trick works cuz it's really interesting
uh you know I I could probably just kill
myself on a cactus will do that if we
would go again alright so yeah I got a
little spawning platform up here at at
250 and right above my beacon so I spawn
in the beacon light here and these
chests are full of well not exactly full
but the hoppers at the moment I'm still
working at setting this up the hoppers
have boats in those feet to a dispenser
here full of boats and we got a crafting
table up here we have ender chests which
is probably the way I'll have to refill
this because I'm not I'm not lathering
up here every time I got a refill I just
kill myself and spawn up here this isn't
one of the important things to have a
floating water block one block in front
of the dispenser and one block below
that the boat
and spawning let's see if we can make it
this snowflake that would be pretty cool
alright here we go
Oh oops actually I want to die I'm not
I'm not getting for the water um
sometimes again you can run forward and
you won't fall I'm gonna try that again
where's the snowflake not there over
there okay I'm going to try that again
just run forward you kind of get stuck
on the boat like that it's kind of cool
all right come on come on come on no not
quite
I wonder if I if I put water up in the
air if I could and that's how you do it
as a perfect parachute if I put water up
in there like floating water blocks
every so often if I could slow down my
descent if I hit them I'd be pretty cool
okay so let's do this just a few more
times this is actually a lot of fun
let's actually I want to see notice this
that if you're on a chest above ice you
get the slippery effects still I want to
see if you can still shift and walk off
of a chest yeah you can keep that in
mind if you ever building a pipe with
Jess okay so the thing that you should
really be scratching your head about
with this like if you weren't distracted
by my amazing James Bond skills here
there's no bed around here as you may
notice so why am i spawning up here oh
that's what we'll get to soon that's
that's what you're that's your puzzle
for today try figure it out before I
tell you I put a few more things up here
and her pearls I want to set up in the
corner another dispenser like so with a
few ender pearls in and I may set up up
here I may set up up here to ups in a
row some way of equipping myself with
armor and
have some dispensers - on auto equip me
- in time three a load the terrain okay
so now if I die up here I should be able
to walk up here get a ender pearl I
don't think any of the world's loading
now that I refreshed it no that was
really bad it looks like I'm in outer
space now because nothing is loaded this
is actually a really Wow even the
beacons off a really useful thing - it's
not just for fun like normally if you
spawn somewhere you're you spawn at that
spot but with this I have the option of
like teleporting 100 blocks + all around
me with an ender pearl like you can
throw it super far because I'm way up in
the air so check this out I tested this
in creative you don't want to throw the
ender pearl up like this you way I think
the optimum angle is actually
straightforward so let's see where this
takes me
and we're at 319 163 nineteen one sixty
to seventy two so we teleported over one
hundred and blocks I was like a hundred
and fifteen blocks give or take kill me
please
so yeah it gives you a lot of range when
you respawn if you want to go to a
specific spot you can just look over the
edge and ender pearl to it assuming the
world loads down below um let's try this
with a few more camera angles let's try
without going in f5 like this I want to
see if I can survive the boat drop OOP
whoa that's different
alright so this is a little bit tougher
I can't see the ground can't see the
ground and it's not loading Oh trees
trees are dangerous oh okay that was not
a good parachute took three yards or two
hearts oh not creeper creeper I'll take
an Enderman or skeleton death no no
oh hey jerk alright um what's the other
can't wrangle I want to do this at angle
to see let's try this out I think you
spawn always facing south let's go west
this time all right
oh it's so much fun
oh oh oh I was bad what was that I was
only two or three hearts that's that's
not too bad I like the view of the road
from up above - I don't know if you
noticed that it looks pretty cool this
uh this road I got running here ah yeah
this is how the trick works by the way
good at nighttime whoo all right let's
go down I just need to use a world here
so we're in a creative world and I was
setting my spawn in a bed
the thing is normally if you set your
spawn in a bed and you obstruct it so
these are the spots that you can spawn
around a bed normally not a pie though
and when you when you block those and
you kill yourself you know I probably
should checked what what spot I was at I
might not be able to find my way back
here yeah
so my bed is obstructed and now I'm
somewhere far away oh I like the desert
I just will work here now alright so my
my bed was obstructed I had blocks
surrounding it um let's do that again
glass bed
let's go wool this time okay so I'm kind
of experimenting here too a little bit
all right so bed set my spawn in the bed
now I think if you put glass all around
it you will spawn in the glass I believe
let's try this out
oh no on top of it that's right so
that's that's your hint there you spot
on top of the glass instead of in it all
right
now you can specify a spot you want to
spawn if you change all all this ground
one block below the bed I had torches in
my inventory for a reason because I
wanted to light it up so you guys can
see gap you change these blocks to a
transparent block like glass change them
all here we're learning today both of us
all of us why both both does it make
sense all of us Ariel kill ourselves
again Oh a bunch of portals here can't
remember what I was doing
go over there our bed was obstructed
because it was all glass at the floor
level but you can specify a spot if you
have one solid block so we will spawn
right up here this is only valid spot so
let's set our spawn again since it was
obstructed you can fill this in kill
ourselves we spawn right above here and
we can make this go all the way up as
high as we want kill ourselves again and
now we spawn all the way up
here which is pretty crazy so that's
that's what I was doing to spawn up in
this guy I don't know if you noticed it
but I had fences running all the way up
the beacon lighting the beacon lighting
covers most of them so you don't see
them and that brings me up all the way
to the top um you can do a lot of really
fun and evil things with this - as you
can imagine if you know where someone's
bed is and you want to tick them off
well let's just say there's any number
of traps you can set up to do it um this
is probably one of the evilest imagine
you surround the lava in obsidian Jill
you spawn in the obsidian go game mode
respawn in the lava there's a there's a
delay though before you start taking
damage and if it was obsidian you
wouldn't be able to break out you just
keep died and you'd be stuck so be nice
to your friends or you can spawn people
on pressure plates and Oren or even now
that's something we were messing around
with yesterday was spawning people like
on a on a bunch of tnt carts have a
bunch of tnt carts at the top and have
them explode instantly I didn't get it
detonated properly though I can't place
him
oh I had it there I had it yeah you got
to find the sweet spot on the rail there
it is I don't think that's going to
explode though unless I unless I mess up
the carts somewhat yeah well you get the
idea you can do some pretty crazy and
fun traps with this
this is where I have the bed set my
world here up up by the stairs up in
here it's not very accessible at the
moment I want to change it up a bit
unfortunately where the beacon is in my
world I'm a little limited on how I can
access this thing um it's right up there
and the beacons right above and if I try
to sleep in it at the moment it's night
right yep
nighttime song and I leave the bed this
is where the block is this is the center
of the beacon now to leave here that
this is important to know the way this
works if I set my spawn in the bed and I
leave the bed or if it becomes day while
I'm sleeping in it
I don't spawn up there I spawn down here
by the bed it's only if I die that I
spawn way up in the air like that so
keep that in mind but yeah I have to
have the spot here is the thing because
I don't want to move the beach in so
what I should probably do who maybe um
maybe if I dig out here I might be able
to even move the bed this might work if
I have it here I'll have to test it
later
umm what am i doing what am i doing
focus I want to put the bed here instead
right there yeah and I'll make it so I
can walk out through the glass out here
somewhere and then down to the stairs
probably
well I hope you guys enjoyed that little
trick there and also I hope you liked
the the direction we're going with the
brewing room I liked it a lot personally
on now unfortunately it is that time
once again we got to wrap up the episode
so let's go through our comments I
picked out three today three whole
comments but they're all short ones
first one is I think the slow sad looks
looks good in the room yeah yeah I like
it too especially now that I decide to
not make all the walls totally courts
like we have little bits of red or we're
going to some red here you know it
breaks it up a little bit and it helps
to make this look a little better I
would say second comment hey ESO don't
forget you haven't finished the gold
farm I know I know we're going to do it
don't you worry that's not something I'm
avoiding her that I'm putting off also
check this out I found and the remnants
of an old zombie spawner here a long
time ago when silk touch came out I
decided I would test to see if silk
touch would pick up the spawner and it
was at a point where you weren't able to
so I did break one spawner in my world
this one and I really regret it now
because we're we're at the spot where we
could use it and it's not there anymore
even though it seemed like I would never
need it you never know that's why you
never break spawners they're da meant
for today we're going to work on the
gold farm don't worry soon I must ask
ISA why do you call soulsand slow slow
sand because I've been playing this game
a long time and it wasn't that long ago
we didn't have these tooltips like where
it says ender pearl cobblestone glass we
didn't have what what do you call it log
reports or
patchnotes really when when a new
Patrick come out notch was very
secretive a lot of people don't really
know this I don't think he was very
secretive he would add features in the
game and not tell people Dinnerbone does
that too a little bit but for for lesser
things but like not she wouldn't even
tell us the name of blocks he added it
was up to the community to come up with
names and this is just one example that
some people called it soul sand some
people some people called it slow sand I
was one of them because that name made
more sense and still does make more
sense to me then soul sand close stone
people called light stone that they
called it bright stone there was another
really weird name for it too I remember
I don't I don't remember actually I
don't remember the exact name of it it
was some I think I'm like a technical
like real-life type of glowstone I don't
know I don't know it was it was a weird
name though so yeah that is why I call
some stuff different stuff then it's
actually the proper name for this stuff
cool thanks for watching guys I hope you
enjoyed it I'll see you again next time
bye bye
you