hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back we have a zombie in our potion lab
right now guys I want to show you this
to point something out to very important
all right so you might have noticed this
happening in some of my other videos the
older let's play videos every now and
then I'll have a zombie to show up in
this lab right but if you look at our
lighting the lighting is good
the lighting is just fine like most mobs
need 7 or less to spawn we're at like 9
10 11 you know I made sure when I built
this thing we were good but I'm still
getting zombies spawning in it only
zombies because I'm pretty sure it's due
to this mob system over here when the
zombies fall down if they survive or
maybe even if they die
I think only if they survive they have a
chance of calling a reinforcements those
can spawn at light level 9 or less so a
little bit brighter area which is why
we're giving zombies in here so if you
guys ever build a mob system or if
you're doing anything with villagers
especially you got to keep that in mind
because you might get zombies where you
don't want them it's not a big deal
though like as long as we're not getting
creepers in there I'm perfectly fine
with that now I got something to show
you over here a new addition to the man
cave probably my greatest most useful
invention yet guys are you ready for
this
oh yeah alright guys so today's episode
is a bit of a special one I left it up
to you to decide what we're doing today
to leave a comment and tell me what you
wanted me to work on next and somebody
said in the comments Ito you have a book
just look at your book you have a
million unfinished projects pick one of
them no no this is your guys's episode I
wanted to do something that you want me
to work on even though I might not
necessarily want to work on it and of
course you guys were not kind you picked
the one thing I'm most scared of we are
going to be working on Wilson today aha
I think Wilson the library and the Nexus
room were the top three I noticed in the
comments now I don't like I want to work
on Wilson but I don't want to work on
Wilson I've been putting off finishing
this guy because I know what's involved
like this is not a simple thing
unfortunately it's not a simple task of
adding on to it or tweaking something I
got to tear a lot of this wiring out and
just redo it pretty much all the wiring
actually and if you remember how long it
took me to build this I'm not excited to
to redo it all but I would do it for you
guys this is your episode we'll see how
far I can get with it it's a little bit
scary now if you guys don't know if
you're a little bit newer to the let's
play series Wilson here is a tamagotchi
we're trying to build he has a facial
system so he can express his motions or
his a state of well-being right now he's
dead I think he has six different faces
he can make he's got a health bar up
there which is depleted he has a weight
um so if I over feed him he gains weight
if I under feed him he loses weights
he's got a happiness meter up there and
a hunger meter right there alright so
the goal is to keep all all these bars
in tip-top shape so that he doesn't die
on us and that I he's a healthy pet
basically all right so couple issues
with
our Wilson guy here though I think
that's how we turn him back on okay
that's a sick face right now he's sick
uh-huh
we ran a beta test to this guy and like
it does work the system but it's just a
little bit plain right now and there's a
couple things I want to change like
right now his facial expression is
linked to his happiness meter which
doesn't make sense because he can be in
the best of moods like smiling and then
he can be dead the next second so I want
to change his facial expression to link
up to his health bar makes more sense to
me and we just have to add more variety
to the Wilson game because as it was it
seemed a little bit plain we need more
things like we need to make it so at
night time he gets angry at us if we
wake him up that kind of stuff maybe
make it so he poops and gets sick easier
you know little little things like that
all right I'm going to start tearing
stuff outs mmm
that shouldn't be he's very angry right
now come on Wilson you can die it's okay
there we go good boy he's dead yep so
I've been working on Wilson here for a
little while now making very good
progress I'm happy to say we did not
have to destroy all the wiring I found a
way to do what I wanted to do without
tearing it all out because this is more
complicated than I remember I was going
through some of this stuff it's like no
I can't rebuild this there is no way dig
way too long but yeah I just did a I
found a way to do a patch job just to
add another wiring another wire into
into Wilson to make it work
so now his face is hooked up to the
health meter instead of the happiness
meter which sounds like a simple thing
but it was a bit tricky actually it's
funny when I'm looking at my wiring now
in the
future here I think I have learned a few
things like very rarely in my wiring did
I use this this little trick with the
slabs you know where you can go up very
compactly I don't think I knew how to do
that when we first built Wilson because
we built Wilson when the redstone update
first came out so like hoppers renew
droppers comparators all that stuff I'm
pretty sure I did not know how to pass a
comparator signal as well so you can go
comparator redstone dust block
comparator block redstone dust you can
move it up to three blocks before you
need another comparator um and yeah so
we have a signal of two or one that'll
be one and see it carries it all the way
through which is pretty cool so it's
like a comparator repeater basically
keeps the analog signal and that's what
I had to do here to get this to work so
from the health memory this is the
hell's over here
I went I added in another wire down
below here so the comparator goes down
then we got comparator comparator does
like a zig zag here comparator
comparator kind of repeats the signal
all the way down to over here I did have
to move a bunch of wiring to make this
work though otherwise it would have went
through it and not worked properly that
took a bit of time but before this is
the happiness memory over here this is
what used to control the face and all
that stuff and I had like a comparator
here doing that but I was able to get
rid of it and just pass a signal some
distance to over here from the the
health and all is good so basically we
did what I wanted to do the main tricky
thing now we can add like other stuff
and dispatch that into so three three
lights this is his neutral face seems to
be working okay now so what should we do
next good question
I'll have to think about it
I was just doing some testing here like
right now Wilson is sick I tried to give
him his medicine this is what cures them
right so I throw it in his food thing
and look at that it gets stuck on the
hopper like any block except for that
one if you throw it into the middle of
the hopper it falls down like it doesn't
pick up a full block has that always
been a thing or and I just never noticed
or is that new 21.9 I wonder that's an
issue though definitely an issue um if
you run it along the side of the hopper
I got a hopper right here that's being
powered so it won't pick up any items
but they should flow or top it but if
they go down the middle they sink down
into the hopper model you know doesn't
take up a full block now okay well we're
going to take this opportunity since our
feeding system is broken I never really
liked it over here to be honest this
doesn't make a lot of sense is this like
a random hole over here that we feed
Wilson with ideally I would like to have
to throw the food into his mouth but due
to the complicated Redstone behind the
whole facial system here we can't really
do something like that so I thought
maybe a good alternative would be to
have like an offering hole over here to
Wilson so if we ever want to give them
something you got to throw it into there
then we could have like a piston a
piston oh yes this is working it did not
work
piston yeah that extends here so if we
just fed them we have to wait a little
bit of time before we feed them again we
could just have this block come out so
that we can't keep feeding them you know
because it takes some time to eat you
know you can't just throw a million
steak at them and expect them to eat it
right alright so that is the new plan
I'm going to move all this food system
stuff all this stuff controlling its
hunger so these item filters these are
old-school item filters by the way there
they're too wide instead of the
the classic one wide design we use
nowadays so all this has to be moved we
have some hopper clocks over here that
have to be moved as well and that will
free up some space back here if we want
to add anything else okay so I got that
done we're gonna go check it out in just
a second but first something very
exciting here we are collecting clay oh
yeah just love that sound
so you know a lot of times I build
something in my world here and you guys
never get to see it after that I I take
it for granted because I see these
things all the time and you guys might
not see it for many many videos so I
thought I'd give you a little update on
our our clay outpost here we built this
a few episodes ago this hole in the
ground is getting quite a bit bigger we
are grabbing the clay because we're
probably going to try do some work on
Wilson like some actual building as well
try refine the look of that area a bit
better I don't want to keep it grass
like we have it there I think I went
down lower sure - yeah and I think even
lower maybe oh maybe not so I definitely
want to use red clay I think for Wilson
I like red clay a lot probably my
favorite of the colors the cyan is very
good too though
and what else I think we might build
Wilson out of either yellow or this
white stuff I don't like the spice stuff
so much because it's got like a pinkish
hue to it but it might look okay
because if we're building with red it'll
go with that a little bit better - we'll
see we'll try it out all right fantastic
so we went we got some clay and stuff
which I do not have on me one second
let's make sure to grab this so we're
going to do some building on Wilson here
in just a second let me first show you
the changes made to the feeding system
so no longer do we have the little thing
we throw the food in over here that's
gone this is all ripped out I did
actually leave a lot of like redstone
stuff here but it's easy to move
if I need to in the future like if I
want to build some other complicated
thing in this space it's possible to
move it pretty pretty easily so we got
our hopper timers over here this one is
for the steak I think and this one is
for the cookies if we give a Wilson a
cookie he gets less hunger I shouldn't
supposed to be it for ya keep that at 4
gives them a little bit of hunger gives
them a little bit of weight and also it
gives them happiness I believe cookies
are fattening but they make them happy
um yes and there's also the thing for
the medicine and all that still so if we
throw food into his feeding hole now
like a steak nice juicy steak E and
seize it one one light right now should
go up yet went up good so however long
this block is here we'll determine how
long before we can feed them again if we
want to add a delay to that right now I
have a very short just as a so I can
show you this and still go down here so
the food goes over here then there's one
hopper here for the steak item filter
here for the cookies one here for the
apples and then there's one more for any
garbage I might accidentally throw into
it it can catch that too um there's
another hopper timer over here that's
what makes that block come out up there
for the feeding delay I think I want to
make that wait a bit longer
maybe I'll just throw a full stack and
see what that's like um we'll be out of
which nearby each of these item filters
branches off to one of those item what
are they called popper clocks yeah over
here this is a good trick by the way if
you guys ever do hopper clocks or
anything with hoppers if you can put
blocks over top those hoppers you may as
well do it because I think that helps
lower the laid you get from them it
doesn't have to check tipping and pull
items in and also if you're like digging
in that area you don't have to worry
about blocks falling into your hoppers
that happens to me quite often I'll
return to a bill
project later and I'll start like mining
out some of the area and then stuff
falls in the hopper and I don't notice
it and wrecks the timing on everything
and oh it's good just to block it off
alright let's do some building so I want
to put some quartz here I think alright
um yeah I think last time we worked on
Wilson actually I asked you guys what I
should do with the look here I saw some
of the responses there were some good
ones um some people like change the red
clay here with wood I saw some where
they kind of mixed like half and half
they did green on one side then another
color on another one I think I think
what I want to do with this is keep it
very simple you know the focus should be
on Wilson not so much on our our frame
here are the look of the the room I
don't want to keep it this nature theme
I think it deserves like a technical
theme like a nice smooth clean look that
the clay gives us um
I don't like the sandstone for example
because it's got a strong texture to it
right it's got that cobble look we don't
want that we want a clean look um we're
gonna take advantage of the way the eye
works you know like if you have a blank
sheet of paper with a dot a black dot on
it you will instinctively maybe not
instinctively but you will look at that
black dot on the paper right so likewise
we're I think I'm going to use white
clay here as like our blank sheet of
paper and we want to focus well I just
destroyed that lamp we want to focus on
these lamps when we walked in right
these are our black dots on our paper
that we want our eyes to to draw
attention to so clay is very good it's a
clean clean texture block and I think
it'll work out pretty good here I'll try
it out and to see what it looks like the
other option is yellow did I bring any
yellow I do not
yeah let's quickly go get some yellow
we'll just try it out
yellow is a good choice as well it's
kind of a brighter color but I think it
will distract a little bit from from the
lamps got a little bit yellow orange it
could be another good choice
but honestly white is probably going to
be the best I just want to check it out
though really quick here whoa I love how
you can activate the wings now whenever
you want that was a really good change
the yellow kind of goes because it's a
little closer in color to the lamps but
also because of that I think it will
distract from them but it goes well with
red I think I'm gonna go with the white
we'll try the white out uh-huh so that
is the white clay look I'm happy with it
I think it's very good yeah I tried out
the yellow did not like the yellow as
much I don't know what else you would
use it does achieve the effect I want to
so I think I'm going to keep it as that
so maybe we will try change out some
more stuff here um let's just try to
break up the floor a little bit so I
think we want to mix red clay and maybe
one other block I'll try white clay and
just see what it's like oh whoops
there was a hole over there that up
there is the storage room wiring by the
way if you're wondering what that was I
don't think it's going to post too much
of a problem I think we can build around
it um also since there's no white clay
stairs I just did quartz up there that's
the age meter on Wilson by the way I
don't think I mentioned that today or
for all of you that don't know so
basically the goal or the winning
condition of Wilson is to get that bar
to fill up all the way to live out is
his full life without dying prematurely
you know and I'm trying to keep him
alive here right now see if I can't I'm
having trouble with it so because when I
feed them I don't think it's giving them
food I think it's less than one light
every time at the moment which is not
enough so I'm gonna have to bump that up
a bit and also when his weight goes up I
have no way of getting it down so maybe
what we should do is have some exercise
option we can we make Wilson exercise so
if he exercises ideally I think his food
should go down weight should go down
health maybe goes up a couple points and
Happiness people don't really like
exercising so maybe it should go down
they feel good afterwards though so
maybe it should go up I don't know but
that might be one cool thing we could do
that's a more variety uh what else I
thought of an idea with a mood meter
maybe we have any lamps no we don't for
the mood meter I was thinking we could
have five lamps and randomize what what
light level they're at so if he's in a
bad mood his happiness will go down
quicker than normal
he's in a good mood it'll do the
opposite it'll it'll kind of go up
quicker than normal you know that way
like because I don't want it so that
when we when we go to take care of
Wilson like right now it would be like
give them food and then do something to
make this happiness clothes go up and it
will the food and the happiness would be
pretty consistent with each other we
want some variation with them we don't
want it just to be another thing to top
off so if like sometimes is happiness
goes down quicker than his food and
vice-versa I think that would be a good
idea if you know what I mean that was
probably complicated and not very well
well said all right there is a pathway
over here this sort of connects to where
does this go I got the firework room
over here I want to keep this open
though let's build around it and I guess
we should go in a bit more
yeah I think we'll have a border here do
that and then maybe make it a little
door frame here so it'll go up and
around kind of like that back down keep
it all red clay and then connect it to
these stairs I'll do some some building
off-camera here and maybe we'll try do
one other thing this episode's just so
it's not all Wilson too so this is what
it looks like with white clay on the
floor don't really like it to be honest
it's too much it's way too much we need
a different floor I do like the shape of
the room no I think that's good so we
got our door here I added a door on the
other side as well there is a cave here
that we might want to link eventually it
goes down to nothing basically at the
moment the old eats road over there
that's where the skeleton is apparently
that I keep hearing goes up to here to
our snack o matic
yeah eventually I think we'll we'll do
something with it yeah so we're going to
do one more project really quickly here
I need pack dice forts so we're gonna
get it from the Nexus here I want to do
this because a lot of you say I never
use it which is not true
I just don't use it on camera a lot
because this is a long-term storage room
guys it's not like when I use constantly
so whenever I I need a spot for like
several chests of ice for example
hopefully that's right I think that's
right I don't have like a spot for a
double chest the fact ice in the man
cave for example so that goes into the
Nexus whenever we get like a whole bunch
of something yeah there it is good yeah
so the Pat ice is four and not a super
exciting project but it's what I want to
get done nonetheless I want to down all
my nether tunnels have a three-wide
thing of
a pat dice and this stuff is great
because you can put tracks on them right
let's double check yeah yeah of course I
can of course you can I knew that so
yeah we can ride a minecart over top of
it if we want we can have horses run
down here still we get the super speed
boost if we jump down the tunnel and in
the game currently we have speed boats
and if that is a feature that's gonna
stay this is going to be amazing
I definitely I would be a fool not to do
this honestly because those boats are I
think at least I can't remember what it
was back it's at least three times
faster than minecart so it's insane and
a lot of my another tunnels here need
need work anyway like I have to go about
1500 blocks down this way to get packed
ice that's where my my ice bike biome is
to do that I have to travel most of that
by foot and it's a terrible journey I
have to go over a one wide you know
nether netherrack bridge I got going
over lava and it's extremely dangerous
gas shoot at you and yeah I want
something better so even if they do fix
this boat boat thing I think this will
still be a nice tunnel so I'm going to
work on it for a bit then we'll try it
out we'll see if the boats are going to
work or not because I'm worried
zombie pigman are going to spawn as well
and and block the way we will find out
yep so I got a lot done having a lot of
fun with it
yeah this is like so cool I don't have
any sides on it at the moment though so
it's very easy to fall off because it's
it's actually kind of tricky to go
perfectly straight it kind of bounce
around a bit whoa
and that is why I took my fire resistant
potion right geez gonna wreck my my
thing there oh alright alright let's get
back up quickly those guys make the
craziest sound oh I missed oh oh I did
not want to throw ender pearl start it
let's try to shoot the gas ball guys
invisible there he is
alright now I'm lost
there it is yeah you hit my thing I'm
gonna have to fix that now
ah but yeah this goes at least I think
thousand blocks are close to a thousand
blocks oh and that was the last boat to
go let's make another boat real quick
here so I'm about two-thirds the way of
what I wanted to do here um I think I've
broken at least 50,000 blocks and placed
at least 10,000 this episode it's been
crazy so we're gonna wrap it up I've had
enough for today oh that is the way to
the amplified bass right there any
entity I hit with this though it does
stop it like zombie pigmen stop it even
like items I drop see ya instant stop so
I'm gonna have to slab over top the ice
I think you see like even that
netherrack stop me there so yeah I hope
they don't remove this this fast boat
they know it's the greatest thing ever
somebody suggested if they do plan to
because it's it's a little bit goofy
they should at least add sleds into the
game it would be really cool if you
could like connect the dogs or the
wolves up to the sleds you know I think
that would be a great idea anyways I'm
rambling let's let's finish up the
episode here so the comment of the day
pick two of them this is episode four
four four first one says etho according
to statistics in Canada there are more
donut shops and more Donuts bought and
consumed per capita than anywhere else
in the world so what is your favorite
kind of donuts I find that surprising I
think it's because of Tim Hortons oh
there's not really a lot of donut shops
like a lot of different types there used
to be one called sir donut that I I
think all closed down or something and
we don't have like Dunkin Donuts here
that I know of that's a marriage in
thing but yeah we have a lot of Tim
Hortons my favorites donut type is
chocolate dip I like apple fritters a
lot I like yeah we definitely need the
slab this is the zombie pigmen rackets
they they wrecked everything you know I
hate those guys and we need we need some
sides all right that was scary
I like the powdered Donuts blueberry
cherry filled or good I hate the only
Donuts I don't like are the ones that
are cream filled and I don't like
anything that's like caramel maple
butterscotch flavor I don't like that
type of stuff but thank you for your
very important question second one etho
you should you should put feather
falling on your light rock it stacks
with the feather falling on your boots
so you don't take as much damage for
falling now that is pretty incredible if
it's true I can't remember when I was
testing that if I ever did try feather
falling we're going to try it here
though
because if that is true we will be able
to use enderpearls
like crazy because they take a lot less
damage from ender pearling if you have
feather falling stacking do we have any
here it doesn't look like it let's check
here if it's not here we definitely have
some at the library Oh
feather falling okay do we have enough
levels now to put it on our key doo doo
doo okay let's head over to our anvil
real quick here and so I haven't
breaking on here still don't have a
mending book mm-hmm
maybe in creative we'll try it on a
fresh pair we do have him back up there
yeah I kind of thought I tried this
before and it didn't work because I'm
creative you can get an enchant a lot of
things you can't do in survival now
doesn't look like it alright well that's
going to be it for this episode guys
thank you for watching hope you enjoyed
it and I'll see you again in the next
one take care bye bye