hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys once again are you my guy are
you my guy I'm looking for one of them
one of these white guys has I did it
again it has a name tags for sale I want
to buy some name tags on my tree grew
again are you kidding me
stupid tree uh I had like a sapling
there ever it's very rare but it'll grow
sometimes I wonder if we update this
it's still despawn probably have to
break one of them wait are you the are
you my guy I think they're trying to
break out I hear him there's a guy out
here butcher nobody cares about you okay
he's on he's on the right side still
that's fine
seriously where's my name take that I
need to start wait I can't remember
doubting you that's you ten name
villagers I know there was a point there
was a point in time where you couldn't
but I think they've changed that I want
to try okay
although that's a little
counterproductive isn't it I'm trying to
buy nametags from a guy and then I'm
going to use him to name the villagers
so that I can find the guy to buy
nametags from all right I got a look
around he was here unless he died ah
I'm sad now I looked around I think he
is actually dead he was like one of my
favorite villagers this place isn't
quite secure like they'll just like
wander off these stairs and take fall
damage sometimes there's there's a few
places like that so they die eventually
over time kind of kind of like old age
you know if they run around this village
for too long
so maybe we would try to get a new name
tag guy not that I really needed that I
just I just wanted to get him um all
right what you got for me
I think we'll get a book trade again Oh
what is this written books class we'll
do that let's ease in here no no he's
not in here mm-hmm there we go there's
there's the next book trade blast
protection three for 39 that is bright
see if we can unlock the next one just
by doing this I might have to do that a
few times this is by a bunch of classier
check it out by the way from all that
zombie zombie flesh trading from the
gold farm we got a stack of emerald
blocks to spend baby
I wanted to buy like 20 or 30 nametags
just to have them but I don't know if
it's gonna happen now now we got new on
Fortune three oh that's actually that's
a good one
it looked pretty cheap for for that
enchantment that's a pretty high tier
enchantment in this game um all right
like something that usually costs quite
a few levels to put on a tool Oh baby
the other one he was selling them for 24
I thought that was a good price but
maybe it wasn't uh-huh you're my new
favorite uh I'm gonna I'm gonna get one
of these I can't remember if there's any
trades past this all right I'm gonna use
one of these try dating this guy -
because I can't remember your name
villagers oh it's probably it hmm I
think that's my line I think it might be
bugged here
because I remember I named one recently
on the minecraft server I named that guy
a pool that works at the kwik-e-mart
right but I think you're supposed to
hold shift and right click but that's
not working for me it's got a name what
am I doing wrong
I don't know I'm scared all right guys
get ready for this I was doing some more
trades with him and we unlocked guess
what is silk touch books for 10 emeralds
unbelievable that is pretty powerful you
might be my new favorite villager you
might be not 22 nope sorry the other
guy's still better Uncle Leo where's
Uncle Leo here here here
Monday Monday you're skin and bones hey
easy now easy calm calm down all right
let's trade I finally found this guy for
20 that seems to be that possibly the
cheapest you can get them for oh and
that's it you got six well refresh whoa
whoa ah yeah this place isn't very safe
I think that was the butcher though so
we're good nobody like them darn it
I'm gonna kill this guy just for the
iron to see peon hit me hopefully you
can't hit me
ohyeah iron farm checked it out got
three hmm
so I decided let's stop by the library
for a little bit today I I've been
seeing a lot of requests in the comments
for me to work on this again so we will
spend a little time here let's see where
did we leave off we got this I think
this is the last thing I did here's is a
staircase thing I'm kind of we got to
figure out how we're going to store our
enchanted books
am I still missing I'm missing the
glowstone I thought I had that there I
guess it's just in this one ah yeah we
got a store enchanted books here some
somehow in these bookshelves and there's
there's basically two ways I can think
of doing it either we try to hide a
minecart chest in the blocks themselves
or we use like a piston and move the
bookcase out of the way and then have a
chest behind it that would probably be
the more reliable method I'm going to
I'm going to try the minecart thing
though let's see if we can do that okay
it's been a long time since I've tried
this but I think this is how you set it
up I got a minecart up there you're
gonna drop it
you got a block there I think it's
facing the wrong way though mmm we'll
see how this looks I think the minecart
is not facing the right way
oh and also yeah okay let's see what it
looks like on this side oh and can we
place the bookshelf back okay we can
that's good I don't think it's gonna be
right now
darn it I clicked it I didn't click it
this might be a directional thing I've
never never really used this method so
you I put the block down make sure we
get the block down I forgot okay and
then we break it and it falls that way
again yeah it's directional
so yeah it's kind of a problem see how
the minecart changed directions there so
it would only work in the sides not not
this way pretty sure yeah mmm we're
going to try this one more time but
we're going to push it the other way
this time and see if that makes a
difference
so can I place this still yes I can now
okay so that's not going to work I can
do the side ones I got my cart there it
didn't work if I pushed it from this
side with those side ones but it does if
I pushed it from like going this way so
that's good but it doesn't work this
direction so do I want to keep it this
way I had one more idea here but I don't
think I'm going to get it working
it likes to curve when it leaves the
track like that unless I bump it just
right sometimes it will fix itself such
a pain though I don't know I had it
right and it went off start it oh you
see that it left this track and it was
perfectly fine it was nice and straight
but if I'm pushing it this way Oh
actually I wasn't too bad
come on get a little straighter
definitely would be a pain to set up a
lot of these but we will try okay let's
see if this little will do it yeah it
doesn't look too bad actually can access
it might be able to pull it off ah no
we're not doing it we're not doing it
this way is too frustrating oh wait wait
wait I'm having such a hard time
straightening this one I don't know why
yeah I don't it looks good don't be
fooled guys I've been fooled before
don't be fooled
that's it wants you to think
right but it's not it's not just wait
and it looks good yeah it does that
though you see that sneaky little
minecart hmm it looks good for a few
seconds and then it pops out again
ah no okay so we're gonna we're not
doing it this way it's going to be way
too painful I'm going to make them
animate the bookshelves move with a
piston and we'll have buttons hidden
around here cool so check it out guys I
got a piston set up now and I liked it a
fair bit more it's a little easier to
control and set up so we've got one
chest here got another one over there
over there and down there and if I want
I can I can lean these chests in it
chests in an anvil and I'll keep the
name up on the top left here so once I
figure out where I'm putting stuff
that's probably what I'll do ah so for
right now since I'm kind of out of space
to store these books this is actually
pretty urgent project because I'm
running out of storage space in my cave
and things are getting pretty messy
maybe we will make this left Cove area
here our armor books for right now so
we'll put let's put all the protection
books in this chest and later we'll
probably end up moving these around so
there's an issue with some books having
two enchantments on I'm not quite sure
what to do about those are some have
three or four even got another
protection there another one there let's
see let's make this our projectile
protection sure okay got another one
there oh I decide another one oh I got a
lot to organize and we'll do fire
protection this one blast protection in
this one where is it
there you go and we got another one okay
I'll show you the wiring real quick here
- it was a little bit tough to to wire
it in such a way that the the pistons
wouldn't interfere with each other
so I have I have a wire running
underneath there and it could powers
this block there's like a redstone torch
below this or something then I got
another one running from here to - up
there and it adds a bit of size to the
whole thing but does it matter too much
because we have nothing planned out
there and I guess we can change this we
will put armor books for now again I'm
not sure how much storage I actually am
going to put in this library but we may
may change things around later this one
we will turn into sword enchantments for
now or to go hey where'd my word my sign
go is it up it's it's gone is it oh it's
up there
okay sword what did I put them right on
this armor books sword books okay all
right so we're going to move on here
we're gonna do some building planning
now basically this wall is pretty much
spoken for now isn't it so this is how I
build by the way I get what I need done
and then I figure out how much space I
got left and like in this case since we
don't really have anything to work with
we're going to cover it up I might want
to change this out later though I think
if I I don't know here's my question to
you guys if I have if I use books all
the time is it going to get to the point
where it's too many books or should I
like just change this to planks you know
or maybe some like half and half I don't
know
I'm using books a lot and I have a
feeling it's going to get overwhelming
if I do it too much alright anyway so
we're going to start curving this path
out this way I think is a good plan to
spruce wood so I think we wanted to go
at least up to here maybe further let's
see there's no real way to get to this
part of the library so we might want it
to go underneath this this bridge thing
we built - okay get that going and oh I
shouldn't have a lot of red wool here
okay Oh start it this thing I never did
fix by the way and I'm scared to fix it
with the minecart physics the way they
are um I was talking to doctor him the
other day he was telling me how the
reason we're having so much trouble with
the hopper minecarts at the gold and gas
firm on the Minecraft servers because
apparently depending on how many items
are in the hopper minecart affects how
how quick it goes or how quick it loses
momentum so it's almost impossible to
make something consistent at the moment
which is interesting all right I did
kind of want to put a statue here it's
getting pretty close to the wall now
though maybe I'm instead of putting the
statue there we'll put a statue in front
of a big window could be cool um all
right so do that the books that I get
from the comments I was going to put up
on this like all along here um somehow
have them stored here so we'll have to
build out oops
place one block and mess up see ya I'm
not too sure exactly what I'm doing with
that yet another another plan which
we'll go check out right now actually is
I want to have a rail line going from
the gold farm there to the library and
we'll try to make a spot for for loading
enchanted books at the gold firm then
unloading them at the library here
because I do a lot of enchanting at the
gold farm there's a lot of badness
underneath that hill to witches and a
baby zombie did he find me oh he found
me no can't touch is he fighting him off
oh I did not touch him I didn't do that
I I take no responsibility alright so
what we're gonna be doing here I tried
laying out this path but I think it
might be a little too plain little too
plain it that's well floaty paths aren't
too good so we're gonna maybe attempt a
suspension bridge of some sort and also
since the gold firm is based on even
numbers we kind of need to make our a
rail line even here too so even though
we don't need two rail lines I'm going
to make two
let's see I'm going to start with oak
let's get it going here maybe while I
fumble around with building for a bit I
will bring up a subject so I've been
seeing in the comments a lot more lately
that I should start a new world in my
let's play guys there's a big big
decision for me so it's not what I take
lightly
I want to get your feedback on it though
because I've been seeing it more and
more it's like well it might be that
time but I'm not quite ready for it
personally but maybe soon maybe soon
maybe 1.8 1.9 but I want to get your
feedback from it as we are right now in
our world here I pretty much have all
the farms I need built which is good in
a way but it's bad in a way too I
noticed a lot of people have this
problem like well I don't want to get
too specific into it but once you get
all your farms built then then it's like
you don't really need to make new farms
unless they're better alright and I've
done that a few times like I've made a
better in German farm I really need a
regular rail for this corner because
everything's going to attach um all
right let's do the rails later yeah so
was I talking about
new world new world right oops
so for the most part the survival aspect
as well it's still in in my world here
but I pretty much have most of stuff I
need just like ready ready for me
already like I got so much stuff in
storage it's insane if you saw it all
like pretty much unlimited diamonds and
coal and lapis and all that kind of
and even like building blocks like clay
and stone I got tons of it ice and you
know if I need something I got it
already even even today like we got a
whole bunch of nametags and yeah so that
that is all set and that's good in a way
because I can build quickly and like get
stuff done quicker than if I was to
start fresh but now there's not much of
the survival aspect left in my world
here to be honest um
so that's that's kind of one one of the
things about starting one of the fun
things about starting fresh we could
possibly like if people don't want me to
make a new world I kind of want you guys
to vote on this too by the way but if
you don't want me to make a new world
maybe if you want me to start fresh we
could just go out to that flower forest
and the amplified terrain I found and
kind of do a fresh start there with
without having tons of stuff with us is
another option um and see how that goes
but yeah I don't know let me know what
you guys think leave a comment if you
want me to continue in this world I do
have a lot of like open-ended projects I
haven't finished yet and there's a few
new projects I've been considering
starting so it's not like I'm totally
out of stuff to do here but still let's
see what I wanna do maybe every fifth
block yeah we started this world back in
episode I think 105 so it's been it's
been a long time I just kind of realized
that the other day like first the first
world we were and we're only in it for
like 100 episodes and in comparison to
this one we're over 200 episodes now but
the game has improved in a lot of ways -
like your worlds don't get broken like
they used to that's kind of good
especially if you keep like fixing
things which I've done pretty good with
anyway
this is let me know in the comments what
you think hmm well I'm not entirely sure
about this bridge design let me know
what you guys think of it but we might
roll with it oh man
get out of here I kind of like it I
think it's pretty cool
I would like to add some lights to it up
above there still and also I want maybe
some curvy braces to go from one post to
the other give it a little more
character would be cool but it is common
to reading time guys so here we go this
is the one I got for today it says hey
etho I have a question do you still play
with the midnight society I used to
really enjoy the pvp stuff you did and I
noticed you haven't done anything with
them for a long time or at least haven't
recorded it ah yeah I can't talk about
the midnight society if I if I I tell
you about them I'll have to kill you
because we're a secret society and and
yeah we do be just Ken we can't talk
about it okay
for those of you that don't know what
the midnight society is it's big it was
basically or it is still is a thing ah
an undefined group of well this is four
blocks apart what did I do here that's
not right it's like a undefined group of
gamers that like to play minecraft PvP
games together we would play games like
nail you might remember I uploaded quite
a few matches of that on my channel also
played revolution quite a bit sand
hoodoo and calamity and a bunch of other
maps Oct see maps we did quite a bit or
do quite a bit it's a kind of like a
past tense present tense thing we don't
play together as much or at least I
don't play with them as much as I used
to
just because I'm really busy most of the
time and also I think we I noticed like
there's not enough pvp maps for
Minecraft like good ones and we ended up
playing a lot of the same map over and
over and I think we kind of got bored of
some of the maps like we played nail to
death and and like a lot of the maps we
just played them to death that they were
good Maps but you know like any game if
you play them for two too long they get
kind of boring but lately we've been
playing together a little bit where I've
been playing with them a little bit new
game called ramparts which translator is
doing the redstone stuff on right now
and and Rick's yacht and I believe Sugoi
built the map and yeah so that that's
coming along that's pretty good map I
find if you're wondering why there
hasn't been matches it's pretty hard to
record a game that has good audio
because like not all the guys have
perfect mics or mic settings so um and I
play mostly for fun when I play with
them so you know I don't want to be like
fix your mic or anything like that but
yeah sometimes it can be tough to get a
game recorded that I I that I feel
comfortable posting on my channel um
just because you know if there's a
slight problem with anything people
complain it seems so yeah audio audio
quality is important anyway
I'm but I'm blabla here I will talk to
you guys later that's gonna be it for
today thank you for watching I'll see
you in the next one bye bye
you