hello how's it going everybody this is
Ethel welcome back how you doing
hopefully you're having a wonderful day
I where have I been
I'm sorry guys I'm sorry I know I
haven't uploaded in a few days and I do
apologize for that
I I took a day off which is not
something I do too often and it just
felt so good that I took another one on
off and then when I went to record
finally my headset broke and I took
another day off in it's been spiraling
out of control so I'm back don't you
worry I'm back here I managed to take my
headset back together and hot glued it
together so it works again and I will be
getting a new mic soon to replace it
because it's going to break again
probably but don't you worry guys I am
back and I have not been doing totally
nothing here I have been building stuff
in our worlds most notably I've been
working on the Nexus so let me just show
you what I've been doing it's
unfortunately it's nothing very exciting
you know we have all these little grindy
projects to do around our world and I
know they don't make for great video so
I've been like pushing to get this stuff
done off camera so I had to run all the
wiring to the Nexus and it's just about
all done this wasn't here last time if
you look at our days you remember like
two episodes ago we were on day 6,000 we
just hit day 6000 we are on day 6000 129
now I have spent an insane amount of
time 129 days in the last two episodes
just doing this kind of stuff let me
show you though how this all works now
we can actually visualize it which is
pretty cool oh I don't have any redstone
on me here let's just use a lever I
guess so you can see here how this kind
of works now so if we send a signal to
this and we're not going to spend too
long on this I just want to show you
real quick because the block is over
here the signal goes
right if the piston was extended and the
block was over here let's break that
torch the signal will go to the left and
basically is a junction right it
switches between either the left or the
right and this is what I'm referring to
as the bits there's eight bits total so
it goes through eight of these junctions
so if we follow the signal here goes to
the right then it goes to another
Junction and it goes through there and
again we hit another Junction it kind of
does split hairs all the way down and
finally it gets to one of these droppers
just one of them depending on what code
we enter into that keypad up there so
it's going to select whichever dropper
we put put the code in for and every
time we send it a pulse the dropper gets
a pulse shoots the item up to the water
stream here and then the water stream is
going to deliver it to us at the front
of the Nexus uh-huh
so that's that's kind of how it's all
working and it's so stinking close to
done I tell you guys I really wanted to
just push and finish it all but still
got a little left to do but I did wire
up the darn it I did wire up the
upstairs here too so you got all these
wires running up now every everywhere
the park or - this is insane I tell you
uh-huh so just a few connections left to
make but I have also done some other
finishing work remember we made that
book last episode let's find it here yes
this over here of all our unfinished
projects we got the Nexus on the list
but there's also a ton more here maybe
we will address some of these today
let's just hop into the nether real
quick so the other thing I worked on is
the tunnel to the desert village up over
here and it is basically done now just
got one thing left to do let me show it
to you this was a huge project
unbelievably huge but yeah we got it all
finished all polished up all the way
down here another brick all over the
place which is cool I changed out the
wheat we had growing here and I changed
it to nether warts nether warts instead
because magma cubes are spawning here
and trampling it which kind of stunk
the only problem we're having is the
zombie pigmen keep landing on the tracks
like they walk across the tracks here
you see there's one right there so we're
gonna have to cover this we could either
use slabs or carpets I think we might oh
man I don't really like using slabs I
think I'm gonna go try some carpet let
me go see if we got enough carpet to do
this
no take it back I dig it back just don't
hurt me take the children just leave me
alone no oh man okay so I was setting up
a portal here guys that accidentally hit
one of them and now I'm going to be
tormented forever oh this is terrible so
we got to do a few things with a stun as
well we got to move this portal into
proper place and it's not really aligned
where it's supposed to be it's supposed
to be over here I think this one is for
our speed mining so we'll set it up over
here and try it out but yet I went and
got some some carpet as well we'll try
it out right now oh this is the worst it
took me so long to make up with them
last time I think I had to go to the
ceiling and that did the trick
alright so I'm we're gonna try four
choices here red carpets gray carpets
and regular stone that we saw before and
get ready for this are you ready for
this
nether brick okay so these are four
choices what do we like the most for
covering for the track here I'm going to
say let's get rid of the stone for sure
I think the nether brick makes the most
sense here because we've used it already
but I like the low profile of
the carpet so this is actually kind of
challenging we have read with the nether
wards but I really like the gray I'm not
sure I think I'm going to go with the
gray does that make sense we're gonna I
think we're going to do it though yeah
yeah I've decided okay oops well those
are broken for good I'm using the wrong
pick here let's light this and see where
it takes us
okay we might actually have some enemies
on the other side here too okay they're
friendly I almost did one of them so it
took us the same portals I guess that's
okay
our speed mining operation is up like a
100 blocks or 200 blocks that way so I'm
gonna probably have to break this portal
and move it as well oh man well they got
me guys they had their fun oh and he's
got my boots you know I took off my
diamond armor for today cuz I thought
that's true I was trying to be cool for
you guys but I think I gonna wear
diamond armor for bits now I know what
you guys are thinking you're all like
etho how you gonna get all that great
carpets cover over the track can't do it
you can't do it man it doesn't exist and
you are right you are right I I've never
really been much of the sheep farming
type of guy so I very rarely have wool
but you are forgetting about the secret
stash here guys can't be about the
secret stash
aha all this wool in here has come from
spider string yeah that's right the old
cave spider farm it's just been sitting
here I never use it I'm going to use
some of it right now to get the gray
carpet oops
oh hey no no I think I just came up with
lyrics for a new song oh you forgave me
oh no II did it's a trick it was a trap
it was a trap
it was a trap and he was he was all
friendly and stuff and then these guys
jumped me from behind and get me oh he
can't look at this cheetah guy he's
walking on the carpets that carpets not
for you okay that's a bit of a problem
so it turns out now that we've done the
portals and we finished up all the
details and now we even have carpet here
we actually just finished a project
number 11 on our list is done you know
you can't click where you want where you
want to in these books I can't like
click here and delete it so I can't
cross it out darn it
but yeah let's go take a ride here guys
oh wait a second okay we got some iron
here we can make a minecart hopefully
yeah we're gonna take a ride down a rail
here I did something I never do I
actually labeled the portals here I will
be putting out a new download to the
world here soon for you guys I'm not
going to announce when I do it but
probably once the Nexus is functional
I'm going to put download to the world
and then you guys can check some stuff
out we've done and you know I know you
guys are usually confused when you fly
around the world or do what you do so
I'm going to try start labeling a few
things around here for you
yeah let's go take a ride down our new
minecart tunnel it's like the low
profile you know you go like this it's
up high there's the other portal to our
speed mining area and this looks messed
up yeah this tunnels huge oh but here we
go
this is our end over here and we're
going to set up a few things down at
this end as well what I want to do we
talked about setting up a mining outpost
for the sand and the sandstone here
friends yeah we're friends okay good
we're just going to set up a couple
double chests around here maybe down in
the ground down in the ground and how
should we do this let's do like this I
guess
yeah just a little bit of storage a
little area near the portal that will
hold a buffer of stuff and then let's
grab some hoppers just run a chain down
the side nothing too complicated just
like this and that'll be our basic deal
and then I want what I wanted to try was
maybe run a nice pass yeah okay so check
this out guys we're just gonna do it
like this I ran a water path or nice
path whatever you call it all the way to
over here this is where I've been doing
our mining
reiben eating the sandstone and the sand
and all that good stuff oh I fell
usually what I do
I'll mine out a bunch of it to my
inventories fold and I have to head back
right now we have like a storage area up
by the portal and we don't have to go we
don't have to go there to drop stuff off
we can just throw it in the water stream
here and unload just kind of cool a
little bit simpler and then we just keep
on mining even though our inventory
filled up so I like that it's kind of
like what we did at the Mesa biome a
little while ago we set up that crazy
thing and set
way simpler it's just a water screen
just throw the stuff in and move on with
your life type of thing so the hoppers
will pick it up over here and then when
we're ready to leave all our duties
should be in the chests they're nice and
simple and we got the minecarts tunnel
all set up so we can just fill up some
storage mine carts and we'll probably
set up so that we can push them through
the portal okay so I just move the
portal down here by the chest so it's a
little bit more convenient and what
we'll do got to change this out to a
dispenser I don't have one on me at the
moment but pretend it lands over here
and we can just unload our stuff
fill up the minecarts I have all this
garbage on me when I come here obviously
but we'll fill it up and then send it
off type of thing let's just double
check I did this right I slanted the
rail on the other side so hopefully
connected to that oh it didn't sand darn
it
all right it's very good we got that
working guys and we are going to move on
to another project here just trying to
add a border kitty-cats you you are a
problem you know what it is it's that
mob farm they keep teleporting out of my
mob farm and just randomly showing up
all over the place so I got all these
cats and dogs all over the world and I'm
not sure what to do with them and they
just sit there forever we might need to
make a home for all all our pets or
something I'm not sure
so from down here it looks like this
this is maybe a bit clunky yeah yeah I
don't know it's not a lot of room to
work with here
I just tried to add a little bend into
the path and then it goes over to this
area we worked on another day anyway
let's go down here what I really want to
work on is this fire workroom it's
pretty pretty plain pretty unpolished
right now if you don't remember how this
works basically we hit a button and it
randomizes what fire work materials it
gives us so we got gunpowder and magenta
dye and make a star out of that you
throw it in the hopper and then it does
it again until you are ready to stop you
just hold onto the item put in the chest
and it's it's supposed to make
randomizing fireworks really easy and
then you're just going to put them
together afterwards so we need a few
things with this room let's try to give
it a nice floor well maybe I don't like
town narrow this walkway is either so
we're going to expand it let's make it
at least the three by three so this
probably has to go to the jab is just
watching us now yeah let's let's shave
all this away maybe let's just try first
stop grass floor like the rest of the
man cave that might be actually what we
use the keep things consistent anyway
and I brought some jungle leaves with me
what I like to do in these little tight
areas like we we have this sort of nasty
ceiling here where it's stone brick and
I sand and droppers and stuff we can't
really do much like there's not a lot of
room to work here so in areas like this
I usually just put a layer of jungle
leaves and I think that looks pretty
good usually all right here's what we're
going to try to do I'm gonna try to talk
and build at the same time so that we
can have a quick conversation so like I
said at the beginning of the episode
here my headset broke the other day guys
which means I'm gonna have to get a new
microphone like the mic itself is fine
it's the headband
that's that broke on me it cracked a
long time ago and I just taped it up and
after a certain amount of time
eventually the glue kind of let go and
it broke officially the other day and
I've taped it back together and it kind
of works but I can tell it's very flimsy
it's not going to last long and this is
the same headset I've used since I
started YouTube the Logitech G 330 I
like it a lot but it's actually
discontinued now so we're going to have
to get a new one and I'm looking at the
80 2035 microphone I've had some people
recommend it to me and that's probably
what we're gonna get but you know what
that means guys do you know what that
means
my voice is gonna change probably yeah
it's not it's not going to be exactly
the same hopefully it sounds okay maybe
maybe it'll sound even better when we
get a new microphone but yeah every
microphone is a little bit different so
it's probably gonna change slightly so
I'm just gonna prepare you already for
that wait a minute this doesn't work
actually it's way too low let's get rid
of that but yeah I'm kind of curious to
see what a new microphone will do with
my voice sorry kitty like I don't know
none of us really know what we sound
like to other people
like how we sound to ourselves is a
little bit different from what other
people hear and I have to go buy it from
what I hear in a microphone rights and I
feel like I put a lot of power into my
voice but then when I hear it in a video
for example I feel very muffled like I
feel like I put a lot of you know
different emphasis and feeling and all
that into my voice and then it's like
this straight-up monotone type of thing
so it might just be me and I don't know
what I really sound like but I'm curious
if a new microphone will change that
like I think some people pick up
different in different microphones and I
might not have the best voice for my
current microphone it might be too deep
you know too deep and the microphone
doesn't pick up that range of of tone or
whatever so yeah it should be
interesting when we get a new mic to see
what happens you know what we're missing
yes you know it's you know it's I got to
do it we're gonna put an arch in its the
mandate we have to have arches let's put
one maybe over here and be a tiny little
arch oh oh are they ever going to fix
that glitch where the blocks
aren't what they're supposed to be can
they even fix that I'm not sure it's
been in the game so long actually maybe
we need to go down one more probably but
yeah it's like some people they'll
they'll almost be mumbling and you can
hear them perfectly fine like they're
not putting a lot of power into their
voice it just picks up so well by the
microphone and for me I feel like that
doesn't happen I got almost yell for for
my point to come across so yeah anyway
rambling here let's maybe try to connect
to this will kind of just go around
alright so anyway I'll say I'll finish
this off camera alright everybody so
unfortunately we are at a time for
recording today but we've pretty much
got this room done maybe just a little
bit more polishing what do you think
about it you liked it let me know in the
comments if you do or not
and we probably have to add some chests
here for the Gunpowder and for storing
the fireworks and that all that kind of
stuff too I just realized
so maybe on the sides would be a good
place for that or maybe even over here
and here
throw in some double chests but anyways
let's get to the comment of the day for
today it says etho it'd be awesome if
you could make a recap video for your
newer and older fans
I know only I know only new I know only
about half the half the projects on that
list I'd love to be filled in on what
things you started a while back but
never finished AHA that is a great idea
you know I checked today and it's been
actually over a year since we did since
we last did a world tour around our
place here so maybe next episode we'll
do that that sounds like a good idea and
we can kind of go through all the
projects we've done and how they work in
and all that kind of stuff I think
that's a good idea anyways guys I hope
you enjoyed today's episode I'm gonna
try to get back on schedule again with
the videos and hopefully hopefully you
enjoyed this one hope you have a
wonderful day take care see you in the
next door
and bye-bye