[Music]
hello hello
welcome back everybody this is etho and
today guys to begin with here
i have a new mini farm designed to show
you
but first let's check out the old crummy
design
so this is my current best mini farm in
our world here
the one i've been using uh today i was
this
i was getting some carrots because i
want to start using golden carrots and
for our food instead of steak all the
time
uh golden carrots have a better
saturation value
so i built this off camera um
i don't know if i've shown it in a video
but basically we got a little bit of a
shield here
because we want to be able to afk here
we don't want creepers sneaking up
behind us
skeletons can still shoot through which
was
kind of dumb on my part but whatever and
this is a switch to turn it on
uh so each of these dispensers has bone
meal in it
basically you plant down your crop and
then
dispensers grow it pretty much instantly
with the bone meal
and because it's a dark spot we then up
update the carrot
and it causes it to uproot and goes back
into our inventory here
um are we losing carrots sometimes if
you get the timing wrong it doesn't work
yeah we're still losing carrots gotta
like stop and right click and
then the number will go up yeah now it's
going up okay so this is the sweet spot
so you want to be able to afk here for
as long as you want
is the goal a lot of these mini farms
though they have the problem
your inventory is gonna fill up a food
right and then it starts falling on the
ground
and then it'll despawn over time like
within five ten minutes you're probably
gonna have items despawning
so the the big change i made with this
farm compared to my other ones
is you can automatically pick up the
items so underneath this slab is a
hopper
and underneath the tilt soil here is a
hopper mine carts
so food lands there it gets picked up
which is pretty cool
if you just kept the hopper minecart
underneath that soil though you would
not get any carrots or seeds in your
inventory
and you would run out of stuff to plant
so you have to like
not just leave the hopper mine cart
there but like
bounce it back and forth so it'll pick
up a little bit of stuff but you'll
still get enough items in your inventory
you
won't run out of seeds and carrots and
it's been working pretty good here
so far so then items go down to your
storage
yeah so today guys i was using that farm
and i got to thinking i bet you could do
something better with observer blocks
now right
and within a minute of trying it's like
the first thing i tried the simplest
thing i could think of it
actually worked i couldn't believe it uh
so this is all you gotta do
is redstone there redstone there on the
observer
and have a dispenser going down
so simple it's unbelievable i don't
think you can make this any smaller now
and then you've got to till that oh
that's not the right tool that's the
right tool that confused me for a second
yeah make sure you got water nearby to
keep it hydrated all three dispensers
are facing the farmland and then you
gotta block out the light to that
that block there so a slab works nicely
you can still click through that
uh fill these up with bone meal
and then all you got to do is plant your
stuff and it's it's done
so check this out uh let's clear up our
inventory a little bit here
like a soul
look at that isn't that crazy like
there's nothing to it it's unbelievable
uh-huh but if you only place down one
seed
it'll uproot and then
uh it doesn't grow it actually uproots
before the
it tries to get bone milled here so the
second one you place
catches the bone meal from the first one
and keeps the cycle going
and the other thing that's really cool
about it is it's really fast here like
if you look at the number
in the dispenser or 35 or so if we start
growing
uh it actually uses the bone meal faster
than
a single hopper can refill it now if we
look the number is actually lower than
when we started
so if you want to like keep it
continuously running you need to hook up
two hoppers to the dispenser and have
like a double chest above
so it'll get the the bow meal quick
enough
okay is the recipe still golden
nuggets or did that change still the
same okay cool
cool so we got golden carrots guys easy
to make them now
i wanted to see if our what did we call
this a pig power switch or something
does it still work it still works
awesome
and does it close again yeah
all right and as you guys can see i got
116 levels right now so i want to spend
these before i die
and and lose them all here like i
usually do
so uh yeah i'm just going to put it all
into books i think and see what we get
here
that's not how you enchant i don't
enchant often there we go
and clicky clicky
oh sweeping edge sweeping edge three
yeah look at that that's
highest level okay so this is our final
final haul here of all the items let's
hover over them real quick in case
you're curious
we did get another sweeping edge thing
here too
cool okay so i gathered together a whole
bunch of different books here we're
going to try to get them all on a single
sword if we can
and interruption yes
i think the trick is not to add them
onto the sword one by one i think we
want to
try pyramid style this so combine the
books first
so we combined two books into one there
then we'll combine these two books into
one
i think if we just added them one by one
to the sword uh wouldn't it be possible
become too expensive and we'll combine
these two
and you know i'm not even trying to
rearrange these i should do that
actually
because that was cheaper okay and then
we want to combo
these two together maybe 15 levels
now eight levels that way okay
yeah i might have messed it up already
because i wasn't rearranging the books
i'm not sure or i might have just wasted
levels that's probably what i did
okay and now i think we can probably
combine these two
for 30 23 okay
look at that are we gonna be able to get
him onto the sword
no i messed it up no
darn ah so sad so
sad but we got another chance at this
i'm gonna try it again
uh we got eight books here we're gonna
try to combine them pyramid style
again this time i'm gonna be careful
though like i'm trying to keep this
enchantment cost
low i think is the goal
that's ten that's two okay so i'm going
to combine those two
okay i'm gonna combine looting and
mending it's only four
yeah i think this is working out much
better okay we'll do uh
fire aspect and sharpness together
that's only four
sweeping edge and unbreaking three was
only three at the cheapest
these two together that's eleven
and fourteen yeah fourteen i think the
mistake i made last time is i put these
books together i think i should add it
to the sword first
and then add the other book on top of
the sword
hopefully oh that's 27 already
okay well let's get ready for some
disappointment here i think i messed up
again
uh but we will see we will see i'm gonna
do the cheaper one first
it's 35 okay we can do it for 35 yes
awesome so this is the most enchantments
you can get on a sword in survival i
believe i don't think i've forgotten
anything there we have seven different
ones all maxed out
i'm gonna give it a name
and let's go try it out so we got a
sweeping edge on this baby i haven't
played around with that yet
uh from what i understand it makes it so
your sweep attacks
apply more damage to the mobs around you
so maybe if we
take a swing at our cows here it'll kill
all
no okay so it doesn't do a lot of damage
yeah yeah i'm not impressed
like the splash damage usually would
only do
half a heart maybe it does like two or
something now i'm not sure
but anyways guys i wanted to show you
the flash furnace system again here
today because i've been working on it
and it's it's pretty much
all done now uh the guts of it at least
and i've added in a fuel port to it now
so if we want to give it fuel
i've been using planks planks seem to
work very good for this actually
so just throw the fuel in there it
distributes it
to both sides and then there's a hopper
minecart right over there that runs over
top of
each of the furnaces and delivers one
plank on the way and one plank on the
way back
um every time it smelts an item which is
pretty cool
and let's just go ahead and check out
the speed of this thing so you might
have noticed i also
doubled the amount of furnaces so it's
not 64 anymore it's 128
so it'll smelt twice as quick now and i
think we can actually go up to
uh 192 at the most and then we're gonna
start having trouble
but yeah basically we throw in our fuel
over here it gets distributed
distributed distributed
to all the furnaces evenly and
takes 10 seconds for the first item to
smelt
plus whatever leg you have from your
hoppers and stuff
also gets added onto that which is not
much time at all
so it does one stack at first just to
get it done and then it does
two every every 10 seconds here
if we made it 192 furnaces though it
would do three every 10 seconds so
i'm tempted to do it but uh
yeah that's that's the rough speed of it
now which is pretty awesome
i was thinking about it today uh using
charcoal is actually
terrible i just realized how bad
charcoal is as a fuel actually
because like you can convert one piece
of wood into one piece of charcoal right
a piece of charcoal will smelt eight
items uh but you have to smelt
the wood so it's it's like you're
getting seven items out of one piece of
charcoal
while if you just turn it into planks
four planks will smelt six items so six
items versus seven
yeah the charcoal is a little bit better
in terms of efficiency but it's very
easy to waste
the fuel efficient efficiency if you
don't smelt exactly eight items with it
yeah so that leads nicely into our next
big
building project guys our next big farm
that we're gonna work on in our world
here
it's gonna be a fuel farm we're gonna
dedicate a farm to making furnace fuel
for our
our big smelter now and like i said
charcoal is not really a great option
uh but we're not gonna use planks either
blaze rods
not so great because you gotta actually
kill the blazes yourself to get the
the blaze rods we could use coal but
we'll run out of it eventually
and i would rather use it for building
blocks in case i want to use
coal blocks and lava buckets are are the
best
fuel source in the game they can smelt
100 items but if we have 128 furnaces
that's that means we need to smelt 12
800 items to make use of all the fuel
in a single smelting cycle
or that's like 200 stacks of items
so yeah lava's not great in our our
giant smelter thing we want something
that will only do like one one item or
so
and surprise surprise this might shock
you a little bit
we're going to be using mushroom blocks
as our main fuel source
so they have the same fuel
smelting time as planks it's one and a
half items
so we don't have to worry too much about
wasting fuel with them
which is nice and also you can instant
mine mushroom blocks so that
uh that opens up some interesting
possibilities when farming them
unlike wood which if you're manually
harvesting it
it can take a little bit of time all
right guys so this should be pretty fun
i've never
made a farm quite like what we're about
to build here i got an
idea in mind for it um so here's our
smelter building right over here
and we're going to try to keep it fairly
close to that so we can send the fuel
by rail or something to it and we don't
have to move it ourselves manually it'll
be all automatic hopefully
and we're going to just build the
mushroom farm around the perimeter of
our pumpkin farm here
i think would be a good idea should look
half decent that way too
because we need a big long straight line
for this
is is the goal so one issue about
like trees is leafy spawn time right
with mushrooms that's not going to be as
big of a problem like after you chop it
down
you don't have to wait for the leaves to
to disappear and like
reclaim the drops the saplings with
mushrooms you chop it down
then you grow another one you chop it
down and you grow another one so that's
what we're hopefully going to be able to
do with this
let's first figure out how high this has
to be i want to dig two blocks down
maybe we'll go up to here so you in
order to get it
to grow on normal soil you need to build
a sun shield
for the mushroom so you got to go and
make a diamond above it
at the minimum that's the center you
gotta
go two blocks out from it all around
all right let's see if that'll grow
yeah now we can plant it here okay cool
so if we grow this it will be
uh yeah that's perfect that's exactly
what i want so i want it to be
where we can walk underneath it
and it always grows one block below
your barrier up here so it'll always
leave an air space there
so if for example we set up
something for us to walk uh walk on at
this level
and we use our our axe
we'll be able to instant mine all the
way down like that and then if we go on
the other side
we'll get the other part of it right
and that'll be a pretty quick way of
chopping down a mushroom i think
but let's not just settle on the first
idea guys let's try a couple different
things here and figure out what is the
best
method for chopping down mushrooms uh so
i grew them in a line like i plan on
i'm doing in the farm here and we're
gonna try out mr horsey first off
got a couple ideas to try out i think
the horses could actually be really good
though
um because horses are fast if you have a
fast taurus and you give it a speed
potion
oh my goodness things will be crazy
let's see if we can instant mine while
riding a horse though okay so he's got
oh yeah we're fast we're fast
oh oh yeah we go underneath the mushroom
if uh
we go underneath the mushroom if we're
riding a horse too that's right
here let's let's do it a little bit less
chaotic let's just hold left and go
see if it gets every block or if it
leaves any behind
that's not bad that's not bad right
maybe if we had a haste beacon here it
would be better even
it's hard to say but yeah that's fast
that is really fast
cool okay that's one idea just out of
curiosity i want to see if we can
harvest the mushroom while flying
what just happened i have no idea did
you see that i was like going slow and
then i just flew
that was crazy
oh ah nah it's it's not really gonna
work
and let's go ahead and try out the mine
carts now i think this one will be
pretty good
so we're not going to have haste to
begin with and then as we get closer to
the beacon there
we will get haste and we'll see if that
makes a difference as we
chop down here okay and we want to be
able to get at least half the mushroom
as we go
so let's go
hold left click all the way down looks
like we're doing a fair bit of it i
don't know forgetting the entire thing
though
oh it's much like the horse like it's
it's it's kind of choppy like when
you're in a minecart or you're riding
something
you you uh
what am i what am i trying to say you
can only chop things down half
half the speed of normal so that is the
downside
and it looks like we're not doing enough
here
yeah because if we went by on the other
side we would leave blocks behind still
so that's not gonna work i think we'll
just have to to watch it probably
oh check this out guys this trick still
works apparently like if you don't want
to set up
a sun shield for the mushrooms if i try
to place this here i can't i can't grow
the mushroom here because it's in direct
sunlight but
if you place down a water bucket first
then place it in there before the water
spreads
then you can plant it down but as soon
as it updates it will
it'll pop off so you gotta like just
grow it right away
like uh let's try that again
or i bet if you try growing it and it
fails then it'll probably pop
off too like if there's
there's something blocking it from
growing like that
if we try to grow it oh it doesn't pop
off
really but if you place a block next to
it and it updates then it pops off weird
now we don't have a whole lot of time
left this episode guys but we'll we'll
try get started on this project anyways
so i figured out a design i like here
for the sun shield
because we want to be able to grow our
mushrooms on regular dirt without
having to worry about anything
so this seems to work out pretty good uh
basically you need a five wide
area blocked above it and uh
put some glowstone over there so it'll
light up the area as well
but it's not too bright that the
mushroom can't grow there so that should
be good and let's just double check our
height again
yeah that's a good height there okay
cool uh so our
our thing we walk on is going to be
running all along here and all along
here
and then we'll also want to set up like
a water system to automatically collect
the
the drops together at some point here as
well
but this is the pattern i'm doing it's
pretty simple just glowstone there
oak stairs all around that
and tried to break up the pattern a
little bit with the bracing in between
with these dark oaks
and then we'll probably connect it on
the side somehow too
this part over here how did i do it
i think i did it like that and then
like that's not that you probably care
but i'll show you anyways um and then
like that and like that yeah that's
that's the pattern
and uh today i also want to show you
guys my rough plan for the redstone like
how we're gonna
operate this farm how it's gonna work so
obviously
we would like to have a dispenser to
grow the mushrooms
right this would be filled up with bone
meal which will hopefully
deliver with a a mine cart of some sort
so we don't have to manually refill
each and every mushroom spot and
that'll make the the mushroom grow
and then what we want to do is deal with
the mushroom stem so i picked this
height for a reason
there's four mushroom stem blocks in
total two of them are above ground and
two of them are below ground like if we
if we mine these out see there's two
blocks down there
dealing with these is a little bit
tricky with a mushroom farm
but i have an idea we're gonna set up
two pistons over here to push us
the stem sideways when it grows and then
we'll
probably control those with like
a redstone torch here we'll probably go
down again
like that okay and then
what do we want to do guys i want to
give a shout out to
maisuma games because when observer
blocks came out
i saw he posted a video with all kinds
of awesome
double extenders different designs for
double extenders and
i'm going to be using one of them over
here so
sticky piston regular piston
and i think he had a block underneath
here i'm trying to build this off of
memory a little bit
and you send power to this block over
here to activate it
then i think he puts let's see i think
he put a piston over here
yeah so that gets that gets activated
and then he faced his observer
that's a dispenser observer blocks
downwards so when
the piston arm gets detected it'll send
power to
this block over here
and when this piston is up one block
then it gets powered from that
and yeah i think that's that's the idea
let's go ahead and try it
hopefully i didn't mess that up so let's
pretend these glowstone blocks
are mushroom stems right
so no
well these two would push them over to
over here then
so let's put them over there first then
we press the button
and you see it makes it go up two blocks
so it would then be next to the mushroom
stem that's over here
they'll be grouped which is pretty cool
if you put a sticky piston up over here
it'll actually
pull the block down as well
you see that that's so cool such a good
design and you can tile this design
like side by side and it works which is
amazing
very cool stuff all right so yeah we'll
use a regular piston there
okay so let's try to figure out the
timing we need on this thing
um i think we want to activate the
double extenders first and then
these pistons on the side i think would
be better
so i have four ticks of delay over there
and we have a monostable circuit here
see if we can use this
i think that worked right
and then oh no no this block's not
supposed to be there
huh i wonder if that broke it yeah i did
this
piston is not supposed to be there
either okay so we're doing it too fast
let's slow it down
let's try hmm
we will bump this up to four i think the
the delay was too short
okay let's try this again make sure it
doesn't break
okay that time the piston retracted with
it that's good
and this did not go though let's add
maybe a little bit more delay here okay
let's try again that time it seemed like
it worked
yeah so that would go up you would
harvest this and then you're left with a
one by one hole instead of a two by one
another thing we're gonna do with this
guys is we're gonna plant mushrooms
diagonal of the spot over here
so we can put one over here one over
there and hopefully we can squeeze them
in
in a couple other spots so that this
will be the only place they can spread
to
and when they spread there we don't even
necessarily have to plant them ourselves
they'll just spread to that spot and
grow automatically
which would be cool uh but let's go
ahead and try this
uh using mushroom blocks now so these
two blocks would always stay here these
two mushroom blocks right
so that we have a one by one hole and
then
this would grow grow
no nothing blocking it okay just got
unlucky
and then when you press the button
it'll do that so there'll be a two by
two thing of stems here
and then when you chop that down
these two blocks will be there still
okay so then you just gotta remove the
top here
and hopefully that will make this fairly
easy to do
and then there's gonna be water streams
like here
here here and here to push all the
the drops to the center here um
all the drops will fall down this hole
and then we'll have a hopper mine cart
that runs underneath that dirt block
there
to pick up the stuff through the ground
is my plan that's what i want to do
anyways
but unfortunately it is that time again
guys
oh we're out of snowballs dang it
uh yeah it's that time again guys we're
gonna have to wrap up here
uh this is how we get snowballs in case
you didn't know
uh we'll try to get more done on that
mushroom farm next episode and probably
some other things as well
but here is the comment for the day guys
it says
whatever happened to your dwarven
treasure dave i know it was basically
abandoned since it wasn't too efficient
or practical
but what happened to the space you had
cleared
nobody ever asks about the treasure cave
i think about it all the time but nobody
cares about it
except for you good sir or madame
uh yeah this is the way over to the
treasure cave we don't go over here too
often
uh the original plan with this was to
have our
if any of you played donkey kong country
you know when you walk in and there's a
big pile of bananas
i was gonna do something similar with
with our gold blocks and iron blocks and
stuff in the middle here
but i found i use those items way too
often
and like i place it down and i'll need
it the next episode pretty much it's not
like i
keep stuff on hand for very long i i
burn through our resources very quickly
uh so nothing really happened with this
i
recently cleared out a tunnel here for
it as i was thinking about doing more
with it
but nothing happened like when i was
working on the man cave the other day
and i tried putting trot and dirt here
just to see what it looked like
because this is a desert biome as well
which makes it hard to
do the nature theme uh right now all i'm
doing here is i'm keeping a bunch of
books i'm too lazy to haul over to the
library and also this is our
our cemetery our unofficial cemetery for
some of our old and broken picks
and tools that can no longer be repaired
because i overused them
repaired them too many times before
mending came out
and that's all that's there right now
i'm glad you care about it
anyways guys hopefully you enjoyed the
episode if you have any comments or
feedback please leave it
down below and until next time
take care bye bye thanks for watching
cthulhu is still alive by the way
[Music]
you