[Music]
hey
how's it going everybody this is etho
and welcome back to my let's play
i'm much appreciated that you could join
me today and
i'm much appreciated i'm not very very
very well appreciated
no i appreciate you guys joining me
today
uh i don't know if you saw it but on
reddit there was this amazing post
about the sheep the rainbow sheep that
we got to try out today
uh very cool apparently if you name
a sheep jeb they've got a new effect in
1.7.3 which i'm updated to now by the
way
and also this this version of minecraft
i'm sure a lot of you saw this too or
you know about this
but there's an option to
have twitch streaming built into
minecraft like it's built in now
so i'm definitely going to take a look
at that and i might
do more streaming if it's as easy as i
hope it is to do that
but yes what we got to do just jeb
i think like that will work
i've only got three name tags so
unfortunately but look at this
isn't that so cool that is
awesome i love that i think it should be
our mission to
to name all these sheep jab we need 32
name tags total to do it
but i want a rainbow sheep farm for sure
that is so cool uh so what happens
also when you shear them
you just get what color it is normally
i'm pretty sure you can dye them again
and it doesn't
remove the rainbow effect
[Music]
i tried it out on on pet wolves i was
hoping it would work on the collars too
but it doesn't
so oh wow that would have been neat too
because you know how you can dye the the
wolf collars now
would have been neat if you could make
it rainbow they need a rainbow dye in
this game that you can just apply to
things too that would be
pretty sweet all right
water bye bye
rainbow jib sheep don't drown on me
i always worry they're gonna die all
right
very good oh
this thing seems to be working okay
except the white
and the gray it's always white and gray
that doesn't show up here so there
i'm going to have to take a look and see
where it's blocked
something is blocking the water stream
to bring it there
but what we're going to do to start off
with today i've been working on that
underground village and that place
is turning out pretty cool
pretty excited about that project now
and we're going to do a little bit of
shopping
because yeah just wait till you see it
things have changed a little bit over
there um
i needed some some wheat
wool zombies always
there's like a hole in the roof in the
tree farm i think and they fall down and
they
they can come up to the villagers here
they can't kill them though
let's grab some paper that's not it
there we go and i said a long time ago i
wasn't going to use my dirty emeralds
for trading with villagers so i'm going
to stick to that we're only going to
use emeralds we we find or that we get
from
shopping here uh with these guys
the rest of those emeralds i'm going to
use for building like
if i want emerald blocks
see i wonder pretty sure you can use
died well we'll bring some of that in
some of this
and let's make our way on over to the
village i'll show you it um
it's always a challenge trying to
remember how to get there i need to set
up a proper path to it
i think i usually go down it's a maze
i gotta figure out every time i go to it
down here
take the rights
did i lose it no i think this is it yeah
the gold box that's how i always
can find it go down here
definitely need a path though because
this is it hurts my brain thinking about
it every time
uh there's been several zombie
infiltrations as well
and we've lost lots of villagers uh but
they seem to
be reproducing at a quick rate so that
the village hasn't died off yet
and yeah look at all the guys all the
life around here now
just it's getting insane
villagers everywhere even an iron golem
spawned inside the red house that we
built last time
and i've built two more houses we got an
orange one now
uh up here i built it up off the ground
a bit
we got one two three four five doors in
this one
and then i also built a purple house
over there
and this is jungle wood
because it's got that pinkish hue to it
and yeah we got skylight there for it
and i made an adjustment to the
greenhouse too i decided
like this used to be stone
and green and there's like iron fences
and stuff it didn't look
very colorful and friendly like i wanted
the village to look like
so i got rid of all the stone and the
iron fences and stuff and now it's
got wood to it and i've i've cleaned up
the inside of all the buildings too
they all have like the proper color
walls and floors and stuff now
instead of being stoned inside
so yeah things are coming along pretty
good here
look at this it's like a line of
villagers coming to greet me
baby villagers that's pretty cool
i'm worried i have an infinite uh
villager breeder
going on here unintentionally because
then the amount of villagers being
created
is a little alarming i'll have to keep
an eye on it
it's i think it's close to the max
population by now like
there's a lot of doors in this village
but there's a lot of villagers in here
already and they're still being
made so i don't know
but yeah we're gonna do some trading um
i got started here accidentally recorded
a bit
without the right settings so uh here we
go
uh i'm gonna try to do as much of the
trading i can on camera so we can have
some fun with the
money management and that sort of thing
and we'll have a central chest
with our emeralds in that we we get from
trading with them
and i may eventually build like a little
a bank building
here too just for the fun of it
where we can deposit and withdraw our
emeralds
the problem is i find
starting out with from scratch with
these guys is a bit tough because
most of the trades they are
hey did he run away when i was trading
with him
what is going on guy this guy's more
expensive
most of them are trying to sell you
things instead of uh
buy things from you so it's kind of hard
to get emeralds to start off with
there's the other one
i want to find a cheap uh paper sale
oh my goodness they're just everywhere
and they're running around so fast
oh protection 4 book that is good but
it's very expensive 25 emeralds
that's a good book i like that one
eight and look at this one this one is
incredible
silk touch one efficiency two only costs
two emeralds and and you need a pick to
put it on
so this is like a really good villager
we're going to try to keep around as
long as we can
um eyes of ender are useless to me
don't want cookies um
you saw that guy already i think
all right here's a paper trade it's a
very expensive one this is like the most
expensive paper trade i think
[Applause]
hopefully we'll find a cheaper one
there's some wool
and they do take colored wool that's
good
thank you sir
trade uh oh
punch two bucks 27 emeralds
there's another guy it's not a great
trade
i'm hoping unlocks a paper trade though
come on oh written book
for emerald okay
here we'll give him a bunch of books
[Applause]
get away from me this is a new one we'll
take this
please give me another book trade or
enchanting oh i like that
that's a good one the first time i got
bottles of enchanting in this world
that's kind of cool the unlock
will get some more not really a viable
way of getting xp
like not a quick way come on guy
unlock a new trade still nothing
he wants all my money there we go
unbreaking two efficiency two
not the best
okay here's the guys looking for 19
wheat for emeralds
i will take that for sure
spending the emeralds so quick i don't
know if we're ever going to have
any any real amount of them on us
hey we wore that one out
you have to give us a new trade right he
didn't give us a new trade
i might have messed that up because i
think he's useless now
maybe you gotta just trade once and and
kind of wait
for it to un unlock a new one
i don't know i'm still pretty new to
this whole trading thing i've never done
it very much
should we do it i just want to see
mostly what these guys unlock as i trade
with them too
nine gold for an emerald ouch uh
i think we'll need to set up some some
way of
of getting rid of the guys we don't want
to keep around to
um in the most entertaining way possible
of course
problem is they're hard to control you
can't really i don't think you unleash
them
all right i'm going to do this again
[Applause]
oh that's a scary noise
that one's done i don't want a compass
[Applause]
all right so that's probably gonna be it
for the trading for today
and yeah i think the next step to this
village we gotta
build some way of eradicating the
useless villagers
and that way we can get new villagers to
trade with
and that way we can keep trading with
them otherwise i'm just going to run out
of emeralds
really quick here
so we're out of the village but before
we left i counted how many doors were
there and then
in total i found 47 so
you divide that by three and there
should be 15 16 villagers max
in that village but i think there might
be more than that
already so we might have an infinite
villager breeding situation going on
in which case death and destruction
is going to have to sweep through that
village
and we'll have to try to figure out how
to stop that from happening
but uh anyway we might head back there
later today i'm not sure
but i asked last episode if if you guys
are enjoying watching me do
work on these old projects or if we
should start some new stuff
up and surprisingly a lot of you
seem to enjoy watching me work on old
projects like get them done
um i think that uh the general
feel was i should mostly focus on the
older stuff and
have a few new things here and there so
that's that's what we'll try to do
oh you know what i need i need some
glass uh
so we are gonna do something at the
library here today not
really work on the structure just an
idea of what we can put inside the
library
this is an experiment i've been wanting
to do for a long time
and it might end up being a cool little
feature for our library
i keep going around the door we can go
through it let's just go through the
door and fall down
but i i want to try and make something
out of mine carts
sort of like a sleight of hand game
i want to have a bunch of minecarts
randomly going around a track here
and see if myself and you guys can
follow
which which of the minecarts has like
the diamond in or whatever
kind of like you know that cup game
people play where
there's three cups and you gotta find
whatever underneath it and he spins
spins the cups around does all this
fancy stuff and it's hard to
start to locate the actual one kind of
like that except
using minecarts with it
and i think i might need to dig this out
a little more
i would like to be able to see
everything within this three by three
uh window oh i hit a button there
that i wasn't supposed to in fact i'm
gonna just put a border around it for
right now
and this is gonna be the floor to our
library actually i built this
the wrong height let's go up one more
i'm pretty sure the floor for the
library is going to be at this height
okay so i think this is going to work
let me show you guys
uh we can see through this three by
three window
everything down there that's that's a
nine by nine pad
and i think it's let me double check
this one
two three four five six blocks down
and though my idea with this is
release of minecarts with an item in
that we're supposed to track and then
release a bunch of
uh storage minecarts with that are empty
when i said minecart the first time i
meant to storage my car by the way
um have them going around this track for
a certain amount of time
and then randomize each of these
junctions so
all the minecarts will get shuffled
around quite a bit
and i want to see what it takes to fool
fool our eyes into not being able to
uh track the proper item if that's
possible that's my goal with this to
make it so you can't actually
follow well not that you can't follow it
that's difficult to follow
the proper item it'll make more sense
once we actually do it i think
so i'm putting power rails uh in a few
places i don't think we need too many
mine carts
keep their momentum pretty good nowadays
there is one problem i think we will
have i don't think i can actually
have a junction like this where it goes
four directions i think you can only do
three directions
otherwise when you power this i don't
think it switches
do i have anything i can power with no
take my word for it i'm pretty sure it
doesn't work
so
i don't know if i like this pattern
actually
anyway i'll try to come up with
something hopefully end up with
see how many junctions is this this
might be too many junctions
i was hoping to end up with like 12
different junctions but i might have
went over
over that i might have got carried away
here
um
oh well i'll i'll try uh finish this up
and then we will work on randomizing all
of these
came up with a new pattern might go with
this one uh we'll try it out
uh creeper just blew up by the way
that's what all this junk junk is about
but i lived we're all good um so we're
gonna do
just a default test if none of the
junctions change
what does the minecart do when we let it
go on here is the question
that might be cool on its own we'll see
what's going on
huh oh did it run out of
it ran out of speed because it wasn't
switching
oh well yeah i guess it would end up
there wouldn't it just goes around in a
loop
i think if the junctions are switching
we won't have to worry about
it running out of speed okay so
obviously it all ends up here because
it's a loop
okay so the next step to making our game
here is to
randomize each of these junctions and i
marked them out with a dirt block over
top
uh so i could count how many there were
and and visualize it easier
in total we got three per side so that's
12 and then
eight in the middle so 20 total
the ones in the middle are probably
going to be the toughest to deal with
so let's start on those first and the
way i'm going to do this
to do it with redstone alone you would
need a t-flip flop for each of these
probably
and like a hopper randomizer and it
would just be
insane so we're we're not doing a
redstone method
we are going to use snowman walking
around on pressure plates to trigger
them
i think that's the best way of doing
this
um so we will have a redstone torch
below each of these junctions let's
see make sure it works okay so it's
going like this right now
remove it yeah okay it's switched good
here i can show you the the four-way
junction now i think
might not affect it because it didn't
look like that track was connected
oh yeah okay see it it doesn't switch
now because it has four options
aha keep that in mind if you're ever
working on a track
because that confused me for a while i
can't remember what project i was
working on
i could not figure out why the junction
wasn't switching though
all right i'm gonna go i'm gonna hollow
out underneath all this
probably is the best thing to do and
i'll put a torch under each of the
junctions and then it'll be easier to
work with this
okay very good we got all the redstone
in place and i'm quite happy with how
this turned out
uh was easier to do than i expected even
so 20 junctions all all wired up here
basically we'll have once i think we're
going to try one snowman in each of
these side ones
so one snowman will trigger three of
these
and we'll we'll just have him like
walking around
in that area so he'll he'll be able to
walk between five blocks there
so we'll do that for each of the sides
and
it's just a pressure plate torch
underneath
goes up to the torch and then the
junction is right above there
so it's very simple uh the middle was a
little tougher to do
but it wasn't too bad either so i got
eight
pressure plates and a ring all over
there
the ones in the middle these ones that
one there that one
that one there that one there those are
easy to do just
again torch and then up to another torch
in
the junctions right above the corner
ones were a little tougher
i got to go into repeater there's
redstone
dust up there so the repeater powers the
redstone dust
goes to this block and then up to a
redstone torch and
the corner the corner one is right above
there so
i think this should be good to go and we
might put two snowmen in the middle
we're gonna have to try this out just
see how it goes we want
the least predictable setup as possible
though is what we're aiming for so let's
let's try and test this out if i can if
i can get out of here
i sure i had a way out i think it might
be here yeah
okay so to get the snowman in place is
also gonna be
a little tough i think but uh
might be able to do it watch out for
creepers
it was just night time i think we can do
it like this pretty
pretty well just build them in place
drop them down they won't be able to
escape
and hopefully they walk around a fair
bit if they don't walk around too much
we might need more snowmen
okay we'll put him there get one in this
side
oh i hear him triggering stuff that's a
good sign
all right snowmen are nice because they
don't make noise
i'm starting to use them a lot more
they're bad if they
escape though because then they just
leave a snow trail
all over the place uh that you'll never
be able to clean up
so make sure they can't escape if you
use them
for stuff like this
okay that's four in place
honestly not seeing a lot of switching
going on i thought there would be more
oh and this is missing i must have went
through here
hmm all right let's get what
let let's get them going in the middle
too
let's we're for sure putting two here by
the looks of it because it's pretty slow
move around guys the problem is they
don't have a lot of blocks to go to with
their pathfinding so
okay things are switching now a little
bit
they also don't walk all the time is the
other problem
maybe we should get one more in there
and one more in each of the sides that's
what i'm going to do
we'll try that out
so i think we're about ready to try it
out it's switching
pretty decently might need to be faster
yet
because it goes through these periods
where nothing happens and then stuff
happens
a lot but uh
yeah i went and i got some other glass
too this might be better
the white the the clear glass is just
not very clear
is the problem
that might be better i wish i could just
float on invisible blocks
it's probably a trick i could do with
that
um but yeah we're gonna put a minecart
down to see what it does
start off with i also added some
boosters on the edges hopefully that
helps it from stalling
we'll give it a little push so it
shouldn't
stop i'm pretty sure it and it should be
hopefully fairly random looks like it
got stuck in the corner
see if that happens a lot no it doesn't
seem to
that's good it moves fast doesn't it
holy
uh-huh all right let's try add some more
and see if they crash into each other or
what they do
exactly i made six total
hopefully they don't like follow each
other's path exactly or
or anything like that that's that's why
i'm hoping it switches pretty frequently
oh if they stack up like that too that's
bad i never even thought of that
um
hopefully they can separate
um so two of those are stuck together
all right they're having a hard time
splitting i don't think
oh they did split oh now they're back up
um
oh this is weird
okay that is a problem i wonder what we
could do about that
and they once they stack together they
seem to
have a hard time separating
when i introduce them into this though
it's not going to be like all together
it's going to be one
every few seconds and they shouldn't
clump together like this so much maybe i
just can't leave it run for very long
all right i'm gonna stop it we'll try
this again
okay we're going to give it another try
here i'm pretty sure the same thing's
going to happen again though
uh got a little launcher here the re the
real problem is
the junctions just don't switch fast
enough
so they end up taking the same same path
as each other
quite often sometimes minecarts just
stop like that too it's weird
and rather than bouncing off each other
minecarts seem to
uh stack up with each other
unfortunately
i was hoping they would like bounce off
each other and start going opposite ways
and
and like lots of crazy stuff happening
but they just
tend to go with the flow
so yeah to get this actually working the
way i want i'm gonna have to do a
redstone method it looks like oh look
they split
they split come on guys
get out of that figure eights and do
something cool
that would be pretty hard to watch
though even them even though it's
predictable right now
them bouncing around like that is pretty
hard to follow
but yeah i gotta do a redstone method
that switches the junctions a lot faster
that is just not changing at all
look at that that's the problem right
there oh and they stopped
all right it was worth a shot anyway
i'll i'll try to fix this
and we can try it again later oh
permanent stop
unbelievable
all right anyway that was fun
i like that anyway
all right guys that is going to be about
it for today though um
i don't know if you checked out the
comments on last episode but
oh man there were some stories i asked
people what their most painful
experience was
uh physically painful not not
emotionally painful
emotionally painful not quite as funny
as some of the stories i got
um yeah there was there was a lot of
good stories lots of comments too thank
you everybody
you really want to sell me something oh
that's a good deal
we'll do it we'll do it
come on don't lose them they all seem to
be going into that red house
for some reason
oh i did too i wanted to do one
all right or did we unlock we might have
unlocked this earlier i kind of remember
this
enchantment anyway uh
yes so lots of comments i picked out
three sort of at random
so here we go as a response to your
question my most physically painful
experience was when i went to an ice
skating rink
with my friend i've never gone ice
skating before and i knew
i was going to be horrible at it
after about two hours with the practice
walkers
almost like old people walkers i tried
to go without them but i stayed
close to the wall i was doing good but
then my left foot slipped and i fell
down
grasping the wall let's just say
i can't even touch my toes but i did the
splits
the real splits where your crotch
touches the floor
worst day ever
ouch uh number two here
easily my most painful experience was
when i went was climbing
castle peak in the
what is that soraris soraris i was
bouldering without a rope or anything
when a foothold broke under me i slid
slash fell
down the slope which was a good 40
vertical feet
off the ground oh i finally stopped
falling when i landed on a boulder
directly on my knees ouch i smashed both
kneecaps
got my arms wedged into a crack almost
dislocating it
no breaks but i strained one but i
sprained one knee
i was able to limp down safely though
yeah that would hurt that's
yeah i've never really fallen off of a
hill or
or like out of a tree or anything like
that so i don't know what that's like
but i can imagine not well i guess i
i have fallen off my bike going pretty
quick before but
yeah definitely a scary experience i'm
sure
third one is the last one i picked out
well when i was in my seventh grade my
stomach
burst open due to a perforated ulcer
spilling vomit and acid all over my
insides
i couldn't breathe and i was
uncontrollably moaning
i got to the hospital and was in surgery
before school got out
i didn't go back until two weeks later i
ended up with 27 staples
ouch from that's from the surgery
definitely will be the most painful
injury
for a long time
yeah that that was a bad one um
i don't know about you guys but i'm
getting hungry uh so thank you everybody
for your responses there were some good
ones
i yeah there was some
some very painful sounding ones too
um some of the stories were funny some
of them were just like
gory and painful and say ooh um
i i like the funny ones the most like
the first one
anyway thank you for watching everybody
i hope you enjoyed this episode and i
will see you guys again next time
take care bye bye
[Music]