yo what's up everyone this is etho and
welcome back to our single player let's
play world how you guys doing today
don't forget to get your snacks forgot
about that sign I thought I would try to
get on today and record an episode even
though I don't have a lot of time to do
it today but hopefully I can get
something good out for you guys I've
been very occupied with the vanilla
minecraft
map reset lately both with preparing for
the end of last season and now the start
of the new season is very exciting and I
want to be on there playing but don't
want to neglect this series either so
try to get an episode out for you today
even though we don't have a lot of time
to record I do have a pretty cool
project plan for today and hopefully
we'll get a lot done on it but first I
just wanted to show you this thing this
is what we were working on last time
this is for the bombing system that we
were setting up it looks like it's all
good to go the only thing we have to do
yet which we're not going to do today
just because of time constraints I have
to mess with it for a while is we got to
hook up a control system for these trap
doors to let the skeletons and creepers
in at the right time and I want to make
sure I set that up in a way that it it
won't jam up like we got to prepare for
or plan for not prepare for plan for
mistakes in the system like if for some
reason a zombie gets into the into the
skeleton chamber you know we don't want
it to get stuck or something like that
because the skeletons not shooting like
it's supposed to because the zombie or
something like that so I'm guessing the
way I'm going to control these is going
to be time-based somewhat but also will
probably do some logical checking like
if there's a mob in
in our holding areas down there check
that out make sure make sure it does
it's up it works properly is what I'm
trying to say I move some buttons over
to here controlling this thing that's
what get some mobs down to a one-hit
kill but let's head on over to our other
base even though I got our project plan
for today I do not know where I'm
building it yet so what I'll have to try
scout a spot for it before we begin
alright everyone we are back at our man
cave here and I have scouted a location
for our build project for the day let me
take you to it here it's not very far
it's just over this way a little past
the brown mushroom farm that shall never
be completed it seems like it's close
but it's not done just over this way it
this looks like a pretty decent spot I
was looking for a rectangular shaped
room which is in pretty low supply the
thing about caves is they're usually not
that open and the few places I do have
that we're open I've used so this is
about as close as we're going to get and
we'll just rip out this middle column
expand the walls and stuff a little bit
I was looking for a 25 block wide area
at least this is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 roughly at the
widest so we'll have to expand it's at
least 5 more blocks for our build what
are we building today etho you might be
asking well our big project is drumroll
please
ethos lab we're gonna try build ethos
lab here look at all these brewing
stands I got ready so we have a brewing
room already we built this a long time
ago and it's been great it's a it's a
very cool build very useful up over this
way the problem is I had to like Jeff go
right I might have killed him
I don't know so we only have Tom working
here and Tom's good don't get me wrong
but you know most these chests or empty
they've always been empty he can't keep
up with the demand
you know and when I when it comes to
potions I've always dreamed of just
being able to do let's see we have any I
don't think we even have any I'm looking
for a splash potion any splash potion
all right good there we a little work
I've always dreamed of just being able
to do this just throwing potions and
wasting them without giving a care you
know but truth be told it's a bit of
work to get them with that potion room
even though it does speed things up
quite a bit I don't I don't use them
loosely I I use them only when I need
them basically and I want to just be
able to use them whenever I want so I
have come up with a design for a new
brewing thing finally and it's pretty
good I'm really happy with it
we're going to go really overkill with
it to something worthy of burying the
name ethos lab so let me clear out some
space and we will get to work actually I
am in a pretty big hurry here to get
this episode done so hopefully this does
a good enough job just a random cluster
of TNT
that takes out the Middle Pillar very
cleanly I will be very happy we also
need to remove this wall a little bit
let's see what this does
whoa please do a good job that looked
pretty good oh I love TNT yeah look at
that
that's that's wonderful let's lower this
a little bit get a little more TNT going
stand the wall a little more I wonder I
don't know if this is long enough this
room either another one over there
oops I should probably move yeah yeah
cool
and put one more there now I'll clean it
up I like to keep a few of these quartz
ores around like in their or form so
that if I ever need a few levels for
something I just put a few of these down
whenever I need it they give so much
experience points
oh that was my silk touch fortune there
we go
30 levels I just want to repair this
what quick of mine do all right all
right check out all that space we got
now that is wonderful I don't know how
much we're going to need for the build
how big ethos lab is going to be
I haven't pre designed it in creative or
anything what I have done though is I've
pre designed the mechanics behind our
brewing setup that we're going to do so
maybe I'll run you through that before
we get to building we got a nice floor
and to work with here too so the way
brewing works in Minecraft
let's just get this up we can use
hoppers and stuff to automate everything
it's nice what I would like to do is
make a fully automatic brewing room with
the least amount of efforts from me
required so I've come up with a pretty
good thing for that um
if what we can do will I be able to
place this okay I always miss trying to
place it on a brewing stand it's such a
small hitbox there we go okay so what we
can do we can add ingredients to our
brewing stand automatically from the top
there and it stays in the brewing stand
that doesn't leave we can also just
going to power this we can also put
bottles in from the side and those go
into the proper slot if we attempt to
put these from the top they don't go it
only accepts valid ingredients for it
the thing is though these don't normally
stay in the brewing stand if this is
unpowered they automatically go through
the bottom so it's it's a stuff little
juggling act we got to do we got to make
the brewing or make the potion stay in
long enough to brew and then unpowered a
hopper below to suck it out and put it
into storage right the time it takes for
a potion to brew is 20 seconds I think
pretty much exactly 20 seconds like for
this bar to go all the way down so I'm
going to be using a clock a 20-second
clock that's on for 20 seconds like it
will I'm going to use a hopper timer
that will turn the redstone on for 20
seconds and then off for 20 more it's
going to alternate between the two and
the general idea behind our brewing
setup is have let's see how do I do that
I think I have two blocks redstone torch
to invert the signal and that so one of
these hoppers is powered right now one
of them is not if we switch it it
reverses okay so right now it'll go into
the brewing stand I'll hold it until
this is unpowered then it will go from
there so that's what we want and no new
potions can enter into the brewing stand
while it's in this state so we can
alternate between adding them in and
taking them out just by an on and off
real simple that we will control with
our twenty second clock so my design is
based off of this what I'm going to do
is have let's give some chests going
here OOP I think I have a crafting table
up here actually before I make another
one like I always do
okay so I've kind of come up with a
snake tileable pattern for brewing
stands that's pretty good there's lots
of different designs for for brewing
stations there's a lot of cool ones out
there I'm not saying this one's the best
or anything but for for my purpose for
being lazy it's pretty nice I think the
idea is to just pick one you like and go
with it so we'll have a reserve for
bottles there so bottles can get taken
out of that chest automatically and put
into the brewing stand and they went
through the bottom will also have a
chest at the top for ingredients so we
can have a large buffer of ingredients
that's
and then what I want to do is like say
we have a water bottle here I want that
to turn into an awkward potion here and
then move down a line add to another
brewing stand and convert that into like
a speed potion or something and then go
further down the line make it extended
speed potion and further make it
extended speed splash potion you know
just keep it going had like a long-ass
snake pattern of brewing stands so I
found a way of doing it what we can do
is have the hopper facing to the right
with the way these hoppers work though
the the potions or the bottles go down
two blocks here so we got to get those
back up so I use droppers to do that get
that up two blocks and then those go to
a reserve a nice little buffer chess
thing and then see I think I've messed
this up what did I do wrong this isn't
looking right Oh No
maybe it's right maybe it's right yeah
this is what I do
okay so then hopper goes to the side and
we have our next brewing station here
and again we have a hopper on top which
I'll never be able to place there we go
and we have a chest on top that for the
next set of ingredients and you know
just it keeps going down the line
another one here so it's a pretty simple
repeating pattern get our hopper there
now the thing is though we got to power
these droppers to move the items like
that piece of cobble will automatically
get put to that one we need to power it
to get it up to this chair
they go through both where'd it go
I think it went up to the chest through
the hopper it's probably stuck in there
yeah okay so you gotta send power to
that and then we also have to control
the inversion of these two hoppers to
control the flow of the bottles right so
I'll show you how I plan on doing the
redstone for all this it's actually
pretty simple as well
we we need to set up two different lines
of redstone one of them to control the
hoppers and one of them to control the
droppers we don't want them interfering
with each other because for our clock
that's running the twenty second clock
that needs to send one pulse to these
and in that time it needs to send I
think three to the dropper because for
every batch of potions were brewing
we're creating three so if we only sent
one it would only send one potion
through and then two would get stuck in
the dropper and it would pile up and
back up the whole system we need three
pulses for the droppers okay so I want
to put our inverter for the hoppers one
block away from them then have the
hoppers powered using these repeaters
like so and again you can see them
inverting ones on ones off always then
the droppers I'm going to have another
repeater one block up like that with
with our hoppers though this torch adds
a one tick delay to to this one so to
balance them out I'm going to set that
at two and then we are going to have a
separate line of wire at the top here so
this redstone and powered will go to the
droppers and only the droppers not the
hoppers they just had the figure name
that was so similar to each other you
know it's kind of cool but at the
time I think you could get confusing
really easy see there's a redstone torch
underneath here though so we got to make
sure it doesn't power this line at the
top so we put a repeater over that and
that's only one we need to worry about
right that's okay so when this switch is
it doesn't power the top line which is
good okay this should give you a better
idea of the repeating pattern for the
redstone we have the one line down here
for controlling the hoppers you guys
send power to each of these blocks you
can even power them from underneath it
doesn't have to be from the side like we
have here and then we have the other
line at the top here for controlling the
droppers all right and I can take you
through on a quick run of this to how
it's going to work so we got nine water
bottles in our starter chest here they
can't go through at the moment because
this hopper is being powered so our
clock is going to switch this it's going
to turn the power on for 20 seconds that
gives it time to let the bottles into
the brewing stand they're being held
there because now this is being powered
right so after 20 seconds the potions
brew this turns off for 20 more seconds
and that will send them into the dropper
those are ready to be put into there
then we got to send I think three or
four pulses into those droppers and it's
four actually so we do that with this
per cycle we do this
we sent two so that now has one in this
chest one in the top one one in the
bottom three we'll bring the bottom one
up to their top one went into this chest
so we need four pulses and finally we
have three
they're so these are ready to go into
the next brewing stand once it switches
again so if we switch it for another 20
seconds now you can see both brewing
stands have had bottles in these would
be awkward potions at this point so if
we had sugar in there it would become
speed potions and this would be brewing
the next set of awkward potions to go
down the line so it's pretty cool pretty
cool oh you know what I don't actually
need all that redstone I was thinking
about it I can simplify it quite a bit
this is one of the ways I could set it
up or I could even totally remove like
that most of this actually hear that
that that that's all that make it one
wide only and it all I'd have to do then
is power the droppers from below and
these blocks from below like I can do
this like if we put blocks in there
they'll make it all the way up to the
chest if I just have a redstone torch
below it so it'd be something like this
got it up one to the next dropper there
do it again it goes up into the chest
anyway that's the concept behind it all
let's stop talking now and get to
building because we're running very low
on time let's try to get at least
something done
I've decided instead of aligning it like
making this main entrance I'm going to
make over here the main entrance and lay
it out this way we also don't need it
quite as wide anymore because we
optimized the redstone there so let's
just pick a center say around here is
our center I got a layout planned I want
to have if you were to make this brewing
thing you own
you really need one snake that has five
brewing stands in it because the longest
brewing recipe you're going to make is
going to be about five steps to it and
then you just got to shuffle around the
ingredients in the in the brewing stands
and you know move the potions out into
storage every time you switch to a
different type of potion you're brewing
but with me with this lab with ethos lab
I'm going to setup like 10 different
snakes and have every single potion
possible to make all the time and and
have a chest for each of them so I'm
going overkill with this that's the
center I want a five five wide walkway
here in the middle and we'll have one
block here for skin and then the
redstone will go here okay let's let's
just pick an arbitrary starting location
how about there does that work yeah oh
wait no no no we need the hoppers and
stuff okay so let's see start starting
it is the hard part once you got the
pattern going it's easy so in the middle
we're going to have four sets of four
stage snakes it's going to look pretty
good though I think all right get our
pattern doing so we'll have one pattern
here and then another one going here all
right and then we'll have one block for
redstone and then another set go in here
and we'll have a skin on this side and a
skin on this side so you won't be able
to see any of the guts to it really
just an outside appearance anyway that
is the main concept behind my brewing
setup here
let's actually get to some building here
before we run out of time today try to
get a little bit done anyway so with my
room I kind of have a layout planned out
maybe as I build I'll explain some of
this so with my setup with ethos lab
here I'm aiming to make about 10
different of these brewing stand snake
things like some of them will have four
stages some like five I'm going to have
a couple that will be two stages what
I'm aiming to do is have us have one of
these like brewing brewing snake things
designated for each of the potions in
the game if you guys were to build this
so you don't really want well you might
want to do that you don't really need to
do that though all you really need is
one of these snake things and have five
stages to it because of the most complex
or difficult potion to brew is only
about five stages long like a splash
extended invisibility potion will take
five stages to make uhm so all you would
have to do then is a shuffle the
ingredients around in your brewing stand
and empty out the chests if you want to
switch to a different type of potion but
what I'm doing is just making it so I
don't ever have to empty the chests or
change the the brewing ingredients I'm
taking this super duper lazy way to do
in this but downside is I have to make
this big elaborate room for it all which
I enjoy doing so I don't mind doing it
this way but I'm going to get a bit done
here and we will continue now I tell you
the two things I go through the quickest
in this game are iron and redstone
I just cannot get enough of it I wonder
why it's because I do stupid stuff like
this all the time okay so I was messing
around with the wiring below we could do
something like this this will work I
might be able to get rid of some of
these repeaters and make it a little
cheaper but we can control all this from
below which means we can keep it super
thin like this if we want and my plan
with this room is we're going to have
about 10 of these snake things so we got
four of them made here this one is
probably going to be for regeneration
potions this one for instant health this
one for strength this one for fire
resist and then we need to set up about
six more of these throughout this room
so maybe like against a wall here or
there or you know we got plenty of
options still I'm going to try not to
make it a perfectly a square or
rectangle room if I can help it maybe
add some decoration and stuff to it but
for right now let's focus on the center
of the room I want to have a five block
wide path here so that's why I
positioned it like this and at least I
want all my paths in this room at least
five blocks wide so we have seven blocks
here I left one block for each side here
so we can add a skin to it and cover
over most of this stuff so we can't see
it and I'm going to try use quartz to do
it so like we could do this
it's blocks of the things here I want to
see I want to be able to see the brewing
stand for sure and the chess if we could
see the chess
somewhat that would be awesome and be
able to access them from over here let's
another stair there okay we can still
see this chest we don't really need this
chest
much as these ones either this won't run
out too often that's for the ingredients
let's let's do this okay and 10 we huh
it's kind of cool
yeah I kind of like that sure I do it
over here too I ran out of quarts quick
- yeah yes guess why that is ok ok what
do you what do you guys think of that
that's pretty cool I think all right so
maybe we'll do something like that and
then I want to have a stripe of like
roller or something something colorful
over here and and here and then the
three blocks wide to something else in
the very middle give it a real lab look
you know let's change this oh yeah cool
so here's an idea of what it's going to
look like when it is done pretty
presentable I would say we didn't even
put a block behind the brewing stand I
tried quartz maybe we'll put glowstone
or something the court stands out a bit
much a lot of stuff though like we can't
put a block there or or there or
anything that has to be there for the
mechanics yeah I think it looks good so
then the other side starts right there
so hardly anything in between the two
which is awesome I'm going to control
all this with one one o'clock I think
and I'm gonna have an on/off switch for
two so I I don't want this all running
all the time that would be crazy just
whenever we're low on potions I'll start
it up and shut it off when it's done but
that's probably going to be it with that
for today we'll work on it some more
next time and and most likely get it up
and running but it is that time to do
the common thing that we do so here we
go
comment for today hey etho do you have
any idea what you're going to build for
the new season a mine crack or any
brainstormed ideas on the subject I'd
love to know what you think and keep
making amazing videos otherwise my snack
storage will overflow eat those snacks
alright thanks for interrupting uh well
I've been messing around and creative
with different build styles I've been
trying to come up with something I liked
and then you know once I find a style I
like I'll I'll use that in the new
minecraft server um that hasn't been
going so well lately or so far I haven't
found a style I really like I went
online and did some search for fantasy
like architectural builds and I found
one I really really really liked like a
picture that someone made computer
generated and it's looked incredible I
started to try and make the style in
Minecraft and it looked really plain and
really nothing like the picture because
we don't have the colors we need in
Minecraft and we don't have the level of
detail to make to make that one work so
I kind of gave up on that then I started
messing around with all types of
different stuff I've tried underwater
builds themes Space Station build themes
you name it I've tried it so far and
haven't really found a look I like yet
um for my first base I'm just probably
going to wing it and hopefully it looks
good and then if I do a main build I'll
I'll put a little more thought into it
and make sure I have something I like
I've also I've been looking online at
like epic build videos in Minecraft try
to get some inspiration from those
people have made some really amazing
things something I'm noticing though
like I'll take something they've built
in their video that looks amazing
build it in the vanilla texture pack and
it looks absolutely trash it does not
it's I think a lot of these builds are
texture pack based um I don't know I
can't get like what they built to look
good with without the texture pack so
still still having trouble finding a
style without you know cheating kind of
it's not cheating but you know I'm not
the only guy on the server so if I use a
texture pack it's not going to look the
same for everyone else so I want to try
make it look good the normal way I don't
know we'll figure something out anyway
that's all for today I hope you enjoyed
it take care guys have a good one bye
bye
you