[Music]
hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode I got
something to show you here we are in a
creative world right now and I've been
working on that idea I brought up last
episode at the end of it you remember
where we're gonna build a mobile storage
room at our amplified terrain area we're
gonna try to get that going today but in
my creative world here I've been working
out the little details on how it's gonna
work and I am pretty happy with what we
got here it looks like it's gonna go
okay so just to rehash the idea with you
basically we're gonna build these
storage room shells we're gonna have a
few of them around
amplified terrain and the storage
minecarts are gonna move between the
different storage room areas and
depending on where I am in the amplified
terrain world and just hit a button at
one of the storage rooms nearby and all
the contents will move to where I'm at
and that way I don't have to keep
running back and forth or setting up
temporary chests all over the place
because I do that in the man cave and I
got to tell you it is annoying I waste
like two three minutes every time I
forget an item when I'm building
something in there and sometimes I'll
like set up temporary chests and fill
them up with junk and then I finish up
my project and I totally forget about
the stuff in the chests and it's like
where did all my redstone go and then I
find it a couple months later it's like
oh my goodness it there's this chest is
loaded with pistons and redstone and so
I've done that quite a few times
hopefully with this mobile storage room
idea that's not gonna happen as much so
let me show you how it works I'm just I
just got a test setup here I don't have
several stations set up I just have one
setup and it's feeding into itself using
this mine Kirt loop looping track so
here we go this is what it does press
the button get it going and it sends out
five mine carts at a time sort of in a
train type of deal and then they all
funnel in at the next station they'll
fall in from the top like that and they
all line up very nicely in the proper
order which is really important because
otherwise like if we have signs here
labeling what's in each of the chests
and they go out of order you're never
gonna find anything sort rooms this can
be really annoying so yeah it seems to
work pretty good this design is a
totally modular - I can add as many of
these columns as I want or no no no
these are these are rows right wait I'm
gonna mess this up this is a row this is
a column so I can have as many either
way I can have as make columns or rows
as I want with this I'm not gonna
overanalyze that the way the redstone
and all the the tracks are set up it's
it's expandable you have as many or as
little carts as you want with it and I
got it nicely compact here I'm really
really happy with how I did the redstone
so let's let's do it again you can see
it goes over a detector rail over here
when it goes over the detector rail it
tells this thing to trigger again and
you see it trigger there but there's no
carts in it so that's what stops it from
looping over and over so that would be
column you can have any any amount in
the column you want because of that
because it'll keep running until there's
no more minecarts left basically and
then let's get it going again we will
focus on the row sorting so it comes
around feeds into the station here goes
over this detector rail and it makes
these that track junctions track at
Junction it's slurring my words like
crazy trigger at just the right time
that they all split and go into their
proper column so that's cool and the way
that is
I figured it easier just to show you
here than doing in the LP world and in
the LP world we're gonna be focusing on
making the stations work together which
I don't have set up here we have to
figure that out yet alright so when it
goes over this sends up depending on the
length of this current you can adjust
this to add more columns and if you want
but it goes starts here triggers this
Junction first two ticks later triggers
this one and this one and this one and
that's how it breaks them up like that
and these Pistons trigger two ticks of
part two so they're in sync with each
other down here so that is pretty cool
so there are a couple issues with this
I'm gonna point out just with the way
minecraft works if you try to send one
of these minecart trains into unloaded
chunks like this station that's far far
away all the carts are gonna merge
together kind of and have fun have fun
separating them I'm not gonna deal with
that with my setup so if you plan on
doing it you're gonna have to come up
with a way of separating them afterwards
which I may look into eventually but not
not with what I'm doing here second
issue if you log out log back in the
minecarts both have a visual glitch like
they're being is shown down here they're
not actually down there they're there in
the same spot as these minecarts
basically so there's a visual glitch and
they also will will fall down into the
other minecart below so they're merged
together actually thankfully though they
seem to separate themselves properly
see when they're riding they're
Heather's two together now and when they
fall down they should all work out okay
a little bit of a visual glitch going on
still I think but yeah we had seeds in
the bottom that in the top before and
now it's it's worked out properly even
if it doesn't look like it it is it just
takes a little while for it to resync
when you log back in and that's yeah
that ones down here even though it's
there all right cool so we have our plan
figured out I know what we got to do I'm
gonna start a building now we're in our
LP world finally seven minutes in what
is going on here but there was a lot to
show and I actually forgot to show a few
things but I want to try set up three of
those today three of them is enough to
show it working and demonstrate the idea
later as I feel I need more around the
area I will build a more and then it
shouldn't be pretty easy to connect them
together I would say so I want I think I
want one up here in this area I like
this area quite a bit you got this cool
view over here there's like a pathway
that way and I especially like this side
because we have the lake below and I
want to do some stuff with this lake and
then you have this amazing overhang that
runs for a long long ways in the
darkness that I want to do something
with do eventually
so we'll put one maybe against this wall
all right it's getting late time I think
I'm gonna put another one at the top of
our jump pad area here let's see if we
can do this again today oh man
it's actually pretty challenging well I
pause there for a second I was thinking
maybe here but I'm not sure yet this is
probably too close to the other one
we're building all right so let's go up
further
and I think at the very top I was
planning not here a little bit further
never gets old I love that in this area
maybe against that wall we'll have
another one the issue with this area
though is there's so much darkness up
there in the mobs dislike trail down the
mountain I'm worried it's gonna get
blown up if I build something here this
would be a good spot though because this
is up high and we could if we're ever
building something at the top of the
mountain area this would be a good
storage room location and I'm not sure
where I'm putting another one yet I'm
gonna look around but I will get to it
here and I will teach you up probably in
a hour too when I get it all done so be
right back and we are back guys we are
back I got three of those stations set
up all wired and redstone Depp which is
cool
we're gonna start testing them out now
this is like three or four hours later
big surprise this is gonna take a lot
longer than I initially expected setting
up the stations did only take like an
hour too but I'm starting to run the
tracks between the stations and this
place is huge like seriously I have to
run the tracks so far it's yeah this is
not a small project anyway we're gonna
go test this out so let's see yeah yeah
where do I get a jump down I think we
should aim for yeah I think let's aim
for over there for this test I want to
see if it keeps the train formation as
it runs our path here so it's basically
gonna go down this thing and then dead
ends and then it falls a long long ways
and I'm hoping it looks cool as it falls
so that's sort of what I'm going for and
we got to make sure the carts don't
merge in on each other as it does this
if they do we have to change this up
quite a bit all right
here we go run don't miss it
don't miss it how have I not died yet I
don't know I've had so many close calls
out here they come yeah that looked good
actually
that was good there they go oh man just
to go from one station to the other one
this is the track we got running right
now I have to definitely make sure no
mobs can spawn in this stuff or go on
the tracks otherwise all the contents
and the minecarts are gonna get mixed up
and messed up
oh no no why did it not work oh they all
went to the first one ah man all except
for one this one went to the proper spot
I'm guessing I may have some timings
wrong this is where we put that second
one by the way I just put in this wall I
may move this cart rail so it hangs
underneath there instead of going
through the mountain like I have it
currently what it's doing actually is
kind of cool it goes and probably see it
better over here it's pretty complicated
to run the track through this this kind
of terrain actually see just go up and
over here
alright so it this is overhanging the
same overhang you can see actually I
didn't do a good job of it this line is
that's where the track is it's right on
top of those blocks so it comes out this
way takes it right goes down this way
through the mountain and then up and
around somehow yeah and then it falls
from there so that is the first stretch
of our journey I gotta try figure out
why this did not keep the right timing
no so I will be right back aha so I got
the problem figured out here hopefully
it's not too big of a problem to fix it
this is why I didn't just do a tutorial
by the way I want to
I want to like test this thing out for
reals and make sure it works the way I
hope it does because if this thing is a
major flop that would be a big waste of
time for everybody so the issue is these
junctions normally when I set it up
originally they defaulted to face to the
right now they're facing to the left so
it's opposite because it's a different
direction we're facing so I'm hoping I
can just let's see let's get us a
redstone torch going here and invert the
thing and then this will just change the
delay a little bit yeah I think that'll
work yeah let's just put this on top all
right so now that torch adds a tick of
delay so let's decrease this and these
defaults to the proper direction now I
believe yeah so next time we run this it
should work yeah goes all the way to the
end cool all right I'm gonna run it
again let's see what happens I'm
noticing our first one here is incorrect
as well so I'll have to change it if
this works let me show you how I'm
loading them and just basically dropping
in from from here pretty easy seems to
go in the right place always all right
cool let's try it out I know this is a
lot of work this is more work than just
running back and forth ever will be but
that's this is what makes Minecraft fun
is doing stuff like this oh no you don't
not gonna happen
all right and it is nighttime and
raining maybe I'll cut one more time in
and pass the time oh yeah and this time
I put some items in the chest so we can
make sure they go in the right order so
from the left to the right we got stone
redstone grass
cobblestone and coal so they should end
up that way at the station down there
too if they go in the proper order all
right let's go try beat it there if we
can we gotta go or this way and oh man I
get so turned around yeah I think we're
in the right spot I think it's just
right there oh that could have been bad
I am totally lost now we are not gonna
beat it Oh feel into Pearl feel ender
pearl okay well I made such an effort to
get there early oh come on there we go
today okay they're here they are a
little out of place aren't they what is
up with that stone red stone grass
cobblestone and coal whoo-hoo
that's right order but they move forward
a little bit unless it's a visual thing
I think they didn't move forward though
although I can't bump them oh oh I think
it oh yeah they were in the right spot
uh-huh so they desynch like boats do
visually and it can really make things
hard to figure out sometimes I think
they are in the right spot actually okay
good all right guys so we have maybe 10
minutes left this episode and I've
decided we will go do a project at the
manty because we've been we've been
really focusing on this area I want to
get a good start to it right but I don't
want to give you guys an impression we
left the man cave behind and honestly
I'm sick of digging rail lines today so
I don't want to do any more here anyway
but before we go I'm going to tell you a
little more on the plan with this thing
because as it is it's not set up
correctly I don't actually want this
rail line to come
- this thing I want it to run beside it
right and only if the carts are supposed
to go here then there will be a junction
that triggers and then the carts can go
into the station if they're supposed to
his idea is not that they go to the next
station down the line they go to the
station that's calling them which could
be any of them so when I hit a button
here it's gonna trigger a t flip-flop
which will convert a junction to let the
carts go to the station I I hit the
button at right you still following me
it also has to tell the other stations
that they should try release their carts
and the station that has the carts it'll
it'll send them down into a loop will
make a loop between all the stations to
actually call the carts I think the best
way is going to be to send a cart down
the rail line because we have a rail
line set instead of running a red
redstone signal to all the stations
we'll use the track we have send a cart
down and as it passes by each of the
stations it's gonna do the same as it's
basically pressing this button here if
there's carts at that station it will
release them down the track if there's
nothing it won't do anything
so the carts will go down the loop and
then they'll go to the station that has
the D flip-flop set oh stop stop take it
back oh I'm destroying everything oh man
I really wish you could stack carts like
really really wish that right about now
cuz these are not fun to move around it
is a pain oh I do have the chest okay
good um let me fix this I don't remember
how to fix it I think I had that there
and then no that's not right
all right all good all fixed the other
station I built by the way I never did
show it will have to run the rail out
this way to this hill through this hill
and then Oh
and so hard to maneuver the terrain this
is why we need to set things up more
more efficiently it'll go through this
hill there's an arch that we have to
make it cross let's go down I think by
the torches is where I have it yeah it's
over here but there's an arch between
these two mountains I'll have to make it
run through there or underneath the arch
and try build something cool like a cool
little rail line and then it ends up
here and I don't know if I'm building
something here yet I kind of kind of
like the spot so maybe we will but yeah
that's that's where I got it found out
something new today too by the way
something I didn't know about Minecraft
if you have a jump boost of two you
don't take fall damage as easily you can
drop five blocks without taking fall
damage which I did not know that is
actually pretty cool if you dropped six
blocks you do take fall damage oh yeah
so many mom's all right to everybody so
we have made our way back and we are
actually going to do some resource
gathering here which is not something I
usually do on camera but this is special
this is very very special I haven't used
our ice tray here in months in months
I tell you so long I can't even remember
when I did it last because I like this
thing so much that I basically gathered
enough ice to last a lifetime I thought
but we have finally ran out has
so much ice stored up all gone and we
have to get more I love collecting ice
that sound is so great let's see if it
still works yep looking good
perfect all right cool and it survived
the patches I am happy what are you
doing in here oh oh I should have done
that that was bad
so what what I want to do here guys just
really quickly we don't have much time
left but it's going to do a little work
on this room this is our mob room where
the mobs fall down and give us all their
precious gunpowder got quite a bit of
gunpowder just good haha lots of
gunpowder lots of drops and it's it's
getting messy at this point we better
turn them down to they're gonna use
annoying very quickly yeah things are
starting to get messy in this room like
I'm dumping into all these extra chests
and I'm just going to file the chests
more and more oh no you don't know you
don't
I caught a baby zombie heading towards
his village so I I reinforced it a
little bit better now with leaves and
stuff because that scared me he he would
have took out all the villagers I think
if I didn't catch him anyway we should
probably keep a similar theme to what we
did here because it's not a very big
room I don't want to do any drastic
change to the theme so I brought some
bricks and I figure do that here drop
anything no figure we will do a brick
rim around the
wind oh that's scary I don't really want
this glass here I liked it more without
it but the drops are splatting all over
the place and I didn't really have a
good way of dealing with that because
there's always that chance mobs are
gonna bump into each other on the way
down and they will they'll fall outside
and not land on the hoppers even if I
lowered the hoppers yeah so I think
we'll just have to leave it the way it
is
we'll do brick there and maybe another
thing works here like this and then we
would put a water stream here kind of
like what we do do out there the water
is in set one block and I don't know if
we can pull off this thing with the
stairs that we do around but that would
be cool we also need to sort of set up
some automatic sorting here so let's
plan to put a chest access in the middle
maybe we'll do it like this chest here I
want five total put maybe two over here
or these trap chests I don't want trap
chests wait a second let's get the
regular ones not that it really matters
that's just prefer using regular ones
when I did well actually we will need
yeah let's do that
I have a trap down there and a regular
one right next to it and then go over a
block this way do the same thing and
keep the pattern so trapped on the
outside not that it matters I just I
have this I want everything to be
symmetrical when I do it like this okay
so we will put bones and arrows in
maybe this side and we will put zombie
flesh and gunpowder in this one and then
we will put random other stuff in the
middle one like like the sugar and the
glowstone and the bottles the drive
route route to that so maybe let me do a
little bit here we're not gonna get much
done but I'll try try to do a little bit
okay everyone so I didn't get much done
with the room here but I decided to
focus on getting the sorting system in
place so the floor is all ripped up
still and I'm gonna make it look nice a
little later but yeah all the items they
go down this hopper chain here towards
the end and as they pass through here
they end up sorted in these chests so
this one's for bones this one's for
arrows oh you did not just do that where
did you come from the middle one is
gunpowder because that's the most
important yeah zombie flesh and then
this is for random items that don't get
sorted in to anything else and it's a
pretty classic design basically
comparator wire goes down goes to a
repeater and then to a redstone torch up
to the hopper this one this hoppers
faces to the left this one faces to the
right into the chest and that's about
all you need oh yeah and then there's
weight on that one
there's items in there to identify it
anyway so we got our comment for today
picked outs and I thought I'd bring this
one up because I kind of forgot to look
at this when we were in the creative
worlds before but it says a etho I saw
that boat launcher thing you built and
thought maybe you could try creating a
minecart launcher as well three or so
power rails and then launch with a slime
block land on a power rail and keep
going until it until at destination also
I think the item detecting carts instead
of the time carts would be better it
will probably take more work to make but
I think it will pay off later on
as in you won't have to do as much work
later thank you for your input
so yeah let's head over to that world
again and I'll show you what happens
with slime or with that slime block
minecart launching because I was a
little disappointed to be honest because
we were planning on making mine carts
fly between the islands and that is
probably not gonna happen - well
basically that's as far as you're gonna
get it loses its speed really quickly
which is kind of sad whoops did it too
quick there so this is with an upward
piston and a sideways one so that is
like what you're gonna get at max if you
take away the sideways one you get this
instead yeah so I don't know about that
don't know it's not really much to see
but anyway we will keep thinking about
our future plans with the amplified
terrain and hopefully do projects around
the man team still but I hope you
enjoyed today's episode and I will see
you again next time
have yourselves a good day bye bye
you