hello everybody this is etho and welcome
back guys to another episode of our
let's play series so today guys this
might be a bit of a shorter episode um I
do not have much time to record usually
I spend at least eight hours on a let's
play episode but today I have lesson two
so we probably won't get nearly as much
done as we usually do but I'm gonna be
busy for the next few days too so I want
to get you at least something for the
weekend or else you're gonna think I'm
dead or something I don't know so last
episode we built this Enderman farm and
it's working really great really well
not good well okay I took the messing
that up last time um I asked you guys
what we should do for the pixel art for
this thing cuz we got this big white
blank canvas right it's a bit of a waste
to just leave it as it is we should give
it some more character if we can and the
most requested thing is that we turn it
into a watermelon or a lime of some
sorts and honestly I have no idea how
that would work guys but thankfully a
couple people also suggested I should
like make a dragon pixel art or
something of that nature so that's
that's what we're gonna do here uh I
actually just checked online for some
dragon images and there was a really
good one that I'm gonna do here and I
think it's gonna fit in the space so I
got my blocks already here and I guess
we'll just
get it going here the feet are going to
start right here and here I think we're
going to put it right in the middle oh
yeah I think that's looking pretty good
right
this was actually like a Pinterest post
like for a quilt or something I think so
I never actually saw it in-game I was a
little worried it wasn't going to look
good but I think it's going to be good
so I'm just I got the outline all done
guys I'm filling it in now and it's
going pretty good
losing a lot of bone blocks but it's not
a big deal I thought this episode would
it be a good one no to ask you guys a
question you know how we do the comment
of the day at the end of every episode
every now and then I like to ask you
guys questions too though so we had the
1.10 release not too long ago they're
presumably working on the next version
my question is what do you guys want to
see in the next Minecraft release what's
that one feature you want so badly that
they haven't done yet or what do you
think they should be working on just out
of curiosity I want to see what you guys
have to say I actually thought about it
here for a little bit what what would I
say I'll give you my list of three guys
these are the three features I feel they
desperately need to add or address in
the game number one of course is
inventory space they've added so many
items in the game and since the
beginning we haven't done any more
inventory spots except for the shield
space which is like half of an inventory
spot kind of it's not like a full yeah
it's sort of counts as an extra one but
we need more we need more desperately
they have made it nicer to like manage
your inventory with this whole
middle-click thing I use it all the time
now and it's great if you want to select
the block if you have it middle-click
and you got it which is really really
useful once you get used to it my second
thing they need to deal with the whole
slab and stair issue because every time
they add a new block in the game people
want them to add a slab variant for it
and a stair variant they can't keep
doing that though I don't
thank because that also adds to the
inventory issue right they actually need
to create a block that is a slab that
you can like put other blocks in kind of
like the carpenter blocks but maybe
they'll deal with the problem in their
own way you know try to come up with
their own clever solution and ideally be
able to rotate the block every which way
but yeah that's that's a big thing
another big thing is entity leg they
need to optimize entities in the steam
like mobs and just like items on the
ground that kind of stuff they did take
the time to optimize like particles not
too long ago and that was a big big
improvement now if they could do
entities too that would be great
yes that's it right that's pretty good
I'm really happy with that actually that
looks like the the minecraft dragon
right and it's actually surprisingly
detailed for the size you got the wings
you got the spikes think I messed up the
tail it looks like we need more black
there I got to stop looking at these
guys too but yeah I think that's I think
that's what we want one thing I might
say though is it is pretty plain over
there still right I even though that's a
that's a big pixel art there's still a
lot of space left to fill here so I was
thinking we can survive here maybe we
try to make like an Enderman pixel art
to not just the dragon what do you guys
think if I enter in it's pretty good
right oh my goodness I mean I'm going to
keep it though let me let me change this
I'm gonna move that up and let's do like
a bunch of them try to make it look like
a pictograph maybe okay guys so I think
I got this all done I fixed the tail and
everything got a couple more Enderman
down let's go check it out from a
distance here
but yes awesome I'm really happy with
that actually what is it about the
Enderman why do they look so derpy I
guess it's the eyes cuz I got the white
in there maybe I didn't liked how I
looked when I changed the white to black
I don't know I think it's good that guy
on the end there's my favorite with the
Egyptian arms you know because that's
that's what I'm trying to make it look
like just a pictograph cool alright well
we'll call that good for the pixel art
maybe I could fit some more decorative
stuff up there but I think I'm fine with
that alright guys so I'm just getting
some blocks here together for our next
project I'll be honest with you that
little bits in the end there took up all
my recording time so I couldn't just
release a five-minute video I decided to
delay the episode and now this is a
couple days later I am still extremely
busy but I have found probably two or
three more hours I can record today so
let's try to get another project done
quickly here so last time we built that
the Enderman farm I was debating between
that and a gold farm or this general
building general building takes a little
bit of prep work though usually a little
bit of thinking but a gold farm gold
farms are easy so that's what we're
gonna do today I think we'll get started
on it anyway and it should be fun
because we can test it as we go here
okay but before we start building it I
do want to try to figure out what's
wrong with the old gold farm here so the
bunch of zombie pigmen stuck in the
portals right now I'm gonna turn them on
my problem is I have no idea where
they're going
I did this one nope this one that's why
you should label things to guys by the
way so yeah you see when I turn the
portals on that giant leg that's our
first big problem with this farm but
even after even after they go in it if
we go in these portals is it gonna take
me to the same place as them I wonder
did I can't seem to find them well still
lagging still lagging yeah this old
firms not working the best anymore
that's the part that's really confusing
me though cuz they're not going to the
same place as me when I go through the
portal so what where are they going I
think I have to look in like an MC edit
or something to actually figure it out
because whenever I try to find them
they're just gone uh-huh so that's a
little bit of a mystery to me guys I get
the impression portals might be broken
in the game currently like the zombie
pigmen are going to the wrong spot or
something because when we both go
through the same portal at the exact
same spot I've done this test a couple
more times we should end up at the same
place right but it's like they just
vanish like they went somewhere they
shouldn't have I don't know and we also
have that leg problem so here's the plan
we're going to build a new zombie Pigman
farm and we're going to try to build it
right above the nether hub if we tend so
I don't have to travel too far to use it
this platform is that why 232 I think
ideally we want to go as high up here as
possible
so mobs despawn when you 120 eight
blocks away from them they instantly do
spawn pretty much and the bedrock
barrier is that like 128 right so if we
go up to the very top here nothing
should be spawning below that bedrock
barrier as long as we stand above this
points or at this point here so we're
going to do this much like we did the
Enderman farm build pretty low tech
let's mark this as our
Center ich area I'm just going to start
putting down some spawning platform and
see what happens here I guess we do have
to like if we plan on standing here no
mobs will spawn within 24 blocks of you
so I am going to go out a little bit
here before I start building in the
platform okay so I'm just going to do
like a seven by seven platform here to
begin with this will be our first test
in the game previously mobs would not
spawn above 240 I think that changed in
1.9 though so let's take a couple steps
back and now I think they spawn at the
very top of the world alright this is
the moment where we want Sambi Pigman to
appear on that unless I'm wrong ok we
got yes not exactly what I wanted so
that is one problem
oh he's vanishing oh and I'm dead oh no
no no don't blow bolts hold things here
oh snap okay maybe we don't want to
build at the very top we might need to
add a gas proof barrier somehow but yeah
this is good we're getting zombie Pigman
spawning at the top chunk so we can we
can build this at the very top of the
world here and we're going to call this
hardened clay block here our center
point it's right above the the elevator
we got going up here so this is the very
center of the nether hub if I'm not
mistaken and then we're going to leave
at least a 3x3 platform for us to stand
on here as well so I counted 24 blocks
out here and our spawning area is going
to start here and we're going a couple
blocks lower than we were before so that
we can we have the option of putting a
roof over top here that will stop gas
from spawning and also the the big magma
cubes and all that kind of stuff that we
don't want alright so I'm going to do
pretty much the donut firm design I'm
sure most of you guys have seen that
we will try to optimize it a little bit
from what I've seen a lot of those donut
firms have very long travel time so
they'll have like one killing area for
the zombie pigmen that they try to
funnel them all to we're going to set up
several killing areas so that it's
hopefully a little bit more efficient
that way but the general idea is just to
get a whole bunch of spawning area down
so I'm going to build a big platform
here and then we will start having some
fun awesome
so I've been building our spotting
platform here guys a big giant donut
it's got a 53 diameter circle for the
interior here and I'm probably gonna
make it at least five blocks wide and
we'll just see how that works but while
I was building we actually got some
internment spawned so they added this in
1.10 where Enderman didn't spawn very
rarely in the nether and apparently they
can also pick up netherrack now I want
to see if we force force-feed this guy
or look how delicious I know you want it
did I push him up a block well that was
weird somehow I made him go up a block
it's like he has auto jump can I do that
again
what okay that's very very weird
actually normally you can't do that with
mobs right is it just Enderman that do
that if I try to push his zombie pigman
he's not going up there
okay guys very cool so we got a basic
donut built snouts like five blocks wide
probably a few hundred spawning spaces
though this will be a good first test
for it we want to see how quickly they
spawn and respawn on it hopefully we can
get a never ending cycle of death going
on here so I'm setting up some trapdoors
here for this test they see these as
regular blocks in their pathfinding so
they actually run off one of them as
they try to walk to the next one and
walk walk overtop the air and and just
die so there's really not much to these
farms you just got to build a spawning
area shoot
of them and then they should all start
rushing me right okay looking good
looking very good so now how quickly are
they going to come back I don't see any
yet oh there's three but they're not mad
yeah so we need a lot more spawning area
this is not nearly enough let's try it
again
but you see what happens if like the
guys over there for example why can't I
shoot them what's going on you see they
got to walk all the way over there and
then all the way over here we need to
reduce travel time as much as possible
because that takes them several seconds
so we want lots of areas where they can
fall down potentially okay guys so I
just used up all my clay blocks I
doubled the width of this ring the
spawning ring so we should get double
the spawns let's try it again now and
just see how big of a difference that
makes on on how this works we have to
get rid of you guys quickly oh oh oh is
it is it lagging wait a second they had
very stuttered movement now it's going
quick again though cool cool they're all
dying very nice so we got a guy there
already still very bad spawn rates so we
need a lot more spotting area by the
looks of it to make this do what I want
it to do yeah seriously why are they not
spawning
oh man that took forever yeah we need a
lot more area than who
hmm but yeah I am totally out of time
here for today so we'll have to finish
this up another time unfortunately sorry
for rushing this episode a little bit
let's just go down here oh they're
getting stuck over there ah that's a
problem okay that explains it that
platform is a big problem because
they're landing on it and then you stuck
but yeah unfortunately guys I do have to
wrap it up here a little bit on the
shorter side I apologize for that but
next week my schedules back to normal so
hopefully everything is good again ah
here is a comment I picked out for today
though it says etho do you sing at all I
was wondering if you could sing the
chorus part of Way Down Yonder in the
minor key because it is such an ear worm
ah yes I can sing I can sing because
everybody can sing but very few people
can actually sing well and I am NOT one
of them I do not sing in any key I
cannot hit any notes I am tone-deaf
I am very monotone and have very limited
vocal range so I'm not gonna try thanks
for watching guys hope you enjoyed it
hope you have a good weekend until next
time thanks for watching take care bye
bye