[Music]
hello everybody and welcome back to the
let's play series and yes oh snappers
it's officially here everybody the 1.18
update is here
my head's racing
ideas are flowing plans are being made
decisions need to be made so yeah let's
get into it here guys we got a lot of
stuff to talk about a lot of things to
consider so if you haven't been keeping
up with the 1.18 update if you don't
know what it's about it is not a content
update in any way
there's no new blocks there's no new
mobs nothing like that 1.18 is part 2 of
the cliffs and caves update and
basically
uh even though it doesn't add anything
new it's gonna completely change the way
we play this game guys it's huge because
it redoes the way the surface terrain
generates
it redoes the way the caves generate
plus the world height has changed so we
have an extra
64 blocks lower down we can go with
caves plus another 64 blocks we can go
up in the world for building
and the other major thing is ore
distribution
and placement has completely changed as
well so it still follows similar rules
like you want to go to the bottom of the
world for diamonds
copper is higher up in the world that
kind of stuff oh there we go guys 320 is
the new build limit used to be 255 right
this is what it looks like at the top of
the world i just wanted to check it out
see how it is
i wanted to see if i would get a funny
feeling you know when the world height
changed the first time i got a funny
feeling the first time i climbed up but
i think i'm kind of used to seeing the
world uh from higher up now it doesn't
really uh affect me like it used to
oh let's go for a drop down though
that's a lot of heights that is a lot of
height guys i don't know if we're going
to use it all but we have it now if we
want it and i guess if we're going to
talk about the ore changes let's just go
find a cave right let's go look below
the man cave see what we find because
there are new caves right below us now
uh oh yeah and i wanted to show you this
too
uh these glowing squids they spawn over
here which is kind of cool i tried
putting like guardians in this water
before to add some life to the man cave
and they died on me but uh
and squids don't spawn here so now we
have glowing squid at least it'll
it'll create a little bit of activity in
the water there which is cool
yeah this part of the man cave isn't
really uh um finished or anything like
that but maybe maybe we do something
with it now maybe we do
uh
if we head down let's just dig
right over here and see what happens why
don't we so
how are we going to get through the
bedrock is the big question
any ideas any plans well
turns out there is no bedrock
which i'm actually kind of happy about
oh
dude where'd that come from oh the
gravel fell and there was live on top
actually i think i do want to go to new
terrain later just to check out a couple
things because i'm curious now as a
secret like why 11 is lava level right
but it probably isn't anymore
is there a new lava level or is there no
level level i don't know i gotta i gotta
look around the new terrain to figure
that out but uh
my world's gonna be a little bit wonky
now because we have the old generation
with the new generation
and in some ways i got the best of both
worlds and in some ways it's just going
to be kind of odd
but yeah let's let's check this out so
the final four blocks
that used to be here that used to be
like stone and bedrock mixed have been
replaced now we now have deep slates
under the man cave
they removed the bedrock layer and it
just kind of keeps going now
and now there's going to be caves and
stuff down here as well so this is kind
of cool like i can actually get deep
slates all over my world
which was something i was a little
worried about like normally i'd have to
go very far like thousands of blocks
away to get this stuff and uh nope it's
it's available everywhere so that's cool
oh here we go we got iron
oh
snappers
we got some redstone guys
oh yeah
oh
we got clay guys look at this
okay yeah this is what i was looking for
this is what i was looking for guys oh
snap so this is below
the man cave
there are so
many bats
what's going on down here
dude look at this guys
oh i was a mile away come on
uh yeah
this is pretty awesome
oh we got glowing squids oh this is one
of those pools with like uh
the clay
the different layers
oh man
so yeah we're gonna be doing some stuff
with this
we'll get to that later though yeah so
ore distribution this kind of shows it
pretty well so if we look ahead there we
got some iron we got some redstone way
up there even higher up i see some
redstone way up there
there's some lower down stuff there
there's some diamonds way up there iron
there
so ores tend to generate at pretty wide
varieties of heights right
um but they do have preferences to
certain y levels where you'll find more
of them so for copper it's like at y48
iron
y16 lapis is zero i think gold is minus
or it might be minus 16. i can't
remember that one
and then diamonds and redstone the
further down you go the better
you'll find more um now there's a bunch
of nuances with that like i think
diamonds have a less likely chance of
being shown on surfaces now you mostly
have to dig to find them uh sometimes
though like that that's an exposed one
there so it does happen and yeah check
this out we do have mine shafts and
other structures generate in this lower
part of the world as well i've seen in
my testing mob spawners forming down
here i've seen amethyst geodes so
basically everything spawns underground
which is cool i double checked on the
the gold thing it is at -16
is the prime layer and
you get more in bases and there's also a
second layer and it's complicated
but uh yeah you look around minus 16 for
it um and then also diamonds they first
start showing up at 16 and then go all
the way down to minus 64. so that's a
huge range
but they're more common the lower you go
down and
this is big guys did you notice like
what has happened here
this is all deep slate right at the
lower ground areas
so
diamonds show up in the lower ground
areas and it's deep slate in the lower
ground areas
that means you can no longer speed mine
diamonds in this this update
because
they're gonna be forming in deep slate
the diamonds and you can't insta mine
this stuff even with ace too so that
means diamonds just got way more
valuable way more rare
with this update
we got like one of these square rooms
still but without the dirt
oh man okay so kind of important
discovery here i was i was running
through the mine shaft right
and
i haven't seen any cold all the coal
generates up higher in the world
i'll live a little yes
um
not down here so once you use up your
torches you can't make more
you know like before if you run out of
torches you just mind some coal you
carry some wood with you and you make a
bunch more right but no now you got to
think ahead and actually bring enough
coal with you
to do it
thankfully i got an ender chest i always
have coal
somewhere
i just got to be careful when i place
this down that the the creepers don't
blow up my life savings
where's my coal oh
oh
no no no systems guys systems there we
go
what does it mean when there's moss in
the ceiling does that mean there's going
to be a cave
not necessarily interesting
huh
i thought if i dug there a tape would
open up but uh no
wait a minute wait a minute there's clay
though
aha
okay
all right i'm understanding the system
here i wanted to check out
not down there
holy smokes
that's a death trap if i've ever seen
one
um no i wanted to check out that one
chasm we just saw where was that
oh there's a mine shaft or uh minecart
the tape has been relatively dangerous
with like the mobs and stuff
oh yeah you can get coal from the chests
oh yeah that kind of makes sense i don't
think you'd get enough from that though
um
let's go down here let's see what
happens
oh yeah there's lava level okay so it's
at minus 54. uh
that's basalt
oh it's an amethyst
geode
oh i gotta mark this
yeah yeah it's a full geode awesome okay
that's a that's a big find
um
i gotta do something here i gotta do it
i just gotta do it
anyways we could probably spend the
whole episode exploring the new cave
system but i kind of want to keep things
moving here so let's let's continue on
i'll do a bunch of caving off camera
just so i can get a feel for it and have
some fun with it you know
uh but yeah we have a decision to make
remember i said there is an important
decision so i have loaded up a brand new
creative world here just so we can get
an idea of how things look how things
feel
um
because
new world guys no no
i know that's what you're all thinking i
think we're going to keep the old world
still i love that world um and it's kind
of at the point now like 10 years more
that we've been going it feels bad to
abandon that world
it's kind of like a historical thing at
this point
um so what we have to decide though is
do we change it to use the new terrain
on the surface so
let's just fly around here a bit get a
feel for it get an idea for it
um
as it turns out i thought amplified
terrain was going away and like we were
forced to use this new
uh surface level terrain system
no it turns out amplified is still in
the game my world is still set to
amplify and it totally overwrites all
this new stuff that has been added so we
need to decide
do we get rid of amplified and go with
the new system or do we keep amplified
and just forget about this surface level
stuff so
just flying around here a bit i've
noticed like it's definitely a lot nicer
than it used to be
um
it's way more interesting than than the
old terrain
but it's still very
vanilla
is what i'm noticing like there's still
huge flat areas um there are definitely
more hills now but they're always
rolling hills they're not like jagged
hills
and
these features though i think still
apply to our amplified terrain if we
generate new stuff
like where it has these big holes hold
out holes and stuff
uh that we will still get an amplified i
think from what i've seen
we use this new stuff though i'm kind of
leaning towards no
i think i want to stick to amplified so
here's my here's my reasoning on that by
the way
and i'm i'm willing to be persuaded if
you guys have an argument to persuade me
i'm all ears
but like none of this terrain is like
wow i gotta build something there right
it's all pretty
pretty standard pretty tame
for the most part i think it is an
improvement though over the original
but amplified like when i see that stuff
it's like wow i really want to build
something here
you know and i don't really get that as
much with this this new stuff even
though it's cool yeah so with the new
terrain system there's definitely some
dead spots like we pretty much flew over
entirely flat land there which is not
ideal
but then there are some cool things like
this is a plains biome with a giant
mountain in like that's cool right you
got the nice flat areas to build and
then you got the mountain in the
background which is kind of the dream
you got a river cutting through here
like i could see you doing something
with this area okay we're definitely in
a more interesting area now so let's
just fly around here a bit more it seems
like it's going to be very seed
dependent like you might get lucky or
you might not
this terrain is way more interesting uh
with the new system
it's a bit more hilly around here uh we
got the jungle it's my favorite biome in
the game i think
and then you got like big height
variations happening over here big flat
spots still for building but you got the
cool terrain around you which is the
dream
and then we got a mesa i want to check
out this
so there are definitely some cool areas
yeah this is cool i like this
okay so what we just saw was 1.18
terrain in a random normal seed now this
is 1.18 terrain in an amplified seed so
this is what we're competing against
which do we prefer
i think i prefer amplified uh but i'm
not gonna make the decision today i'm
kind of leaning on you guys a bit for
your feedback what do you think as well
uh can you make an argument against this
i don't know i am getting stutters i
don't know if it's because i just loaded
this terrain and it's still settling but
that is a concern for sure
stutters are not good but uh this look
looking pretty cool
uh-huh
so this is the new biome as well this is
the uh
drip stone case i don't know if it's
supposed to spawn on the surface like
this
not too familiar with it but it's doing
it in amplified so there we go
uh and then this is the new
ice peaks i think
what's it called
frozen peaks yeah so this goes right up
to the very
tippity top of the world 320.
yeah terrain will go all the way up an
amplified
which means there's gonna be tons of
iron up here because it spawns
super frequently at the very top of the
world
if there's terrain there
um
yeah i don't know
so for my play style i'm thinking
amplified is better because i generally
don't build like nice cities and
villages and houses and stuff i'm more
of a wacky builder
and wacky terrain is maybe better suited
to that
oh this is also the new terrain or a new
biome
sparse jungle oh man we got lucky that's
like all together here
anyways you know it's something for us
to think about we don't need to decide
right away but like if we want to build
a base somewhere new like then we need
to decide
which we might be doing i don't know but
i kind of want to play around with the
underground area to begin with with this
update so that's what we're going to be
doing here today i am gathering some
materials in our let's play here for
project underground okay so the three
main ingredients to project underground
are gonna be soul soil
we're gonna need a ton of bricks
and we also need a bunch of tnt
okay so here we go everybody we are back
down under the man cave in this cavern
we found ready to begin
project underground so
this is a bit of an odd idea
i came up with it like the day before
the update came out i was like i was
trying to think what should i do what do
i want to do
and i had this this idea come to me okay
now i've i planned this out a bit
there's a couple different stages this
can be a little hard to explain all at
once so we'll just take it one step at a
time
and first i'm just going to show you
what i'm actually going to be doing here
so it's very simple we're going to put
down soul sand i think i wanted minus
415 as our center point
so and i think we're going to make this
five blocks wide
and what's our y coordinate 39 is
probably good
okay so all we got to do is put down a
layer of soul sand five blocks wide
right and we're gonna run this all the
way to the wall there
very simple very simple
and then
it's this stuff with the mobs
we're gonna put down some brick stairs
hello creeper
came to check out project underground as
well i see
uh-huh almost missed them there okay
then we got stairs on this side
and
ignore the zombie and then
slaps
like this so this is all we got to build
it's very simple there's not a lot to it
souls soil
and slabs uh-huh so as you've probably
already guessed here what we're doing is
we're building a path this is our basic
design for the path
and it's gonna run through the
underground cavern here have you ever
seen one of those minecraft videos where
somebody like cuts uh
a long minecart track through a bunch of
terrain and then they ride through the
terrain to show it off in the video you
know what i'm talking about
we're doing something similar here but
instead of like showing off
the above ground terrain we're gonna
show off the underground terrain
and we're gonna make it run through the
caverns
okay so check it out everybody we got
our basic path in here and so far it's
pretty cool right like this did not take
much effort this is very simple
and we can kind of check out a nice
peripheral view of the the cave as we
walk through here i think it's pretty
neat
and we put the sole soil under the slabs
here so we get the sole speed effect
from our boots we can run along here
much faster with that
um
and yeah so we want to keep this design
fairly simple like just the basic design
so that we can get a lot of it done
because we want to branch not just in
this cavern but to go to other caverns
and kind of connect this highway
to our entire underground we're kind of
using the the
man cave as our hub for the underground
and it's going to branch off from there
to other parts of our world
this is the underground highway
um okay but now we've hit our first snag
right we ran out of space to work with
and this is a much bigger snag than you
might expect because as we've already
looked
or figured out we can't instant mine
the deep slate right
so when it comes to expanding we're
looking at a big problem here because
this stuff is very time consuming to
break and if we were to
dig out space for the highway there oh
my goodness we are in trouble yeah so
it's very important we come up with some
good tunnel bore strategy here for
getting through the land and this is
what i'm planning so we're gonna go i
think two blocks up is what we're gonna
try and then i'll have to dig these
tunnels these two by one man tunnels
there's no way around this i just have
to
suck it up and do it basically
you can see throughout here we do have
like some
soft areas
so the tunnel
is gonna end up looking pretty varied i
think
but i just have to like dig this out and
the goal is to connect this up to
another one of these caverns now i
happen to know i checked the head
there is a cavern directly in front of
us here about a 100 or 200 blocks ahead
i think yep yep check it out another
cavern guys another giant massive hole
underground
that we can take advantage of here uh so
the idea is we're gonna try to connect
these all together and there's lots of
them like there's tons of these things
scattered underground uh most of them
are quite like densely packed close
together as well this is a bit of a
stretch compared to usual
um
but now what we're gonna do
is one of the fun things
this is where the the project gets
expensive
uh i am not digging this out there's no
way i have found in my testing that
a double layer of tnt actually does a
pretty good job on deep slate but yeah
it is pricey
and we're just gonna run this through
the whole tunnel
okay so it's just about six stacks of
tnt for this first little stretch
i think we are good to go here no mobs
yeah okay let's do it let's do it
and
whoa
oh it followed the whole okay
back up back up
[Music]
sorry that was a little loud
but yeah it does a pretty decent job on
the tunnel right
oh it's still going and i'm not
i gotta keep up with it otherwise it'll
stop
i think
all right
very good so that's a a good amount of
space i don't know if i got the height
right let's find that out in just a
second i just want to light it up so i
don't get mobbed when i'm building the
tunnel
oh it's getting bad on this end
we're good we're fine everything's good
i got my tanky armor on i'm i'm not
taking any chances here okay how are we
lining up here uh yeah it looks like
two blocks up was probably the right
call maybe we could have went for three
i'm willing to do a little bit more
digging
uh the idea is we want to have as much
head space as possible
like as much up here
open up so it doesn't feel
claustrophobic as we we run through here
so we are probably about two to three
hours into building like non-stop
building uh at this point it's not the
most exciting building i gotta say
it's very repetitive
uh but at least we got great views right
i'm loving the second cavern the second
one is so cool there's like multiple
layers to it like up there we got layers
we got
like a cool cascading
water structure there it goes way
far back
over there
and like another layer up over there i
don't know how good it's gonna pick up
on youtube i know youtube likes to
artifact everything
there's a lot of clutter
in these cave systems so
i think like if i was to clean this up
oh yeah a lot of fish are spawning here
apparently uh if i was to clean this up
i want to get rid of some of these
glowberry bush or vine things there's
like way too many i think uh we also
uh probably want to hang some drip stone
and stuff in here but yeah this is where
it connects to our tunnel
and this this is like no polish i
haven't polished it up at all and it's
pretty good right it's not too bad just
raw
the way it is
uh it is a fairly long tunnel
very long path too
so that's where we're gonna get into our
next stage here okay
so yeah we got a long
long straight path and as you run down
here even though we're moving very
quickly it kind of doesn't really feel
like we're moving all that much right
and that's by design this is very
important that the camera is not like
going all over the place as we run
through here that there's not too much
happening
for stage two yeah so there's actually
like a bunch of different reasons i
wanted to build this path thing today
and one of them was just i thought it'd
be a great way to check out the caverns
like from a safe
observation deck kind of thing
we can look down we don't have to worry
about getting mobbed when we're up here
you know it's it's kind of nice right
um the other thing though another main
reason for this path is it's going to
function as a transportation system in
our world
and i
was messing around in creative the other
day
and i figured something out okay
something i thought was pretty
interesting i haven't seen before maybe
somebody's done it before and i just
haven't seen it but
uh
it's pretty cool
so this is gonna be a way for us to play
around with it and uh just show it off
to you guys as well
so what we gotta do for stage two here
is flood
this uh whole middle thing now it's not
gonna flow off the edge or anything nope
we're good
so
i'm i got a ways to go here we're about
400 blocks long with this path at the
moment
we will try to expand it more in the
future but i'm out of bricks for right
now cool all right so we got it flooded
all the way down there we are ready to
move on to the next thing you can see
we're still moving quickly through the
water as long as we got depth strider 3
the water doesn't really slow us down
and we are still getting the soul speed
effect you see the particles are still
appearing
through the water even so that's cool
and the reason i built this out of
bricks by the way even though it's kind
of a
it's not really an expensive block but
you gotta trade with villagers for it um
is it kind of works good with the green
color of the vines and the moss and that
as well as with the blue and it looks
pretty good with the
deep slate as well so it's kind of a
good all-around color for down here uh
okay so next up we gotta get this thing
ready to go we are gonna need to move a
dolphin down here for dolphins grace
and my plan is to set this up like so so
sand over there
we're going to drop them down from the
ceiling here
and then we'll just piss them into place
i'll just set this up for him like that
and i got to go up and like
drill a hole all the way down here
somehow
how do i do that actually let me i think
the way to do it wait
i gotta go like up and then i gotta come
back down again so i'm gonna
pillar up right where i wanna go up
and dig the hole up and then i'll just
dig my way down after
oh
oh no he hit the cactus farm
oh man okay so this is the tricky part
of the whole thing uh the closest ocean
to our base is not not the guardian farm
that's not an ocean
um
it's quite far away actually it's like
800 blocks or so from the man cave we
gotta go all the way over here this is
also is not ocean this is just a lake
over here
but i have found a little little piece
of ocean
right over here oh it's updating
it's loading very slow
yeah right here is ocean
aha so we gotta get a dolphin or a few
of them from here and bring them over
all right we got a couple of them here
so let's name these guys speedy so they
don't despawn as we're moving them
where's the other guy but you
stay still
all right then we're gonna lead them
okay and then we gotta
give them some water breathing i think
okay then they can move out of the water
without dying
oh stay put speedy stay put speedy no
okay
it
didn't quite work
oh man
it's because the water wasn't supposed
to come down with them he was supposed
to fall through the air
come on speedy
let's get it up no
oh he's so dumb
it's my fault
um
yeah so this is speedy number four
hasn't been going the best
oh you you kind of
i don't know how do i unattach him
i don't know
ah this is a problem
he's gonna put the block there and swim
away and then the leech break and he'll
fall down
hopefully
oh why is this so tough
so hard to move a dolphin
did he fall is he there
speedy he's there okay
okay and he's got an item he's happy
let's just block this and we're done i
tried the piston thing and i squished
one of the dolphins somehow with it so
this just
worked better
okay
we got him in place that's all that
matters okay let's get rid of this
piston let's get rid of all this garbage
i had a creeper blow up on one of them
and uh yeah you know it's it's been
tricky now it's very important if you
ever want to store a dolphin you gotta
keep them in a bubble column like this i
got soul sand with water above
he's forced in that he can't get out of
it uh if you just give them water with
air above they will eventually die
so yeah this is a safe way of doing it
though and you have to name take them so
they don't despawn when you leave the
area
okay
so let's get to the trick now
so i was messing around with it i found
a way to get the dolphins grace to work
outside of water like you have to be
touching water but you can have your
head out of water
which is kind of cool that's what we're
trying to do here so
we're going to mine up
five block patch here
then we will have stairs over on this
end
stairs on this end
and
let's see here i wish i had more bricks
i think i'm going to build this up
now the mobs are still getting up here i
thought i took care of that
okay
this this area is gonna need a bit of
work still uh then what we're gonna do
here is just get some temporary dirt
blocks fence gates
that i tried this with signs and it
behaved differently so you got to be
pretty picky on how you set this up uh
and then fence gates opened on this side
break the dirt blocks and now
actually i'm gonna put some
slabs over here
just for now
that when i place water against that
it's not going to fill up the slab spot
okay and then uh
water fill in this area
and we're creating like a little booster
station for the dolphins grace
oh i fall down don't creeper don't
creeper
uh okay
so yeah check it out
all we got to do
is hold sprint and forward
and booyah
we got dolphins grace for a few seconds
right but we go uh pretty fast with it
uh and this is also a two-way booster so
we can use it going the other way as
well
so check this out
hold forward and control
boom
uh-huh you can go out of the water for a
bit and then go back in and you will
still have the speed boost as well
it's kind of a fun thing to play around
with
oh out of the water in the water out of
the water
reboost
aha so the idea is we're gonna have
these booster stations set up every few
hundred blocks in here and we'll be able
to zip through the tunnels very quickly
i don't know if i can like look around
as we're going oh not safely
and the really crazy thing about that
that wasn't even the max speed we
weren't under the effects of speed 2
which gives you 40 more speed so
if we set up beacons and stuff with that
uh yeah we'll go even faster let's try
it out with speed 2
and i was worried this might get a
little too fast though honestly
uh so we we might need to do some
adjusting yeah we made it way past the
water
so we
last time without the speed 2 we only
made it to about here before it stopped
this time we made it all the way to the
end
so it's definitely faster
so if it's too fast if we want to slow
it down there's a couple things we could
do we can get rid of the sole speed on
our boots we can get rid of uh speed 2
from a beacon like if we want to control
the speed and like take a more scenic
tour
uh but if we want to go really fast we
have that option as well
oh man
i also wanted to check out
really
uh if we can uh
get this to activate with our elytra
what happens oh yeah we oh yeah yeah
yeah okay yeah so that's that's going to
be something too
so if we want to take off in the middle
of our run and like go somewhere in the
cavern here we can
let's try that again
this is still like i haven't played
around with this fully there's still
some things i'm figuring out with it uh
yeah okay so with elytra you can take
off just from the ground
which is pretty awesome i like that
not very quickly though there might be a
way to do it better
let's try again
oh yeah you gotta you gotta double tap
space very quickly the faster you do it
i think the faster you will take off ah
it's so much fun
but anyways i do have a stage three in
mind with this plan if we want to
develop it further we won't have time
today
but the idea for stage three is we
actually start building in these caverns
like some of them will probably keep
organic like this but how cool would it
be if we actually like start setting up
farms down here maybe building
custom biomes or building trees like if
you think about it each one of these
caverns
could function as its own uh pocket
basically like it could have its own
biome its own purpose
and it's got all this space already
hollowed out for us
there's a lot we could do right imagine
like
the highway here if we
turn it into like uh
almost like a bridge running across here
i think that would look cool
oh
was that creeper
i am like having a hard time with the
mobs today guys these guys
have been giving me a hard time all day
trust me
uh but the other idea with stage three
if we actually like start building stuff
on the layers like there's layers up
here uh this will also function with
riptide
and we can like hop between the layers
there's another layer over there we
could hop to that we could hop back
to our highway you know
i could see it being pretty pretty cool
and fun right
so
uh yeah we might do more with it i'll
see what you guys say about it what you
think of it
uh but that's probably as far as we'll
get with it today but yeah it's that
time again guys let's wrap up our
episode with the comment of the day it
says hey etho whatever happened with the
noteblock music i really liked it
i really liked it too
uh yeah so this has been asked a whole
ton i thought i'd give a clear answer to
you guys just so you're not confused
anymore about this so i first started
doing the noteblock thing because i
thought it would be a good challenge to
myself to kind of
force myself to learn how to
[Music]
like convert music from sheet music or
from tabs or whatever to
actual minecraft music it's actually
kind of challenging because you're
limited to
two octaves in
in minecraft and only a certain number
of instruments so it was a great
challenge right i learned a lot doing
that about how music works and all that
but uh the other thing is i thought i
was legally allowed to do it
because i'm actually generating the
music on my own computer right it's a
original work
so i thought uh no it turns out there's
something called a melody copyright
claim which i very quickly learned
a bunch of my videos actually got
claimed for that no surprise there so
that started to become an issue i
stopped using like music you would hear
on the radio
and just pretty much limit myself to
video game music
uh it turns out like even nintendo's
claiming video game music these days so
that's not exactly a safe area either i
technically don't have the right to
copy any music is what it comes down to
so
oh that kind of sucks so it's more like
what can i get away with if i do
continue to do it and that doesn't feel
quite right right um
i did kind of limit myself down to just
video game music though and i found like
a lot of songs were hard to
turn into note blocks because it's
actually challenging to do that like to
take a
a song with lots of different notes lots
of different octave ranges and bring it
into minecraft
is not easy right the music i found most
or that was easiest to do that with was
super nintendo music so that's what i
was mostly doing and then i kind of ran
out of
like good songs to do with that so
if i kept doing the note block thing i
just kind of keep repeating the same
music that i've already done and like
the challenge is gone for me so it's not
as fun for me anymore and it would get
repetitive for you guys so i just kind
of stopped doing it is what it came down
to
i did really enjoy it though
and that's where we're at now
thank you for the question i hope you
guys enjoyed today's episode hope you
have yourselves a wonderful day
take care
bye