hey what's up everybody this is ESO and
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play series here I do apologize I
might sound a bit raspy I just woke up I
got morning voice I had my coffee but
it's not going away and I don't know why
usually after my coffee it's gone but
not today
it wants the ones that linger wants me
to sound groggy and raspy and nasty uh
yeah so guys I was just doing a little
bit of check up on the Nexus here and
there there is definitely a couple
issues going on I've noticed some of
these item filters got messed up I don't
know how that happened or when it
happened I might have just done them
wrong and I never noticed but we were
know we got to do that this is supposed
to be stone slabs they can get messed up
if too many items enter at once that
might have happened or I might have just
set it up wrong I'm not sure but we'll
have to keep an eye on it so we got some
items flying by here just dropped off a
bunch of flowers and stuff from from the
man cave all right
but yeah guys big news this is an
exciting day you might have noticed last
few episodes I've been a little bit like
frustrated with this game it's because a
lot of stuff hasn't worked I've had that
big lag issue and it was driving me nuts
like I wasn't able to do any redstone
cuz redstone is all about timing and you
can't do redstone if you can't tell the
timing of the game because it's lagging
though shouldn't be in there all right I
think that's all good kind of want to
watch these items and just see where
they're going make sure no more messed
up it was this that one or two I found
one at the start that was messed up too
alright so they're going down but yeah
this is the big snapshot we've been
waiting for it seems like the lag issues
been
you can ride horses again and a whole
bunch of stuff is just a lot smoother I
logged in and is like wow what's my
frame rate that cuz it seemed like I was
at like 240 frames per second or
something but now is this just running a
lot smoother which is great
it doesn't seem smooth right now because
I'm recording at 30fps
and because the Nexus is doing all kinds
of crazy stuff I'm actually getting
pretty bad framerate at the moment but
just in general it is pretty good okay
that must be nether warts I think it's
okay now there's that sheep in here he's
been in here forever but yeah guys is
the plan for today the challenge or the
goal the project I have in mind is we're
gonna make an automated tree farm that's
what I would like to do first thing we
gotta do is catch a ghast for it so
we're gonna head over to the nether and
I will meet you there once my morning
voice is gone hopefully yeah actually
before we go do that let's try something
here together so I got like a cutaway of
an item filter like you see how it it
looks like that over there so I copied
that over here there's a significant
flaw with my design in the Nexus
basically let's say we're filtering oak
wood planks right if this was the start
to fill up let's see to a certain point
like say all this the chest below filled
up with items what's going on it's not
working oh I'm doing it in the wrong one
right it's supposed to be the top one
not the bottom one it's like what's
going on that's not right
I'm trying to prove a point here and
it's not it's not happening yeah so if
this starts to fill up I think it'll
mess up right oh maybe not oh that's
that's good
well I was worried about nothing then
apparently I thought like if this filled
up then these stone blocks would go out
of place and mess the whole thing up but
it seems to be okay actually all right
never mind
Nexus is working just fine food me
hungry me eat you all right guys so
here's the plan we are over here at the
the gold farm we're here because this
thing will spawn gas for us every so
often and we're gonna try to catch one
and bring them to the overworld let's
just make a portal to begin with here
just so that we know where it's gonna
generate in the overworld I know there's
a lot of tree farm designs that use
Withers so like automatically collect
the wood and that they're really good
definitely really good we're gonna try
to do one of it that uses gas so for a
couple of reasons just because I think
it'll be more fun is the main reason but
also I'm a little afraid of the winner
ones because sometimes the updates can
cause them to act it's weird and then
you have a wither loose in your world a
little bit worried about that okay this
is not exactly an ideal place to come
out actually this might be by the ice
spike biome right I think so all right
what we're gonna do first off here he is
break this portal and we're gonna resize
it so that a gas can go through it
hopefully without suffocating cuz right
now it's just too small we need it to be
four blocks tall and probably wanted at
least five blocks wide alright hopefully
this will work out okay the idea is we
want the gas to come through the portal
and then he's kind of stuck in a cage
here he shouldn't be able to move too
much if we go through the portal we can
hopefully get away from him pretty
quickly without him blowing himself up
or us up and then once we come through
we want to break the portal so he
doesn't get sent back
and then we we have them this is gonna
be the most tricky part of the whole
thing most challenging part I think and
we're trying to figure this out as we go
instead of me like figuring this all out
and creative before handle we're doing
it like the good old days or we
discovered together I think that'll be
more fun oh snap oh snap but it might
also be doomed for failure I'm not sure
this could this is a project that could
easily not work they added some new
sounds for the magma cubes that yes I
haven't heard these before they're they
sound like slinkys now all right we got
a ghast here it's freaking out a little
bit it's all good now we have to trap
him I'm tempted to go in there with an
invisibility potion and see what happens
but he's in such a good spot I almost
don't want to risk it you know let's
let's do this break this we gotta try
get him cornered without him blowing
everything up here if possible all right
so we're gonna start like making a line
don't get out don't get out don't get
out and then like we gotta build a
portal and push him through and see if
that works all right you should be stuck
in the corner now oh that was risky good
as long as we have uh something to hide
behind these magma cubes though that are
gonna give us trouble
no man stupid magma cubes let's see what
happens if we do they after us I'm
actually really scared being here let's
do an invisibility and I think you gotta
take off all your gear what do we toss
there's so much good stuff sword let's
see what happens if we go out and open
now oh yeah that worked great all right
that's not gonna work okay new plan
I just put a portal in the corner right
and maybe the gas will you pushed into
it or we could try ourselves the light
it's hopefully that connects to the one
we made all right eventually we would
get a desk to go through just by random
chance but can we speed this up somehow
I don't know like you see how the zombie
pigmen or pushing them I'm tempted to
just go in there and try push him is
that a bad idea it is am I gonna do it
steel up first yes I am alright here we
go so into that board oh you fat bugger
go we got him
alright now I'm gonna go in quickly
quickly don't go don't let the magma
cubes in please work please work please
work please work please work
no it's fondest in the cave right next
to what really oh that was weird it was
lit up in here when I broke that and
then it the light vanished oh we're
getting big lag time double golden
record e oh my goodness
four saddles this is like the craziest
chest I've ever found but where is our
guest
that is the thing we got to figure out
here yeah no idea what happened to that
gasps he was just gone
let's Hey okay that guy's just fun
should we try to push him through
now we can get another one
let's just make sure we go to the same
spot here it's kind of important
we did go to the same spot that's good
we have zombie pigman here alright so
we're gonna try to get another gassed
and get them down here I made this just
big enough for them okay round 2 here we
go this is like playing air hockey come
on gotta get into the goal gotta get
into the goal can't see it's the zombie
pigman they're they're blocking me best
goalkeepers ever come on no oh this is
not working there's way too many Pigman
in the way yeah take him out
all right oh he's like oh come on it was
raised up right on it it was beautiful
fire causes damage very quickly now a -
for some reason we got him oh all right
please work don't suffocate
please be there he's they're not
suffocating ok let's get out of his face
we got a ghast we got a ghast we got to
break the portal so he doesn't go back
good oh that was trickier than I thought
it would be so now we have to start
blocking this up give them a little bit
of privacy should we do it out of glass
so we can see maybe I don't want these
zombie pigman to get out of here now you
there get out of the way he won't move
yes kill the zombie pigmen don't kill me
I kill you I miss I miss
whew that was close oh there's still
more in there though there's so many of
them they're not able to get out oh they
can get out one by one
got them be the last one okay now we're
gonna have to name this gassed there's
still more in there okay let's let's get
them out of there
I don't want to go in there and then
start getting attacked you know then
then it's all over
if we name them we named them so he
won't despawn we're making progress here
and it'll block him off so now we have
to reduce his cage as small as possible
a four by four by four is what I want to
try to do here let's see if this works I
think he moved right okay if that works
we should be able to place the block
right on top we can take good we reduced
the size we're getting smaller
aha there we go so we got um trapped in
a four by four by four cage now super
tight you'll notice he doesn't even turn
or anything now he's got nowhere to go
he just stares straight in front not
that that that's really important but
this kind of looks funny so I made a
backup of the world here just in case I
mess up as well like if we kill them or
or something stupid happens we'll be
able to revert and I don't have to go
through this terrible process all over
again but we're gonna start
experimenting now so we got to get them
shooting we'll probably have to change
this out with stone right so that so
that he doesn't free himself or
something
okay so let's you know I kind of thought
hmm
like there's no middle block now is the
problem
does let's try this one
I guess oh yeah you could shoot through
that
well happens if you do it on this one
then you can shoot through that one too
that's weird so it's not like censored
then alright so we can have a hole that
he shoots through next question is how
do we get them to shoot the wood because
we're gonna have the trees get harvested
and then get pushed into a line like all
the wood into a line and then we got to
get them to shoot the wood and then we
have to collect it
missed all right I'm gonna move out of
the way oh he doesn't see down missed
this might be tricky oh it's because we
got it kind of to the side we want it
right in front of the hole right yeah we
were one block to the left there do it
like this now you shouldn't have trouble
did he didn't break that iron did he I
think irons pretty blast-resistant I
must have broke that what you can't
break spruce wood
no something is wrong here I know for a
fact yeah there you go we got it you
gotta get that you drop from it - this
isn't looking very promising all right
let me think about this for a second how
are we gonna do this aha so I got a
pretty good idea here I think we're
gonna use water downward flowing water
okay I killed that bat that was
unintentional but I enjoyed it yeah
we're going to do this let's try this
out so the idea is it should make the
bullet go down all right instead of
shooting at us it'll go down and then we
can aim it at whatever we want is the
theory still hit us it does seem like
it's going down more though here maybe
we need something in front of us to
protect us let's try this
that was way off to the left that was
fine that hurt
not working as good as I hoped let's go
up a step
oh yeah this might be it
we're still getting hit though aren't we
not that time not that time oh we might
have found the answer here oh yeah I
think this might be good calm down
alright so the idea is we would try to
get the wood to go in a straight line in
front and like keep keep filling up that
spot and yeah you see that it dropped as
wood good very good
let's try again yeah we got to it almost
seems like it's not destroying the wood
either
yeah we got to that time the challenge
will be trying to make this efficient as
well so we don't lose it every time got
three that time all right
oh I didn't put the wood down but the
idea is we could be we want to make this
so we can afk right so the idea is we
could be like facing this direction
planting trees put something heavy on my
right mouse button right trees grow get
auto harvested the wood gets pushed
around the front here it's harvested put
some hoppers down below maybe some way
of preventing the fire from destroying
everything
so we're not getting shot in the face
anymore right yeah I think this will
work okay look at this
decided to try it without the water to
see if it was actually doing anything it
definitely was because I'm getting shot
in the face every time without it so we
need the water oh maybe not every time I
hit the gas shoots randomly but yeah it
the water was definitely changing the
trajectory well I guess the next thing
we got to do here is figure out how to
get the most out of these shots so we
lose the least amount of wood and it's
the most efficient that that we can get
with this design let's see what happens
if we put hoppers here first stop so
we'll put wood over top see if it can
collect it's pretty consistently I put a
trapdoor in there
hopefully he doesn't shoot it looks like
we're okay did we get we got two that
time all right that's good try it again
she broke all three we got three good
hoppers seems to be working okay
yeah we got both of them very good I'm
running out of wood does it do these
tests we're kind of far away from base
is the only problem with this yeah I
think we got both of them let's see it
does cause a fire on the top here
should be 11 yeah we got 11 very very
good actually does the gas blow-up
hoppers I don't think he does let's
let's check that out just to see if we
have to worry about that
oh man I'm jumping high yeah it looks
like the hoppers are okay that looked
like a direct hit to it yeah I think
we're okay with the hoppers not breaking
one idea like if we're worried about the
fire
we could have let's make some slabs I
don't think we could just put like slabs
here but we could have like a sweeping
mechanic so every so often like on a
clock have this slab push over to the
right for a split second and then pull
back and that will get rid of the fire
if it's on top of any of the wood like
if there's a wood here on fire this slab
goes over top it's gonna put out the
fire and then retract that might be one
way to do it well I guess just to see if
it works or not let's put iron trapdoors
on top of this wood alright my worry is
like the gas ball might hit the side of
the trapdoor and then it won't destroy
the wood I'm not sure but we'll find out
here yes okay would that do oh no it's
still got it still got it
oh okay yeah that might be a good way of
doing it then then there's no moving
parts it just works you know that's
usually a better way of doing things
still have the fire down here but if we
lower the blocks it won't happen
yeah I like that a lot
all right guys well I'm I'm very happy
with what we got here so far like the
harvesting mechanics this we got our gas
steer he seems to get 100% drops out of
the wood he destroys which is great the
hoppers down below here never seemed to
miss picking up the wood and basically
we'll have a delivery system from the
tree farm that will push the wood into
place here like kind of like this get
into position we found out how to stop
the fires from the gas balls and if we
have slabs on the ground here or just no
blocks at all have absolutely zero fires
and we got the trap door Oh actually
we'll probably want to put like obsidian
or something here so it can't push this
far a block of obsidian here or
something but yeah we got the trap door
there I added a little safety mechanic
so it's always closed unless we're
standing here on this pressure plate
that'll put up the trap door put an iron
fence here so that we're out of position
like we were sometimes getting hit if we
were right against this block in front
here and I put another trap door here so
there's no fire bonding in this position
and yeah it just seems to work one 100%
so far all we got to do now is build the
tree farm kind of an important part of
this as well but that's gonna have to
wait until the next episode
unfortunately because it is time to wrap
it up for today so here we go we got the
comments of the day that say what
happened to drum nouvion nights I need
more Team Canada so we went to record
that like we released three episodes we
went to record it one night and oh yeah
you got a hold or you got a press
spacebar to activate the wings that's
gonna fly through the tunnel man uh what
was I saying
Ariel we did it oh man you didn't
activate that earlier than the normal
actually hit my head that time
alright this can take some practice uh
yeah we went to record it one night and
beefs internet wasn't really working and
then we kind of decided like the series
wasn't doing good for me on my channel a
lot of you guys didn't seem to like it
so I don't know kind of decide not to do
it anymore
that wasn't my first time doing an
adventure map it seemed like a good
adventure map but I don't like adventure
maps they're kind of boring from from my
brief introduction to them they're I
don't care about stories and games
usually I'm more about the gameplay and
I like to be challenged and just didn't
have that for me still haven't fixed
this but yeah anyways we might do
another map and a CTM map or something
but nothing to set in stone yet so we'll
you will see if you have any comments
about that if you want to see a CTM map
please let me know in the comments but
yeah here's the second one says hey etho
have you played any RTS realtime
strategy games before like Age of
Empires 2 I have I had Age of Empires 2
I had age of empires 3 oh no what oh
this one always works no I did try
Starcraft like the original Starcraft
didn't really play that much
I played Warcraft 3 quite a bit though
online I got I got decent at it but I
really like the custom games in that
more except for DOTA DOTA sex yeah I
think I've talked about that before
though and I think I've played Starcraft
2 very briefly didn't really appeal to
me too much what else was there I think
that's I think that's all them actually
not a big RTS guy oh there was um mm-hmm
I forget the name of it though I have
played more I just forget the names of
them because it's been so long yeah have
played them I find them stressful though
and not not as fun as a lot of games
it's more about winning it's all about
winning instead of about having a good
time you
no and I don't generally like those
times the types of games as much but
they are fun once in a while uh-huh
anyways we're gonna call it here for
today hope you guys enjoyed the episode
I hope you have a wonderful day and I'll
see you in the next one take care bye
bye