[Music]
so
hello everyone this is etho i just died
in the game
in one of the worst ways you possibly
can i
suffocate in a wall uh this has happened
to me a couple times before
basically i underpurled and got stuck
into a wall
and i was not able to free myself in
time
and i suffocated which okay
no big deal right well this has happened
to me a few times and every time this
has happened to me i've never been able
to find my
stuff again it's almost like it
disappears
so we'll see if we can find it here it's
almost like finding a needle in the
haystack
so i ender pearled out through the mouth
and got stuck into the ground
here i'm guessing i didn't see exactly
everything just went black
and scary so
actually let's use our search tool here
looks like there's a bunch of items up
there yeah entities
are at 50 up this way
oh and there's water right there i heard
grass break
right before i died like dirt broke so
maybe that's what this
is this water here maybe i
busted some of this oh well that would
be up here then
oh there's my stuff yes
oh sweet okay
did i get it all looks like i got it all
okay that wasn't too bad i thought i was
never gonna find it again
i was just out collecting sand for today
for something i was doing
all right and i didn't even mess up my
river when i broke that lily pad
where did this lily pad come from
was it here must have been
cool
that was a relief i got my stuff back uh
it's always such a pain when you got to
remake your picks and your shovels and
your swords and
the main thing i was worried about was
losing my boots but we got it all back
uh and now we are back at the
underground village again today just for
a brief moment here i have uh
i've been setting these up it's moving
day it's moving day for our villagers so
i
got a whole bunch of doors inside these
houses we're gonna see if this works or
not
i cut a line up to the sky there
so sunlight can get down these doors are
facing
uh this way here so this is considered
like the outside
this area and i know from when we were
working on emerald village
you only need like a a two block space
that's one wide for it to count as a
house
so i think this will work uh it just
needs a little bit of space so this is
this is outside here so i think at night
time they're going to come in
here and then they'll probably wander
around the cave but we'll see
that's if they recognize these as houses
so i got that one ready
uh there's seven doors in there and then
i also got seven doors in this one
and we'll we'll see what happens here
so last episode we were working on that
villager purifier thing we're gonna try
it out
um i got a water drop ready for the
villagers here
and we'll go up i cut out a tunnel here
which i'll
i'll fancy up if this works
at a later time got some stairs to come
down and then
i just made a little room here which
i'll i'll make
a little bit nicer yet too if if this
works
but my plan my plan is to
free the villagers and then have the
zombies chase them down the tunnel and
hopefully that works
um i was not able to have pistons under
these half slabs though because when
they're stepping on the pressure plates
it was powering the pistons and i
couldn't get them to move
when they were in the powered state
uh so to free them i'll just have to do
it manually
you're free actually one of these guys i
think it was this one yeah he's selling
diamond chest plates which is pretty
good
yeah you're free i wonder if they'll
wander out on their own
they're definitely able to
yep come on walk this way there we go
they went to go see each other
interesting
i would like them to be over here before
i free the zombies
yeah just like that okay
so this might be their death we'll find
out
i'm gonna have the zombie hopefully
chasing down the stairs
go underlay undelay
that worked pretty good that's right
oh oh don't
okay so he lost his target there
i wonder if we can get him to lose me
nah he's pretty fixed on me he'll
probably run though even if he's chasing
me right
hey guys i think you should get going
yeah i really think you should run
go man go
you know i can get hurt here too not
just you
oh oh okay so i got to be careful about
that
stop going this way
i need him like
yeah like that okay this isn't as easy
as i was hoping
maybe i made the tunnel too wide it was
two blocks wide or
less it would work perfect i think
if they're at the edge like this it's
like they don't want to go sometimes
the zombie can get by them
friendly zombie
oh did he turn on them no he didn't he's
afraid to jump down
okay well
all right that didn't work so well
all right we're trying this again with
the one one block wide tunnel
they're pretty hesitant to move
this guy's this guy's really close i
guess i would have to push him down
myself
there we go oh he came down this time
though
if he's focused on me these guys are
safe it looks like
all right guys the village is yours uh
i know you like the swimming pool but
there's a lot more to see over here
okay i'll i'll let him be down here for
a bit see if they find the houses or not
okay so after some time here it's been
about 30 minutes or so
both the villagers found this house they
both went in it
uh they keep getting stuck in this
little flower bed thing though so i'll
have to change that
uh he has no way of getting out at the
moment
one of them found this house up here and
actually went in it which is good
and i think he's just wandering around
the caves at the moment
which is fine if they see this as a
village they won't get lost in the caves
they have not found this house yet
though and that's what's really
important that they find
this one because it has seven more doors
in
and in total that would be 14 doors
which would support four villagers but
if they only find that one house
it's only enough to support two
villagers
which means they're not going to create
any baby villagers until they find both
these houses
work montage
mushrooms
oh yeah need more num noms
[Music]
super tractor mode engage
aha
i have a skill testing question for you
guys
you ready for it how much wood could a
woodchuck chuck if woodchuck could chuck
wood
the answer a woodchuck would chuck as
much wood as a woodchuck could chuck
a chuck wood
[Music]
all right everybody we have moved on to
the stronghold base here
and it's been a very very long time
since we worked on the mob
system so let's do that today as well
uh so if you remember now we have
the mob system set up we have the mob
sorter set up i think last thing we
worked on
was this quartz display area which i
like quite a bit
so we have zombies that fall down there
skeletons go there
creepers fall there and then if we hit
this button
it releases lava oh
why'd that one go out further than other
ones that was weird
that time it didn't okay um that
releases lava that gets the mobs down to
one hit kill
so we can we can send them through there
or we can just drop them straight down
this pipe and they'll they'll die
instantly
but if you remember our goal with this
thing is to eventually make an automatic
tree farm but before we do that we have
to work
on that bomb factory i made an episode a
little while ago called bomb factory
so hopefully some of you remember that
that's what we're going to try build
today
um so with these pipes up here
we got the three the three pipes you see
the zombie one
skeleton and creeper so
normally and the mob sorters up there so
normally
the mobs will fall down creeper will go
down this water here and then fall down
the hole
but we have these piston setups as well
that allow us to switch the direction
of the water stream now instead of going
to the right
the water goes to the left that one's
for the creeper
this one is for the skeleton i believe
and that will
let's get some more scaffolding
that will bring the water or and the
mobs up to this point here
i would like them to i think fall down
over at this place here so let's uh
set that up
like that i don't know if you can hear
the lawnmower outside but it's probably
gonna get picked up in this video
it's been going for like an hour
um
yeah so why actually no not let's not
use a sign there we're gonna use
trapdoors
uh because we did something similar to
this up at the mobs
order where is that
where is that yeah over here so what
we're doing is we're pushing the mobs
uh down this pipe they get to the trap
door and they stop and then it opens and
closes
really quick so it only allows one mob
to get through and we got to do the same
for each of these because we only want
one skeleton and one creeper to get
through at a time
if possible so let's
let's try to do it the same way
all right oops
oops let's place some more glass
why not all right
okay so trapdoors will control allowing
them
uh to fall down there let's see what
else
so i got to extend this water stream
with the signs and whatnot
here can we put one
i think we got to put one
all right and build this up
and we can get water there i'm going to
work on this just a little bit to get
this
uh section done it's going to be a bit
repetitive
there we go we got this pipe sorted done
now
so the water stream continues here
creepers will get pushed down the stream
up to the trap door and then this is
going to be controlled by redstone to
open and close really quick like that
they'll fall down and this is our next
section here
and the skeleton pipe is much the same
not sure if we can get into it
let's try here
this thing just had to be above us so i
can't walk on top
here it's not not enough space
um all right so skeletons they take this
route here
water gets extended and goes to this
trapdoor and then
same thing in fact we could probably
just set it up
uh so that we have
let's see we'll put a block there
redstone between the trap door blocks
and then another one and we would just
need a repeater
send power to it and it would go through
both and control both at the same time
that's the way we'll probably do it and
then we'll put our redstone over here
somewhere
um but let's go down this is where the
complicated stuff is going to come into
effect
down here i think i want to make
water streams down here as well
one there so the mobs will fall in water
so they don't take damage or anything
and let's see
i think the way i had it before is i had
a piston here
that moves glass up and down to allow
the mobs through or not
this gets extended
right so that would mean
you guys probably don't remember what
we're doing here and you have no idea
what i'm talking about
but uh just keep watching it'll make
sense in a bit
so okay so
they'll come to here that means they're
going to be
standing about here when this piston is
up
so we need this a look through area here
so the skeleton and creeper
can have a clear passage to each other
because we gotta get the skeleton to
shoot the creeper to get him
angry at the skeleton so that when the
two combine they explode
um okay which
side does the snow golem go on i think
it's
creepers here snow golem must be over
here then so we need another one of
these
sections
snow golem goes right here yeah that's
that's right
we'll taste that
i i shouldn't build with this much glass
it's hard to see stuff
oh even for me this this starts to look
really weird
um all right so
we're gonna put pistons above here if we
can hopefully
these trap doors and that redstone up
there's not gonna interfere
i bet you it is yeah it is darn it
yeah i gotta lower this even more at
least one or two more blocks these these
pipes need to be extended
all right i took care of that it's a
little bit lower now and i don't think
the redstone is going to interfere
anymore
uh so these these streams when the
pistons go down
here we want it so that
the mobs will then fall again so i'm
gonna put a sign here
keep the water from flowing down and
we're gonna start another tube
there and there
get that over there
that there okay so now it should be safe
if we
do this right yeah
okay so i'll run you through the steps
to this
this is what i plan on doing those back
up
and we might have to go build this in
creative i'm not sure it's actually
pretty tough to build
here uh what what i want to do
so we got the two streams uh skeleton
and creeper and then off to the side
here there's also going to be
snow golem so let's get him in there
and he's staying alive good good this is
river biome
some biomes they just die instantly and
so it's a good thing we didn't
get stuck in one of those so
instead of actually
let's go back up here just real quick
instead of doing this actually where we
open them both at the same time we'll
probably do it
individually first we'll open the
skeleton trapdoor
and the skeleton is going to fall down
here
into this stream and he's going to get
pushed up to
this wall right and then
once he gets to this place here we need
these two pistons
to retract pull up the glass block
so that the snow golem can see the
skeleton and take a
take a swing at him and then
the skeleton's gonna get hit by a
snowball
and then we want to knock him onto a
pressure plate
let's set that up here
do a stone pressure plate
[Music]
and then we want a piston up over
here to push him back into the water
stream
like that so we need this pressure plate
to power that piston
let's maybe do it like this whoops
no that's another advantage if we were
to go build this
in creative i could fly that would be a
lot easier
nope let's do it up here
and i got redstone good so connect that
to the pressure plate up to the piston
and the pressure plate holds the water
in place so yeah
if this if this skeleton gets hit by a
snowball he's gonna get pushed into this
pressure plate
and then that's gonna activate this
redstone and push him back
this is also going to then go and
release the creeper up there
so creeper will fall down here get put
between the skeleton and this
and the snow golem these pistons lift up
again once more
and that will make the snow golem and
the skeleton take a shot at the creeper
creeper's going to get angry at the
skeleton
and then we want these pistons to go
down
and the angry creeper and skeleton will
get
sent down the tubes and then when we
want them to blow up we
combine them somewhere down the line so
that's the
overall overall plan behind this
now how to do it all um
yeah i'm going to hop into a creative
world just to simplify this and i'll
show you
what i figure out there i guess
i got it guys check it out this is what
we need to build it is so cool
um so what it is or what i did
i ended up putting some trip wires
inside these water stream things so
i can detect when the skeleton enters
here and when the creeper enters his
and if they're in there still because
another thing we got to worry about is
when
if they were to despawn if it's going to
wreck the system we got to be able to
handle that too
but yeah this is this is what it does
get ready for this
so we got skeletons in this dispenser
and creepers in this one
when we release a skeleton
that's so cool it's like a million
things happen in this little area
it doesn't work 100 though i have to
still
fix a few things
oh so much stuff happens there okay so
after the skeleton gets released he
activates the trip wire
that tripwire then tells these
uh pistons to pull up like we like we
said before
they get pulled up for just over a
second
um that's controlled by this here this
is uh
connected to the tripwire this redstone
here
that goes to a monostable
thing and we have one for the creeper as
well
that goes to this this is a pulse
extender which makes it go
the signal lasts over a second and then
that goes up to
an inverter and to the pistons
so
see that stays on for just over a second
that time it glitched out it looks like
this the golem missed
hitting the skeleton so he didn't get
knocked onto that pressure plate
uh so i'll probably have to add a clock
on here
if that happens to try again um
they never miss the creeper though when
he's in there but since the skeleton's a
little bit further away
it's a farther target and he sometimes
misses
time set zero but yeah that
is pretty cool
i love that so much
all right and then the idea is we move
the explosion to whatever we want to
blow up
which is going to be wood from our tree
farm
yeah that's it guys
well that's going to be all for today
everyone but as always
we have comments to look at i picked out
one for today this one says hey etho
me among others really wonder why you
stopped playing on the s
p server minecraft please start play
please start playing on there some more
and even if
you don't please tell us why
except except for that i have nothing
more to say but have a good day
and excuse the english at some places
i'm swedish
just like anders um okay so
we're allowed to tell people now uh the
reason there's been no
s p well there's there has been some but
there hasn't been as many
the reason i haven't been playing on
minecraft vanilla
so much lately is because we're
resetting the map
and we've had that plan for a couple
months now and it's just sort of
discouraged me from building anything
because it's going to get
deleted so the plan is to reset the map
in 1.6 which is coming out
in like a week or so and
then when that happens i'll probably get
back into s p
like i was before so don't you worry
guys it's coming back
uh but that's all for today guys thank
you for watching
and have a wonderful day