[Music]
hi again everybody this is etho
welcome today's episode welcome to
today's episode even
today we'll probably do a continuation
and follow-up of the pop-up sheep farm
here
you can see it's up and running which is
awesome
um yeah even with the full hour last
time i was not able to get this all done
in one shot
i needed more time so we'll we'll work
on it some more today
i really like this farm uh right now the
only thing working
or the only way it's working is with
manual reset we have to hit the button
every time we shear sheep
we want to hook up the automatic system
using the water
today if possible i was going to wait
for
the dispenser thing in 1.3
where you can shoot and pick up water
from dispensers
but somebody pointed out that
you would have to have this open like
it wouldn't look very good because you
wouldn't have a flush roof or flush
ceiling
so we're going to do it the old
old-fashioned current way
of using pistons to to let water
down instead of using dispensers it'll
it'll look better
and yeah i'll show you the wiring
this is what i hooked up at the end of
the last episode i went to all these
and ran this wire here which goes down
to this torch and this controls the
reset
on these things that's the reset torch
right there um
yeah so it's pretty much all wired we
just need to do the water system
and uh what else was i gonna say
oh yeah big confusion a lot of people
had was why i chose to use pistons here
you can use glass you can use half slabs
upside down half slabs
if you used upside down half slabs you
could even make the floor completely
seamless like no no different textures
here
but i chose to use pistons because i
like that
the texture to it kind of breaks up the
room a little bit
compared to using stone bricks for
everything
um yeah but even if you guys use
glass or whatever on this you still have
to push
the block down with the piston because
you can't place it
with the sheep there it doesn't let you
so
just choose whichever one you like the
most i like the piston the most the look
of it
but you'll still have to push him down
the way i did there
um what was i going to say
losing my train of thought here if you
could like if you could use a lamp there
it would have been
awesome because the way this is wired
repeater goes to that block there if
there was a lamp above that it would
it would work like an indicator light
like i have
here except without all the the crazy
wiring back there would have been a lot
simpler
but you got to pick a block that won't
suffocate the mobs i've tried it out
and unfortunately
lamps do cause suffocation
nice feel there i can't reach it
oh no i need an assistant
hmm how can i do this
yeah you see it it damaged me
not the best demonstration but you get
the point you have to pick a block that
won't suffocate the sheep otherwise
you'll just
all die so you got pistons half slabs
um stairs i think you're okay you could
use
uh you know a bunch of different blocks
leaves is another one
yeah but i chose pistons
so to start off with today i think what
we'll do is just a little bit
of cleanup you can see quite a bit of
stuff if you look through these grates
there's not much we can do about that
but we can help it out a little bit
if we were safe to put some blocks here
and now should look a lot better
if we accidentally look through the the
grates you know
you know you have to be from back here
you it looks really good but if
you have to be way up close to see the
redstone and whatnot
so that helps i'm going to do that for
all of them and also
something i want to do is just
cover up this wiring i don't i don't
want to open like this just in case
water spills or whatever
so i'm going to put a block there and a
half slab here on all of them
and maybe something else i'll do is
put a half slab between these so i don't
have to jump as much if i'm walking over
here
yeah that helps a bit it's a little a
little bit easier to walk around now
i don't know if i ever showed this thing
working from down below here
you saw the grass grew and hurt the
piston
pretty soon he'll eat it and pop up
my inventory might look a little
different i
made a little bit of a mistake when i
was recording a clip
i tried to show the water system by
by manually placing the water down and i
left it down for too long a bunch of
sheep died
so i decided to load back up instead of
replacing the sheep a little quicker
this way so i had to redo a few things
here
but we seem to be where we left off
because i backed up the world just
before i started recording
all right so i was looking at the wiring
here and it looks like i could
pretty easily put in a master reset too
uh if i if i run
this is the wire i need to connect to if
i ran
like repeaters going this way on both
sides
i could easily have a manual reset
for for all of them and then also i can
have the water reset thing
so i might do that
you know what on second thought that
won't work because
i can't have the master wire connected
to these individual wires
otherwise like if i had it going here
and i pressed the button for this one it
would reset everything
down the line that it that it's
connected to so
i'm gonna i'm still gonna do it but i'm
gonna do it over here and keep it
separate so it'll go something like
uh
like that so this wire doesn't connect
to the master wire at all but the master
wire can power it
and then here i'll probably do
peter here here and here
block there and there
that'll work it's a little bit expensive
but whatever
we can get more redstone
um so a lot of you know i've been
complaining a little bit about my mouse
recently it's been giving me trouble
a lot of the times when i would single
click it would double click
or a big problem i was having is when i
would try to drag a file around or
something
it would sometimes just randomly let go
of it
and drop it in in folders and i'd have
no idea where it would go
and oh it's just causing me
a lot of angry feelings
whoa so it got
pretty bad to the point where i either
had to get a new mouse or fix it
and you guys have been suggesting that i
should clean it out
clean under the buttons so i tried that
today
and uh i opened it up i was expecting to
see
expecting to see a big layer of of grime
under the button like
dust and dirt and gooey junk or whatever
underneath uh blocking the button
somehow
but uh it looked pretty much
clean i was a little disappointed when i
opened it up
so i closed it i i ran my finger over
whatever dust i could see
try to get rid of it um when i closed it
up
i wasn't expecting it to i fixed
anything
but yeah it's like all better now
so thanks for the suggestion i don't
know
i guess it's just it just must really be
sensitive to dust or something because
there wasn't much
but it's working just fine now or seems
to be
okay so i ran the master wire on both
sides now it's
it's all set up for a test run uh
you would only use that if you had all
these sheep up and you had them all
sheared
or that would be the ideal way of using
it
i still plan on using the automatic
system
pretty much all the time but
it's good to have more options always
so i just for right now i have a lever
in the middle there
to control it when i build the front of
the farm i'll probably
have two buttons one for the the master
reset
the manual one and one for the automatic
system
okay let's try this out let's see how
much it lags the game and
if it's uniform or what
that wasn't that bad i don't i don't
think my frames per second dropped all
that much
i was expecting worse
you know what they actually regrow their
wall really really fast
i i'm impressed
uh before we can continue on here we'll
have to take a little detour
and go to the end because i'm on my last
pick and it's almost dead
for the water system we'll have to clear
out a bit more land in the middle here
go up a bit more so we need some new
picks
i'll probably try stockpile a few picks
here first one up is a 43.
oh man yes
and i broke the efficiency for streak
awesome
uh next up is a shovel i've been without
a good shovel for a while now i've been
using
this thing let's hope for the best here
oh
okay that was unexpected i'll probably
have to enchant another one because i
want efficiency
but that isn't necessarily bad either
let's go again here so we're doing 43
this time
that's what i wanted that's exactly what
i wanted i never get unbreaking
and efficiency together on a shovel so i
finally
finally got a good one
we are not done yet we're having an
enchantment frenzy today
oh does not get much worse than that
uh we'll make this one the last one for
the day let's hope it's a good one
leave on high notes
it's it's good it's good i'm happy with
that
oh boy well i got some sad news for you
guys
um
hmm
it's all gone gonna have to get some
more
uh this is pretty much all i got left
i got some there and
a little bit here and and that
so i don't know if it's gonna be enough
to do the water system
um it'll be close
you'll get quite a bit from this i think
uh the water system is actually pretty
complicated
at first i thought it was going to be
really simple but
in all honesty all honesty
it's like i'm confessing something uh
but the thing is
i want it to look flush with the ceiling
right
so you can't just have one piston
because
if the piston retracts it's still it's
going to be like one block above that
be quiet and water won't be able to flow
down
so you need like a double extender
really
and it gets pretty complicated i figured
it out though i went to creative
and messed around with it a bit and came
up with the solution that's
that's pretty good i don't know it might
be possible to compact it a little bit
more
or make it better but i'm happy with it
so
how much do we have we
might just be able to make it work
i need more repeaters as a problem oh
you know what i could do
um people have been requesting a tour of
my place again
i might do that soon there's not a whole
lot to see really
yeah you just saw it pretty much
but maybe i'll i'll go around and
explain things because i get a lot of
new subscribers every day and i
sometimes
uh i could be a little bit more clear
about what's going on around here i
guess
you can always watch older videos though
if you want
i'm not going to force you but
i'm lost where am i where am i going
i think i want to go this way yeah
i still got that thing sitting there and
there's
loads of redstone in it and i could
probably tear that down
bear squirrel has taken this design and
improved it
and posted it on his channel so if i
need to rebuild it i'll probably just
copy what he has there
with improvements and i don't need this
sitting here i don't need to copy it
from this
so may as well get we
get what we can out of it and clean up
the place a bit
well we got a little bit out of that
anyway hopefully
it'll be enough um i'm extending this
building a little bit over here
just so that the water surrounded the
very first one
um don't know where we're going to put
the
front wall or whatever it might be over
here
but it'll be fairly open even even what
we do put there um
see we'll move this
yeah we'll extend it out to there
uh the trouble
with the water system is we need at
least two pistons for it
to move it out of the way and the other
big issue is
i don't want
here i'll just put this down to show you
if we have the water sitting in just one
block
like on the wood there uh we'll be able
to see it
from down here even when the water shut
off it'll drip
through which i don't like so we need it
at least
one block off that wooden layer there
too
which makes it a lot more difficult
but i have figured out how i want to do
it
let's see do i got pistons yes
so i've i'm gonna be doing
a little bit of a cheat here it just so
happens since i made this
ceiling out of wooden planks if we use
pistons
they look very similar the regular
pistons so that's what i'm gonna do
and i don't mind if it looks a little
bit different it kind of helps to break
up the room a bit
instead of it being all all monotone
so that's what we'll do for one of the
pistons
and then so when it's
when it's down like that the water would
be shut off type thing
and then our second piston we'll put
over here that'll be a sticky piston
and let's see
i might be able to show you this i i ran
the
stone brick here already for the wiring
i'll go
something like
let's see this one gets pissed in there
and then
um oh no that's not in the right spot
that has to be one block higher over
there
i ripped out the ladders now i have to
ender pearl up every time
so it'll be like that then we'll have a
repeater
at the regular piston set it too
and we'll keep it powered
and then it goes to the torch like that
so
since the pistons extended it looks
looks like it's flush with the roof like
that
or with the ceiling
if we hook up a button here i
might be able to demonstrate what
happens
[Music]
that's good right then if we were to
send power
just to
the sticky piston here
since this is being powered
i'll just cut our lights a bit
this is what happens
so it doesn't pull it back because it's
extended then
so it stays there kind of like a cork
in the hole um
why did i come down here just gonna
ender pearl back up now
but that when you hit the button it
shuts the repeater off so
it retracts and can move again so
what we need to do is uh
make this go all the way down and then
i think loop back
and power just the sticky pistons
yeah so that's what we're going to try
to do i'll run this wire down here
and hopefully i didn't figure anything
out wrong here
and we'll see how it goes
okay i got this about half done now so
we'll try it out
there there's one two three
four repeaters to get all the way down
so that's four four ticks
and let's see if this works see see if
it causes a leg or anything
seems to be okay
that's the first stage then we got it
what i'll do is i'll
i'll kind of make a u here i'm cheating
a bit make a u and make it come back
uh that is not the best way of doing it
what i should do is uh
right here set up my delay and then have
it go this
this wire so that it goes this way
but instead i'm making it go back and
come back around
so that'll make
the water in the back stay out the
longer than the water
no it'll make the water in this front
stay down longer than the water at the
very back
so if it was too long it would drown the
sheep but i think we can get away with
it
because the farm's not very long
okay so at the bottom of the u here is
where we're gonna put
the delay i don't know what to set it at
we'll have to play around with it a bit
to get it right but
it needs to be long enough that the wool
will wash into
the grating uh but if it's too long
it'll drown the sheep and i'll get
really mad
so we gotta find the sweet spot in
between
so what we'll do we have to invert the
signal
i'll just put down a bunch of repeaters
and tinker with them afterwards
oh and
yeah okay let's connect these together
that won't work we need to
go up and cut the wire
and here we'll put a block
that should work okay
uh maybe we'll leave it that for now
that's should be a fairly short delay
because they're all at one
then run our repeaters back
and yeah the water will be
right here
where that block is so uh we'll have to
have blocks
on all four sides so there's gonna be a
block
here that we'll have to run our wire
through
on all these we're gonna put the water
in last so i want to make sure this is
right
just so i don't accidentally kill the
sheep again
oh there has to be one here too
okay well i'll uh i'll get this line
done and we'll try it out
all right let's give it a go here i'm
not sure if it's going to be bug free or
not but
that looked good that looked good
so we only want it open for a little
while
um that's way too short though the way
it
is right now so we'll add a little bit
more to it
to the delay at the end there i got more
repeaters on the other side
too uh
if there's quite a bit of leeway with
the water time i'll probably add some
more on the side
just to make the effect look better
what are we going to do
we're just doing dry runs for right now
we'll get to the wet run
soon see how that
is
lots of redstone i'm gonna have to go
mine some more soon
that looks cool uh maybe we can try to
run down to the other end
and see if we spot any glitches
i'm worried about that end one but i
guess we can't really see it
maybe what we'll do
is temporarily disconnect it here and
test it all on its own
let us
i don't know if that's gonna work
no that won't work because we don't have
the torch
hmm
a little close ooh what happened there
okay that might have been from my
messing around i'm not sure
um
not sure we will we'll try it again one
more time
and see if the block gets pushed with
the way it was before
so there is a problem uh even with the
way it was originally it was pushing the
block down
so it's because i did this last one
differently um the tri-safe space
it goes inward with other pistons so
what i
think i need to do
oh that's a problem too
we'll just cut it there we'll put
this back
no that won't work uh if i do that it'll
send power to that wire again it'll
create a clock
so we'll keep it like this i guess
and then have the repeater on the other
side
and hopefully
that fixes it
okay because the holes over there not
not where it made one
actually it's it's not extended either
is it
hmm
me trouble
okay we'll we'll have it in the right
state to start with just to make sure
and let's give it a go i think that'll
fix it
moving the repeater there i think that
did the trick
please please please yes
that did it pretty sure
yeah okay so it's working now uh i'm
gonna put the water in now and we'll
we'll give it a go
there we go we got the water in place
and uh you can see
the water just sits right above the the
piston that's
the cork there uh when the sticky piston
pulls it out of the way the water goes
straight down the hole so pretty good
i've made a world back up because this
is where things can get
really bad really quick so
let's hope for the best uh i also ran
this down here just so we can see it
when we press it
first try
oh and that is why i made a world back
up
i forgot ah nuts
okay i'm gonna load the back up i need
i need like a something here to hold the
water in
all right this will do for now uh i also
put one of these on the back wall
so it doesn't flow down there either i
just noticed that two of my sheep are
dead
are gone or something don't
know when that happened or why
um so i'll have to replace them i guess
um anyway let's try it out
okay that seems pretty close to what we
want
uh we will give it an
actual go here so only if there is wool
there will they get reset
that's the idea anyway
see if it'll move it far enough in that
time i don't think it will
nope that one piece stayed
is close but we need a little bit more
delay
the sheep went down right
yeah there's the wool
so the benefit of doing it that way is
it
it'll automatically get them down and
it'll collect their wool automatically
and if they're in the middle of a cycle
like
if they're down here but the grass has
grown it won't interrupt that
like the the master reset switch
does
let's try one more time here
and that really wasn't that long that
the water was down so i think it's no
problem increasing
it
oh
sometimes the sheep make these sounds
like they're dying but i think it's just
because there's so many of them around
but oh what happened with them
hmm well there's gonna be some
troubleshooting here i think
but uh i'm gonna call it an end for
today
hopefully you guys enjoyed this episode
again and i will see you again
some other time
[Music]