[Music]
hello and greetings everybody this is
etho welcome back guys to another let's
play episode and we are about to do
something crazy just for the fun of it I
saw this today I was like what was that
for why did I build that and I think I
think I built this for a world download
I it's a it's a player cannon by the way
I think I had it set up where I could
launch it I went inside logged out saved
the world so that when people would
download it and and load up the world
they would like instantly get launched
into the sky and I had it set up where
they would survive the launch but not
the fall I think yes oh just for a
little bit of fun we're gonna go inside
this is not planned at all I have no
idea fell survived I think I'll survive
at least the blast at the start but I'm
not sure because I'm gonna put on this
armour protection for we got our
protection for shoes with feather
falling
I don't think we'll survive the fall
even with these because we don't thing a
lot of damage from the blast but we'll
see at one piece of blast protection
armor this is a live for the moments
moment do it just for the fun I am gonna
make a rule I'm allowed to ender pearl
only when I'm about to hit the ground
not not as I'm going up if if you don't
know this what you can't ender pearl
downward and like have it keep the
momentum of of your fall like if you
ender pearl downwards you're gonna hit
the ground before the ender pearl anyway
but I'm aiming to hit myself with the
inner pearl if I'm going the right speed
that will work otherwise it won't anyway
I'm overthinking this let's just do it
no backup 30 levels I have some good
stuff on me I don't want to lose so
whoo-hoo I'm gonna block - whoohoo okay
I didn't go sighs I thought I might we
were fine there oh yeah that was pretty
cool
sneaky creeper alert he doomed himself
though still hasn't happened yet guys no
creeper blasts now I don't even think
even once in my base an incredible like
all the time I've been here like this
bridge has never blown up or any of
these other things I've built I think I
had a creeper blast here once lay a long
long time ago but they seem to get stuck
on these fences and they do stupid stuff
like that where they just fall down to
it so that's a-ok and there's even like
a hole right up to the surface here and
stuff never falls down on me it's it's
pretty cool
anyway we are at 30 levels let's go
ahead and do an inn chance did I fix
this yeah I did okay oh let's enchants
an ice block
protection 3l tickets not bad the vine
farm guys looks like it's doing okay
mmm-hmm pretty good I've been working on
that tunnel that we started last episode
let's let's head on over there I suppose
I think I put the brick in here
yeah there we go it was so sad guys I
went I collected clay put it all in the
furnace all eight furnaces full full
stacks in each one and I got to pick it
up afterwards and it's like hardened
clay it's like that's right you gotta
put the clay balls in not not clay
blocks and so I had eight stacks of
hardened clay that I couldn't make
bricks out of it was pretty sad like I
didn't get hardened clay easy from the
Mesa now so I don't need to convert real
clay into
that stuff anymore and it's just a waste
if I do so that was pretty sad
especially since I spent like half an
hour collecting at all and I only have
like three four stacks left from the
mistake anyway so let's go ahead and
make some stairs it's probably plenty of
stairs I decided to go with with brick
for these things that I think it might
look pretty cool it has that structural
look to it like it's it's kind of like
stone but it has color to it as well
which is what I wanted if I used wood it
doesn't really make sense because wood
rots of course this is minecraft but I
think this is I think brick is probably
the best choice and I don't use it very
often so it's kind of cool to to use it
here I think so we will make this come
all the way around and I sort of did
like the random garbage in the in the
ground here it doesn't look that great
in my opinion it's a little too chaotic
it sort of sort of bugs me but it's
gonna be flooded with water anyway so we
just want texture underneath the water
let's go back up yeah let's go look at
what this looks like we did two all
right yeah we did two now that it goes
all the way around yeah I think I like
that it looks very strong like it's
holding up the ceiling I'm thinking
let's let's try to break up the ceiling
too it might be cool to have like tree
roots coming through the roof and the
walls make it look like this is actually
a cave and maybe have dripping water in
places could be pretty cool let me go
ahead and finish up all these these
bring around things okay I got the brick
done guys
here is the reveal I like it I think
that's pretty cool
I really like how the 3d works like as
you approach it
expands out I mean like the ring like as
you get closer it expands out and
something about that just is really neat
because it does it all the way around
anyway I like it and I'm happy with that
I think brick was a good choice for the
material so now let's go ahead we're
gonna do the flooding I think it's time
for the flooding anyway I would like to
change his dirts with maybe podzol or
mycelium I'm actually not too sure how
mycelium looks with brick I don't know
if I've ever seen that before but we're
gonna flood this two layers thick
thankfully flooding is so easy you guys
remember before ice like before you
could pick up ice water was so tough to
work with
now you just down a couple blocks you
don't need to move half-a-million
buckets of water around it's wonderful
although you know what these blocks here
these are gonna be annoying maybe I
should take these out just temporarily
because I want to do one more layer just
short of the dirt here and then maybe
I'd like as a drain with water flowing
out down into this too would look cool I
guess that kind of looks like a sewer
system if we do that there's nothing
wrong with that though all right so this
is good let's get the next layer going
[Music]
Oh what was I gonna say I had something
I wanted to talk about man I had the
perfect thing to talk about if there was
one of these moments where I was just
doing something repetitive and now I
can't remember it oh and it's not
flowing darn it let's see I think I can
make that update what's that gonna talk
about this is gonna eat at me guys
you have no idea if I don't think about
it soon and it's gonna be too late
because I'm gonna be doing something
else where I I have to talk about what
I'm doing instead of something else
anyway terrible terrible segments in
this video I apologize but we did flood
it that looks pretty good water looks
really good with brick the blue the blue
and the red combo pretty happy with that
we'll get these back and then what I'm
gonna do I think that each of these oh
you know what before I flooded that I
should have I think I need to lower
these one yeah yeah cuz I think we're
gonna gonna go into the wall here like
this dig up and then get more water
flowing down here this is fine right
yeah so break the ice oh this is where
water budgets are better because it
doesn't make water if there's there's
nothing under it all right and we will
put another ice block there all but it
it did that whoops don't panic we can
fix it good all right let's see what
that looks like I might want to do that
for all of them hmm
hmmm I do like that maybe put some
glowstone up in the water - it'll help
light up the ceiling yeah I think that's
good okay just try to put some bricks
around the door we're not going to spend
too much more time on this to date I
wanted to do a few other things around
the cave here see try this out yeah I
think that's good now oh I don't I don't
have any wood on me that's gonna try the
the tree root thing - tell you what I'll
do the water get some lights in there -
and then maybe grab some some wood and
we'll try it mimic tree roots coming
through the roof or something and Boo
yeah sorry guys you missed it it's done
I just went ahead and did it you should
have never blinked you blinked and it
was all done crazy now this was this
took me like an hour was pretty tedious
actually working out all the little
details I have to go collect more leaves
and wood and and I don't know how
interesting it would have been lots of
fiddle farting around as butyl below
would say but I'm pretty happy with how
looks might have went a little overboard
with the leaves but it's pretty good and
then in places like you see there
there's there's water dripping I just
like dug two blocks up stuck a water
block up there and a stone below it so
it looks like the ceiling has water
above I guess that's where the the water
table is at yeah that's it and it's
dripping down into the cave and this is
a water system to prevent everything
from flooding even though there is no
drain yet something like that the birch
leaves look pretty good I'm happy with
them because this is the desert and it
looks relatively green for being desert
I think this is an oak leaf right here
for example and it looks a lot more
yellow I might change it
I got a few of them mixed in I don't
think it's too bad it kind of adds
variety to it over here these are oak
leaves though but it turns to forest so
they look a little more green haha but I
think we should move on to something
else we spent a lot of time here the
last two episodes maybe I'll just do a
few random things around the table can I
remember what I was going to talk about
now that that perfect moment has passed
by the way I tell you guys one when
people are recording when they're doing
their commentary they're a lot more dumb
than the normal because it's a lot
harder to think and recall information
when you're when you're trying to think
forward to what you're gonna say I guess
I don't know yeah but what I was gonna
talk about oh my goodness all the slimes
that have accumulated I wanted to talk
about future projects we've been doing a
lot of like finishing touches and and
working on older things which I have
enjoyed doing Oh snowballs but future
projects I wanted to tell you guys some
of my plans some things I want to build
in the future and kind of see how he's
doing it I hate when they do this look
at this fool he's playing with my my
thing here
amazingly no horses have been freed by
the slimes yet but I want to get your
opinions on what you want to see I have
a bunch of ideas of things I've wanted
to do but haven't started yet if you
have ideas don't be afraid to let you
know either
guys seriously but one of them maybe
I'll just go through a list of a few
things I want to do I've been thinking
about building a zoo in the end and try
to collect all the different passive and
hostile mobs including like gas and
stuff and try build exhibits for them in
the end
and name things with name tags so they
don't despawn the thing is they I've had
trouble with that and in this area even
that zombie we saw last episode he's
gone I don't know what happened I don't
think I logged in on peaceful but I
might've but in the end I'd like never
log out there so stuff won't spawn if we
put a name tag on it
I don't think another idea of course I
wanted to build the Nexus is what I'm
calling it
like a giant storage room with light
lots of minecart stuff dreaming again
bring stuff to and from a storage room
I'll probably connect the portal network
up to it and and my end portal to the
storage room and it'll be like the main
collection of all my junk in this world
I wanted to build had an idea of maybe
building a castle something I've never
done before
castle with a twist though here we're
gonna head on over to the spider farm
that's another thing I've been wanting
to fix might go to like one of those new
areas we saw when exploring with the
cool terrain build a castle there
normally when people build castles they
don't furnish the rooms or anything they
just kind of leave them blank because
it's more about building a big structure
than it is about fine-tuning it
yes but I thought it would be cool to
make it like a redstone Museum castle so
all the empty rooms we'll put like a
redstone device in like what do you call
it an exhibit hey like it'll be one for
for probably while there's probably
gonna be like ten or twenty forty
flip-flops and a little description for
each one how it works and that will I
think that'd be like a cool way of
teaching people redstone and also as a
sort of a reference for myself because
there's lots of different designs for
stuff that I often forget about so if I
have a master reference to redstone
devices somewhere that would be pretty
cool
Oh that last one was important that's
another idea been wanting to do some
stuff with the horses and and like
donkeys and stuff like build a stable
and and try to breed really powerful
horses I guess I don't know what am I
looking for here I want a a chess
because my inventory is a mess right now
I think there was a few other ideas I
can't quite recall right now because I'm
recording and like I said people kind of
get a little dumb when they're recording
just a little bit not not super dumb but
what we're gonna well maybe before I
change topic so yeah if you guys have
ideas let me know I guess I pitched you
three there kind of tell me which one is
your favorite time look I had more but I
just can't remember them oh you know
what I was supposed to do that's I
brought some bones please tell me I
brought the bones bone meal that works
we need more red die so this spider farm
I had like sixty for hoppers underneath
and the spiders are falling down and and
dying on the hoppers but that is just so
wasteful I want to I want to reclaim
these hoppers there's another rep like
exact same
copy of this farm like a little further
over there - I think I think we I have
it set up where you can see it if we go
back out I've made that ender pearl
throw lots of times by the way yeah over
there there's another one so we're going
to get rid of the hoppers and instead we
are going to did we're gonna set up a
hopper minecart that goes around so the
whole base here I'm gonna change ooh
that's not a chest wait wait I want that
back yeah we'll have a hopper minecart
and we're gonna make it trigger we'll
probably set up like some trip wires
that when the spiders fall down they
activate it and that tells the hopper
minecart to go pick up the string and
then when it gets the other end it stops
until they fall down and trigger the
trip wires again that way it's not
always running when it doesn't need to
be I really don't like having clocks
running in my world um so that should
work out pretty good I think and then
kind of need to set up some way of
bringing the string from down here up
and if if I eventually build that Nexus
that the master sword room instead of
bringing it like just up to nowhere
it'll take it to the Nexus to the main
storage room automatically on its own
that's kind of the idea behind that
that's gonna be a tough project for me
to start though because I need to gather
a lot of stuff for that before we beat
units I like using red clay for anything
involving minecarts I don't know why
it's just well I do kinda know why like
it goes well oh that was I made it dark
goes really well with like redstone
blocks like out of all the all the
materials it's one of the better ones
these normally stand out just terribly
we're gonna be using power rails for
most of it because we have a gold farm
now
and that is one of the awesome things
about having a gold farm
free tracks who needs regular tracks
when you can make gold power rails for
pretty much free so I think I'm just
gonna do a pretty wasteful I should have
brought some real tracks with me cuz I'm
they're gonna connect like that hmm but
I want to make it zigzag all the way
down and then to power it put redstone
blocks below in places and it'll power
up the whole line wait for it wait for
it
I love the explosion when they hit the
ground that looks so cool okay we got
the tracks down there's two ends to it
that I haven't done anything with yet
let's hit on down got him I made it go
this way just cuz that's that's the
natural way the tracks from connecting
it with it was a lot less trouble that
way so all we really needed to do this
should be pretty simple maybe we'll put
them at head level above head level yeah
yeah let's Oh what do we have here
possible new place to expand - mm-hmm
whenever I see random tunnels like these
I always like to check them out because
this might be something I blocked up
in the past and totally forgot about
don't quite recognize his spots huh okay
I hear lava I want a zombie wait a
minute like I've lit up all the cheese
so if there's a zombie that's pretty
surprising actually
where is he yet oh I did distract it so
easy
it could be an unexplored cave here yep
keep going keep going or nuts I'm gonna
get lost down here down this is
important guys trust me Oh beautiful
it is a dark cave old man really it's
pretty big to you creeper
all right just a second here I'm sure
I'm gonna find torches in just a little
ways here I can't imagine I missed this
cuz this is right under my man team this
is a big area I think I think this is by
the slime farm yeah that's the slime
farm right there the old old slime farm
I don't know if you guys remember it one
attempted to ender pearl I guess I never
went to the other side of it never lit
it up we're doing it oh yeah a half slab
I hear slimes still though that's kind
of dark I think that's above where I'm
here in the slime I don't think wait
where is it it's over here yeah yeah
that's that's all fine all right I'm
gonna I'm gonna head back up sorry for
the detour trip down memory lane here
okay like I was saying before I got
distracted we're gonna be putting trip
wires on each of the sides here I think
just four four per side is enough we're
really covering 50% of the area here so
a spider has a 50-50 chance I think at
least of triggering
this when it falls down and since lots
of spiders are gonna be falling down
that's his pretty good odds that they
are gonna activate this with with only
four all right I think that go get out
of here torch nobody likes you do that
okay this that's how you play strength
oh we're shorts good thing we're right
by a string farm how perfect is that
there we go okay I'm gonna put stairs in
here just these still work right yeah I
never know I always get confused if you
have a solid block trip wires don't work
underneath but if it's a transparent one
it does still actually over here we're
gonna dig this out okay so spider falls
down hits the tripwire have a line of
redstone under here maybe
so the any one of them will activate
this this redstone and then we just need
power rails at the ends here and just
connect this I'm gonna have to wreck my
design though if I do that that's
terrible
alright regular track just we'll have to
move the redstone block over here that's
okay so spider falls down that gets
activated the spider falls down here
still gets activated that should
probably be a hopper below actually
because we're gonna be taking the string
out of the hopper minecarts same it's
over here
get that over in there place it good
good
anyway you get the idea it's pretty
simple
wait I did that wrong okay maybe he's a
little more complex than that that I'm
letting it out to be now it's it's
really simple
poppers just about done here
power real perfect and now that we got
the hoppers let's make a hopper minecart
and test this out and I'm gonna put
chests and stuff underneath as you can
imagine all right hopefully when the
spiders fall down they don't land on
these chests I'm gonna remove the
torches when this is all done too
obviously
well maybe maybe not all the torches but
I'll light it up so that the torches
don't affect the spawner up there even
though they probably don't right now
anyway all right spiders show your ugly
faces oh that's not good wait how did
they land that none of the tripwires
activated that was surprising there's
one right there
did they fall through the tripwire
without activating it man come on I
think you must be falling too fast and
they're falling through it is that
possible let's try one more time
should work come on spiders and you day
now oh it's spinning its spinning this
water above here is unnecessary by the
way I just kind of left that because it
was there from before
ouch yes still in inactivated did I do
something wrong down here hmm
that is really surprising yeah I might
have to move these up higher so that
they're not falling as fast I think
they're falling too quick in there
they're passing through without
activating them okay I think it'll work
this time otherwise I quit guys can't
handle it anymore
there is redstone underneath this side
of the trip wires and those it comes
down to each side here so it powers up
the power rail from over here mm-hmm and
does the same on the other side too so
let's go up once more hopefully no
spiders get caught on these little
crevices I made for them oh I made it
yeah I thought I messed that one up
okay come on come on spiders what I'm
standing here they try to go into the
wall I don't think it activated they
like try to climb the wall sometimes cuz
they move in midair towards me
Demond spiders could have been an
unlucky one there was only one spider
that fell there and I think you fell in
the middle come on these guys are slow
holy cow
come on while we're young and not
looking good
seriously come on okay we're gonna try
this again I'm not gonna stand so close
to it and see if that makes a difference
okay some spiders just fell
no hopper minecart moving that's not
good really wasn't expecting it to be
the stuff to make them activate the trip
wires I'm sure they're falling on them
well there you go on that side I think
they're falling like in the right place
they're just passing through it without
activating it for some reason it's
because it well I know why it's because
spiders are very small like their hitbox
height-wise is pretty small and same
with the tripwire hitbox so I think they
can pass through it pretty easily okay
that time it worked
spider survived he was tracking me and
he went into the wall I think it's okay
though it's hard to say
there we go oh that was weird why did it
bounce back it's like it hit the spiders
carcass before it disappeared
ouch it did it again huh anyway it's
kind of working I'll probably add some
more trip wires and watch it some more
but I've gone way over time for today so
I'll I'll fix that up on my own time so
comment for today guys this one that I
thought was pretty good it says etho you
always said the point of the man cave is
to keep the look of the caves and now
you're digging straight tunnels super
sad face cry cry run down cheek okay the
man cave sort of the goal with this was
to use the the shape of the caves to
help me decide how to build stuff which
I think I did a pretty good job with
that so far like a lot of this this area
is natural but I have changed things
like even today you saw me I put down
some stone over there and I've made
little adjustments here and there to my
liking there has been a lot of things
I've just dug out as well like the sheep
farm here was pretty much solid stone
all over here that I dug out when I
built that same with this room and lots
lots of things I've just dug out big
areas of land but like there was a cape
that went here and I made it straights
for example it used to be pretty pretty
rough around here so this using the cave
the original team shape sort of a
guideline to help me decide how to build
things and it has resulted in a pretty
good looking
basse I would say especially this area I
really like like there's lots of
elevation changes and stuff I would not
have thought of doing this like in this
shape if it was a meat is building
normally somewhere it's because this is
the shape the cave was and I just
adjusted it a little bit to make it work
I guess so yeah little adjustments here
and there again this this was not
straight like this for sure it was
pretty rough and I think I dug a ton of
this outand yeah you know there's just
some things it's not too bad if it's
man-made especially if you try and make
it a little natural like but add
randomness to it like like I did here I
think helps but yeah that's that's
computed for this episode some other
things some other rules with the man
cave of course is not to use torches and
finished areas so like you can tell here
is not a finished area because there's
torches everywhere while over here it's
it's a lot better and I think there's a
few other rules I had with this anyway
that's that's it for today's episode
guys I hope you enjoyed it and I will
see you again next time take care bye
bye
[Music]