[Music]
you know guys
as excited as i am for another uhc
season
i am deeply and deeply concerned about
the changes with skeletons like they
they accounted for over half the deaths
before i believe
and now they are insanely skilled like
they
they got their rapid fire spamming and
all kinds of crazy stuff they get flame
bows now
and and thorn's armor and all sorts of
crazy crazy stuff um so
in future uhc seasons if and when they
happen
i don't know when they're gonna happen
so don't ask
but if another one happens i don't know
how it's gonna play out i think the
skeletons are gonna get most
of the kills i gotta say
because man these guys are
good um
this is a trick by the way this this is
actually a bug in 1.5 that i'm
exploiting for this intro and with that
let's get into the let's play
so yeah here we are in the let's play
world
and we're going to be working on our mob
system today that's the plan
uh at least to start out with again and
i've had this big plan for the mob
system for a long time
the problem that happened last time is i
started building it and i kind of got it
to this point
and then i didn't really know what to do
with it so then i start building the
area around it and we
we sort of decide on the shape and the
emp units and all that
and then shortly after that i had
another idea
but it was too late we already sort of
settled on
the look of this place and i needed more
space to do what i wanted
but since we're redoing everything
it it doesn't really matter how big the
thing is i can
i can change the shape of everything
and make the mob system as big as i want
now so we have a lot of freedom and a
lot of this stuff is probably going to
get
ripped out and changed and that's fine
but yeah this is a five to seven
step project each step very complicated
uh what i want to do the first step we
already have done the mob system itself
the second step what we're going to be
working on today
is the mob sorter
and by the third step you'll know i'll
tell you what we're gonna do but i think
we'll just wait on that for
for the time being so we're gonna
hopefully get the mob sorter working
today i started here already i made a
proper junction that works finally up
here so
as is right now the mobs just fall
straight down
if i want to instant kill them and
if i want to get them into the mobs
order i can
flip a switch and it will make them fall
into a water stream
and push them to our mob sorter system
that we're about to build
so this what this lever does
is it there's a piston there that's
inverted
that opens and closes this
this uh downward falling area and allows
water to flow over top it
when it's when the block is there and
then there's these two pistons that
um release the water and also keep the
mobs from
going down this tunnel when we don't
want them to
because even if they're falling straight
down and this is open over here
they sometimes will get in there somehow
so yeah let's get started here
so the way we're going to be separating
the mobs as you may have guessed
uh we're going to separate zombies out
using villagers and
creepers out using ocelots and then
skeletons we're going to separate
using time and let's just go inside here
oh that's a tricky fall right there okay
we should be safe to work in here while
they fall down i marked where the water
goes up to
up to here and i think we'll make it run
that full length
and have this area here as a sort of a
buffer so if
there's lots of mobs at one period of
time and then there's few mobs it'll
kind of bounce itself
out and then
we're gonna make them fall here and get
rid of this
actually let's just go over there and
maybe tear it down
all right i got that ripped out over
there now we can work in that area
and i made some trapdoors we're going to
use those for
a date right here
wait do we want it like that
yeah that should be fine mobs will fall
down here
this will what this does it's gonna flip
like this
really quick and that'll only allow one
mob to get through at a time
i'm pretty sure because if they're if
they move forward a little bit they'll
be inside the trapdoor and then they can
keep
walking and fall or keep getting pushed
by the water currents
uh so they're gonna fall down here and
we'll control this with
redstone uh i have sort of
built this in creative already but i
just built like a rough copy we're gonna
have to figure out a few things
still with this and make some
adjustments i'm sure
i i i just made like a manual version
where i was
uh putting the mobs in and controlling
the doors and that
myself but we have to make it fully
automatic
but from what i could tell it seemed
like this was going to work i don't know
how accurate it's going to be either
as far as separating the mobs goes
okay mobs are going to fall
see they need space for their heads so
that's two blocks uh they'll have to go
one more down probably so right there
is where we will
have them fall wait how far of a drop is
that that's
that seems kind of far
uh one two three
one two three four yeah that's fine
they'll take a little fall damage that's
that's not a big deal
and then we will make this come up
and i got to decide which way i want to
put the villager which way i want the
ocelot and all that
uh let's see there's not a lot of space
on this side since they're falling down
already
so we're going to try to put the ocelot
here
to separate the creepers out so to do
that we'll need
a half slab to hold them in place
oh i knew that's going to happen sooner
or later
i hate working up high man
it's like everything i do redstone and
everything i have to work
on these little platforms that are real
pain
and i would build a big platform but
then you gotta move it and
it rarely saves time
okay we got to make a little holding
area for an ocelot here
maybe make that come up oop
there glass there
and i trap myself perfect
let's see we'll put a half slab
and then glass block here i guess
so in that one by one area inside there
that's where we want the odd slot and
we'll have to go
tame one the nice thing is they finally
fixed that
i believe where the pets were randomly
teleporting to the player
when they got within a loaded chunk so
that was another problem i had last time
i tried to make a mob
sorter is uh that glitch made it
impossible to get an ocelot in place
and keep it in place
okay fall down ocelot there
then we will make the creepers go this
way
and to do that we have to trick them
into falling
we'll have to have
trap doors there's this trick you can do
with trapdoors where mobs will
see it as a as a block right but
since they're moving kind of quick they
they don't stop in time and they'll fall
off
as they run onto the block because it's
such a small
collision mask on it
okay
and then we'll make this just make
things a little clearer
this might take a long time if i build
it all on camera maybe i should stop for
a sec
um
well basically what i got to do here now
is i gotta make a big platform so when
they're running away from the ocelot
over there
they have a lot of space to run to
otherwise
they won't know where to go so we need a
fairly big platform
and we'll have to take out more of this
wall i'm sure too just to make it larger
so anyway we got that going then
we're going to have a villager either
here or here let's
this doesn't really matter does it uh
let's put them
let's put them over here and we're going
to do the same thing we did with the
trap doors
we're gonna go two blocks and we'll have
our real block
take that out need more trap doors
there's a crafting table right there
maybe i'll attempt it
there we go see i don't always make a
new one sometimes i'll go find
an existing one all right
trap door over there over there
again we'll use glass to hold it in
and then we need a villager over here
um maybe back one more block so we can
hold them in place
so like right here we want a villager
okay so maybe i'll uh put some more
finishing touches on this
and then i'll be back
oh target acquired
target is wearing yellow polka dot fuzzy
sweatshirt
is in stationary position preparing to
engage
still no sign of movement
doesn't see me
here here kitty kitty oh target moving
north seven kilometers per hour
is he going come on give me a break
here kitty kitty kitty
these guys are so tough to get
and he vanished
found him target reacquired
moving in
where did he go these trees
he was just here now he's gone again how
does he do it
oh there he is
i'm just gonna stand here
okay he's not coming he says while
you're further and further away i'll
stand
here you want this fish don't you
oh oh no bad timing
ah i lost them again
there's another one over there
oh these guys are annoying come on
this is really
oh a kitty
whoa
ah come on these stinking cats man
oh they're there they're all there
oh checked it out oh he ran what
guess what guy you're out of the trees
you can't hide anymore
that's it that's it one
two and he took off because i fed him
dude he's in the desert like i can't get
close to him
and he's gone don't you want fish
he's running sideways i'm gonna stand
right here
and he's gone where'd he go there he is
oh not another one don't go back into
the jungle
don't you dare even think about it
no no bad kitty
that's it yes finally
one two three
four five oh finally yes
that took like 20 minutes to get this
guy i guess you gotta run at them
then stop oh
that was annoying by far the most
annoying thing in this game
quite the little journey we had little
guy and you gave me a hard time
let's get you into your forever home
you did not follow me i don't like you
hmm why no follow
this way
and a little further
oh my goodness
that's not for you that's for the
creepers
i can't get them out of there now can i
uh maybe if i go up here
if i get far enough he'll teleport there
we go i'm just going to sit them down
and push them in i guess
although i can't get them up this unless
i do that
that's right stop
in you go this is
much simpler
okay and we're gonna take oh
i don't like this guy i really don't i
hate to say it
[Music]
something tells me he's right above oh
man
i'm going to go there
and i'll extend this and
in you go little guy
perfect cover it up and it's good
okay so we got the creepers taken care
of we got to get a villager in here next
and that's probably going to be worse
i hate to say and we got to get them
right in that spot
there and then we might
even be able to test this today
you know what i wish i wish i spent like
forever making a crazy device to create
villagers out of zombie villagers that i
could easily move to my place
oh wait a minute i did that that's right
so i'll be able to get a villager pretty
easy from this and the tracks will take
them
right up to the
the room we're working in the only thing
is i got to get him up to his spot so
i'll have to use
water elevators or or minecart tracks or
something to get them up there
so we just flip this on
and sift them out with this
and there we go why is the trapdoor not
working
you almost got out i thought the
trapdoor was hooked up maybe my redstone
broke from the update
but we will grab one of these
and assuming this all still works we
just give them medicine
that sounds pretty low
and now we play the waiting game
ah we got a librarian librarian in the
house you're gonna go for a little ride
guy
uh let's get to transport
oh i guess that didn't quite work
anymore
hmm that's too bad i'll have to force it
this time
there you go and through the portal
and no go ah
i thought that would work
there he goes
and how hard is it going to be to get
him where i want him to go i guess he
has to go up
here no i i just have to animal over
there
should really get some tracks yeah
you you wait here for a sec
yeah i got a bunch of tracks set up here
to get them up higher i'm going to
see if we can get them through this
portal i might be able to just push them
or
guide them without
having much trouble what i should do is
just block this
off block this way off and then i'll
have no choice but to go where i want
him to
and if i push him a little bit it would
get even easier
come on your new home
he's actually not moving around much is
he that's awesome
there you go yeah go through
go through guy that's not good
just to make sure he doesn't go to the
other side
oh what no no no no no now you're moving
no no no no no you want to go in there
that's your new home that's where the
chocolate is
hmm
that's not good is there a limit how
many times they can transport or what's
the deal with this
because i had this problem with the pigs
too they wouldn't go through again
okay i use the mine cart to get him
through he wasn't teleporting
any other way it seems
now oh you went through the wrong side
wait wait
no dude dude
settle down get into this mine curt
please ah yes
i got him awesome
now no don't come this way
now i think we have it
up you go if that can't handle one chart
i'm gonna
really be upset with these furnace
minecarts
oh no
it's all right we got it just had a
little trouble around the bend
got another bend coming up
he's happy oh bumped your head watch it
yeah that's as far as i made it go so
now i got to make it go up to
there and i'll make it go right to
where he needs to be right guys this is
end of the line for you
these guys these guys are just freaking
out right now
okay up you go
should drop them right into the spot i
want them
mile and hopefully the
neither of these guys die because it's
going to be a huge pain to replace him
this is time consuming
perfect right into there
we will get this fixed up again
and i gotta get that minecart back too
let's see if we go on the side like
this oh i gotta go a little lower can't
go lower
what you gonna do
let's go over here
all right that's a this is actually
probably the toughest part of this whole
project is getting these guys to go
where i want
there we go yay and
now what's going on
this isn't good
this is a glitch it's fine all is good
i'm gonna re-log just to make sure
awesome guys we got this ready for a
test run but i'm gonna have to control
everything manually at the moment
like these these trap doors
i'm going to hook up to a redstone
circuit but for now
i have to use the levers actually what i
want to do
yeah i mean i made trip hooks what i
want to do with this
is hopefully
see we gotta go one block higher
so over here we will
set up some trip hooks
one over there one on the other side
and what these will do if a mob is in
this area
right here it's gonna turn on a redstone
clock
that will automatically automatically
control both of these doors and they'll
both open real quick like that
as long as there's a mob here if there's
no mob here i don't want the clock
running
so that is
the plan let's put that there
as a reminder and this will still work
with glass below like that which is good
should probably cover this
beautiful all right so the idea is
mobs fall down here there's another
trapdoor
there uh zombies will seek out the
villager fairly quickly
but the creepers they only do or they'll
only move
quickly if they have a easy time finding
a spot to run to so that's why we have
all this land here we might have to
expand this some more yet this is 11 by
so they'll try to run over here and then
they'll fall down this
but the skeletons when they fall down
they don't really see a path to go to
because they really
i think they only really look at this
block this block
this trap door and that one so it's very
unlikely they're gonna move right away
when they
fall so as long as we flip this soon
enough
as long as like after they fall if we
flip this pretty quickly afterwards
uh then it should keep skeletons from
going this way or
or that way uh because they are
able to go both those directions if they
choose to we just have to prevent them
from choosing that
but enough talk let's give it a go hey
so let's
uh let's flip this this is all ready
right
don't want to be wrong about this
because this could easily all explode
oh creeper first two yay
okay so he's over there
and he has a perfect
line of sight to us um
that shouldn't be let's get over to this
spot
yeah so he moved fairly quick
that guy went there let's get this out
of here
the skeleton see he waits around for
quite a while
and before he has a chance to move this
will flip
oh that's that's too long we need more
land here
mobs do this thing now where they glitch
through the glass again
if they're under pressure that guy moved
quick
that's fairly quick
this is the main thing though that the
skeletons don't move let's just wait and
see how long it takes them to go
there he goes and he didn't fall down
this is really weird with the mobs i
hope they fix this
this guy should push the skeleton off
yep
that's pretty cool
and it should only let one through at a
time
uh with that gate up there they kind of
hold each other from
getting jammed all into one bunch
oops so let's try one more zombie
beautiful so we're going to drop them
into water streams below and then with
that
we're going to move them to where we
want and we need them separated for step
three of the project which we will get
to another time
so that'll probably be about it for
today
but before we end the episode i did pick
out a comment for us to
consider he says hey etho i think that
you should start a new series
i know march has been a busy month for
you yes it has
but maybe in april something like vex's
infernal minds for a seat
for a ctm or another game note that you
might want to play don't starve when
that game goes
out of beta i have been actually
considering
maybe uh recording a few more episodes
of that because i haven't played it in a
long time i think since uh
well i did play it a little after i
finished my series but i haven't played
it
probably in at least two three months
and terraria will receive
an update in the next few months also
really i thought that was only on
console anyway
you should also google starbound i have
looks like a pretty cool game
and it has caught my attention i think
you'd make a great playthrough
if that of that when it's released just
my thoughts love your videos thank you
for showing
aha yeah i'm definitely going to be
starting some new series
uh once i get some spare time here i
have been busy during march and that's
kind of the reason for less videos but
i'm still trying not to rush
them because i don't like rushing videos
yeah it wrecks it wrecks the quality and
then
you know people don't want to watch them
but
in april i should have some free time
again and there's two older games i want
to record i'm keeping it kind of secret
at the moment
but one of them i is i'll probably be
recording
next like that's that's the next series
i'm going to try to
um in april most likely
but yeah thank you for watching everyone
i hope you enjoyed the episode
and i will see you again next time
[Music]
bye