[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome guys
to
another episode of our let's play series
this is going to be
me losing my train of thought aha yes of
course today
is the world tour episode guys episode
number 450
we're gonna go around and check out some
of the stuff we've built in this world
since we've been playing oh i'm so glad
i looked that direction
although he is not interested
that's kind of weird isn't it okay he's
he found me now i've never had
life very rarely had creepers blow up in
my base
amazingly
those stairs threw me off and today is
not one of the days it's gonna happen
so yeah we're gonna go around our world
guys check out some of the stuff we
built over
over our time here uh i'll try to give
you as much information as i can
as quickly as i can we have a lot of
stuff to see the last world tour we did
was over an hour
this one's going to be long too because
we've built more stuff since then
hopefully i can be a little bit more
concise
today let's start with the history of
things guys so
we're on episode 450 of our let's play
series but
i've actually had two worlds since the
beginning
this is our second one uh we started
playing in this world in episode 105
so that was the very start it was right
around the time
the nether fortresses came out in the
game and they did the biome
changes and all that kind of stuff is a
long long time ago
but we've been here ever since
[Music]
that's our nighttime tune i'll show you
that now since it's kind of hard to
reproduce
um but yeah we've been here ever since
just hanging out
this is like our main main area the man
cave
i started out i wanted to live
underground
uh in our world here because i was a
very bad builder
and just a little hint for you guys if
you didn't know if you're bad at
building
go underground it's the best because you
don't have to build rooms or anything
like that
it's it's a lot easier to make things
look nice
all right guys so let's go ahead and
start our world tour right over here
this is a good spot because this is
actually the spot in the world i
probably spend the most time
right right on this grass right here
because uh
we got our storage room over here this
is the first storage room i built in the
world it's got like this little cool
shutter system it opens up when you step
on the pressure plates lights turn on
that are hidden behind the chests and uh
really like the storage method i used
here like instead of having one chest
for one item sort of thing
i group stuff together so all the red
stones
in one chest i'm very uh messy though
that belongs in the ore chest and the
books don't belong here but yeah you
kind of get the idea
um kind of grouped everything together
food in that chest sort of thing and
then when you go out
doors close and i use this storage room
a lot
like this is where i usually go when i
want to build something but we do have
several other storage rooms that are
for a longer term storage in the world
which we'll check out in a little bit
um also we got our furnace room right
next to it which
constantly am using this thing we might
even need to build a
bet a bigger and better furnace room in
the future because
eight furnaces is not quite enough oh
yeah when you when you take items out of
here it actually plays a little note
correction when you put items in there
it plays a little note
like so and the light turns on and
each one oh yeah that one's broken
that one's been broken forever and i've
never fixed it
all right yeah they each play a note
except for the one
and if any any of these furnaces are
running
then this light these lights turn on as
well
which is kind of cool we have a little
block swapper crafting table thing here
i don't know kind of cool i guess this
is where i hide like my anvil
and on the other side we got a ender
chest that i use
very very often uh up the stairs here
this
is my sheep farm
that's the morning tune by the way
[Music]
and those are really important because
when you live underground like
this you have no idea what time it is
above above ground so i like the
little note block indicators we also
have like lights in the ceiling in
places like those
that are controlled by daylight sensors
so they're on during the day and off at
night
which is kind of cool we actually have
like a
ender pearl thing i never use here i
always forget about it
oops oops i'm getting attacked
there we go never use this again
anymore i used to use it all the time
before but i forget about it nowadays
um all right so this is our sheep farm
like i was saying
basically you go up to it grab your
shears you run along here
we got a rainbow jeb sheep for whatever
reason
and this is what i called the pop-up
sheep farm
it used to work using a double buds
system so it would detect when the sheep
would eat the grass
and then pop them up when their wall had
grown but
things have changed in the game where
it doesn't quite work that way anymore
it can't detect when they eat the grass
anymore
oh yeah it would detect when the grass
would grow and then when they ate it so
that was the two steps involved
and then they would get popped up once
you shear all the wool or whatever
you have a couple options here you can
press this water bucket
and that makes water oh it's broken
uh what
well that's news to me that's never been
broken before i don't know when that
happened
but the wall falls down these grates
here which activates some pressure
plates which activates
the repeaters which makes all the sheep
go down
that have had their woes sheared at
least it used to it doesn't quite work
too well anymore
if they don't all go down for some
reason there's also this button here
which tells them all to go down and then
these buttons control
each thing individually then all the
world gets funneled to over here
into this chest and then i can take it
out and store it here
kind of a primitive system but i built
all this before hoppers and that came
out so i had to
kind of make do with it um
oh yeah when the sheep pop up the light
turns on in case you didn't catch on to
that
over here is where i get my ender pearls
where i keep them
stored there's like a chest up here you
can drop them off
and then you step in here and
fills you up which is kind of cool lots
of storage
i think like three double chests worth
or so
over here this is an access room which
probably doesn't work now that i think
of it
there's a hopper minecart underneath
this grass block but
i found in 1.9 they they made a change
where i'm having a hard time getting
getting it to pick up items through the
ground for some reason
yeah that's the thing they're not
picking up items i don't know what the
deal is with that
but yeah this door is supposed to open
maybe we will just manually put an item
in
like you saw the dirt fall on it and
pink rabbit for some reason
and uh this just has a bunch of potion
stuff
for my first potion uh
lab i built in the world we have two
this one's kind of retired but basically
it was a bunch of
dispensers with items in all the
different like
potion ingredients you need bottles and
nether warts and all that kind of stuff
all gets funneled down to the central
hole here
and of course this was all built before
we had hoppers and that kind of stuff as
well so
this was pretty pretty well automated at
the time but now it's pretty uh
crummy looking um
kind of hoping they fix that
i'm just thinking we should have started
in a different area like i just did a
fixing episode and i thought i had
everything done and now
like everything i've shown you so far
has had some some issue with it
but uh like this still works it's just
not as good as it used to be and i can't
really change that
uh this i think is a bug so i think
it'll get fixed
by itself but most stuff in our world
here does work
take my word for it um
this was one of the first projects we
built in the world it's a little mini
mushroom farm
step on it automatically harvests the
mushrooms we get like three
each time oh four four
wow it's pretty pretty amazing and we're
actually using uh
a backup for our world here world tour
today so i can break stuff
and it doesn't matter so if you're
wondering how anything's working
uh basically got a brown one on one side
and a red one on the other side
and yeah they grow and
yeah over here is my melon and pumpkin
farm
also pretty simple in the past this used
to shoot out
a hoe uh every time you would go in here
because
you were used to not be able to grow
melons and pumpkins on just dirt you had
to till the dirt
for it to grow on it so you would have
to till this and then put it back down
and then it would grow oh yeah and over
here we have storage for the melons
and on this side for the pumpkins um you
can probably tell i'm not a super
super organized person it doesn't matter
to me too much
uh this thing you look at this and
you're like etho what is this crazy
device
why it's uh
it's just there for nostalgia pretty
much um
this used to be the cave spider xp
farm i used all the time it was really
important to our world
i built this around the time
xp was first introduced to the game xp
levels and all that kind of stuff
enchanting
and i used to spend hours here i would
just stand here
cave spiders would fall down the water
stream here
they would be reduced to one hit so you
just basically spam them
with left click and it would kill them
or throw a damage potion at them and
kill them all at once
they would come up this this water
elevator here
did like a spiral thing and then somehow
it goes like over top
and then over and then drops them so
that they take damage but
uh one of the patches made it so it
didn't work and i ended up redoing this
so now we
actually are still using the cave spider
spawners
there's one right there but we're we
have a different farm form that we'll
check out in a little bit
um but i didn't want to tear this out
because it was really important to the
world
this is our slime farm
very impressive i know there's no slimes
here for some reason but it would divide
them
small medium large slimes into their
correct spots
the the big slimes actually get uh moved
out of here automatically
and go around a track just for the
funsies of it
around our tree farm there if we go up
here
we can check it out i built this at the
time
when they they made the big change to
slimes they used to
always spawn below y16 and then they
made it so they could spawn at
level 40 and lower so i built this
spawning platfor
form for them right at level
it says y39 dude what is with the
creepers today
seriously i've seen like so many of them
but yeah they spawn on the on the
platform here they fall into the water
the water pushes them
up the elevator um and then they fall
down after they get separated and then
you kill them with a looting sword or
whatever
i've also added a automatic way of
killing them now
basically they go over the water and
since they can't swim anymore they sink
they fall down here and drown
slime balls fall into the hoppers and
there's probably if i was to guess
some sly balls in here i empty it every
now and then
and that is where all the slime comes
from in our world how's this one doing
there is a switch actually to switch
this so that they don't fall down here
but i don't remember
where the button is for the life of me
but if we break break over here there's
probably a bunch of redstone back here
yeah these are double extenders or i
think
where's the button guys i lost it i
don't know how to change it
or was it actually it might be through
here
oh let's break everything i should have
brought some tnt with me
is there a button here there's no button
there
there we go finally happens
all right so slime farm check
the slimes that fall down they uh they
fall down in a mine cart
off here we got a little viewing window
and it puts them underneath the
sandstone
they go around a loop around this uh
tree farm
this tree farm was also one of the first
things we built it was really important
it shows shows memory to everybody that
donated to me
when i first started my youtube channel
all the names of the people and the
amounts and
the dates that they they donated um
back before i was like making any money
doing youtube but nowadays i'm doing
okay so
i obviously stopped the donations one
once that happened
but i really appreciate everybody that
helped me out in the beginning
um otherwise you know i might not be
here today doing doing the youtube
that's i love ever so much um
this is a farm we never see really
and because of the hopper thing it
probably doesn't work but yeah
there oh look at all the redstone
oh my goodness well i'm hitting this
place up
next time i i'm on my world but yeah you
stand here
right click and it automatically uh
harvests the flowers and then this carts
you can send it off and it will pick
them up
let's see if it works doesn't work
fix your game mojang it's supposed to
pick them up through the ground but
yeah something's up with hopper mine um
let's see there is another tape spider
spawner
oh yeah there's this one here i never
did anything with that huh
there's another double tape spider
spawner back here though this was the
first one i built
back when i was still experimenting with
uh
how tape spiders spawn and how to
control them all that kind of stuff
because back in the day that was like
pretty pretty new concepts
what do we got over here
uh yeah i like to have to figure out
exactly what area
the spawners spawned the cave spiders
and
what conditions how the lighting
affected it all that kind of stuff
wasn't really known at that time
so they would fall down
and then they would climb up here and
then you could just
kill them kind of thing all right let's
keep on moving here guys we got a lot of
stuff left to see in the man cave alone
not to mention the rest of the world
such as this thing right here
this is called the ugly brick thing
every
man cave needs one of these it's amazing
you got crafting
you got pressure plate to hold the water
in i thought that was so clever at the
time
and need water pick it up
i've actually seen like people that are
mimicking my man cave style here they'll
add an ugly brick thing
in their man team as well it's like a
requirement
uh over here run faster which is splash
potions of swiftness
live longer supposed to be healing
potions
got extra storage hidden back here and
another crafting table because
yeah i don't know um
this is our potion lab i was very proud
of this build when i
i first made it still am i i think i
think it's pretty cool
it's got like a spiral door to it on a
timer so it stays open a certain amount
of time
inside we got uh pixel art swiftness
potion
um storage for the potions and i
color-coded them so like uh
purple's reed regen um orange is virus
resistance
why did why was that word hard i have no
idea blue for swiftness that kind of
thing
and then over here this is the
the main brewing area so you stand
underneath the water
and the idea is you click the button for
what you want so
you see how it says glass bottles and
netherwart so glass bottles is the top
one
press that it gives you 30
i believe or 28 i suppose
okay something might be broken up there
and
oh yeah you got to fill them so you
right click
on the water source up there it shoots
them out of your inventory
all in one spot here the idea is i don't
i didn't want to move to have to fill
these brewing stands so you can just
stay here the whole time
because i'm lazy and then uh if you
don't want netherwart you hit the
netherwart button
you get netherwarts i should give you a
10.
okay that one works and then whatever
other
ingredients you need like blaze powder
gunpowder
press the button all gets delivered to
you you fill up the brewing stands
manually and take the
potions out manually it was pretty cool
i used this a lot
but nowadays we have a really really
cool potion lab
that's all totally automatic so we don't
go in there very often anymore
also this was the birth of the ether
door the
door with the hole in the middle uh
that you can enter pearl through it's
like the only three by three door i make
for some reason
this is project pokemon the goal
originally was to get one
of each type of villager uh there
there was six villagers when they first
came out six types one of them i didn't
realize you couldn't get though the
green coat one
so i made a spot for him but we've since
readjusted this and now we're just
trying to get one
one type of each villager that's good
such as this guy he's special because
he's an old villager he still has one
written book for one emerald trade and
now you can copy written books so you
can get tons of emeralds
from this guy if i really wanted and
he's also got the
the current price two for one that they
usually have
press the button here and it switches
them
kind of cool i also just realized this
thing is broken i think i need to add
trap doors here
because i had uh the one guy below get
mixed in with
this guy so gonna have to add that
anyways over here
a little two by two door this is like a
holding area you'd
drop villagers down here and then there
was a
underground village i was going to build
here called emerald city
so i hollowed out all this ground and
started building these houses i thought
they looked really good at first when i
first made these i even had sandstone
mixed in originally
and uh yeah
i kind of realized later that this place
is kind of ugly oh what's in these
chests
okay nothing too special lots of snow
some sand oh man i should i should take
some of this stuff
not too bad there is actually some
villagers here i believe
yeah they're still here cool
what is it old trades guys
i never want to lose these guys it's
kind of cool to have the
old villagers still anyways we
eventually
abandoned this project despite you guys
really wanting me to work on it
uh and instead we have a different
underground village
that worked out a lot better because i
wasn't building the full
houses and then in the new one because
these take up a lot of space and like if
you look at
the village from here you got the back
of the house and
blocks your view and i don't know it
just wasn't going very well so we
we started a new village which we'll
check out in a little bit
this is our ufo cow farm
basically you go up here if you want to
do some fishing
get a fishing rod oh is it going to work
guys i have no idea
stand over here do some fishing
oh please work
it's not retracting them at all fishing
is a little weird in 1.9
like if you have a boat down next to an
animal sometimes
the fishing rod just doesn't work and i
don't understand why
like if there's any other entities
nearby all right that kind of worked but
yeah the idea was it would shoot them up
into the water here
and they would get funneled down to
a single spot we did test this recently
and it was working it's just really hard
to do
but they fall down here and then you
get your steak steak and potatoes or
whatever
and this is a little piston elevator to
go up to the surface which
actually works now i believe now that
they fix
pistons which is pretty cool um
there was a little drop down thing here
i used to use all the time
and the map of our world there i'm gonna
update that maybe next episode because
we've built a lot of stuff that's not
shown on there anymore
got some pixel art cow over there
and we can go down to the farm
over here
these have swords hoe
food to feed them i use this farm quite
often this is my main
food source the steak it used to be a
wheat farm
as well i don't know how many of you
guys know that um
underneath all these dirt blocks are
fences
there was a glitch in the game for a
while where you could
um you could till the soil plant the
crop and jump on it and it wouldn't
trample the crop if there was fences
below
so this used to be a wheat field and
cows and then you would
where is it where is it i know it's
around here right here
pull that the lever and all the wheat
would get harvested
and all the cow meat would get collected
down
to this main trench and then you pick it
up
got the storage over there kind of cool
all right we gotta really move we're
running out of time
uh we got a little storage thing for
jeff jeff died don't know what happened
to him
uh cave spider spawner with a viewing
window over here
that's there to confuse you guys uh we
got our
our flower farm the two high one
which seems to be out of bone meal that
one's working good
lilacs are the superior to high flower
by the way if you didn't know that
um over this way that we have an ender
porter
pretty much self-explanatory does it
still work
still works guys all right so all right
that is a project i would love to get
working
perfectly but i'm having trouble with it
like i'll go through a portal and i'll
just randomly get teleport to it
ideas though you press a button and
it'll take you to the different
uh place in the world that'll make the
ender pearl land so we got
i think three of those throughout the
world that we can
transport to but i'm having issues with
them
moving on this got blown up earlier uh
another view of the teeth spider
spawners over here
um you can go down and click the string
in those chests
and over here as well and then we got
our fishing shack
pretty simple little thing nothing
really to it
uh this dead end's got some goodies here
that i should clean up one day
uh you know that snowball machine we saw
at the beginning of the episode we got
an access room to it over here if we
need to
to go check out the chests or the
minecart system for it or whatever
it automatically gets loaded with
snowballs from over here
which again hopper mine carts are not
working for who who knows what reason
got extra shovels or zombie flesh
there's a shovel in this dispenser ice
i don't know what happened in there
yeah who knows um then we also got our
oh what was this called a mini farm
where you can
it's full of like bone meal most of you
guys know what these are
they're pretty common nowadays but you
could plant
seeds here you step on the pressure
plate dispenses bone meal grows the crop
instantly and then harvests it
with the piston um
this way is a part of the man cave we
don't see too often the river
uh down here and then this is a room
which was supposed to be
for storing our treasures in block form
but it
became very very tedious when i was
using it because you'd place it then you
got to break it
anytime you want to use it so right now
it's
random extra storage and all our picks
that have ticked the bucket that we
can't repair anymore
i've been storing here um
we should make a graveyard for our picks
in the future though usually they die
though like i don't
i don't remember to store them in time
they'll break and then they're they're
just gone
um our original enchanting room you
could control the bookshelves with these
levers
back when enchanting took 50 levels you
guys remember those days that was pretty
brutal
that gave you a lot of control over it
and we also have uh
extra tools and stuff up here when i do
enchanting i use this quite often
actually
still over here we have a vine farm
low tech hoppers down below that
collects the vines
down here is that my one and only
chicken farm
which was supposed to turn into a mini
game but i never did that
full of eggs and stuff there's probably
probably hundreds and hundreds of eggs
that have stored up here over time
and a bunch of chickens up there but you
know all those comments of the day they
need feathers and that's where those
feathers come from
if you didn't know that um
got an elevator here just a minecart one
for using our elytra wings
goes up to the top of the world and
there's a ice tunnel here that goes to
our
end portal okay back at the creeper face
this was the very first thing we built
in the man cave
eventually i ended up putting a portal
back here through the lava
that you can control with the buttons on
and off
and i'm gonna lose my voice before we're
done here guys i'm telling you
secret access room when you right click
on the redstone or this
is to put uh oh is it empty
it actually ran out of stuff are you
kidding me
but i just hm
i thought i saw it shoot arrows recently
oh we're trapped here now
um yeah arrows shoot out of the eyes
flaming arrows every so often and they
land over here
i think it must have just ran out
honestly
down here is one of our favorite
projects and
some of you your most hated project
wilson are tamagotchi
in minecraft pets top bar is the age of
him
that's his health meter weight happiness
hunger
very very complicated redstone device
this is
like a nightmare he actually has seven
seven different faces he makes he can
get sick he has a bladder system
um you can feed him through his feeding
hole here
all kinds of crazy stuff work in
progress but it does actually function
at the moment too
so it's like semi-complete i guess you
could say
zenith our greatest and most amazing
horse
protected by microsoft all right we got
our horse stables over here
go inside block goes down go inside
block goes up kind of thing pretty
simple
i love this area here though this this
area is pretty cool
i like the water and just the pass and
everything about it oh yeah let's grab a
horse for this
all right who is this the boss this is
the horse elevator
2x2 thing
last time i used it it was safe to drop
the horse down too let's just double
check that
yeah perfectly safe cool
uh we got a mushroom farm over here
which i do use actually forgetting the
mushroom blocks quite often
[Music]
grow mushroom plays a tune everybody's
happy
what more could you ask and
that dead ends this goes over to our
armor
stand thing we just built swapping out
our sets of armor
and put quite a few in there if we want
our snack-o-matic
one of our most crucial builds in the
world obviously
and this area is a work in progress
still
old broken eats road over there i don't
think we did go over here did we
hello yeah this is like
just a little simple rabbit and pig farm
did the rabbits all escape
no we got
a lead dispenser here potions for the
horses in case we want to super speed
them and let's go off this way i suppose
this takes us to some access rooms to
the wiring
and on top of our current potion room
kind of a work in progress area we got
our simon game we're working on
the memory game it's almost done
actually i just need to
buckle down and finish it um
oh yeah we got a firework room here hey
for manufacturing fireworks
automatically kind of you just
uh how did it work you throw
item in there and then it gives you more
yeah automatically dispenses
random ingredients for the firework so
each one's different
um another way to get to wilson
i think we're getting close to done with
this area actually let's go check out
the potion room
there is an arena back there you know i
totally forgot about that we should work
on that one day though um
there's not really much to see there
though yeah we got our fully automatic
brewing system this makes the awkward
potions over here
and then when we flip this lever
that starts the brewing for all the
other types it's pretty lead you i don't
leave it running all the time that's for
sure
got our netherwort farm
another one over there so yeah it chains
the potion so it starts with the
sugar
sugar then it adds redstone to extend
them
then gunpowder to make them splash
potions and
fermented spider eyes to make them
slowness potions
and each step of the way you can access
the potions here
all automatically controlled and there's
a there's a
minecart running around above here that
delivers awkward potions
i believe to all these stops yeah this
should be full of potions
kind of makes it stops drops them off
yeah kind of cool actually let me
correct myself it's not
fully automatic it's close to fully
automatically it brews just about every
type of potion
but in order to make it run you do have
to feed its
water bottles so you go up here shift
right click they get shot down into the
hopper there and then there's a huge
storage for the water bottles
they get converted into the awkward
potions and all that kind of stuff
so that is how that works one of my
favorite builds i love how it looks
it's really complicated and very useful
so it's kind of like the best of
everything
i really like this this brewing system
another etho door over here which can be
controlled with uh golden carrots as
well
which i'm low on gold so i don't have
any
this is my basic hostile mob farm
uh they fall down from a spawning room
above which
i think we used ocelots and wolves to
make the mobs fall down and villagers
for the zombies
it actually works pretty decently though
honestly
and we got the different drops over here
gunpowder
zombie flesh and this is the random junk
we get from like witches and that kind
of thing
over on this side of the tunnel here we
have a skeleton spawner that we haven't
done anything with yet
but i've been mostly using that as a
storage room for all the drops we get
from the mob farm
at the end of the tunnel this is our
underground village
i really like this place pretty happy
with how it turned out it is incomplete
though we still got to do more
decoration that kind of stuff
but i like the houses and kind of cool
kind of
kind of crazy we got floating houses
like oh my goodness what is this about
every night there's a daylight sensor
that makes the fireworks go off here
and it plays the zelda tune we have
a killing room here for the villagers i
don't use this too often though because
not because i i love the villagers but
it leaves these arrows behind
that don't despawn and i'm worried
that's going to cause ledge if i keep
using it but yeah basically
bring the villagers in here and play a
game of last man standing
is idea let's go out here
i think there's about six or seven
houses and houses in here though
and they work by uh i did dig up to the
surface
and then like this actually counts as a
house over here
behind the doors
yeah that's a zelda tune i think we're
out of fireworks so
um so each house has something like that
like 10 doors or whatever
and there's a couple machines in here i
know there's a mini farm
in one of the houses i think this is for
making
written books automatically you like
throw your written book in here and it
gives you
an unwritten one automatically or
something i don't know
for mass producing emeralds if you want
and yeah that's about it for the man
cave i think there is one more
thing how do we get to it guys up here
up here
one more thing here this is how the
village kind of came to be
um there is a zombie spawner
right at the end here oh that's kind of
interesting it's a villager spawner
that's just like a graphical thing
though it doesn't actually spawn uh
exclusively villager zombies but they
spawn in these little spots here and
then you can cure them
if they are villager zombies and then we
brought them down over here to our
village and if for some reason a zombie
siege kills all of them we could
repopulate it pretty easy with that
thing just drop them down here and
they'll
reestablish themselves all right guys
man cave stuff is pretty much done
except for this as well the waterfall
let's not forget about this we
built this for the elytra wings oh
man i flew through there kind of badly
are we going to make it even
oh we're not going to make it i kind of
hit the wall there
but yeah this takes us over to the
library somewhere outside of the man
cave
it's got like a piston translocator
conveyor belt trick thing here and then
it takes us up the elevator
right to the library one of our never
ending projects
but we can do our enchanting here we got
anvils
one breaks and more fall down kind of
cool
we got oh it's night time we have a book
matrix thing here so all our books are
stored in chess
and if we need a certain type like uh
respiration 3
press a button and it should deliver it
to us or feather falling
might take a little second all right
that should be
respiration respiration three and
feather falling
they're falling
okay might have a little issue there we
got two books that time
maybe you can't use it that quick
quickly in succession
yeah this is a work in progress we will
one day finish it i hope
i'm not very good at building stuff like
this so hey you buddy
like big giant buildings that need roofs
and all that kind of stuff
i just struggle with that this is also
where we store our comment of the days
which uh a lot of the old ones
apparently got glitched out
but the newer ones still have the
comment written in them
recently in fact last episode we built
our
gold farm oh i missed let's try again
yeah there's this bridge here the whole
idea of this bridge was to bring
enchanted books from the gold farm
to the library
you come with me ignore the shape of the
la
of the gold farm here i'm gonna work on
that hopefully
um yeah zombie pigmen come in through
the portal here
and then we crush them and kill them get
their xp
uh we can light the portal with this and
this breaks its
um yeah we just saw all this stuff so
i'm not going to get too into it
over there is uh iron no
poppy poppy farm um
we built that just before we built the
nexus so that we would have lots and
lots of poppies and maybe some leftover
iron for all the hoppers
it was going to require just over here
is the man cave
this is the other exit that we keep
seeing so you come out over here
to the left takes you to the swamp just
kind of experimented with a possible
look for it
with the mushrooms and the netherwart
and the crazy path
all that kind of stuff there's a system
here for collecting ender pearls
from the end that go through the end
portal
that's the true spawn right there
and then over here is the abandoned mine
shaft
this is where i did a lot of my branch
mining when we first started in the
world but i don't really come down here
anymore
i think there's like a snow golem that
walks around on these uh
oh never mind he died i think
maybe used to be a snow golem up here
i still see the snow he would make the
lights blink though oh he is still there
look at that
yeah you'd walk on pressure plates make
the lights blink
um there was a system here for breaking
down boats to get oak wood out of them
in case you wanted to convert jungle
wood into oakwood for example
and then that's broken very good very
good
yeah lots and lots of branches here
though and again this was a way
i paid tribute to the people that
donated to me in the past
because i kind of ran out of space in
the tree farm
gave them each their own tunnel uh
this is a cool trick you know you can
still use this i think
putting lily pads above water
you can ender pearl right through them
all right i'm losing my voice guys i'm
not good at these long episodes i've
gone through like
five glasses of water already it's crazy
uh custom tree over there this is a kind
of a custom river too
don't really have time to go take the
tour down it but it looks pretty nice
when you do ride the boat down there and
then we enter
sandy city over here the what do you
call it a port
kellis or something gates
which is pretty cool it's like a 5x4 or
something
i did not design that though i copied
the tutorial for it
um got our sandy city houses here still
need to add a lot more again
kind of a work in progress whenever i
feel like doing some building
i can come here uh the pyramid over
there needs a lot of work too but that
is our
mob system that we saw just a little bit
earlier
covered up all the hardened clay with a
pyramid shape and
hopefully we'll refine it in the future
there is a cool little thing here
that i would like to maybe fix
uh i'm having issues when i leave the
chunks this breaks
that's not how you use it guys it's like
a little worm
fountain machine thing though there we
go
oh what
is it not working now i'll have to
investigate this later
oh wait what it used to shoot them
sideways but now
oh now it did i guess the trajectory
changed a little bit
i don't know anyways there is uh
i'll show you guys this
this is one of my original traps when i
did world
downloads because uh you see this
these didn't exist when i generated the
world it's a sandstone well with lava
inside
doesn't make any sense i actually built
that and made a trap there for you guys
over this way is more of the river
got like trees planted all along it um i
do eventually want to like build a snow
city up here would be kind of cool like
our
our wooly mammoth up here the penguin
and our ice cube farm this is where i
get all my ice from
is it still working yeah i think it's
still going
ice freezes gets pushed to the right or
to the left into the main
thing here we've got a mine cart running
down below that pushes it upwards
eventually it makes a big 10 by 10 by 10
thing of ice
tons of ice penguin
i like penguins by the way all right
view
view of sandy city looks pretty good
let's go on a little bit further let's
fly if we can
speed things up um we got our
our path here that kind of runs through
got a little cobble wall um
a house here which is supposed to
control our fireworks display we'll
check that out later maybe
that's like our very iconic uh view of
our world
that you've been etho thing over there i
like that thing a lot
a little character of myself more custom
trees
one of the ender porters is over here
the other one i think got blown up by a
creeper
which is another reason why i don't use
those too much anymore
um we got our blacksmith house this was
just a little fun build
kind of felt like building a house
because i never do that
and down below is our purpur smelting
room
i know guys don't don't say anything i
know don't use purpur
i just tried it but uh yeah we're not
gonna
we're gonna not gonna build the room out
of perper
it doesn't look the best i thought you
know hey it's a purple smelting room
let's build it out of perper
no we got our wheat field here with our
windmill with our guardian elder up in
the top there it's kind of cool
i like that a lot over this way is one
of my favorite builds and one of the
most difficult builds and one of the
builds we still need to finish
called the nexus our massive storage
room
kind of computer system with the other
ender porter over here that got blown up
this thing is really cool though it this
is what i use for my long-term storage
we can have like
three or four double chests of each item
that we want to put in it
got a little an index system here if we
want to
request a certain item out of it each of
these is labeled
4a in blue so let's say for example we
want
white wool is 2f so we would press
2 this button here and then f
to select it
all right that enters our code which
gets displayed up there
pull a lever or press the buttons here
and it should dispense white wool if we
have any in the system
and then if we want to drop white wool
off for example
drop items in the chest here and it goes
into the system
we might not have any white wool oh it
was coming i was just impatient
i was impatient but yeah it all gets
brought up to us which is pretty cool a
lot of work to be done on this yet
though
and i want to hook up rail systems to it
and all kinds of stuff but that's
kind of the look of it inside not that
you need to go inside to use it i just
wanted it to look good as well we got a
pumpkin farm over here
and guess what guys
guess what i finally
got an eight pumpkin villager that i
brought over here
not that one yeah just a lefty chance
after we brought the leaven pumpkin guy
here
a little bit later i got another one
that was eight pumpkins that's the best
trade you can get
um so all our pumpkins grow here
when they block the piston like that it
blocks out the light and then the
daylight sensor makes the piston extend
and it gets automatically brought to the
middle here
stored into the chests and we got tons
of pumpkins
okay so nexus is over there windmill and
wheat field and tractor it's all over
there further on though we have our
original village here
which i totally secured i made a fence
all around it lit it all
up um like back before
you could trade with villagers back
before they did anything
when they were just called testificates
um this was one of the villages
that spawned them and i tried to suit it
up and make it cool
we got like a little wheat these farms
here all of these are totally automatic
like that and now they actually replant
them
which is pretty cool i keep saying
pretty cool man
gotta stop that uh also made like a
little
custom nether hub thing here with an
ether door i think this was the first
one right
first one i made
first ethel door that is using that
t-flip-flop uh
method and more recently we built a
course fruit farm here
i built this thinking i would use it
maybe two or three times total and then
we would have so much per per blocks i
would never know what to do with them
but i use this thing constantly like
i've used it probably 20 times already
and i still need more
and they take too long to grow i wish i
made it bigger
but yeah you press a button after you
break all the seeds off
automatically harvests them this is all
on a timer so they all perfectly flow
again this is a backup world though so
we didn't get any seeds there
not a big deal they all get sorted and
then brought over to that blacksmith
area we just checked out
you got a little access to the wiring
and all that kind of stuff down here
okay moving on past the village there we
have the guardian farm which we recently
tried to improve a little bit they spawn
there this is an
old old world guys if you generate using
the seed i'm using currently
since the terrain has changed since i
made this world this area here is
actually
ocean it if you generate with the
current with the seed i used for this
world
so it thinks a guardian temple is
supposed to spawn there so i hollowed
out all the grounds
filled it with water and that's how i'm
able to get guardians there
uh we recently just did this
fancy little killing chamber for the
guardians they fall down
here right yeah there they go onto some
hoppers collect their drops the drops
get sorted into these
chests and
we just saw that stuff so let's get out
of here oh yeah there's a
an elevator here i'll just i'll show you
too
kind of my new go-to design for
elevators i really like this i hope that
translocation trick stays in the game
let's go in through the portal here too
just so i'm going to show you
um this room here we have the option of
killing the
guardians there or we can bring them
through this nether portal
uh to be stored here and we can kill
them with our looting
sword or whatever there's a poison
dispenser there i think that's instant
damage
to kill them okay so we got the
guardian portal right over there if we
keep going further though pass the water
into the snowy region here
i just took a short break so hopefully
my voice has recovered a little bit
it was getting kind of raspy i can't
talk this much guys it's killing me
uh yeah we keep going we get to the uh
original ice tray here which no longer
works because this biome
changed it's it says it's tiger but it
doesn't get cold enough for the water to
freeze anymore
unfortunately that made the water
eject to refill it after you harvest the
ice
but yeah that's why we we built that ice
cube thing which is even better
even more ice can be stored there which
is cool
i said which is cool instead of pretty
cool this time maybe
maybe a slight improvement maybe all
right
let's keep on going over into the swamp
area
you see we got the giant tower there
that is the first hostile mob farm we
built in the world
also the mysterious house on top the
hill there that we do not talk about
um yeah this this is where this
the stronghold is located in the worlds
the main one i use
um i think they made it now though that
multiple strongholds can spawn like
infinite
the further and further out you go which
i think we should check out sometime
soon
so i'm kind of curious about that yeah
this is the one i picked
it's pretty close to the man cave about
800 blocks away
this was supposed to be like my main
base that was the plan when i first
started here but i didn't
man i tell you guys i really wasn't a
good builder
i didn't know how to make this room look
good
and i just dragged my feet and dragged
my feet and
uh this area kind of got broken after
time and then i didn't want to build
here and
all in all this kind of kind of got left
behind as a
relic of the past um
but like this mob system still works we
had a way of making
we called it a bomb machine or bomb
factory over here
it was a way of making skeletons shoot
creepers
which did work very well the only
problem i had is i had trouble
separating the creepers
the ocelots just didn't quite do the job
too well
um so i had a hard time making this work
i was trying to make like an automatic
tree farm with it
and now though in the game it's easy to
separate creepers so maybe
one day we'll look back into that whole
concept
this is going to be our storage room
this is like back before i think trapped
chests or before you could put them side
by side so this is the
arrangement i found that worked best and
we have that on all four sides
never did end up filling them though i
don't think
down below here is where we have
some other some other kind of crazy
stuff
uh also that tunnel in the man cave
leads to the stronghold that one we
didn't go down
by the ender porter this is the
silverfish farm i
calculated it so exactly enough
silverfish would
would fill this room there in these
blocks right here
each one of these so that when you kill
them all you would get 50 levels back
when you needed 50 levels to enchant
something
it was an idea i thought was good at the
time
but um kind of just became a novelty
project
i really wish they would make it in the
game so you could use silk touch on the
silverfish blocks then that would
actually have a purpose again
and like on servers people would build
silverfish farms
just to troll people i think if you
could move the blocks around easy
um yeah we got the whole silverfish farm
over here
the spawners inside there um they fall
down into the water stream above the
stone block there
which gets replaced by a stone generator
when they enter the block a buds but
detector
detects it and makes a new stone block
take its place and this gets pushed down
they all get stacked together into the
big clump over here
and you can use a poison potion on these
to
really get a bunch of them spawning at
once
man all my stuff is like out there used
to be poison potions in there but i
guess uh they're all gone
anyways oh and i'm out of an ender uh
pearls now at one point in time we built
this like long tunnel here too
i can't remember where it goes but it
was for transporting the silverfish
to do like underground mining nowadays
though we got beacons and you can just
haste mine stuff super quick there was
also another tunnel that goes up to the
surface here
to move the silver fish i don't remember
the whole concept for that even
what was i doing guys i was crazy in the
past i tell you
not that i'm not right now anyways
uh inside this silverfish farm is also
our ender portal so let's go through
that
and check out our end i guess that's
where the ice path also leads up right
over here
a long 800 block tunnel to get to here
from the man cave
go inside and
let's see we have this crazy
randomized musical randomizer it
sometimes gets stuck though when you go
through the portal
let's shut it off and turn it on
we need uh we need ender pearls where
could i ever get some ender pearls hmm
hmm if only we were in a place we could
get ender pearls
uh my portal used to be over here though
ender pearls would get ejected into here
and
go to our true spawn and get collected
this is a musical randomizer
which sounds pretty cool
[Music]
we got a broken eats road here this goes
to
our original ender ender farm the very
first one
[Music]
i don't know what's going on up there
guys but they're all spawning in places
they shouldn't
uh the idea of the farm was there's like
a bunch of pressure plates up there and
that when they would spawn on them
pistons would push them down they would
fall down to one hit kill
range you know um
yeah looks like it's broken at 1.9 i
really like how this farm looks though i
think it's pretty cool it's yellow and
orange wool with a
ton of redstone uh torches around it
i guess in 1.9 mobs don't spawn on
pressure plates anymore right so that's
that's a big flaw
right there but they're spawning on on
stuff they shouldn't
as well oh
i don't think they fell down all right
let's keep moving
keep moving before they kill us there
was also a system to bring
ender pearls you load them up here and
when it would
fill up totally it would take off unload
at the
by the portal there at the start but we
have an
ender ender 2.0 as well let's go check
that out
because that one actually works still
getting chased getting chased
all right so we built this really long
glass
uh pathway to our enderman farm under
enter 2.0
that other enderman farm the original
one is
actually the original enderman farm like
before i built that the way people made
enderman farms is they would
like flood their entire end island and
make a system where you would look at
all the endermen
kind of like the blaze farm design
they would funnel them down into a cone
and kill them that way
um volume
it's like i had a brain part there for a
moment this is the ender ender 2.0
though
this one is based around the concept
that you can
um you could use tnt to
to kill all the endermen and it would
count as your kill so you would get
xp from them and also uh extra ender
pearls if you have your looting sword
selected so there's a big column of tnt
here
this flame oh
oh yeah it still works still works
uh-huh so they're all just within range
that it'll kill them they fall down
of course using the vine trick that was
later discovered
um now though enderman farms use
endermites generally
but this one still works pretty good
good enough for me anyway
and also just manually kill them they
are one hit kills i'm
pretty sure
all right moving on
okay so we are back out of the end now
over at the mob system again
by the way all those torches you see on
the outside those control lights inside
the mop system so you can turn it on and
off like stop the spawning totally
inside in case you're wondering about
that
over here we're over an hour in on this
tour by the way
i'm trying to rush we can't cover
everything in full detail
either unfortunately as much as i would
like to and we might
miss a few things so sorry if uh you
don't see what you want to see in this
in this episode anyways rambo ramble
this is a zombie villager curing machine
kind of just built it for the fun of it
not really for super practical use i
have used it a few times though
we got a lever to control the spawning
and the zombie spawner there
uh this controls which way they go if
they're either zombie villagers or
zombies
they're villagers they go inside the
tunnels there
the zombie villagers if they're just
zombies they go into the killing chamber
here
um then the
zombie villagers they land into these
areas here with the tripwire
and actually detects like if they're
there and if they are and we press a
button
the villager medicine all the ones that
have zombie
villagers in will get um a weakness
potion given to them
you can also see like the lights turned
on how did you get out here
i don't even know um
and then you feed them apples and you
press another button here villager
transports
where are they coming from oh because
uh i know i know i know
wait no i don't know seriously where'd
they come from
did they get out of here somehow oh the
slab is missing here there's supposed to
be a half slab there
alright uh let's try out the
villager transports yeah only the ones
that have uh villagers in
have the mine cart released and then
that takes them to the portal
um i think we got coal what's the coal
for
no no no oh he almost killed me
that was close that was very close
and i think that's actually all the
stuff we can really see
is he gonna get me nope
uh in our main world there unless we go
further out so let's go into
our nether now our nether is a little
bit of a mess
but not too bad
uh let's start over here actually this
is our main nether hub like the center
of our nether
near zero zero um
this portal down below connects to the
man cave
and then it goes out the four cardinal
directions all around here
so each each direction has a few
different things
that we can check out and above here is
our gold farm our original gold farm
oh yeah over here
oh let me in we worked on this last
episode so i'm not going to go
too super detailed on it and i'm also
kind of still trying to fix it because i
think there's a couple issues with it
but yeah you can light the portals with
uh
this button yeah then all the zombie
pigmen get
uh portaled through to that uh floating
red
and uh cyan clay building we saw earlier
in our episode here something is wrong
in 1.9 though guys like look at this lag
it's insane
insane um
let's see if we can shut it off like
everything is just frozen
transporting mobs through nether portals
does not work very well
in 1.9 uh above here
oh we can't go in mine carts right now
the game's just frozen
i'm gonna pause for a second
okay let's keep on going i guess so
uh down each of these tunnels we have
like a little selector panel here
this doesn't actually do anything
anymore
like the selector panel still works this
was going to be for like a grand
central uh minecart station
but i i never ended up doing it um
and at the moment i'm switching over to
ice roads
so i just kind of left that in because i
liked how it looked
we also have these horse swapping
machines
so we can have up to two horses per side
oh we took damage
i'm telling you guys things change in
this game so much
every patch there's like little problems
like that that happen
it's kind of frustrating but at the same
time a fun challenge to try to keep
everything working
all right so we got this cool little
tunnel here this was
extremely difficult to build like
whenever you met make another tunnel
this big
takes forever to build it
when you have this much detail but i
really like how it looks
uh through this portal is our obsidian
farm
and what this does is you go through
it spawns a new portal with more
obsidian you break it
and then we have our main portal up over
here
there's a witch i'm really scared of you
stand in here
press a button oh this is not gonna end
well guys
hey it worked got out just in the nick
of time
awesome but the portal closes behind you
so when you go through again it's going
to spawn a new portal every time
and you get more and more obsidian now
you can actually
farm obsidian in the end since uh every
time you do the dragon fight it respawns
the pillars
uh this is just like some mining
operation we got
and further down here actually not too
exciting it's just uh where i clicked my
sand at that
at the back portal there all right it's
back at the nether hub and if we go down
this direction
again we have a horse swapping thing
which we can see a little bit better
he took damage again though
i'll have to fix that i guess that
dispenses
a speed arrow and you get them out when
you flip the lever here
but yeah i'm switching over mostly to
ice roads now so this is kind of the
default tunnel design i decided to go
with
which is also why i'm using so much
purple blocks lately
uh we have a turn coming up here to the
left this takes us to our mesa
biome uh this is where i get all my
heart and clay
and we also have the rube goldberg
project here which admittedly i have not
worked on enough
i know some of you guys have wanted me
to add on to that and i should
um yeah this is like a clay mining
outpost you press a
button here oh did it run out
whoa the in release storage minecarts
you're supposed to be able to release uh
regular minecarts i guess they're all in
here right now
uh when they come back they go into here
as well
and then at least regular mine cart this
takes you over to the mining area
there's item filters there to filter out
the different types of clay
got like a little bridge oh we're going
back
into the machine
goes into cactus gets destroyed okay
let's go back
what oh my goodness i just want to go
down there
oh and i think it's nighttime right now
this is a bad time to be here
up above here though this is like where
i do all my my clay mining right
if we go up higher though outside here
this is where the rube goldberg machine
is if i remember correctly
all right so here it is it starts out in
this little house with this villager
dude
we only do this on special occasions
such as today
just release the lock here so he goes
outside
oh you're gonna regret that fella
blows up the ground he goes down this
little waterfall thing
and we actually have a path on the side
to watch us i don't know why i'm over
here
you run down you can see him go down and
if this works out properly he should get
put into a minecart as he makes his way
down
this all happens pretty quick and i'm
low on ender pearls
is there any in here nope
oh the tripwire's broken no
i hate that stupid patch one of the
patches broke
all the tripwires in my world which
really really stinks because there's so
many i don't even think about like this
one here
that i gotta fix go
into the minecarts do it
do it oh please
all right so he's supposed to go down
here pretty fast that releases the tnt
minecarts
he goes up to the gravel pile that frees
him
so he's able to then activate oh yeah
that's going to kill me
[Music]
whole bunch of dnd minecarts fall down
where does he go again
runs down there oh he's good he's going
so fast
this takes quite a bit of setup just to
pull off
i forgot how difficult this was
yeah you got to put the minecart in
before before we do it anyways he goes
into his little compartment there
turns into beast mode villager in his
giant cannon of flame and destruction
torches this awesome village of uh
of dreariness what did we call this
drearyville or something
i built this all in one day and uh
it was a long day but like the whole
village
gets catches on fire here
and it's kind of like a mining village
sort of thing
throughout it there's tnt though that
explodes as he flames up the whole place
it's pretty cool i like this a lot to be
honest and
more tnt
[Music]
i can't remember when we did this last
but uh
man how much stuff did i have here
anything good we got some rails hey
some rails some tnt uh-huh
this was kind of for a subscriber
special i think or something or episode
400 i think is when
i built all this stuff so if you want to
see the whole thing kind of in its full
glory you can check it out there
okay so back on the ice road here if we
go to the left there that is the clay
outpost but if we keep on going
still a work in progress these tunnels
i'm trying to to get
them all finished so that speeds up our
transportation time
um whoa hey there
should be kind of thought we would hit
it already did i pass it
oh i passed it okay down there is where
my ice spiked biome where i get all my
uh
packed ice from the amplified terrain is
supposed to be on the left here though
and i missed it
should be right around there aha
that's why i can't find it i blocked it
accidentally when i built the tunnel
okay so over here is our amplified
terrain
not the fanciest portal yet but
uh this is a base area a lot of you guys
like and i don't really do enough here
unfortunately in my world
if you didn't know some somewhere along
the line i decided to switch over to
amplified terrain
so i i loaded up my world in nbt editor
and then i made the change
um then i did some exploring found this
area here it's
really really nice um
it's really hard to build stuff here
though i gotta say
i don't know i'm not much of a builder
really i'm more of a
technical minecraft player um
so when i see something like this this
huge area we got filled with cool
structures
it is very intimidating to me recently
though i did try to do
a new look for it we got this like
little uh
um what would you call it what did we
call it
mine shaft mine rail system
mine yeah let's call it a mine
a little mine area that we're trying to
do
for the underground areas we got a
custom tree here we have this really
cool
minecart system if i can find
find out where they are right now
oh got jump pads all the way up um
there's also a flower farm here but i
can never remember where it is
yeah so here's our storage room here
with the mine carts inside the idea
is we can fill these mine carts up with
items
and it's a movable storage room like we
can have like 25 of these storage mine
carts
and we have three of these storage rooms
built currently we can add more
though and if we ever want to work in a
different area with our items nearby
we can actually move them this is mostly
complete
last time i tried it it works it's a
very elegant
very well-timed system
so when they go to the next location
they'll they'll stack down in the exact
same order that they
were over here it's also a little slime
launching platform
which is kind of hit and miss because uh
slime blocks never seem to work with
proper timing
um i think those went over here right
no they went back up to the top there
let's go check out the top they should
be there waiting for us
slime blocks are also a little bit
broken in 1.9
if you didn't know
um i
seem to have forgot to put the levers in
here
what yeah this isn't working currently
because i forgot to power these power
rails so they all got stuck it looks
like
anyways typical etho mistake
let's move on to a new area
okay things are about to get nasty down
in the other cardinal direction here
though
uh gotta work in progress ice road this
is where the witch farm is it's not
pretty definitely not pretty right now
and which farm
still needs a lot of work too like i
gotta light up the caves i still haven't
fully done that yet and a couple other
things we don't have like a nice room to
gather the drops or anything like that
but the land is like all cleared out
here i'm pretty sure
and this is the witch farm over here so
we got three layers
uh they spawn in there and then arrows
shoot them so that they fall down
uh over here and then there's hoppers
below that collect the drops at the
moment
but yeah still needs a lot of work
that's pretty much all there is here
so we are just about done our crazy long
tour here guys
let's summarize so from the nether hub
we go go down here we have our
obsidian farm we have our mining we have
our sand gathering
uh off this way we have the
clay outpost we have the rube goldberg
machine there as well
and we have the amplified terrain and
way at the end we have the
packed ice uh collection area
down there is where we just were the
witch farm
is all that's down there i also go down
there whenever i need to
collect nether quartz seems to be the
best place for it
and then finally over here
this is like the main branch this goes
to
a couple different things that such as
that guardian
room we just saw also the portals to the
stronghold and that uh
zombie villager purifier and also to the
the village i believe it connects
somehow to that
if we go through here one of my favorite
builds in the world actually is the dual
blaze farm
also a little bit work in progress we
recently gave it a makeover though
using the purper blocks and sandstone
there's another blaze farm in our world
i can't remember how to get to it i
think it's like off
that direction somewhere though
using a single blade spawner we just
kind of built the same thing
here dual blaze spawner
and all the blazes collect together
using a minecart system it picks them up
brings them up there and then the the
minecart gets broken on a cactus the
blades get ejected
pushed down into the middle by pistons
as they gather these lights
go from one two three four five once
they hit
five a crusher system automatically
damages them and keeps anymore from
falling down
and then you throw a damaged potion at
them and you get
blaze rods and tons of xp it's measured
so that you get
three levels so every time you kill them
you get like
an enchantment off of them which is
pretty cool and then what do the storage
minecarts do
guys oh yeah it brings the mine carts
that break
up their back down so that they more
places can get carried off
beautiful there's also a system here to
shut off the farm using lava lighting
on both sides in case you want them to
stop spawning
now if you keep going down this nether
tunnel though you do get to a point
where you hit this frog
this guy's from castle crashers i i
really like the castle crashers
so i decided to build them in our world
here you know i totally forgot
but we actually have some stuff built
here too
you remember you remember it guys i
haven't seen this in so long
because i forgot about it until just now
oh
don't die we have an experiment we did
oh and also this was my first wither
farm wither skeleton farm
also forgot about that yeah you see like
i did a bunch of
stuff to make the spawning race a bit
better
can probably just fly down to it
actually got a big spawning platform up
there
i did an experiment where i was trying
to
make a village in the nether because a
long time ago
as long as you didn't update your nether
ceiling
uh it would count as light shining
through so these counted as valid houses
and you could uh
spawn villagers was the idea
so these are old old villagers um i
don't know what's through this portal
oh that's the mushroom island what gave
it away i wonder
yeah that's where we got the mushrooms
from aha
all right let's keep going down that ice
road though
and finally guys at the very end of this
ice road
where the frog is we reach the big
old nether fortress here this is where i
do like all my wither skeleton farming
nowadays
i did a lot of work improv improving the
spawning rates of these guys
like i slapped i slapped a whole bunch
of the nether here
and also flattened out this whole
fortress and some places they got
multiple layers for the spawning
we got a beacon here to give us
resistance and all that kind of stuff
uh-huh i think at the moment i have like
with their skeletons skulls
what's the word 22 22 and a few beacons
um this way over here is another portal
this is to the tree farm we recently
built
the automatic tree farm that uses gas to
harvest the wood
or a gas we did a crazy
like orange green yellow red clay scheme
here
i'm like stuttering now guys i've been
talking way too long
we still need to build a killing system
for these zombies
but other than that this is all done
so it works like this you stand here
that makes the gas shoot it opens up a
trap door
um as we stand here wood gets pushed in
front so the gas balls destroy it
why is there two there
i'm not sure the wood gets uh pushed
aside here above the hopper zone none of
the wood gets destroyed
by the gas balls it's 100 collection
rates
and it gets funneled into this chest
we built that tree farm like only five
or ten episodes ago if i was to guess so
i'm not going to go super detailed on it
you can check it out if you want to
in some some of the older episodes uh
above the beacons
in the wither farm though
uh takes us up here at the top of the
nether pretty much at y224
this was our second gold farm and this
thing was awesome while it worked
we used to have 10 iron golems walking
around in there
and they would kill the zombie pigmen
get xp
and and drops with like the looting
effect and everything
um and the iron golems took no damage
nowadays they do though
they get killed pretty quickly by these
pigmen
but we also would have gas spawning in
here and the iron golems would kill the
gas
and we had a system below here where a
minecart would pass by
would pick up one of each of these items
so it would
it wouldn't pick up any of the golden
swords as it went through there
and then would drop them all all the
goodies off here and
go down below in the chest so it would
get gas tiers
gold all kinds of good stuff and all you
had to do was afk
but we might need to make another gold
farm if i can't get that first one
working because it's super leggy and 1.9
we will have to see but that that about
does it i think
there's only one thing left to do
not die let's head back to
the lake to the you've been ethod to
finish up the episode
ow hey no stop it you're wrecking the
end of the episode
that we're going to celebrate with the
comment of the day and of course the
fireworks show
it's kind of a tradition for us let's
get our music on the roll get our jam
um yeah so over here
we have a system where we randomly eject
fireworks underneath the lake
which is pretty fun let's go ahead and
flip that
start the show
[Music]
i love this thing
and let's miss the fireworks show
because it's a zombie as i look away
and we'll probably have to turn this
down too it's pretty loud
all right guys comment of the day
actually we got a
we got a little deck here now
to enjoy them on all right comment of
the day guys
uh it says by the way etho what happened
to your secret streams
anything coming on twitch keep going
mate you're awesome
well thank you very much uh
i have streamed a few times guys on
twitch the last time i tried it
it did not go very well i'm pretty sure
i got ddosed
which wasn't the best
or the stream didn't go very well anyway
it was all laggy and i had to stop it
um yeah i don't know i don't know if
that's like a really really common
problem
but uh it does kind of discourage me
from twitch also with twitch you gotta
you gotta do it regularly for it to
really count it takes a lot of time
so you can't really do youtube and
twitch but maybe once in a while just
for fun
we'll try out the twitch as long as i
don't keep getting ddosed
recently guys actually pretty awesome
my internet speed has doubled like my
download and
upload has doubled so
i was just barely able to stream before
maybe
maybe it's pretty good now i should try
it and on youtube
i might switch over to 1080p or 60fps or
maybe even both if i can now that i can
upload faster
we will see except for series like the
modded minecraft i don't think i can get
60fps in that
because it's so resource intensive
uh-huh anyways might look into streaming
again just for fun
i really really did enjoy it
uh what else was i gonna say oh yeah i
wanted to get you guys a big thank you
for uh your support as well i don't say
this like all the time i do
want to though since i'm usually pretty
focused with my commentary but thank you
guys for all your supports
with the series and with me and my whole
youtube endeavor
man i tell you like even on last episode
i looked at the comments very good
comments we got like 4
000 comments on the last episode and i
didn't even do anything really
special but you guys just
oh man you guys are so supportive i
always have nice things to say and i
really appreciate that
um and there's like 12 000 likes it was
a good
good uh good to see that i'm still
getting good support from you guys
um i do you do make this a lot of fun
doing youtube like if i didn't have your
feedback
this wouldn't be all that exciting i'm
trying to figure out if we can launch
this thing
it's like a one-time thing so this is
the perfect time to do it
i don't even remember this was like when
slime blocks first came out i wanted to
try one of these
it's like a missile thing oh yeah it
still works cool
cool cool so let's go out with a bang
guys
thank you ever so much for watching and
for your supports
hope you enjoyed the world tour so if
sorry if it was a bit long
i tried to hurry um couldn't quite look
at everything i know
and uh well if you want to see stuff in
more detail you can always look at the
older episodes
but yeah this is it for me quite
literally
this is a backup though thankfully
hope you enjoyed have a wonderful day
bye bye
you