Hey, there, whereyet is the old Aljozer Etho, up
in them Dercanelland and I tell you woots
whather dey went out Ootside and I saw a boot o
three feet t o snowa boot. Ther madee Mus ran down
the street and had been thaced by a Porror
beariers, that it was so caught out. I tell you
why you don't see that Eber day up in Tem near
Canada Landby, At the end E, last episode we
started working on an expansion to our
netherhab, a village or breeder system up above
here and I got a little bit more done on it. We have
like t a sandstone ground. We got some neather
brick mixed tins, some purple wool. I know
everybody loves the purple wool. Oh yeah, it's
just amazing, so we kinda had like a sloap
ceiling here. We might try to do that glass thing
up there as well, and maybe we'll change the
sandstone to smooth sandstone i haven't
decided, but we gotta get some lighting up here.
I tried like using the lanterns and I don't think
they're going to work the blue lanterns maybe,
but they don't give off enoug light to actually
be useful. I think so, li. e. I don't like the
orange with the purple and the yellow and stuff.
Maybe it's not the worst thing in the world. I, d.
no, I kind o. like whatl we did below as we had some
purple glass in the walls and places, I think
we'll do something similar, either full block
or I got some pains as well, And then I think we'll
just hide lighting behind these. Ah, probably
two blocks up, so you can't see it at all. I think
if it's over here that one lookes good. Yeah, I
don't like tati, Ge, At least the block hirher,
uhhuh, uhhuh, maybe ye'll dislike punch holes
all the way down here, Nd I could look cool, too.
Oh, you see that they just woke up. Oh, all right s
o snappers. We'e got this place all put together
and it's very similar to the hulbelows. We got
again that nether brick. We got the glass in the
ceiling and up in the middle there is my mind
cartt elevator to get on top of the bedrock, So we
kinda have to leave that there or that's a lot of
villagers, isn't it? Myg gal, be carried away
with a number of beds and stuff, H. we'll
probably start shipping these guys out to other
places in our world, and then I won't refeed them
for a long time until population drops down to
like ten or so. so. Yeah, the idea is if we need a
villager now, anywhere in our world, we got
these drop shoots on each of the four a tunnels.
Maybe we'll put them in a minecurt. They won't
take a all damage that way, all right,
everybody. well, I think our plan for to day is
just to do a bunch of random stuff around our
world, as as my fancy way of saying, I don't have a
plan. but now I got like a hundred things on my
list I want to do. and uh, most of them aren't
really. They're just like random little
projects. So Ive recently been like making a
bunch of Mani farms in creative, and one that I
thought was pretty good was a coko, be n farm i did
so I want to add that into or world for brown, die
and let's build it together here really quick.
Ah, this. I goin be for the storage and aright.
You guys are paying attention right yet, Yant o
Kate. We get some hoppers in here. It's goin t be
double hop or speed, so we got one hopper going to
the chest here, Ond one going in over there. The
cogo beans will transfer superfast and in order
to plant coco beans, it has to be on junglewood,
so we get a piece of junglewood there. We'll
plant them there. There's two dispensers you
can bone mail, cocoa beans or ampobomial. in
these dispensers I got be very careful. those
sheep don't get out if they do, or we're in big
trouble. They're going t take over the world.
Nobody's going to be happy with that. Let's I. I
just realized you guys aren't going to be able t
sea too well here, ell mi hav Ben. a bad idea, Ca,
Iwill get a piece of red stone there on that one
and we'll have to put one here too. shift. click
areayou. see what's happening here. Now we just
need a clock running to triggers those
dispensers so we're going to use an observer
clock is two observers facing each other like a
so in here cookin a way, And now we'll have an
onoff switch for this ting by moping, one of
these out of the way. Oh, isn't going to get out it
wer goods. It a torchup there here. I think he can
sceep here. Oh, he was just about to make a run for
it, so you might have noticed when we first set
this up. it was kind of going like kuckk, quick,
and now twice ha speed. I didn't change
anything. Thatthiss will happens when you uh th
ook thelever up to this All right, So now we'e got
ta hook up a harvester for it as well, we're just
going is a piston to do that, but we gotta get a
piece of red stone on top of the cocoa bean block
as where the cocoa beans go. Ah, but we a made sure
it doesn't connect to the other ones next to it,
So we're going O put a block overtop here. cut it
off, and now we're going to add some chests up
here, fer bomiuo that will flow down to the
dispensers. It just takes two ball mail to grow a
cocoa bean to maturity, unlike like a wheatan
stuff, which sometimes takes three, is always
two. and then all we got do is get our pis ten rates
facend down at the cocoa bean and hard to do. Got
it okay good, and we'll put a repeater over top of
that En break our leavver, for now, The leaver as
just there ecause. it's annoying. we're going
to move it up over here now. Hoh, that's our aunt
off, switch, An, we can just decorate it.
However we want an, we put some blocks in front
and jest for luoks. He might want to put trap dor
fror, your hopper or something. But that's
about it. We just flipped this to turn it on and we
uh rite, click with our cocoa bean lug. An at all
the brown eye you could ever want. It is mass
producing the stuff like super quack, All
right, so this is like loaded up bundling down
here at two times a speed. Oh, those poor guys.
they have even less space. Now I discovered up
the redstone with some haybailes wi'r going to
head over to the end now. and I got a bit of a weird
project Iy wante to do over there, so let's take
our inder porter. baam. Been using this thing a
lot. It is actually really awesome and we arent
there. Yeah, I kinda want to build some kind of
transportation system, in the end to get to
those types of portals, and also Ea Ourmain
portal here from our obsidian platform here,
dig out a tunnel like a three by three tunnel that
goes right to our portal and all those other
little portales and fill it up. I water, and then
get adulpin here, so we get Dolphin's grace, and
can es ziprate through our our end, nice and
quick. I can be a lot of digging though this goin
take a long time and we're going to need to get
some sol soil afer step. Watch your stat, wee
goin a fall Efa. it's bout a hundred block
tunnel, actually, so we're going to line the
floor with the sole soil so we get this sole speed
effect from our boots and go even quicker
through it. Okay, I think we're ready to start
flooding this thing, so lets git doin thati that
to go all lrong here with our water. So yo' going
to want to build like a wall around the platform
here, so when the dolphin comes through, he's
not going to jump off the edge on us N now, for the
easy part, we just gotta get Adolphin into the
end. That shouldn't be too tough, right. I have
no idea. do they do? They come out of the water. If
you. If you pull him out, I, ah, no problem, no
problems. so we're about two, three hundred
bucks away from our stronghold bass, actually,
now we gont make sure this is a little bit
confusing, but they will die if they stay in the
air too long, and they'll die if they stay in the
water too long. So they kina got to alternate as
we go here. We got a f. I think two minutes though
that they can stay out of water. O, and I name Yeu a
speedy. Okay, I think we're ready to go speedy.
Let's do this. Give Hem a slow falling potion oh,
how do I think about this idea? By the way I was
thinking it might be cool with the one point
seventeen up date with the the lightning rods
and stuff. What did they make it? So that charge
creepers drop tea and tea. A. So that'llah give a
reason for like actually wanting to use the Uh
lightning rods, and like setting up a
chargecreuper farm and farming T and t from
them. I think that could be pretty cool, itki
help solve the whole uh tan t dopping glitch that
they still haven't fixed Bcause. I don't think
they want to ecause. There's no replacement for
it in the game. That'll be a way of getting the t n
T. and then they just need to add away of uh,
moving tent. Ah, anyways, we are about here
speedy. Oh, I'm sorry, let me let me guide you
through. You got to be quick, O'r, running out
time. I know you're excited to see outside of the
ocean and stuff, but you, we got to go here. Oh
man, I think we're running out of time. come on,
speedy. Going there? We? o. we got em. when a
flood is goon foeti. Oh, he went. he went in
Okeco. Ah, this is tricky. Cam. I give him some
water. Oh yeah, that's a. That's what I should
do. I sh. d just use the water to get Am Mhore, I
want em, rasped Kat'. we got the glass there.
good. good good. you're goin a block. This it is
trapps, and now we. Oh, I killed the water. Oh no.
I din. Okay, hoo. we need that water. An I' gong t
add he water right there Ban. we got speedy in
place, so as long as he's in a bubble stream like
that, he will never suffocate Ah, Otherwise
like, if you just leave em in water, they'll die.
If you leave em an air, they'll die. so an Iwas
cleaning up a blockene in there with em, and I
don't know, if he's refreshing the De span time
on that every time it like goes to his nose, She's
like non stop doing it. though, so I'm wondering
if that bloch will stay there forever or if it's
going to decay Y after five minutes. No, all
right, So we also got a bubble elevator that goes
from our tunnel up to the pordal. Ah, now what
we're going to be doin is fightin a couple
withers, cause we have no more beacons. left. I
want to set up a speed to beacon for this stunnel
as well, so let's get to doin that. An. I want to
see if it's going to bluw. our glass here.
Probably will Eis put Enston there if it does.
Ah, yeah, we got Toms o Ann stone from from all
that mining. Look it all. Oh, it didn't it didn't
bor nice. I. yeah, it's still there. So if you
want to keep a item around for some reason,
that's one way to refresh, it. let's give this
thing a try now. Ok, so the ideas ere going to come
in to the end and like a lot of times we do this jest
to get back to span. So then we just hold old
control and honestly, the Sowest part about
that was the elevator hum. Is there a faster
elevator we could do? I wonder. Aha, so that's
pretty cool. but Weave also added in another
tunnel which we're going to try out now. I
haven't tried it yet don'knowhow I's going to
work, An we'll probably be adding more in the
future to go O other places like these, these
little portal things, Um, le olice. Let's give
us a try. So there's ai. whoa. o. whizzed, Ray
Pasttit Can be careful how I do it. I guess Arryel
hat's better. He'll launch us out. how far that
take us from the island. A, not as far as I is
hoping. I was hoping I' like really launcos.
Maybe I got a hold space before I leave the exit.
Maybe we dragged on the ground and I was kind of
hoping you'd like launch us right to the Ann.
this thing over here, but I guess at doesn't
quite take you all the way. It gits a a nice boost
to it though, For sure, Yeah, the friction in
this game just kind of sucks the air. friction it
like instantly stops you no matter how fast
you're going. Oh, Ky. I tried it a couple more
times here and there is a trick to it. We gotto
press space right when we exit the tunnel to
activate our litras, and then we kindo dislike
soare all the way here without even needing a
rocket. Yasso. Here's an idea. Maybe, instead
of using a bubble elevator at the end, let's
build a staircase using slabs to get up there.
Ecause. it's only I think, like ten blocks we'r
gonnta climb if you try to swim vertically Ind
water. it's very slow, so we don't want to do
that, But if we can, Ah, staircases up with
slabs. it should be very fast. Ah, if we can do it,
let's test it out. I actually don't know. To be
honest. Oh yeah, we go over top of it. look at that
awesome woe and the cool thing is you get the sal
soil a speed of beck through slap, so we
shouldn't get a big light camera jerk, e, ap yip,
so we changed our tunnels slightly. here. we
have a staircase now. every two blocks we go up
one vertically and we'd have Sol soil below the
slab, so that we still keep that to soul speed. A
fat. Ok. yere e go and okay, Kind o sows you down a
bit. I think yeah, I think with that we were
slamming into the sides of the slabs just cause
we're moving so fast, we would need to space it
out even more like every four blocks C up one or
maybe even every six, but it was better than the
Bub oil rigers, who'll probably leave it like
that. Ah, anyways, we are going to be doing
something else here. Well, I'm Mannao. show you
a failed O attempt. I. I did here. I thought it'd
be cool if we could hook the Ender Porter network
up to a nether portals and then be able to hit in,
hit a button, an hill, aport to the portal and go
through all in one sort of thing here, so we got
our inderpearl hovering over here. Ah, the
problem is, it's actually really tough to do so.
And then I wanted the clothes after we go
through, too, so I set up some chains here to
align the pearl properly, so we're still. We're
hovering over the water. We can throw it down.
Ah, the problem is if that pearl gets too close to
the portal, it'll actually go through the
portal. That's one. issue, this is what we want
to happen right here where we go into swimming
Amose, and having the chain above us does that,
but it doesn't seem to happen consistently, but
when that happens we like instantly start going
through the portal whence we tell eports, which
is the dream, so I'll either teleport into the
water on to the portal block or somewhere in
between, We wan a telleport somewhere in
between ike, we just did if he were going through
the portal or getting tha happering screen
thing, and while we're here we can still throw
the pearl down within the four seconds it takes
to go through, so that's the perfect situation.
But you see this time it didn't happen. we're
standing on the portal blocks and sometimes we
go in the water even so I don't know why it's not
consistent and that is why this isn't really
working out that time a girl went through the
portal. Honestly, though, I think this is the
case where I'm being more fancy than I need to be
like. If you think about it, my goal is to have a
button at an anterporter to take me to the nether
portal, and we can build nether portals
wherever we want. Why wat? don't we disfild a
another portal at each interporter and then
have a button to go through, the big downside I
would say to this, though, is it's going to be
harder to make it look good. Because a obsidian
doesn't look the best. Then it s can take more
space and all that kind of stuff comparato is
tellporting somewhere else in going through a
portel. Yeah, I'm not sure the best way of doing
that. To be honest, I migt have to think about it a
bit more. Maybe gi's have ideas for it. Ah, but
we're 'n changed things up. now we're over at the
lab. I thought we'd do a little bit of progress
here. This is a small bild. so I think by far I
asked you guys what I should add to this thing.
and uh, one important thing I forgot was the
Aquaf affinity Helmits were going to add like a
somewhere to pick that up here. But uh, what I
want to build today is another suggestion. You
guys had to add some kind of ah like cobblestone
generator, I think that's a good idea because
this is the mining lab and that would be a way of
generating infinite blocks to test out the
mining on right. Ai. It kind of fits the theme.
What's the centere here right over there is the
technical way of the lining things up. Make sure
you don't move your mouse round too much. Ah,
okay, I think this is the middle right over here.
So what we're goin to do E is buille like a
Collstone generator, but that's not all. I also
want to build a stone generator and a Basult
generator and try combine them altogether.
Each one has a different hardness, so that's
great for testing. things in thin will do like
bassalts, maybe stone here and cobblestone
over here, and like, tried to squeeze em this
close together and built some sort of like
decorative machine for it, Ah, there's one
group of blocks. I very rarely usin this game.
It's the glaze terracotta, but I recently saw
like some one use it in a bill that An they
combined like five to seven different colors of
glaze, tarr, cottat, thegether, and it looked
so cool. It really inspired me to try use the
stuff. E, more, um, but man, I suck at it. Okay, I
think this'll work O this word that's cool
right, It's an odd number, right. So you gotta?
we gotta do something weird with it. Thes stuff
works best when you're working with even
numbers Cays, T. it's like two by two patterns.
Now Can lets do like this Will get the doughnuts.
Then I think that'll be good. Yeah, okay, I'm
happy with that. Maybe let's bump this back one
more block. Actually, Okay, Well, we got a basic
shape for our machine figured out now I will have
to dress. it up a lot, though I'm an Adda border
around round here. The idea behind the magma
block is like handling in a metal factory when
they're excruding metal. I want to make it look
at Uor, squeezing Nhiss through a dye, and it's
like henging up the area around it. You know. Ah,
we're going to add some signs above this
properly with their hardness levels and stuff
like bats. I want to get some pipes running in
tear with water and lava, and also like some
campfires to make you lookike it, smoking or
steaming. But before we get to fully decorating
this sing, let's actually make sure we can do the
red stone part of it. Usually when I do red some, I
figure out the interface first, so we kinda got a
idea of what we're doing now and then you do the
red stone, then you do the final detailing O, K,
so cause sometimes like, you'll you'll do the
red stones and you'll figure out. Oh, I need more
space than this or something, And then it's like
impossible to make it work. And if you've
detailed everything, that's all just wasted
effort. then Um, okay, so we'e got ta get Sol soil
below. We gott get ice. We ca get lava on the other
side or piston over here. Oky, that's basult
dun, now e te copestone, Okay, so we built
another smart piston over here, we're going to
have water next to the note, flock. it'll go down
and then we're going to make the lava flow into
that. Think we can treak this now? I hope M
Colpstone, Yes, Yes, and then for the stone one,
it's going to be a bit more tricky. Ecause. We
can't do the note block, smart piston thing,
What we're going to do instead. We'v gotta
observer down there. It's going to try detect
when the water disappears, so if the stone
appears, the water will disappear and it will
make the piston extend. Is the thought anyways?
Let's see if that actually works Ey that shuts
off the water or it pushes twice. It seems to be
fine though the ho snapper's all right.
Everybody, check it out. We got er done. We
worked out the final details on this thing. Ah,
so we got a lava pipe flowing into one side. We got
a water, pipe into the other. they combined
together to make the differenc to different
stones here. Ah, put some orange glass on the
lavaside, blue glass on the the water side. In
the middle we got brown glass, and in the back
there we got some camp fires with the the smoke or
the steam rising up is put Tdawn on top of our
redstone, seems to work Oky, and yea, that's
about its. A. These are supposed to be like
pressure, gages and stuff. I don' know. I'm not
the best, look like imaginary details. Oh, we
got some vents in the back, Yere with the blast
furnaces and uh, well and all, I'm pretty happy
with it. It felt pretty lonely on its own side.
Added in some more of these column things as like
a color contrast An the he bulket up. I got
anether brick on the back there like we did over
there to keep in consistent and all in all seems
to be good, so when we mind thes out, they'll
start ot of producing hast thot our tools. Then
this an's orgin rigt gat ya oky. got worried for a
second. There is is very slow. Ah, anyway, is it?
It's kind of like a dimmiky fun little bild, but I
enjoy doing it. so I hope he as like te few, but
anyways, guys, I think it's about time we wrap up
for to day, so the common says Hey etho, I notice
that you explained the mechanics of Minecraft,
like the Speed Potion trick and things like
that. I really appreciate these things because
they make me better at the yame. On With my
question, why did you start doing this? Yes, I
would say. Ah, like talking about Jame Mccanx.
has been prettykey to the series Lik ever since
it started. That's just something we've always
kind a done right. I think a large reason for that
is because it's just the way I naturally tend to
play video games. I love learning games at a base
level, Like the key mechanics on how they work.
Um, not just mycraf. like all games. it's like
something I focus on a lot. Um, for whatever
reason, this is something I enjoy and then a lot
of people hate replaying video games, Like if
they have to start over or something. they just
dread it, but I love it for some reason cause
usually ill, I'll play through and then the
second time I play through, it's like Oh, I gon t
apply all these things I learnt the first time
and play much better the second time and then the
third time you get do even better and it feels
rewarding that way to me, which is probably one
of the main reasons why Rogue likes are one of my
favorite types of games. A, because they're
designed, for replayability in improving
their skills and stuff. Um, but yeah, just in
general, I think learning games at a base level
makes you better at them and adds more depth to
the game. so you appreciate them. More Mind
Draft becomes more interesting to people that
way and all in all, I think it's a good thing,
right, I hope anyways. Hope you guys enjoy
today's episode. Thank you for watching until
the next one, take care, have a good date. Don't
hit the iron gollum by light