hello everybody this is etho welcome
back guys we are in the end once again
or I'm still in the end kind of check
out my bridge it like changes colors as
I walk you see that oh what is happening
what is happening the bridge is alive
it's a it just happens when I'm in f5
mode it's like that the glass is
fighting for draw order or something and
it changes as I move it's kind of cool
anyway so I'm still working on this
thing I let's see what did I do
I've added the border all along here
goes all the way to the Enderman farm
and it is deceptively far like you see
the farm out in the distance there and
you walk towards it and it it's like it
doesn't get any closer you just keep
walking and walking and watching and
watching and it's still really far away
so that's a pretty long pretty long path
here I just wanted to try a few things
with you guys and then I'll finish the
rest of this off-camera but I do like it
with the borders on the sides makes me
feel a little safer on here too because
every now and then Enderman like to
teleport into that spot specifically
right over there from the island I think
it has to do with the way they're
teleportation code works there's some
priority to that spot for some reason
it's kind of interesting but let's see
what did I want to try I wanted to add
some lighting to this glowstone wouldn't
really work too well with this and
torches wouldn't work really good but
these sea lanterns are the perfect color
I think let's just see what they would
look like as planning on having like
three of them overtopped every so often
that is not a seed Lantern there we go
maybe like that
because it's really dark in the end I
kind of want some light oh yeah and they
they're animated I forgot that looks
cool what else could we do we we should
have some way of attaching them to mmm
crafting table there we go here we go
this is what we're doing let's try to
see what it would look like if we made
it out of panes we had like this is that
a good idea maybe hmm
I'm not sure if I like that all right
anyway I'll think about I want to do
something like that all the way down
maybe like a light every 16 blocks or so
so I'm going to be adding the water
stream here I don't like having the
second line of glass like this one here
so I'm gonna try to do it without that
and we have to do some trickery with the
water if we want to do it that way well
spooky sound okay here is here's what we
got to do I think we got to place a line
of blocks next to this ice level three
four five six seven eight
build that up one so it'll hold the
water end place the water good and then
we have to be really tricky here we have
to play around the way water updates so
I forget rid of this unfortunately a lot
of this ice is gonna go to waste though
because I shouldn't have placed it
already then I think we're free to
remove this because the water's gonna
get priority to flowing downward there
or it's gonna try to to float towards
those holes I just made and like this
block here it sees this hole over here
so that is closer than if it was to try
to flow over the edge this way and then
if we put that there it's again this
hole over here is closer than the edge
so it doesn't it doesn't flow that way
and it does that all the way along if we
add it that way okay and then we're free
to remove this cool and yeah that's
perfect so I have my water stream here
still and I don't have to have that
border of glass that I don't like too
much it's pretty cool and I'll work just
the same oh so nice of you guys to drop
by and help me out here yeah this will
make it easier yeah that's fine yeah
walk great in front like that that's
cool
oh yeah you want to take a bath there
that's fine I'll wait my face like that
that's cool is your place
pretend I'm like the maid or something
go about your business
no I did not look at you oh I did look
at you all right this is getting very
fun it's this block okay let's go back I
like you have to totally redo a lot of
this stuff okay go over here I'm adding
in an ejector thing for the ender pearls
and I wash it away some of my redstone
let's see places oh I can't cuz of the
hopper here do I dare waste the hopper
here I think I do is this way easier if
I do it got that back get this back
there goes the hopper all right now do
you work very good very good I liked it
I'm going to want to put something up
above that though shoot them all over
the place
excellent that is going back here I just
have one more water stream to add oh
yeah we are done in the end guys the
project is done you can go do something
else finally this started out as a
simple idea it's like oh I'm just gonna
add a water stream next to the path and
I'll be able to transport enderpearls
really easily six to eight hours later
we are done it's a big project actually
but it looks cool it's gonna be really
useful so to get you up to speed
Casey missed last episode the idea is we
are going to get our enderpearls I've I
use enderpearls all the time right and I
keep running out and I have to come here
and transport them manually and it's a
real pain so now we have sort of an
automated system of getting enderpearls
back to our home basically this will
shoot them out and the water stream
carries them all the way to the end
portal those go through the end portal
and end up in a hopper in the overworld
right by our man cave so it's really
really cool and hopefully there's no no
problems with this I do actually really
like these lights now now that I got
them all set up I think they're pretty
cool look how far this path is like oh
man I really want to get some beacons or
maybe a horse or something or maybe on
the other side I'll have a an ice stream
that I can jump in you know where it's
like you jump on the ice and you move
really quick type of thing I might do
that just getting around the bend okay
yeah it looks good I think they're going
up the item elevator okay yeah I some go
up good so I think we're good here
save me snow golem now you missed it
save me you got it you got him you got
him nope
he still cares about me alright I'm
gonna get out of here so I'm in the
middle of doing a real test right now
I sent 30 stacks of ender pearls it
almost seemed like some of the ender
pearls we sent the first time didn't get
there so I want to just kind of see
what's going on although those hoppers
probably can't to pick them all up at
once are they gonna be here oh I don't
see him here alright there's one in
there oh they're still being uh
figured out okay let's check the chest
mmm that is not 30 stacks of ender
pearls where are they going they're
disappearing somewhere somehow three
four five ten fifteen so half of them
did not make it what on earth I all look
into it another day I think we've spent
enough time on that today alright guys
so what else are we going to be doing
today well we are going to build that uh
an iron farm yep
building an iron firm
oh you guys are so funny you believe
anything I tell you I love it
oh you're so easy to trick no obviously
we're not building an iron firm are you
crazy
mede build an iron firm uh uh no you
guys might not have known this but this
snowflake was always meant to be a
flower farm we are going to be building
see how to explain it to explain it it
so we built that flower farm in the
amplified terrain recently right I tried
to make it so we could get poppies but
really we weren't getting many poppies
from it so we are missing that type of
flower from our collection so I am
building a puppy farm here and my plan
on how to do that is to build like a sky
village with at least ten villagers in
it and we're gonna make a trap in the
middle and every now and then it should
spawn iron golems that will will fall
down and then we can kill them and get
their poppies yeah and I'm not gonna go
into too much detail about the build
here because this isn't really this
isn't my design at all I'm copying
documents that Oreo lots of people that
have made these types of farms and yeah
I'm not the best guy to explain them so
I'm just gonna go ahead and build it
here and maybe I'll give you a few more
details as we go here ah you know what
guys I don't actually know how iron
golems spawn like I don't know like if I
put water over this ice if they could
spawn in this spot so just the air on
the side of safety I'm gonna put a layer
of snow here maybe I will adjust it if I
find out later that they can because I
think it would look better if we could
see through this ice still from below
but yeah I think just to be safe will
cover
you know I often have people ask why I
would why I don't build an iron farm
what's the reason for it and it's just
something I decided I didn't really want
to build because I thought it would take
away some of the fun of the game for me
because currently if I if I need
redstone I go speed mining I get tons of
redstone from that if I need like I
don't need anything else really I have
multiple gold firms I have lots of lapis
I can get lapis from villagers I got
like three stacks of emerald blocks and
I don't have a need for diamonds so
really the only thing I would ever want
to go caving for is iron currently and I
kind of like that it gives me a reason
to go taping every now and then it's not
like I got to do it all the time but
it's just it's really a good bounce I
find the way I do it currently and if I
had the an iron farm I don't think I
would go caving any more that being said
though there are times when I kind of
wish I had an iron farm like I've done
this before in an episode where I will
just rind caving like I'll go caving for
hours and hours just to like get a
beacon or something and that kind of
stinks that's not very fun and then when
I go to record the episode it's like I
am so out of time and so worn out from
all the caving that I have to like
record a bad episode so that kind of
stinks so that's one instance where I
would possibly consider having an iron
farm also maybe if I had a large project
in mind that required a lot of iron that
I didn't want to go grind for I might
also want an iron farm in that case hmm
okay so one of the things that might
prevent us from finishing our puppy farm
today is we don't actually have ten
villagers to spare currently so I've
been coming here every so often and just
feeding these guys bread to get them
breeding I think when villagers run
really quick like that that's when
they're they're okay to breed if they're
moving around slow it means they are not
you see that guy you see this guy he's
moving really slow if I feed you bread
will you run yeah look at him go so I
think that's the sign that you can get a
baby for them hey how are you little guy
how about you guys you want some bread
so you can initiate breeding and
villagers by trading with them there's a
rare chance but the easiest way is just
to feed them you can give them three
bread or I think ten carrots or ten
potatoes to get them into breeding mode
this guy has been stuck here I feel bad
I'm gonna free him they will they get
trapped in fences like permanently
unless you free them there you're free
right
can you move there you go he's running
cool I just learned something new today
doors now stacked to 64 I think it was
16 before when they first were able to
stack that's interesting so believe it
or not there's actually a central seem
to everything we've been doing in
today's episode as Randleman Diskin
jointed as it might seem I am preparing
for something do you know what it is you
have five seconds to figure it out five
four three two one
you failed sucks to be you yes
everything we've been doing has been in
preparation for that that the DA that
was a terrible drum roll the Nexus I am
planning on building the Nexus very soon
and I made a little shopping list of
things we need to gather before we even
think about building it because when I
start building it I want it to go super
smooth I don't want to be running around
for materials so I want to try collect
stuff beforehand and this is like the
minimum of what I expect we're gonna
need for certain things so I want to
Fisher collect all this stuff in this
list before we start it currently I am
in the middle of designing it a little
bit of background information too
because some of you probably have no
idea what I'm talking about a little
while ago like several months actually I
brought up three big build ideas that we
might do in our world here one of them
was like a redstone Castle idea another
one was a zoo idea and then the Nexus
the Nexus is like a giant crazy storage
room command center type of building I
wanted to make you my world here and
that got about half the votes and that
was about it I haven't done anything
with idea because I didn't really know
what I wanted to do with it I I don't
want to just build a storage room that
like has been seen before or that's been
done before I wanted something that
would make it unique or cooler or had
some kind of trick to it that's that
made it special I don't know something
it needed something you know to make it
worthwhile and I have that idea now I
know what I want to do and I've spent
some time experimenting with the idea
and I know how to do it with redstone
the only thing I need to do yet is to
organize how I want the storage room
because there's going to be lots of
different materials in the game right
like obviously I wouldn't want to have a
double chest for for dragon eggs because
there's only one so I have to decide how
much storage space I want for the
different items what I want to store and
that kind of stuff because not
everything is equal
minecraft and then I also have to figure
out how I I can best lay out everything
I'm gonna do and we need the materials
this is not a small list stack of or a
chest of chess that's like eight chests
of wood because yeah that's a lot of
chests we need three chests of iron I
don't want to grind the iron that's not
gonna be fun by teaming so that is sort
of the purpose to this poppy farm as a
side effect of getting poppies I suspect
I will get a little bit of iron from it
as well uh-huh
but I'm gonna make a rule that any iron
I get from this is only going to go
towards beacons or
rare exceptions I might use them on big
projects such as the Nexus okay I'm
gonna keep this iron separate from my
normal iron and this is just for me this
is so the game is fun for me
basically it feels more balanced not
having an infinite iron oops
let's see you did I cover everything
with it what else did I want to talk
about maybe we'll go over this list a
little bit more so three chests of iron
it's a ton of iron to two chests of
glass that's not gonna be too tough ice
we might even have already stone is easy
droppers the only other one that's gonna
give us trouble is this chest of
redstone there was enough space to write
it but that means redstone blocks not
redstone dust that's a lot of redstone
so I'm gonna have to do some speed
mining for that maybe today actually we
will experiment a little bit with the
chests of just one what's a good way of
growing trees I just realized I made
this a little too small
No aha very good so we pretty much got
this thing all complete we got the water
in its two layers and got the doors got
these little side compartments for the
villagers I believe we need to put three
in per side or maybe two sides you can
have two and the other two need three
I'm not exactly sure how these poppy
farms work but we'll try it out later
yeah so the only thing we need to do is
get the villagers up here which
unfortunately we'll have to do next
episode because I'm out of recording
time for today need to go to bed it's my
bedtime
let's go hop in check it out all right
hopefully I built this okay I'm not
exactly sure like I said I'm just like
trying to follow Doc's tutorial although
I see I made mine smaller than the one
he built so hopefully it's okay I'm not
very good at following tutorials because
I don't really listen to them I just
build what I see I think the snowflakes
still looks okay even with that they're
pretty cool yeah so one thing though I
will try to do before we end this I'm
gonna do just a quick little tree
experiment here let's go to our spot our
little testing spots ah
all right over here over here by the
path so usually whenever I run out of
wood in this game I will come over here
grab my spruce my spruce saplings I am
barely talk I'm so tired
grab these bonemeal please tell me
handsome
you're still yes I do and I'll grow like
two three or four trees and I'm good for
for quite a while again of these 2x2
trees what I am wondering usually I'll
get a few saplings from it to bonus what
I am wondering is can I do a four by
four tree and still get a sapling profit
from it or not that is what I want to
find out because this would be way nicer
to harvest than a 2x2 okay throw that do
that one so I might chop down a few of
these four by four trees oh that's not
gonna grow is it get rid of this that's
puppy oh come on guys it's middle of day
you're out of here
wolf get up move are you mine yeah you
are
kill spider right now hurry he's gonna
kill me Wow okay what what just happened
it's like we we resolved into a peaceful
solution here the spider is like okay
I'm not gonna hurt him the wolf is like
okay I won't hurt you oh hey come on
maybe not totally peaceful I think
wolves have trouble getting these guys
actually because they're so big okay you
sit down don't eat my food alright yes
what was I saying I'm gonna chop this
down I'm gonna keep track of how many
saplings we did and we'll check it out
okay
well I chopped down to four of those 4x4
spruce trees and this is the results we
got so it takes 16 saplings to grow
those and then this is the profits and
it's pretty obvious we got a decent
really good profit from that actually
with the exception of the fourth tree it
was just by chance a lot shorter than
the other ones and we only got 15
saplings so it was one short of breaking
even but overall we got a lot more than
I expected and probably do a 6 by 6 or 8
by 8 tree and breakeven which is pretty
cool so I'm gonna try that out later
again we need this wood for the Nexus
and so I'm gonna start saving up wood
and we'll have to get redstone and and
then eventually gonna have to try finish
that as soon as possible so we can start
getting some iron because it's not like
we're gonna get iron the rate when we
finish it it's gonna take a long time so
probably we'll have to do some caving
still even with that just so we can
speed up the process but anyway here is
the comments for today it says etho I've
watched just about all of your videos
and I've enjoyed all of them and always
look forward to your next one but I
would like you to put some more thought
into a single-player mod pack series
which you discussed on your last feet
crack pack video I personally would
really like you to do it and I feel as
though a lot of others would as well
right so just to clarify a lot of people
are still asking me what happened to
crack back on my last episode I went
into detail it was basically technical
problems server became unplayable for me
so I stopped playing on there I
mentioned I might start a single-player
modded series but currently I think mod
makers are in the process of upgrading
to Minecraft 1.7 there was one leaf
block left by the way on that fourth
tree I'm still waiting for it to
de-spawn we might get one more sapling
but if I feel it's not quite the right
time to start up a single-player modded
series like that I want to wait for the
1.7 stuff to come out and then I might
put it back together and play a series
so I'm just waiting a bit right now is
what's going on
and then we'll see what happens from
there but thank you for your comments
and all your comments everybody really
appreciated support has been great
lately getting lots of good comments
lots of like views on the videos lots of
likes and all that good stuff so thank
you for that I am going to say goodbye
for today hope you enjoyed the episode
and I will see you again in the next one
take care bye bye