[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho and welcome back
to another episode of
the let's play series so we are down to
just five more episodes everybody
until the world tour is taking place
that's just
five more episodes to get things done
around here nice and polished up and
presentable for for you guys when the
world tour happens
and i know we're not going to get it all
done
not even close there is so much to do
around here
but you know what that is perfectly fine
i honestly wasn't expecting to get all
our unfinished projects finished in time
um the main reason for setting some kind
of deadline was just because
well i'm a procrastinator at heart and
if i have
a deadline if i force myself into one by
verbalizing hey i'm gonna get this stuff
done guys
then it tricks my mind into being super
productive as i cram to get it all in in
time you know
and uh yeah it's been working we've been
getting lots of stuff done around
our world here the nexus got finished
super spelter revamped
we've been working like crazy on our
nether tunnels and
before i started recording this episode
i went and i revamped another
2000 blocks of our nether tunnels i kept
the same design but i redid the floor so
that we have the blue ice
and yeah so check it out here it looks
almost exactly the same except the floor
is a little bit different and we got the
blue ice down the center so we can
travel
much much faster which is great for
getting around
a lot of people are wondering why i use
power rails instead of regular
rails down the middle to stop the mobs
from spawning it's just because like if
i ever want to hook up minecarts to go
down here i don't have to rip out all
the rails and put power rails in
i just have to hook up some redstone to
power these and hopefully for
episode 550 i'll also find some place to
host my world download so that you guys
will be able to check it out
and one of the things i want to do this
time around is just make it easier for
you guys to find
stuff around the world because i know
when you see it in the
episodes it can be hard to understand
how it all connects together
because i cut and skip skip places right
i don't travel to them usually on video
it takes too long
so maybe uh one idea i had was to do
something like this this is the north
branch of the nether hub here so i got
i got north at the top here and then on
the zed coordinates
minus 374
the first one here is the mesa mining we
have to turn left to get there
and the dreary build and this kind of
just shows you
what's down this path is that a good way
of doing it maybe you guys have a better
idea i was also thinking maybe using the
lodestones and having those in a chest
near here
now i should probably mention this as
well last episode i teased the idea of
doing some kind of teleportation system
um it looks like it's been patched out
of the game now it was in the game for
many years but it doesn't seem to work
anymore you used to be able to throw an
ender pearl through
a nether portal it would go through and
land
in the overworld it would like actually
load the chunks
and land and then you would teleport
um the coordinates in the over world
like if you're in the nether
that would multiply your coordinates by
eight times basically or if you did it
the other way over
world to nether it would divide them by
eight and you could get back to spawn
quickly that way
and so i was hoping to set up a system
to precisely control
where the ender pearls would go but it
looks like it's not going to be possible
now
unfortunately
still rains underground i'm getting a
little worried they're not going to fix
this bug before
they're done with the update you know so
lately i've been going through some of
our older projects and just figuring out
what works and what doesn't
what needs to be fixed um and i found
out
surprisingly this very first gold farm
we did
actually still works the the one that
sends them through the nether portal to
here and then we got the crusher
and stuff and then we got the trader guy
over here it's a little bit hard to
set it up so that they go through the
portal though because we got to disable
all the other portals
uh in our world basically uh but yeah it
does work
actually so that's kind of cool um
i noticed this guy has a trade for four
redstone
per emerald old school guy here
that's kind of cool i want to set up a
brewing stand so he can restock but i
can't get in there
all right i thought i could elytra down
let's uh maybe just put it over here
put a brewing stand you guys are okay
with me trading the zombie flesh
infinitely um i found out
you can't trade redstone infinitely with
him
now that he's restocked like it was
great out there you saw that
originally but now that he's restocked
it seems to be infinite
which is the first guy i found able to
do that in my world here
so can i use that
i don't know like redstone's one of
those items i always struggle to get and
uh
this guy might be the answer anyways
let's get to it here i got three fairly
big
projects in mind for this episode and
hopefully we can get to all of them
so by the nexus here this is an area we
frequent quite a bit
uh something we don't see as often
though is the guardian farms just right
over here i see it
myself a lot but i don't show it in
videos a lot
it kind of always bothered me that i
never finished this it's got the stone
walls still
this looks super boring and plain so i
think today we're gonna focus on
making this a bit nicer we have some
creeper blasts here that i never fixed
then there's a there's a lot of work to
do here
also if you cover guardian farms like
the water
it increases the spawn rate i thought it
was just a little bit but i checked the
wiki page
apparently it's 95 more efficient
uh it doesn't mean we're going to get 95
more guardians because like
um there's no mobs spawning in caves
near here so
it's it's just going to fail a little
bit less so it'll help out a bit
okay so here's the deal we built this a
long time ago and
i didn't plan stuff out super well back
then or choose block
pellets or anything back then really so
everything is built out of light blue
glass the floor
the walls everything light blue glass
and we're not going to be removing this
because it's
very difficult to remove glass in this
game very time consuming so instead
we're going to pick colors that work
well with
it um so i'm thinking we're gonna go for
the new warped wood
might be cool like the strip kind
and then probably shroom lights for
orange as a contrasting color
kind of like the guardian color scheme
right they got the blue and the orange
on
all right there was a system here for
picking up uh
ink drops from squid but squid don't
spawn in this farm anymore so we're just
going to remove that
yup yup this workbook looks pretty good
i think so we're going to be using that
for sure
and probably we'll mix prismarine with
it as well now here's the thing
we don't have to worry about mobs
spawning on this glass here but even
during the day time we're gonna get
slime
spawning down here this passes through
some slime chunks
so we gotta stop stuff from spawning
here
so we're gonna slab over this and i
think this is where our prismarine is
gonna come in
so i was thinking we'll go up a slab
and then we'll have the workbook it's a
little bit lighter i think
and then we'll go we'll kind of
transition we'll go
this and then we'll go a row of this and
then another row of this and then
another row of this
and then maybe we'll go back to dark
over here and then super dark and then
lighter dark and then back to this
and just do a bunch of rings around here
yeah i don't know about this one guys i
don't know like sometimes when i'm
building i'm super confident in what i'm
doing and this time it's like
well might be okay
all right everybody so i think it's
about time we get started on our
second project of this episode we're
gonna be making a farm for the worked
wood and the crimson wood
shroom lights that kind of stuff we
haven't done that yet
and i am tired of farming that stuff
manually now i know there's ways of
making totally automated
versions of these farms they usually
require quite a bit of redstone and i
thought it might be nice to do a simple
one to get us started
like a simple effective one especially
for those of you that don't
like doing redstone projects um
so here's what we're gonna be doing
we're gonna have a space of seven
between the two sides here
and then just have two rows of
netherrack then we're gonna take our
bone meal and use it to start spreading
this nylon down the rows
so that we can plant the fungi on top of
it for growing the trees these things
here
um down the middle we're going to place
obsidian
one block above the netherrack and every
five blocks so a four block space
between the two this is what the tnt is
going to land on to blow up the trees
and harvest them
so this first layer of obsidian that the
tnt lands on will get
most of the wood from the trees but
shroom lights tend to spawn a little bit
higher up so we probably want to go at
least two layers
up with the obsidian so we're gonna have
a three block space and then at the
fourth block here
is where we're gonna do our next thing
of obsidian and that's gonna be placed
somewhere in between the two
all right and then we're gonna start a
third row with the netherrack
and i'm using the dirt there just the
scaffolding uh
but you can see all the spaces in the
netherrack line up with the obsidian
below
right so we do that and then uh we want
enough space between the netherrack and
the obsidian that's
the tnt is not going to blow up our
dispensers so
i'm hoping this is enough we got one two
three four five six seven eight nine
at the tenth block here is where i got
the netherrack we'll see if that works
or not
but i'm gonna go underneath now and
start placing our dispensers facing down
this is where the tnt is gonna go in
okay so i got a fair bit of tnt on hand
so i'll probably put a full stack of tnt
in each of these as we go along
uh now the important thing is when they
shoot out of the dispenser they don't go
perfectly straight down they'll go a
little bit to the left or the right or
forward or back and they might not land
on the obsidian
properly if that happens so we put
blocks around
the dispensers one block below here just
to make sure
it's going to hit one of the edges of
these blocks and align perfectly
straight
if we want to get a little bit more
fancy with this farm we can also add
water down the middle and then
one two three four five six seven eight
blocks
on both sides and then we'll have a drop
down
and i'm gonna go along here with our our
pick and break and all
that'll function as a very simple item
collection system to our farm
and now i think we're ready to get it
going here so let's go along and start
bone mealing
our first batch of trees and we'll find
out how much of this i messed up
very good very good so we got our first
batch of trees grown here and this is
what it ended up looking like and you
can see some of the trees get very tall
actually but most of them are about at
this level
here that's like the average um
unfortunately it does
kill all the nilium under underneath if
you have blocks above so
the slower we go here the more of it
will die but i
i just want to show you some stuff
before we start blasting
so you can see some of it will reach up
to this block
uh but none of it seems to get to the
very middle here so that seven block
space in between is very important
because if that netherwart spawned
underneath the dispensers then the tnt
will land right on it
and then blow up our platform up there
and
i think the way we're gonna activate
this like we could set up some redstone
but i think the idea with this farm
is to keep it as simple as possible for
you guys
so this is what we're gonna do it's very
low tech but we're gonna be using
pressure plates to activate
the dispensers and ourselves as the
timer for this farm
why do we need a timer what is going on
here let me tell you
one other thing about this so let's say
tnt lands on this obsidian and then tnt
lands on this one and this one blows up
first uh it's gonna push the tnt on this
one
over away from this one and that might
cause it to
fall off of here or just move over a
little bit and start blowing up stuff we
don't want it to like this netherrack
so we got to kind of control when this
stuff gets released
and we're going to use ourselves to do
that so the trick is we're actually just
going to hold shift to slow ourselves
down and by the time we go from this
pressure plate to the next one over
uh this tnt is going to be exploded
hopefully
we can kind of just go unfortunately we
can't see the farm working though
just gonna look back and make
[Music]
yeah this sure not blowing up so i think
we have enough space in between that's
good
let's keep going here all the way to the
end
okay here we go we made it to the very
end let's go see the damage down there
yeah see the stuff falling in the water
going over the edges
cool cool and you can see we took out a
pretty good chunk of the
the wood and the nether wharton stuff
none of the netherrack got exploded
that's great
some of it's going to land on the
netherrack there
uh it'll fall down if we grow another
tree though
and i did a really crummy collection
system
looks like some of it's getting stuck so
probably gonna make something a bit
fancier
okay there was none on this other side
so it's it's not too bad
all right so then all of our drops got
collected together over here and let's
see the grand total from one harvest
okay lots of netherwart blocks and
not as much as i would have expected
honestly three
okay okay and 27 shroom lights
i wonder if much of it got exploded i
hope not
it might be worth just going across here
and picking it up too then because i'm
sure there's a bit here
okay wait a sec did i take it out of
here
no that that was still in there so there
was a lot on the nether rack actually
there was one two three
just about four stacks of wood all right
good stuff so i did a few harvests there
and we got a bunch of warp stems to work
with
so we're back at the guardian farm again
now we got the materials to
to work on this um i think i was getting
like 3.5 wood per tree which isn't bad
but we weren't getting a whole lot of
shroom lights i was a little
disappointed with that honestly
so yeah it's it's not going to be like a
long-term solution for sure
um we can convert that over to like an
acacia farm or something though like if
we replace the netherrack with
soil and grow like birch trees acacia
trees oak trees
and then when we get to the top here
what are we gonna do i think we're gonna
go down the center let's get our silk
touch
then we're gonna build this back up to
the top with shroom lights down the
center of the column
and yeah check it out so that gives us a
very simple column here but
i think it's what we're gonna go with
simple is good though because we're
going large scale with this so
um we want something that's easy to
produce
and it's got a bit of 3d depth to it i
like that it gives off light
it's another plus to it so i think
that's the style we're going to go for
so that's going to go up
it's going to go around each of these
edges all the way over here and we're
going to make like a cube out of it
and then probably we'll do it on this
side as well but let's just do this
interior part first
oh and also uh we're gonna use it to
make like a border
um like over here i think
yeah and it'll connect like at the
bottom here from from the side to that
side
does anybody out there still use sand as
scaffolding or is it
is it just me i kind of like it still
it's cool aha all right so
added a bit more detail to it we got
some lines running through it
um just for a bit more character
and had a bit of a base to it and this
also connects all the way down to the
bottom now too
now i'm working on the top here and a
guardian shot me off
but i think we're gonna have it one
block above the water yeah look at this
guy he's trying to get me already come
on man i just got up here
they hit hard too i guess at the top
here we got to replace this glass with
shroom lights
all the way down and then we'll have
another beam going across the water
question mark yeah and then we'll have
to fill this in with something
all this poor llama that guy pushed him
off like 10 minutes ago and he's still
bouncing around
it is a bit on the plane side still but
i think we can add a bit more to it
over time i i think it does look a lot
better than what we had originally here
though with just the glass uh
still not quite finished with our design
down here i think the thing that's kind
of
making me wonder about is maybe i should
get rid of the dark spot in the middle
maybe keep it all
right but it kind of reminds me of a rug
the more i look at it
east persian rug oh yeah look at that
okay let's go check out
huh huh let's go let's go check out our
guardian farm down here
this is where we actually go to get our
stuff um
but we were totally out of prison marine
for a long time here and let's see
okay so while building that we got like
a double chest pool
cool cool all right that should be
enough to do a bit more here
yeah so i think next up here we're going
to try add in some prismarine walls for
a bit
a bit more detail to it i feel like they
would look cool if we added them all
along
the sides it's pretty close in color
and then maybe we do some kind of at the
top there
no aha so check it out we got a woohoo
so i don't want to cover up too much of
the glass because again the point is we
want to be able to see the guardians in
the farm right but i think having just a
little down the top there's fine
so i mentioned we used to get squid
spawning in our guardian farm and we
don't anymore and i just checked we're
down to our final like chest of ink
sacks
so we're gonna run out pretty soon in
our world here
we're gonna have to add that to our list
of things to do we need a either a
wither rose farm or another squid farm
built soon
all right everybody well we did a bunch
more building here and used up all that
warped wood we harvested and all the
shroom lights
um it's probably a good stopping point
for this project today because there's
many more hours left to go on it
but uh yeah i think we got the center
thing completely done
unless we want to add more details to
the
columns or something but yeah i think
it's good did the prismarine on all four
sides
um got the shroom lights all in we
finished up the rug
down here and even filled in the little
space we have there was all stone before
uh
and then on the top we did cover that up
too just made like a
giant target kind of kind of strange
and then we got started on one of the
sides here still
trying to figure out what we're gonna do
exactly i feel like
like i tried doing one of these columns
i feel like this needs to be
wider like maybe instead of a three
block like a three by three maybe a five
by five would be
better since the sides longer as far as
what we're gonna do on the four sides
here i'm not
quite sure i'm open to suggestions but i
was thinking maybe
we do some enormous kelp farm like if we
fill this up all the way i think each
side's 64 blocks
long so that would be like 256 kelp
plants we could squeeze into here if we
wanted
and then it would kind of mirror like
what we have on this side we'd have the
glass in the water on this side as well
also i'm not sure should we add more
columns like part way down here or do
you think
just two in the corners is enough to
support it and probably the most
important view here is a distance view
because most of the time we're just
gonna fly by this thing it's very rare
we're actually gonna go down
um down there to check it out
okay so next up here we got a bit of an
errand to run we gotta get some fuel for
a couple of our smelting things so stop
by the bamboozler let's get this thing
fired up
and just see how long it takes we got to
fill up three shockers of bamboo
i got a little bit on me let's get it
going
all right stand here and uh
it takes a little bit of time doesn't it
not bad
not bad okay first off here we gotta
head over to the blacksmith building and
refuel our purper smelter this thing
over here i
i realized it was out of coal and uh
it's been backing up so that's not good
you get the bamboo in here i guess it's
only a single chest i thought it was a
double chest here
uh-oh um and it was uh between 30 and 35
seconds per shulker i just to fill up
at the bamboozler all right let's make
it a double chest the other thing we
gotta refill here is over at our gold
farm
the golden sword smelter
you know when i first did this i just
did it to appease you guys because you
kept suggesting it i was like okay i
kind of rolled my eyes it's like that's
not gonna produce any gold you know
uh smelting down the golden swords but
actually you know you get a fair amount
it's like
maybe five to ten percent boost to the
the gold farm if you smelt down the
golden swords and the third big project
i wanted to get to today is the piglet
bartering system we started last episode
i think we're gonna wait on this though
because we're kind of out of time
and mojang changed the bartering
trades uh with this latest update
so i kind of want to wait one more week
just to see if they change it again
because i feel like there's a couple
things they could tweak on it
uh maybe let's talk about the bartering
for a for a second here i'm kind of
curious what you guys think about it if
there's anything you like or don't like
about it
i'll kind of go through what i like and
what's changed here
so they got rid of the glowstone trade
that's no more and they also got rid of
the magma cream
that's no more instead they put in
spectral arrows and
black stone actually let's put these
here and blackstone over here
a couple other things also changed with
the bartering they added water bottles
as one of the trade items
along with fire resistant potions i like
the water bottle edition but i feel like
they should get rid of the fire
resistance
so that's like if you sort the potions
you'll end up with just water bottles
this way you'll get them both mixed
together and i don't really like that
personally and they also greatly reduce
the amount of items you get
with the bartering which i think is good
because it would seem pretty overpowered
they cut a lot of things in half uh-huh
so overall i would say i do
really like the bartering system in the
game i think it's a great addition
um i think it's a cool cool mechanic for
these new mobs
uh i like that they gave gold more of a
use in the game before it was pretty
much just for power rails and
and food but now it actually
is something pretty useful now i've
heard a lot of people say
bartering is overpowered and it is to an
extent
but i feel like it's a good bounce
for most things um if you compare it to
something like villager trading villager
trading is just
insanely broken you can buy like
diamond tools armor enchanted books
whatever you choose for one emerald each
and it's like
holy smokes and then the variety of
items is just insane with that
it pretty much covers everything in the
game while this it's more
just a few general items and a lot of
like weird items that you wouldn't
normally get like
the fire charges for example
very rarely would you ever craft that
right it's kind of a cool item in the
game
but people don't really use it but if
you get it for free from bartering
if you just get it people will start
using it in fun ways i'm sure
um same with spectra arrows they're a
cool item in the game but people didn't
really craft them because it's like four
glowstone
for two arrows nobody wants to do that
right but if you just get it you're
gonna
use it and not feel bad about it so
we're gonna play a little game here
we're gonna play
guess which item old etho thinks is the
biggest mistake to the bartering system
which one needs to be removed more than
any of them
you know you know what it is it is
actually leather
i think this is a huge huge mistake it
needs to be removed from bartering
um so i feel like they shouldn't add
things
that will take away from other aspects
of the game and i feel like this removes
the need to make cow farms
in the game cows are pretty much only
good for
food and leather right and food you can
get from a million other places so
leather is their specialty
and guess what you can also get leather
from hoglands and many other places
the thing is leather also has very few
uses in the game
bookshelves books you know maybe
item frames guess what you can buy all
of those from villagers
but overall i would say most items you
get from bartering are pretty great
actually
i think everybody likes getting gravel
from it crying obsidian is a cool one
these two i like i love that they added
blackstone actually
i think that's great because the other
way you're gonna get is by grinding it
out which isn't always fun when you're
doing a big project
um this one's kind of okay too i don't
mind that
i think the controversial ones are ender
pearls because that kind of removes the
need for enderman farm but
it's also more of a convenience thing um
and you'll still probably make enderman
farms for
xp uh same with the nuggets you know
that might remove the need for
iron golem farms but not actually
because you won't get enough iron this
way i don't think
uh string it kind of removes the need
for cave spiders but
you know you always need string for wool
or something
so like you'll use that up i'm sure and
obsidian there was a way of farming it
by spawning in the end platform
breaking it and respawning it in so that
kind of removes the need to make those
kind of farms uh but overall i don't
think anybody likes mining obsidian
really
so not gonna complain about that one
either um
quartz is an interesting one it kind of
removes the need to go quartz mining in
the nether
it's not an activity i ever liked myself
so i don't mind that personally
there is something very interesting
about the quartz trade as well that i
think a lot of people didn't realize
uh it's a way to generate like diorite
granite and
andesite you guys remember this trade
nobody does it because it's like such a
waste but if you're getting
you're just getting quartz i think
people will start doing this and then
like andesite is actually a block people
use quite a bit
so for two quarts you can get four
andesite anyways
sorry about that i did a bit of a ramble
there but let's do a quick
comment of the day to finish up it says
hey etho so in 1.16 wither skeletons are
aggravated by piglins right
well couldn't you use this for a wither
skeleton skull
farm and also have an infinite source of
coal
um so yes no
and yes so unfortunately you can't get
skulls this way you have to actually
kill the wither skeletons as a player
kill
that means you have to kill them or you
can also use your wolves
to automatically kill them that's like
the main way people do it i think
uh-huh but otherwise it's a good idea if
you want coal or
or bones or something uh-huh
anyways hopefully you guys enjoyed
today's episode thank you for watching
and until the next one take care have a
good day
bye