[Music]
hello everybody this is etho
and i think you know what's going on
here
i need more mindless activities i can do
in my world here so that i can talk
because grinding
enderman gets boring quickly but anyway
just a short intro for today's episode
we're going to be doing something
strange
something a little out of the ordinary
it's been done before but not
not often we're going to go visit
another world of mine one i've
spent many hours working on and that
i've talked about a
fair bit but you've never seen it
can you figure out what i'm talking
about from those clues well
if not i'll give you a few more
uh as you know i'm a big fan of vex and
the super
hostile series he's made i've played
through
canopy carnage legendary spellbound
caves
we're playing kaizo cavern right now
in the huge series and they're a lot of
fun i like the challenge
ctm map stands for capture the monuments
and the goal is to collect
16 colors of wool and put them
on the final victory monument that's how
you complete the game
and the wall is very difficult to get
those scattered throughout the world you
have to find it
and plow through countless mobs to get
it
in dangers and that's what makes it fun
so sometime around the middle
of me playing legendary i got into my
head that i want to make a
super hostile based map as well a ctn
map
because i enjoyed them so much and with
no
prior experience with map making or mc
edit experience
or just general large scale
project experience in minecraft i
decided to work on one
and it was a it's been a great learning
experience
but thinking about it today i want to
get back into map making again
and i realized working on the ctn map
again
is probably just going to be a waste of
time i don't think
i would ever get it finished even if i
put a lot
of hours into it uh and i just don't
want it to go to waste so we're gonna
see it today and i'll
take you through it basically there's a
few things about the ctm style i don't
enjoy
in map making uh exploration is kind of
a big part of them
which requires you know making
interesting terrain and that that's
something i have no
skill for whatsoever so
i don't really want to get into that and
well you'll you'll understand once you
see the map let's let's go check it out
it's going to be fun i've been excited
to show you guys this
so here we go
oh man here we are in the cpm map
uh this is a spawn area where you start
out
i never did name it so i'll just keep
calling it ctm map
uh throughout this and we'll probably
i'll probably take you through the map
uh show you some cool things i like
about it and
just general general commentary
things i like don't like whatever a
little bit more background about why
the decision to not
or to discontinue that's going to say
not continue this discontinued
the decision to discontinue this came
from
i got a new map plan a new style map i
want to make
as i was building this i kind of
realized my favorite parts
of map making is setting up situations
for the player you know setting up traps
and mechanisms and that type of thing
not really the whole
building or making terrain or that type
of thing
that's not what i found fun i like the
the mechanisms
so the new map style i have will take
advantage of that
it'll mostly just be setting up
mechanisms and stuff
um and also while i was building this
a lot of patches came out a lot of
changes were made
interestingly yeah
one of the patches that came out made
these fall off and now
now it's back again where they can stay
on mob eggs came out
that's a huge thing kind of removes the
need for
spawners because you can control how
many mobs yet which is huge
with my setup in this map i was relying
on natural spawns and
and mobs from spawners mostly
and it made setting up mechanisms very
challenging
to do it with spawners compared to eggs
you know
uh we got lamps we got upside down
stairs
and slabs we can make things look better
now
and just just a lot has changed i made
this
before anvil as well
but yeah enough docking let's get into
this this is gonna be
cool so you start in this room this is
to mimic
uh an interrogation room as you might
have guessed
um a little bit of story here when you
get in
sit down and stop screaming one of
spazz's most esteemed torture
interrogators will be here shortly to
greet you
spaz is very curious as to why you
entered his world
your bravery is commendable but negated
by your stupidity
all humans should know that you are no
match for him
so you start in this interrogation room
and uh
captured by spazz's men and these guys
are just kind of
watching you which is pretty creepy
when you're ready to go you hit this
button i don't know if this is going to
work still
sounds like it and after a certain
amount of time
you might wander around here a bit
this is one of the reasons i want mob
eggs because this thing
can take any amount of time
there we go finally because that relies
on a spawner and
oh yeah mob ai changed too so that guy's
not even coming after us anymore
although i'm in creative mode that
doesn't help
uh you go through here well what your
options are to either
bust through this glass and try get that
chest there
which is not recommended or go out this
way
then there's some more hints pro tip you
may eat oh no
this is a survival map resources are
limited you are allowed to harvest any
blocks that you wish to
obviously this means you can also this
means you may also
break any blocks and pro tip you may
even steal torches you find
so this is the first trap in the map
really if you try to take these torches
haha you're dead
um this is kind of like a prison
uh if these guys killed you you would
end up in your cell otherwise you're
just outside of the cells
and there's lots of these guys trapped
here
you can tell a lot lots of
a lot of parts of the map are not
complete um
i'm actually just going to go ahead and
sleep here's an overview
of what i've got done as you can see
there's no terrain
i have no idea how it would get this
underground because this is supposed to
be underground
as far as i know there's like no fill
features in mcedit that would
make that easy all right
let's get back down those are the prison
uh storage room i don't think i ever
finished
nope um
um beating rooms
there's gonna be none of the chests have
anything in it i was gonna wait till the
map was
done before i put items in the chest
because
i was gonna bounce around you know
once all the natural mob spotting rates
were figured out and all
everything was figured out then i would
put items into
just the difficulty that way
there's a lot of mobs around here we're
going to switch them off for a sec
meeting room a one of these is a trap
it's this one
and that wouldn't really do much i would
just told you in this room
you'd have to fight the zombies uh
there's another one
here which is not a trap
oh yeah another big change that occurred
was you can break
blocks a lot quicker with your pick or
you know certain certain blocks quicker
with your axe that that patch came out
so you can break spawners really quickly
now which really has a big effect on
things
this is just for fun
anyway you find your way through the
little bit of a maze here
takes you to this room this is my
favorite room that i made
there's some spawners here are we on
yeah
just for fun underneath is lava which
lowers the spawn rates
because at this point you won't really
have any gear
and you might reckon that recognize this
from
the good prank i don't think i put
anything in the chest
oh i did paintings temporarily
if you go this way this takes you to
interrogation room
it's kind of cool this was supposed to
be
like i think i was going to put some
iron armor in here
a little bit maybe some food oh
that's that room and then
this room's a this one's pretty big
there's uh there's a spawner up there
which will either spawn them on the
bridge
or they'll fall down here
there was skeleton spawners up here
which will constantly shoot at you
until you take them out you can go
through these doors
there's oh this this got triggered
go up through here go up here to these
and then there's a chest here as well
which is empty
um there's a tnt
cannon there which explodes around here
i can't remember if it's set up or not
there's a hidden chest down there
[Music]
so you can see there's there's quite a
few mobs in here it would be very
difficult to
balance the amount i wanted using
natural
mob spawns because
you know it all depends on how much you
land you have out there how many dark
spots you have around the area
but this is way too many also you get
enderman
with natural spawns which can wreck
things
um let's see
so those guys fall down they can fall in
the water and come get you
they'll spawn indefinitely in these
pillars
there's uh spider spawners as well
if you go up the stairs here you kind of
get distracted by the creeper face
and that pops down which is
empty but we can put
arrows or i think even
i'm going to try a splash potion when i
made this
uh splash potions would only get shot
like one block out of dispensers now
in one of the patches that was changed i
want to see if it will hit me
oh it does that's cool so i could have
put a damage potion or something in
there now
but we will put arrows in
i can find them
come on
there there
okay so this is this is the effect
kind of cool got a couple of those
there's they're there on the other side
as well
so i really like this room i think it
looks cool uh
took a very long time to make because i
pretty much
did it block by block although
i only built half the room and then i i
duplicate it to the other side
basically um
very cool view from up here if you have
to go back for some reason you can jump
off into the water
nice
all right
so then you get up to this point and you
guys might recognize this room i showed
it in one video
i really like this room too it looks
cool this is an intersection
again there's just tons of mobs around
because it's not balanced
this is the first wood you would see
give you
one piece which you can't really do
anything with
a lot of people were wondering about
this trap obviously it's a trap
but how does it work well if you
break this wood block or you can break
the sand or the gravel
and then that happens
there's a chest down here
aha i bet you didn't expect that
[Music]
aha yeah so it was kind of like a fake
out but actually a trap
you know you think it's a trap at first
then oh there's goodies down there you
hop in the hole
and then yeah it actually is a trap type
thing
uh over here this this wasn't really
bounced the way i did this there's uh
this path here leads to trees to get
wood
and then that was supposed to lead to
the first wall the white one
and that was supposed to lead to the
outside world
upstairs
uh we'll go over here
this is one of the first areas i made
i'm not overly happy with it
and for some reason that's triggered
okay uh you come to this window and it's
you see trees which you need
oh that's what's wrong
there we go so
then creepers start falling down but you
have to get in there to get your
to get wood you know to get saplings
longer you wait to go in the more
creepers
will fill up the room they fall in from
up there
although that was changed slightly
somehow
so that's kind of like uh what you have
to do to get the wood in this map
but there's still no stone
uh this over here is the first wall
this beginning is a little bit of a mess
blaze spawner here
there's a player sensor that makes those
trapdoors open and close and go
chaotic like that
um this was an idea i was playing around
with there is
an end portal there the idea is
[Music]
if you find an ender eye hidden in the
map
it'll make going through here a little
bit easier
if you put it in there
right there
right now you got four blades or four
zombie spawners up there
if you put that in
the tnt goes off
and i get sort of that uh i also had it
set up so if you break this
it'll trigger a trap because i had it
set up so
[Music]
the way it works is it uses a bud switch
to to detect
uh you placing the ender ion but uh i
thought if someone was to destroy it it
would do the same effect
so we need a a way of determining if
an eye was placed in or if uh it was
actually destroyed
so it can it can sense both but later i
realized that you can't actually destroy
ender portals i thought you could for
some reason so that is uh
pointless
go through here at this point of making
the map i was just kind of a little bit
i wanted to get a lot done so i just
copied this room
over and over and over again and kind of
made like a maze out of it
and you go through each area
doing that and these would be full of
mobs
and these rooms are not set up they're
supposed to be
mob spawners in each one this here
is an idea i had for
special stations that will heal you or
give you a speed increase or strength
if you walk into it you get a a speed
potion
because this area is pretty big i want
the player to be able to get through it
really quick
it's challenging making
something like this though because you
don't want the player to get the potions
which is only possible if you do a three
by three thing of bedrock around
a dispenser because if you
if you have bedrock like that for
example if
they set off a tnt here it can pass
through a block
diagonally and blow up the dispenser
and they could get potions that way so
if you're if you got a lot of mob eggs
or a lot of potions somewhere you have
to make sure the player can't get it
which is a real challenge
oh i got something my throat i'll be
right back
all right that's better i had a little
bit of a drink here let's continue
there's not a whole lot more left to
show but
but yeah this first area was going to be
kind of like a maze
although you could easily figure out
places you've been if the door is down
like this
and each of these rooms is going to be
customized a little bit
different spawners different amounts of
spawners and
you know some might have laven or water
but i never got to that point
these doors are actually really simple
i like them a lot though it's just
pressing the button updates the sand
which makes it fall
that's all there is to it i like it
so yeah the idea is they would run
through this pretty quick
and fight all the mobs i see on the way
and there might be some healing stations
throughout
just to help them moving quick help them
move quicker
some of the dead end rooms might have
chests in
but
you can see you could get lost pretty
easily just because it's so
so massive and it kind of loops back too
so if you
go one way you might end up back at the
beginning
this here is a little bit of a
oh it's triggered
uh-oh
yeah triggered already uh when i did
the restore i didn't delete the folder
so i think some of this stuff
is messed up
let's see if there's more than one nope
well this
too bad uh there was a a gas station
here
and this door was up so when you got to
the door
you since it's a long
long hallway here you might have thought
this was the end
or the destination you were looking for
but uh when you open the door falls down
[Music]
you get that
[Applause]
supposed to scare the player
but uh yeah not the best demonstration
there because it's already
activated
but anyway um i guess we'll just cheat
here
this is the maze again
this is the room we're looking for this
one here
i kind of graphed this out on paper
first and just
play connect the dots and that's how i
came up with the pattern
let's go to this one we'll switch it
back to peaceful
oh and this is trigger two dang it
uh i should have just deleted the folder
basically
there's a sand door here too i actually
think it was at this level
and there was a lever in the middle when
you pulled the lever
it caused the sand to fall down this
hole
to here
we'll just mimic it
and if the sand in the corner falls
in the corner here does this
kind of cool way of making a staircase
for the player to get down
and the sand would land like this so it
would have been flat
and then this was going to be the wall
room area
uh there's going to be by this point in
the game
uh ma biggs came out and i was going to
set up an ambush here
for the player and the wall room
pretty close to over there first wall
but that's about as far as i got so you
could imagine
i've spent oh probably at least 10 hours
on this map
and i didn't even get the first wall
down so that's like
not even 1 16 of the map done
no terrain was made so to actually
complete the map probably would have
taken me
well over 200 hours or so
and i just don't want to put that kind
of time into it
and again like i said there's a
different map style i'd rather do that i
think i could actually finish and would
be a lot more fun
for myself and the player
so that's what i'm going to do and
with the new map style i plan on
streaming it on twitch tv when i work on
it
instead of having it all secret because
once you know the traps in this it kind
of
takes away from it with the new map
style i'm going for i want it to be
maybe replayable you know not
necessarily
knowing where the traps is is the main
part of the game it's just
learning how to deal with them is the
main part of the game i guess
i don't it will make more sense in the
future
i also started working on a victory
monument area i was going to do
a bud switch style one
it's kind of the shape i came up with
for the 16 wool
set 16 3 6 12
and 7
19 so 16 wall plus the iron gold and
diamond block that's what it's for
i got one of these set up just to try it
make sure it works
that would trigger a light or a note
block or something some visual indicator
that
you you got the wool placed
um something you guys might find
interesting i'm sure most people know
this uh you can actually hack
potions with in editors
a normal speed to splash potion
lasts for oh
you can also make them stack like that
it usually lasts for one minute and
seven seconds but you can
add an extended factor to it so it's
actually three minutes
which is kind of cool so you normally in
the game you can
you either only get extended or you know
tier two
but if you hack it you can get tier two
and extended
combined which is cool and this was just
a little
experiment i was doing
um whoa whoa whoa
get back up
glass i thought one of these had there
it is
uh you can put other entities in these
spawn eggs
and in one point in the game you could
uh
like shoot tnt off that instantly
explodes for example
but that was later taken out and now
just shoots nothing
or you could spawn boats that way or
mine carts from eggs
but yeah
that's the map
i hope you enjoyed it um
not necessarily going to scrap this i
might take some of the rooms and use it
in future projects
but i would rather just start fresh
something new that i want to work on
so that's what we're gonna do
so i hope you guys enjoyed today's fun
little detour there
checking out the map um
to me it's not really sad saying goodbye
or
or putting it aside anyway uh i'm not
the type of person that clings to things
i'm a little worried though that some
people might
be disappointed as they were looking
forward to
playing it i know but
i just think my efforts would be better
spent making
a simpler map that's more fun
as i guess the way i would say it the
the new map idea i have is to kind of
make like a dungeon
style game where you have uh
mobs spawning specific specific number
of mobs spawning from
mob eggs and
as you go through the dungeon you get
different loot and
gets more challenging as you progress
further
type thing and there'd be traps hidden
and that's the type of map i would
rather make
instead of you know focusing on
making something that's fun to explore
and
the way i had that that ctm map setup
wasn't very good it was
there's too many traps i i was having
too much fun
adding them and it would would have been
overwhelming to the player i think
to have all that going on constantly and
that's also
what was making it take so long to build
but uh next made a really good point in
one of his videos that it's a lot easier
to
work with negative space than it is with
positive space so
to start with a big lump of land and
then take away
from it to make your map instead of
starting from nothing and building
from scratch your map it's a lot easier
to work
with negative space and i made the
mistake of going with positive
space because pretty much everything you
saw there was
place block by block which is no way
to make a map a big map
but anyway i rambled enough for today i
will say goodbye thank you for
watching everybody and i will see you
again
next time
of course four in a row
you