good readings everyone this is etho and
welcome back to another episode we are
we're going to head on over to the
nether to start off with today I have
been working on the track system there's
a zombie pigman in there this is a
little risky we still haven't solved
this problem if I enter pearl into him
we're in trouble here
whew now we solved it holy smokes like I
hit me for six hearts that was dangerous
so yeah we're going to go to the nether
and we're going to work on the rail line
well I'll show you where where we're at
with it at this point in time I have
been working on it here and there and
right now I'm like trying to figure out
how I'm going to do the inside of its
like let's try this out I tried a a wild
style here with a bunch of plants and
craziness and then there's also just a
straight-up lever thing here the way I
originally was going to do it I don't
think is going to really work originally
I was just going to have a bunch of the
bunch of half slabs like this but the
thing is we got to power these these
tracks somehow and I could do detector
rails but then when we get to like a I
switch like this we can't have detector
rails here really the mess up the
junction so ideally I would like you to
work with just regular tracks and power
it some some way like with levers
I've also redone the top part and I kind
of like this we got these like beams
going across now pretty cool we still
have our lookouts through the iron bars
and if we go outside it looks relatively
decent too
um walk faster so slow so sand doesn't
help either all right so this is what it
looks like from the outside oh hey guy
how you doing tonight oh come on I wanna
missed again
Ariel and he died oh we did get it sweet
okay so it looks pretty good from the
outside let's just earliest I'm content
with it you know I could get super fancy
but then the problem is it's going to
take a really long time to build a
tunnel if we do anything too crazy even
this took a long time because there's
this a lot to it if we keep going
further this way we get to another
fortress where I do most of the wither
skull hunting over this way and just
barely see a fortress there that's where
the dual blades farm is in there so
we'll probably have this go this way at
some point then up ahead here I better
save some of these ender pearls or we're
going to run out very quickly and then
this it this is to the stronghold so
this is the first Junction we're going
to work on because this is a really
important place to do and silver fish
farm and all that stuff all right so if
you guys remember the plan is to make an
intelligent track a track where the
carts know where we're going oh yeah and
by the way out of all these styles
they've been trying we're going to go
with this first one I think the main
thing I got to watch out for here is I
got to make sure there's no air spaces
on the left and right of these tracks
and with this it's like stare stare
stare lever stare stare stare both sides
no air spaces if there's air spaces
right next to a track you're going to
get a lot of zombie pigman on your track
and with my setup here there's going to
be at least two blocks beside that won't
be air so you shouldn't get too many
zombie pigman once this is all done even
as it is now I don't get too many but
you know if a car hits a zombie pigman
it's going to cause some trouble
although they wait a minute they
probably avoid it now don't they that is
a that's a good question but yeah what
we're going to do I had this idea to use
a hopper minecarts okay so you get a
minecart and a hopper um these buttons
here these these destination selector
buttons they're going to release one out
of ten unique items so I think we're
going to set up some dispensers here and
each of those will send out a unique
item and hopper minecart will go in
front of us when it goes over item the
dispensers release it's going to pick it
up oh that wasn't too smart that that
card is gone let's do this again
I forgot I got the power to all these
now let's make another one alright give
it a ghast here and we'll make it go
this way but yeah these hopper mine
carts they pick stuff up off the track
all right and then when it goes over
another hopper that matches that item
then it's going to tell the junction to
switch that way and should work out
pretty good
I would think so if we go back here on
this is where our buttons are I figure
we'll use the length of the wire to
trigger the dispensers somehow although
that might be a little tough to do I'm
not sure let's just stick this out and
see where
this is a wire here we should run into
our tunnel somewhere around here there
it is okay so we got one two three four
five six seven eight nine ten ten blocks
here and we'll just mark that okay I'm
gonna do a little bit off-camera here
and try to get this going and then I'll
bring you guys back in oh boy we have a
big problem here
big big problem I kind of made some
assumptions here that I shouldn't have
these hopper mine carts I thought they
worked like normal hoppers like like
they would have similar behavior like if
this went over top this hopper I thought
the items would pass through but it's it
turns out you can tell by my tone it
works okay what the heck I just tried
this and it didn't work
turn it again
I don't know what's going on I swear I
just tried this and it failed not that I
wanted to fail this is good news dude
okay never mind this will work so this
is the idea like we're going to make it
so this hopper will only receive items
of its time like for example if we
wanted it just to take stairs we would
do something like that
in reading no we're good
and then like if you had if you had a
block that didn't match in the in the
carts it won't go through so that's
that's the plan with this and I've
changed the selector panel because this
style wasn't really working for me
the way this one works it's inverted
which means like four of these Pistons
are up right now and only one of them's
down we it's kind of hard to control
dispensers with this setup we can invert
this but it'll get a bit bulkier which
is fine but then the power is going to
come out from the side like we would
have to put our dispensers over here
like what we would have to deal just
I'll just show you real quick here to
get the power out from this thing we
would need
a repeater here hello heard you oh where
are you going crazy repeater okay um not
sure what's going on now um what I'm not
in okay whatever yeah like that and then
to a torch so we'd have to do that for
the whole row and then put our
dispensers here but I kind of want that
out our output to be on the top or the
bottom would be most convenient which
doesn't really work with this setup so
instead we're going to use that other
selector panel I made just recently
animated tutorial on and I got it set up
over here already so with this set up
all the lights are off except the one
that we have selected we're getting a
little bit of lag from this because of
the snapshot the zero seven a there's
lighting issues but if we turn smooth
lighting off it will it runs really
smooth so I'm guessing this will get
fixed in the future patch
oh boy okay more problems bigger
problems
ah I'll be honest with you I thought
that the biggest problem is going to
have with this like the the toughest in
the bureau I thought was going to be
this whole selector panel issue how do
we get a unique item into a hopper and
onto the track in the nether because we
can't use water to move items where we
want really um so I thought this hopper
minecarts idea was the ticket to getting
this all done today
and it is definitely a good idea I would
say so let's just do this real quick
what this is the the wiring for my
selector panel by the way so I can I can
get the input from the top here really
easily and I'm going to have dispensers
with unique items in each of these at
the top and then we have tracks on top
of this so basically when we hit the
button we're going to have another
dispenser somewhere that's going to
dispense hopper minecart onto the track
or release some opera minecart onto the
track and it's going to pick up
whichever of these items gets shot out
so let's try this out we got stone there
but nether acting that one logging that
one one of these oh I put two of those
and that's okay so now if we go down
here and we make a selection only one of
those should shoot outs and the hopper
minecart will only pick up one right so
pick that one and here's the dispenser
go back up we should see the second one
over yeah right there so we selected
this one yep and the hopper minecart
would go by pick that up do a hook
around and then go down to our track
right and then we would get released so
I got my head around that
the next problem I'm having though I
didn't think these hoppers were going to
be such a big issue but they are they're
they're pretty complicated so - let's do
this let's get some power going here
here's one of the big issues I was
having which I think I got figured out
now but you see this like we can hold
the item in there and then only stone
will be able to enter right no because
we can't actually get an item to go in
now because it's locked all right cool
if we lock the one below that if we lock
the one below that we have a new problem
all the items we put in this top one
will go down into that so we won't we
won't be able to detect what or like
prevents like any item that passes over
this hopper at the top we'll just go
down through it and we won't be able to
detect the unique ID of the item right
so I did come up with a solution with
that and I'm going to build it in this
world I was messing around and creative
for about half an hour here trying to
figure this out I'll rebuild it here and
just show you what I had whoo party look
at them all I've never seen this many in
here alright so check it out this is my
solution to the problem I was having
it's like a cutaway of how one of my
hopper junctions would work here so this
all looks good to me like this should
work but it doesn't and I'll tell you
why in just a second and this kind of
shocked me but this is a solution I came
up with for the whole hopper problem we
can use a minecarts storage minecarts
that will bounce back and forth if
there's an item in here so I got this
set up so it'll only hold 22 items so we
can do this like we want this thing is
going to bounce back and forth until
there's 22 left in this hopper
and then it'll stop then if we we can
still add items in from the top
beautiful like it just picked up the one
and it sent a redstone signal which we
use to control this Junction but this is
the kicker this is the problem oh this
is a sad news I got today I thought like
that like they did do some changes with
the hoppers I thought they were all
stable and everything where I'm in oh
seven eighty right now but no we still
have some pretty big inconsistencies
with hoppers so we put three items in
that time before the comparator kicked
in one two three four on the fourth one
that time it they ticked in you can see
this Junction switching at time it went
on one one we wanted to go on one that's
that's what it should do but sometimes I
don't know why
I like it's only sending the signal one
block this is not a user error on my end
this is an error with the programming
there's more than 20 22 items in here
definitely and it's not kicking in an
extra length here still nothing ooh and
it's like if I update it like do a block
update then it checks and finally it'll
go so we might want to hold off on this
until things become more stable now
let's just sleep here and I'll show you
and how it's going to work like an
actual running example of it because it
occasionally I can get it to go this
it's not reliable at the moment so if we
have a hopper minecarts going by let's
just set it up and it has a piece of
stone in it it will be able to pass
through this hopper as it goes by and if
does that the junction switches and it
should go this way I think it picked up
though maybe I think the carts moving
too fast too at the moment so we slow
this down a bit it's pretty delicate
like that's another consistency I would
like to see changed as well that where
it will always pass an item through the
hopper that would be nice sometimes it
does sometimes it doesn't it's more
likely though if we move it back a bit
and another problem I'm going to have
with my setup is the hoppers when you
break a hopper minecart it splits into
two so I can't just like run it into a
cactus - and put it in a hopper or
anything like that all right so let's
let's hope for the best and let's get up
a little higher so we can see this time
all right so come on go the right way
nope uh-oh it's my only minecarts did
the item go out this time no all right
maybe I'll have to mess around with this
some more before I can show it oh there
is that's what we want so that's that's
how this should work
if we do it again though you can see we
don't always have it working
there's inconsistencies it's like it
randomly chooses to update sometimes
this is original setup we had to I
didn't I changed it back to this just to
prove it yeah that time it went
straights and that did not go out so I
think I think this will work
eventually I they just need to make
stuff a little more consistent it seems
I hope they do anyway
and welcome back to the nether again I I
set up the proof of concept for this
thing I'll just show it to you if we go
up here
down there you can see it was up up up
to this dispenser this this has our
hopper minecarts in we'll have to do
something different though because like
I said if we if we try to collect these
hopper mine carts they'll break into a
mine cart and a hopper and we have no
way of putting them back together except
manually so we may have to store the
full mine carts not at the item itself
but we come up here and hopper minecart
gets released we have our dispensers
we're going to try select this one the
one with the women but it it goes around
hooks around to the other side in case
we selected something from the side goes
down and up through there and then this
way so if we try it out if we pick this
middle one we should get a hopper with
one piece of wooden let's go up you're
quick to kitchens and I didn't see it
might happen too quick I'm not sure mmm
okay well there's four in there let's
pick that one next we'll know for sure
that way
Oh dangit really oh what a jerk he burns
this place down I'm gonna be sad out
there and get him from here
now gotta you closer don't oh oh he hit
the sandstone - Wow
man Wow okay I'll have to make a note of
that that area out there is not done yet
so don't worry too much about that and
this is all a mess again put that there
that there and we'll have to make a few
repairs with this oh there's another
stair excellent is that the way it was
probably I can't remember okay what were
we gonna do it's like that one maybe
let's go up and that's all messed up now
I got a piece of wood from it
what no no that can't be right we might
have to make some refinements this why
would it I'm sure we picked that one and
there's still four in here what is going
on Oh
hmm why didn't they pick it up that's
weird
anyway yeah we'll make refinements this
app picked that one up that was weird
we can we don't have to have the
dispensers downward either we can have
it on the side shooting this way as far
as I can tell the hopper mine carts
don't drop items into dispensers or hop
or no they drop in hoppers they don't
drop it into droppers yeah all right
anyway that's enough of this for today
okay I think I know what happened there
actually what happened is the hopper
minecart was getting released before the
items were getting dispensed so the
first time didn't pick up anything
second time it picked up the wood from
the first time and then this third time
and picked up whatever from the second
time and so forth and so on and so yeah
that's the dealio here's a comment I
picked up for today which do you like
better feed the beast
or vanilla hmm well if you think about
it feed the beast really is just vanilla
plus a lot of extra features so beat the
beast I would argue is technically
better but when people play feed the
beast they play with a certain style of
gameplay like all the stuff you do I'm
doing here in this world I could do and
feed the beast as well but when people
play feed the beast they get into
machinery and automating stuff to the
max and all that kind of thing which is
a lot of fun too in vanilla I really
have been enjoying this redstone update
especially all the command blocked
changes and and yeah just really
enjoying redstone a lot lately and I do
like building and all that too you know
but
you can do that in both like I said so
if I had to pick between two I would
probably go for vanilla just because
that's what I'm used to and that's what
you know this that's what this games
about but I enjoy both quite a bit
they're both very unique and they both
are kind of like two different games in
the same game you know so that's going
to be all for today guys I got to
replant this wheat and finish my map oh
yeah they're not flickering now because
I'm in no seven much much better I like
it okay guys have a good one
thanks for watching