[Music]
let's start this episode out right
level 50 on an axe trying to get my good
axe back
uh yes excellent
i can say goodbye to this piece of junk
cool okay so the new patch is out 1.2
um and i figured we should dedicate this
episode to it
i'm not going to go over all the details
of the patch maybe just a few
mostly the ones i'm interested in and
also how they affect my world
here so one thing i was very curious
about is the enderman farm
still very loud i was worried the rates
were going to get cut in half
from the new patch because the height
increased
to twice as much um
so that means the game would have to
check
or have twice as many chances of
cancelling out when placing a mob
which should cut the rates in half but
they seem to have changed the mob
spawning so this is still working
very quickly which is good for me
still getting good rates
um i don't know exactly how the new
mob spawning works we'll have to figure
that out
but uh seems to be pretty good still
it's definitely changed though that's
for sure
um i think what we're gonna do now we're
gonna head
back to the main world and we will maybe
play around with a few different things
all right we're back home again here and
i was just feeding my cows and i know
something strange
with the new updates they seem to uh
want wheat non-stop like even after they
breed
they want it even the little ones want
it and you can't give it to them
or or you click them a bunch of times
and it won't work and then
eventually it will like you just saw
there
spamming right click maybe
[Music]
it's very strange and it's not
well maybe yeah it is all of them
[Music]
terrifying absolutely terrifying
so hopefully that gets fixed i don't
think that's intended
because i bred all these guys except
that one
and that like i would click on the cow
three or four times
and they wouldn't eat it and then
finally they would take it and
they would get the hearts above so
there's gotta be something wrong with
that
i had i did play around with the new
upside down stairs and slabs and
everything smooth this out like i wanted
to
added wood below the fence there and
re-added the fence
i like how it looks
doesn't really block the vision and it
keeps you from walking off
and helps to keep the wood look going
throughout the
place here which is nice um
yeah just i'm loving the new patch it's
awesome
i think the next thing we should do is
uh i'm gonna use this looting sword on
the cows because we'll probably get
it doesn't have any other enchantments
on it like damage or i mean sharpness so
it's probably the best sword to use on
cows to get extra
steak
but yeah i want to go check out if silk
touch will pick up ice
and i also want to check if you can pick
up silverfish with
silk touch i don't think you can but i'm
hoping maybe that changed or something
so let's go on a little bit of adventure
here
also i had a few people telling me this
style of elevator doesn't work anymore
so let's try it out
and it does so it might just be a server
issue if it's not working for you
they are affected by lag quite a bit oh
hello what the
oh i broke broken armor piece
lost my pants
okay i stumbled across some ice here uh
the rumor i heard was that silk touch
will work on it
so we will check that out uh
this is 1.2.3 we're in and
i also notice this when you enter a new
biome the sky
changes instantly
never never noticed that before
okay so touch
does not work dang it ah
i was really looking forward to that too
really that's disappointing i hope they
re-add that
man stop spreading false rumors guys
who's doing it
happens every patch uh we
are going to go check out uh
silver fish yet even though they most
likely
can't be picked up i'm just curious i
want to know for sure
all right we're at the stronghold now i
found a few blocks over here that are
silver fish
i think that's one that's one that's not
so these two
are oh
dang it please be alive yes
oh man didn't blow up the spawner either
that was uh
okay i gotta i should seal this room off
really i don't trust
ah i gotta do something better about
this room
what the
yeah i'm getting freaked out here
okay um
sorry i'm all flustered right now i
wasn't expecting that creeper
i looked before i even came in here for
one and i didn't see any
ah just give me a moment guys
give me a moment
i just wanted to get this lava covered
actually i'm just going to block it i'm
i don't need it
and this keeps happening they keep
entering blocks near the lava and
then it gets free
oh man
okay that's one
that's not so let's try silk touch on it
this is indeed
silk touch yeah
it harvests a block but they uh it's
just a regular stone block i think
yeah so you can't get them
let's just see if they stack yeah they
do so they're just regular stone
blocks unfortunately
okay um i think i'm gonna head
back but before i do i'm gonna
harvest some mossy stone and crack
bricks from around here
uh something i keep meaning to do but i
i just skip it because it's
not something i want to record but uh
got a little bit of time today so i'm
gonna do that
so this is what i ended up getting we
got three and a half stacks
of the mossy ones and two of the cracked
and some other stuff uh with that
stronghold i think i'm just gonna
break down the whole thing for materials
because
i don't know it's it's a mess that one
it really is
i was thinking about maybe trying to
restore it and getting villagers down
there or something
to live but it's not a nice stronghold
really
so maybe if we find another one we'll do
that oh i'm still on short
but not this one because i don't like
the stronghold
now what i would like to do and what
i should do is check out and try find a
jungle
i've been so confused about those things
people telling me
i can't get them people telling me i can
having to
edit your nbt file and all that stuff
but it sounds like with all the changes
they made with anvil
format and their ability to save the
biomes in
the actual map now which is an awesome
improvement
uh sounds like i can get a jungle
in my old world here so we're gonna go
look for one
yeah i love the ladders they're so much
better now so you they don't seem to
have a mask
oh they do have a mask
i thought maybe it's because i'm
i'm standing on it i know you can hmm
i could have sworn i grabbed it before
like
oh if you're climbing up like this if
you accidentally
uh go off i think you if you just hold
right you can
re-grab it but now it's not working for
me yeah i like that
i don't know very weird okay
i'm gonna go try finding jungle i
don't know what the best way to go is
because i've explored a lot
around here uh maybe i will go
let's see so we got the mountains that
way
uh the stronghold is that way
and it's mostly just desert around here
maybe i'll try go
this way i haven't really went that way
for anything yet
if i remember right and i will let you
see if i find one
okay i've been walking from that
direction and past the swamp is a desert
here i guess
and uh mountains over there
i'm gonna go a little bit further this
way looks like there's a forest ahead
i'm really wondering if i'm going to
have like that chunk
border the steep cliff that you usually
get if
if biomes don't match up or if they fix
that
i really hope they fix that it'll be
cool if they can
add new biomes and stuff to older worlds
without
corrupting things hey guys
and i'm pretty sure jungles are my new
favorite biome
i haven't had a really good look at them
yet but uh
from what i could tell they have the
greenest grass so
you know that's where i want to go
before big forest
i've been playing a lot of uh
multiplayer lately
there was another prank that i was
involved with
i'm gonna have video of that pretty soon
really funny against good again of
course
and be the blow although mostly against
good
oh wolves ah
nuts i wonder if they still despawn
these are like the first wolves i've
seen in my world
[Music]
and every time i've well i found one
other set
but i didn't have any bones so i guess
that's the second pack i found
and again i don't have any bones so
they're probably going to disappear
looks like there's ocean that way
yeah i don't know
oh man it looks like snow yeah
i also brought a whole bunch of
um of these with me see if we can find
any more strongholds
i'm guessing that's back
to our spawn there we don't want to go
that way
all right i'm going to look a little bit
more and i'll keep you up to date if i
see anything cool
found a little bit of cheesy snow over
here
just a little bit kind of cool
this snow biome is pretty massive i came
across
a ravine
nothing too spectacular about it just a
regular ravine oh there's lava in the
back there
which is super dark for some reason
uh i see something over here too a weird
must still be generating or else that is
a really weird
thing oh there we go
floating floating island nope
um yeah
um not seeing a whole lot of anything
besides snow
all right we're on top of a hill right
now to get a better view and it's just
snow
everywhere huge snow biome
and it's getting pretty hilly up ahead
there but
i still see snow a little bit of forest
that way so maybe we'll
head that way and hope for some smaller
my homes or something
gonna throw another one of these
this is where we are that's pointing
back home
so maybe we won't go to that not
particularly looking for a stronghold
today or anything
just uh just curious if i will spot one
out all the way out here
that forest biome is pretty big too so
i've
exited that into the mountains and
hopefully we'll find something different
over there
still generating you can see lab over
there
nice steep uh
really hilly area i like it
um but
still no sign of a jungle i'm worried
i'll have to go really far to find one
and that is still pointing back home
okay
um let's go check out this lava
oh
that's pretty cool
right next to the creeper that's great
very nice this is a cool area i love how
the mountains are on both sides
oh that was close
oh okay enough cooking around let's get
out of here
okay so that's the big snow biome over
there that goes into the
giant forest biome a little desert there
but i think the desert's
really big over there then we have a
little swamp
um i can't quite tell if that's desert
up ahead there
no that's still the snow one i think so
we might have to try go
that way and
we'll see
i hope it doesn't go into an ocean
um
yeah there's not a lot of jungle around
is there
that's that's a lot of water i bet you
it's an ocean
darn it um
yeah i better make a boat
we found it's awesome i can see it just
starting to generate uh that was
actually
just a swamp i went a little further and
there was swamp on the other side of the
water
and then there was some forest and then
planes then some more forest here
and finally jungle
no no nasty chunk border
which is awesome
and it's just getting light out so we're
actually going to be able to see it
awesome
right to the top man nope nope
oh i could have killed myself there
there's a skeleton
bye-bye
very cool watch them dance
so i'm going to get some saplings when
i'm here i'm i'm not going to bother
getting a cat just yet
um wow
this is such an awesome biome
oh yes look at it
so green i don't see any grass
oh there's a dress it's not really that
green is it
i thought it was supposed to be greener
let's go look
yeah it's nice don't get me wrong i
thought it was going to be
really bright green like the old
rainforest
before they did the huge biome change
oh saplings and these trees are
like the best for collecting uh wood
so definitely want some saplings
i wonder how big this whoa i don't know
how big this
uh biome is
looks fairly big oh
missed the tree i wonder if you get like
ravines and jungle biomes i don't know
if i've ever seen
anyone with ravine yet
go over here
so we are fairly far away from home
though
oh i thought it just fell off there
and we are still getting pointed back
home so there can't be a whole lot of
strongholds around
people are telling me there's more than
three per world but i don't know
how to get it to track another one
unless they're really far apart
awesome okay now we're back to forest
haven't seen a cat yet
cool well i'm gonna look around here a
little bit on my own and then we'll be
back at
the home base
so i cut down about two or three of
those big trees
got four stacks of lumber from it that's
incredible
and i got 20 saplings now i wanted to
see what they look like
in different biomes the big trees so i'm
gonna
try plant one in a snow biome here
and let's just see what this looks like
i hope oh they might not grow
didn't think of that no they grow
hmm
i guess we need more space probably
i'm gonna go over there
okay let's try this again
no
ah maybe you can't grow the big ones and
grow the small ones
that's too bad
you know what it was i think it was the
snow blocking the tree growth
i i put it up one block here and i grew
first
try it looks a little
weird not the best looking tree
you can tell it doesn't fit anyway i'm
going to try
a few other biomes so i'm curious i want
to try it in a desert and i want to try
growing in the nether
fail
okay i'm going to cut this down
yeah the easiest way of cutting these
down i think is just to go to the very
top and work your way down
if you got a quick axe it's amazing
this is my efficiency four one
just work your way down
there's really not that much for
branches on them too which is nice
it's a little bit
it's real pain if you don't get them all
though because they're way up in the air
then
there's another one
so as far as farming wood goes
if you're just looking for planks this
is the way to do it for sure
but i still really like the look of dark
wood and light wood
compared i don't like i don't know if i
really like the way this
wood texture looks it's kind of
i don't know if i'd ever build anything
with it
it's uh i don't know maybe you have to
get used to it
let's look at it all incredible
okay uh let's go to a desert and try to
grow another one
all right i made it back i'm gonna try
it in the desert here
just to see what it looks like
made an s
that's uh that's interesting i'm
guessing that's what it'll look like in
the nether
two but i'm gonna try it there just to
make sure
i'm just thinking of how you could maybe
add a lot of
life to a desert quickly but
it doesn't look like it's really alive
when it's yellow like that
okay and i want to try the mountain
that doesn't look bad i like it in the
mountain that's pretty good
good color uh because like i said before
the mountains would look a lot cooler if
they were full of trees i
i would imagine so that might be
an idea
and finally i want to try it in the
nether so here we go
yeah yellow like the desert
not bad though um adds a lot more color
in here
even though it is an ugly color
but it will most likely burn down so
i always wanted to try what happens if
you throw one of these in here too
oh you can't throw them at all okay
right clicking can't throw it i
am a little worried i don't see any mobs
in here
i've heard they might be spawning on top
the roof
not really tracking any with the e thing
though
very strange i only see one zombie
pigman here
none oh there we go okay they're
probably just spread out
all right i'm going to head back
all right i'm a little disappointed i
didn't find any more villages in all
that
uh distance i traveled but i guess
i really didn't go or i didn't really
find any new deserts
or uh plain areas i think that's the
only place where you find villages
or i'm assuming anyway we'll check on
these guys
haven't seen them in a long long time
going to be doing some changes here
people wanted me to build a little area
for them and that's probably what i'll
end up doing and i'll maybe keep this
as like a little lobby room
and then further extend it
with like a village for them my own
style
and maybe man they're so much faster now
maybe a little fun facility for them too
but yeah didn't find any villages that's
uh that's too bad
that guy i have in my laboratory keeps
trying to escape now too he's so quick
you
can almost get through the door even if
he's miles away
yeah i'm talking about you
uh but anyway i'm going to call it an
end for today i'm having a lot of fun
with the patch
i hope you guys are too
uh you got some more cows to kill i
will uh be doing a really fun project
next episode i think
it's not the mob trap or the storage
room and it's not
a village thing it's something
completely different i've been wanting
to do for
a couple weeks here finally gonna just
do it
next episode i i hope so look forward to
it i think a lot of you will like it
it's not the slime thing either i got
lots of things i want to do
but i don't know i procrastinate
but anyway thanks for watching guys i'll
see you again next time