welcome back everybody this is etho and
today guys we are back in our let's play
world do you see what I see do you see
what I see
that's not how the song goes I am a very
good singer don't you don't you doubt it
ah these cows they have like these black
lines on them yeah you see that guy is
that the mushroom it goes like really
high up so she's looking to adjust the
right angle you see those black lines
there's one right there very strange I
don't see it on these cows just these
ones uh-huh well I fell I fall down so
guys I want to give you a big thank you
on last episode the World Tour you guys
were very supportive and I appreciate it
I wasn't really expecting you know out
of the ordinary like support on that
video butthole man you guys were very
nice and I appreciate it
lots of use lots of comments lots of
nice words and things like that we went
around our world we looked at some of
the old things we built and some of the
broken things as well I want to try fix
this first project for today a lot of
you were wondering why I have so many
broken things it's because this game
changes so much like honestly I like I
believe we even fix this UFO thing once
before I killed a cow with my ender
pearl how is that even possible
I know I did it but it sure seemed like
I did there all right so we're gonna go
for a simple fix hopefully let's see if
it's possible I just want to go down
lower and see if we can fling the cows
higher if we change like the height we
sit at here so we'll go down half a slab
lower if I have to slab I mean one slab
alright gonna do a little bit of trial
and error here
probably just killed another cow oh that
was a good throw okay and see if we can
get a height here that works I do really
want yes very good job you you change
the height so you can fall down now okay
okay
brand new fishing rod let's try this out
so oh I remember right the trick was to
get the ones in the corner it seemed
like we're flinging them not as far now
the goal is to get them in the water up
here oh that one was actually very close
oh yes
Oh baby was it just because I was doing
bad at it before maybe it maybe it
wasn't even broken because it was kind
of a game oh yeah it does work okay oh
cool okay it never was broken now we
know yeah this was supposed to be like a
game like it's actually a challenge to
get them in the water that's the way I'd
wanted it oh snap look where we are guys
how long has it been since we were last
year last episode aha you guys are
always telling me I never come here and
it
we were just here last episode what are
you guys talking about come here all the
time
uh I want to work on this thing next are
our mobile storage room I was just
taking a look at it here and you're
gonna hate me for saying this I think
it's actually done as well like it's uh
it's not done but like it functions okay
so the carts come in here they fall from
the top this all seems to be in working
order and if we go down here this all
seems to be working in working order
press the button
things happen that's a good sign right
let's see if we we can see it happen
here okay so these all pull out I think
the timings are all correct and the only
thing those this track doesn't go
anywhere but maybe for testing actually
it does go somewhere doesn't it I don't
think it was complete though but for
testing maybe what we'll do for right
now is just like veer this away from
here and make it loop back on itself so
we got to take this track here and make
it connect back to the start up here
yeah has to connect to over here and
then I'll do a full loop around and we
can we can see if it actually is working
properly so I'm going to set that up
right now
Digga Digga Digga to get to get to get
to get should be right through here ah I
have connected no leavers I see you
there mr. creeper you're not gonna get
me this time
Oh bump why have I never lit this area
up I have no idea right by the portal
right by my bed
all my items I've never lit it up so
that the creepers can blow up all my my
goodies here apparently cool so we got
this thing looping around on itself and
we should be able to check out how it
works and if it works I'm not sure I
think this should though from what I've
inspected so first test we're going to
do we're just going to stack maybe five
mine carts on one of these I think this
is how we load it right maybe we start
here and push it that might be a bit
more consistent okay and if I remember
right this these hold five mine carts
per column or maybe it wasn't even
limited I don't think it was limit is
just how high we make the stack but I
think we made it four five right yeah
well that little stack pretty neatly
actually so to begin I think we just
have to activate this
let's just see what happens we also are
interested in what order they come back
are they going to fall down this chamber
the front one there I'm not sure oh they
went to the front one oh that's
interesting because there's so little
distance in the track okay maybe we
can't test this year there's not enough
distance in the track for it to finish
and this is going around in an infinite
loop okay we're going to give this
another try now I just ran a whole bunch
of track so this first station connects
the second one and second one a third
one it's just a third one doesn't
connect back to this first one so it's
not quite complete at the moment but
what we're really interested in oh did
he break the redstone I don't even care
about these items honestly I just the
redstone oh my goodness so mad right now
you have no idea I'm so mad ah stupid
creepers mortal enemies for life alright
track looks okay yeah he blew up the
mine cause I'm have to reset this one
second okay third time's a charm rights
so we're interested in what order they
arrived so pay attention to the items in
these mine carts we want them to arrive
in the same order in the same positions
I heard a squeak it was my keyboard
though apparently I thought it was that
creeper like a sizzle sound okay so
particularly the bone and this redstone
torch and maybe the stair pay attention
to let's hit the button and it's going
to go on its merry way here
oh there's still some my cart stuff down
there I want to get it
garden day let's try to keep up so those
fall down here they go down to there and
I hooked it up to the station can we get
there in time oh man I think it's beyond
this wall right yeah it's up over here
quickly quickly quickly oh okay
that was pretty good forgot to remove
these so now that the orders should be
the same ideally stare that's great
torch oh it's looking good guys
it is looking good bone yes okay I think
I think we nailed it there perfect so
this track also connects over to our
third third station which is in a bit of
a weird spot like not somewhere we
actually would use for a long time
probably but it kind of crosses over to
here and I got to run one more track
that I'm really dreading from the third
station back to the first one look at
this view this is awesome ah let's see
it we'll go to the spot and I'll show
you how far away it is okay this goes in
bends around to another one of these
things yeah it's kind of a random spot
the idea by the way is we hit a button
and it's going to request the carts from
whatever station it's at and they should
arrive here it might take a little bit
of time but they should get here we have
to run a redstone signal to the stations
or some other method as well but we have
to run a track all the way up to we see
it up there it's like somewhere up there
from here Digga Digga Digga one four
eight we want to go up to 153 and I just
broke something turn it ah okay we were
close I broke some redstone whoa we
have a full loop now so we can send
these mine carts to the first station is
the idea that we're going to try it out
just to make sure it works and make sure
they arrive in the right order and all
that stuff - oh this one sent Oh Oh then
visible minecart or did actually send a
extra one out there not sure
Oh loud noises okay so this goes to here
we saw this already double check
something weird happen with one of those
mine carts I'm going to leave what the
deal was there might be one repeater set
robin there Oh is there a ladder stuck
there too
oh that's not good
no something got really messed up uh
well I guess before we try to fix that
let's see if this station works like
before we move these carts back since
they're here let's let's send them on
their way to the new track I just built
this one and this one I wonder what's
going on with that you remember a long
time ago and we were you probably don't
remember a long time ago when we were
working on this we had issues with mine
carts going invisible even though the
words what am I trying to say like they
would appear to be invisible but they
were actually there I don't know if
that's happening or if they're it's
actually sending out extra ones okay
we'll follow them this is the new track
that's not a good sign oh snap okay they
all bounced back some somehow why did
that happen
Oh disaster guys absolute disaster okay
they went up here and some of them fell
down it at least I hope see two there
one there the rest got messed up okay
okay good news guys I'm
they have solved the problem I'm
starting to feel I need an assistant to
our partner or something because I
missed some really obvious stuff
sometimes there's no redstone up here
guys I never put the redstone in so
these these junctions are supposed to be
controlled by something and that thing
is not here to to do it so I'm going to
put that in right now and hopefully this
will work also I checked out the first
station this is the third one by the way
first station has some inconsistencies
at the top here compared to the second
one so maybe if we get everything the
way it should it'll work let's hope for
the best here all right well it's
do-or-die time guys this is our final
test it has to work otherwise we're
given up perfect
okay Oh No why does it do that it seems
every time it does that is when we have
problems too but everything is at
everything is as it should be I've
double-checked like 20 times the
Redstone is all right
and it's just this invisible minecart
thing I can explain where it seems to be
sending to mine carts I don't know if it
is or not is it gonna bounce back don't
bounce back don't bounce back don't
bounce back ah
oh snap it might work oh it works it
works guys guys it worked okay okay now
is this one gonna work because maybe
it's just after it goes once it has
trouble the second time okay Jenna did
that there and there okay we can't
actually ride we can't ride and follow
it it will kill us there's a crazy drop
on the way so let's try to enderpearl
there quickly oh that might have been a
perfect ender pearl oh man just about
perfect beautiful and come on come on
come on yes okay last one last one okay
we got to do it you got to do it
I was just about to give up honestly I
didn't think this was gonna work but it
seems like it might do the trick now
alright let's go follow oh what a relief
I have spent a lot of time
troubleshooting this and I am very happy
very very happy now okay and last no I
am so mad right now I have no idea
what's messing it up not a clue alright
I'm gonna do the rest of testing
off-camera here because we've seen a lot
of that today but I think I got it
figured out now turns out I'm an idiot I
put a redstone torch to power the thing
to power these power rails cuz without
it they're unpowered yes okay well I
didn't realize this redstone down here
is pointing at this torch so whenever
these these minecarts go over top here
to trigger the whole thing it unpowered
this rail here and they all kind of
stopped and bunch up and then bounce
back so let's just move that to maybe
over here and power that and everything
should work perfect
yep that did the trick guys I just
tested it all and it seems to work
perfectly now so that's great the only
thing left to do with this like it works
as it is now but we can't request carts
like I want to so if there's no mind
cards here if our storage items aren't
here I want to be able to press a button
and it's going to check the other
stations for the minecart and if they're
at that station we want it to
automatically bring them to us and then
stop here and we want that for all the
stations so I've been trying to think of
an elegant way of doing that it's
actually pretty complicated as it turns
out so what we want to do I think let's
tap a bit of land here rather than
forcing the minecarts to always arrive
here and fall down we want to change it
so that they have the ability to pass by
each of these stations and instead will
have a junction that when it's enabled
it will it will go to here basically
it's going to be really I might have to
change a lot of stuff around I think
darn it's because these tracks don't
come up very nicely they're all like
going down and coming up and they're not
like beside beside here but yeah
basically have a junction all right when
we press the button here I want mine
carts to be ejected from a dispenser and
it will go down this track and let's see
this is going to be so messy oh
basically have another Junction here
sort of thing minecart will get ejected
go down the track when it passes by each
of these stations will have a detector
rail and when this gets triggered it's
going to it's going to power this whole
thing so it's going to send any mine
cards that this that this minecart
passes by you see so as it goes by the
station's if the mine carts are there
it's going to check them and send them
down this track and once it finishes a
full rotation we want to send it back
into this dispenser and have this this
thing switch so that the mine carts go
here yes I'm not doing it today that's
the rough idea though gonna take a
little time to work that out now we're
gonna head back to broken track we're
gonna head back to the man cave area do
some projects around there hopefully
fixed it good good good
I don't want to stop and like fall in
the lava here like that one time so any
broken tracks
let's get fixed
these guys still angry though they seem
cool now alright alright to new to our
series guys these are moments I'm going
to call talked in build moments ok so
where I take time to talk to you guys
about stupid things I have to say so for
today we're going to build the sandy
city wall a little bit we got to build
it up to this level here and raise it up
like two blocks or so and I'm going to
talk to you about something stupid so I
don't know what it is every morning
every single morning I am stuffed up I
have a raspy voice you might be able to
hear it right now I'm recording in the
morning right now and in fact at this
very moment the snot in my nose has sort
of hardened to a specific density where
it resonates with my voice so as I'm
speaking it's vibrating and tickling my
nose it's the worst thing ever and I'm
wondering is it just me guys do you get
do you get stuffed up in the morning I'm
wondering if I'm allergic to my pillow
or something like is this normal oh it
bugs me though every single morning it
takes like two three hours before it
clears up and I feel like a normal
person and I want it to stop like maybe
it's my pillow that does it's whenever I
wash my like bedsheets and stuff I still
get it but I don't eat I don't wash my
pillow I just wash my pillowcase right
so maybe there's there's something to it
or maybe it's totally normal and I have
to live with it I'm not sure something
else not quite so stupid I want to talk
to you about is the Minecraft combat
update if you guys have not been paying
attention and even if you have dinner
bone tweeted the other day that he's
adding dual-wielding to the game so
you're gonna have a left arm and a right
arm right now you can only see my right
arm well you can't see the arm at all
because I have the blocks there but yeah
you know what I mean and
sounds like the plan is you're going to
have another inventory spot here and
whatever you put in that inventory spot
not just weapons but like anything if
there's something in that spot then your
left arm shows up and I'm curious if
they're going to implement anything else
to that like the idea is to make it work
with shields right there's gonna be
shields in the game so you can block if
you left-click I assume no right-click
it would be right-click like you do
currently so I'm wondering maybe they're
going to make it so if you have blocks
selected in your left hand if you if you
left-click that would be reversed so
like right now the place blocks you have
to right-click maybe if you have blocks
in your left hand though you can
left-click to place those ones and
right-click to place whatever is on your
hotbar
like dual wield the block placing you
know what I mean
that might be pretty cool like right now
for example while building this wall one
of the things we need to place is birch
slabs and rather than having to switch
my hotbar all the time it would be kind
of nice if you could just like switch
you know just like right-click for one
type of block left-click for another
type whatever you have selected but
instead you gotta like scroll and yeah
you know what I mean a little bit
annoying wait I'm doing this on the
wrong level I think those have to go up
one more what a disaster alright so
we're going to get to the comments for
today guys I picked out two and the
first one here says once you build the
Nexus how much do you plan on using it
well with the amount of time we spent on
it I hope we use it quite a bit even if
we're not directly interacting with it
like putting items in or taking items
out we will always be using it
technically because it's going to be
storing our items always right so it has
that function but hopefully we we use it
directly a lot too like for example are
our storage room here
if you look at this chest you can see
there's not a lot of one type of item
maybe at most two or three stacks of one
type of item like oak leaves actually
there's a lot of oak leaves here but
what I do when I get like 20 stacks of
oak leaves I can't drop them off in this
chest I need somewhere to put that and
that's what the nexus is for and then if
we run out of them here we got to go get
some to refill this chest and that
that's kind of the idea behind it maybe
we won't use it all the time or maybe
not all the time on camera but we will
be getting stuff in and moving stuff
around I'm sure quite often the other
comment here it says one thing that was
kind of frustrating this is starting
about the world tour last episode was
the amount of projects that don't work
anymore or projects etho will do later
sorry to be a buzz killington but isn't
the world supposed to be a collection of
working automatic machines isn't that
the entire point it's nothing against
etho but common come on you know I saw a
few people say that and like come on
guys common um I think just about
everything in our world here works
there's only a couple things like this
elevator I don't want to tear it out
though because in the future they might
fix the way piston arms move you maybe
this this thing here but we kept that
just for the looks of it but overall I
think most things work in our art world
here even this old automatic for this
old potion room sure we don't use it
anymore but it still works so I'm
getting unfairly treated on that one but
but yeah anyway as far as not finishing
projects yeah that happens that
definitely happens since the way I like
to play the game sorry if it bothers you
but it helps to keep the game more
interesting to me so that's the way I
like to play it's when we always have
open-ended projects in our world
and as as I've gotten some feedback from
you guys it sounds like a lot of you
liked it that way too because then you
know there's always something new and
and there's a lot of variety that way I
hope I hope you like it
anyway hope you guys enjoyed the episode
thank you for watching as always hope
you have a wonderful day and I'll see
you in the next one take care bye might