hello
everybody and welcome back we are once
again at the enderman farm today because
we had some problems
last time where it exploded on us i have
no idea
why how could that have happened
actually i do know why we figured it out
last time
uh so i've rebuilt it and modified it
i think it's okay can never be too
certain though oh
i was like i'm gonna jump in the water
then while i was in midair it's like
no i'm gonna land on the quartz over
there and then it's like oh
you know what i might die let's jump
back in the water
that was close um
yes i've modified it this is what i did
i have half slabs here
and i'm not done modifying it there's
problems with this method too
the thing is xp orbs cannot get over top
half snaps
and i'll i just i left it like that so i
could show you
um 30 levels let's enchant
so touch efficiency 4 very good okay so
xp orbs don't seem to be able to go over
half slabs
unfortunately so if i stand in the
middle
i'll get a few of them but the majority
it does that thing where it looks like
they're they're by me but then they
teleport back to up there
um so you can't get over
something seth suggested to me is i
should use
upside down half slabs and i was like oh
yeah that makes
that makes a lot more sense that's a
good idea
so if we do that
it works pretty good but it also has a
problem
and these i think like the thing is last
time the tnt was getting
uh knocked out of place uh from the
middle there when we were using the
pressure plates the half slabs seem to
prevent that
um so we got to have something solid
there
the thing is we got to find a
combination that works and still allows
us to get the xp
orbs if we can otherwise i'm going to
have to punch holes in the glass
in a bunch of places to make it work
wait wait wait a minute i'm not that
dumb
i know what i'm doing i'm a professional
right i did that right yeah i think i
did that right
okay so now if we stand here we get the
majority
of the xp orbs but for some reason
there's a few that get
stuck
uh within the half slabs it almost seems
like
it's very strange
uh by the way i
i've been doing a little bit of work on
my wither farm and
a bunch of other things and i've used up
all my work picks so that's why we're
enchanting uh work
work picks today we're trying to get
work picks anyway i only have silk touch
and fortune picks and
unbreaking picks we're a little bit shy
let's do this
get one more uh but yeah you saw when i
came up here a few xp orbs were still
lingering
around this middle so they didn't make
it on the all the way down
unfortunately
so i have one more idea that's what i'm
looking for by the way these
um one more idea i'm going to try use
oh i can't use snow can i
if i use snow the water is going to wash
it away
unless i melt it into place
um i'm gonna try and make snow work that
might be
what we need and i think xp orbs might
be able to go over top it
can't use trapdoors because then that
would require putting a block like
here or something and then xp orbs would
get stuck on that too
um so i'm going to get some snow and see
if that if we can make that work
man what is that
you hear that noise it's something is
walking around here is that
it's not you is it no it's not you
it must be a slime like a little slime
that can't really jump
you know what oh you know what it is my
hostile sounds are really low so i
probably can't hear him
oh yeah yeah where is he
he's probably way up there oh there he
is
okay mystery solved
okay so snow slabs this is a bit of a
stretch i don't know if this is even
going to work but
if we just have one if you look at the y
we're still at 4.0
when we walk on it if we get one more
down though
it goes to 4.125 so an eighth of a block
every every slab you add to this 4.25
and a half slab is equivalent well a
slab just a slab it's equivalent to that
4.5 i believe
let's get one down just to check so it's
possible xp orbs can get over top
just uh if it's not as high like that
um and tnt is only 0.98 blocks
by times three like all all sides is
0.98 blocks so i think
this should be enough to hold it in
place and prevent it from going into
these these spots that we don't want so
pretty sure this is going to wash it
away though
let's just try first
nice placement what
i watched it okay so i'm gonna what i'm
gonna do
get these out of here such a simple
problem
like it's such a little problem and
there's should be a simple solution to
it but i'm having so much trouble
oh we can actually test it right away
here let's just kill a few of these guys
and head on down see if it'll go over
top
no seriously
stinking xp orbs they can't get over
anything
huh
let's try this one more time i guess
that just leaves me with the option
punching holes through the glass or the
upside down half slabs
um i lose a little bit from that that
was the thing
and it really starts to add up if you do
this a few times
yeah that stinks okay
darn it
okay one one last idea here and then
we're moving on uh this might blow it up
let's hope not i do have a backup from a
little while ago if it does
but what if we just have the
did you see that he went right in my
face
uh what if we have the water up here
like when tnt goes off even through
blocks
it like it hits you so maybe it'll do
enough damage to these guys that'll
kill them still
is my theory let's let's just try it out
let's just see
might not kill them should be
safe from explosions oh it does work
well whoop-dee-doo that's a lot easier
it's just no half slabs
nothing just open air space over there
and do it however i want yeah that's
that's the trick that's what we're doing
oh yeah i'm liking this a lot more i can
i can put whatever i want here it
doesn't have to be the quartz blocks or
a solid block
i got glass there now so it's more
transparent i can see
the xp orbs easier it looks cooler and i
got rid of ladder which the xp orbs
sometimes would
kind of get stuck on not not really
though
some for fortune two um yeah look like
look how much cooler this looks now
from this angle
forward
i love how that looks it's like you can
see all the xp orbs going to that
central point above me now and
coming down on me like oh i think it
looks neat
so that's cool and i can even modify
this now
so that's uh well i did modify it so
that's
i can even use it from up here if i want
don't think this will kill me oops
let's find out um if i'm up here the xp
orbs get to me easier and quicker
does half a heart damage i took off my
shoes
so it doesn't waste your ability
and i even put in a trap door here if i
want to do enchanting on the second
layer
like if i'm standing up here
oh so oh and i'm happy with that
oh most likely i'll use it from down
below more often though
but anyway that's enough of the enderman
farm it's working now i'm going to
release the
the map download uh pretty much for sure
unless there's some other problem
somewhere
so check the description if you want to
link to that
and i've also been working on the gold
farm so let's head on over there
trying to get a lot of things done
before i release the world
and let's do one more of these
silk touch plain old sickle touch i got
so many soap touched now it's crazy
all right let's let's head on over to
something else
and by the way i just want to let you
guys know i'm using my mine shaft again
i haven't
i haven't used this in a really long
time because i thought i mind out all
the tunnels
turns out it was just some of them all
the ones along
here seem to be intact still so um
i haven't gone branch mining in a very
long time i always go caving
but when i need redstone this is the way
to do it
and so that i've started doing it a
little more now
got two stacks for the project we're
about to do i realized i have absolutely
no redstone dust left so i had to
go do a bit of branch mining um found a
dungeon on the way got a saddle
and that kind of stuff while doing this
though i had an idea of how to get
resources quicker
and i'm going to try it on on the
minecraft server because i don't really
need
stuff too badly in my single player but
on minecraft i am
dead broke so next episode we might look
into that
on minecraft if it works i'll show you
my new method but
yeah on to the gold farm
redstone xp
nice
all right everyone so this is the zombie
pigman farm the gold farm i have added
in
these rings so that the zombie pigmen
fall where i want them to
and then down below here i have also put
in
uh that's a hopper mine cart you saw i
just picked up a piece of gold
i set up a track that goes underneath
each of these
drop points and it picks up
whatever whatever those guys drop on the
track
when they die um this minecart by the
way you can pick up stuff if it's
if it's like um
against the iron bars here it's fine uh
it can reach that far but if it's on the
other side of the iron bars it won't
pick it up it's too far away then
uh so i got that thing going around on a
loop right now
let's see what it's done it's
just barely a stack of it right now i
haven't used it too much
and you saw some pigment just fell it's
not really supposed to work when i'm
down here but it does a little bit
now the idea with this farm and i
i should mention this was an impulse
idea oops
was uh one day i decided i want to make
a gold farm i wonder what would happen
if i made a gold farm where the zombie
pigmen spawn below the ceiling
and i i sit above it and i figured
it would work pretty good and i wouldn't
have to do a lot of work with it
it's been quite a bit of work but i mean
i wouldn't have to clear out as much
netherrack as if i was to build
uh a different type of zombie pigman
farm not a not a portal one but just the
regular spawning pad one
i would have to clear out a ton of
netherrack for that
so this is experimental concept and i
didn't plan it out too well
when i first came up with it and
now now i'm working out the details and
i'm i'm wondering how
things actually work so the idea is
when i'm up on the ladder above the
ceiling there i want
spawning pads to be just within
128 blocks where they can spawn
the thing is i'm dropping them now
and they drop like 20 blocks or so and
there's this rule in minecraft if a mob
is
more than 128 blocks away from your
player
then they despawn very quickly
the question is this is the detail
i haven't worked out i've never known if
if they despawn like in a few seconds or
if it's like
instant like the next updates
it checks it instantly just spawns
anything
outside of 128 blocks it's something you
can't really figure out too well in this
game
unless you're looking at the game code
so i've never never figured that out
exactly i'm sure somebody will tell me
in the comments um somebody that's
looked at the code
but regardless i should be able to
figure out in game i'm pretty sure they
are despawning instantly
so as they're dropping they're
despawning if
if they could just stay around for a
second they would hit the ground and
i would get the gold
if you know what i'm talking about
anyway so what we're going to do here
which will help us figure it out in game
in case i don't find out from somebody
is we're going to set up an item
elevator
that will transport the gold up above
the ceiling because
when i'm up there i have no idea really
what's going on down below
i have no indicator so if we set up
some way of sending gold up there i
could see what kind of rates i'm getting
while i'm above the ceiling
um i'm sure let's get a farm or not a
farm
elevator going i came up with a pretty
cool design for one i guess
you can probably make it come out here
where's a good place to go up
maybe this corner let's go outside a bit
again maybe i'll clear out some more of
this land and make it come outside
after considering it i decided to put
the item elevator over here instead of
over
there because this is the middle of the
farm
on the side that gets the least gas so i
think uh
should be good and it's going to come up
right on the outside of the farm
i don't want it close to the spawning
pads because that will affect the rates
um
the closer it is to them so
let's begin so this is a pretty cool
design
what we're gonna do is make the this
minecart will come out
let's make it come out over here on the
outside of the item elevator
um
and i'm trying to think of how to do
this
i just built this today so i'm going by
memory
we're gonna have two hoppers like that
and uh power rail over top this is where
the minecart is gonna unload right here
and it's gonna unload
into
dropper
like so and then we want an airspace for
this dropper to shoot
the items into
and then we want a piston below that
that will come up and squish the items
that we shoot out
so that they flow upwards we got to make
sure there's no air spaces around though
otherwise it won't work
maybe we'll make this out of glass space
base layers
anyway so
we can see what's going on a little
better
okay so items will will shoot in this
one by one by one
hole here and we're gonna hook up a
little bit of redstone it's not too
complicated
and lay down a base people always ask me
why i use stone bricks
for redstone um i don't like using
like cobblestone is so abundant in this
game it's a good block
it's fairly blast resistant if you're
dealing with creepers
and you can see the redstone clearly on
it
um i often will
place cobblestone and
uh stone you see everywhere throughout
the world but if i
if i use stone brick i know it's a block
that's important
so if i'm mining around in my cave and i
see that i know not to break it because
there's probably redstone on top of it
so that's why i use stone brick it's a
block i like to use for redstone
okay so if there's an item in here
it will send out a signal to a repeater
there's items in take those out
that goes off unless it picks it up
again because there's so much junk on
the ground
and i picked it up again
my inventory is so full okay so there's
nothing in that's off
uh we're going to go to one more
comparator and this is going to be a
pulsing one so we switch that to
negative
or subtraction whatever it's called uh
loop it around
so now if there's an item in here this
this clock is going to run
it does that flashy thing make it come
around if uh if we connect to that
it connects to that comparator we don't
want that so we're gonna put a
redstone repeater here at one tick
and now you see it's it's uh pulsing
like that let's change this with a solid
block
that transmits redstone and now if
there's an item in there it shoots it
out
into that one by one by one area
that's all good um
now next part of this
the unloading thing
let's see how did i do that
this is the same unloading system i set
up
in my potion lab where the minecart runs
over top
no i might need more guards around here
i really don't like when yeah shoot
okay so comparator
that's fine do that up to a redstone
torch
and this goes like that
okay and just on the back we need a
little bit more
um the comparator goes through
i can't see barrier goes through this
block
then we're gonna run that like it goes
through
through here to this side as well and we
run that up
to this parts and that's done
okay and finally we need to hook
this sticky piston up to this
i guess we could do that
get that going and then we'll put
redstone below it
just about done here and then we'll see
it working
um okay so
redstone signal will send downward to
here
i don't do redstone on camera too often
so this is a
little change um
i used to do it all the time all right
to the repeater to the block to
i think the pistons all the way over
there
hmm
all right we got to be careful about
this as well
can we no we can't do that um
man it's tricky
i guess we can just do this right
this is different than what what i set
up before i think so that's what's
throwing me
alright so destroy the track
so that should be good now there's eyes
and
items in here that distance should go
down
shoot them into there then when it's
done it
it goes back up like that
gas they're all around to me driving me
crazy
i got the sound way down but
it's not helping oh
sniper he nailed you right in the face
boy
you gonna take that yeah
all right um so i got the item elevator
going almost all the way up to the
ceiling i ran out of box when i was up
there
but it's picking up stuff
good to see missed that one because it
was on the left side
should get it on the return no problem
yep it's still filling up okay so we're
gonna make that minecart go
down this track but i just set up this
temporarily
and there's two different settings for
this thing we can have it at
four this repeater at four and what
that'll do
it'll un load it uh sporadically
it's broad periodically
what's the right word
i can't remember how many does it does
at a time
i think it's like six
don't don't you dare so it unloads six
at a time
if you have at that setting or if you
have it at three it unloads the whole
thing
before the piston retracts again or
extends or whatever
now it's doing the whole thing and when
the minecart's done load
unloading the the launcher system takes
care of sending it back
all on its own so
this is a fully automated minecart
unloading elevator
system that should take things up to the
top here
once i make it go all the way and we can
make it go as high as i want
and then set up hoppers up nice throw
really how did you get up here
you want to make life tough for me don't
you
one by one get out of here
dang guy all right so i gotta attach
this to the ceiling
so i gotta fill in all these cracks in
the bedrock if i can
hopefully that's possible
make sure like all this stuff needs to
be filled in i don't know why i'm
hollowing out
when it's already filled in should be
solid
yeah i think we're good
okay so i do have a plan here a little
in-game test we can do to figure out the
answer that question i had before
what happens to mobs when they go
outside of the 128 block
barrier from your player do they
instantly despawn like
next frame or does it take a second or
two
what is the the time approximately
i can't get it figured out exactly i
don't think but uh
i'll know if it's instant or like a
second or longer
based on this test so we're at y106
the spawning pads for the zombie pigmen
at the lowest point is right here
so um if we add 128 to 106
i'm gonna go up to i think that's 234.
let's go up to 230 up in the sky
and we'll call this zero barrier right
here so
once they once they drop off the pads
and start falling
uh they will hit zero
i'm saying zero weird i feel they'll hit
zero
barrier um
and they'll be outside the 128 block
range and
if if they hit the ground the gold is
gonna come up to the top there so that
will mean
after they leave the 120 block range it
takes them a second or
or more probably because that's about
how long it takes them to
hit the ground if i get no gold while
i'm up there that means
they probably despawn instantly which
means my farm
is going to need some adjustments here
because that's going to really affect it
so let's double check this thing is
still doing its loops
i have to do a little bit of a messy
setup there it's still going okay
i think it's double good
it's about to go
didn't collect anything all right well
we're gonna head on up
and we shall figure it out pretty quick
it was darn guys this was a tough shot
to make
before and now i got two zombie pigmen
up here to deal with
oh don't hit them
don't hit them move
move just a little bit please
pro all right so
this thing it's working a little bit
too slow to really say for sure what's
going on
i can confirm i was getting gold up at 2
but not much like one or two pieces
every time the minecart was going around
and dropping stuff off so it's not it's
not a lot of gold
but they are hitting the ground at this
height so
that's a good sign so really what it
comes down to is i got to improve the
efficiency of the farm
by mining out the netherrack there's
probably caves in the ceiling i don't
know about
that kind of stuff to deal with there we
go
so we got one piece
when i do that then the farm might
actually run okay but as it is right now
it's not very good
at all so at least i have an idea of
rates and stuff
now that i have a collection system set
up and a way of sending it up here
and i just made this out of gravel
as a temporary thing because i wasn't
really sure what i'm doing
or what block i want to build it out of
so be quick to remove
that way anyway that's enough
of the gold farm for today
oh i heard it go
huh i wish i could just go invisible
and have things spawn like i was up
there and
actually be able to see things down here
would answer a lot of my questions
okay everybody so it is common time
again today
and just got a really quick one so
this was a common suggestion i got last
episode and i think the one before it
even
so i just want to touch on again clarify
once again it says hey
etho it doesn't say hey etho this is
etho
why don't you just use a dispenser full
of tnt
then you can just click a button and
that should work without a hitch
ah so the thing is with the ender ender
to use the tnt i need to ignite it
myself
it has to have the etho tag connected
with the tnt
if i ignite it like by placing it
against redstone
or by um having it
having it launched from a dispenser like
having a drop from dispenser
that's not going to have my name
attached to the tnt because
it's just done by the environments
i have to either light it with a flint
and steel
or light it with a flame bow for it to
get
recognized as my tnt and then i did xp
orbs from the enderman with it so that
is
that is the caveat the catch to the
whole
enderman farm alright so
once again world download should be in
the description
it's been a long time like 50 episodes
or more
so i'm sure i don't know what's changed
in the world but i'm sure a lot has
changed
what is that
i think that's my i think that's my
spawning platform
not quite rendering uh anyway so
hope you guys enjoy that hope i hope you
like the episode and i will see you
again next time bye bye
you