hey hey everybody this is etho and
welcome back to another episode I am now
using the 38 a snapshot and the big
change with this one is the sounds we
got new sounds a couple new mobs and a
few other things and I'm just it's like
really overwhelming when you hear them
all at first get louder sounds but I
think I think I'll get used to them cows
are really weird aren't you I have like
a breathing sound now that's cool a lot
of the sounds I think they need some
tweaking yet like that almost sounds
like it's getting cut off before it
finishes playing they got walking sounds
they sound extremely heavy I'm not a big
fan of the new grass sound it's got like
a squeal to it almost I think it's
supposed to be like a rustle but I know
just sounds kind of cool and I really
like the planks all the sounds like have
a lot of depth to them they're very very
detailed and there's new fall damage
sounds not sure if I can get that going
it's more of like an impact zone now I
think and of course water sounds there's
lots of splashing and stuff that's cool
don't really care for the the watching
underwater sounds like they're really
harsh at the moment especially this soil
sand soil sounds like you're really
pounding the ground when you walk for
some reason but I'm sure there's still
tweaking things could be cool once all
all done but it'll take some getting
used to anyway
also the item frames you can see from a
long distance now that's a good change
what if they change
explosions I don't think it did
and I'm not going to find out not here
anyway
oh yeah you can see the item frames from
a long ways away now it's pretty cool
with the storage room though I still
plan on doing The Cove idea just so that
we can get everything to fit just
otherwise it's going to be pretty tough
to and I've been organizing a little bit
I think I'm going to do it like keep all
the block types together like I kind of
had to decide like do I want to keep
like all the stairs together and all the
slabs together or do I want to just keep
them grouped by their block type like
stone together sand together you know
type thing I think I'm just going to go
by block type mm-hmm I check it out I
found a bat in this little space here
I'm weird like this like when a new mob
comes out one of the first things I want
to know is what kind of collision box it
has like can he fit through a half slab
space like that and we're going to find
out maybe don't think you can Boop
where'd he go
yeah I don't think you can alright I'll
let you free boy they're spawning in my
room here quite often every time I come
here I always see one now having a hard
time getting out anyway what I want to
do today is work more on the storage
room area here figuring out the layout
and I need to clear out some space so I
got it all rigged with TNT let's let's
have some fun and a wooden wooden button
I have no arrows oops the skeleton
sounds man they are pretty crazy
thank you mean skeleton skeleton
I think it's night time
alright let's let's get this going there
it is it'll make it all the way
I'm pretty good
we might have it oh I put two buttons
just in case it stalled out on me
there's one up there too OOP OOP okay
and hit it from here
Oh an arrow is going to break hmm there
we go
the bats don't give any XP and they're a
passive mob they don't fight you
sweet alright I'm going to clean up that
mess we just made get it all flat that's
the fall damage sound by the way ah it's
like everywhere I go I hear slimes
everywhere it doesn't matter where I go
they're so loud just driving me nuts
now this is quite the coincidence
there's like one dark spot
apparently in here on the silverfish
block I think it's like let light level
7 or something and don't mind that and
just so happens Sambi spawn in there and
not just a zombie but a villager zombie
and my stuff I left it here from last
time I went looking for them so that we
have them perfectly contained how
perfect does this go or how perfect you
can this gets I should say so weak this
it's shaken it takes a while though
what's my particle set I don't know
it's got like a red red particle effect
I wonder wonder how long that's going to
take them well it took a long time I
actually got tired of waiting in left
for a bit and then finally when I tame
bat you switched to a villager so we we
have our first priest bottles of
enchanting cool I just will let him out
let him roam free and see how long he
can live here if he wants to go I don't
think he wants to go it's just non-stop
slime noise like you kill them and then
they come back within a few seconds it
seems that's sneak you guy man where'd
he go huh oh I see yeah no XP so I'm
definitely going to have to have slab
around this place to stop them from
spawning because it's something that was
something it's going to do anyway but
now the it's all the more urgent listen
to the listen the sound when you go up a
level to 28 to 29
okay I kind of like that scared me the
first few times did I realize what it
was yeah but once we get rid of the
slimes our mob system or will work
better too there's just so many around
here huh but anyway I'll show you what
I've been doing here I will just let
them be I guess I tried placing one of
these doorways for the coves and just
trying to get an idea for size and
position and how I'm going to do all
this I think I need to make it go this
way a bit more this is how I'm going to
do the doorway though there's not going
to be any doors on it it's going to be
open because I want to be able to see
inside and have easy access and then
what I want to do for the middle is have
like stairway over here somewhere that
goes up and then same with on the other
side they'll kind of meet together at
the top there and there's going to be
like a balcony that goes all the way
around this place and that'll be one of
the ways of getting up think and then we
might have some supports beams
holding up the balcony area or the
overhang and we'll try hide some
lighting into that because otherwise
it's going to be pretty dark around here
and I'm using a I'm just using the wood
right now to get a feel for it then
we'll try you something else I would
like to use more snow in that but you
know I feel kind of limited with what I
can do because I need I need stairs and
I need half slabs and there's only I
think seven different blocks types in
the game that you can do that with and
four of those are wooden planks the four
colors and then you have bricks which I
rarely use and then you have I guess
there's cobble cobble stone brick
sandstone I think that's it yeah I think
that's it I think eight eight different
types so I am kind of limited to what I
can do
but we'll try make it look good I think
I'm going to move it back two or three
more blocks here
got ya what we going to get today guys
let's see very good
mmm I guess we're going to be doing some
troubleshooting the mod system has
pretty much stopped working and I don't
know why I have a feeling it has to do
with all those bats somehow there's this
skeleton very strange like it was
working okay for a long time then it
seemed like it just kept slowing down
little by little hmm
this is bad news if we can't fix it
let's I'm going to head over to one of
my x-rays I think just checking the
entities around Underground's mm-hmm
everyone head over to one of my x-rays
and see if we can learn anything hmm
you know I'm trying to figure out why it
slowed down I don't see any bats really
there's a few slimes jumping around ooh
my bad but I don't see the problem
there's a cave over there I miss to just
notice that
huh
okay leaving the area and coming back
seems to fixed it it's going do it again
I'm guessing there was a slime overload
somewhere it could be it could be bat
related but I doubt it because I'm
pretty sure they would have their own
mob account like they wanted to share
their mob talent with these guys I don't
think but I'm just guessing okay guys so
I got one two arches done now and our
storage coves are going to be behind
these door frames then I put I started
laying out the snow here and a circle of
the appropriate size and I'm just using
that as a guide for shaping this we
might be changing some stuff here I'm
trying to figure out how to do the
staircase now and I owe it was almost
thinking it would be cool if we did like
a diagnol staircase that started here
this is the center between that frame
and that frame we had one going up and
then sharply turning this way I don't
want to see how it'll go if we do
something like that let's see how should
we start this maybe mmm
what if we I'm stirring these blocks
just random clocks probably just to get
the shape going that's we're not going
to be using cobblestone don't worry
hey get out of the way all right it
might be a little strange so with ya I
think what we would want it to do is
start to get wider as it gets up here
and then start branching off forking off
two directions I'll mess with it a bit
off camera here and just see if we can
get the shape we want okay so this is
kind of what I want but not exactly
pretty nice to walk up good curve to it
this is about the height I would want
the next layer to be I think nice down
view of the place but the slope is way
too gentle I need to use stairs for sure
and I do like the idea of of like having
stuff behind the staircase to what am I
going to mess with now I think is just
using stairs to the half slabs
and the snow I'm not really sure what
we're going to do about the snow I'm I
liked how it sort of bounces it out
having it on both sides but to keep it
visible I don't know how that's going to
work out
anyway let's see if we do this so one
idea I had the other day guys and let me
know what you think of this I I told it
to a few people and they seem to like it
how cool would it be like oh I noticed
something like dude wants and I'm sure a
lot of people want I want it myself
they're like I want a way of getting mob
eggs in the game I think it'd be cool if
they did like a Pokemon thing like where
for example you threw an egg at a mob
and it would capture it like they would
hit the mob then they would just
disappear and the the mob egg of that
type of mob would drop on the ground I
think that'd be a cool way of getting
mobs that way it wouldn't be really
exploitable either like one worry with
ooh with including mob eggs into vanilla
is that people could use it to get cheap
XP or something like that this way you
know you're not creating a mob you're
just storing it oops
still getting used to there we go how
this all works then should we go up
again
that could be cool try to work something
out with this
OOP no needs to go here ah this is such
a mess so I'd be a vehicle way of doing
the stairs I'll mess with that a bit
off-camera here yeah I kind of like the
idea of doing something like this where
wraps wraps around a pole or something
and have when you want to the left one
to the right get up pretty quick
nice height up here plenty of space
underneath to put stuff it'd be good
maybe add another pole around here
somewhere yeah I'm going to play around
with this some more I think after after
this episode and try get a more official
shape and maybe mess with the colors a
bit and I think we think we'll have our
paths figured out all right guys I'm
going to get going for today but I did
pick out a comment for us Minecraft
developers do watch ethos lab snapshot
38 a item frames no longer despawn when
the player moves 20 bucks away that is
all that is not all the reason I bring
this one up today is because dinnerbone
actually responded to this very subject
today personally on the reddit and he
said like he has subscribed to me and he
does he did say he watches the
occasional video but as you can imagine
he's a busy guy he doesn't have a whole
lot of time to do things like that um
with this with this thing specifically
he said he made that change before he
saw my video he did watch my video but
this is like a change that a lot of
people would come up with not me
specifically like it's it's something a
lot of people would want so that's
that's how this got changed some things
like might be a bit more specific like
that whole mob egg thing I talked about
today
um by the way if that was implemented I
think it makes sense to have to weaken
the mobs first kind of like you do in
Pokemon I really hope that gets added
because I want mob eggs in vanilla if
that was the yet added it would probably
be because somebody watched my episode
and where a lot of people watch my
episode and tried to convey that idea to
to Dinnerbone or somebody else at Mojang
and again that would not be directly
because of me it would be indirectly and
yeah so that's the answer to that anyway
thanks for watching guys I'll talk to
you guys next time
have a good day