so I have a skill testing question for
you guys okay are you ready for this
alright check this out check this out ah
you see what's happening here you see
this you're paying attention okay so why
did the chicken cross the road why did
the chicken cross the road do you know
that's why so welcome back everybody
this is etho how's it going guys
if I didn't mess up the name of this
episode should be called musical portal
that is what we're going to be doing
first off here let me introduce you to
the concept as I get the stuff together
I guess I'll just grab all my redstone
stuff droppers yes so I tried this out
today and create it finally this is an
idea I've had for quite a while and
tried it out today it actually sounds
pretty cool so we're gonna build it in
our world here so I can show you guys
and so we have as a permanent feature
too because I think it's something I
want to keep in our world but we're
going to build it in the end just so
that there's no worries about it causing
leg or anything like that not at all
whatever so let's head on over to the
end okay oh we probably need more note
blocks actually so the concept is I
wanted to hear what it would sound like
if we built a redstone device that
randomly played music for us that's
that's the goal with this thing try it
it out it is pretty interesting I think
you guys are going to like this so we're
going to build the device by our end
portal in the end and it'll be a cool
thing that we hear every time we we
leave the end and return to the normal
world here so let's take our cool ice
road here oh and I'm hungry if only I
could inject food
liquidly liquidly yeah sure into into my
body but you know I never did check this
out I left a torch here let's just peek
really quickly to to mark the spot
because this is where the tape spiders
fell down and I saw there was a zombie
spawner here where's the cave spider
spawner this little sidetrack there's
definitely a tape spider spawner right
around here somewhere
very close I think maybe not I thought
there was is it above us maybe they're
not spawning now no it's not there
mmm-hmm let me look forward to you I'm
curious now okay I found it somehow I
did not see this when I was building the
tunnel even though it's right next to
the tunnel like right right next to it
uh-huh okay I guess because this wall
was here I didn't see it anyway let's
make our way over to the end and we will
start building this thing hmm
you know our end here is pretty messy so
I'm going to do some infrastructure to
it too we're going to try make it look a
little nicer I'm going to build a road
like a little path and an area around
the portal here out of ice and then
along the path is where we'll put the
note blocks like we'll line both sides
with note blocks that play music so this
will go from here to where is it where's
where do we come in at yeah over here
so probably go up to here I'll have an
elevator that will bring us up to this
path we're building and if we want to
leave the end it'll be really easy to
get out this eats road I'll probably
have to shorten it it doesn't need to be
this long anymore so I'll just like chop
it back maybe up to there or something
because it's in the way as well right
now
yeah I'm probably gonna die here so here
we go oh ah stupid Enderman it's fine
Ida needed to go back anyway I'm I'm
glad they did that need to get some dirt
mm-hmm there we go save me a trip Thank
You smashy smashy aha
so we got kind of a new look going on
here we got the packed ice and stone
brick I kind of like it maybe one or two
more colors mixed in would look cool got
like a drop down around the portal which
I like as well
this item stream will be able to lower
down to this level and get rid of this
garbage so that's cool but we're going
to put in the note block randomizers now
I'm going to show you how to do it
actually really simple so let's get to
it here basically I got the foundation
laid for it all along here I'm going to
put dirt so let me get the piano sound
from the note blocks because I think
that sounded the best I tried a couple
different ones today and pretty much
only like the piano but we'll experiment
with it just to play around with it put
note blocks on top that one you when we
hit them piano sound all right and I'm
gonna put 13 down I don't know much
about music theory okay so somebody else
might have better results with what I'm
doing here just because they know what
they're doing there's a lot of different
ways you could do it there's lots of
different probabilities you could have
there's different amounts of note blocks
different tunes and frequency of
activating the note blocks there's lots
of variables to this thing so there if
you want to try it play around with it
you might come up with something cool
but this is just what I did earlier
today and I thought it was pretty good
so do that's alright we are going to
make a bunch of randomizers here so
comparators going and terminer mad at me
again darn it
and down below we'll have droppers do
not use dispensers here they don't work
so you drop your schooling all along
we'll have to fill these with items this
is what determines our probability so I
tried earlier today having nine items in
here so which what we got to do let's
see and by the way I have this extra
repeater at the end here so that we can
lower the wiring one block and then
cover over it like oops like like this
kind of thing so we can hide the wiring
later let me go back up here my crafting
bench this is one of those times where I
really should have just made a second
crafting bench like I usually do and
have them like right next to each other
but I went all the way back here we need
what items
yes let's grab some more items and grass
blocks were work I guess some slabs sure
fences why not all right we need swords
all right so you need an item that will
transmit the power signal more than one
block so something that only has one per
stack like a sword and I did not do that
right oops okay so yeah well you get a
bunch of wooden swords ah man that ice
or I mean that glass I thought it was
gonna go off the edge here okay my
inventory is too full so in each of
these we need eight regular items that
stack to 64 right so we'll put that in
and this and this stick why not and the
item that will travel three blocks from
the comparator is the sword alright and
fence and what else do we have one more
junk item come on it's gotta be another
one
yeah there might have been a better
choice there above this will have
hoppers then and down this line more
wire this is what's going to activate
them all okay and then we're going to
hook a clock up to this and it's going
to constantly activate these randomizers
and if the sword goes into the hopper
then it will travel three blocks and
activate the note block all right so let
me finish this up here and we will try
it out oh all righty so we are pretty
much ready to go here we just have one
more thing left to do we have to tune
the note blocks so currently they're all
the same the default the way I did it
and again I don't really know what I'm
doing here I just added two to each each
one down the line so this one's at 0 1 2
1 2 3 4 5 oops sometimes I do that when
I'm counting 3 4 5 6 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 1 2
3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 and etc etc and it does
something like this when we're all done
so we are skipping one of the notes in
between each note block I don't know if
that's a problem or not
sounds interesting regardless I don't
know
so let me finish Sudanese and we'll
start started up here yay we are finally
ready to go here so get this all tuned
correctly right yeah that sounded right
we're gonna start it up here what do you
think it's gonna sound like random note
blocks being played I had no idea that's
why I wanted to try it earlier today
I thought it was going to be very
chaotic but I was I didn't think it was
too bad you can be the judge of it
yourself though so I'm only going to do
one side to start off with and then
we'll try adding a second side to it and
we'll see the difference okay here we go
aha so that's it basically um let's go
look at the hoppers here the redstone so
you see most the time the pulse is short
sometimes it gets extended here though
the repeater and that happens when the
sword goes into the item hoppers yep
there there there so every time that
happens it'll play the note fruit for
down here um so that means there's 13
note blocks
hey you don't you steal that dirt don't
you steal that dirt
13 note blocks and they're being played
one out of a nine chance that means on
average there's going to be like one and
a half no blocks activated each time or
so well that's that's probably not right
but quite often to note blocks or more
get played
sometimes only one sometimes none
there'll be a delay right there I think
there's a delay
you got like it's replaying there for
there that was a long delay there anyway
that's one set of them I kind of like
out sounds more with - to be honest
we'll start up the second one here just
adds more I don't more life to it I
guess with more being played
I don't know why but I could just listen
to this for so long because you never
know what's coming next with the sounds
that I'm I just think it's kind of neat
every now and then you'll just pick up
like these random patterns that happen
and it's cool
all right now just really quickly we're
going to try a couple random mixes just
to to see what it's like so we have now
piano and whatchamacallit bass drum bass
drums in bass guitar snare drums and
bass guitar now and I think this will be
our last one bass guitar and piano
but anyways guys I thought that was a
pretty cool little interesting project I
hope you felt the same way lots of
variables to it if you set this up
different than what I've done here
you'll probably get a different sound
out of it might sound better or worse I
don't know that's something I didn't
mention is you can also play around with
a tempo on it so this is sort of what I
had it at here just two ticks on the
repeater this is equivalent to 0.4
seconds between notes but you can you
know add more delay if you want and it
changes things quite a bit
ah if you set it to one something
something important happens so hoppers
they have a speed to them and if you try
to go too quickly they'll not they won't
be able to put the items out of it
anymore two ticks on the repeater is as
quick as the hoppers can run so yeah
items get stuck in here and then that
throws off the probability and
everything but yeah anyway let's go do
something else
ah you know we never did got 14 other
stars let's make some beacons here and
so I can actually use them last episode
we bought 15 Wizards
well actually was 14 turns out one of
them didn't spawn so that's why we were
short I have more obsidian there that's
good what am I looking for glass there
we go very low on sand right now I might
need to go harvest some soon all right
14 oh man oh oh did we not have enough
wow we did have enough glass even do we
have anymore
I have some melting right now yeah we
should have enough with that yeah we
should go get some sand sometime soon
because we have a lot of gunpowder just
laying around too and we can make that
into TNT but I am no longer getting my
sand from the same place anymore I need
to find a new place because I don't want
to keep scouring the landscape and I've
just about mined out all the sand there
actually um
14 beacons well I want one here for sure
because we just have the speed - I would
love to get haste - over here used to
have it but then I I borrowed it um what
else was I going to do
oh yeah enchanting I just going to do a
pick repair here and I got all this
quartz on me I'm going to mine this down
and we will head over to the Nexus and
just do a little bit of building there
you can put it anywhere here I'll but I
need the material don't I darn um
alright I'll have to go get some of that
um I'm at yeah I'm actually low on tools
right now I never thought that was going
to happen again but turns out I haven't
enchanted anything in a very long time
and just about used them all up
let's see and buy low on tools I mean I
still have a lot here obviously but most
of them are not like really good stuff
see efficiency for let's combine that
with this so we get efficiency five see
if that will work
Oh with the anvils gun
oh there we go
still has the chicken guts on it I feel
so bad nine levels okay that's not bad
okay we got enough levels for mining all
the courts uh let's call this pick let's
see what if we do reverse always check
21 okay let's do this
and let's call this one earth Slayer aha
oh man check this out this is like
perfection here we have a broken
efficiency for unbreaking 3 and
efficiency for still touch 1 it doesn't
get any better than that that maxes is
out efficiency 5 so touch 1 unbreaking 3
let's call this one in honor of terraria
we will not to area Terra Firma craft we
will call this our Pro pick all right
you see this this is why I don't really
mind getting garbage enchantments like
if you just get unbreaking 3 not a big
deal you just combine it and then you
have a good good shovel on your second
go ah usually I don't bother re-rolling
up my enchantments because of that
eventually it all kind of just works out
I find Wow I come upstairs and I see
this this guy he's been stealing my
ender pearls
somehow he walked onto the pressure
plate and activated it
one guy we got away with the - if I
didn't catch him okay guys so we're just
going to do a little bit of building
here at the Nexus I want to see what it
looks like with quartz running all the
way down you guys seem to really like
this combo with the the clay and the sea
lantern so that's cool or these people
in general I don't know if everybody did
something I've noticed thing though is
not a lot of people like these bricks I
don't know if it's because of how I'm
using them here I wasn't planning on
using them but I kind of worried that in
general people don't like them which
kind of makes me sad because I like
comfort I'm gonna wanted to use them for
a few things and I worried people are
gonna like anything I build with them um
I'll probably do it anyway okay so let's
keep going here and we will see what it
looks like when it's all done all right
so I pretty much got all the walls
finished here this is what its gonna
look like that's pretty good right I
like it do you guys like it please tell
me you like it I can't handle it if you
if you tell me you don't like it because
you said last episode you did I you'll
drive me crazy this is just the lower
part of it though that's actually going
to be about at least eight blocks taller
I believe so it's going to be a pretty
high room or high tunnel um got to do
the floor yet I haven't decided what I'm
using for that but anyway we got a color
scheme going down it goes from green to
blue I think that's cool and we might
have the colored beacons like right here
and have a rainbow effect going down as
we get enough beachings to do it then on
this end they'll probably be a tunnel
that connects to the other side here and
probably at the front too
um but anyway that's going to do it for
today guys let's read our comments
says etho how would you say these words
listed below now I believe these are
words that people often say different
from each other so I think that's why
why he's asking me this I think that's
the point behind it or she he or she um
so I'll tell you how I'm going to say
how I how I usually say them and how I
think they're correctly said so I say
aunt I'm pretty sure that correct way of
saying it is aunt if I was reading
formally I would say that um like in a
public setting for some reason I say
roots
some people say routes wash I don't know
if there's any alternate to that oil
theatre some people say theater like
they really put the theater I don't know
I say irons some people say I Ron I
don't know why salmon some people say
Salman cart Oh caramel I think some
people say caramel um fire water I don't
know how you would say those wrong water
I say sure I say data that really bugs
some people um because I believe it's
data but I also say lava and I say Java
and you'll notice there's a sort of a
connection there with the the middle a
and the end a and and for whatever
reason I have unity in my speech with
those words and so I always say data
ruin I say crown I think that's a
Canadian thing but I believe the correct
way is crayon right crayon toilets New
Orleans New Orleans ah New Orleans there
we go
some people say New Orleans or something
I forget there there's something that
really bugs the work or leaners or
whatever they're called anyway pika
not pecan pecan both again probably
spitting image Alabama I say Alabama
lawyer I think some people might say
lawyer I don't know
I say coupon some people say coupon with
a you coupon mayonnaise syrup pajamas
PJs cots aha
there we go that's how I say it and how
I think some people say it and what I
think is correct
anyway that's the list so thank you for
watching guys I hope you enjoyed today's
episode I will see you again in the next
one
oh yeah and I also did a little bit more
building on this oops I don't know if
you can tell but yeah I think I did this
part here with a stone but yeah see you
guys again in the next one have a good
day bye bye