[Music]
well this is interesting
i uh i think i stumbled into the most
intense staring contest ever
they're looking through walls at each
other
greetings everybody this is etho
no i'm not looking at him um i was still
here from
last episode and i got an idea for
something i want to try
just to see how it looks i think we
might build around here i was
going to start the furnace room maybe
that's what i'm thinking for today i
might do some other stuff
about what i was thinking of i was in
this area
and i kind of like this this arch here
this really wide arch i have
obviously excuse me
obviously i still have my morning voice
morning voice gone um
not the way to start a recording uh
obviously
i'm going to change this but what i want
to see
is how it would look if i made another
arch that went over
this walkway here so let's
let's do a duplicate um
do that and oh you know what i need i
need half slabs
oh yeah also with this uh since
the mobs are going to be able to spawn
on upside down half slabs which is what
i have in these
corners uh to make this mob proof
for 1.3 i'll need am i out of fences
nope there i need to put something in
these corners so how's this gonna look
should i do that i wonder there they are
um
yeah what else could i use like i could
use these or these but they wouldn't
really match would they
i might yeah i think i'm just going to
do this
yeah good enough okay sometimes i jump
over these
so i don't close it if i plan on being
back here again soon
also another thing i need is crafting
tables
a serious flaw i made when building this
i did not plan to put any
crafting tables anywhere so if i need to
craft anything
there is none like
i have no specific spots for any around
here which is a problem
for sure okay that's a stair
then half slab half slab
um then the fence would come around like
that
with that
just want to see how it looks
i could do it like one here
and one here as well but that might be
too many arches
i'm not sure
do this
and then i would duplicate this effect
as well probably
what do you guys think is that a good
entrance to the furnace room
maybe i'll try it i'll put four of them
i'll put one for here and one for here
because i still got to figure out what
i'm doing
with this ceiling i really like this uh
curved feeling i go i got going with the
ceiling here so i may try to keep that
with however i finish this
okay you know what i actually like this
quite a bit having four of them
looks better than i thought it would
especially this one here is good
for the furnace room it's it's not as
wide as this one or
this one um i tried it for this side as
well but i don't like that
so it's just too much especially looks
weird from
here so we're going to take that out
but for the furnace room i think i'll
keep that
although like with this one just having
a single wide one looks pretty good
maybe yeah i'll just put it back to how
it was here
get our fences
so i i think that looks good coming back
it's not too enclosed
and then i could do something with the
ceiling here pretty easily because it's
it's got four sides then to work with
um what i wanted to try is maybe
like the supports pillars for the arches
these
i wonder how it'll look if i changed it
to
different block
[Music]
hmm
i don't know
these corners have to put something in
these corners as well where they join
anyway i'll leave it like this for a
while
oop i'll probably think of something
and i'm sure you will give tips too so
what i'm gonna do i'm gonna start
clearing out my furnace room area
[Music]
the only thing i know about it is i
wanted a window
put that in long ago i don't know why
but i just want a window there
just like that 3x3
so that's one thing we've got to keep it
in it
i'll probably expand it a little bit
further this way and
this way and since it's a furnace room
it should be built out of stone
type blocks maybe stone bricks
but anyway i'll work at clearing the
space and the shape and
then we will start figuring out what
we're gonna do all right guys
checked it out this feels about right i
like the size this feels like
the size of furnace room i would want
like
you don't need too many furnaces you
really don't i think between
8 and 16 is ideal anything beyond that
you probably won't use them anyway and
if it's
if you don't have enough though
sometimes it can be annoying
but yeah we got our cool view through
the window this was further back than i
thought though so i may try to bring it
in
another block or two
if you go out over here
it does seem like it's a little close to
this bridge too so
that wouldn't be terrible um
this thing hmm
it doesn't like this is one of the first
things i built here and it's not
it doesn't match it's sandstone do you
guys think i should change that
it doesn't bother me a whole bunch but
if i ever take down that wall
i don't i probably won't but if i ever
was to
i wouldn't want to look at that all the
time
um anyway
yeah the furnaces will probably go
on this wall and this wall and this wall
i'll leave
open or i'll put chests here with blaze
rods in or something
but i have hit the storage room area i
forgot about this
i'll have to take that into
consideration when building i can't get
too close to it
so the furnaces probably start
either here or here
now i was hoping to include redstone
into this project
somehow just to make it more fun and
flashy
always makes it more interesting i was
going to
reconsidering making a shutter system
for the furnaces similar to this
that's one possibility another thing i'm
most likely going to do is this gimmicky
thing here where
when the furnaces turn on the lights go
on
uh no blocks play and when they're done
lights go off and no blocks play again
type thing
give you a little indicator signal of
when
the furnaces are done clicking
um so let's go let's go see how we have
to rig that up
we'll go to the old grass patch
where i do most of my testing
if i can find it there it is
all right
well let's do it over here you like my
canopy
oh yeah um
yeah so we'll have our furnace
and then we will oh you know what i
forgot it's pistons
those are all regular is there a slime
ball in one of these
chests
nope okay i'm gonna have to cut it
all right i got him let's do it you've
probably seen something like this before
or exactly this even where you have the
t-flip-flop bud switch behind the
furnace
torch there that's
and then we need some redstone
there there
another torch
mist there we go
this comes back uh torch sends power to
up here
and i think you do it like this you have
a repeater
uh two blocks up and you need
redstone i think i have the exact same
type of t-flip flop or t-bud or
bud flop whatever they're called in my
jukebox setup
and so if you updates the bud switch
such as when the
furnace turns on and off
now let's get yeah we want an indicator
light above the furnace right above it
if possible so we'll put it there
and i think we'll have to run that down
okay so now like
the furnace turns on light comes on
goes off it goes off
so i'm going to put that behind every
furnace the thing is
we can't put them side by side if we do
this
with this setup i'm sure there's ways of
doing it um
i bet you some grass just grew or died
there
um but yeah we'll just have furnaces
side by side
maybe four on one wall and four on
another that way we can have eights
and it should be pretty good
yeah so with this setup with the storage
room there i think the closest we can
have the furnace to this right wall
is over here although i do want to check
above
if we're doing these uh t flip flop
okay uh maybe this is the closest we can
have it then
if we were to go four on this wall it
would take us to
here
um
i still have no idea what i'm doing with
this if i'm if i'm doing the boat
elevator stuff
still or not i'm not sure
but it would be in the way
hmm unless i go out further this way
actually this wire is going to be in the
way even if i put it here probably
huh okay let me think about this
and in a mere split second i have
figured out what i want to do
so this is where four takes us on this
side and then
one two three fourth one would be here
and a fifth one would potentially be
here
so what i'm going to i'm gonna have
three
on this wall okay
and then i'll have five on this wall
we're gonna take this thing out
it's not doing anything it's it's of no
value to us right now i hate removing
something so old in my world
but the idea isn't really thought out
so and it's causing problems now so
let's get rid of it
and even if i was to do it i would want
it to be built out of iron
bars i'm pretty sure instead of glass
panes
or else glass blocks or something else
anything but glass panes okay
so we're gonna do it five furnaces
these will have to be here we have to i
put
i put this here to c and it
there's indeed a problem um
there's a wire right there and
right there and we would need to put
wire on top here so
we should move it out one more block to
there
the furnaces would go here here here
there and
one more on top there
and the rest of the space behind is
going to be for the wiring
and we will make it all blend together
nicely
oops
because i'll probably have to adjust
this water a bit
excellent day so we have our eight
furnaces our eight for an eye all ready
here with the t-buds hooked up
um actually let's try one
let us try one
what should we make let's make coal
charcoal
light goes off oh yeah that's inverted
that's right
and
[Music]
wow fences burned for a long time
there we go works like a champ so we
gotta switch these
uh just update the the buds
an extra time
okay
all right so off by default
um i guess what we should do next
oops
gotta do this one uh i wanna hook up
note blocks this i don't know
where or what i should do with that i'm
not very good with note blocks
um probably only need
two or so to make a a tune and try
make everyone a different tone or
something
not that
now i'll worry about it later uh what
we'll do
let's figure out how the front's gonna
look um
should we i'm not gonna do the shutter
thing i don't think
just wondering if we should copy that
look
um oh yeah you know what i want to do
actually is make the floor lower so
like this one it goes down half a block
let's do the same for this one
let's take that
maybe let's end this here whoops
grab these
okay and then it will
switch to stone perhaps
and we will work on including
other types of blocks once we have our
shape figured out so we'll just use
stone brick
for now and see how it looks
should we maybe we should put stairs to
get down
right there and the full block in the
corner and then the floor will be half
slabs we'll we'll try to make a pattern
using a different type of block later
but for now we'll just do solid
okay and
and i guess probably put some lighting
in the ceiling
also yeah this will look good with the
furnace is slightly off the ground
but not a full block up i think that's a
good look
i'll put full blocks here
maybe don't really know what i'm doing
um what would look good
how's this look if we just enclose it
like that
[Music]
hmm
nope let's try
put stairs at the top here
that's a little bit better um
what about stairs at the bottom
and
we'll just hide that i'll have to update
them again and sync it
afterwards yes
yeah that's not bad um
[Music]
still not entirely happy with it
that's not bad how would it look if we
do this
from this angle um hmm
[Music]
oh you know what would be cool maybe
let's grab some of these
and put them in between
that's kind of cool
yeah okay um i guess i'll do the same
for this one and i'll get back to you
all right i'm going to give you the full
effect of it here we're walking
in and oh
oh that's nice
so yeah that's pretty good already as is
but i want to make a few more changes
there's some things i don't like
mainly can't see this furnace
can't see it from out here see every
single one except
that one so this has to go for sure
um
and with this extra space here would
almost be good to have
some sort of entrance into this wire
room area
in case i have to do maintenance or if
if people want to check it out or
anything like that
because there is no other way with the
way i have it right now
you'd have to dig in
okay anyway back to here
um
[Music]
can we put over here how would that look
is that better
better
this has to go too
oh i hope you didn't hear that
and to be consistent i would probably
have to change this one
oh that looks weird now
uh how would you how would you join it
i guess full block and whatever i do
here maybe
no can't use that stuff um
maybe a fence of some sort
or
[Music]
probably not the wooden one maybe the
netherrack
uh anyway what i thought for behind here
leaves i think leaves would look really
good back there
mainly the jungle ones if we have them
no where are all my jungle leaves
well we'll try with these first
otherwise it's just gray want some color
in here
hmm is this a swamp no it's forest
i gotta try the jungle ones these ones
are too thin
been in this area for a while we caught
ouch quite a few of these guys that guy
shot in my face
oh oh i probably messed up the track
didn't i dang it
jungle leaves yay
oh okay let's see how this looks now
i put pumpkins in two that way if all
these lights are off we'll get lighting
from the walls
uh through the leaves i think that'll be
good
that's better they're a lot thicker
that's for sure
yeah it's pretty good uh let's
let's be sure though let's seal this all
in
that and then
wait yeah that's right
then the
yeah that's good i'm gonna do them all
we'll see how it looks
you get you get a better feel when you
do them all
it's uh it's hard to tell it's just one
it's that versus this
or this
i think this is my favorite i put the
pumpkin one lower and one higher so you
don't see the orange like you do on this
one
okay i got all the leaves in place and
i'll give you the effect of seeing the
the furnace room going down these stairs
that looks pretty good it's not
overwhelming the green it's
it's hidden behind the gray of the fence
so it's
that's actually a really good look i'm
going to use that for more things i
think
yeah let's look through the window
haven't checked that in a while oh yeah
the question now do i keep this as stone
or what do i do
i never really decide what i'm doing
with the walls in here like if i'm
keeping them
the the stone look and just replacing
all the dirt and that with stone or
or should i do the whole cave with some
other type of block item
i'm not sure um
and then like fill in the holes like
that shouldn't be there that hole there
and maybe smooth stuff out a bit more
anyway uh yeah so the effects
you put something in to cook
we'll do another one of these light
comes on
which is a bit pointless because
obviously you get the visual effect from
the furnace
you can see the fire through it and the
furnace also emits light so it's not
like it's doing a whole lot
but it just helps to emphasize it
and uh it's easy to hook up because we
got
just the way that that particular
tea bud works it's easy to put a piece
of clothes or
a lamp at the end of it like that but
the
the main idea is to put note blocks in
here
we will put those i'm expecting
above like we can easily
put a wire on top of this and make that
go to some notebox above or something
uh only a few though not many
but the main the main point of this
i'll show you
i'm going to run a master wire behind
here
on all of these
which will connect them all together
i'll not connect them all together it
will
tell me if any of the furnaces are going
because if any of those are on this this
wire is going to be powered by these
torches so
we will have a main wire
and then we will send that signal to
other places
in the cave so we'll we'll probably send
it to this room
first of all we might put some indicator
lights in the floor
and yeah so when
say we smelt we have something smelty in
all eight of these we won't get
signaled until they're all done with
this way
otherwise we would get signals for each
individual one
but yeah like we might have a signal up
here
some some type of indicator light or i
was thinking of using that zelda soon
zelda tune excuse me
for that and also we could have could
run the wire over here
just a few places around so we can see
just it's not hard i have lots of space
underneath this ground like i don't have
much stuff
below here that i have to worry about
running wire or anything
plenty of space
aha so that's the furnace room as it is
we will continue this
project next time probably
or maybe yeah probably next time
of course as always give me your
feedback we're gonna put a door here
probably an iron door and i think i
might change this around
some somewhat yet but anyway we'll work
on that next time thank you for watching
everybody
i hope you're having a good day and i
will see you next time