your readings everyone as usual this is
etho I'm happy to announce that we now
have subtitles for our episodes isn't
that amazing I thank you thank you very
much I thought you'd like that
you better be amazed I spent 30 levels
on that intro so yeah I'm rocking the
new snapshot here a week fifty a-and
there's been some quite a few new
features and changes in the game we've
got the 3d items I believe if you throw
a statute gives you a different look to
kind of a stack look of items so yeah
that's that's pretty cool man it's been
if you think about it like they skip two
or three weeks without a snapshot then I
didn't get the snapshot from last week
because it seemed kind of buggy so for
me it's been over a month since I've
gotten any changes in the game so I'm
I'm excited and there's been there's
been a good number of changes from what
I can tell so I am going to mess around
with those just a little bit today get
those away oh yeah I put the advil there
now oops that worked out pretty good
with this waterfall thing one that I
thought was really noteworthy is they
changed how protection works on armor or
something they nerfed it somehow so
either yeah either they nerfed
protection or they boosted the other
attributes like fire resistance
and all that stuff is before protection
did exactly what fire protection did
except it also did exactly what blast
protection did and all the other
enchantments it was all them combined so
it was very overpowered so it's it's
good they nerfed it but at the same time
I'm kind of sad because not going to
learn that learn how it changes the game
because it gives you a huge benefit
knowing how damage is calculated in this
game if you're playing any PvP game like
like you'll notice if you guys watched
UHC the other seasons you know I was
kind of soso about getting an enchanting
table but then they'll like the last
season I I wanted an enchanting table
like I had to get it before we we fought
anybody that's because I knew when
enchantments did them and how important
they were so yeah I'm not so I got kind
of mixed feelings about this text on the
screen thing too it's good for new
players I'd say but I think they should
include an option to disable it and
there's also a problem like every time
you use something it seems to display on
this screen not just when you select it
it doesn't do when you place it at least
like every time I hit something with a
diamond sword it's going to say diamond
sword I chose this try it on our slide
let's see if we can get them to launch
for class oh there they go
there wasn't as bad as the time before
though man that was crazy
you're flying all over the place the ass
is dining sword every single time you
use it which is a bit overkill so
hopefully I have a future who's disable
it and also if it's enabled that it
doesn't show it every time later I do
really like the 3d item I drop so
apparently that doesn't it's really
taxing pain and all that much more
that's cool that's cool anyway let's get
on to that mushroom farm thing down over
here wanted to work on that a bit today
and there's one other thing I really
want to mess around with is the
fireworks man there's a whole bunch of
guys down here slimes everywhere I tell
you another big one in the back every
time I come down here this slime okay
give me one moment I'm going to clean up
the mess here mmm you know I killed all
the slimes even the ones in the farm
upstairs and I still hear more sounds
like they're in a cave or something up
above here maybe oh no it's getting
quieter interesting oh you know where
they are run over there okay duh alright
guys let's get this going here so I went
through and I found out where I want to
position the mushrooms if we have eight
of them so everywhere I put a brown
mushroom is where I marked so that means
like each of these needs a seven by
seven space to grow
so that means the entrance would be here
right there guys
okay and the general plan I have with
this farm is I want lights to come on
and do things when the mushrooms grow so
I'm going to force them to girl and
that's that's about it it's not going to
be super fancy or anything another
change with the snapshot actually is
nice my shovels my wonderful shovels
they don't work like they used to
I actually have to use axes I think I
hate it
let's try it oh yeah doesn't work at all
somebody said it was like efficiency two
or three but it's it doesn't work at all
now pics don't work either Oh No
aha so I have to carry an axe around
which is proper ideas but you know this
is so convenient just use a shovel I
wonder yeah let's see how it works on
our farm doesn't work on mushrooms
either so we need an axe for mushrooms
that's the proper tool form and gate
well it's important to keep in mind yes
this building each of the mushrooms in
need a 7x7 area to grow so we want this
314 wide and it is currently one two
three four five six seven eight
whoops 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 so we got to
get rid of one one block with so I think
we're going to put a wall right here and
then we'll have to shave this all this
stone down and put a wall here let's
just mark this side that didn't go in
the right place now goes here okay
so I had an idea for a look for the
walls alright let's try that out first
or no no no you know what we got to do
first let's get I brought some grass
we're gonna try grass blocks and just
see what it looks like but we got to got
to get that growing pretty quickly it
takes forever start off with that
I think the slime farm is above here I
think that's why we're doing so many
just it's probably going through two or
three slime chunks alright so we get
some grass going in time it should grow
and fill us out if we like it we'll keep
it if not we'll do something else over
here it's still desert over here really
over here is forest though yeah that's a
better green ok yeah so the look for the
walls I want to try out I brought
brought wood you can try either this oak
or the Spruce forts fences dirt sugar
cane ice for water and we might need
that too ok so if a mushroom is here we
want this as a sinner let's try it with
with these first this is what I want to
do I want to have all right right I need
an axe darn oh man I wonder if I have
any enchanted still I haven't used an
axe in so long let's try this out first
I gonna we're gonna go look for one
let's go look just the moment I'm pretty
sure I still had one left fortune - I'm
breaching 3 come on I'm sure I had one I
bet you it's shoots up its my trees
there I'm gonna go look one sec spider
jockey
hey they don't the spiders don't chase
you during the day that's awesome
it is not there and it's not there so I
don't have one darn get new plan get to
level 18 one shot
yeah just about there 18 awesome so I'm
going to combine these two and we're
going to get our acts that way okay
efficiency 3 braking 335 no way 18 yes
we have our ax okay we got our X we got
our X now we can finally build for reals
so I was thinking going up three blocks
let's try it out
Oh much better much much better I guess
yeah I think it's going to have to be an
even number because seven by seven I
think we have to have a 2 wide post
before the next one let's just see how
this looks
we can change it to later okay something
like that let's just dig this out a
little bit then I want to have can you
not use oh you can't use the pick on
dirt even anymore this is getting really
specific uh-huh well I guess people
can't be so lazy anymore alright so I
want that all dirt
and get that all dirt will have water
here so let's get our ice will probably
hide some lighting back here to maybe
what do we have to yeah we have to
actually use it I'll pick on this hmm
this is going to take some while to get
used to I tell you and then yeah
basically I want to do sugar cane just
see how this looks
oops so it'll grow up like that and then
have fences just to give it a nice
looked nice nice general look to this a
little bit of depth how's that mmm how
do we feel about that for the walls kind
of good I think I want to experiment
with different materials though so I'm
going to try the dark wood and then we
might try out planks and maybe a few
other things okay I set up a little
example of what it would look like with
the spruce wood I think I'd prefer to
oak more personally I'm going to try
with planks now all right this is
regular planks it's pretty good but I
think the other colors are going to be
better yeah that's the spruce planks
they're they're pretty good I like them
a little bit more okay here we have the
birch wood and I I really like birch
wood in this game it's a nice block
that's pretty good
I also brought eight mushroom blocks
with me that's all I had I'm just
curious to see what these look like
might be fitting in a mushroom farm
although
hmm so you imagine what it would look
like if it was all that that's pretty
weird hmm maybe all right last but not
least here we have the wild strawberry
of the wood family we have the jungle
wood it's pretty good too
kind of got that pinkish hue to it now
we got to make a decision what do we
want to actually choose I was looking
over the video I think it's a see
they're going to be the mushroom block
one I thought that was kind of cool
difference or the spruce planks I think
I prefer the Spruce planks what was that
lots of slime I think I prefer the
Spruce planks the most because they make
this fenced area look like it's really
bright because the trim is darker than
the fence color and that's kind of what
I'm going for here so we'll do the
spruce planks we might want to change
this also instead of making it too wide
here maybe you make it six blocks for
the fence and then just the one one
white thing
and the final choice was drumroll please
did that that the spruce wood there we
go I think it looks pretty good as
messing around with the these pillars in
the middle different stair patterns and
then I decide I should not do that
do you know why because then the fences
don't connect so that was a bad idea but
yeah it's worth a shot anyway and I went
back behind here I made everything to my
OCD acceptance level I made everything
stone I still have to change these
torches I probably want to put either
glowing pumpkins or or glowstone or
lamps or something back there that's
what's giving it its brightness and then
I'll solid fill this with something to
this to block gap but yeah I think this
is going to work out pretty good so
moving on
while there's also the choice of what to
do at the end
should we just have two more of those or
what I don't know
or we could maybe have that style but
maybe change the shape or I don't know
because it's somewhere we got to
incorporate bonemeal and dispensers and
or chess or something and maybe an axe
or something to cut down the the
mushrooms but anyway I have lost all my
markers because the mushrooms are
spreading for some reason and I think
they're up ruining each other so yeah
what I wanted to do with this I think
this is this is one advantage of only
making it five blocks I still might make
it six but one advantage of making it
five is I can easily tell where the
center is although I might mark that on
the ground somehow well yeah using a lot
the lights here I probably will so I
think what I want to do have lights in
this shape get a shovel do like a little
corner corner highlighter thing around
the mushroom do that for each mushroom
and then below will light that up with
redstone torches we would need oh man
I'm out of stone brick think what we'll
do is we'll just uh I kind of want to
set up a clock here where these lights
will start flickering if the mushrooms
drone I don't have a redstone let's see
what it looks like lit up
okay right here and right there there
and there
that's pretty cool I may also want to
put a like a border all along the side
just something one wide could either do
it out of the spruce planks as well to
see what that looks like or we could try
change it up with something else
oops hmm might want to try to change it
but anyway I'm going to install the
lights and maybe try pick out a trim for
the bottom
oh man enter man he's having a bad day
it's not happy I wonder why they do that
I've seen that happen a few times it's
like they're mad never looked at him
just freaking out all right so I got
some of these pumpkins let's see what
they look like oh I can't place it coz
they need a block below darn that's
annoying that means I have to change all
these well not change it but you know
what I mean I'll have to do that and do
that hey then do that then do that and
that's and yeah all right let's just see
what I don't want to be able to see the
face of the pumpkin from the other side
so let's just check that out
voices coming together little pretty
quick
hopefully he doesn't steal these things
then why I get the pumpkins and I'm
gonna put the blocks between here could
be pretty much covered though I would
think now you can see them a little bit
it's not bad
ooh yeah I can live with that I need to
do a big glowstone hunt again I'm really
running who really running low on
glowstone way I think I can live with
that
okay so I'm going to do that for all
them and I could go find some more lamps
because I just used all my glowstone up
okay I got all the lights and now it
might be too many lights I'm not sure
there's a lot of lamps so that's like
over a stack I think well one problem I
think we're having here is the grass
doesn't really go well with the lights
so we should maybe try some other things
I have a little setup here to show you I
have a tea bud switch up there just go
up real quick yeah this is our tea blood
switch much it's the same same one I
used for my jukebox ah
and the idea is if a block goes next to
that piston it'll trigger a circuits and
then when it's removed it'll undo it or
whatever so when I grow this mushroom it
should grow exactly that height so that
it will trigger that that piston up
there Oh hmm
hmm might have figured it's still wrong
it's one short huh mmm what to do about
that I can force the mushroom to grow
taller if I have a block here I don't
know if I want it taller this was
unexpected okay my choices are either
have a block to force it to go taller or
lower the piston one block problem about
trying to lower it one block is well no
I could pull it off if I really want
it'll look weird though I think I'm not
really sure what I'm doing about that
yet but I also wanted to try a change of
floor something else I want to do let's
try the birch planks on the outside of
this and then the Spruce ones on the
inside you know what I mean so I have a
have a square this going around it look
like them it almost look like my
silverfish farm I guess if I if I mix
these two blocks together that marble
look will make these dark might be
better than the grass
hmm goes with the lamps better that's
for sure do one more to get an idea of
what it would look like and yeah we got
to go mess with those fireworks don't we
we're running out of time for this
episode so maybe we'll we'll just leave
it at this for today and go go play
around with the fireworks for a little
bit whoa keep doing that that's the
possibility what if we just make it all
all this wood
oops
poor mushroom all right mmm I think was
better mixed so yeah I need a block to
force the group taller if I want to go
that way I could I think I'd just use a
sign even have a sign up there somewhere
and that would do the trick
where else have a piston right here okay
well that's about where we're going to
leave it for today if you guys have
ideas suggestions let me know it's also
messing around maybe I want to do
regular planks instead of the birch just
to tone it down a bit but yeah that's
where we're at for right now uh yeah
it's firework Tim guys I'm excited I
haven't really I haven't messed with
them at all yet so this is gonna be fun
for me I haven't I've seen a few videos
of the fireworks but like only when they
first came out and I think in the videos
I saw people weren't doing them right
because I read the wiki and you can do a
lot of cool things with them it looks
like so fireworks start you can mix that
makes it a large one
do that dad you can get all these
different shapes and effects and colors
and it's going to be a lot of fun I
think mix dyes orange yes if you're
going to do orange you should just use
orange show right so yeah we're going to
make a few of these and then to actually
make the rockets you have have between
one two or three gunpowder
let's do three on this one and you can
have multiple stars I love fireworks
guys I got to say that so I'm excited to
have these in the game flight duration
three small ball large ball that's cool
it lists every single one maybe we'll
make a few of them let's make a really
really cheap one there's there's white
ones this is like wait no it's like the
lowest power one you can make I want to
make just a few to mess around with it
Gold effects I think I wonder if you mix
effects - let's make a red we had a
feather no so you can only have one
effect burst first one sounds cool so
you can't have like a big burst then too
bad ooh
yeah large ball I'm gonna make just a
few of them here and we'll we'll set
them off I'm like a kid in a candy shop
right now this is awesome okay we got
this is the lowest one the white low
powered rocket one let's check this out
oh my goodness
that's so awesome okay I think I found
my new favorite thing in the game right
now oh my goodness is that my fade one
no this is my fade one okay I made a
fancy one that fades colors too it's got
two bursts a large ball super high
flight oh this is awesome with ones this
oh this is the one with all the balls
there's five balls in this one oh my
I only saw two though okay I love the
fireworks that is amazing so I think
yeah I'll tell you what I want to do
with the fireworks there is oh oh no
don't blow up darn it
making a mess there is okay we got the
river by hearing right guys then oh yeah
protection doesn't work so good anymore
I'm taking a lot of damage there's this
Lake here
yeah I should have made one more
firework to try this I think I could
probably rig it so I can launch
fireworks from the water though and I
want to put on a firework show for the
500k subscribers special hook up some
dispensers down here there's a tape here
and I don't think I'm going to hook it
up to a timer I think I'm gonna try set
it up to work on a random timer but I'll
shoot them out of the lake and I think
it's going to be awesome so that's our
fun project plan and I'll try to get
that done as quick as I can
but yeah fireworks
I love the fireworks well I'm sorry guys
but it's that time again we have to wrap
up the episode but first let's read the
comments so number one comment for today
whoa dear etho since you have been doing
a Survival Series since 2008
you've been playing on hard and you have
started playing FTB actually oh yeah
yeah you know what I did start on
playing on I did start playing on hard I
forgot
have you ever thought of doing a
hardcore let's play or a single-player
FTB series the problem with like just
doing a straight-up hardcore series is
you can just hide in a hole and you will
never die so you need to have a drive to
put you in a risky situation so just a
straight-up hardcore world probably not
going to happen I need some kind of goal
one thing I thought of for like a short
series is maybe try get all the
achievements in the game as quickly as
possible in hardcore mode so that would
involve killing the ender dragon and
doing a whole bunch of other things just
seeing how quick I didn't do that sort
of like a speed challenge I guess but I
never got around to that but ya need a
goal if I do do something like that
doo doo
number two Issa question I was digging
in a mine and I find two silverfish
block does it mean I does it means I
find stronghold because I searched
around
but there was nothing what do you think
thing what do you think there was a
patch recently where they changed it so
random blocks all over the place will
have silverfish
I don't know how rare it is I haven't
generated any new world to really
experience it myself but yeah just
randomly digging you'll encounter
silverfish now so that's pretty cool and
that's it's two comments whoo
I'm going to call it end for the day
thank you for watching as always
everyone and I hope you have a great day
oh yeah