hello everybody this is etho thank you
for joining me again as we play some
minecraft today you get your snacks
ready come on go get em pause the video
go get them what about your smile you
got your smile on get it on come on
let's go here we go so I talked about
this before a little bit and to start
off this episode I think we should work
on our transportation system for our
cave system for our man cave and I
mentioned I wanted to do a bunch of
stuff with water so that's one aspect
want to set up kind of water roads etes
roads still water around this place so I
can travel by boat I also want to have
pathways to walk on of course so I can
travel by foot and some people were a
little worried that I wasn't going to do
anything with my car tracks don't worry
we will have mine carts in the mix too
but I don't know how it is where you
guys live but here they're a little bit
silly how they build houses they they
build the houses first and then later
they build all the roads and it causes a
huge problem because now you got people
around while they're building the roads
they should do the roads first like they
do in America or at least places I've
seen in America so I've been hesitating
to do that in my world here I should
really do my transportation systems
first and then build my little projects
around them so that it all flows nicely
the problem I think I'm going to have is
getting a nice balance between having
water walking and minecart tracks
I might have to expand areas in the cave
to make it work
but anyway we will make it work somehow
first thing I want to do is make a boat
elevator to the surface here that was my
plan so
so let's do it mmm well bad news
it seems minecraft doesn't like us today
we got a big problem here I thought it
would be a good idea to back up my world
before we started that water stuff I did
that and everything got corrupted and I
cannot fix it so when I try to put when
I tried to play my world after that it
was running at about 0.1 frames per
second no matter what I did I tried
deleting my folder and all that stuff
and reacts tracting my backup and the
backup is just corrupt my world got
corrupted so we're back to wherever the
world was in episode 109 was my most
recent backed up before that so some
stuff is gone mostly mostly some of the
farm stuff we did and I'll have to fix
it sometime off camera I'm pretty sure I
can I have a pretty good memory for
those kind of things but yeah this is
different a lot of my resources are gone
to now I did some caving before can't
remember I think it's too small right
now I have to make it bigger
possibly oh maybe not oops all day well
that didn't help things
yeah problems so I'll have to fix that
and of course everything down below here
is gone our ladder is back here our
freakin pigs are back and yeah what can
you do
got to make backups more often I just
realized we lost the slime farm too so
I'll have to re hollow that out and see
now if you remember from last episode
but I showed this chest with all the
goodies in and now it's a lot more empty
unfortunately oh well uh it happens
areas aren't lit up now too but we're
going to work on on the water system
today anyway so what I'll do here first
kind of eat away some of this cliffside
make it more straight
all right there we go so now we'll set
up our boat elevator and we'll do the
new style with the glass panes so it's
just a 3x3 type thing let's see that I
might remove some of some more of this
cliff because it doesn't look as good
when the glass connects like that the
yeah I just gotta go all the way up
doing this and then fill in the center
oops with water
okay
whoa-ho-ho
did not mean to - they're all done
actually took a lot of glass more than I
was expecting there it is it goes oh
it's probably 20 blocks high or so and
now we just need to fill it with water
I'm I don't know what would look best
but I think I'll just put signs up here
for now to hold the water in place kind
of looks weird yes but just for now
anyway we'll figure something out and we
just place water all the way up got two
more buckets with me
yeah so what can we talk about while we
do this I did kind of announce that I'm
doing a survival map now I started
working on it having fun doing that
there's going to be a lot of traps guys
a lot of traps I wasn't really sure how
many I was going to do at first but you
know they just keep coming to me so I'm
guessing there's going to be a lot of
traps throughout the whole map I keep
coming up with some pretty creative
ideas for traps it's like yeah one of
those things I have a knack for I think
should be a lot of fun if you don't mind
dying all the time it'll probably take
me forever to finish the map though if I
do ever finish it - hopefully I do it's
going to be a lot like vex super hostile
series that's what it's inspired from
but obviously it'll have my own style to
it I don't want to copy him directly or
anything like that going to be a lot of
mechanisms and it's lots of Pistons
stuff should be cool okay so now we just
need like a pool that we can drive our
boats into here to test it out so I'll
do that and then we'll try it no no no
it's going to work man you just you just
kind of imagine it a little bit you'll
come up with your boat and then they'll
be like a lake up here with rivers and
stuff on the surface everything will be
accessible by boat it's my dream I'm
going to make it happen you'll see and
then it'll work trust me what we'll do
is we'll have a like a free drop here -
for getting down so from the lake
there'll be a free drop to a lake below
the
we'll not late but a pool of water below
and that's how you'll get down this is
just for coming up and it should work
out nicely just see this trust me you'll
see just give me time all I need is time
alright we're going to try it out let's
make sure it works so you should just be
able to steer your boat into here no
problem I'll take you up up here and
then there'll be a lake or something to
connect to is the plan
in front of you somewhere
uh-huh anyway ah I'm going to take a
little break from this maybe y'all
rehaul out the slime farm or something
cool slime farms back then take long to
remake and it's almost exactly the same
so apparently you can use your sword now
to get slime balls from these guys which
is cool and we have six slime balls what
can we do with six slime balls hmm maybe
we'll try make a mushroom farm or
something I worked on that wheat and cow
farm too and I got a fair bit done
staying closer to the way it was
probably won't take me long to recover
from this loss ah one nice thing I died
before when I had a ton of stuff on me I
got from taming so now I have a second
chance of getting that stuff again
without dying so there's some benefits
to having to resort to my backup here
yeah so I think I'm going to try make
some mushroom farms here just very
simple ones I know you can get mushrooms
by harvesting the giant mushrooms that
you grow with bone meal net but I'm
going to try make the old-style
mushroom farms even though they're nerf
now there's a there's a limit now only
five mushrooms can grow within a nine by
nine by three area I believe so these
are just going to be really small farms
I think the way I want to do it is I
want to have a pressure plate to harvest
stick it over here get started
that will stay in here and then let's go
in and it's going to hollow out an area
here for the mushrooms to grow let's see
how to do it I think I think I'll just
make a little tiny Oh shape thing so
have we'll have the water here and it'll
go left and right around a block I'll
have more blocks here yeah so if we have
water here it'll flow around and stop
like that that's how I want to do it put
that there for now and so I'll put some
sticky pistons down here like so
block one over here
block okay and polish this up a little
bit and these will be special blocks I
got to start using different types of
blocks I think I'm getting too addicted
to these stone bricks but I'm not sure
what else to use people say sandstone
doesn't go with these very well and I
love sandstone I want to actually I
wanted to try those nether brick or the
nether brick out I like that I like the
look of those okay how do we do this now
so maybe underneath pressure plates
above there I'm going to switch this
with Kabul so I know it's where the wire
goes and it will go over through here we
should run into the Pistons I believe we
keep going hopefully maybe not out there
there okay how do we do this I think
I'll just come one block too low here
I'm going to put a redstone torch on
this block
ooh right over here for the pistons this
will be for wire let's see what do we do
here I'm going to put block here can you
guys see I hope you can see and I will
have a repeater which will send power to
the torch and then wire
yes very good
so now if I step on the pressure plate
awesome perfect first try and then we'll
have our water here so I want to harvest
my mushrooms I just walk up you'll get
harvested go right to me recent ice and
simple okay but now we need our source
mushroom I'm going to put it just in
here nice little spot for it
I will do the red ones first for this
farm put our block above and I think
we're about set here that and we can
probably just fill this in now cool and
hopefully this works I don't know this
is my very first mushroom farm I really
hope it works we will replace these ooh
I should have done that no no no careful
we're going to replace these with glass
panes so we can see I think now we have
to use glass blocks otherwise the
mushrooms get stuck okay there Oh
replace that one it's got to be perfect
very nice I'm happy so if this works I
will make another one somewhere for the
brown mushrooms cool alright so what are
we going to do now alright I figured out
what our next project shall be we are
going to make an enchanting room here I
got a pretty good idea how I want to do
it it's going to be it's going to be
adjustable is what I want
so like ideally with enchanting rooms
you want 30 books around your enchanting
table right thing is once you have those
30 books around your enchanting table it
becomes very difficult to find like
level 1 enchantments as it like instead
of having no books around it becomes
really easy you just saw 2 there
I'm just using level one isn't as an
example once you have lots of books
around your enchanting table it's
becomes more difficult to find lower
level enchantments so that's why I want
to make this adjustable so that you can
choose between doing high level
enchantments or low level enchantments
easily without having to put your sword
in like a hundred times to find what you
want type thing so I'm going to use
sticky pistons to move the bookshelves
out of position so they won't have an
effect on the enchanting table I set up
a ring actually I'm not going to put one
there I'm going to go all around here so
I do it like that then what I'll do is
I'll I made a staircase here and I run
wire we're going to split these two sets
in half so have wire here and wire here
like that and now if I put levers on
that control one side or the other side
so I want to do that for the top and for
the bottom circle of bookshelves so I
don't that's the thing I don't have
enough reads to make enough bookshelves
at the moment so I'm just going to use
planks as a substitute for now maybe
I'll throw in a few bookshelves just so
we can see how it works so you see right
now where this bookshelf is it's not at
it's not having any effect on the
enchanting table it's in the wrong
position but if it gets moved down one
then it will
have an effect or it should yeah you can
see that you got the chain cymbals
flying to it and we'll do the other side
not having effect Goes Down and there
they they start flying you see the
levels are a bit higher now ok so that's
the general idea behind it they're not
flying anymore but now we need to do it
for the bottom as well I guess the best
way of doing that will be to dig down
blocks all around in the ring oh and we
got stuff below I guess should be fine
actually
over here I'm not going to put a piston
stupid that block I wonder what's down
there oh I think that's where I have my
pumped into actually Oh too far ok
Pistons all around
like that and then we'll have to put
wire beside it so like over here is a
good spot go around I'm going to replace
this with cobble this is something I do
so I know it's where the wire belongs if
water ever washes it away or something
or if I'm digging I don't I generally
won't dig through cobble unless I know
what's there okay I'll put our wire down
and this will all be hidden so it's fine
once you have your shelves there or it
should be and just put something in
front here I don't know it'll work
okay so I'll do it for the other side
now yeah and in the back we'll just have
two bookshelves that are always there
that don't move just because it
simplifies things a bit and it doesn't
really matter too much cuz it's still
fairly low level stuff oh well I just
doesn't have effect because it's they're
not bookshelves right and okay yeah I'm
liking this this should work out nice I
think what I want to do now is try get
that lever down to here so that wait can
I go there no maybe we'll try put it up
here somewhere then maybe here
that will be our targets okay so we can
do that pretty easily I think just go
let's get rid of this gravel it's that
way we want it all to be hidden if
possible although if this bookshelf
comes up you'll see the wire behind so
we should go in one more block because
this will go up and if I put a wire here
you'll see it so maybe I'll have to put
it here or down here let's put it down
here I'll probably switch this with
sandstone I'll have one there and other
one there that controls the bottom right
this will control the top right if we
can get it to go there um let's see I
shall do it off camera sorry about that
it's just so much easier to do stuff
when you don't have to worry about
timing and talking and all that stuff
okay so what I'm actually gonna do is
the switches with sandstone now because
I know I want it I need it relievers
there I'm going to use some redstone
torches at indicator lights so we have
some kind of visual indication if it's
on or off
then I have the wire ready to go here
goes up like that and it is long on
Earth's short enough to so one two three
four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve
redstone power to travel fifteen blocks
so it's within range they all go down
it's very nice
so now copy that on the other side I'll
probably have this built up it'd all be
hidden there will be something behind
here to and behind I'll replace all this
stone with something to probably
sandstone I don't know just to give it a
clean look we'll try hide all the
pistons and I may lower the ground to
just so otherwise it's going to be too
high in here it'll feel cramped maybe
and there might we might put a door
right here maybe a piston door okay well
I'll do the other side I'll see you in a
bit
actually I just checked and I think
we're about out of time for today so
we're going to wrap it up now we'll have
to polish this up later
let's stick in another book shelf and I
want to do at least one enchanting today
so here we go oh wait can you
oh wait let's we got to get it to lower
lower them all for maximum level which
is still really low for me
seven seven seems to be the tops
come on give me seven give me a seven
oh you still got to do it a hundred
times
come on to my five six Wow
come on aerial efficiency one I'll take
it I like efficiency cool so that's the
raps I might need to adjust the mushroom
farm because I don't think it's grown
any in like 30 minutes so it's not the
most efficient oh there we go we got one
I might adjust it still I don't know
it's not really something I plan on
using lots it's just nice to have nice
to have it there so that if I walk by
some time and there's five mushrooms or
four mushrooms I can just get them
really easy okay thanks for watching see
you guys next time