hello everybody and welcome
let's get to this i realized last
episode i wasted a lot of time talking
and we really didn't get much done
uh so
it's a creeper in my wiring um
just before i started recording actually
accidentally pressed right click on my
mouse when i had a torch in my hand and
apparently you can place torches on
glass now i had no
idea no idea
so that was a shock got the glass floor
done here
and just to begin with i wanted to kind
of make this room look
better or to like do the walls you know
so it's not all cobble
so i kind of planned out what i want to
do i came up with these four by four
tiles that i'm going to put across out
of stairs
and i'll probably have a line of
something here
then one two three four and then another
line is something at the last level
there
is my plan and the line of something
i think i'm going to do like the the
marble
look and see how that goes so i brought
some
dark wood and some light wood and we're
just gonna put it across see how it
looks
to begin with and i think i want the
outside to be white i counted it
and it should
work out pretty good like this yeah so
four white and three dark
yeah i know you're there
he's gonna he's gonna do something
kind of like that and along the wall
this thing still hasn't actually no it
jammed once on me
um i think i know how to fix it though
so i'm not too worried i still need to
tinker with the the wiring there
make it perfect yet
but overall it's still running really
well can i put one more
so we'll do that first well let's
go down below that better be the same
guy
yeah that's kind of cool i like that
come on man yeah
oh man he almost blew up
you guys are so hard to
predict now and he's gone he took off
ah okay so we're gonna do another line
like that
at this level i don't know
if we should like have the blacks in the
same place and then
like black white black white or if we
should alternate them
it would match the floor if we did black
and over here
let's just see what it looks like
hmm yeah yeah i think we'll do it that
way
so i'll finish that and then we'll get
back to this oh no
yeah yeah that's right that's four
blocks in between okay all right there
it is
uh i cleared out the space in between
two so we can put our tiles in
and the tiles are four by four so four
high
and four wide and we have one
two three 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 13 14
blocks there so we could fit three tiles
in and then have
a one wide border on both edges so
maybe we will make
those black the borders
like that
i think i clogged the hole where the
creeper came in i think it was up there
oh there's more where is he
i bet you that's the same one i killed
two
if he's one hit that's him yeah it is
okay
all right i feel a lot to see for now
um
yeah we might have to break that up a
bit it looks a little bit
strong is that the right word strong
i don't know uh so
the the patterns i found require stairs
so we have
five texture options really and since
most this
room is wood i think i'll try the wood
one first i was maybe thinking do
another brick
but i don't know and basically we're
gonna go
three like that three upside down like
that
and this way as well
and then three over there
and that makes kind of like an o
like that and then in the middle
i think that's okay i don't know
maybe i should have had white over here
instead of black
and then this goes
we want it uh
oh how do we do that
we want it like this nope
that get placed the wrong way
it's so hard to work high up placing
stairs like this
like that that's what we want
and we'll have to get a little bit
higher for the next one
like that and then
nope
uh there no ah this is tough
there and then there okay that's the
pattern that's the four by four tile
we're going to repeat
see how it looks
and then we'll put something behind it
too so it won't be cobble
um it doesn't look as good as i thought
it would i'm going to try another brick
instead
i would really like to use sandstone but
we don't have sandstone stairs
so i'll replace that try again
and i'll be back
okay well that's the nether brick there
i'm not happy with it either something
needs to change i'm not quite sure what
so i'll just uh
well i'll compare the two i'll look over
the video and see which i prefer
the only other options are brick
cobblestone or
stone brick for the pattern
and i don't think those three would look
good so it's kind of between that
and wood
but we'll have to maybe do something
else with this shape
and we are back so this is what i decide
to go with
the wooden planks i think they look
better than the
nether brick and i changed up the way i
was going to do this before i was going
to have all the tiles
connected together but now i have them
inset one block
and we have these borders between them
all i would have liked to have a little
bit more
in this corner like you know what i mean
have it
reach like that all the way up and have
those moved over
one block to the left and one block to
the right but
that just won't work with the shape of
this room or the size of it
so this is uh this is the way we're
going to do it now the only
issue i'm having with this or my only
dislike is it's dark
it's too dark up there now first of all
and with this marble
look we got going on it's not really
working either the middle one looks okay
but then the side ones don't look great
to me so what i think i'll do
is change this so that
that's a white one and we might change
that wooden plank the regular wooden
planks there with white wood
and we will make this dark
and i missed like that
and then over here put
a lamp turn it on
and also surely have at least one wooden
or white one up here oh wrong block
give me that back
like that
oh and maybe uh make two
dark blocks there and then
repeat the pattern at the top so there
would be another lamp
at the top there and at the very top row
there i'm going to do these tiles again
but with a different pattern
another one i like and i think that will
look pretty cool and that will light it
up enough
then we just need to put something
behind there so we don't see gray
and i think it'll be pretty cool so
i will work on converting this again
and there it is so that's the first
layer done here
and i'm i'm really happy with the way it
turned out i think it looks pretty good
it's a little bit busy i like a little
busy looking there's lots of different
shapes and whatnot
but i like it because most the stuff i
make is usually pretty plain so this is
a nice change
and the only other thing i really don't
like
not that i mind too much is the very
corners i would like to include
like a light there and a light there to
bounce out the look
but like i said with the width of the
room we needed it to be
two blocks wider for that to happen
which it just
isn't that big so not a big deal
and we will have to put in a detector in
one of these corners too probably that
one there
so we'll have to rip out a few of those
wood blocks anyway
just for the function of the room but i
think we can move up
to the top now and i'll show you the
pattern
i picked out for that it's amazing all
the different uh
patterns you can do with these stairs
now that you can put them upside down
all right oh
so again it'll be much the same
oh
wait a minute i guess i gotta
raise the roof raise the roof one more
block
okay i'll be right back okay this is
really weird
this is really really weird i came back
here to get some supplies right
and i was jumping around took some
damage
didn't think much of it but for some
reason now i have the ability to
pass through blocks
very strangely i can't even jump out of
this water
i think the game thinks i'm lower than i
actually am or something
so like if i jump my head goes into that
block
or if i run into this tree
the leaves don't stop me i can run
through the
a little bit so weird
what the heck
okay my y coordinate says i'm at .62 i
wonder if that's normal i'll have to uh
oh whatever class does
can i run into this
kind of i almost did it [ __ ] if i had a
block down i could do it
nope not letting me what about
oh that's so weird
yeah it thinks that it must think i'm
one block lower than i actually am
okay enough goofing around i'm gonna
re-log and see if that fixes it
okay it's fixed my height is the same
though so that wasn't
the issue something got messed up in the
game code
okay so i got this uh upper layer
already all prepped
we can start building it should go
really quick because it's uh
pretty much exact same as that lower
thing over there so we just need to
replicate it
uh just a different four by four tile
pattern we're going to be doing
so we will continue
the dark wood in the middle like that
and actually in the middle over here as
well we will have
lamps at the very top too like one there
and the white wood and the way i've been
powering these lamps is i've just been
putting
levers behind them and turning them on
like so let's see how much light does
that give
yeah it looks pretty good we have block
light
5 6 9 10 11 12
10 yeah yeah it's pretty good
as long as stuff doesn't spawn that's my
only concern and they won't because we
got glass here so it doesn't really
matter
we'll do that the corners go like this
all right very good
and i'm gonna put a tile here too even
though i don't think we have one below
but that might change yet i'm not sure
let's see okay anyway you get the point
so the tile pattern we're doing for this
is much the same as that one we still do
the three stairs
facing the same way in the corner but
instead of
the upside down stair facing
this way we will just do another one of
these
like that do that for all four corners
and it looks pretty good i like this
pattern too quite a bit
so we got the grid very simple
there we go so like i said we just have
to change the gray behind it because i
don't want it to be gray we might put
leaves or some lighting or something i
don't know
but that's the idea
and i know i know it seems like i'm
doing a lot for just a simple
xp system that doesn't really work too
well
but that's all second priority the main
thing we want
with all this contraption uh
is a silver fish we want to be able to
produce silverfish
for digging i think that's going to be
really cool when i get it working
very good plus this is fun i'm having
fun doing this project
okay so i'll finish this up and we'll
take a look
all right i forgot to grab something at
the base so i need to go back
and i want to show you i got a portal
here now i was just curious to see
where it would take me if i made one
and surprise surprise it links up with
the other portal the nether the other
one i was using
you can see the tree over there still so
if we go through this again
it takes us to the portal in the middle
of the field
so
i think it does that because i've heard
you need to make them a thousand blocks
apart to prevent that
or else make the portal from in the
nether not
from the overworld here overworld
whatever whatever you want to call it
the main world or whatever
am i going the right way yes
all right i'll see you back
at the silverfish
all right so we got that done
it looks pretty good let's check it out
from below
actually we'll take a look from above to
kind of get a feel of how to look um
now from below
oh
yeah the void fog is kind of blocking
the vision a little bit because we're at
11 here
all right well i'm pretty happy with
that the only thing we
should maybe do yet is the ceiling
i didn't really plan what i want to do
with that
i was thinking of trying like a stair
rim
around it so um
maybe you can pick here
and do upside down stairs
like that all the way around
and then at certain sections maybe have
a grid type thing so like where this
this post is or whatever uh we need to
have
we need a half slabs for this
get some half slabs
yeah this project's quite a bit of work
really
okay we'll try like this and those will
connect every four by four area probably
oh that's where there's a hollow space
under the stairs i didn't know that
so it would go
um let's see we would make this
go like that way like we'll have cross
sections that join up
at each of these posts going that way
and then another one
over here and then going this way here
and this way and that'll leave a four by
four
area on top and we might sneak some
lighting in there
and maybe the marble look i don't know
let me let me work on this a bit and
we'll see how it looks
hmm that's the grid
what do you think how does that look
makes it feel really open in here that's
a pretty high ceiling
the gray would obviously be something
else i'm not sure what
um if we do go with this i can get rid
of this darkness on the stairs there
i think by removing a block behind it or
something
should fix that and
with this grid this corn the corner
pieces are three by three there
and then the sides are four by three
and the middle is a four by four so
that's the pattern
which is fitting i would say because it
kind of matches this pattern
where the corners are small and those
are wide and then big
type thing
actually you know one thing we could do
like i kind of want to incorporate some
lighting in the ceiling too because
the middle of this looks really dark the
glass
and it would brighten up the room i
think we could maybe
take that out
and like put a lamp there actually let's
try it on this one
like have a lamp but instead doing
straight like that
maybe switch this out with a stair
type thing
give it a little more shape and have
four of those one
one in each of those and let's see if we
can get
it lit i don't know if i'll be able to
find that
actually let's let's get the coordinate
that is 447 and 862.
447 862 447 862.
this place is a mess i gotta move these
chests
four 47.
no too far 862. we're really close
right down there okay
so we'll light that up
and just block this so we don't get mobs
although i'm pretty sure this isn't
safe anymore my little work area here
after all these adjustments
yeah that's kind of cool
block lighting is 11 below
yeah all right well
let me know what you think of the room
if you got any suggestions on how to
improvements
let me know as well um
got a bit more work to do on it
hopefully
uh maybe we'll try break it up next
episode i don't know
what we'll do we'll see um
i was hanging out with rob the other day
too
that's the guy behind doors versus
zombies
we've got a pretty cool invention
to show you we were we were messing
around the other day
so i hope you enjoyed this ending clip
and i will see you guys again
next time thanks for watching
i like that
okay now i see yeah
i also want to point out that you don't
actually have a way to turn it off until
it just runs out
why would you want to turn it off
yeah that's the new standard rob
for doing what it's not actually
threatening though
you're just walking around and zombies
are flying on your screen everywhere
and then
guess what happens
oh what did you do that
picked the minecraft over they in the
mine cart
no why they all go flying out
cause i broke one of the tracks
it keeps going over the thick the
detector rails right so it doesn't have
a chance to retract
oh okay if you were to make like a
a t junction you could switch it off
that's pretty hilarious
oh that's weird the zombies actually
push it
yeah it's actually getting faster
oh i like that that looks cool it plays
like one song and then
like once and then doesn't play the
second time
dude they get flunk so far
like i know they keep going all the way
out of there yeah out of the circle
yeah did they farm that man they just
keep going
they're just flying zombies
oh do you see what it's like broken now
it's not even going around it's going
back and forth
so the zombie flesh on the track
stopping the minecart oh that's it
what the hell
that is so buggy