[Music]
hello
everybody this is etho we are
back at the mob system stuff today i've
updated to 1.5.1
seems a lot smoother right like the main
thing they fixed in it is the smooth
lighting
performance issue and not everybody
experienced it i was
one person that was experiencing it
though i definitely noticed a
performance hit between 1.5 and 1.4.7
and now it seems to be really smooth
so that little bit of jitter is gone for
me some people had it worse than others
i know
like some people could hardly even play
so that is awesome
uh to get things back the way they were
but yeah i was just about to do the
redstone well i kind of started already
for this and i thought i would cue you
guys in on what we're doing
uh so what we have to do is we got to
make this trap door open
and close really quick
the mob will drop down onto that trap
door there
and then after after a little bit of
time we want that to open and close
as well and then let another mob in
so uh the way i have this
there's a tripwire hook right there
so when the mob is one blocked in front
of the tr
the trap door it'll basically do this
it'll flip this torch
and that allows this clock to run
and once the mob passes by the tripwire
it stops so it's not going to be running
all the time which is something that
bugs me about clocks i don't like it
when they run all the time
that'll be good uh this is much too fast
though if we slow this down
yeah that might be better
maybe even slower i think we gotta stick
a mono stable in here though so the trap
door
does a quick open and close just not as
often
then we gotta go down below here
and try to connect it to here too right
there
okay i'm gonna try to put two repeaters
here actually
i'm guessing we'll need to because it's
got to be the time
from when they drop there to down there
which i'm sure is more than
four ticks so we'll have to
set these at eights
and i am trapped um
don't ender pearl into the mob system
that's never a good idea
okay very good
now if we flip this
it's almost in reverse that's that's
good so
i'm just gonna hook up a monostable to
this yet and it should be
good to go
so all the redstone should be done now
we might have to change some timings on
things but all the components are here
so
we have our our clock activator here
this is our clock then it goes to a
monostable circuit here
this changes it from like a long pulse
to a short pulse
uh or in other words instead of the
trapdoor being like
open close open close
it's like open close pause open close
pause open close you know real quick
and then but it's still the same
duration of time between
uh the pulses and then it goes down to
here to the other trap door with an
eight tick delay i'm guessing we will
have to add more to that though because
i forgot
not only do we need to account for the
time it takes them to fall
down onto the trapdoor but also for
their pathfinding to kick in
so they go where they need to but we can
run a test now to see what happens
so i'm gonna flip this and should have
checked if it's night or day that's
gonna affect our
spawn rates here
it must be nighttime let's go sleep
best way to get down and over here
and right there's my bed
uh get your snacks guys if you didn't
get them already don't you forget
never forget it's implied every episode
get your
snacks okay
okay let's go back up
oh it's doing things what's it doing we
got a creeper in one spot already
i am stuck i can't jump feeling
claustrophobic let's go over here where
it's open
oh we got a skeleton coming
sounds like
oh you see that first problem
he's he didn't land on the door even
that's the problem
yeah so there's definitely timing issues
already
it's okay we'll work him out
see that opens before he gets to the
trap door even
okay so i'm gonna do some fine tuning
here and then we'll
we'll see it really working hopefully
well good news it looks like the
silverfish farm is still working
perfectly even after the redstone update
so all the redstone changes did not
break
it which is very good i am not
i don't want to change anything with
this i'm i'm happy with the redstone on
it and i don't want to
have to fiddle with it anymore because
it is like 100
accurate now um
took me a long time to get that right i
did not
say the same about our mob sorter though
it is not 100
accurate at the moment it is maybe about
from what i just tested uh we
will go check out the changes i did it's
a little bit more improved but we have
to do some more
improvements maybe first thing i changed
i increased the clocks so this is
21 ticks now about 2.1 seconds
and monostable is as short as it can be
for operating the trip door i have added
in
more delay down here as well to to make
that work because they have to be
like the same length for it to work down
here too on this trip door
uh so this is what do we got here we got
20 20 ticks down there
or two seconds and then i added in a
trip door
right over here which doesn't move at
all it's just there to create
a few pixels distance from this wall
because they were falling down and not
landing on the trip door there they were
landing on that block
it's connected to and that is not good
so
anyway let's run a test we'll see what
it's like now
uh one issue i was having is it can't
keep up with my mob
system
zombies go after the villagers creepers
run away from
ocelots over there oh that looked weird
it's like he fell then he came back up
and went that way
skeletons they just sit there and fall
down
the main problem having with this at the
moment is the creepers
they kind of sit there too long
sometimes and they'll just fall down
it does seem to matter how many guys are
up there though
look how backed up it is
it's pretty accurate though as long as
things are running smooth it's accurate
but when it starts jamming up like that
yeah you fell in with the skeleton
they start pushing each other a lot up
there it starts to mess up sometimes two
will fall into the time
too
that seat just sat there i tried
extending the size of this platform
uh it seemed to help a bit but we need
something else we either need
i don't know if adding a second cap
would make them run away quicker
or if i can add like another layer
to this like if i went up like this and
made a path
for them to get up like if i start
making the second platform if they would
see that
i don't know what the
the range is on the path finding for the
mobs
but that's another idea but generally
it's working
relatively decently at the moment
but what is this all for you might be
wondering
uh i had fun reading the comments for
last episode
because a lot of people are trying to
guess what i'm what i'm intending to use
this for like what's the point if
if we can separate items out now using
hoppers and all that why don't we just
separate the items instead of the mobs
and i'll tell you why
uh this is an idea i had about
six six months ago to a year ago already
actually it's just been sitting there
and it's been bugging me that i haven't
done it yet so we're gonna go to one of
my old creative worlds i
managed to find the project again and
i'll show you
step three of the mob system
all right guys here we are in one of my
old old creative worlds
uh i have five or six or seven
main worlds i use i'll just pick one
randomly and i'll
start building little experiments like
this all over the landscape
no real order to it or anything so
it can be really challenging to find an
old project after i've built it
and this was no exception this took me i
had to go through every single world
and like fly around the worlds for quite
a ways to see if i
maybe missed it somewhere finally i
found it here it is
this is gonna be step three of our mob
system
uh the bomb factory
this is a bomb factory um
this is really cool maybe we'll start
with
just an example of it so there's going
to be three
main components to it uh there's a snow
golem over there
safely tucked away behind closed doors
safe from any danger we have a skeleton
uh we're gonna have a creeper in this
path
here
all right right between the snow golem
and the skeleton
but he doesn't get released right away
this is what happens uh
this is made for like several months ago
and it doesn't work
quite right anymore because mom behavior
has changed
before i had to use a monostable circuit
to run it
but now i found if i put a wooden button
here
it pretty much works every time
the the main thing that's changed is
skeletons and like snow golems they take
a good second before they shoot the
first time before in the past it was
like
instant like he would instantly shoot
when this door opens and then the
skeleton would instantly shoot back and
it was a real challenge to to close this
door
quick enough so that the snow golem
wouldn't get shot by the skeleton but
now
it's really easy so anyway here's an
example
boom so what happened there
uh the door is open long enough for the
snow golem to see the skeleton
he shot the skeleton there's a check
that happens here though to make sure
the skeleton gets shot because sometimes
these guys
miss the snow golems and
this piston retracts glass block
it looks like it doesn't put it back
like it's supposed to because it's not
it's not set up right but
it retracts this glass block and
allows the skeleton to get moved to on
top of that pressure plate
and that pressure plates activates this
piston which pushes them off of it
and then it's going to run and release
our creeper
which now that we have a mob sorter we
can have a gate that just releases
one one creeper and we can control it
properly that way
so the second time we open the door
uh the skeleton will shoot the creeper
first
um i'm not quite sure how this is going
to work out like uh
i have to adjust the timings and
everything to make it work again
but you should you saw the skeleton shot
the creeper because this creepers in
between the two
uh the snowglobe shot afterwards i think
the creeper will still detonate on the
skeleton though once they come together
yeah don't blow up
so what i can do
is transport the skeleton and the
creeper
wherever i want and i can use them to
blow up blocks
like uh it's kind of like
free tnt basically that i don't have to
craft or anything it's all automatic
you can get the skeleton and the creeper
from my mob system
no problem and then
we can get them to blow stuff up so
step four or five or whatever i don't
know what
we'll call it later but one of the
things i want to make
is a cobblestone farms so
we'll have cobblestone generators and
then
we'll make them detonate the cobblestone
and then we'll collect it
but the main thing i want to use this
for is an automatic
tree farm to automatically collect wood
uh it's gonna be really tough to do and
a lot of fun
but it is possible with the game now i'm
pretty sure
uh it's going to be a fun project that's
for sure
but there's there's going to be a lot of
complicated steps to it
but basically we combine them at like a
sheet of
wood or something have them blow it up
and then the wood will fall down onto
hoppers or whatever
this is something i set up like months
ago because i think i planned on using
it
for a tree farm even back then but now
it's a lot easier to make this all work
so yeah
it's going to be fun it's going to be a
lot of fun so that's the idea we're not
going to work on that today maybe we'll
go do something else just to change
things up
i hope you like the idea though
what are those two goofballs up to today
what are they doing
back up walk away
i was never here
anyways what are we going to do now guys
what shall we do
i actually have something to show you
do you remember the brown mushroom farm
of course you remember i only worked on
it once or twice
but yeah i worked on it some more
yesterday
and i did the ceiling and i kind of like
how it looks actually we did like this
grid pattern thing
i thought i'd show you i'm trying to
figure out how to connect it to the wall
now
and i experimented with some other block
types because i
was hoping to change like it's just all
one color and i was hoping to
add another color in with the wall but i
couldn't find anything i like
so we might just keep it this isn't
exactly going to be a
high high use building i don't think
so i'm not too picky about it i tried
putting some wool behind the fences
i don't know not sure what to do
when the mushroom grows it's going to
activate some redstone
turn the light up or turn the light on
up there
then i want it to do like a light show
on the ground maybe some note blocks
like a little tune that will play
until we harvest the mushroom then on
this end we gotta
put something i don't know what we'll do
here either
we might even to continue
here like have a door that goes further
into another part of the cave
oh maybe
this nether brick and sandstone
at the top here i never really made it
end anywhere i just
just randomly stopped it same with on
the other side i never really
made it do anything it just randomly
ends so
uh maybe what we'll do
like it kind of wraps around the ufo
there
maybe we'll mimic oh i said that fast
mimic
uh what we did there and make it wrap
into the wall
on this other side so
do something like that
and another brick will only go up to
there and then
we'll figure out some other ceiling for
this tree farm area if we ever do that
that's a lot of work to change the
ceiling on there
um but maybe eventually we'll get to it
this will all be wait is that right
huh this is four blocks wide
it seems a little off doesn't it
oh well it'll work
there we go that looks a little bit
better i would say a little more finish
complete uh it still connects to nothing
though but you don't really see it at
the moment
we don't know what we're doing with this
area
and then eventually it'll transition to
another type of ceiling if we do one
over the tree farm
if we ever get to it this side turned
out okay
changed this wall moved the fence
uh maybe
yeah that's better right
we'll put something here it's not going
to be a flat wall but for now it will be
had to transition here that was a bit
tough but
it works it's good
huh another idea i had today
up here you know this room i never
really knew
what to do with it until today i think i
know what
i want to do with it finally so bedroom
was kind of always on my mind put a
bedroom here but today i had another
idea
so to get into this cave
do you know how i do it do you know how
i get in here usually
right through here so to get
into my to my home here usually all
well there's a hole here i sometimes go
down over there there's a drop
and there's another one i sometimes use
where is it we should change this
too i don't like this anymore but
yeah over here is another hole i
sometimes jump down to get home
only works if you have feather falling
and sometimes i'll just fall right
through here
let's jump down here get back in my
point is i need a better place to get
into my table an actual entrance would
be nice you know
i have ways of getting out too like i
have the elevator
getting out's a little easier i can
enter parole
up there or there's another
ender pearl spot over here i use often
so i got a few easier ways out than in
but let's just try and make a staircase
here and see
what that's like
by the way i was having some trouble
with my computer
the other day i was getting my fan all
the signs
is like it's usually my fans pretty
quiet then all of a sudden my computer
fan was like
you know it wore out or got dry the
bearings in it or something
and started making terrible noise this
goes quite a ways
um so i took my computer apart
opened it up took the fan outs uh oiled
it
that took care of the sound issue i also
vacuumed out my computer though
there was a lot of a lot of
dust a whole bunch of it
uh and i was getting blue screens before
like
one a day usually and i was considering
maybe getting a new computer by now
because it usually every three years or
so i'll get a new computer
you know i don't get top of the line
when i get a new one i'll get like above
average
usually so it's a bit cheaper
but still kind of expensive
but i think i can hold out a little
longer now because ever since i vacuumed
out all the dust
i haven't gotten a blue screen so i'm
guessing it was overheating
and everything's pretty good now
so yeah maybe we'll do this it goes up
quite a ways though doesn't it
it's thinking of just having a nice
little staircase entrance
that's a pretty big staircase
[Music]
yeah we'll do it this is a good place
like we got a nice view over here
i think that's a good idea
and maybe i'll break it up too instead
of like having a
solid staircase all the way up i'll have
a platform halfway
with something and then we'll go the
rest of the way
okay i got the basic idea laid out here
this
area i extend it to seven blocks so we
can put something on the walls and
we'll have a ceiling or something maybe
another arch over here that goes over
top and then
up we go we got a platform i made this
five blocks and then we go the rest of
the way
and each of these flight of stairs goes
up seven blocks
so it splits right in the middle and
should be good so i think that's what
we'll go with
and i'm just gonna make it like i made
the other staircases to be consistent
with the the logs on the sides and
the regular oak stairs
and it'll look pretty good maybe we'll
put fences on the logs
too
it'll be nice to have a proper entrance
to get into here because i do
i do feel a little silly jumping down
holes all the time
to get down here
it's not very convenient
cool well i think we're about done for
today aren't we
it's about that time uh
i guess maybe we'll head over to the
library
we should do one thing on the library
i'm going to wire up the door to it
today just so we make some progress on
it
here we are at the library and i just
finished wiring the door so let's take a
quick look at it
so it's a three by three door with the
center missing
and this is what the pistons do on it we
have eight pistons
three per side and then one at the top
one at the bottom
and they all do a quick pulse like that
so if we put this here here
here here and
there there there and
there that's our door
just like that so this is a quick
pulsing door
it leaves the blocks behind even though
it's sticky pistons
oh i guess we need we need to put some
courts there there
there and there too um
but yeah pretty cool the reason i really
like this door is because you can
run and keep going like it doesn't you
don't hit the door
as you run through it so that's pretty
cool
so this is the wiring goes up to the top
piston from there
half slabs the wire just goes back and
forth
up to the top and
underneath the pressure plates it goes
to a monostable circuit here it's just
the piston that goes up and it lets
it turns it into a one tick pulse that
goes up to the middle
which goes up the side and it goes to
this this piston
over here and it can go underneath that
as well to the other side and that's how
it
it gets to there so
from the other side of the door exact
same thing just reversed
and it's pretty simple so that's
that's one more thing done with the
library it's
fairly large though um it's okay we got
lots of space
it'll work out and we'll put a skin over
top this side too so you won't see all
this stuff
but yeah i picked out two comments for
today let's check these out
number one why do you only wear boots
for armor
i have a helmet on no i got this from
a mob last episode so i decided to just
put it on
this these are my boots protection three
feather falling four
i always wear feather falling four boots
for ender pearls because they reduce the
fall damage you take from them
you can ender pearl a lot
uh more often without any trouble
because normally you take 2.5 hertz of
fall damage with these you know it's
like
that time is half of hearts or hearts
you know
it's a lot less i don't wear more
armor because this game is pretty easy
as
it is even in the nether i haven't died
in a long time in my single player
so i'm not too worried about dying and i
like the extra
potential the extra risk behind i have
to
be a little more careful you know uh
second question
hey etho do you play any games on a
console or just pc
i do have an xbox 360. i don't use it
too much anymore i'm pretty
uh pretty solid on pc games only they're
they're a lot better anybody that plays
pc games frequently knows this they're
they're better uh the main reason i like
console games is because of the
relaxation element to it it's a lot
you know you can sit on a couch and use
a tv
but with my pc the way i have my
computer set up actually i have a
wireless xbox
360 controller so if i want to use that
with the game
with a pc game i can and i also have my
computer set up where i can
put the image out on my tv and sit at my
coach too so i can
i can play pc games exactly like console
games pretty much
uh there's no there's no real
benefit to console for me
anymore with that setup so i like pc
games they're awesome
most of them have better graphics for
fancy games and
just the whole customization you get in
games on pc like minecraft you can have
custom skins you can make
custom worlds there's no size limitation
you know there's just a lot of benefits
to pc gaming over
console gaming that's my opinion
alright guys thank you for watching i
hope you enjoyed it
have a good day bye bye
you