[Music]
hello how's it going everybody this is
etho and welcome back to another let's
play episode so I'm gonna start this off
with a little bit of bad news everybody
you might want to sit down for this are
you sitting down sit down good boy
okay uh so the ender Porter
still no good guys you know I saw a lot
of comments about this I was pretty
excited about it as well like with the
new bubble streams you can float
minecarts in them you can floats anvils
falling sand all sorts of different
entities mobs but I guess they don't
really hurt the projectiles the hope was
that we could throw an ender pearl and
have it just float float in the bubble
stream but it behaves just like it's
slowed down still but it it goes up and
it just comes straight down so maybe
I'll show you guys the old design here
too I played around with this a little
bit to see if I could get it working
today again but doesn't seem like it's
it's gonna work we still got the same
old problems so I'm gonna turn it on got
the sound turned down a little bit it
causes an incredible amount of leg
especially now with the the crummy
optimization on redstone but basically
we got the slime block going up and down
repeatedly and you would throw an ender
pearl
the water slows it down so that it'll
hopefully bounce off the slime
apparently in this version of Minecraft
though it doesn't really work what am I
looking for I was supposed to do this
off camera I forgot okay got a make a
sign but I did figure out how to get it
working again today I'm just gonna make
a slight adjustment to its basically we
need likes something to hold the water
in here
and then a sign here so that the water
doesn't try to flow down ever and if we
do that then I was able to get to and
repel suspended still enough that
happens every time that time it failed
let's try again oh oh look at that so we
got a bouncing enderpearl there and the
idea is like you can activate this
piston here and it'll shoot the
enderpearl sideways the slime will
bounce it this way and then it'll it'll
hit something right and then you
teleport there so we have these a couple
of these built in the world I think we
made three of them and you hit the
button here and it takes you to the
Nexus like it activates the one at the
Nexus and then we get teleported there
or we hit this one and it teleports us
to the man cave a couple hundred blocks
that way all right
the issue is just to clarify cuz you
know I had this built I thought it was
really good and stuff and then I had
issues when I would go through the
nether through the nether portal and
come back or if I sometimes when the
chunks with unload and reload just by
going away from it then coming back then
sometimes the ender pearl will just
randomly land even though it's not
supposed to might happen here it's
loading in no no it's fine
doesn't happen every time just if it's
in the right position I guess but yeah
if the chunks unload and then reload
that's that's the issue I was hoping the
bubble streams would like solve that
problem but I just they don't work at
all come on oh there we go you see that
so we got teleported there it activated
even though it wasn't supposed to
alright everybody so today is the day we
are gonna go look for the new ocean
biomes
and hopefully find that place to set up
base set up our new ocean base
underwater base I'll just show you where
I plan on looking for a new ocean
hopefully
so we're gonna take the ice roads cuz
they're convenient over there I think
this is the which firm oh this is super
annoying by the way like it's really
hard to nudge these guys out of the way
now in this update so if they spot in
the middle of the track here I've put
the rails in the middle to stop them
from spawning yet it's really hard to
travel down here this I don't know where
this portal goes actually I should check
that out someday
ice road over here is not completes by
any means it's still a pretty big mess
but look how far we are gonna go here
thankfully we can travel the distance in
pretty much no time at all all right so
we've got some boarders here with so we
don't fall in the lava goes through
another fortress then over here this is
where we found one of those mansions
what are they called just matches so you
know on the dark oak biomes I'm just
gonna leave the boat here and now we're
gonna go beyond that's to Newton new
uncharted territory here ice road ends
dug out a little bit of a tunnel here
and we're probably just gonna set the
portal somewhere around here so one
question I get asked often is why do I
carry you around so many ender chests
with me uh that's a good question good
question
a lot of times when I work on a on a new
build
I'll always leave an ender chest there
and then I don't have one on me right
unless I have a stack of them then
there's always it always guarantees I'll
have one when I need one right but it
has another pretty cool function if I
ever like get stuck or I'm in the nether
or something I need obsidian I'll just
break them down and get obsidian that
way all right with the fortune pick all
right so we got obsidian for our portal
let's try out this area here I guess now
we're doing the corners we're doing the
corners guys I'm not skipping out so you
thought I was going to there no no no
all right here we go
new territory please be an ocean
probably won't be will have to fly
around a bit to find
probably and there might be a whole
tunnel idear so I'll probably have to
cut the video Oh
oh hey look at that I didn't cheat or
anything guys we found an ocean right
away oh that's cool
okay looking at the coordinates in case
I lose the spot again
11450 nine blocks out holy smokes
alright is it a big area we've got the
kelp
what is this underwater ravine died here
oh I am lost how did we get here oh it
goes down I see it's like why am I in a
cave now I thought I was an underwater
ravine hey I guess you can't use the
fireworks this year
for swimming okay
let's got a little bit more this way
hopefully we'll find an area with deep
ocean a lot of people are worried that
because my world's amplified I wasn't
gonna get the new biomes but I don't
think that's gonna be an issue
oh look at this oh we got coral here too
awesome
that did not take long at all I didn't
need no dolphins to find this even oh
man how do you get the chest I can't get
it I break the boat I don't want to
break the boat special a whole bunch of
poisonous potatoes okay
I think you're guaranteed to get one of
those oh I don't even know what they're
called the orbs yeah I got a break it
got a break in buried oh yeah we got to
find a buried treasure
right that's how it works so we find the
boats we feed the Dolphins kelp they
lead us to the boat and now we got to
find a treasure that's how it works
is there another chest
I'm breaking it whoa whoa somewhere
around here it's gotta be here right
so is it yeah it's a chest in the sandal
that's cool we get we got a heart of the
sea so I think you're guaranteed to get
one of those right in these very chests
100% thing TNT
I like that little blip iron a little
bit of food all right well it looks like
we have a pretty nice area here actually
where should we set up base because I
really like the coral biome the water is
really nice there all right but it's not
deep it's my one concern with the base I
want to make I want it I want it to have
deep water so maybe we gotta like dig
dig down or something like settle there
but dig a lot of land outs that's the
way to go by the way I'm not an idiot
I'm just forgetful you can just like
swim through these these things you
don't have to break the boat oh this is
a different layout - oops so not all the
boats are the same frost Walker leather
boots oh my goodness so is there like
always one garbage chest and then one
good chest another buried treasure let's
go try find it
so it would be this way right
oh we were on the map for a second
did this way
no it's this way oh I'm not good with
directions there we go there we go
figured it out it's gonna be up over
here then what we're getting close we're
getting close we're right on it and
[Music]
nothing oh man this pirate is stuff
pretty good should be like right around
here guess there's a little bit of sand
left I'm gonna take out some of this
stuff I can't find this chest oh there
it is there it is it was understandable
a little bit off the island though in
the water though yeah we got another one
cool they stack and pretty much the same
kind of stuff
I guess maybe let's try find like a
guardian temple because that'll be in
deeper water and then we Wheaton maybe
is that the boost effect from oh there's
magma oh oh yeah that's dangerous nice
and sizzly oh oh he's got a he's got a
trident another dolphin died where's my
food
I'm gonna die wait a minute wait a
minute there it is whoo this guy's gotta
try it man man those hurts good I got
good don't do it oh this is freaky man
he's like slowly coming around the
corner to get me oh he dropped it nice
first trident oh that's sweet
now we got to get the oh it's all broken
though or they always like that impaling
interesting even probably repair him
right I'm gonna have to look up how to
do that cuz I don't know oh man that was
that was pretty cool actually so do it
like this stuff
hey you know you want fish don't you
wait does he play with this stuff oh I
think he does oh that's cool I didn't
know that so if you throw items in the
water they kind of chase it and toss it
around Oh what is he doing he doesn't
like the lead he doesn't like the lead
guys how he's gone oh snap check it out
nautilus shell and fishing rod so we
have 11.5 percent chance of getting the
drop here
when we kill them with a looting three
sword
according to the wiki page okay here we
go here we go we need those Nautilus
shells for for making the conduits we
need eight of them oh we got it
holy smokes I'm either really lucky or
maybe the informations wrong now he
didn't drop the fishing rod okay so I
think I just got lucky there
to be honest I didn't care about the
fishing rod I just wanted this so I need
eight of those and then one part of the
scene aha
so I think I found it here guys I looked
in like 5,000 by 5,000 area and I think
this is the best spot I found to set up
a base it's it's pretty good what I want
doesn't really exist I don't think but
this is as close as I'm gonna get to it
probably I have certain criteria I'm
looking for like I would really like to
set up in a coral reef here we got a
pretty decent sized one you got the nice
blue water here all the plant life and
stuff and the only problem with this is
it doesn't go very deep none of these go
very deep ideally I would like to set up
a base in one of these coral reefs
that's like it.why 30 and this only goes
down to
fifty-three rights so I don't think
we're actually gonna live in a coral
reef but we're gonna want to live beside
one we could live here but then I'd have
to do a lot of terraforming which is a
lot of work so I think the next best
option is to set up the side one in a
lukewarm ocean I marked the spot with
some yeah down over here people live
somewhere around here so you'll notice
we go way down that was kind of at the
level of the coral reef and it goes way
down another like 10 to 20 blocks here
we're at Y 30 here which is about
perfect I would say you have the option
of going down more if you want or you
have like 30 blocks of water above you
so if you build tall towers or something
underwater it's gonna look good still
there's lots of boat wrecks I'm finding
tons of these things all over the place
we got the nice coral in the backgrounds
it's pretty flat too for building which
is usually kind of nice but also another
important thing there is a guardian
temple right beside this too which is
pretty cool I don't want to set up base
at the Guardian temple I think the
guardians would get kind of annoying and
then if we build the farm for them you
won't get normal mobs very often I want
to have like a natural mob firm and then
if we go like a couple hundred blocks
that way then we'll get the the
guardians like maybe we'll build XP farm
over there in the future could be cool
but yeah I like this I like this area a
lot one important thing why we want to
build near coral reef in the snapshot
that that's out right now that I'm using
31a you need the warm water to grow
corals you see that if you guys tried
that in the official release it's not
going to work not till the next update
but it doesn't work when you go to that
light this is deep lukewarm ocean
you get the kelp but you don't get the
coral so we're gonna need a coral biome
nearby possibly I think in the future
I'm surprised they didn't do this
actually they're gonna change it so that
this is just a hunch of mine I think
like even harvest these with with silt
that's right
so we inform them I kind of thought we
would use these to craft the coral
blocks like these actual blocks here but
I don't think you can craft these not
yet anyway but maybe in the future
they'll change at where use the corals
to make them like maybe nine of these
will make a blue one oh I get it
I got another one Wow doing pretty good
I just kidding I saw my song I'm gonna
get them don't you worry guys first
diamonds in the new area excellent
alright guys well one thing we should
probably do right away here we're gonna
be working in this area a bunch right so
I decided to put a portal in one of
these coral structures and I modified it
slightly so I think the way to do this
we've got a block up the sides right and
like sandwich ourselves in and then
remove maybe one side and the other side
yeah that'll work
alright then we light it and break the
I think that should be good that looks
weird alright so we probably gotta fill
in the water - right it's not gonna put
it out it's weird like the top part of
it looks fine but this part not so much
all right let's see where it takes us in
the nether we got to link up to our ice
road now
oh it took us right to the same spot
okay where will this take us now I took
us for we came out of Richland okay I'm
gonna break this one Oh as a glass
shattering sound now I didn't know that
we got another tried it dude if I get
this it's gonna be like one in 10,000 my
luck today no I don't think I got it
right kelp kelp no I don't I don't see
any tridents so it's eleven point five
percent chance of getting the Trident
with looting three rights but the first
first Trident guy I found and then the
two novelists first two Nautilus guys I
found all drop stuff so that was like
one in a thousand which is pretty lucky
I think so I discovered a glitch I think
I was digging up I was in the cave I was
digging up to get to the water rights
and some sand fell on me and then I just
glitched through all the blocks and I
fell through the world and lost
everything that sucks man what do I do
did I I don't think I deposited that not
all the shells even I can't remember if
I did I'm going to check what did I have
on me so I had my good armor I had my
good tools oh man that sucks so bad
beyond that I don't think it had
anything important and then I'll just
Nautilus shells right let me check did I
deposit those not that they're really a
big deal so I put that away I put those
two away shells are gone no I mean like
come on guys right like I'm a good
person I think I tried to be I follow
the rules as as much as I can I think I
don't how
do I stink straight down right and now
it's too much it's too much guys that
can't dig straight up now either can't
think straight down can't dig straight
up like where does it end I don't know
I'm ragequitting though I need time to
get my deer back and stuff right so most
of that I don't really care about to be
honest it's gonna take a little bit of
time right but I do have like backup
Elijah wings I've gone round quite a few
of the fortresses and stuff so not
worried about those the big thing is the
sword that sword had like seven
enchantments on or eight or something
that was hard to make kind of sucks
losing that plus we've had it forever
it was kind of growing attached to it I
do have a backup that's pretty good but
yeah that's the main thing and I'm upset
about anyways it'll be fine not too
worried about it well you get the
building next episode I guess I did have
some plans but they'll have to wait
let's get to the comment of the day it
says now pay attention guys because this
is important right I don't want you to
be victims either it says okay ergo
remember what I said last time about how
you should try onions I was wrong I
thought I was all under control and as
of recently I tried to go a day without
eating more than two onions but I
couldn't the onions have taken over as
soon as I realized the possibility of my
demise I locked myself in a room and
tried to cold-turkey my way out of the
misery but after two days I relapsed I'm
checking into rehab on Monday I hope
they can help me wish me luck now
there's nothing they can do you know I
know you're trying to say that onions
are great and you can't resist them and
stuff but they're terrible absolutely
garbage you'll ruin your life there's no
way around it let that be a lesson to
everybody don't eat onions stop putting
them in every single food item ever made
when you're cooking is a filler product
that tastes terrible and gives a
terrible crunchy nasty texture
honestly like it's the red onions those
are what really gets me green onions if
they're cooked well they don't really
bug me that much but the red ones that's
strong like nasty flavors just avoid
them guys that's it for today we'll get
back to the Aqua base in the future here
and we'll probably start working on the
ice firm or something next episode too
but anyways that's it for today have
yourselves a wonderful day take care bye
bye
[Music]