[Music]
oh yeah so we finally found one in our
world here guys these are actually kind
of tricky to get these these beehives so
yeah welcome back to another episode of
the let's play series we have updated
now to the where is it there it is
the 1.15 Update is out guys also known
as the bee so update we have we have
bees in the game we have honey blocks
and all kinds of cool stuff like that
it's mostly a bug fix update though but
pretty excited about the bee things so
I've been out and about exploring our
world here looking in new terrain
because these do not generate in
all-terrain no no no no you can't just
grow a tree to make them generates or
anything like that you have to generate
new chunks and when a tree spawns in
those chunks you have a 5% chance it'll
spawn a beehive wild beehive like this
now they also only spawn in plain
sunflower Plains or flower forest so
flower forest is probably the best place
to get them but I don't have like any
flower forest in my world or I have
trouble finding it so it's been hunting
around the the Plains here I've been
watching it for a little bit looks like
the bees have have made some honey so
they come out of the hive every so often
and then they go look for the flowers
there they're big chunky little dudes
they pollinate the flowers and then they
bring it back to the earth they're their
hive and like every five times they do
that they produce honey or honeycomb
that we can harvest so if we want to
collect the hive here there's a couple
ways to do it if we don't have like silk
touch on us and we want it as break it's
we have to put a campfire underneath it
I believe so that they don't get hostile
otherwise when you break it they they
just all come flying out of the hive and
attack you okay that didn't work
nevermind by the fire
okay so that doesn't work I thought it
did no and they stung me and I'm poisons
and after they sting you they lose their
stinger and they die in like a minute
afterwards if you look at him on the
back here he's got like got no stinger
now okay I gotta go find a new one now
all right I got pretty lucky here I
think this is the same Plains biome and
I found another hive so that's cool the
Sun is setting right now we got a couple
bees out and about I found three of them
flying around there's one right over
there I'm kind of watching them cuz I
think they're supposed to return to
their bee hive at nighttime right now it
looks like he's still looking for
flowers because it you found one over
there oh there's another hive here oh
alright well that's great news that
means we have two chances here to get a
bee hive without messing up hopefully so
I looked around I don't see any more
bees flying around so I think they
returned to their base I'm gonna use a
silk touch ax this time I think the ax
is the proper tool for harvesting these
and this time we'll have silk touch and
yes it drops as a block now so it says
it's got two tags I think that means it
has two peas inside I could be wrong
about that I think it for sure has at
least one though okay and then let's go
get this other nest here
let's fly around a little bit see if
there's any more bees flying around
because if we grab it before they return
home then we're not gonna get those bees
I don't see any around so I guess we'll
just grab it see what it says Oh little
guy fine manly screams and everything
what was it what's that also two tags so
we might have four bees now something
bad has happened
no oh no oh no oh no oh no this is not
gonna end well okay five and a half
hearts not too bad
today is not my day all right I just
built this off camera it's gonna show it
to you guys today like I might need to
do a couple repairs on it
all right so we might have a couple
problems to look into a little later
today but we're gonna focus on the B
stuff to begin with here I want to I
want to try set up a honey farm as soon
as possible so these are the hives we
got the two hives let's put them down
and yeah the bees came along with it I I
wanted to name these guys just to see if
there's more than one because apparently
like when they go back into the hive
they keep the name taken and everything
so that's kind of cool
we'll see if another guy comes out of
here because it says there's two tags
but one of those tags might just be
keeping track of like how much honey is
in the hive I'm not sure how that works
let's get this guy down to it yes oh
another guy he came out like right away
this one not so much right oh he went
into the different hives I I didn't
expect that I thought they only used one
hive I guess they can unless he's
attacking the other be in there hope not
yeah so I actually haven't played around
much with the bees so I'm trying to
figure out their behavior today as well
so it's night time I don't think they're
gonna come out of the hive during night
so I'm gonna sleep here see if they
emerge in the morning
I think there's like a cool-down after
they enter the hive before they can come
out again okay I might have messed up a
little bit um accidentally picked up the
hive when happy was out of it and he
attacked me and lost his stinger um yeah
so and the other hive I grabbed was
empty apparently so we only had the one
bee yep so that means I am back out
exploring looking for some more beehives
and I actually found a brand new flower
for us like when I arrived the water was
flowing down and everything so I thought
okay this is it this is the gold mine
the B gold mine right because there's so
many trees here if everyone has a 5%
chance there should be a lot of beehives
but I haven't found a single one which
has me a little bit shocked honestly
because I thought they generated here
yeah I'm gonna have to keep looking I
guess I I don't know I'm gonna look
around a little bit closer just to make
sure
whoo-hoo all right we found another
flower forest guys this is actually a
huge one by the looks of it and I found
for sure one beehive here I saw a bee go
inside it so we got at least one bee
what's this firm move a bee nest with
three bees inside oh it tells you if you
get a triple okay so that's all we
really need then we just need three well
we only need two so we can we can breed
them right but I'm gonna look around for
more hives since I've come all this way
we are about 8,000 blocks out away from
our our home base yes got another one
found another one I decided just to
sleep here I think I went through the
whole biome and I only found three but
if it's daytime they might be easier to
spot as they fly around out of the hive
oh yeah they're rare they're definitely
pretty rare Oh check it out it is a
birch tree one so they can spawn in
birch trees not just oak trees awesome
alright so we're back
home again but we brought with us check
this out six beehives from that one
biome the first flower forest we found
had none but that other one was huge and
we did pretty good there so our first
goal here I just want to get our
population of bees up that's like the
main thing to do so you can apparently
breed them if you hold the flower yeah
they come and kind of and follow you
around which is cool they eat flowers
and yeah we got a baby bee and you can
feed them flowers to make them grow up
faster too which is cool
so I think it's very important as we're
doing this not to put all our bees in
one basket because I think if I pick up
a hive and they're all gonna attack me
they'll all lose their stingers and
they'll all die so we want to have like
a couple different colonies around our
our place just in case I mess up again
will you eat more bigger though
I don't think he is very good very good
so we're making some good progress here
I put down a couple more of the hives
but I'm gonna save these three just in
case I make a mistake I don't want to
lose everything and have to go look for
more so I put down two more and they had
two in each so that's six starter bees
and I've read them I think four times or
so some of the bees they went over
towards this forest here and they never
came back even at night time like they
just stayed out there
I think they died a few of them I
noticed like when some of them flew over
the water they took damage so I don't
think they do too well out from the wild
yeah we have a few bees in our hive here
and you can see they're starting to fill
up with honey when it turns yellow like
this that means it's full they pollinate
it at least five times and you can see
it starts dripping honey like that too
underneath so that's cool now I think
there is some redstone stuff we can do
with this too so let's just check that
out
I think we can hook comparators up to
this I think we can use observers
oh yeah and dispensers we can use
dispensers which is also pretty pretty
awesome spencer's let's grab some
bottles and shears and just play around
with this a little bit so we can see how
much honey is in here by how far the
signal goes so I think if it's at five
its full while like this one we can see
isn't full just by looking at it let's
see what it the Redstone says u3 so that
only goes up to three right now uh-huh I
don't know I don't think you can check
how many bees are inside though I don't
think that's possible so we can we and
harvest these hives if we cook them with
a bottle we'll get honey if we cook
click on my shears we get honeycomb but
we need a campfire underneath if we
harvest them ourselves otherwise the
bees will attack us I think so one way
around that though is just to use
dispensers if the dispenser does the job
for us they'll leave us alone I think so
I'm gonna try to get some honeycomb if
we put some shears in there and this is
full
we should get it I hope they don't
attack me they didn't okay cool so then
you see we got honeycomb ona gives us
gives us three each that's pretty good
that's what we need to make our own hive
so yeah there's wild hives and then
there's custom homemade ones right
would she make like that so that's
that's our own beehives and I think they
function pretty much exactly the same it
would be kind of cool T to give the bees
paper or something so that they could
make their own hives like if they can't
find one and it's turning nighttime
maybe they they could make their own and
then this block would be farmable but as
is right now I think you can only get
these out in the wild but these you may
get as many as you want and these also I
think get comparator signals and stuff
so that's cool look that up to test it
out
let's try put some bottles in this one
just to make sure that works oh that was
weird the B popped out for a sec oh yeah
and it puts the honey bottle in the
dispenser cool cool what happens if it
is full as my question does it shoot the
honey bottle out then and if it does
that'll make farming this a lot easier
because then you don't have to filter
out the honey bottles right it'll shoot
out oh it did shoot out okay yeah that's
that's gonna be handy very cool and you
see the signal strength goes back to
zero so another pretty cool thing about
the bees is after they pollinate some
flowers they will actually drop the
pollen as they fly around so you can see
this guy he's full of pollen and he's
he's dropping these particles every so
often and look at that whenever they fly
over your crops they will advance them
at growth stage which is pretty cool you
might be able to do some neat stuff with
that I'm wondering if you can put them
in like minecarts and force them over
your crops or something I don't know I
kind of suspect it doesn't do it very
much is the problem cuz I'm like hold on
this guy here and he's he's not really
growing the crops too much it's probably
just like every once in a while right oh
there we go again
like maybe every 20 seconds or something
I was the guest maybe fifteen seconds oh
I think that might have been from the
other guy
oh I messed up again I placed down one
of my own homemade hives and picked it
up not thinking and a bunch of them came
after me and stung me and now they're
gonna die oh there goes one ah that
sucks
looks like they calm down so if they get
mad just run away from them if they
don't sting you they won't they won't
kill themselves like this guy he was mad
at me but he never stung me so he's he's
gonna be fine he still has a stinger
alright everybody so I've been goofing
around a little bit here just starting
to figure a few things out with the bees
let me show you a couple things so I
tried building one of these I got two
bees inside a little holding area here I
just want to see like the baby bee can
escape like these guys are too big and
chunky to get out of there we'll bring
them together see if that works it'll be
small enough to get out yeah so if we
want to make like a breeding area that
works pretty good that's pretty simple
let's see I think I think if you're
trying to do a bee farm like this is
probably the simplest and best method of
doing it just hook up a comparator to
the bee hive when it gets totally full
the signal will go five blocks into a
dispenser aimed at the hive and then you
can put foot either shears or your or
your glass bottles in there let's use
glass bottles as our example here so I
think what I would do is just fill that
up with the filter that way our glass
bottles will stay in the dispenser and
then whenever this goes five blocks the
honey bottle will go in here and down
into here alright so you just gotta put
like five empty or five stacks of the
glass bottles in here and eventually
I'll end up with five full ones down
here so that's pretty simple on a larger
scale I wouldn't use this method I don't
think the problem is if we go for
redstone it takes up quite a bit of
space like to do this also red stones a
little bit lady in the game it's better
to avoid using it and this is not all
that easy to tile as well I think if we
want to go for a larger scale firm
observers are gonna be the way to do it
like look at this this is something we
could do this method would allow us to
put the beehives side-by-side it's
easily tileable right
no redstone dust but there's definitely
a couple problems with this method as
well
the idea is this chain here is where we
feed our glass bottles and we keep that
full and they'll they'll get distributed
to all these dispensers right so that's
good that's simple and then we want
these totally filled up these dispensers
that way the honey bottle gets shot out
and they may all get picked up by the
hoppers below that works apparently I've
been testing it out seems to be pretty
good there there's a couple issues
though yeah that's actually let's take
these back out just make sure these are
kind of full all right so if we trigger
that like whenever honey goes into the
hive here it's gonna trigger the
observer flip the trapdoor go down into
the dispenser it'll shoot out a glass
bottle which will end up in here now
four out of the five times this hive is
not gonna have honey in it is the
problem that means it's gonna shoot
glass bottles into the hopper here and
we don't really want that to happen but
we can't really avoid that unless we use
the redstone method which will be
bulkier so we're gonna have to send
those we're gonna have to filter those
bottles from the full ones and then send
the empty ones back into this chain
which isn't a big deal I don't think the
other thing is though the way we got
this laid out
you see we two bottles went in here
trigger again two more go in two more so
what's happening is the observer is over
here going down to the dispenser it also
triggers the one next to it so if that's
in the middle it's gonna trigger the
middle one the one to the right and the
one to the left so that's three bottles
per trigger so times four four out of
the five times are gonna be empty glass
bottles we don't want that's twelve
glass bottles which we'll have to send
back into here that's not great so what
we can do is that I just changed the
pattern a little bit so that this
observer goes into a block before the
Descent this dispenser here that way it
only triggers this dispenser and not the
one next to it here so that's a little
bit better but a little bit bulkier
you see it's still at 30 there all right
but this one this one's gonna get
activated only one time I think that's a
little bit better I like this more than
then this style even though this one's
more compact let's see there's another
problem I noticed as well though
let's just play around with that so if
we we have a bunch of stuff in here
and we trigger it quickly like if we do
it slowly it's fine it'll always go into
the hopper but I noticed if I trigger it
quicker it's like the hopper can't keep
up and then they start shooting out past
it alright like this is fine if we go
slow if we start you start going a
little bit quicker they start shooting
out so that's one thing to keep in mind
with this design as well okay so I'd
like to be in this little area here I
wanted to start testing this thing out
but he's not doing anything like I don't
I don't even think he has pollen and he
won't grab from the flower here so I'm
not sure what's up with that he might
belong to a different hive that he's
trying to get bad to or something
he might need more space I'm just gonna
watch him now that's nighttime I'll see
if he goes into this high because he's
just been flying here all day yeah even
at nighttime he won't go into the hive
here there's a few other bees still
flying around too so I'm not sure what
that's about
yeah what do we do about this I tried
leaving the chunks and coming back and
he's still not working this this bee is
on strike he's not doing a lick of work
maybe let's try to give him a little
more space if that'll fix it I'll bust
this out so he can fly up
he's still just trying to get out of
there you guys I want to be in there
it's a flower right below you and a hive
you got everything you want
look what more could you want in life
okay maybe let's try a little test with
these two again let's put a beehive over
here all right so they'll be able to
enter from here I'm gonna close this off
we'll breed a new baby bee so they'll
have a flower in here and they'll have a
hive axis let's see if that works it
they'll go in the hive and pollinate the
flower and stuff okay that worked so
that baby bee he went right to the
flower and then right to the hive so we
gotta be careful where we get our bees
from we can't take them from another
hive I think and then add them to our
system when we make it otherwise we'll
get a zombie be like this that does
nothing it was this fly there forever
I'm a little curious about something
let's try this do these guys triggered
pressure plates or do they float above
them looks like they float above them oh
he did hit he did hit it though and he
went down like that every now and then
he'll swoop down I wonder why okay look
at that only that guy's doing it not
that one
oh it triggered one bottle came out okay
that's good
that is very good so four out of five
will be glass bottles looks like another
bee went in there I think they can enter
from the side of the hives actually they
don't have to enter from the front so we
actually got a worker in there now he's
trying to figure it out
he can't I'm surprised that you can see
it like through the blocks that's
interesting all right well he might find
the hive - I'm not sure I don't think I
mentioned this but I believe the limits
be leave yet it
I believe the limit for the hives is
three bees maximum I think there's three
in there fourth one can't go inside yeah
the plan is next episode
we're gonna make our big beef those lab
get all the honey and honeycomb in the
world but why do we want this stuff why
do we want it because we're kind of
running out of time this episode I guess
so these two things are pretty good with
the honeycombs we can make more beehives
but we can also make a decorative block
called
honeycomb that sounds pretty cool when
you walk on it actually so that's pretty
neat that's a nice block I could see
myself using that oh you don't use the
pick on it don't use that either okay
you don't use anything on it
yeah it's none of these four and it's it
doesn't look like as sheers either huh I
guess I guess it just takes a while to
harvest be careful if you're if you're
placing a lot of it down I guess yeah
there's a honeycomb box and then this is
the big one here the honey blocks oh
yeah look at these things they also
sound pretty cool so they're kind of
transparent they're very similar to
slime blocks they slow you down when you
walk on them I believe that feels slower
and you also can't really jump when
you're on them so that's a very unique
block I think that's pretty cool oh I
just got a cheap in sticky situation
jump into the honey block to break your
fall so I didn't know this they're
actually smaller than a full block you
can actually like I'm standing on the
piston here so you go in like 1/8 then
an eighth or a sixteenth of a block and
yeah if you if you like push yourself
against them as you're falling you do a
slow fall which is pretty cool pretty
cool also if you throw items at them
they kind of slow slow down the side
which is weird very weird this is gonna
have big applications in redstone as
well because they work much like slime
blocks in the in the sense that they
move blocks connected to them
all right but the big thing is they
don't actually move the slime blocks so
that means we can do stuff like this now
that wood couldn't before because
eventually you hit the limit on how made
you move uh-huh yes I'm pretty happy
about that as well probably try make
some redstone contraptions with the
honey block soon as well so maybe let's
do a couple other things here so this is
neat as well you make sugar from the
honey it's a good food source as well
it's look at this our food is full right
now
like all ten haunches but this is like
one of the few food items that you can
eat while you're full and it'll still
give you saturation you might need to
eat though to max it out so that's the
only problem I might be using that as my
main food source I haven't I haven't
figured it out yet I'll know once I try
it for a while but yeah that that gives
you saturation even after you're full
which is cool there's a few other things
that change like again we had a lot of
bug updates as this updates and a couple
new features like if we try to sleep
during the day we can now set our spawn
points even though it won't let us sleep
so that's neat I went over I used the
mushroom farm today and I noticed this
right away is like this is the level the
mushrooms are supposed to grow it and
some of them grew taller now which is
different so they I guess the check on
them changed which means I'll probably
just have to put a layer trapdoors at
the top here so that they always grow at
that height instead but that's worth
noting I think look in the inventory
here or our our GUI it looks like we got
highlights around the buttons now which
is a nice little feature and check this
out - this is pretty cool it's a simple
feature but it's nice iron golems now
show how much damage they have I think
there's like three different stages of
damage they display depending on how
many cracks they have so this guy's
looking pretty worn out right I think we
can heal them if we give them my iron
ingots that might have been
the second stage of damage this isn't
the guy that escaped from our tape by
the way he died this is a new one I just
put down you should on the Left home I'm
telling you the cruel world out there
can you take one more hit
can't tell oh yeah you hear that crack I
think that's when it switches so I think
he's at the most damaged state now so
each each ingot heals on one stage I
believe yeah so he's not fully repaired
still not fully repaired now he's good
brand new
that's neat I like that um let's see
let's head over to our place here I'll
show you the building that burned down
so I did finally add another building to
Sandy City oh my goodness right at this
rate we'll be done in ten years
a blacksmith building over here so this
is kind of cool I have like a little
shoppers area here people can stand
check out the products that are made and
then we got a furnace over there that's
what burnt everything down I've got some
stash of materials to work with is anvil
cauldron for cooling things etc etc
right I tried to lay it out like a like
a store would be right so this is the
work area for the guy this is the
storefront cashier area armorstands
where we can display some some armor for
sale and over here is like where you can
watch them working and stuff right not a
lot of detail on this side I'm planning
on putting another building here and
then maybe an alleyway between so I
didn't do much with that couple plants
outside here too and then on top I just
put like a bell tower oh yeah so we got
some a little bit of a roof over here to
stand on there's plants over there
banners hanging down and over here we
got a bell
can we bring that with the Trident I'm
not sure oh yeah you can look at that
cool cool but anyways let's get to the
comment of the day it says hey etho you
haven't mentioned your Internet in a
while have you managed to get better in
it Internet or are you still struggling
with uploading overnights great video
the Flying Spaghetti Monster so yeah if
you guys don't know in the past I had
some pretty bad internet I had like 0.4
upload megabits per second I had to add
to endear that for for many years the
early days of YouTube but now I've
gotten better internet and they improve
it every so often - which is cool I just
did a speed test and I get I wrote it
down here somewhere yeah 95 megabit
download 16 megabit upload so that's 40
times faster than it used to be which is
pretty good it takes maybe two or three
hours to upload a video on average I
would say now that I'm uploading at 60
frames per second and nine twenty by ten
eighty so it's not bad it's not bad at
all I can't complain anyways hopefully
you guys enjoyed the episode if you did
enjoy it please remember to exercise
today even if you didn't enjoy it you
should probably do that looking forward
to playing around with the honey stuff
in that so I'll do that next episode but
until then you guys have yourselves a
great day take care bye bye
you
[Music]