hey everybody welcome back to the let's
play today I didn't really have any
specific project in mind I'll probably
do a bunch of random stuff little
projects first thing I'm going to do is
convert all these swamp trees or most of
them into glowing trees that's something
I've wanted to do for a while got our
original glowing tree up here so I'm
going to go ahead and do that and I'll
see you guys in a little bit okay well
it's going good here I think I converted
quite a few trees think about 32 maybe I
don't know I can't remember how many
pumpkins I had when I started all I'm
doing is I go to the top of the tree
remove one leaf one log place the
pumpkin and then leaf again and that's a
glowing tree a few leaves will die when
you do this but overall it's pretty good
and yeah that's all there is to it
excuse me I'm burping here just drinking
coffee
remove your pillar use that to get up um
yeah this is what it looks like when
you're all done it's pretty cool in my
opinion I'll probably just do it on
these swamp trees I don't think I'll cut
them down for wood or anything since you
can't can't grow swamp trees so like to
use them for decoration keep them here
oh that's a lot and erm it one hits nope
all right on to something else I got
some good news
water canals in the slime farm seem to
be working as far as I can tell a little
helper over here so when they're in the
water they can't jump as a little
worried they weren't going to be able to
get up these stairs because some people
commented that they can't but yeah they
can and I've seen about four or five big
slimes in that hay in that corner
already so they seem to be getting
around these that bends no problem -
which is excellent I might try do a
little bit with this today yeah okay let
me think about what I want to do now
probably from top of my head I think
I'll make this go up then I might make
it do like a switch plate so it a little
left then back to get some height for
the slimes and then I'll drop them into
three different holding chambers maybe
one for the big ones one for the mediums
and one for the small ones kinda what
I'm thinking it should be really easy to
separate them - so give me a sec to get
prepared here and we will do something
okay let's get started here now I am
going to be changing this around quite a
bit I originally I wanted to keep that
like this just so they would match and
this is just going to be for small
slimes but now I kind of want to try
separate them just for just for the
kicks of it for fun and I don't really
need to copy this one here this needs to
be like this for the cave spiders
because of their annoying climbing
ability and ability to sneak out of
small areas this works very well for
them but we don't really need it for for
the slimes here so let's tear this out
start fresh and I got an idea I want to
try out here I don't know if I'm going
to keep it but I just want to see how it
will work out I hope I didn't wreck
anything there oops this pick is too
good I tell you efficiency five it's too
good you just end up breaking everything
with it I actually almost prefer
efficiency for just because of that okay
get rid of this glowstone well see it
went through two blocks there did not
want that well I did but that's not what
it is trying to do okay so we will have
the small slimes here maybe we'll put
down glowstone just to mark it right
there and I guess we'll do these walls I
guess we're going to do a quick two
something like this that will be the
holding area
I'm going to be making this up as we go
along here something like that glass in
front so they'll fall down into this one
by one thing I'll probably set up
something to get the drops out too but
what I want to try do will have the
medium slimes over here let's give her
this water okay and we'll have it
similar I should probably get some more
glowstone will have a 2x2 area here Oh
sounds like we just got a new one a big
one let's check it out
oh it's at least yeah two big ones in
here without dying wanna want to see one
of these guys through the obstacle
course get up here
I just we have to kill one of them -
tomatoes to make this okay I'll check
the water get up here
get up here and we will make them run
over here just want to make sure he gets
around a corner
everybody's having a good time
beautiful yeah that works good okay
let's sit back there yeah so this is
what I was wanting to try here don't
don't look at this is the final thing
I'm doing here this is just a test that
I'm setting up what I want to try to do
is have a chamber here for the small
slimes and then a 2x2 one for the medium
ones and then 3x3 for the large ones so
there's a two block gap between them and
the idea I kind of want to try out is
first off automatically separate them
into each of their appropriate sizes but
then I want to see how this works out if
I have them self separating thing as
well so for example if I have a medium
slime in here
and I manually kill it it's going to
drop some XP which I would like to
collect and then it's going to split
into small ones and I want to see if I
can get a manual or a separator here
that they will use themselves so in this
holding area for the medium slimes
there's going to be a little staircase
here and it goes up goes over here and
then falls down into the small slime one
so when I when I separate them they're
pathfinding should make them go up here
and then they'll fall down and then they
can't get back into that chamber and I'm
gonna do the same thing over here or at
least try to so if I do something like
this medium slides can get up here and
then they'll get up onto this glass here
as well and then they will fall in and
they won't be able to get back up this
is what I'm trying to do just to see how
it goes I'm I'm curious
so yeah this will be another brick over
here okay and here just experimenting I
will probably want to use glass somewhat
with this so the final thing so I can
see it from an angle because the way I
had it before you pretty much have to
look straight on to see the slides in it
like if this isn't glass here because if
if you look at it like this you won't be
able to see anything really
unless it's glass or something else
transparent okay yeah okay I'll finish
setting this up and then we'll hopefully
do some water canal systems get them up
here and separate them and I'll see you
in a little bit again so this is what
I'm planning at the moment for the water
canals you can make it go up here it's a
half slab and then these are stairs
there and there and it's going to go
this way and then it's going to do a
u-turn and start going this way I got to
get this up oh yeah and the water is
going to go in the corner here so it
should push the slides up these stairs I
got to get this up to I think why fifty
three or so that's the whole point of
doing the switch switch back or whatever
it's called
so was it at about 39 40 there I'm going
to get it all the way up to here
46 over here I think it's going to go
three blocks above here so all the way
up to 52 is how high we have to get 51
or 52 to make this work the way I'm
thinking and let's see what is our X or
Z that is 178 it's hard to do this
because I can't see how far this thing
here is away from the waters canals
below all the lands in the way when I
say 178 this is 190 so I have 12 blocks
or so to work with isn't a whole lot
okay so at maximum we can make them go
up one block every two blocks out we go
if we do the stairs oh no my efficiency
five pick now I don't think I have any
good ones left
Jenna finish Iblees farm man okay yeah
like this so goes block then stair
blocks and stair that's a the quickest
way of getting them up ah that's not
counting ladders so the thing about the
ladders it only really works with the
small slime some of you might have seen
that I'm trying to not use them because
I want to move the big ones there and I
have played around with trying to make
big slimes and medium slimes go up
ladders in the past
don't turn out too good so with upcoming
patch and ladder is not having closure
to ask the small slimes might not be
able to climb up them anymore either so
I'm trying to prevent using them what I
need to pick okay
I'll give you an update a little bit
here yep things are going good here I'll
show you these the idea behind these
pathfinding separators again so the big
slimes go here they are two point four
blocks in all three directions in size
so the big slimes can't get to this
smaller chamber here because it's only
two blocks in there 2.4 in size so they
can't fit through here the smaller or
the medium slimes will and then they'll
fall down but it's a 2 block drop so
they can't get back this way the medium
slimes or small sliders can't make it
back this way either when I split them
here then we'll have nothing but small
signs left and they make it they can hop
up here hopefully we'll see how it goes
again I don't know how useful that's
going to be or anything just doing it to
try it I got the nel path thing I think
figure it out pretty good here so this
is it this is the path I can take it and
go like this and we got a big slime here
you will actually be very useful to help
us see if there's any spots where you
stuck so the first one now you can get
higher let it stuck here higher oh baby
this is getting pretty fancy here
I got rid of all the crummy walls and
replace them with stone brick this is
perfectly shaped so the large slimes
and get up here over here we have a
little viewing window area I'll probably
make this whole wall here glass so you
can see it from outside possibly and
goes up and this is where we'll start
separating them right around here
I'm going to put alternating glowstone
for looks and light on the way up here
so yeah I'm liking this a lot it's
perfectly shaped so the large slime can
get up with just enough space and yeah
this will all be water canals pushing
them up here too so I'll have to have
the signs lots and lots of signs in here
or I could use fence gates but I'll
probably do signs and I'll see you guys
in a little bit when I work on this some
more again yeah so the slime project
kind of added a little bit of a bonus to
this part of the cave we have a little
viewing area here now so you will be
able to see the slimes coming up and
going to the top there ah let me know
what you guys think of this I'll have to
have some better place to stand here to
see it because when you're down lower
you don't see a whole lot to be honest
but I don't I kind of like it let me
know what you guys think there's any way
to improve it or if I should just
completely block it off had to trim away
a little bit of the stone this is pretty
much set up for the water now I start
adding some already
and I haven't seen any slimes come up
yet
but probably pretty soon I'll get one
for the corners I just put one two three
by three things so and there's three
stairs over here put the water in the
corner and they're forced to flow into
the stairs and I'll do the same probe
for this corner Oh No
dang it dang it dang it dang it dang it
dang it oh that hurts
but yeah despite what just happened it's
going pretty good
so I'm just starting to work on the
slime separator here the automatic one
the idea is pretty simple only small
slimes will be able to fit down here
because they're 0.6 blocks in size all
three directions while medium ones are
1.2 blocks in size and all three
directions so they just can't fit down
here too fat too fats so what I'll do is
I'll have signs here that the water will
be able to flow on top but since slimes
don't swim in water they should just
sink down here I would imagine into
another water currents now we're going
to set up
so another water current will be below
I'll push them this way and we want it
to push them down into their little
holding chamber we have setup which
should be right here we got to go to
there one two three four five six seven
eight nine ten eleven Oh might not work
like I hoped we can extend this using
the stair inside stair and sign trick
anyway so yes that's what we'll have to
do just about done here we got all the
sign filters set up so this is for the
small ones then this one here is going
to be for the medium ones and we don't
have to worry about slope the small ones
getting in here because they already get
sifted out at this point so that's why
we do the small ones first do so that
there's none at the medium ones
otherwise they would fall down there too
and then over here we don't need to put
signs above for water because there's
nothing further this is the last one so
this is where the big ones will fall
down and then we just got to get them to
their drop points down here ideally I
should have had this water canal thing a
little bit further this way I guess but
whatever we'll make it work and I did
have a couple slides come through here
and it seems to work okay so far okay
we're just going to put the rest of the
water in here
I think this part is all done and we
just need to work on the separate water
canals put one here careful not to fall
down whoa
that scared me must be close to the
surface yep okay so the medium ones will
fall down there big ones will go there
they will fall down into a stream here
and then we need one more yet over here
awesome day hopefully I still have a
sign on me nope darn yeah make one
alright we got a sign so for the small
slimes over here is their water canal
and I'm going to make it so there's a
sign right here and it's replaces with
stone brick and water right above there
should do the trick
awesome yeah and I'll fill the city oh I
guess we should place that and that's
good that one's done this medium ones
pretty much done just have the large one
alright
replace all these walls with stone brick
and the floor okay with the big ones I'm
going to cheat a little bit here I have
pressure plates because this is at nine
blocks long this thing and water only
travels eight blocks so that way I don't
have to have two streams here do it like
that
and if you take them right to the end
close this off I think that's everything
here so now all I have to do is watch us
make sure it works and we'll have to fix
this front here because I'm not going to
keep it like this this is pretty pretty
darn ugly if you ask me I have to try
figure out something that looks cool
we'll probably integrate some Pistons
into this and other things as well but
for for this time I'm just going to
watch it well it looks like we've got a
few slimes here and they're behaving
he's not getting out so I guess what I'm
going to do is just try see what happens
if we split them see if they'll make
their way up you can do it buddy oh
you're so close oh you know what they're
gonna track me I didn't even think of
that
so as long as I go over here uh-huh
yeah I didn't think of that
again I have no idea if that's gonna be
useful at all having the extra separator
there but I just want to see how it
would work and I think I'm going to end
the episode here we'll have to watch
this a project for a while again just to
see how it works
we'll probably do something else next
time but for today thank you for
watching and I'll see you again next
time