[Music]
hello
greetings word to your mother welcome to
another
episode of let's play some minecraft
with etho
today i thought we would step away from
the man cave for a little bit
work on something else head back to
the stronghold over here with the
silverfish farm in the
future storage room and mob systems
that's where they're gonna be
and work on these for a little bit um
i know i said i'm not gonna leave a lot
of projects unfinished in this world but
it's happening and deal with it because
that's just the way i
am but i think we're doing better with
this world than the old one at least
we are actually finishing things like uh
we started that mini storage room and
finished it
all in one shot which is good
now with this silverfish farm the reason
we kind of stepped away from this
project for a little while
i you see this room up here
this is basically
right at this level and in this position
here is where our future
mob system and storage room is going to
be this is like the level
that the floor will be at pretty much
hovering just a little bit above the
silverfish spawner here
so that will be active and hidden away
in the basement somewhere
and we're going to have a mob system in
the middle of the storage room like i
like to do
now what i did you see this little heidi
thing here
basically i sealed myself in for 30
minutes or so
came back and i was just checking to see
if the silver if the silver fish farm
here is stable
and it's not after
it'll run for about 20 minutes or so
fine but then it's
it jams up generally so
it needs to be redone the way i got it
built right now is technically
correct the problem comes with
the silverfish glitching through blocks
like when this piston goes up they will
sometimes
not go up with the block they'll get
stuck inside it
and suffocate and gold poi and go places
where they don't belong
so we're going to rebuild it exactly the
same
this spawning room and that can all stay
but this part here
all this stuff needs to be moved we're
going to rebuild it the same though
something on fire
i'm going to rebuild it the same except
instead of having a piston push them up
from below we're gonna have a piston
push them from the side
so that uh they won't be forced down by
gravity which is i think the main
culprit behind the problem of them
glitching through blocks
and instead of having a drop like i have
here
we'll just have it all flat i think and
not have a water stream pushing them
and see if that works out better so
off i go and i'll work on that a little
bit
okay so before i had the silverfish fall
down and they would enter
the side of the block of the stone over
there
the new plan is to basically move
everything over
two blocks to the right here and instead
of entering the stone from the side they
will enter it from
on top so right where this cobble is
is where they'll enter the block and
they'll just free roam
on this part here there'll be no water
stream
and then when they enter there uh this
piston will push out
sideways and prevent any more from
being able to enter the stone before
it's ready
that's the general plan so basically i
got to move everything over two blocks
and since there's no easy way to do that
in minecraft i gotta tear it all down
and rebuild it fun
okay so here's a little bit of an update
on the progress this is about an hour
later
not as much done on it as i would have
liked in this amount of time but the
thing is i built it once already
and had to tear it out again because
the piston that pushes the silverfish
out of the way
was right next to the bud switch so
every time it would do that it would
update the bud switch
which was a mistake now this time i
built it
i made sure that wouldn't be a problem
this is
in a place where it won't uh cause this
to update
so it's basically where we're at right
now
it's working good i'm really happy with
this setup
uh this little section here is the bud
switch
piston extends block comes out powers
this
wire goes to one torch and then to
repeater
power is this block here which is
diagonal of the piston so
that's a pretty compact one i'm happy
with that and
then it goes
over here as well branches this way this
goes to the cobble
for the smooth stone generator and it
is the wire is one two three four five
six seven eight nine ten eleven twelve
thirteen long
so we don't need it to stick a repeater
in which is good it'll be fast
not that that matters much so the only
thing we need to add yet
is the delay this oh
this wire here needs to branch off again
to delay and then go to this piston
and that delay needs to be long enough
to give
time for smooth stone to generate
and that's all there will be to this and
i think it's going to work
pretty confident about this i hope it
does because i don't want to rebuild
this
another time i've probably done that at
least
10 times total now with this thing
so i would like to get it working finely
all right it's finished got it done
and then i tested it out afterwards too
and i filled up this entire room
with silverfish that's over 150
no problem at all didn't jam up once
so i'm really happy with it so far i
think it's stable
and we can
[Music]
finally assume that we won't need to
adjust it anymore in the future
i'm hoping oh damn no i did it i did it
what the where's my underprogram
must hit a silverfish right here i must
be on a region border it lags every time
i walk across
that border pretty much you see that
every time i go across almost
almost
try it again yeah
so this killing room like i said before
is not finalized we will do something
a little bit more fancy in the future
but for right now
it does the job
let's put a few more don't we
come on come on
hmm
oh well okay let's do it poisoned
that hit two only 11 seconds worth for
me
[Music]
and then damage
will it kill them all
kill me whoa
oh now they came out you see that
um
yeah it's quite a bit of xp just from
that little amount
oh
[Music]
okay so let me clean up these guys and
i'll show you
the final system here
all right so we can see it up and
running here i had to go away for a
little bit
and stood next to it for a few minutes
again
that whole room filled up no problem no
jams
so that's about 400 or so silverfish
it's gone through
without any problems so far
so i think we have it working stable
finally very happy about that
i did go with a water screen here after
all
just because it seems to help to get
them to that point there
a little quicker than if they're free
roaming on that
area there or so it seems i don't know i
might play around with that yet
that sandstone block there we can
probably lower the timing a bit
to make this even quicker uh
basically it just needs to stay out long
enough to give the smooth stone
time to generate so we could probably
cut that
time it's extended at least in half if i
was to guess
but i will have to tinker with that
i'm all out of keys because we get some
more
uh this wiring nothing changed except i
added
like i said i was going to the the timer
here
grant is off over here this repeater
prevents it
or prevents the current from over here
from flowing back
to the smooth stone generator
then we got our pulse extender this is a
t
flip flop no not a t flip flop rs nor
latch
um this is a delay over here
wraps around goes to this
and that switches the our snore latch
again
but it also branches off over here and
goes to the top
so this is the same as that pulse
extender i showed a few episodes ago
where there's no wait time afterwards
and it doubles up the length of the
repeaters
and basically this just connects to the
piston up here
so that's all there is to it
um and i guess we'll just
have to watch it over time and see how
it does
this room over here i'll probably make
instead of making it spread out
horizontally like this i'll probably
have a smart piston push
these blocks up six blocks and then
we'll push that column to the left or
something and then
have that all push over this ways
so it should make a six high
maybe 12 by 12
thing of blocks i'll have to do the math
and figure out maybe i need seven i
can't remember to get that amount i want
and beyond this
i think we're gonna play around with the
mob system
and see how that goes i'm gonna use the
same design i used on the minecraft
server
as far as
efficiency and ease of build and all
that goes i think it's
probably one of the best options i don't
want to use one of those
mob systems where the water flows over
the pads because that causes an
extreme amount of lag even though it's
probably a little bit quicker
i i'm going to try to avoid avoid using
something like that
i've been listening at this level here
and you can just barely hear the pistons
and the silverfish noises
so this is going to work out really well
we won't
have that annoying noise or it won't be
very noticeable anyway
uh when we build our storage room up
here that stuff will be happening in the
basement out of sight out of mind
which is kind of the idea and uh
at that level there we're we're far
enough away from these silverfish that
they can enter the block because if you
get
too close to them then they track you
and they won't enter
stone blocks until you're about i think
like eight blocks away from them or
something i don't know for sure
so that's fine but we're also very close
to the spawner because it
is i think this height here
right in the middle there so
we can walk quite a ways away from this
middle
and still have silverfish spawning
like if we're over here they'll probably
still be spawning
anywhere in this room actually i think
we would be in range
so
this is going to turn out pretty good
once it's all said and done
we're going to head to the end and
finish leveling up to level 50
do an enchantment and
then i don't know actually you know what
i wanted to show you too
uh if you notice my pick disappear in
this s
in this episode it's because
i've been doing some uh demolishing
taking the stronghold down harvesting
the
the mossy blocks and the cracked ones
before
the silverfish destroy them all
looks pretty cool apparently
i wasn't here before this must have been
hidden because i found the chest with
stuff in
um
yeah over here there was a staircase
that went down that's all gone
what was that there's a lot of slimes
around this area too and that's about as
far as i made it
so i'll probably keep demolishing it
i don't know if we're building a base
here we don't really
want this here anyway and it's good to
get the blocks from it
and it looks kind of cool even with the
all the good blocks gone it's really
open now
all right we got the 50 hoping to get
something with efficiency and unbreaking
and we got just that beautiful so
that'll keep me going for a while again
uh i guess now i think
i think what we'll do is we'll go to a
creative world and just build
the mob system and maybe stress
test it a little bit i don't really have
mcedit working so i can't build a full
one
in a flat world or anything like that
like i wanted to before
but we can play around with it a little
bit get it fresh in mind
so off we go
yeah so we're in a creative world right
now in a super flat
and i i just want to build like one
layer of the mob system
to get it fresh in mind and to show you
guys
uh how to do it in case you want to copy
it and to run a few tests on it as well
afterwards
so basically there's
these three by three pads they're very
small
and one more there you start with like a
a big flat thing like this
and i think in total there was 12 pads
yeah it goes like that
so there's no signs involved with this
mob system there's no pistons
or anything fancy like that it's
pretty bare bone much like the old
old-school mob systems i used to build
uh
i always built the six by six pad ones
but this one
has even smaller ones three by three
to decrease the amount of time the mobs
need to wander to
fall into water
and it seems to work pretty good so
let's see goes one two three four five
six
seven blocks eight blocks from
the middle the water ends just
short of that
and i don't think there was water on
this side of the pad i think
it went from
there the next one
let's try this let's see how it goes
yeah
yeah i think that's what it was
we'll extend this out
put another stream
yeah so this corner one it goes to
emerges with that
and the mobs keep getting pushed that
way
so it's like that
and we'll probably build this pretty
quick
in the world it'll be i think about 30
blocks or so above
the the end portal in the stronghold
area there
will kill the mobs by dropping them
i might set up emp units i kind of have
a plan with that
yeah that's that's really simple
and then you don't need that
don't know what kind of block i should
build it out out of if you have any
suggestions
let me know um
i was almost thinking of doing like half
slabs on the sides too
to make it look cooler but i'm not sure
if
letting in that faint lighting will
cause any problems
goes like that
um i think i covered
above that actually yeah
yeah something like that and then the
walls would go up
two blocks and then the next
next layer would be above that
i think no wait these pads need to go up
two blocks
so that the mobs can't hop back up
the next layer would be over here
and i believe i put half slabs
see where are our wooden ones
right there yeah i put half slabs over
here i don't know if i'm going to
do it that way because another another
thing i could do is do like an upside
down half slab here
and then uh spiders
no that won't work because uh if a
spider tries to spawn
over here they'll be able to
if there's no half slap so i guess we do
need it
um i'm going to do a little bit more
workout
here off camera and then we'll run some
tests
yes that's what one layer looks like
it's all enclosed now
each layer is five blocks tall
and i just did the top out of glass here
so we could see inside but
you would do it out of some solid block
and
in my lp world i'm guessing
i'll start it about y 40 or so
and go all the way up to
why 128 or so i'm it'll be
i think about 16 layers total
which is i figured out with these 12
pads
12 times 8 is 96
and if we do 16 layers 16 times 96
is 1536
so that's quite a bit of spawning space
i think it'll
be sufficient um whatever block i do
choose to build this out of i gotta
i gotta choose something where i can get
a lot of it quickly
oh i missed a spot so like wooden planks
is obviously easy to get
any any type of wood is pretty easy
stone is really easy to get like stone
bricks cobblestone
regular stone but things like
wool or um
sandstone brick those type of blocks
not really ideal for this
and since like a lot of it's going to be
underground it doesn't really matter too
much what it looks like either
but or maybe we could do sandstone if
it's a mixer's handstone and something
else that's not
too tough to get i don't know
i would like it to look good maybe not
all
one one type of lock like this or one
plain pattern and
i also wanted to try spawn some mobs on
here and see how they react
how quickly they fall in the water
this is they're going to behave just
like
they would in survival if i was out of
the area and they weren't targeting me
the big thing is that they don't stay on
the pads for too long like that guy over
there
oh don't blow up if they did that
um their idle timer would kick in and
then they would get stuck on the pad
until
they despawned they wouldn't walk off
if they linger too long that's one of
the reasons i want the pad so small here
but overall it seems like they're
wandering off pretty quick
and this thing will spawn zombies
skeletons and creepers only these half
slabs in the middle prevent spiders from
spawning uh and it's only too high in
here so enderman won't spawn either we
don't need enderman
in the main world in our lp because we
have the enderman trap
and i'm also watching this thing here
this is something else i wanted to
check out that i couldn't really do on
the minecraft server
is uh if we got a lot of mobs in here if
the middle jam up it'll prevent each
other from going down
completely or not
seems like they're getting in each
other's way but
they're still falling down so that's
good i don't think it'll be a problem
yeah they're still falling down that's
okay
so this should work out pretty good
and on minecraft it took me about
two or three hours to build that that
big thing
that was without any materials i had to
grow
tons of trees and stuff too and and
harvest that
uh in my lp world i got a lot of
materials so i think it'll go fairly
quick
and there's no pistons or anything so i
it's very cheap
and shouldn't cause too much lag either
because
there's no water currents being made or
pistons moving or anything like that
so it should be good anyway i'm going to
get going here
uh i was supposed to record this a few
hours ago but i ended up playing dwarves
versus zombies with paws and and tom and
rob and all those guys
we're very addicted to that game
and i was supposed to do my taxes
tonight and everything too
and i never did so i have to do it
another night
but we did record tonight as playing
that so
we'll probably both be releasing videos
pretty quick of it
and i think you guys will like it it's a
very cool game
i love playing it it's it's like a mod
for
like a bucket mod for minecraft
and it's pretty cool but
that's it for me for today thanks for
watching everyone and i'll see you again
next time
[Music]
you