[Music]
hey
what's up everybody this is etho and
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play series how you guys doing
today
uh i am very excited here today we are
going to be doing something special
uh it's hard to believe but we've been
playing the series for years
and years and years almost 500 episodes
now
and believe it or not there's still
things we have never done
in our let's play series here and today
we're going to be doing one of those i
brought up the idea last episode of
maybe trying out a texture pack
just to see the world from a different
perspective not as a permanent thing
i want to clarify not as a permanent
thing just a one time thing for funsies
just to see how the world will look
different here with the texture pack
and i brought it up last time you guys
seemed okay with it
didn't really see any people against the
idea so
if you are you missed your chance you
should have said something last time
so uh you also mentioned we should maybe
check out
shaders so we're going to be doing that
too
uh but one concern was like our last
world tour episode was over
an hour and a half long how are we going
to see our world
or much of our world uh checking out
shaders checking out texture packs
it's gonna be hard to to really see much
so i thought of an idea here are you
guys ready for this
here we go
[Music]
[Applause]
summer in the hills those
hazy days i do remember
we were running still at the whole world
at our feet watching
seasons change our roads were light
with adventure mountains in the
way couldn't keep us from the sea
here we stand up
this is home where we are
ever strong in the world
see your shadows in the trees
[Music]
[Applause]
aha so hopefully you guys enjoyed that
uh little montage of our world hopped up
on shaders here
i had a lot of fun editing that together
on on my mac
just kidding i used a real computer not
a potato
but no that was kind of something
different right i had a lot of fun with
it
i was watching it back afterwards though
and it's like
you know there was this really graceful
moment in the song
and for some reason i included the scene
where i face planted into
the desert well there it's like ah i
probably should have done something
different for that scene
oh well uh yeah anyways it is a fun
thing
fun thing to do here so this is the
silders
vibrant shaders that's what i recorded
the video in and
that's what we're on right now i've
tried a few different shaders i'm not
super accustomed to them but of all the
ones i've tried this one's definitely my
favorite
it gives it uh it like boosts the
saturation of all the
all the colors which gives it more of a
cartoony look
instead of a realistic look i would say
and in my opinion maybe we'll talk about
some of the high
high points and low points of shaders so
in my opinion
everything above ground in the sunlight
like where we are right now looks pretty
incredible i would say
i i like it a lot uh personally um
especially like when you look at the
windmill here it's it's just incredible
like the
the amount of colors and stuff and the
brightness to it it's just
looks pretty good but now there's a lot
of down
downsides to shaders like you can see on
the windmill there there's a weird
shadow
jumping around that's from the beacon
over there which you can't really see
because the sun's too bright
and there's a couple issues
um i have with shaders um
especially when you go underground
things get really
dark but in the trees here for example
oh man this looks beautiful
absolutely gorgeous i don't use that
word too often
but i would use it here and i couldn't
believe like i was
just looking at the course fruit here
for example like that
i just stared at it and it's like man
that looks incredible for some reason
i don't know how they do it but yeah
something as simple as course fruit even
looks amazing
or if you stare at a block it just seems
like so much more detailed
so yeah that that's the good to it
the bad is like weird shadows
uh darkness underground if you use
shaders you kind of have to start your
world using shaders you can't just
convert to them because then
certain things aren't going to look
right i would say
but like anything in the man cave i
thought looked pretty bad
anything underground
but here let's check out some of these
other shaders as well i got two more
loaded up soos and mr meeps
this is the seuss one and this
i believe is made by the guy that
actually made the shaders mod
and it's a pretty pretty high-tech one
as well like i think it's the one that
leads all the super fancy technical
stuff with reflections and water
and advanced technique i don't know what
i'm talking about
uh but uh for me
it looks it looks okay i like the sky in
it the sky looks very realistic
uh but i find uh there's like a haze in
front of you at all times i played with
the settings a lot and i just can't seem
to get rid of that like there's smoke
wherever you go kind of feeling maybe
we'll go underground real quick here too
by the way this is a separate
installation of minecraft in case you're
wondering because
to do this you have to install
forge optifine the shaders mod
and and yeah
so i decided to just make a separate
installation separate save file and then
when we're done here we're gonna
we're gonna scrap it and just go back to
our world nothing's gonna change in that
uh yeah it's just
i don't know the colors are a little bit
better underground with it like
the green actually looks green still but
it's still very hazy
i would say and now let's check out mr
meeps
uh real quick here as well and then
we'll get to the texture packs
all right hopefully this doesn't cause
too much trouble
oh this one's a lot smoother i can feel
not quite as taxi on my
computer here texting taxing
also we had to downgrade to get all this
working so that's why there's no
villagers or mobs in our world they all
disappeared when i downgraded
you know underground i would say this
one's actually better than the silder
vibrant one
i think it looks a little bit better
it's not too bad actually all right
let's go above grounds
um after like today's episode something
i've been thinking about lately is
getting a new computer i'm
usually get a new computer every three
years and especially when we're by the
man cave it gets pretty laggy with
shaders on
so after messing around with it here
today it's like oh i really want to get
a new computer
even more badly now uh next one i'd get
we'll probably have a
a gtx 1080 right now i got a 770
and i think that 1080 is supposed to be
like twice as powerful
from what i've seen online
and when i make fun of macintosh guys
i'm coming from an ignorant viewpoint
don't take it
seriously i've like never used a mac
before
all right so this is a friendly jab
yeah this one's this one's pretty good i
like this one too
oh i don't know about you guys but like
when i shut off the shaders here
it takes my eyes a little while to
adjust to it like this looks so weird to
me now even though this is what i'm used
to
am i crazy or is is there something
different about this
like everything looks a lot more pale to
me now
i'm sure the grass was greener before
i'm not sure uh-huh but anyways we're
going to take a break from the shaders
uh we're going to start checking out
some of the texture packs i picked about
i picked out about 10 of them uh tried
to pick the more popular ones that
that i thought looked pretty good so
resource packs there we go uh i think
first off here we're gonna check out the
faithful one because it's supposed to be
like the most true to vanilla just a
higher
detail oh it's incompatible are you sure
you want to load this resource pack
for newer version of minecraft it may no
longer work correctly well we'll try it
hopefully it's good oh
whoa okay
uh that made a bigger bigger difference
than i expected actually
so so yeah it tries to retain
the texture it's just a 32 by 32 instead
of 16 by 16.
so it has to fill in uh all these extra
pixels and it smooths out the
the textures idea i believe so the wood
looks pretty good there i like that a
lot
the grass looks a little crazy to me i'm
not sure why
oh yeah cobblestone and the gravel is a
lot more round looking
uh-huh you know i think the
i think i like the sandstone actually it
took me a while here i was just staring
at it it's like
now i i think i like it actually um
the smooth and the chiseled looks pretty
close to the original
sand seems to just have more speckles in
it right
there's something about like the hay
bales and
the planks i don't like like i think the
normal one looks better than it for some
reason it's almost like there's too much
noise
in the image or too much uh too much
detail somehow is
is making it not look as good to me but
let's head down to the man cave
i don't like these planks what is it
about these planks that i don't like i'm
not sure
or the grass i think the grass has more
fuzz in it too
oh look at that okay that's kind of cool
like the
oh oh they're disappearing
why are they disappearing well they did
look cool
uh that might be a glitch i'm not sure
the soul sand looks really cool
in the netherwarts i like it clay looks
pretty good quartz
there's definitely some positives i
don't like the brick though
i gotta say though guys this episode is
very weird for me to record
like very abnormal it's a little bit
outside my comfort zone
uh usually i have like a plan and we do
stuff and here i feel like i'm some kind
of snooty critic
it's like oh i like that block i don't
like that one i like that one i don't
like that one
but i don't know what else to say
because we're just looking at things
right
uh-huh all right let's keep going here
uh oh i keep forgetting how to do it
there it is resource pack
so that's the faithful texture pack uh
it definitely has some high points and
some low points i would say
i think i would prefer using vanilla
over that though just because it's what
i'm used to
let's see uh let's wait a bit before we
try b dubs let's see this one
triton 128 so this is a high
super high detailed one hopefully it
works and it's for 1.9
whoa
okay now this is this is pretty major
oh even the sound's different too
okay okay
i'm lost for words now i got nothing um
see this looks pretty well
i'm not sure like i love i love this
texture
but it doesn't work with this uh spruce
wood right like
you can build things but then when you
change texture packs it
it just doesn't work anymore because
it's
yeah like if i built something with this
texture pack it would probably look
really good
but to take an existing build none of
the blocks are going to really work
together like they do in vanilla
and i think that's a problem you have
with most texture packs
like this room this looks crazy
not that any of these are really bad
textures it just looks weird right
okay that's that's pretty fancy the
glowstone
i like that a lot
uh we got like droopy leaves hanging
down here
uh the water is nice and blue
uh-huh as we go through the texture
packs here let me know what you guys
like the most as well
um and if you like vanilla more
say you like vanilla more and then say
what what which of the texture packs do
you like
second to vanilla how about we do that
but the lava in this moves crazy quickly
um this one's interesting it's
definitely interesting
but we will we will try a new one here
should we go for b-dubs let's do b-dubs
i'm very excited about this one my pal
b-dubs
i am worried it's not going to work with
our existing builds but we will
see
oh hey actually you know that that
turned out better than i expected
um yeah i like the stone
stone looks good um our lamps here don't
really work though because they're
totally covered up with his uh
different trap doors but like
these work very well if you build with
them
um and let's see
yeah he's got like variations in the
grass
his water looks really good i do like
his water if there was one texture i
could change in the main game
it would be the water i hate the blue
water
like i really don't like it i keep
hoping like they changed the lava
texture
uh not super long ago they made it the
the cheese i keep hoping they'll do the
same with
the water they'll change it to something
better looking
that looks nice that's pretty good right
i like this one now i am a little bit
impartial on this one because b dubs is
my buddy
but i do actually think it looks good
right i think you did a good job on it
uh it actually works pretty well with
our existing build here even
except for uh like we got to find some
faults here
so the sandstone not really working
there's like smooth ones and then
there's uh
normal looking ones i don't know why
that is we should go look at
sandy city up above um
probably the highlights of his pack
though
would be the wood texture like the logs
look incredible and the water
those are my two favorites that i've
seen
yeah let's head upstairs here oh it's
night
um does he have a different sky i can't
remember i don't see a different sky
oh yeah that's so you have to build a
width
with these textures otherwise if you
take an existing build like our
our structure here or the actually
pretty much the whole city looks messed
up
i saw one episode of his where he talked
about the wheat texture here how it was
too bright
too neon yellow it could be he
he updated it for himself and not for
his his pack but man that is neon yellow
b-dubs
at least not my monitor so if you if
you've changed it already
you should change it again uh-huh or
update your pack
all right let's take a walk down the
road here
this is uh too gray i would say
otherwise uh looks pretty good
aha i like it all right let's keep
moving though we still got lots to go
through here
um that's that's high on my list though
we got john smith
let's do john smith all right here we go
this is a pretty pretty popular one i
think whoa we got some really droopy
leaves in this one
oh is it not supported most of these
actually look like normal
next normal textures except for the
grass is different
and the leaves
are the bushes different no torches are
different
i might have messed up with the john
smith it says legacy models so maybe
it's just like a model pack
i don't know i might not have grabbed
the right thing though
so we're going to try ozo craft here now
and
this one i believe is a 32 by 32
it looks kind of uh interesting
maybe we will uh talk objectively about
texture packs for a moment here so what
what i think they should all strive to
do
including the vanilla textures is you
want
you want textures that work well with
each other that kind of blend
blend together so for example the past
we had here was
three very similar textures
in the vanilla texture pack in this one
they're like all over the place
so we got like different textures uh
these two colors are about the same
textures are widely different this color
is different uh certain things
do work pretty good with this one like
the wood and the grass are nice together
the leaves the dirts
it's all good um then you got like weird
things like
the enter chest that's really out of
this world
the coarse fruits it's pretty strange
the stone looks nice in this one i think
it goes well with the
grass and the trees and stuff so here
for example like the sand and the
sandstone should work
nicely together and they look very very
different from each other i would say
so that would be
a no-no but certain things look nice in
this
for sure pumpkin patch resource pack
here we go
oh big leg oh
okay this one's whoa oh
i just pumping pumped in patch resource
pack he has a pumpkin on his head
makes sense so we got like autumn leaves
in this one that's a nice touch
oh it's footsteps it's like what is that
sound that's crazy
it's a really cool looking ender chest
i don't like this line is that
cobblestone
oh maybe they uh connect with each other
wait a second let's just try this
oh i had some mommy didn't need to
do that oh yeah they connected to
connect the textures that's interesting
aha all right this one's pretty cool
yeah the wheat looks very nice
there's crows so here we have this facts
128 texture pack
which uh looks looks fairly interesting
right most of the blocks work together
nicely
with each other and uh
actually doesn't look too bad with an
existing build
i really like the mushrooms in this one
oh clay
oh i did not expect that it's very wavy
very wavy clay it's not bad though
uh-huh instead of having like a sharp
border like you usually have with the
clay it kind of blends
from this this color to that one
interesting
yeah this is this is a neat one for sure
and it's a vector-based one so they have
it from like 16 pixels to 512
lots of options
all right so we're down to the final two
here guys next up is sensecraft
and this is a wild one oh man
i really like the grass in this one like
this this texture here
i think it looks pretty amazing uh but
the dirt and the
the planks and stuff a little bit on the
odd side
let's see a bigger room with them
yeah it's a it's a very
out there one the stone like has
horizontal lines in
uh clay the clay looks very nice
actually i like the clay
and quartz is the quartz difference
uh i think it's the same actually oh
mushrooms are are all one color that's
not bad it's different
uh yeah i don't like the planks in this
one
that's a nice stone brick though i do
like that
all right final one guys this one i'm
actually looking forward to i saw the
the picture of it is like whoa this is a
really out
out there one two we'll see
all right here we go final one excalibur
oh did it actually darken the screen
oh this is like a very rustic
uh very rustic very
um bold i don't know
i got no words guys i'm out of it i've i
don't know how to comment on texture
packs
um it's nice though i like this one it's
very unique it's got a very strong sense
of style
right nice water very nice water and
plant life in this one
lava not i don't like that kind of lava
really but it does go well with the
existing blocks
how's wilson looking oh the quartz
actually is a brick all right
clay oh i don't know about doing that
for the clay the clay has lines in it
that's a weird choice
yeah so certain builds you like existing
builds are not going to look right with
this one
but like look at this this looks very
nice this room here
for sure i like the stone
oh nice sound effects dude that was a
good one
whoa oh you know what
this is meant more as a roofing material
i bet that looks like a clay shingle
ah that makes sense okay
oh the leaves are different here because
it's a desert
they're like a red
aha i like this one a lot though i gotta
say
it's among my favorites oh
yeah oh
man i wanted to check this one out with
shaders
and it's actually very nice
like even underground like i did not
like underground at all
with the vanilla texture pack with this
one it's not
it's not too bad uh and above ground i
just i just peeked here for a second it
looked pretty good
pretty good even the sandstone on our
castle wall here is looking nice
let's get a daytime view here uh we're
out of food
and all the all the items in my chests
are gone because we downgraded so we're
we're gonna have to wrap up here
rotten flesh now we're gonna head back
to our real world in just a second for
the comment of the
oh day like the sounds in this one
that could get annoying though while
flying i gotta say
all right i just want to check out uh
this area here too
more of a nature look
oh yeah
very pronounced manly manly screams
yeah this one's nice i do like this one
a lot
all right everyone so hopefully you
enjoyed today's oddball
episode uh we are back in our real world
now back
on the snapshot 16w39c all our animals
and villagers are back
just the way we left it here and one
last way we could see the world
differently
uh that we never do is lower the
brightness
get it nice and moody in here how about
that to finish up here
i got a comment picked out for the
episode it says
etho have you considered using the
second hand for practical purposes
like putting your food there or torches
or blocks
or even putting there your sword slash
other tools and pressing the switch
hands button to switch between
it could be interesting and useful for
some players who don't know the uses of
it
and could make you gain some time on
building eating collecting
being etho so
i've really wanted to use the second
hand
maybe i haven't tried hard enough i
don't know but i haven't found it useful
could just be me like do you guys do any
of you find it useful
i don't know to me it's just as quick to
use your hotkeys like the numbers on
your keyboard
to pick what you want um
but to switch between my tools here is
no problem at all
i played a game called worms armageddon
a lot though and in that you had to
very quickly switch between your weapons
and i'm just used to like
going through my number keys here like
like no problem at all
and then you got the scroll wheel on the
mouse if you're just moving one item
it's very easy to scroll between things
or
like if you're building i just can't see
the second hand being useful
because you can use the pick block with
your middle click
so if i need grass i just middle click
on grass and you got it
or you know it's just so easy to
just middle click things i don't know
have you
have any of you guys found it useful
maybe
i just haven't tried hard enough to
learn but so far
just doing it the normal way works
pretty good for me
all right guys well hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode thank you for
watching we'll be back to normal in the
next one and
until then take care bye bye