hello how's it going everybody thank you
for joining me once again today doesn't
that look cool like especially over
there so many waterfalls and stuff this
is an oasis in the middle of my deserts
I almost hit the lava and it looks
pretty incredible I gotta say uh-huh
all you guys missing alpha generation
switch over to amplified because it is
pretty cool some of the stuff you see
but yeah we're actually in the middle of
the desert right now if we go over here
you know what we're gonna see Wow that
is my amplified border over here and the
reason we're out here is because I was
looking for some of this dye rights
nowhere in my world do I have died right
so I had to go to new terrain
I even and our amplified bass there's
none there so I pretty much have to go
somewhere new to find it just sit yeah
okay to give you a reference so we're
actually pretty close to the main base
the library is about 300 blocks or so
that way so it's not too far oh yeah and
let me show you the difference in
generation here - real quick so in my
world I have like four or five different
periods of terrain generation we have
this old stuff here the desert this is a
good view of it all well actually no
because I think jungles came out then
and I got chunk borders from the jungle
biome then later we got the terrain
update with the mega taiga and and that
kind of stuff and that's what this is
here and then I switch my world to
amplified and then later even after that
we got the new 1.8 blocks to die right
and stuff so at the amplified base I got
none of these new blocks I had to come
here to get it but anyway I'm rambling I
am rambling I'm going to be doing some
speed mining over here to get the die
rights
let's go down I just set up the beacon
again over here and I guess I want to
dig to the rights to get it so I'm going
to get some of this and then we will
probably go do a little bit of building
on the Nexus just to start off with okay
I just started digging getting the die
rights there's there's quite a few
patches down here it's good slowly we're
getting it but I was digging and I Ellis
all of a sudden fell down this one by
one hole here and I couldn't believe it
this is like the smallest mineshaft I
have ever seen we got this this section
here and this and then it dead-ends is
it that crazy I wonder if there's
anything behind the walls that I'm just
not seeing because sometimes they do
that but usually it's gravel now I think
that's it I think that's actually it huh
Oh stupid granite okay guys so we're
going to do something a little different
today usually at the end of my episodes
I answer answer your questions or reply
to your comments I want to ask you guys
a question at the start of the episode
you see I inversed it so I am wondering
is there anything like really cool you
guys are doing in Minecraft is there
anything unique and fun that you don't
think a lot of people know about like
I'm going to give the example of the
five boys server okay so if you if
you've watched that you've seen us
playing around with the custom NPC mod
now I watch a lot of Minecraft videos
like hundreds and hundreds of them and I
have never once ever heard of this mod
before and that
it's like the awesomest thing and and
I'm wondering what other stuff am I
missing out on in the Minecraft world
because there's thousands and thousands
of people playing this game I'm sure
there's these cool mods I haven't heard
about maybe you guys have a server
you're playing on that's really cool
maybe with some fun meta game to it you
know let me know if you think you have a
good idea for for something fun or if
there's something I might be missing out
on let me know in the comments that's
that's my comment for you for today all
right all right cool so we pretty much
have our floor in now at the Nexus we
have the prisoner ian the sea lanterns
the dye right on the sides we are just
missing all the courts and I keep
putting it off you know I hate mining
courts in this game it's one of my least
favorite things to do and I think I'm
going to put it off another episode just
one more I'll try to do it next time but
yeah so I did realize we're going to
have a problem here though with this
upstairs design because totally forgot
there's actually some redstone in the
front like underneath here in front of
the droppers which in relation to this
lets us go up and check that I think
it's visible though that spot yeah these
are the droppers here so one block in
front like like these blocks here need
to be changed it'll be close so it'll
almost work we might just need to block
out like the spot with something I don't
we'll see but it's coming along so I
think we're going to do a technical
project next there's one I've had in
mind for a long time at the potion lab
here I want to set up a way of sending
potions to the nether on a storage
minecart type of deal no we can't put it
there that's not going to work what
about behind here that might work ah we
might be able to make it work so
basically drop off potions
and then I want them to get carted to
the to a portal so we got to first
figure out something
is it possible to let's see where should
we put this or so much stuff down here
I'm just going to set up temporarily
over here yeah this is going to be a
little tough to work down here there's
not a lot of space but basically I want
to see if we can get the storage my cart
to go into the nether and then go right
on a track on its own I don't know if
that is possible I feel like we've tried
this in the past and I can't remember um
anyway we'll light this okay so this
side doesn't matter so much so we'll
just have some rails to send a cart
through the other side though is where
we want to probably slope the track down
and to see if it'll go on it alright
that takes us to here I did write down
the coordinates of the lab so I'll try
set up a portal around there and then we
can we can experiment with it okay so it
turns out that potion lab coordinates
translate to over here in the nether so
if we build something we'll put it
behind the wall here but we're going to
see first off let's just use some power
rails and make it slope like this and I
want to see if the storage minecart will
stick to the track here when it goes
through the portal or if it's just going
to sit on these portal blocks because
I'm not too sure what it does so yeah
we'll just get some redstone power go
into them and I will light it should be
able to light it still all right and
then we'll push the minecart through
okay I'm gonna push the minecart in but
we're not going to go through this
portal because I don't want to
accidentally nudge it so I'll go through
a different way here to check on it okay
hopefully we don't connect to that
portal we're pretty far away now this is
out by the library
all right and good we went through a
different one let's go to that portal
now and just see where the minecart
ended up this way I always get lost um
should be to the right here right yeah
okay oh yeah so it ended up on the track
that's cool um that means like I did Oh
unless the villager nudged it darn it
stupid villager you wrecked the test
possibly we're gonna assume it worked
though I'm going to start setting
setting this up so behind the wall over
here we will set up a track and I guess
for now just connect it to this track
this goes out to the wither skeleton
farm so if I ever want to move potions
to there in bulk we can do that pretty
easily now which I do want to do because
I always bring fire resistant potions
and and speed potions that kind of stuff
there manually so this will be nice ah
yep I got stuck in the the creeper face
there the lava that I managed to ender
pearl rollouts but did not survive the
fire alright I got my stuff back
everything's good so this is how we're
going to do it we have the nether work
farm stuff back here we have potion lab
stuff behind here so I decided to put it
in over here instead an idea is I'll hit
a button that will dispense a storage
minecart we fill it up with potions then
we just jump up to nudge it when we're
ready to go and that will take it to the
nether I just will go there hopefully we
can get back I think we can all right
then it goes to this this rail oh did it
get stuck oh that scared me this guy got
in the way I guess I hope alright anyway
it goes to this and then
goes this way so that's that's how
that's working um
this will take this back oh that was
interesting wait a minute the items
didn't go through the portal there did
they oh maybe they did they go to a
different portal we didn't get them when
we went through I don't think what oh
maybe we did yeah we must have all right
anyway so the next plan here I don't
want this portal running all the time
because it's kind of annoying so we're
going to disable this and I put in a
detector rail here so what we'll do is
have a dispenser here with flint and
steel in when it goes over this it will
just send a pulse to that okay this
doesn't have to be pretty because we're
not going to be able to see it and then
right after that we want to shut it off
so we'll have a another dispenser with a
water bucket and I think over here and
we just need a little bit of delay for
the minecart to get through nothing too
major this will go up and around okay
but we got to do a double pulse er here
and if I remember right as you I'll do
it off camera I don't want to I don't
want to waste your time this seems to
work here basically does that so portal
stays open for just a little bit of time
for the minecart to go through again an
8 tick delay here then it goes to a
sticky piston underneath this block with
a 1 tick to that and then a 3 tick so
there's a two tick between that for the
water to go out and in but anyway let's
let this dry here so storage minecart
will go down
beautiful that way the portal does have
to stay on all the time in an OS which
is what we want or don't want whichever
is correct there anyway so I'm going to
put some red clay here so can't see all
the stone and it should be good cool so
now that we got that set up we're going
to use it for the first time here for
real I want to send a batch of fire
resistant potions to the wither skeleton
farm and I'll probably go check and make
sure they get there too I kind of wonder
what happens also if we if we send two
of these at once so we'll probably try
that it looks like that went no problem
the other issue though is we got the
zombie pigmen on the the tracks a lot of
the time so that might cause some
problems
let's try send some speed potions there
too I guess
slowness oh that shouldn't be there
doesn't give you a potion effect okay I
was wondering um so swiftness for the
horse okay and there we go so I'm going
to go to the nether now and just check
out what happened
Oh
that's not good okay they would have
made it but looks like the tract is out
here did I bring any with me no I'll
have to fix that okay but it works so
I've been trying to think of what to do
next year and maybe we will do a little
bit more biome enhancement I've been
seeing a lot of comments asking for that
lately so it's been a while let's let's
just do a little bit so this area where
we are right now I kind of wanted to
have a bunch of trees and we built this
one this custom tree here the problem is
this took me like 30 minutes to do and
you know if he gets 10 trees that's 300
minutes so I'm wondering if we could
speed that up if we maybe pay a little
less attention to detail so what we're
going to try is grow a dark oak tree and
then maybe add a bit to it but not like
build it totally from scratch so let's
just put another one over here okay and
I also kind of want them to be a bit
tall so I'm going to start it a little
bit higher and just see if we can make
this work somehow because that would be
awesome Oh what was I expecting to
happen there I don't know okay
so I'm going to build it down to the
ground and we'll just see how much work
that needs to to make it look cool I
wish there was more tree shapes built
into the game so that you could you know
have a little bit more option with it
okay so let's take a step back that's
about the height I want but I want it to
look like that yeah it needs a lot of
work doesn't it so we got to bulk up
around the bottom a lot may be able to
spam wood and see what happens
the goal here is to try to do it quickly
and I don't know if that's possible
actually you know what this one's is
starting out so bad already I think we
will skip it we'll burn it down we're
going to try again this time I'm going
to put a little more thought into the
structure and not spam the wood so much
because that didn't work out so well so
again same thing like yeah I don't know
it's you kind of have to get lucky I
feel when you make a tree to it
it either goes well or a doesn't and
that time it did not go well okay okay
this one's turning out quite a bit
better we're probably at five minutes
into building it next thing I'm going to
do is start trimming these extra pieces
of wood that come with the natural tree
when you grow it and then I'm going to
start bulking up the leaves there and
also it's a little bit flat part way up
so I think we'll add some whoa okay
where was that did I have a beacon here
at one time whoa and somehow I fell down
there without the grabbing ladder I
think I was in so much shock I just
couldn't press the keys oh I know what
this is okay we did a thing here a long
time ago when I was experimenting with
our unloaded chunks work uh-huh okay
this was a proximity detector thing that
we made a long time ago man well good
thing I set my spawn here anyway I'm
going to bulk up the tree and maybe add
some branches partway up there
well you know it didn't turn out too too
bad I don't think right there's still
some stuff I don't like like that's way
too flat there and yeah so there's a
couple things that bug me about it but
the problem is it still took like 20 25
minutes which isn't good the thing that
takes the longest is the the canopy it
turns out so I have one more strategy I
want to try here we'll build another one
here okay so the tree canopy new plan
yeah again let's do it about here we
will have not one not two but we're
going to try three trees grown kind of
close together let's put another one
here and hopefully that makes a decent
sized tree canopy and if we do it at
slightly different heights and and not
really in a straight line it should look
pretty organic I think so we'll have
another one there let's put the other
one maybe here feels like a good offset
alright let's put this one I will put it
level with that one because the tree is
going to grow slightly different too
sometimes they're different heights I
mean okay ooh that's not a tree that's a
tree oh we got a sapling from that that
was lucky okay do that this might be
amazing if it works it might be but it
might not turn out at all we'll see okay
so we do that let's just take a look at
the tree canopy um it's pretty messy
like I'm expecting I'll have to add to
it still but it does cover a much better
area so now I'm going to remove these
trunks and I'm going to grow another
tree right in the middle and start
bulking it up again hopefully that's
quicker we will see so this one took
about 15 to 20 minutes it's a fair bit
rougher there's some flat spots on it
and stuff but it's not too too bad I
don't think so it's a little bit quicker
than that method we use there but not
quite as polished whoop
but still you know 15 20 minutes that's
that's a lot of time for a single tree
so having a lot of these custom trees
might be difficult to pull off like I
wanted so maybe we'll just have a few
standard around the other thing I was
curious about you know on the survival
of the fittest map how they have the
stone scattered kind of randomly all
over the place I think that looks pretty
cool actually have like boulders and
stuff I think I want to try add some of
that on the ground okay I just did a
little sample here I want to see what
you guys think about it before I do more
so let me know I think maybe I put a
little too much down though it might be
too dense anyway that is just an idea
you need like it's some random stuff
scattered throughout here I think to
make it more interesting so I probably
want to add some flowers and stuff as
well maybe some random leaves and debris
that kind of stuff maybe some paths yeah
alright everybody so let's wrap up this
episode for today so that you can get on
with doing your homework sucks to be you
oh yeah no no homework
we're just fun yeah I'm I'm envious
oh hey etho I was just curious but do
you plan on doing LPS of other games
I love pixel piracy and terraria is easy
just as much as all your other series
thanks umm so might play
sorry again if there's a major updates
pixel piracy probably not but I am
planning on playing don't starve again
that's probably my next thing and I know
I've said that in the past but I'm
actually seriously planning on recording
it now as soon as I get some free time
um I'm also very tempted to release a
hearthstone video I don't know if there
would be any interest in that but the
expansion came out I got to buy a bunch
of packs and and maybe do an arena run I
don't know probably is a one-off video
though um yeah probably some new series
coming out soon
anyway that is it for today guys thank
you for watching I'll see you in the
next one bye bye