[Music]
hey what's up everybody
this is etho and today guys this is it
you know
this is it this is the moment are you
ready for it
you know all those trials and
tribulations you have faced in your life
have all been to lead you to this one
moment the greatest
moment of all our lives really
you know in the future you might get
married you might
you might have children you know you
might get a promotion
on all of those days you're gonna think
back to this video and how this was the
greatest day of your life and how those
accomplishments mean nothing to you
compared to this
this great day where we
try to get the nexus up and running
all right guys we're gonna do it today
i'm really determined
i'm gonna try so hard to finish this
thing
okay so what where are we at with it
um first thing we got to do is move this
control panel over because it's in the
way of the wiring we
we need to do here so uh what i like to
do in minecraft if i ever have to
copy something especially in cases like
this where i'm destroying the original
because i gotta rebuild this somewhere
else and we gotta break it
right so since i don't know where the
future version is going until i actually
build
some other stuff here i'm going to look
it over
on video here and then i can reference
the video
if i need to see how i did the wiring
later because it's actually really
complicated
and i want to look all around it here
okay i also made a backup of my world
though just in case this video isn't
good enough for me
yeah i think i've seen everything so we
can safely tear this out i hope
i really hope or i'm going to facepalm
facepalm desk desk palm my face
or something i don't know um
okay we're going to tear this thing out
what we got to build in its place
or next next in our wiring chain here
i can't pick anything up man
my precious redstone get into me my
precious redstone
don't you despawn on me okay i think
we're good
well we gotta build in its place when we
press these buttons
on the nexus every time we press it it
makes
four wires light up and before we were
using eight levers
to control what item we get from that so
the first time we press it it's gonna
light up four wires the second time we
press it
it's going to light up four other wires
and we have to save
that into memory using something like
this i was just trying to
figure out how i want to do it here so
let's say we press a button over there
and it makes these two wires light up
right
in order to save it into memory what i'm
going to do is just have locking
repeaters
and press the button the repeaters get
unlocked and then locked again
and then the buttons gonna unpress and
these will
get unpowered but it'll still save uh
what button or what signal we got from
that button press
using the locking repeaters right okay
perfect
so as you can imagine some time has
passed here
i have been working on building the head
of the beast here
head of the nexus got it all hooked up
to our control panel
and i'm about to test it out but let's
just take a moment
let's let's look at this look how
beautiful it is you know
on that day when you marry your wife
in the future and you're reflecting on
how beautiful
she is you're gonna think to yourself
she is
nothing compared to how beautiful the
wiring was
on this great day we are experiencing
here together
yes okay well
the memory unit is up there and let's go
check that out first
okay gotta pillar up getting very good
at redstone parkour here
you wouldn't believe it so uh
let me let me just make a button maybe
we'll put it on this thing
so we have four locking repeaters down
there and four
up here and there's a piston here which
switches between the top and the bottom
memory
um so when we press wait actually
just a second there's a piston under
there that doesn't work
let's put the button over here so i send
a one tick pulse to this piston
and
because it's a one tick pulse it leaves
the block behind when it retracts
and when we do this
that happens more than i would like to
admit
that was not so smooth i am getting
oh i did it again what
what okay now i've
i feel bad i have to go back to redstone
parkour class
okay so these have a slight delay from
when this piston moves
and if we watch
just a second this is a mess let me let
me put this on the other side so we can
see a little bit better
all right so if you if you watch these
locking repeaters you
see how they're all locked right now if
we press this
that bottom row unpowered for a second
and now now it didn't but the top one
did so it alternates between the top and
the bottom
and when it releases that lock it allows
it to accept the new signal and it
clears the previous
memory it had for those four wires on
each row
okay makes sense yes so we have eight
wires in total
and they run down to all these these
bits we have down here
which control where the signal goes
which dropper we activate
to request an item out of our nexus
storage room
and yes there's a lot of wiring
i want to maybe today we'll load up our
world here in mcedit i just want to see
how much like redstone i've placed
in this project how much stone brick and
all that stuff i'm curious on the
statistics because it is such a big
build
all done in survival here um
okay so what i got to do now next step
of this we got to do some testing just
to make sure i didn't make any mistakes
with this because
one little tiny let me sleep please
one little tiny slip up can wreck the
whole thing so we gotta
maybe test each unit one by one here
here i thought i'd show you guys this
too before we do this just to help you
visualize what what we're checking
uh so when we press the zero button
like out of the 16 buttons you see how
we got the numbers here for the buttons
uh when we press zero it should be off
off off off when we press one it should
be on off off off
two off on off off
three on on off off and i just gotta
double check that those
buttons correspond to that pattern that
we got set out here
if it doesn't we have a problem and it's
better we catch it
catch it now before we like cover
everything up and
find out later some things aren't
working and we don't know why
we want to test things out individually
here so it's easier to spot the problems
so we're just making sure these buttons
work correctly
and the reason by the way we're doing
this memory thing is because if we
didn't do that
we have 16 buttons here and if you go
2 times 2 times 2 times 2 you get 16
but we need 256 possibilities so you
actually need
another set of buttons another 16
buttons besides this one
and rather than doing that we just save
one of the button presses into memory
and then the second one so we only need
16 instead of 32 buttons
yes okay i'm making this more
complicated than i probably should
but anyways that's what this episode's
all about though right
getting the nexus going here so if we
look at these locking repeaters when we
press
zero here this is the sign to help us
remember which
which button is what zero is the top
left
so it should be off off off off and i'm
going to hit it twice here just so it
applies to top and bottom memory
all right so if we look at those locking
repeaters it's off off
off off good if we press one
again we'll press it twice just so it's
less confusing
it's on off off off good just like the
pattern should be
uh two should be off on
off off
did i not press the twice i don't think
i did
there we go off on off off good
and on on off off
again i didn't press it twice
on off off and you get the idea so i'm
just going to go through all the buttons
here and make sure i did this correctly
all right it's very good so i just went
through all the buttons and tried them
all out
looking for for any mistakes on my parts
and turns out there was a couple so
this green wire wasn't working properly
something with a delay issue so i got
that fixed
everything is working perfect now i also
hooked up this lever here so we can
request items
that lever i had to sneak it through
and it connects up to this clock here so
if we follow this
this wire down it will eventually lead
to a single
dropper in our nexus storage room that
that we're gonna get the item
from okay and that's probably going to
cause quite a bit of lag when we're
requesting items i'm very curious how
laggy this whole thing is going to be
when we get it going here
uh so as it stands the redstone is done
the basic redstone anyways we will be
adding
more cool stuff later to spice this
thing up a bit
but redstone is done
uh nexus is functioning the only problem
is
we actually have no items in it to try
it out
and we don't have our our request
ice stream finished and to put items in
we we got that finished except
it's not fully implemented so it's not
finished
yes anyways so
this is what we need here these oh let's
get a little closer
this is where the items come from you
see the droppers over there over there
it shoots into the ice goes up in the
water stream and flows this way
we want to get them all collected to a
central location
and delivered to us so i'm not really
sure
how we're gonna do this yet oh actually
you know what
uh oh i have it so
items will fall down here from the input
so we can't put ice there it won't be
able to do that
because it falls from that top stream
down to here
we can't block that way
wait when i
oh man what's this i got the water going
the wrong way even
who's the idiot that worked on this
before me it's supposed to flow towards
me here not
not away from me okay this one we can go
out however we want
um yikes
it's gonna be a little tricky basically
we gotta pick a spot that's open where
we can just drop an item down so it's
gonna like slide off the edge here and
fall down somewhere
we gotta find somewhere where there's no
redstone wiring
for each of these
all right so that's another one kind of
done oh that melted instantly didn't it
i have to be very careful when i break
anything by
water because i can no
no no no
because i can do that was it just one
piece that washed away oh i got so lucky
there
oh that was almost
chernobyl disaster level over there
holy okay we're good we're good i can
fix that let's go back
up yeah i gotta be really careful when i
work around water
in the nexus it's like all
all of our hard work can get can get
washed away you know that disappointment
you're gonna you're gonna feel with your
future kids when they
when they let you down
well it's probably gonna happen
i i was trying to think of how we can
compare it to the nexus here but uh
we can't be disappointed with the nexus
honestly just just your kids
your future kids if you don't have any
right now
um let's see
that one's good uh above there it's
gonna fall down to here so we're gonna
have another
water stream going this way towards the
middle
and let's see let's work this one out
next
i want to tell you guys something uh
about my computer here i'm having a
little bit of computer
trouble and it's i'm not really sure
what to do about it
uh i've always wanted to get a solid
state drive
on my computer because solid state
drives they're amazing things
things load quickly they save quickly
you put windows on it your computer
boots up super fast
and everything just runs really smoothly
so i've always wanted one
but oops but was too lazy to put one in
myself so this computer i bought
uh most recently it actually came with a
solid-state drive with windows on it and
i was so excited
and so happy uh it's a 100 gig drive and
then i got a three terabyte
hard drive besides like just a regular
hard drive
um as it turns out i really don't like
having
solid state drives though because
right away i realized like windows just
the basic installation took up
i think 60 gigs out of the 100 like when
i first got it it's like okay
well i guess i can't put anything else
on it there's a creeper over there
so all my games and stuff i've installed
onto my other
three terabyte drive everything's been
fine except
over time here just because like
computers
constantly get more and more garbage on
them over time
um it's gotten to the point where i only
have one gig free
on my solid state drive like the
important drive with windows on
and like i don't know what's gonna
happen if it ever fills up
entirely because you have big trouble
with your computer if you run out of
hard drive space
and it i don't know what i can delete on
it though it's just like little scrub
files all over the place
and i'm not oh let's put the sign here
this time i'm not really sure
how to free up any more space because
i've i've taken all the big files off so
i don't know not too happy about the
solid state drive at the moment
just because it's filled up and it's
continuing to fill up and
i don't know what to remove
all right like if there was a big like
four dig movie on it or something
sure just delete that but it's not that
it's all these little files
scattered around okay that's good
got two left to do here
okay guys so we got all eight of those
water streams in place
built in place and now we have to merge
them together so i'm making the items
drop
down here and
water is going to push them all to this
central channel
like so let's see let's put another sign
over here
and water further so they're all going
to meet in the middle now
so we got to run this ice all the way
and then in the middle i think this is
the middle here yes
so at the middle here we're going to
build an item elevator that will bring
the items from the nexus up here
and where does this where does this go
on the surface
take your guesses
at the control panel yeah so the items
are gonna pop
up through the floor here uh i was
decide
or i was trying to decide do i want
items to go into a chest or do i want
to pop up out of the ground somewhere
for right now we're going to make them
just pop
out of the ground the reason we're not
making them
go into a chest is because we would have
to use hoppers to do that
and hoppers have a a speed limit to them
of one item every
four redstone ticks right have i not
lost it i think that's what it is
while our nexus here is gonna have a
speed of one item every two redstone
ticks
so it's not gonna be able to keep up
which is why i'm sort of leaning away
from that
right now but we might add it later i'm
not sure
all right so this is coming along
i'm really trying to hurry here because
i've spent two days on this now
and it's late at night and i
don't know i want i set a goal of
getting the nexus done today
but you know it's also good to have
reasonable goals i'm going to keep
trying though
we'll see if we can do it guys
you know what actually you know what the
big thing is that's that's really
making me sad right now that water
that's reversed let's go look at that
for a second
because i don't know how to fix it
without wrecking the wiring
let's see this is like the worst thing
i've done
all right let's sleep really quick so
when i place the water in here some of
them i put reverse
for some reason don't ask me why don't
ask me what i was thinking
where's where's an example we saw one
earlier
um i think that one there was wrong
right
let's go check that one out if we can
get to it
so yeah it was this one i took a thing
of water out i don't know how i'm gonna
replace this water in here like
we gotta turn all these water streams
around so instead of starting
there it's gonna start there and go that
way
uh but it's sealed up pretty tight in
there
maybe man i really don't want to wreck
anything here
i think we can do this we'll just take
out all the middles i'm trying very
very carefully here not direct anything
yeah if we do this this will work okay
i guess that's all i'll have to do it
and then i'll just bust out this one
at the sign and then place it in
and then put the glass back
yeah okay we're good okay so i think we
got our item
merger all complete here as well let's
try it out
just to make sure so i'm going to throw
a torch against the wall here
just to see what it does yeah it goes up
the item elevator there good
so his middle's a bit a bit weird
i wanted to go through here as quick as
possible because
any hang up is gonna delay how long it
takes us to get our items
see like that that's not so good like it
did you see what it did there it bounced
two blocks over here like up to here and
then it
went back and then i wonder how we could
do this a little bit faster
if you have ideas let me know uh we'll
leave it like that for today though
let's let's move on with more important
things
um might go through all this stuff later
and fine-tune it
i know some redstone could be done a
little bit more efficiently in places
that kind of stuff but for now we're
just trying to get it working
okay and we got the water streams fixed
that's all good so item delivery is
complete
pretty sure let's just double check
let's try
that was a bad throw let's just throw
um or here let's do it like this let's
actually use a dropper i'm gonna put my
bucket in here and we'll see if it ends
up where it's supposed to go
when this is triggered so you see the
bucket fly up
there okay and let's just go see if it's
by the control panel because that's
where it's supposed to end up
woohoo parkour let's go sleep
and it's not there yet that's quite a
delay if it's not there yet
probably shouldn't have slept oh it is
there oh you know what it is i never
built the glass up all the way
so it might have been there already so
another really important thing we got to
take care of today guys
is the item in inputs like if we want to
drop stuff off
into storage uh we need somewhere to do
that
in the control room here there probably
be several ways of doing it like
minecarts
drop-offs and that kind of stuff from
farms and
and and whatever but we'll also want
like manual like hey i got
36 stone bricks i don't want so i'll put
them in the chest
and we'll use a trap chest so that it'll
stay in there until we close it
in case we change our mind and pick it
up
so it'll go down with hoppers here
and we want to build i'll pick up that
redstone don't you worry
we want to build one of these an item
buffer thing
like this so if there's items in a
dropper it'll
slowly very slowly shoot them out
if you do it too quickly hoppers can
pick up full stacks of items at a time
is the thing if you do that if we have
items entering our storage
that quickly it's going to mess up all
our item filters
these things over here so like if we get
a full stack of oaks wood slabs in here
then the item filter breaks and
gg gotta redo them all and i will
hate myself because that is not a not a
fun thing to redo
so let's build one of these down here
and
then we also have to connect it up to
where is it i think up over here yeah
this is the start of the input so we got
to build like a item elevator to bring
items up to this water stream
and then they'll pass by all the the
item filters and go into storage and
then we pretty much got everything taken
care of here
oh wait a second wait a second
let's work on the item elevator right
now that has to be glass beside here
this fence can attach
to the sides right i think that's right
okay so build this up very good
so items are going to flow up here and
we might make adjustments to all this
stuff
later if we find it's in the way of
something but uh
items will pop up here let's make sure
it gets aligned against these ender
chests
that looks good so it made its way down
the hoppers there and get picked up
somewhere where it belongs
uh let's get some water going to this
i ran out of packed ice and i'm too lazy
to go get some more today
so we're using regular ice here and
we'll
possibly switch it out later
if we need to all right
is that enough please make it oh we're
one block short are you kidding
one block shorts should i just do a
double
is that gonna make it if we do a double
yeah it should be fine well if we do
that we don't need one here
okay cool so
let's try this out make sure our item
input works we'll put
in maybe some stone brick here
yeah okay we'll put the stone brick in
so we got the
the shooter thing down here
and it just shoots it randomly but it
goes around a bend here so it aligns it
against one of the walls
over here so it gets put against this
wall has to be against the wall to go up
the item elevator there
and it looks like it's going okay going
at a good pace
let's just check up here make sure it's
not flying out anywhere they are not
making it up here where are they getting
stuck
right there
uh-huh is it hollow there oh wow it's
hollow there
you know that's the problem with this
glass it's so clear
sometimes you can't see if you put it
where you thought you put it
let's put a few more in real quick here
just double check this works
and the last thing to do after this is
just to put items into the nexus
uh so that we can actually call
something else
yeah it's looking good gets aligned
against the ender chest
a little bit of bunch up there are they
getting bunched up
i'm seeing two of them together at times
but that should be fine because uh even
if like it's only if like four or five
go into hopper at once that i think
there's trouble
should be fine if it's like two i think
i hope well
i think this is it guys i just realized
um building wise those are probably the
last blocks we had to place for this
thing to be counted as functioning
we just have to put items in which is
what the nexus
is for right so i think it's done
functioning anyway look at it it's not
it's not complete it's not a finished
project uh it's a mess we gotta
pretty it up we gotta add extra
functions that kind of stuff to it
but it is a big step today we are going
to do a ribbon cutting ceremony like i
said so we got our beautiful
dirt ribbon here to honor this day
to commemorate this wonderful build
and maybe i should say a few words
before we do this
this is truly a great and wonderful day
for everyone here in attendance um
you know when you're when you're feeling
down
when you lose your job when your
children disappoint
you and your your wife is
mad at you you can you can be happy
because you
you were here you were a part of this
your life
has meaning thanks to this wonderful
nexus project it is truly
the greatest thing any man or woman or
child
shall ever experience and
yada yada yada i was never great at
speeches so let's get this show
on the road shall we chop
all right ribbon down uh what i'm gonna
do
i think the best plan to get this thing
going
i'm just going to drop off all my items
into a chest here
did i make it i placed it already yes
let's drop off all our junk in here
and remember when we were organizing
this place
i brought over one of every type of item
in the game pretty much and i still have
them here in these
chests we're going to just pick these up
drop them into the nexus i made a backup
just in case something
terrible goes wrong here and i have to
redo this
but uh they should automatically go
where they belong in the nexus
and then when we request an item
we can just enter the code
and whatever item we get we can we can
give it that code
like when we name it in an anvil
um and put it in these chests here
that way everything works out perfect
i don't know we will see how this goes
let's just drop off a whole bunch of
stuff this is actually going to take
probably too long to do though today
maybe we'll just do one batch here and
see if we can request any of them
all right so that's gonna go for a long
time probably
it's the fences let's see if we can spot
where they're going in
it's probably not going to happen is it
this place is too big to really
follow whoa um
if i remember right that that stuff
ends up over here though a lot of those
items at least the wood
was on this row so we should eventually
see the items whiz by here i'm
pretty sure
but it will probably take a little bit
of time to get all the way over here
i'm not too worried about how long it
takes items to go into the storage room
i'm more concerned with how long it
takes to get them out
when we actually need something we don't
want to be waiting
far i haven't seen a single item go by
which has me a bit worried
oh wait a second wait a second
um let me grab some more dirt here i see
the items falling
here
what no
oh i guess that does make sense darn it
okay i made a boo-boo uh
that's a big problem i gotta clean this
up now
we didn't get very many items though
what happened to the rest of them
they they might have went into storage
or else they despawned but i don't think
that much time has passed
uh what i got to do is cut a hole there
and maybe redo some of this
we need this block gone
so cool items are just whizzing by
non-stop
going where they belong i hope
oh and i just trapped myself you know
what stinks about dropping off all your
items is you
can't get around anymore oh
no no no no no no
how
oh the item elevator is totally messed
up because i didn't put a block there
that explains where most items were
going
i was wondering
because of two blocks were missing here
and
where else is it missing
disaster guys we're having issues we
will fix
it but uh why is it still leaking out
we don't need to put blocks here do we
this item elevator was a fail big time
all right well it looks like we got a
couple problems with our system here
guys i'm going to try work those out
and put the items in next episode we
will
hopefully see this thing didn't go as
smoothly as i hoped unfortunately but it
is very late here
and the episode is getting pretty long
so i think we should call it
and i've been recording this over two
days two full days and you guys are
waiting for episodes and i'm not posting
anything
so we gotta
we gotta call our limits every so often
all right so i got two comments picked
out for today it says etho
you should have an oasis in the deserts
desserts no desert that's desert
uh yes i like that idea very simple idea
but
we're trying to do the biome enhancement
thing with like sandy city and all that
stuff
and outside of sandy city there's still
a little bit of deserts
uh that has been untouched maybe we
could put uh
an oasis somewhere with like a pond and
some trees and
try to make a nice little area could be
cool i like that idea
and the second comment says hey etho
have you ever heard of clash of clans
i have heard of it i play it and it is
super
duper popular i think you would like the
game
they have it on mobile and pc but some
put some thought into it anyways i love
your videos
you the best uh yeah i've watched videos
of it i haven't played it actually but i
was curious
because i i kept hearing people talk
about it it's like uh
what do you call it defend and conquer
type of game where you build up a base
and then
other players try to rate it and you get
troops and that and stuff like that uh
look pretty cool
i don't know if there's like one
strategy that always works in it or if
it's like a pretty
interesting game all the time but it
looked pretty cool from what i saw but i
haven't played it yet i didn't realize
it was for the pc i thought it was only
mobile so thanks for
the suggestion hope you guys enjoyed the
episode
hope you have a wonderful day i know you
will you watched this episode you saw
the nexus
coming to come come to life
in a way even though it's slightly
broken
anyways have a good one guys take care
bye bye
[Music]