oh man
pool party oh no flame arrows in the
pool please oh ah darn it
are you kidding me oh what a great start
to the episode stupid creeper I was a
afk underneath the the Guardian firm
here for a while for like two three
hours I come back and I look in the
chest it's the first time I ever went
afk at this thing I look in the chest
and there's like four or five double
four or five chests full of stuff and is
like that seems kind of low this firm is
way less efficient than I thought it was
actually it's even less than that oh
it's only like three chests anyway I saw
that and as like I'm gonna have to redo
this thing this is garbage and I go
outside here and there's like all the
mobs spawned in the guardian farm I left
the door open I guess gonna have to
remember to close that next time
although now I have to repair it alright
alright this actually raises the
question how am I going to repair this
thing most of the mobs have T spawned
when I left the area so that's good oh
no there's still a few here problem is
getting these fence gates back up Oh
going to be tricky because you have to
have a block underneath the fence gate
one more up and over there uh-huh
ouch
and did we just lose to seem like we
lost a lot more than that as my health
I'm still okay oh it's starting to hurt
though okay I'm out of here
I'll get it don't worry ah just one
creeper one creeper can cause so much
problems I think the lab would convert
the stone down there so now they can't
fall through they're all backed up there
we go good as new everything's fixed I'm
adding in something here this would tend
to fall down on the reeds here and then
either the fall kills them or they
suffocate because they they don't bounce
around like the Guardians do so all the
squid ink pretty much ends up here and
I'm going to just set up a rail cart
line to pick that up because I'm not
really getting any of it so just got it
running underneath the reeds and then
we're going to have hopper into the
chest like that and see comparator next
to the hopper then redstone torch goes
up to there and then over like this and
that powers the rail all right so then
get a hopper minecart and that should be
it so when it gets to here it'll stop
and unload and then when it's finished
unloading it will take off again it just
made two other end and it's bouncing
back and there we go we got five okay
guys so moving on here you will never
guess what project we are about to do
although I guess if you did venture yes
I never said it had to be a correct yes
all right anyway so I have decided it is
time we are going to dig a tunnel from
the mantle
to the end portal because I'm I don't I
think it might be a little more
convenient than going through the nether
all the time
so here we go oh you know what I
shouldn't probably brought some Flint's
deal with me do I have a foot and steel
no oh let's catch up let's catch up this
is going to go for a while
whoop do some parkour on the way because
it is about a thousand blocks or so I
did this fail yeah at the trail darn it
oh oh where am I now
uh-oh uh-oh we're missing it oh here it
is how did I not see this oh that's good
let's go you know it'd be cool as if it
was chasing me I should plan to do that
instead but that I didn't have a tunnel
big enough oh yes
all right man nothing's okay spider
why was there tape spider there
interesting ooh and it stopped okay
let's get it going again how far are we
we have to go now man it's 500 more
blocks yet this might take too long to
record I don't know if it's entertaining
enough it is TNT but it's it's pretty
repetitive alright let's keep going
look nope
all right guys yeah so I'm going to be
putting down ice we're gonna make a nice
thing where you jump and you get the
speed boost that those are usually
pretty quick we might put trapdoors down
to to make it even quicker it's going to
be a pretty big project because this is
a very far tunnel oh we're here we're
finally here
oh no silverfish it goes through the
stronghold and that's the end finally
and then the end portal is just over
here poof okay got that done now gonna
place ice and sort of polish it up a bit
ah there's nothing more annoying then it
bunched to skeleton when I have no bow
in a narrow Hall hallway alright this is
not happening there we go
yeah so we're we're doing the ice thing
now I'm going to use bat dice because
probably want to light it up to later
and this way it will not melt on us
somebody stole my portal well that's why
we have to i am worried to see what's
going on my
there's potentially lots of these
Guardians around oh just one okay that's
not bad
we're safe ah I remember one day many
many years ago before I started this
project how good my life was ah we're
almost done we're almost done it this is
one of those really long grindy projects
that doesn't really look all that fancy
when you're done but it's going to be
nice to have throughout the life of the
world here I should have done this a
long time ago
oh man I got it done it is done it is
finished never to be done again uh so
let's go for a little ride in the shall
we yeah so yeah so this is what it ended
up being pat dice on the floor
we got stairs on the walls and i got
these little vertical columns every five
blocks i did it every five blocks so
it's easy for me like I can just look at
the coordinates here and every time it
was at five and zero that's when I knew
I needed to put a column so even if I
didn't know like how it lined up with
the rest of it I could just look at the
coordinates and figure it out which is
nice if you go by tens trap trap doors
on the top this is so you can't can't
really jump it gives you a little bit
more of a speed boost when you go and
every ten blocks there is a piece of
glowstone to light up the path and that
is about it so here we go guys here we
go
oh now I want to do some comparisons
later to will do one more run after this
I want to see if speed potions make it
quicker I'm not sure if they actually do
these these things are really common on
servers but in my single-player I've
never had to do something like this it
looks like we got a stop to eat once on
the way at least and it is really far I
was hoping it would be a little quicker
honestly but it's just so far so it's
like a thousand blocks I was hoping it
would be like a twenty second 30 second
trip it's still like it's like a minute
isn't a second time yeah it's pretty
pretty crazy but I think it might still
be quicker than going through portals I
hope okay here we go round two this time
with a speed tube potion and we'll see
which one is quicker it definitely feels
like you're ooh oh I hit the wall there
that's not good for for the accuracy of
the test feels like you're going quicker
but it might just be a field of view
thing I can't tell oh man I keep hitting
the walls - it's not good this torch
here by the way that's where the tape
spider fell down and I saw there was a
zombie spawner right there - so I kind
of wanted them mark that spot and he's
still want to investigate later so it's
- spawners together whoa and I find it's
really good to have like vertical
columns when you're doing long tunnels
like this it just makes it feel like
you're going so much quicker doesn't it
when you got that thing zipping by
otherwise if it's all the same you can
barely tell you're moving all right stop
twice deed again and time whoa and we're
here I can take it down here come on
there we go
it's struggling so yeah
that takes us to the end it also takes
us to the stronghold base if we want to
go there the nice thing about having
that is sometimes like when I'm doing
work on the on the nether my portals go
down and then it's like I can't use them
for transportation while I'm doing weird
stuff I guess so this is just another
way of getting there too and I think it
is quicker than going through the nether
and here are the results everyone the
first rounds without the speed potion
took fifty seven point two seconds set
and round with the speed two potion he
goes quicker do you think it was quicker
fifty six point four seconds so yes it
was quicker but probably not really by
much if anything it probably just
factored in some air there I don't know
it might be a little bit quicker but
it's not worth it alright everybody so
moving on here let's do a bit of a horse
update shall we it's been a long time
since we like tried to get any better
horses so I moved that our best jumping
horses to this been here we only had two
here and I've been breeding them and
these are all there
their offspring basically you'll notice
there's something something not quite
right in this scene something doesn't
quite belong right you see what I mean
that's right there's a read back there
that's four blocks tall reads can only
grow to three blocks tall so something
is amiss with that I don't know but
anyway let's let's try out the they're
jumping Heights and see if we got any
improvement um alright let's start with
with you over here most of them have
white socks it seems it's a saddle on a
tame them all before I start so that
this one take an hour which base
basically took an hour to do that I use
sugar cane alright you're out of the
contest
you failed waste of our time get out of
here
and let's try the ones with the saddles
on are the original parents so we don't
need to test them let's go over here
Oh rejected it's like so much worse - is
it it's not like a no no no you're out
of the contest get out of here
trying to sneak his way back in alright
all black horse please be a good one no
all right you're out I hate to tell you
but you're no good alright we're running
out of horses here this is why I wanted
to do a bunch of them before we tried
this because I had a feeling there was a
good chance we want to get a better one
now you're close you're you're better
than most but sorry still no good I
think this is like 4.3 75 jumping height
here can it I can't remember exactly
what the limit was oh man this is not
looking good I was hoping we would get
one but where we're not off to a good
start
oh this guy is pretty good he's come on
still real jump here he's close he's
very close but no don't don't think I
don't see you there you cannot get back
into the contest once you failed alright
nope man just one give me some sights
some slight improvement here please oh
my goodness
they keep trying to get back in nope
I should really move that crafting bench
and are you not tamed yeah you steamed
and still no good alright how many we
got left
we got one trying to sneak back in
there's two here hopefully one of these
guys didn't sneak
Oh what oh that was weird
nope still no good this one is really
close though oh man all right last one
oh why can't I
oh I got a I got something my hand
that's why all right please give me some
improvement
now that was like ten horses and no
improvements so this is why this project
has hit a bit of a snag is take a really
long time to get any any improvement
with them which is why I want that
passive mob firm to work but yeah it
just doesn't quite work because we have
all these cow farms and rabbit farms at
our base here I would have to destroy to
make that passive mob farm work oh I'm
shooting at me get out of here so over
at our Nexus here we have a problem to
try figure out before we can really
build the rest of these we need to work
out all all issues we have with it
otherwise we're just going to be
amplifying our mistakes eight times so
we want to get those right so we have
this problem where the redstone torch is
above here are powering the piston this
one here so we got to try move it so
that it still works the way we
originally intended where it splits
between those two and those two um so
I'm gonna try possibly moving this let's
not worry about this for right now I say
that now then I'm going to find out it's
impossible to do it when I actually try
to work it out but maybe if we move it
over one so it's not below the redstone
torch put that there oops
let's see so when this when this is here
it'll power those two that's fine but
when it extends it'll be here and it
doesn't power these two
what do we do oops this pic is too good
all right I think we have to have like
these as repeaters somehow I don't know
if that's going to work though and this
is regular wire so that when this
extends here all this is confusing
that's no good did this have to do away
with that can we get this to work off of
just one repeater is that possible
all right so if the block is here it'll
go to these two on the left but it'll
also go to this we need to stop that is
it possible to stop it doesn't look like
it this is tricky um we could if the
power didn't go through here then we
could have like now now this just isn't
working I got one solution to the puzzle
here it's not as clean as what we had
originally but it'll work basically send
power to these two repeaters if the
block is here it goes through and it
goes to the two like we want and it
doesn't go to the left side if the block
is here it doesn't go here anymore
because I lower it at one so the power
doesn't go through to the right side but
it goes to the left side here if we have
blocks here and here and that should all
work out okay oh this is very quickly
turning into quite the nightmare it's
like wiring a circuit board almost so I
got the I got these Pistons controlled
again that works out just fine like it
did before with no interference from the
torches above now which is good so
basically this second bit runs through
here
it's regular wire does not interfere
going this way because this is a a dust
but it goes through to the repeater
repeaters power the piston above through
this block and the pattern kind of just
repeats as far as I can tell there's no
interference at all which is good now
I'm starting on the third bit and for
some reason I thought it was going to
get like way easier as we made our way
down but we still need just as much wire
pretty much for every one of these so I
might do something like this like send a
pulse to the third bit here and either
goes to the left and to this one or if
it goes to the right it goes down and to
here and through this way it's getting
complicated though because I also need
some way of controlling this these
Pistons so I'll probably go above like
this the main challenge though I do this
if I had all the space in the world but
I'm trying to do it as compact as
possible ideally I didn't want to go
past this is like the last block I'm
willing to go horizontally and the lower
or the less we have to go downward the
better because if we're going to stack
these units on top of each other like
I'm planning
we'll have to stack them higher up if
they take more space vertically so
basically I was trying to fit it into
this which is not going to happen hey
Stu and mining fatigue 3 oh man the
mining fatigue winds though
unfortunately oh there it goes so maybe
one more thing we'll try here I wasn't
100% happy with the quartz and stained
clay thing we tried the other day so
just out of curiosity I'm not saying
we're going to go with it but I want to
try the nether brick and prismarine
combo that we did in in the nether there
so if we do this let's just play around
with it a little bit one possibility is
to have
break here like this I do kind of want
some stairs going across here but we
have to be careful not to use too much
nether brick which I kind of feel we
have done already the ground would
probably be the prismarine stuff the the
dark one all right and possibly then we
would do let's see what let's do one
more row and then what's this is this
needed for something oh it is mm okay I
can't remember did we use polish dye
right when we did it before let me try
that I think it was polished actually
not that we have to do it again but
let's try polished diorite maybe we'll
make it go around just like this yeah it
doesn't look right you only have two
blocks of the dark stuff here I don't
think it's going to look too good so we
would we would want at least four so
let's do this um lanterns let's get some
lanterns here and here I think we'll
have to get rid of the nether brick if
we do this and use this type of brick
yay mmm
- blue - blue isn't it we need more
nether brick mmm I brought fences fences
here how else can we do this stairs
maybe now ah well we gave it a try here
the problem I'm having is that there's
just not enough wall space to do what I
want to do it's only three blocks wide
and with all these different types of
blocks we're not going to make it work
um so yeah well we should probably wrap
up the episode again guys so let's get
to the comment for today this one's kind
of a fun one it says etho have you ever
been arrested or been in heaps of
trouble oh-ho-ho-ho-ho-ho
you know what I'm kind of the type of
person that if there's rules I have a
really hard time breaking them like I
don't I don't see the benefit in it and
I don't really find it fun I guess like
even when it comes to speeding I tent
I can't speed like when I'm driving like
I know what the speed limit is why would
I go faster I can I can stay within it
I've never been pulled over because of
that and never had to pay any fines and
yeah I don't know I'm just that type of
person um I have been I've had like
troubles I guess so um I'll give you an
example hey you really wanted to be in
this episode then you came running right
up to me back when I was like 14 or 15 I
was flying home from the states to
Canada um I was alone and I had to do
the customs right you know you're on the
plane they give you that little pamphlet
then you you fill out anything you have
to declare well I had bought a BB gun
and a Walmart there and when it came
time to filling out the customs you know
at first I didn't really think about
them I was like do I declare this as a
weapon it's a BB gun it's not really a
weapon is it and just to be safe I
decided to declare it as a weapon
biggest mistake of my life
no what happened is of course they
pulled me aside and by the time I landed
it was like 12 a.m. or 1 a.m. is super
late at night I was dead tired after all
the time changing and whatnot and I had
people waiting to pick me up my parents
and obviously they were probably worried
too because I got pulled aside and I had
to go through some special check and
they put me in this room with the x-ray
machines and they just did told me Oh
someone's gonna come by and and talk to
you an hour later I was in that room all
alone there it was like an empty room -
because the airport was like shut down
for the day um I started like playing
around with the x-ray machines and then
when the guy finally came he got really
mad because I was playing with the x-ray
machines and anyway he goes through all
my luggage totally empties it and and
then he he does this thing like where he
says if you didn't declare this on your
customs we would have arrested you today
like he got he was like trying to scare
me or something he got like super
serious um
and then he confiscated it and I was not
very happy about that
and I asked him why and he gave me the
reason that you could paint it or it
kind of looked like a real gun and I
could hold up a convenience store and
they wouldn't be able to tell the
difference which whatever the thing that
really bugged me though is they also
took my bb's which are just like little
metal balls which are not a weapon
they're just they're just bb's right so
I asked them why why are you taking my
bb's and like basically he said don't
give me any trouble or we're gonna
arrest you type of thing like he just
totally abused this position and I I
don't like going through customs anymore
or through the airport because I always
get pulled over for the random checks
now every single time because they must
have flagged me um yeah and the kicker
of the story one week later I was
shopping I found the exact same gun for
sale same BB gun just did a regular
store
and I was able to buy it but it costed
70 bucks that they basically stole for
me and that's that's just one story all
right that's going to do it for today
guys thank you for watching and I will
see you again in the next episode take
care bye bye