[Music]
hello everybody welcome back
this is uh etho as always as you know
and uh i'm sorry we're in the nether
again
i know you hate it i'm starting to hate
it too
uh it's these blaze traps man i have
spent
so much time on them and like of all
projects in my world i've
spent the most time on these and made
the least progress i think
because i keep messing around with
different uh
different ways of moving the blaze
around i know we tried lava
tubes they didn't work i've been messing
around with
them just finding their way using
pathfinding
tried a few different things with that
it works but it takes too long
and i've tried uh
furnace minecarts there's actually some
promise in them but uh
i think in the long run they're gonna
annoy me because every time i want to
collect the blaze together i'd have to
put
a piece of coal or a blazer out into the
mine cart and wait a few seconds for
them to
get collected together so i'm just going
to go the piston route
after all got a
pretty good idea that i think is going
to work out really nice and be
quick and everybody's gonna like i got
my pistons re-added to the blaze farms
i have to make a few adjustments to this
one yet you can see it doesn't
[Music]
they're not the same shape
and i've had other issues too of course
like i had fence gates in these things i
had to replace them all with signs
that's done but uh
anyway i'll probably do a montage of me
setting up my conveyor system here
and i hope you enjoy it
[Music]
hmm
uh
[Music]
ugh
um
[Music]
[Applause]
um
[Music]
hmm
alrighty so the conveyor belt's pretty
much set up here
it's a big giant v i think it's going to
work out nicely
this is about two hours later i wasted a
lot of time readjusting
the blaze farm on the right there
[Music]
because i was trying to do it without
shutting off the lava at first i thought
it'd be quicker
nope nope not at all i had a lava spill
uh that made a huge mess i had to clean
up i almost died a few times from it too
and yeah i also realized later that i
didn't need a lot of the signs i had
in the farm anymore because i'm using
pistons again
so i just have them on the top layer now
where there's no pistons
but anyway let's go for a ride on our rv
conveyor here
so it should be pretty quick as soon as
the blades fall down they'll get
pushed over here pretty quick and then
i'm going to have lava here
that will carry them up and the plan is
like originally this was going to be the
main floor down here
but now well that just messed with my
mind
but now i'm thinking i'll have the main
floor up here
at this height here so
we'll have it'll look pretty cool we'll
have the blaze spawners on both sides
and uh then over here right in front of
us still
is where the blazer gonna collect the
lava will bring them up
to a few blocks in front of us here and
it will all be centered
and should be pretty good and then we'll
have our controls and stuff up here too
so yep i haven't tried this out yet but
i think it's gonna work out really nice
so there's a problem with this thing
right now that you might have noticed
when i wrote it
but when you get to the end
i take that little bit of damage uh
that's going to be a big
problem if i don't fix it so i think
what's happening is a piston is pushing
me
slightly more than one block and
like i think pistons always push you
slightly more than one block even though
they only extend one block so i'm
slightly
clipped into one of these blocks
and when this one pushes me back i'm
inside of them for a little bit before
the game
auto adjusts my position into the air
space here
so that's going to happen to the blaze
too we need to prevent that from
happening
so my idea
here
when instead of having just one of these
extend like this one here
i'm going to try to make it so this
pressure plate
this pressure plate and this one are
connected
so that if either of them are pressed
both of these extend and that way
if they're both extended it will have a
block
for the blades to align against so
to do that we're going to get rid of the
repeaters we don't
want to use repeaters i guess and
see if we can wire this up on camera
without me freaking out
okay so go underneath and
have a block there block there
oh good i've heard start on me too
so now we need to join the two pressure
plates together
and we also have to be careful not to
have this one interfere in the middle
so an easy way of doing that is just to
go down one block so it's out of range
of the pressure plate above
so now they're joined together and we
just need to hook the wire to both
pistons
and i think i'll try to use redstone
torches
if we can so
i would put one there and i have
redstone torches awesome
go up and then where's that piston
so much stuff in my way okay so we got
to get it up to here
um
that's probably gonna be tough to do
maybe we'll go like this
it has to be have to use two here to
make it inverted
and we'll make that sandstone
there that's
yeah it works good so we can probably
fill that in
and then we'll do the same for the other
side here
redstone torch block
torch
and sandstone okay so now they should be
both connected together
and the middle one doesn't seem to
affect them that's good
yeah okay
so let's get this back together and
we'll try it out
and i'll probably put half slabs down
there and stuff so there's no empty
space
for a zombie pigment to spawn
okay let's ride it i think that will
work
if i can get out of here
yeah i think this is probably the best
way of doing it
the furnace minecarts would be cool if
you had to move them a long distance but
this is still
not that far so pistons are
pretty good choice they're just
expensive there's lots of pistons in
this probably
and all the blaze farms and the conveyor
belt it's at least
probably a hundred i would well yeah
probably around 100 or so
there we go no damage that's good that's
what we wanted
and then okay well i'll fill in the
empty space i got left down here
and then i'll be back
okay don't worry i did change this so
that uh
the torch goes straight up to another
torch here and then to the piston
instead of
that roundabout way with the wire and
everything i don't know why i did it
like that before
i think i may have been worried the
torch would be visible but that doesn't
really matter
since we have repeaters and stuff in
there too
i got a half slab there just so zombie
pigmen can't spawn in my wiring
not that that makes much difference
and fill this in put that there
put one here okay so now we need to do
our lava
mava favorite lava mob evader
too many v's and that's gonna go right
here i think we can do it without using
any signs even
uh if we
actually no we don't even need to do
that
oh i want that back sandstone it's
pretty rare for me at the moment
okay we'll have the wall here the
pressure plate will hold
the lava in place so i don't need
anything i just need
to drop a bucket of lava down here it
doesn't need to be full
source blocks because as we found out
before
lava doesn't push mobs at all so
downward flow doesn't matter they still
treat it like a lava source block
and this will go up as high as we want
it to go
and i think we can test this out pretty
soon
i'm excited to see how quick it works
yeah maybe we'll go a little bit
higher
okay we'll go up to there for now and
just see how this works out uh i will
put
um let's put the lava one block lower
over here it'll flow down and we'll put
a cap on top just for now
okay so i'm gonna
i'm gonna enable one side of this and
we'll see how it turns out
okay first test here let's shut this off
blaze will be able to spawn and what
should happen is they should make it all
the way up to the top here on their own
relatively quickly
while we're standing here
okay there he goes
that looks awesome
yeah he's making his way up and i don't
think he's agro
so that's good too
it does take him a while to get up that
motivator though
yeah he's not a girl awesome
so one thing i'm concerned about is how
it's gonna
react if there's multiple blades going
through it at the same time
so maybe we'll get the other one going
here too
let's get just to get the numbers up
to maximum spawning rates up to maximum
and i think if they are to interfere
uh the blaze will just get stuck in a
block and suffocate and then it'll fix
itself but we might lose a few from that
it's looking good oh
[Music]
you got a suffocator
okay it's still working though that's
good
oh you know what they can see me through
these pistons too so i'll have to cover
them up
or i don't think they see me through the
pistons i think they see me when they
extend
if i'm down here another suffocator
oh man another suffocator so i might
have to play around with delays too
if this happens a lot
[Music]
i wasn't expecting this many
but overall it seems to be working
pretty good
i'm glad they're not suffocating at the
where they join together there that's
what i was most concerned about
that would i wouldn't know how to fix it
if they did if that other fix didn't
work
oh they're mad at me up there too i must
have holes somewhere or else they're
seeing me through these pistons i don't
know
getting laggy no
particles minimal
okay well i think i'm gonna leave this
area and uh
make a few adjustments here i'll think
about that first
fall i'm gonna set a delay for sure
because that's where they seem to
get stuck a lot and
look for any holes in this thing because
they're seeing me somehow
okay i got this disabled again all the
blades are gone
there was a hole up there in the glass i
got it patched that's how they
saw me before and i have added glass
all along the blocks that move with the
pistons so
they shouldn't be able to see me if i'm
down here either anymore
now i'm pretty sure i found the cause of
them suffocating over here
the issue is wow
i actually used like half my pick
already just building this thing
the issue is um
if they go on this like if there's a
blaze down below there
i want to show you but i can't do it
without dying
quick yes okay
um right so
if there's a blaze down there and
there's one up here on this pressure
plates
i still can't demonstrate it without
getting rid of it
okay i'm just gonna switch this pressure
plate with a lever so we can control it
that's what happens if a blaze steps on
that pressure plate it causes through
the pistons to extend
and there's no way for a blaze below
that to get through
so it just suffocates so
we need to change this and the reason
this one's extending
there we go is because uh
the block one up and diagonal to it can
power it so this block is powering this
piston here
believe it or not
and we need to fix that so the only way
i can think of is to move this up
one oh oh no
no no stop
oh man that's freaky got lava at the end
of this thing
why did i stop here
oh there's a repeater missing uh where
am i
i gotta get out of here i almost died
i should really get some fire resistant
potions
okay give me a sec to fix this
i've been thinking about it and i think
the only
proper way to fix this would be to lower
the whole conveyor thing
down one block and that doesn't sound
like
fun so i've thought of a new cheat way
of doing it too
instead of having
pressure plate here and one here we'll
just set it up so there's one here and
one here
and then this first piston here won't be
activated so
we're going to move this and it should
still function
pretty much the same i would imagine
so we're not we're not cheating to
we're not cheating in a way that's going
to make this less effective we're just
changing it
so we will have the piston here
so if it was less effective i think i
would lower it just because it would bug
me
and do that
block there and then the repeater will
go
here and hopefully that will that won't
cause any problems i'll have to watch it
i think
um
[Music]
i may have to adjust the delay on one of
these
i don't know should be about the same
okay so i'll close this up and then
we'll try it again and keep an eye on
this
okay first test here they're coming down
lava should disable soon
come on oh he's right above
do you not get pushed
good good
so they were getting stuck in the corner
like that too before
that's okay um
you know what i should do is put the
sign over there so they'll wander off
too
right now he thinks he's stuck
will you move on your own i wonder you
should
don't seem to want to move
[Music]
there he goes and he didn't fall down
darn so it might be less effective
after all
okay i may have figured it out here or
at least something that'll work better
i do have the sign back again so if they
land on
this block they will have an increased
chance
of wandering over here with their
pathfinding
because they view this as a solid block
so they will try to walk over it
they can walk down there normally too
but
the way the pathfinding works uh there's
a
increased chance of them doing it if
it's at the same level
the block so that'll help i've also done
one other really important thing here
there's no reason i can't have one
pressure plate control two pistons so
now when they step on the one over there
two pistons go out instead of just one
[Music]
and the way i rigged that up we'll go
behind here
had to use a little bit of wire
so the first pistons there repeaters to
the left of this block so
repeater sends power to this block and
then you can
steal that power with this wire here and
it carries it up over
to our piston our second piston here
so that should make that a lot better
i think we're gonna try it out here
pretty quick i got that side all ready
too
so let me get them spawning again and
we'll see how this works now
yeah i just got it up and running and
right off the bat we have a suffocator
so i'm going to
adjust this one to
and adjust this to two ticks
or two torch delays i should say
and hopefully that'll help okay
they're corrected now let's see if we
get any more suffocators
yeah not much i can do about that
what just happened there they were too
close together
uh nice thing is it seems to kind of
self-regulate itself
it's good
because uh these things these things
kind of uh
close off areas so they one blaze has to
wait for another blaze to go through
before it can unless they're really
close together
oh darn that wasn't too bad
oh he survived even wow
so the way i'll probably hook up the
killing thing i'll probably do the
splash
damage potion thing because with all
these pistons i'm not going to get their
health
overly consistent that was another
reason i didn't want to use pistons
originally but just simplifies things so
much
seems to be okay i like it i like it
it's quick that's for sure
relatively few deaths from it
and it looks pretty awesome as well
that's weird is it stuck in a loop now
oh
or is that a visual glitch what i just
saw there
see it's doing there's
oh that was uh that was the pistons
retracting probably it's messing with my
eyes this thing
and we got 33 or so in there that's
pretty good
so yeah we'll get lots and lots of xp
from this thing it's going to be great
when it's all set up
i just need to hook up the killing
chamber and figure out some
some of the ground around here too to
make it look cool because at the moment
this is the only
land i have at this level where the main
floor is supposed to be
so got a lot of work to do here
but i am going to end the episode here
uh probably won't do another another one
next time we'll do something else just
to add some variety but i do hope to get
this
finished sometime soon and i will see
you guys again next time thanks for
watching