um did you do this was it you did you do
this to my class fess up who did it
what's going on here I just saw this
forest forest forest forest
oh boy oh boy I don't know what would do
this honestly could be the patch there's
a big line here this never was here
before wasn't here before I'm telling
you I'm not crazy I know these things
hmm we'll have to keep an eye on that
ah he's back Vicky's back so hello
everybody this is etho and we are
playing my my let's play world again
today I I was breaking some of this
nether quartz we've got last time and
I'm hit level 30 figured we would do a
book and chant
try to get some silk touch if we are
incredibly lucky apparently the odds are
not in our favor though power three all
right today by the way if I remember
this is going to be the HD episode I
hope I hope I might forget but I'm
hoping I don't and let's head on down to
over here did I wait as Oh for a I'm not
using oh five because I heard there's
some performance issues and have
experienced them myself as well unless
you use smooth lighting off don't use
smooth lighting that's what I meant to
say um
but yeah I'd been doing some adjustments
with my minecraft I have updated my Java
and I increased the RAM usage when I
play although oh wait maybe I didn't
what is it it's at 9:10 the top right
there and I earn 10 Meg's I thought I
said it four gigs so I'll have to look
into that later this looks weird to me
tune in I don't know huh interesting
anyway a little confused today it seems
anyway what I want to kind of work on
today to start off with anyway is the
nether hub here I haven't done anything
really with this rail line since since
last time basically people who there's
some lighting glitch there too basically
I had that big plan for using chickens
like have it have a chicken in the carts
and then have that go in front of me and
then the space between the chicken cart
and my carts will tell where where to
stop at my stations that was kind of the
plan with this but was I was working on
that just before the redstone update
really took off and people kind of just
told me to wait before I start getting
too deep into here because it would
really really suck if I had if I put all
this work into it and then was not happy
with it afterwards and that was a good
call because yeah there's there's new
and better ways of doing what I wanted
to do now let the redstone update has
kind of come out and things are are
settling down a little bit more so my
new plan with this I was thinking about
it today instead of using a chicken cart
I want to use a storage minecart in
front of the one I'm riding in and it
doesn't matter how far away it is from
me I'm not going to use distance to
determine where to stop instead I can
encode information in my rail line by
like each star
down my rail line I didn't have a unique
item ID so if I have hoppers under the
rail and I put an item in the storage
carts only if it matches the items in
the hopper I have below will it send out
a pulse and tell tell my station that
I'm going to that one sort of you know
what I mean I didn't explain that too
well did I oh well I tried yeah we can
use we can have like so many different
stops with my new plan here just using
hoppers and each unique item we use can
represent a different stop in our track
and then also since there's going to be
a problem with mine carts accumulating
it at different stops and and not being
able to distribute them properly another
thing we can do is put extra storage
mine carts inside of our storage
minecart oh that's right and and have
those get distributed as well as it
moves from station to station if in if a
station needs it it can drop some off as
it goes by but yeah that's kind of a
plan but the problem with doing it this
way is I'm going to have to use gold or
power rails instead of normal rails and
I just want to do a quick test before we
get going with the plan to see if I can
get away with skipping on the power
rails a little bit so I don't have to do
it solid power rails all the way down
try space it out and see how it compares
next be nom-nom-nom-nom-nom
hmm
so you're saying Jeff did it huh Jeff
did it he looks innocent but that guy I
don't trust that guy anymore all right
well at least it's
back to normal now we know what's going
on all right here we go this is our
experiment we are trying to see just how
cheaply candy with power rails because
they're kind of expensive unique gold to
make power rails so we want to use as
few as possible I know it'll work if I
have solid power rails all along now I
want to see if I can have one every
second track so the idea is to have one
empty cart and I'll be in the other one
and see if it can keep up oh that looks
good
it might even be a little bit faster
than me let's ride this for a little bit
see if it gets ahead of us I think it is
actually here than me
because technically I think this should
be slower than us
that is really weird I was not expecting
that
yeah okay so we can actually skip every
every second track here for sure I'm
going to change it for every third let's
even get away with that okay we're going
down to every third block now we're
going to keep doing this until we notice
the empty car going slower than us
assuming that happens maybe something
change with minecarts again it's keeping
up pretty good
oh it's like it it's switches going
other direction faster than when I'm in
it because it doesn't doesn't seem like
it goes all the way up to the Cobble but
with me it does
that's why it's getting a little bit
ahead of us otherwise it would be the
same speed-up t-shirt I'm going to
spread it out even further and we are at
four blocks now this is the turning
point I tried it out already
OOP four blocks seems to be too far
apart now because what happens is keeps
up just about but we're getting a little
bit of a ahead of it the only reason it
kind of stays even with me is because it
turns around faster than us but you can
see I'm slightly gaining on it
ever ever so slightly so I'll probably
just keep it at its three-block distance
between each of them just to be safe but
that's good to know that's that's a huge
savings that's like three times less
power rails will need and I'm trying
five now just out of curiosity see how
big of a difference it makes keep it up
oh oh
yeah see we have this big initial push
when we launched it and it keeps up
until we get like up to here and then
you can see it falls back way to bits as
it loses its momentum that's that big
difference now you know what guys when I
was recording that last little bit I
noticed something you see those
mountains over there you can see them
they're actually visible like they're
there they're rendered so I'm kind of
curious like I've changed things with my
recording here so I'm kind of curious
just to see how well it's doing and you
can see I relaunched my minecraft here
now I'm using the four gigs of RAM my
computer actually has 16 gigs so it's
not a problem for me to give it more RAM
because that I never use 16 gigs that's
that's way overkill for anything I'm
doing um yeah I think before like when I
when I would if I was to stand there and
record I don't think those would
actually load and render so let's go do
a little stress test real quick here and
just see how things keep up the other
thing I'm noticing is when I go to
record well so that's not loaded see
throw load if we wait here a little bit
it might be too far away another thing
is when I when I go to record now very
rarely will it go down to 15 frames that
was a big problem was having before like
I have it locked at 30 but if it can't
do 30 it'll do 15 if you can do more
than 30 and you'll go up to 60 hmm you
know actually you know what's a good
test the storage room I have never been
able to go in and out of that without it
liking my game let's see it's even fun I
leave home and then we'll try go the
storage room and just try it
but yeah I'm definitely noticing a
difference it seems to be a bit better
now
when it comes to recording
do-do-do-do-do-do - ever since it
switched to emulating a server in
single-player my frame rates been kind
of crummy a little bit of a slowdown but
it was as bad as it used to be yeah I
went down to about 21 frames let's have
this up when we do it okay we get in 30
to 36 38 should be locked at 30 over
here 26 3 22 back up 30 this thing also
legs a bit seems to be better though as
going to help a lot and feed the beast
now that I have more memory available
because the problem with using 32-bit
Java like it was is there's a limit you
can only give it up to a gig and now I
can go way way beyond that help things
out a bunch montage begin
all right excellent we got quite a bit
done here on our nether tunnel odd and
you know this tunnel stuff it looks
simple like there's not much to it it's
just a very simple repeating pattern but
it's just so many blocks it takes quite
a while to do but we got got a fair bit
done today on it maybe we will just work
on it together for a little bit and we
can take a moment to talk I want to say
thank you to everybody for your feedback
on last episode ah I do really value
your feedback I read the comments still
I can't read I can't read every comment
like I used to but I do try to read at
least a thousand to 2,000 per episode
just to get idea of of feedback on on
stuff I do see how people react to it
because I am very interested in what
people have to say all right how's this
go
I just would go down here right yeah so
yeah we had good response about Wilson
lots of people pitching in their ideas
which might apply some of them and
Wilson our pet that is and also like I
talked about the annotation thing last
episode and I got a different response
than what I was expecting which is why
it's good I read the comments because
sometimes you know I might expect people
to react one way and they don't but the
general general reaction I seem to get
is that people don't like annotations
actually so maybe I shouldn't do them my
plan was to have just like a like if
you're watching episode 250 oops
of my let's play I would have a forward
link to go to episode 251 if it's out
and a previous episode link to like
episode 249 um if I was to go go on with
the idea but I'm thinking maybe I won't
do it just based off of the response
just like the last I was just going to
do it like on the last 10 seconds of the
video or something have a forward and
backward link and maybe if it worked out
okay maybe have a one or two links to
other series I do but having second
thoughts now it's good to get your your
feedback though because I do aim to
please you guys now something else I've
been thinking about maybe addressing
lately is oh it's going to get dangerous
when we get over there um you know doing
this YouTube thing it's good to get good
feedback but it's YouTube I expect to
get some negative feedback it happens
there's trolls out there there's there's
people that are upset as well with me as
you guys know I do well as a lot of you
know I do block pretty much anyone
advertising on my videos so people are
saying come
check out my server or my videos I will
probably block you with a few exceptions
sometimes I am nice and I'll just remove
the message but generally I block people
when they do that now and I think some
people take it personally when I do that
and they starts that yet I've been dead
again against me like I've wronged them
they feel like they've been treated
unjustly or who knows what goes through
people's heads so not really my
intention and just trying to prevent
spam on my video comments so I can
actually read the comments but the thing
I want to kind of talk about is when
negative it whoa what did I just say
when negativity happens in the comments
guys for my for my loyal subscribers
that the nice the nice guys of you if
you see negativity in the comments Oh
bad time at time whoo right over the
lava pool so when the gas shows up yeah
if you see negativity in the comments
don't don't respond to it please it's
not really helping anybody else
don't argue with people if you can help
it you might have good intentions of
defending me or something of that nature
but get out of here man oh yeah but if
you respond to negative comments it sort
of snowballs negativity because that's
what people see and that's what they
reply to generally negative feelings
stir up our emotions more so than
positive ones so you feel more inclined
to reply to negative comments but yeah
it's not it's not good for me it's not
good for you it's not good for anybody
really when you do it I've been shooting
pigmen and they're mad at me I think I
got a watch out here he's chasing me
down I don't know where he is
but the other thing is I find if people
respond to a negative comment and
instead of leaving a positive comment or
some content and late some comment
related to the video they kind of use up
their comment responding to a negative
person I think I said something around
there guys not that you leave a negative
comment but you were replied to a
negative comment which you know I would
rather get a comment from you relating
to my video or if you have something to
say about the video yeah I do care about
your feedback is what I'm getting at so
please leave it and try to avoid
arguments in the comments because it's
not good for anyone look at it you mad
he's not mad all right
yeah really appreciate your feedback
guys on let's go do something else if we
can probably running a long time for
today actually but we'll go we'll go get
out of the nether no wait no hold on
wait a minute wait a minute
you're telling me Jeff over there the
guy making the potions right now the guy
making my potions isn't a fully licensed
pharmacist and he's making the potions I
drink the stuff that goes into my body
and he doesn't know what he's doing
oh man Jeff Jeff man your coworkers
they've been ratting you out boy I know
what's up here you you don't have a clue
what you're doing do you you don't know
I know you're a prankster guy out there
he told me he told me you messed with my
grass earlier I know what's going on
here so I'll tell you what I'm gonna
give you a test here you made these
potions mm-hmm okay well tell you what
if your potions actually work like
they're supposed to do if you pass
there you messed with my noteblocks
tinge you you jerk tell you what if your
potions that they meet my standards you
can continue working here otherwise
you're out on your keister boy I don't
have tolerance for this kind of thing
okay I'm gonna try so Oh Jeff I think
you got some ingredients wrong in this
potion I don't even I don't even think
it works I don't see it in my list just
be two from the beacon oh dude what did
you do how how could you get it this
round it when you put ink sacs inin or
something this is terrible this is like
ah this is like this is like alpha gone
wrong that's what this is dude this is
not up to par I could go I think I could
go either way Jeff I could go either way
I'm sorta tempted to kick you out right
now
I'll give you one more shot while two
more shots I guess keep my word I'm
gonna try it all of these but yeah you
gotta say I'm gonna let you go let's try
out Justin was this night potion all
right give you another chance
oh whoa Oh Jeff no no no you did not
make this one right either I don't think
I would actually came up though but no
no no no this I can't live like this
whoa all right guys what do you think I
think Jeff is out of here to be honest
yeah this is not a potion I would want
to try in the future this is nuts
this isn't good this isn't good not good
for Jeff Jeff look man I know you're
trying to get out of here because it's
not looking good for you but I'm going
to give you one last shot here even
though implant a firing him either way
but I'm going to give him one last shot
Jeff alright invisibility potion that
better be good okay
Oh where'd he go oh man he took off this
is not a good invisibility potion he he
put some extra gold nuggets in this one
or something ah
how did he I think I've been drugged
this I know I've been drugged these
potions they're not good potions oh man
how long is this gonna last oh man um I
think I'm invisible it's hard to tell I
think Jeff is out of here guys
what do you think I I need a new
employee definitely yeah so we took a
little break from working on Wilson
today we'll probably do a little bit
more on him next episode uh just not
because I didn't want to work on them
today just want a little more variety do
something different for a change
oh yeah there's not a ton no well yeah I
guess there's quite a bit of work left
to do that I think of it it's a big
project I've actually thought of what I
want to do after after we finish this
one another redstone project that's
going to be pretty cool if it works out
I'm kind of excited to start it but
we'll finish Wilson first but the
comment I picked out for today
someone said don't do HD videos because
my internet is bad and then I wouldn't
be able to watch you keep up the good
work thank you thank you now yeah you
can change your you can change your
quality you can select 360p or 480p or
or even 240p if your Internet's really
bad and also I'm not sure if everybody
knows this but if you go to your account
settings on YouTube you can actually
select what video quality you want to
load on default like if you want 720 to
always load and select that or if you
want 360 Jeff I don't know where that
boy is but he's been you've been messing
up my grass over here - it'll fix it by
real log though I hope not sure what's
causing it or how Jeff is doing it I
mean yet also yet with HD videos I say
I'm going to do them might not be on
every single episode like if it's over
30 minutes I might choose to do 480
because otherwise it could be and it
tough to do yeah alright well thank you
for watching guys I hope you enjoyed
today's episode and I will let's dress
up again
much much less like I got to say it's
pretty good I'm happy all right thanks
for watching have a good day