[Music]
oh we're recording hello everybody this
is etho
and welcome back guys to another episode
uh so it's been a while since
uh 1.7.4 has come out and now
the mojang team are back to the snapshot
thing and usually the first snapshot
they release after a long time is just
awesome
because they've had like a month or
longer to work on all these cool little
features
and i am not disappointed this new
snapshot that came out as you've
probably seen is just awesome
it is really cool i'm having a lot of
fun with it you can see i got my bouncy
pad all around me
let's have a little fun shall we oh i
need a sword
any sword oh okay i don't need a sword
oh man that was
cooler than i even expected yeah so we
got new blocks
we got these slime blocks that are
bouncy very cool
very unique properties to them um
you can break them really easy
and is this is this really cool guys
that's all i can say that's it period so
these slime blocks
to begin with it's an awesome way to
store slime like if you got a lot of
slime balls around which i happen to
have or
i did have in my world i had like um
three or four double chests full of
slime balls and now i condensed them all
down into less than
or like into one chest so that's that's
pretty cool so it takes nine
slime balls uh in the grid
i don't know if i'm going to show all
the recipes today i'm sure you guys know
about it already
the snapshot's been out for a while but
you can make these slime
slime blocks just like this i'm curious
like i feel like they need to add a
magma cream block now like
i don't know what what it would do
though has to do something with physics
so like like these do
but to complete the set you know we need
we need like a
a fire block of some sort we do have
fire
i don't know uh yeah
these things are bouncy um
i think i think uh you can't bounce
higher
on it than than your initial bounce it
gets cut in half or something
i'm not exactly sure what it is you can
see as you walk on it
things are pretty slow um
this is also a really unique block
because oops
it is semi-transparent has like several
layers of transparency
throughout it we got the little cube
inside and the big cube on
on the outside i think this is going to
be used for building a lot too not just
for like this physics
fun with physics thing i think it is a
good block all around like it looks
pretty neat
um and it has a few other unique
qualities to it as well
yeah actually i wanted to check do i
have torches on me i do not have torches
on me
darn it i'm pretty sure it lets light
through
um here where can we get a torch
where can we get a torch how do i not
have a single torch anywhere uh
and cut and resume i got a torch
so i could have used sunlight but i want
to check something specifically here
which is this i think easier to do
without the sun
so pretty sure it's translucent
yeah it lets light through it's still
light in here that's good uh what i was
wondering is
if it cuts the lighting down uh in
in level at all like kind of like water
does so let's just check
the torch should be 14 slime block would
be 13
12 at our feet and 11 at our head
and block light says 11 so it doesn't
reduce the light level at all
so that's good to know
and this block
behaves like a solid block which is a
weird thing so
this is the only block in the game that
does this look at the mobs
oh man this stuff is slower than slow
sand even
oh you feeling my cannon dude um
yeah so you can use this with redstone
and stuff you can put tracks on this
you can it behaves exactly like
any normal block except it lets light
through which is the only block in the
game that does that
like if you if you do the staircase
thing
like that and then you put one over top
it cuts it um
so that's that's important to know um
[Music]
let's do one more launch i wanna do one
more launch
uh there's also new stone blocks in the
game
which look pretty good i especially like
one of them
um well like one of the sets i think is
the real king of the the three
oh here let's do the sword this time
[Music]
oh yeah it just keeps going
you know what i didn't check if if it
bounces downward i don't think it
would that might be worth checking
actually
one sec okay so i placed a little
stopper
above uh the tnt launcher there oh hey
look how uh look how transparent they
are though like when you compare it next
to this
the snowflake when it passes through you
can still see the snowflake pretty
clearly through them
that's pretty cool
i think we can launch before they hit us
i don't think this is gonna work
just to let you know oh whoa whoa okay
i missed he did hit us
multi-layer can we get back up oh we
almost need to back up
probably shouldn't be recording ouch
at night here one sec
i'm gonna reset the cannon
oh hey check this out i wanted to tell
you guys this too mobs can
spawn on top of these slime blocks in
case you're wondering
i was kind of hoping they wouldn't
because it is a little bit of a weird
block
uh with it being translucent and whatnot
and it would have been really awesome if
they didn't spot on it because then you
could have
uh tracks on these things that zombie
pigmen couldn't spawn on
you know but but they do spawn on them
so keep that in mind
in case you were wondering i'm a little
worried this arrow
is gonna light my tnt
it's a flame arrow okay we're good
so probably just gonna
stop yeah i don't think that bounced
we that's kind of hard to tell though
i don't think it bounced i think it's
just like hitting any other block
uh all right enough with the bouncy
blocks
all right maybe we're not done talking
about them just yet they're they're just
so amazing aren't they like look
look at that even when i'm holding in my
hand you can see the tree through it
it's
it's so transparent so cool uh i noticed
so it's very similar
in color to forest biome grass
so i might be using this in the man cave
a little bit
i had an idea of maybe
switching this out and just see what
this looks like
no never mind never mind
it was worth a shot um it is very
similar to the grass color though
so it might be used in a few places
uh i just give a little more variety so
not only do we have the slime blocks but
there's been a couple other changes
a couple new blocks there's new
enchanting
which is i haven't looked at at all yet
not in creative or anything yet
so i might play around with that a
little bit today
okay but new recipes new recipes what am
i looking for i want some of this stuff
and some of this stuff and
what else do we need we need slabs don't
we some of these
and the vines
fine fine spines oh i do have some here
good good thing i made that vine farm
guys
that was foresight i tell you so the new
crafting recipe got got a few new ones
to remember
diorite is one of the new blocks
you can make polished forms of all the
new ones by
doing the two by two as i'm sure you're
probably well aware by now
but it's worth going over again um
you can make granites if you add more
quartz
and you can do the polished granite if
you do the two by two
yeah we got too much stuff in our
inventory uh but
if you add cobble you can get what was
it and
endocyte andesite i think that's what
it's called andesite
this is my new this is not my new
favorite
it might be my new favorite block but
this is my favorite of all the blocks
added except maybe the slime block it's
hard to say
and the polished these two are going to
be used a lot i can tell you that
already
because they go very well with stone
and cobble and all that and look really
good on their own
just period you know where can we set up
let's make a wall right here um
that's what they look like and you can
put the polished on
i think it behaves just like stone i
think this is just a
different damage value for the stone i
tried it out in creative silverfish
will enter these blocks as well by the
way
and they convert to the regular stone
texture when that happens it turns into
the stone
silverfish blocks but yeah these look
really really good they go well with
cobble um
like this is this is so similar these
two but
varied it looks good uh gravel
do i have any gravel this this looks
really good with gravel this block
here let's let's get these down too i
know i'm playing favorites
but uh these look good with just like
hard and clay and stuff
i found and uh
if you mix these up
here let's let's make a little
randomness into this if you mix them up
like this
looks really cool too it looks like uh
because of this sharp border around it
the edges it looks like
these panels are sticking out a little
bit and these ones are indented
has like a 3d effect almost in my
opinion
but i don't know it looks like you make
really cool walls with this stuff
especially when you combine it with
other blocks it looks really good
oops um
the the diorite i'm not
so sure about this stuff i think it
would look good from a distance but up
close it's almost
too harsh i find
i don't know i think of the three it's
my least favorite
to be honest here let's make some more
uh and you can find this stuff in new
new generation by the way uh if you go
to new generation
it shouldn't like cause uh terrain
borders
uh so you don't have to worry about that
it'll just be
in addition to the usual terrain you'll
have this stuff
showing up in pockets every so often
underground
yeah this stuff i don't know i'm sure
there's a lot of blocks that go well
with it i think like dark wood
or birch wood even would look well
i'm not so sure about this stuff it's
cool though
what i found guys oh
that's not good
okay well i kind of confirmed something
i was wondering about today
hey hey come on
come on oh that looks weird
oh oh
oh everything's burning
i think he's i think he's a goner can
you figure out how to get out of there
this burnt down too
oh man whoa whoa no teamwork
so i saw earlier
i thought that was a slime for a second
like how why is his head down
i saw earlier
he's cool this burnt i'm guessing from
that
um oh hey hey
you're starting to become a nuisance uh
but i didn't see this
thing burnt so fire has
changed it looks like i don't know if
that's going to be permanent or not
but it's spreading a lot further than it
used to
and it looks like a lot of stuff burnt
down actually
oh man
and oh he's burning what
anyway oh
man i'm not too happy about that fire
spread change i hope that's not
intentional because a lot of stuff is
catching fire
uh i fix some of it using the wood the
the old wood slabs that don't burn
so hopefully that's that prevents some
of it but uh
if it is intentional i'm gonna have to
redesign a few areas i think
uh but yeah these are the new blocks
guys and they look
pretty good i like them i think it's a
good change um
it's nice to get new blocks every now
and then in the game and
they go pretty good together too i i
didn't notice this until i put them side
by side
but these two are really good together
uh even these two are okay
although they're a different color like
quite a bit but
they all share a similar texture
and they added they added
crafting recipes for some other blocks
that we could only get in creative or
very rarely from
from the stronghold and from jungle
temples
you could get chiseled stone bricks
i'm really glad they added this these
crafting recipes
other people not so happy from what i've
seen
um some people like the idea of these
being
like rare sort of trophy blocks
uh let's see what's the other one i
think it's
oh it's mossy oh you know what i don't
have the stone brick on me
uh yeah some people aren't too happy
about them not being so rare anymore
which i like the idea of there being
rare stuff in this game like when you go
find a dungeon or something that you get
something nobody else has and you have
writing rights or maybe it does
something cool or is unique in some way
i don't think it should be blocks though
honestly especially not
these blocks uh what am i looking for
what am i looking for
uh because these are stone this is just
like stone guys come on
these are basic building blocks they're
they're
dull they're not like fancy they don't
look like emerald blocks or anything
like they're not
uh super fancy blocks they're just
regular old
um building blocks that people want to
use i think and
i don't like the idea of there being
stuff in creative mode that you can't
access
in survival because that just makes
people want to play creative mode
instead
or it makes me prefer
like it's one other thing that creative
mode heads has over top of survival um
which you know i'd rather play survival
and have the same features available
but yeah you can make the mossy i
haven't seen a cracked
uh stone brick recipe which i find a
little strange to
include that either although people may
have not found it yet
but i'm really glad you make those now
so if you're like me you're probably
wondering
if this works uh it would be really
amazing
if the mine carts bounce when you're in
them and you can like
bounce onto a track uh far away
let's let's give it a shot here
oh nope no bounce oh
too bad uh didn't take any fall damage
joe
with that fall i wonder if here let's
try that one more time with the track
down here
see if we can snap to the track with no
fall damage
because this is one two three
four that's definitely fall it's
definitely far enough
where you should take fall damage
and they may have had added a silverfish
chiseled
stone brick i saw that today in creative
mode
that might have been in the game before
and i just didn't notice it but
there's definitely a chiseled uh
silverfish block
which may have just been added all right
fall damage
no fall damage okay that's kind of cool
so you can
can drop onto a tr attract and take no
fall damage doing it that way
um here let's try uh horses
do they bounce they probably don't if
the the mine carts don't
oh no wait wait wait just a sec just sec
seconds that's right slow down
slow down take it nice and easy
all right i can't remember if this guy
can jump
oh he does bounce
oh that is cool okay we got bouncy
horses at least i like that
all the more reason why you should ride
a horse instead of using mine carts
nowadays
all right i got to do a high dive with
this guy now
uh this guy he can't jump at all guys he
does two blocks
two boxes is max and he was very tough
to get up here on this mountain
uh you can see i set up a bounce pad
down there that's our targets we're
gonna do an a
very graceful swan dive
off the mountain here hit the bounce pad
do a graceful 9.0 at least
somersaults and
and win the olympics or something okay
here we go
oh i can't see it i can't see i can't
see
all right
jump failed uh still still an 8.0 at
least come on
i think that was uh decent
now that was pretty bad so yeah they
bounce they bounce off the
pads that's pretty cool
we're okay we're all good okay uh so
i'm at the ender ender 2.0 here guys
there's one more thing we should check
out today and that is the enchanting
because jeb has reworked the enchanting
system at least i'm pretty sure it was
jeb
uh and it looks pretty interesting
not exactly sure how it works at the
moment i know you
can kind of get a hint about what you're
gonna get uh
it says protection three dot dot dot
question mark so
i think we're for sure gonna get
protection three if we do this enchant
and there's also a cost now the one two
three costs one two or three
lapis i believe um
so i looked in my enchanting tables
around my world they all say the same
thing they all have the same
enchantments available so it seems to be
worldwide i've tried
moving the enchanting tables around in
different spots too and that doesn't
change anything
so it seems to be a worldwide thing that
doesn't change until you enchant
something
uh let's let's get a few tools going
here too because i
think where did i hide it there it is
it's like where's the crafting table i
know i have one here
um let's do a pick
yeah let's try a pick and a sword i
guess because we're probably gonna get a
different
uh trade here right because you can't
put protection three
on a sword so it should say
okay so there's fire aspect for that
efficiency three
oh one breaking three efficiency two
very interesting okay and
another thing that changed is i believe
uh repairing tools has gotten a whole
lot cheaper like ridiculously cheap
i hope it's not too late see looting
three books
yeah i can't do it looting three is a
very expensive enchantment so it's it
it's way too late to put that on this
thing um
but now we can get like crazy tools in
this game
and actually repair them um
because it's a lot cheaper now
let's see so just let's try to do a
trade here
looking at this honestly compared to
efficiency three and unbreaking three i
would rather have unbreaking three on a
pick
so let's do that because i can upgrade
that
to a work pick pretty nicely
if i get efficiency books efficiency
five
and it's cheaper so let's do it that way
we're gonna get a bad second enchant if
there is one
two enchantment levels one enchantment
level
what's that about oh so they did do that
see i thought they weren't gonna
actually do that because it seemed
really powerful
it only cost two enchanting levels we're
at 16 now it went from 18 to 16.
and we got efficient three on breaking
three so touch
one holy smokes
well if that is not the easiest
enchanting i've ever seen
wow i thought it was going to take away
all the levels
because i did not think they were going
to go through with with that feature
or that change the next one efficiency
one unbreaking one
wait a minute level six
why does this only go up to level six
now
nope and breaking three okay that looks
promising
aspect the fire aspect is still the
trade
or is still the enchantment for the
sword
huh
oh i see something i like
let's get that let's see
let's let's try out the farm dude please
tell me at my flame bow here very good
oh that has yeah it has flame on it we
don't even need it
all right let's get some levels guys
oh yeah haven't been using this farm as
much since i got the
gold farm honestly but it's still pretty
good
pretty good should take us close to 30.
here let's go kill a few guys though i
think we'll need a few levels
silk touch book so that's pretty crazy
you can see what you're gonna get but it
doesn't look like you can actually
change what you're gonna get so it's
just a matter of time before you
you pick that thing although uh
don't take my word for it because i'm
just it's my first time trying it like i
said
uh i'm gonna look into it more later
obviously
all right 30 levels 30 levels i want
that silk touch book
oh man yeah i think i like the gold farm
more
i should have just did tnt again oh
don't
don't fall into the void
all right so cost three let's see what
happens the level so this is six and six
and 30.
let's see if we lose the 30 if we do
this three enchantment levels
okay so we went down to 27.
next book we put in
aqua affinity huh
see that seems that seems really
overpowered can we get a level in 30
enchant
for just three more levels
to me that sounds crazy
like enchanting was already easy in this
game that just makes it
like wow
um all right let's try this out
one two three and lapis is obviously
very abundant
here we go aqua affinity power four next
one what's it gonna be
knock back two this one up to nine again
efficiency three unbreaking two
unbreaking three that's a good sword
enchant let's get that
dope let's try that again
and back up
although it's only three levels what am
i doing here
some reason i thought i needed another
30.
all right might be my imagination but
the xp seems a lot slower
or is it not getting down here
must not have been getting down here
there it goes
okay oh just done breaking it's fine
um okay
yeah we only gained three levels from
that what is that about
so they must they must have changed how
long it takes
to level up now how much xp it takes
right
uh-huh i'm going to do some enchanting
off-camera here just to get a hang of it
a little better
because this is all very foreign to me
let's do one more together though
let's see two wow sick clutch
let's go for silk touch
three levels
okay next one
oh unbreaking three i want that on a
book for sure
all right so i'm gonna do some
off-camera be right back
okay i've done a few enchantments off
camera here and it definitely seems
uh takes more xp to jump the levels now
uh because
i used to go from like 20 to 30 with a
blast from the tnt in here
now i get like three or four levels only
so that's a big difference
but i think that is definitely fair that
they made it
cost more and it looks like you can
bypass
trades if you don't or not trades bypass
enchantments if you don't like them
like uh i don't want luck of the c2 for
for the 30. that's pretty crummy uh
for the sword sharpness three yeah it's
kind of crummy
the pick that's pretty good silk touch
three i will take that
okay now this has changed
we got looting two available so it it
skipped
that uh trade i didn't want so that is
good that does that
um sword becomes something crummy
uh i'll probably go for the looting two
there got a few good things already
actually
it's uh it's a pretty good uh
system now looting three uh
i got some good picks and
unbreaking books i love unbreaking books
it's one of my favorite things looting
and unbreaking are both very good
but anyway just wanted to take a quick
look at the enchanting because i had
hadn't done that earlier today
and that brings us to the comment
section of our episode everybody so
here we go lots of responses about the
new computer thank you everybody
especially a lot of people trying to
help with the fan situation
and suggesting that i check out the bios
was a common theme
so here we go the first first comment
the so-called higher priority
is the bios having an option for the fan
to be always on
i'm not sure if it will do it for your
graphics gpu fan
but it should definitely override all of
the others in your computer
it might do the trick so yeah one of the
things i did check out was the bios
on my computer and there's options for
controlling the cpu fan
in in the bios but not the gpu fan which
is what i'm having trouble with
there's no controls there
so unfortunately that's not the fix and
i've tried reseeding
my graphics cards that is not the fix
either there wasn't like a loose cable
or something
um yeah it's just a very weird situation
some people have said it might just be a
defective graphics card or fan
which i i'm starting to think that might
be true
so i might have to get it checked out
but
as is right now it's working uh second
question
or second comment etho what would you do
if mojing added
onions to minecraft i would
cry because onions are nasty gross
vile we're out of snowballs
disgusting overpowering
terrible pieces of fake food
that people put in food and call it food
they're just bad and nobody should eat
them
hey etho just wondering what is your
internet speed i'm sure some of us would
like to know
that's our third third one uh
i get 5.8
download and 0.8 upload
and usually about 80 to 100 ping
on a us server is pretty normal for me
but it works out okay anyway that's it
for today's episode guys i just wanted
to check out the snapshot today i was
all
excited because it just came out
gotta refill the snowballs really really
like the new features i
i am happy with the snapshot except for
the fire spread
don't like the fire spread too much
hopefully that changes
uh but i hope you guys enjoyed today's
episode once again and i will catch you
again
i did it again i said catch you catch
you what does that mean
i'm gonna catch you i'm gonna grab you
and force you to watch my episode next
time
that's a good idea uh anyway thanks for
watching guys
see you again next time bye
you