[Music]
hello
how's it going everyone this is etho and
welcome back to another episode of our
let's play
series so to begin with here guys i
thought i'd show you an
idea this is a failed idea one of those
things i just haven't been able to get
working
um maybe you guys have an idea how to
make this work but basically
you remember some of you probably seen
my first season of terra firma craft you
remember that one episode where i
dropped the gobble stone on the cow
crushed it and then the meat went flying
everywheres
ever since then in the back of my mind
i've wanted to make a
a towel farm in vanilla minecraft where
we drop an anvil on
on the cows and then the meat starts
flying everywhere i thought that would
be a cool thing
but i haven't been able to automate it
like i haven't been able to find a way
to like reuse the anvils they always
break there's an issue with them because
as you know if you drop an anvil
it takes damage and eventually it's
gonna break right
so there's a way around that if you drop
it on a fence post like it is right now
it stays in its falling sand
uh entity mode so you check this out you
can actually launch it
and if it lands on the fence post again
it doesn't
break right it doesn't take any damage
and if you stand underneath here like if
you're a cow
you'll get whacked it'll actually do do
damage so that's good
the problem is which you'll see very
soon here
there we go after a certain amount of
falling
falling sand entities or falling anvils
eventually do just break
they turn into their item form which
kind of sucks
um this started off as a
as a slightly damaged and built now it's
a very damaged anvil as well
even though it never landed on it
anything it took damage
so it's kind of an interesting thing
here like an anvil will lose durability
doing this
but it won't ever totally break like
this very damaged anvil won't
disappear on us it'll turn to its item
form
once it's a falling sand entity for a
long time like this has been sitting
here so as soon as we try to
to bounce it up it's gonna break again
right so it turns it back to its item
form
it doesn't destroy the anvil but there's
no way to automatically place it back in
the world at the end so that's why i
haven't been able to automate
this sort of killing device maybe you
guys have an idea of how to
i have no clue though i haven't been
able to figure it out
now if you catch the anvil gently
like let's say we we stop it at the very
top of the arc there
and we put a block underneath it to turn
it back to its block form
that's no no bueno that doesn't work
either that will destroy the anvil
because it seems to calculate how long
it's been falling for
and then it applies all that damage even
if it's not moving very fast when it
hits
hits the ground and uh here's how it
works in case you're curious it's a
simple thing
sticky piston sticky piston the anvil
sits
on top of this fence post right and then
it moves it to the right
and then up so the slime block goes
underneath the anvil
and then it moves it upwards as the
anvil is falling down and that's what
balances it
okay guys so let's take a look here at
our big book
of never finishing projects uh we are
getting a few of these done
but number 17 on the list we have the
simon game that's what we're gonna work
on here today we're gonna do some
redstone stuff
try get that done if we can um every
project we get done on there
is a new one i can start and not finish
and not feel guilty
so we wanna get as many of those done as
we can
but yeah last episode we checked out
that new memory system
and a lot of you were excited about it i
just showed it off i didn't actually do
anything with it
today we're going to actually do
something with it we're going to use it
to try uh finish this game and make it
better
so let's let's start with the
demonstration i think it still works
maybe blue let's just try random
pressure plates here
i think it's waiting for input right now
okay it was green next one is blue
i don't know why it's telling us the
answer okay then there's a
pause and now is it going to run through
the sequence
yeah okay here we go yellow
green notice how slow this is guys the
the timing between these is very long
after we redo the memory here today this
should be like
hopefully but that was
like one of the big reasons why this
game was kind of
terrible and i didn't really want to
finish it the way it was
um the other thing
oh man this gives me nightmares coming
back here again
uh the other thing is this was the old
memory system over here you see these
hoppers and the droppers
um the way this was working each one of
these
held an entry so we got blue over there
yellow green we could only have like one
every every hopper dropper combo here so
if we wanted to store like 40 answers we
would need 40 droppers
and hoppers paired together here so this
was not even close to complete this was
going to get a lot bigger
and a lot slower
so the good news is we are done with all
this stuff
we're going to switch over to a binary
system
using that hard drive sort of thing we
figured out
before we were using item filters you
see how it was detecting the clay blocks
the four different colors after it would
detect those
it would save save the answer to memory
over here
the redstone block would move over and
then
that would connect up to the display or
else it would check if it matched
our input depending on if it was showing
us
the sequence or if it was waiting for
our input
um so yeah anyways blah blah blah blah
blah
guess what we gonna do here rip it all
out
oh yes start fresh make it better
let's clean this baby up i think we rip
out everything pretty much
uh from like here to the left
can go everything up here is for the
display that can all stay
everything to the right here is for the
inputs we can leave that
but most of this needs to be redone over
here
and a lot of this was just like timings
to control
the the memory device here which we're
redoing so
yeah let's tear it out
whoo all right well look at that we have
a lot of free space here now
a lot of a lot of work to do to get this
uh
working again uh but i left it off over
here this is where we're gonna start
uh this connects directly to the display
stuff up there so if we press the red
one
you can see the red clay blocks pop out
of the screen
we're on the back side of course so it
doesn't look right but
yeah green blocks up there so now uh we
want to connect our display to our
memory
uh device but before we do that we
probably want to
add some way of controlling it because
when we're putting the input into the
game when we're giving our answers
to copy the sequence we don't want the
display
showing what the memory says there's
like two game modes
to this game it first it shows us the
answers and then it waits for us to
to input the answers right so we want to
shut the display off during the input
so to do that we're just going to have
some sticky pistons
running along here when the clay block
is down
the display will be active when it's up
it'll be off
okay so we're already off to a bad start
here i think this is a redstone bug
for some reason the red one is staying
down
no idea why it's not being powered right
now right
but when you update it
yeah something really wonky is going on
why did this have to happen to me
uh i guess we'll have to do it like this
i got a wavy line going over top
i don't like that it takes up more space
but uh
at least it works right i think what was
happening for some reason
this block was unpowering first right
and then this one was still powered so
it was
diagonally powering the piston causing
it to bud
even though the redstone wire was all
supposed to unpower at the same time
don't ever recall that being an issue in
mine graph but it is now apparently
all right so let's say for example in
memory it's showing the
it should be red right on the display
then
if we want to display that
press a button we can control how long
it shows up on the on the screen by how
long this is powered
or if this is during the input sequence
we don't have to display it on the
screen we have the option
so that's cool uh next thing we got to
do here is uh
again connect this to the memory so
we're using a binary system you know
zeros and ones
problem is zero and one that's only two
possibilities two outcomes
we need four in total here red blue
yellow green
so we're gonna have to combine two bits
together to
create four outcomes okay
now to do that isn't so simple
because we need to build a binary
decoder
um which i've made in creative already
so i'm just gonna build it here and
show it to you how it works and here it
is guys so check it out this is my
two-bit decoder
pay attention we have four redstone
torches down there and we have two wires
up here so this
device takes the information from these
two wires the on
off information and converts it to four
unique
outputs okay so right now it's off off
and that the green one's on right now if
we
do this off on we have the yellow one on
if we do on off we have the blue one
and on on is the red one
so that's that's the key it it splits it
into four outputs we can use very easily
with our display
hmm all right a little bit later here
guys i've been uh pulling my hair out
trying to get this thing working
and this is about as fast as i think i
can get it to work
which i would like it a little bit
quicker honestly but
it's not terrible terrible it's way
better than it was
let's hop down here we'll try to speed
it up a bit more and just see what
happens
alright so notice uh
notice the lights over there as soon as
they settle
these piston arms go down yellow
green you see how the blue kind of
flashed there
but that would that didn't affect it
because the piston arms weren't down
during that flash so it's only
once it settles that it actually sends
the information to the display
uh let's go ahead though and take one
item out of here
and it probably broke everything now
right
let's go look it it doesn't look like
it's good though
all right what's the display doing now
it's broken yep
some sometimes uh green and red were
activating at the same time there
yeah so it's too fast for it well
i tell you what guys i've kind of had
enough of this uh for today here
i i wanted to try finish it but i know
it's gonna take me many more hours so
i think we should uh call it here on
this and move on to something else
i'll just show you what we did uh so far
here though we made good progress
we got our tube our two-bit decoder here
like
like we set up before and now we have
the binary readers set up we have two of
them
we're using a brewing stand method now
instead of the water bucket thing i
showed originally
in the last video this was your guys's
suggestion and it works great
it's a really good idea you also
suggested using named items which you
could do
but this method you don't have to name
anything so i like it a lot
so if you have a non-stackable item like
a shovel in here
this is a zero in our binary reader
and we activate the dropper nothing
happens it stays in the dropper but if
it's a water bottle
or some other brewing item it goes into
the brewing stand
so that's that's our one and you can see
here
i fall down darn it
oh seriously
come on i'm like sliding off that block
you see that i'm hitting the block and
then i'm like sliding off of it somehow
there we go oh man one ender pearl left
to go
restock here so yeah we have a zero and
one
in our reader right now uh this is our
data stream in this chest
and as it goes through we kind of have
to prevent
it from re-entering here so i'm storing
them up here
until this chest empties so if we press
this
it'll advance it forward by one and we
have a one
one and this connects directly to our
two bit decoder so it's actually
outputting a signal here so it's on the
red right now
um we've got one item left here
activated again and we have a zero zero
this time so
that is the green and yeah it works
pretty good
um you can see the items are still in in
the dropper or in the brewing stand here
though
right and i have a comparator signal
here
for both of them which we merge together
and that goes up to this hopper here
which is locked
until this uh the dropper and the
brewing stand are both empty and we're
at the end of the cycle
so next time we press this these items
should start flowing back into here
and preserve the order
or is it one more oh we had one more
item in there i forgot
okay so this time we have a one one red
again
okay activate it one more time
and you can see they start flowing in
so i kind of want to do a little bit
more building here today
last episode we worked on the pyramid
here came up with a design for it
and uh the word is in nobody likes it
a lot of you said it was the worst thing
i've ever built
okay i can take it i didn't take it guys
uh yeah it does have its flaws for sure
got some good critique on it uh too many
holes
kind of expected that's um too much too
much detail for
like as you get farther away from a
build you you need less detail right
and this is like like a close-up build
and like from this distance sure it
looks good
the way it is but from this distance no
no no
so we'll try to remove some of the
detail there's also nothing for the eye
to focus on which is another
issue um a lot of you said we should add
a golden beacon at the top i like that
idea we'll do that
and yeah we'll get to it in just a
second here i want to show you this
though
i put some trod and dirt under or or
path blocks they're called
under the cactus here i think that's a
cool thing right
and then i tried putting it against the
wall here this might be a good thing for
us to include in the sandy city
wanted to uh mess with that a little bit
my big
issue with like sand builds like this
is uh it's hard to mix in other types of
blocks and it's all
all yellow you know there's not enough
variation to it
um a lot of people will mix in blue and
oranges
i don't like that very much so to be
honest personally
but i kind of like this it's a brown
block so maybe in places we'll
we'll try it out here so i'm going to
put some down maybe over here
and see what that's like just mix it in
along the wall and stuff too
probably that needs to be changed
that yeah just doing little things like
that in places i think will help
this place look a lot better okay very
cool very cool let's take a little walk
around here
so i added in some patches of this path
block
around sandy city here just in places
not too much
just to get a feel for it see what you
guys have to say about it
i like it in the sense that it uh breaks
up the ground it adds another color to
it
so it's not all one big glob of the same
thing
but uh i don't know if this is really
really the way to do it
the patches i also tried another thing
here where i just like
put it all along the wall because one
problem is our wall color is the same as
the ground color right
so there's no real separation
like when you look over over there for
example the ground and the wall
it's almost hard to tell the difference
but if you have a separation material
like this it might
be a good idea see what you guys have to
say about that
anyways uh another thing we did the
sombrero cactus last time you guys liked
it
uh one idea was though to change the
birchwood to a spruce wood so we'll do
that as well
just so that we're not using all this
yellow color you know the more we can
change up the colors around here the
better because it's all pretty
pretty similar yeah i like that more for
sure
anyways onto the pyramid here so it
would be great if we could mix in
another type of block but
i really have trouble finding one i like
i know everyone says water and lapis and
orange sand and all that
they just stand out so much if that was
an aqua blue it would look great
but it's a deep blue and that's like a
really bright orange if it was more of a
brownish orange it would look great but
it's not
how about let's try to get rid of some
of these holes just to begin with here
i'm thinking we do something like this
we bring it out or bring it forward one
block
and then we alternate uh stairs and
blocks
maybe would look good we'll try it
we'll try it and then we'll bring also
the spiky part of the wall forward a
block
oh we did that one already okay let's
hop down check it out
okay i think it's better right it's
better
it needs more variation notes it's like
a straight line
uh maybe at this midpoint we change it
up a little bit more
do it like that okay now let's hop down
it's gonna have to make a little
adjustments yeah that's better
okay we're making more improvements do
we even need that many notches maybe we
don't
because i'm worried it's going to create
that whole effect again
if we have too many of those if we uh
if we do more of an arch instead like if
that's a stair
and this is a stair
it'll be a little bit smoother that way
okay a little bit weird because we have
that arch
there it looks like it's offset now
right
so i redid the second layer there now
and i think it looks a lot better
right still might need a few more
adjustments but it's an improvement i
think
i'm going to try to widen those arches
that
inside one there to match more of the
outside
shape uh i centered them which helps a
lot but i think
if we made it wider it might look cool
too
you know what we have a little bit of a
hard call here now because i did that
and i think it looks worse maybe because
we only did the two
and it'll look better once we change
more of the pyramid but i think i'm just
going to go back to
the the thinner ones right
all right so we went back to the thinner
arches again
i've kind of gone through the whole
pyramid now with with some of these
changes
i've also added birch leaves at every
layer which help
to add to the separation between the
layers i think
um still a lot of holes is it too many
still
i'm not sure i kind of liked having the
bottom with all the holes
and then the other layers they're broken
up quite a bit more
and you can see there's a bit of a
pattern to it how it does a triangle
and then we have that tower there in the
middle and over there i think we should
get rid of that and maybe put in an
entrance like an arch archway entrance
would look cool
yeah okay if we make a entrance to the
pyramid over here there is actually a
little bit of space here we could
build inside so that's good i think what
i'm going to try to do is build it out
of dark oak
like so we'll take up the space of the
the tower we ripped out
put another one over here and then we'll
start arching this
uh together and just see what that looks
like uh
we might need to oh actually that's
that's getting pretty tall these layers
are pretty cramped together
not the best design um
i don't know about this well we'll try
it out we'll try it out
okay and then i just let's just do this
right now just to see what that would
look like from the ground
uh-huh okay let's just try this for
right now
this will be opened up it's gonna look
really funny
i know it already
yep pretty funny yeah i think it's gonna
look better here if we put sandstone in
front of the the wood here
so we'll try that out i'm going to
replace this dark oak with spruce though
that way it's a little bit more of a
continuation and
in front of this we should probably put
some sandstone
okay and i lowered it by one as well
which i think is important because it
was
it was too tall otherwise is it this
isn't necessarily like an entrance into
the building it might just be like
somewhere you come out of the building
to look down on
on the people's uh but we may eventually
put us
a staircase to go down i don't really
want to though because we got the wall
down there and we also have the reed
field there
which i would like to keep
oh that's the floor from the next level
okay let's look now again a lot of like
jumping down and checking it out
i don't know about that should we keep
the wood showing
it does highlight it right another thing
to keep in mind about this pyramid by
the way it looks
not so great from the angle we've been
viewing it from
if we're flying let's see if we can take
off here
actually i'll just i'll just under pearl
up it's easier
yeah if we're flying this pyramid is
going to look a lot better if we're up
from some higher ground because the
layers separate a lot better
like if you look down from this angle i
think it looks a lot lot better
or if you fly by it like that then if
we're looking straight on it
at it from here
all right guys we're gonna wrap up the
episode here for today here is the
comment i picked out which is very
suiting
it says if you hate desert themes why
did you choose to build there in modded
that's that's what i knew for sure
i thought with all the new block types
maybe i i could pull it off in modded
but uh
i don't know i struggle with it here's
my thing like sometimes you build
and it just looks good right i love it
when that happens
but sometimes you have to try like five
ten
twenty different things i think i've
redone this pyramid at least ten times
now guys if you
like some of them i did off camera even
um
this is time number ten you'll have to
let me know
i would just i would be happy with it
just being acceptable
you know at this point i'm not even
looking for good i'm just looking for
acceptable but
if people are telling me it's the worst
thing i've ever built i have to keep
trying
so we'll see after today's episode if i
can
if i can pass on it now
well i try it again anyways so uh let me
know what you guys think hopefully you
enjoyed today's episode if you have any
ideas
feel free to leave them and i'll see you
again in the next one
take care bye bye