oh yeah something good something good
something good Oh another one of those
here we go again
oh man there's like 300 it's still going
and another 250 or so beautiful and no
something better good this is going to
be our last try let's hope it's a good
one finally
yes very good well hello everybody this
is etho thank you for joining me again
and you know what you guys you guys do
not make things easy for me I was going
through the comments of last episode we
were planning how what blocks were going
to use for the storage room and
everybody said something different
dang it as opening would be like 100
percent of people say that one thing but
that never happens a lot of people I'll
go through the popular suggestions a lot
of people said I should do the wood
style that I'm used to because I would
almost like to mimic the old storage
room from the old world do like the
checkered floor pattern with wood stumps
wood logs and what else did I have I had
lots of planks wooden planks and that
and I had a minecart track that went
around the middle that's something I'm
probably going to do either way and
maybe include waters decorations so if I
go that route that's that's what I would
be doing another popular suggestion was
that I keep it winter themed so keep the
snow and include these logs here this is
why I'm harvesting them so we can
compare use that snow
stone slabs and what else
oh yeah wool so mix those all together
to create some kind of theme one guy
said well a few people said that I
should do sandstone with nether brick
highlights and yet another person
another good idea I had was that I do an
industrial theme so similar to what I
did it with the blaze farm on the
minecraft server
I would probably keep that mostly stone
like stone bricks regular stone
cobblestone all mixed together and then
iron bars and lava maybe that would be
another way to go thing is I don't have
a lot of experience with different
building styles so it's going to take me
a lot of practice lots of mistakes are
probably going to be made but we'll go
over to the storage room area and we'll
start putting down blocks and see how
they look together probably won't do a
whole lot of building today this is
mostly going to be planning and I also
want to think out some plans for the
technical systems to the whole project
as well and maybe before we head back
here I'll point out one thing as well if
we do the winter theme I'm want to put
ice on the floor in places because it's
got that awesome ability where you can
move really quickly if you sprint jump
that would be really handy for getting
around quick so if I go the snow routes
that is one benefit to it
uh-huh so I was heading back throw an
ender pearls to get back and I threw one
into this hole rights by the mob system
apparently there's a cave I missed move
right here and it looks fairly big so
I'm going to go through here and light
it up to help out the rates because it
looks like it goes away goes down here
too well they need to be buffed what's
this oh how did I miss this oh wow
keeps going
this is a strange wall aha what is this
and just keeps going how did I miss all
this Oh what do we have here mmm I
cannot believe how much I've missed here
this cave just keeps going I'm going to
have to make several trips oh I'll take
it
actually let's unload don't need a lot
of this stuff oh there's another chest
yeah
here's a little tip for you guys if you
ever are lighting up a mineshaft like
this and you want to make it absolutely
mob proof but use your torches
efficiently quite often you come to
these dead ends you want to place your
torch five blocks from the wall so
that's fourteen thirteen twelve eleven
ten nine eight
still mob proof dope oh boy
I didn't handle that very good perfect
get me can't get me o iron shovel woo a
ravine
bad time to run out of torches
it did water saved me
oh-ho excellent that was a nice fine
that chief I can tell this thing's going
a little bit quicker now but there's
still probably a lot more cave missed I
couldn't find like I found a ravine but
then I couldn't find it again after so I
never got that lit up but I'm guessing
that was one of the last main key areas
I have to light up around here so that
was a that was a huge score right there
and we got one two three stacks iron
from it some of that some of these
pretty good all right guys
sorry about that I got a little
distracted from what we were going to do
today planning so let's let's focus on
planning now we're going to plan some
things out to make make some definite
plans yeah I don't know what to do
no no we'll figure something out I'm
sure yeah so the three main block type
themes that I liked was the winter snow
theme type thing
my usual wood style stuff with the grass
and whatnot
and the industrial I think it would also
be cool so those are the three we'll
focus on with this first of all the
winter theme if we do the winter theme
I'm going to leave these EMP units
pretty much as they are the snow the
glass tubes would get switched with ice
for sure when we can this wood will
become dark wood so we'll just put down
blocks see how they look you're going to
have to use your imagination here use it
do it okay we'll also have like dark
wood half slabs when one-point-three
comes out so let's
probably what we'll use for the crazy
way are those in the game already I'm so
confused stuff keeps changing now
they're not okay I think we will have
the stairs as well so if we got to do
crazy stair stuff that this is probably
what we'll use maybe even the light as
well what else did I want to try these
we might use this stuff mixed with snow
they look pretty good together
I don't know how we would use it exactly
this would be easier to use yeah we do
that we'd probably still use regular
fences over here's a rail so let's just
see how that would look passable okay
fence is there then I probably want to
start outlet outlining stuff with wool
as well so I brought all kinds of colors
of wool here like I would I think I
would want to put a highlight around
these EMP units grab this stuff I want
the Gunpowder dot that make app slab
stand yeah I'd probably put like a one
wide highlight around all this oh yeah
that's that's down below there so I
would either use not really a big pink
fan I do like the dark purple in this
game though I really do it's one of my
favorite wool colors not that I think it
would really go with this though mmm
of course lime green is one of my
favorites
again though it doesn't I don't know I
am I want lots of good feedback from you
guys this time because these are this is
serious it's a serious stuff for dealing
with light blue is a common suggestion
with working with snow because they go
together really well if we do the winter
theme we cannot use sandstone at all
that's something we've learnt in the
past from my old ice base can't use it
not allowed if we go with the winter
theme black black would kind of work
anyway we would have to experiment and
pick different bright wool colors to
highlight things I guess I want this
stuff back let's head back up though
I hope we have mmm I hope I'm just
thinking I hope I don't waste too much
time with this because I wanted to do a
few other things today even though it is
getting a little late here right so we
would probably have a highlight there we
might have one on this side as well and
then in the middle that I think ice
could go with ice that way we can hop
around here real quick that would be
kind of cool um and same with at the
main floor level here I would want ice
going around so I can I can speed jump
all around if we go with the winter
theme so imagine it make it happen in
your head okay could also go with the
regular wood theme that I usually do
which we don't sort of already saw if we
do that I would want to probably use
this kind of wood although we could do
the dark wood as well and these would
get switched with either wooden planks
some color or sandstone I'm not going to
tear them down though just to show that
we would do fences around here we would
also try to mimic the old storage room
if we went with this theme so maybe a
checkered floor water features in the
corners or something just for decoration
like we did before then this ground
would be grass most likely or else would
grass or wood I know I brought something
again I don't want to spend a whole lot
of time with this we would probably
still do a highlight here may it may be
out of wood or something to transition
from the sandstone if we go with
sandstone yeah you get the idea or we
could go with an industrial theme if we
go with the industrial theme maybe real
quick
instead of having wood around here this
would be like maybe stone bricks or
stone this stuff would be iron fences I
don't know what I would do for the
ground probably just a different type of
stone from whatever I use for the border
and whatever I use for the border I will
do the highlight around here with these
EMP units I think I would switch with
iron blocks would be very very expensive
though I hate doing this just see how it
looks
if we do the industrial theme grass
looks pretty good with it - for the
floor here um and then instead of like
using water in that we would probably go
the lava root have lots of lab
everywhere I could be cool again you'll
have to visualize this I'm not going to
change all of them I'm lazy but yeah
those are the three themes so think
about it some more guys give me your
feedback I am very interested in what
you have to say of course in the end of
it it's up to me I'm going to make the
final decision I'm going to check the
time and we'll see what we do beyond
here it looks like I can spare some more
time to ramble on so that's what I'm
going to do the next thing I want to
talk about is how are we going to do our
storage system what I want to do is copy
the old LP storage room method so I had
how did I have that had our theme block
below all right then I had buttons lots
and lots of buttons check ooh
torch so I had I did that then I had
dispensers all along if you want one
item hit dispenser and it gets shot out
very cool then above that I either had
the block type that was in the dispenser
so something like that you know for all
all the different types of blocks if
it's if it was an item that can be
represented with a block you I had a
sign above that said what it was and
then above that I also had displayed to
try to get as close as I could to what
was in it
if it wasn't a full block so I would
like to do that again with this storage
room I really like that the problem I'm
having now is how do I do the extra
storage the reason why I'm so happy
about this still is you can actually
shift click into dispensers now before
you couldn't and that always drove me
crazy so this is this is still a good
thing I think and I love having a block
display for for what's in the storage
unit so I'll do that again but yeah the
way I did before is I had a checker
pattern of chess don't think that's
going to work anymore because they
changed the chest block it's not a full
block anymore it gets sunk in like that
sadly that's the way I did before what
should we do now let's see I don't know
well how high can we reach and reach
that one I think we could reach one more
up yet that's what it looks like yeah
that's a stretch though so three blocks
above our display block we can reach if
we need to mmm I don't want to use
storage minecarts I don't trust them
sometimes your stuff just disappears all
right what we could try to do is maybe
now we can actually staff chess either
have double chests above this is just
first like additional storage beyond the
dispenser because these don't
a whole lot if we do that thing is then
we can't put a chest next to it so we
could either checkered the double chests
like one there then one there one there
one there one there
or we could space this stuff one block
apart from each other and stack them
straight up like that I don't know ah
how do we do it if we go with this
method we might have to do a different
method because mmm actually you know you
don't sink down when you walk on these
do you let's check our why it doesn't
seem like you sink down you still it
still counts as a full block just looks
like less um what else now I'm going to
point this out though this is like a
main room here but it's going to branch
off to other things like farms and my
bedroom and it's also going to branch
off to a warehouse type storage area so
this is just going to be general storage
it's going to have a fair bit of every
item in this room all around but then
there's also going to be another bulk
storage room attached to this that will
have plenty of space for like
cobblestone because I'm sure we'll have
way more than we could ever fit
conveniently in here so this is just to
hold a fair bit of every item so a
double chest or two would be plenty ooh
so that's one thing to think about okay
I've been brainstorming this a little
bit and I thought of a better way of
doing the exact same thing what I could
do is have my display block at the
bottom all right then I could put the
dispenser here if I if I want a
dispenser I might not
I might change my mind and that works
right and I can still access it and fill
it toward order click on it like that so
that's good and then above that I could
have chests all the way so that would
give me two extra spots and behind the
chest I can put lighting so I can keep
it pretty bright that way so one two
three four five up to five chests I
could either do a solid five it would be
overkill probably or while I could also
just do single chests and then that
would only be three or five I mean five
chests which would be about the right
number I would need but we can go as far
back as we want so we may as well do
double chests I think they don't look
quite as good but double the storage is
hard to beat but yeah we can do a
checker pattern up type thing and then
in between ah
maybe like that have like a double chest
here and here that would be two of them
plus the dispenser then like that in
between we would put like an upside down
stare of whatever theme we're going with
I have any stairs around I want to try
this that would be enough storage to
double chests is plenty plus the
dispenser we'd be good yeah because if
we use a stair it'll look like a full
block it's going to be the wrong way
right yeah you have to do it from behind
we'd have to put these in first to be
little painful to construct but I have
plenty of time to make it right then you
could also put signs on these in between
blocks that could be cool so if we go
with a wood theme we have wood stairs if
we go with an industrial theme we have
stone stairs there's cobblestone ones if
we go with the snow theme I guess we
would have to use dark wood stairs when
they come out to do that that could be
cool I like this idea a lot more then we
can have them side by side still we
still have our display block at the
bottom yeah
yeah I think that's what we're going to
go with I like it it's messy now because
it's not set up properly but I think
when it's all put together and and made
nice and lighting behind it's going to
look good you just have to use your
imagination I also did a search for
storage rooms storage room ideas I
looked at quite a few I didn't see
anything I preferred more so that's why
I think this is what we're going with I
think the next best thing I liked was
this style it's pretty common have them
stacked like that and then signs in
between saying what's what we could
still have our display block below if we
wanted but I think I prefer this way I'm
not saying this way is better I just
like it more and also we can make it
more compact because we get them side by
side instead of having a space between
and also it reminds me more of the old
LP storage room which is what I'm going
for here I want to I'm feeling very nice
nostalgic with this project so I I kind
of want to build on the old idea but
make it slightly different anyway that's
it for today guys thank you for watching
further news huge is going to be making
a comeback we're playing the next map
already and recording don't know when
the series is going to start up again oh
I guess when we have an intro made and
everything nobody said what map were
playing I don't think so I'm not going
to spoil it but it's very very difficult
and also a lot of messages of people
saying they played me an ace of spades
no probably not
there's no authorised login in that game
so if if you play with an ether or any
mine cracker even if we're together
they're probably fakes because everybody
that sent me a message recently it's not
true I haven't played it in a few days
so just be wary of that there's lots of
fakers on the Internet get used to it
but yeah that's it guys thanks for
watching have a good night or day or
whatever Hey
you