hello hello this is e so as everybody
doing today welcome back to Minecraft
that's the island from last episode it's
completely flat now I took it down it
didn't see me coming it's about a I
think it's about a 50 by 50 island or so
so it's fair-sized nice to have that
gone I gotta fill it in with water yet
but yeah who cares about an island let's
see what we have built now I've got the
EMP units pretty much well they're close
to done anyway let's get my movie style
scrolling feature oh oh okay yeah so I
got lots done with these things now I
did the wiring only one that's not done
as a spider one I'm going to save that
for later
umm crusher works saying opens I still
don't have lava in that one top thing
comes down and they both come down so
just like the prototype they don't seem
to interfere with each other just good
if you don't do the wiring right like
sometimes when you put the crusher out
and then take it back some of the
Pistons don't go back if the barrier is
down so took a little bit of messing
around with the wiring but the big thing
I also got the master switches DUP which
is pretty cool let's see barriers I love
how that looks
I can just hit this all day open closed
open closed and we have the Crushers and
we have the water very cool Oh guess
that one's spilling over that's not good
that should fix it except we lost the
lever from that lots of work into this
can hardly wait till I get my spawning
pads done and then I'll actually be able
to see it working this is going to look
really cool when it's done - I think I'm
it because there's going to be like
glass tubes above each of these things
going up to the ceiling I think it's
gonna have a pretty cool looking effect
and I plan on replacing these sandstone
blocks with glowstone so it'll be like a
plus sign out of glowstone probably and
less closed on melts ice I'm not sure
about that yet I'm sure one of you guys
will tell me in this video yeah that's
better now
let's see items moving there's items
water comes pushes in the long they
quickly fall down to the collection area
pretty cool
so you can manually set each of these
things too so for example I could have
the barrier down and then it overrides
the master switch that setting although
the bottom piston moves for a second
that might be a problem later I just
it's only when it's going down I'll have
to look into that later
so you can override the master switches
these are just here temporarily I plan I
will be able to control them
the master switches using levers but
they will also be done automatically and
then I'll have my manual settings too
which is good let's go check out the
wiring I guess I'm out of redstone
wiring again this was a big redstone
requirement to make this goes all the
way around
these are the three master lines maybe
I'll skip to today so we can see better
ah that's better okay so those bottom
ones some fresher
so that wire goes around goes to the
left here the lever for the crusher is
behind this sandstone block here and it
lights up this wire it goes here around
this piston and the one below it and
that moves it the crusher having this
repeater here prevents any current from
back flowing otherwise it would when you
activate the lever manually if this
repeater wasn't here this power would be
able to go to the master wire and it
would activate all the pressures down
the line so it's very important I put
this here which I found out later and
the second one is the barriers and like
like this repeater here I use the
redstone torch so that power can't
backflow to the master line it lights up
this wire here which goes above to
all right
yeah I don't know how this works all
right there's a piston there so lever
manually activates this wire here power
goes to the sandstone block and flows to
the top barrier piston right there and
it also goes down here to the bottom one
and then the water one goes at the top
here and it's right over here the water
ones not controlled manually so I don't
have to worry too much about that one
I'll power back flowing or anything and
maybe we'll walk around the wire here to
sleek and get idea how it all looks i
stacked the master wires vertically just
because I would use less space that way
add turns out I actually have plenty of
space here like look at these corners
it's all empty so if I need to adjust
these things I probably will be able to
because there's quite a bit of space
between each one yet which is fine yeah
so it just goes all the way around and
these like these things can be
customized to like for example say the
one for Wolves some people were
wondering about this how it's going to
do it I could for example get rid of
this glass block and use a half slab
instead so that when the barrier is down
it'll be glass block and a half block so
I can still interact with the Wolves
without the mix escaping so you know
simple things like that can be done to
each one
this first one here has a fifth lever
just because I had another idea I might
end up doing to all them but I'm going
to experiment with it first I kind of
wanted a way to get mobs into mine carts
as well sure to have that option at
least so that's what this fifth levers
for so I have the lab a very far down
now man there's a glass block above it
this lever removes the last block so
that's stuffed and fall in the lava so
if the glass blocks like that it creates
kind of like a second holding area and I
can run my carts to the corner and pick
up mobs through the glass if you watch
my older episodes around
I believe the 20s or so I did that
before I'm hoping that trick still works
so that's kind of one one other thing I
might end up doing so I would just have
glass blocks over there so I would have
to run like a minecart track to the
corner here and hopefully they'll get
picked up but just an experimental idea
the one point seven point three patch
fix the moving ice blocks with pistons
which I'm really happy about
now the Pistons don't glitch out and the
ice box don't create water streams so
that's great one thing I really like
about being in a snowy biome is I can
use ice which allows you to do several
tricks like for example moving items and
water streams is a really easy really
really easy because you can move it
basically an infinite distance without
having to go down levels like you
normally do because the items have
enough momentum to go from one stream to
another and step by I think up the six
blocks of ice so these will just keep
going around and around until they
disappear or the water freezes
some people are wondering about that in
snowy biomes water only freezes if it's
exposed if there's nothing above it
there's no blocks above it it took
freeze and it can freeze even if it's
moving water like this the source block
wheel that looks pretty cool
cool one thing I'm disappointed about
those it seemed like boats and stuff
don't move friction like they still have
the normal friction on ice Hey look who
it is another is I pick this location is
it's ponds lots of wolves which is cool
so this is going to look a lot different
when it's all done there's going to be
like a skirting around this bottom all
around it you won't be able to see
underneath here also all this wiring on
the outside you won't be will see it
it'll be covered and I'm going to be
building my base around around the
center contraption here they'll probably
be a staircase on the right here and one
on the left there won't be one in the
middle like I have here it will
gradually go up the stairs probably will
come up probably somewhere over here and
same for the other side and there's
going to be water channels we might
actually start building those this
episode there's going to be so you'll go
you'll gradually go up a little bit get
to this part here excuse me ah it'll be
one collection thing on this right side
there'll be one on the left side and
there'll be one in the middle is the
plan one on the right side will have
your passive mobs drops so since this is
cows sheep pigs chickens all those will
merge together in one water stream and
come out on the right side here and then
your slimes creepers skeletons zombies
will come out on and spiders will come
out on this
collection area here and then they'll
also be a switch which will allow you to
either have them separate like that or
merge them together in one main
collection area in the center and that
will be similar to what I have in my
storage room so again the idea is to
have the option to do whatever you want
and not limit yourself the animals are
freaking out what you do with our home
where's all the grass where are all the
polar bears cow feces a polar bear she
thinks she's a polar bear so it doesn't
need to be snowing for the water to
freeze into ice either as you can see
that was a big island this is the other
island I've been working on it's also
right next to the base it's a little bit
bigger but I'm actually dealing with it
pretty quickly I'm getting really good
at control explosions with TNT so
doesn't take nearly as long to clean out
the area and I just have to go up to
about just like a line over here and
that's the only real island left once I
finish this one off it's not really an
island it's a giant landmass
so I'm guessing I will just clear the
grass off of it
and place torches to keep the mobs from
spawning otherwise I need to clear the
island pretty much where that gravel
column is everything left of it from the
way I'm facing right now so I'd have to
like draw a line here and clear
everything left of it
so I'll probably just probably just
clear the grass so I just had another
thought about these collection holes
here I need them for the water streams
to run into and to bring items to but
one thing I don't really like about them
is I don't want to be falling into them
so I'm thinking I'm going to piston eyes
them to what I'll probably do loops is
put like a piston sticky piston here and
I'll have this kind of covered with half
slabs or something something that looks
good
definitely not cobblestone ones and now
that we can move ice no problem without
them creating water streams so normally
it'll just look like that and so the
idea is when I flick this lever to bring
I think the water streams come out first
thing that's going to happen is all
these ice blocks are going to move and
then the water is going to flow so
that's that's the new plan well we might
as well start working on the item piping
I guess so we need to get rid of this
line of ice blocks and we need to run
one underneath it first yeah so spiders
are going to go to spider drops are
going to go to the string too and these
ones also somehow and then this side
will be another line this is for the
passive ones oh you know I got a hurry
otherwise this water's going to freeze
again and it's already starting to okay
so I'm going to dig this out and then
we'll uh we'll be back now I'm just
cutting out the line we made we're going
to make like a little molding water in
to create new ice lower down I got the
molding finished now so we can place our
water in it and then we need to wait for
it to freeze
this is a kind of kind of a weird thing
to be doing but we want a lower layer of
ice so that items move fast on it and
also so we can do so we don't need to go
down levels with our water screen to
carry the items for far distances and so
this stream is going to come around and
join with this one this one is going to
be going this way and then they're both
going to go together that way and this
one will also have squid in I don't know
let's technically a passive mob but I
don't know it doesn't really matter good
okay so I'm going to fill another one
and I'm going to wait for this to freeze
see it's starting to already our giant
ice tray is frozen now so we're going to
do one last thing here we're going to
fill in the airspace with soil and then
we're going to put water over top and
have it freeze as well make two layers
of ice and then when we have two layers
we will go underneath and remove the
soil and place the water streams from
underneath instead of from above here
so a little bit strange it's very
important I get to all my ice stuff
figured out before I put a roof on top
of this thing because when I have a roof
I won't be able to make ice freeze and I
also be got to be very careful now that
how I place my torches because if I melt
the ice underneath this ice it's going
to be a real pain to to make it turn to
make the water turn to ice in because
I'll have to remove the top layer of ice
add the bottom layer freeze and then
place the top layer again and it'll be a
be a big process if I'm not careful
there the floor is as good as new
so I started clearing out some of the
soil blocks in between the two ice
layers just from underneath here I'll
probably replace the soil box you can
see from above with snow in the end of
things
I think that'll look better like but
yeah I need to place my water streams
from below here and it'll all flow to
the end here it's very very good
building this thing up high because it
makes doing all this stuff so much
easier I got to be very careful where I
place my torches now because I don't
want those ice blocks melting uh-huh
anyway I think it's about that time guys
to find in major lake yes I got family
visiting soon I don't know how many
episodes I'm going to get out now but
hopefully hopefully I'll get around to
doing at least something they all these
resources
I got clearing the islands and stuff and
we are going to go back to my main base
or I'm going to go back to my babies I'm
going to say goodbye to you guys now
make sure it's not hard I haven't been
in the nether yet without it being on
hard so I can make sure I keep keep that
promise
so getting homes quick go through the
nether
we're out by my mother base now with
portal again and we are back
back to the second it nether the GL
nether mod go through one last portal
and we're back to the real world pretty
cool okay thank you for watching
everybody hope you're enjoying my new
base as much as I am and I will see you
again next time