little Minecrafters we're back again to
our let's play series this is episode 7
and I'm sorry I haven't been putting
episodes out recently I'm probably not
going to be getting one out per day I
just can't I just can't do them that
fast so I'm sorry if you expect more and
I wanted to thank everybody who left
comments about the road system someone
pointed out that if these if an empty
boat passes over these pressure plates
it's not going to detect it and send the
boat back to make up for it and then
some other people said that even if it
was to detect it somehow it would just
cause an infinite loop with the boats so
I would like to thank you guys for
pointing that out to me I have I didn't
think about those things and I don't
think there's any solution to that
problem although it's not really a
problem because I think even if lots of
extra what is a problem but even if
extra boats did pile up they would go
down in the stream and then they would
start piling up the shaft and you would
have a huge buffer before it causes any
actual problems
assuming of course that water source is
changed like I have in episode 6 to the
proper way so anyway what we are going
to be doing this episode I hate to say
it but we are going exploring in a cave
system because we need resources so
we're going to go hunt for some and I'm
just making preparations here before we
head off I'm going to bring one chest
with me I'm going to make probably two
extra swords actually I'm going to make
four swords total and I'm going to bring
a lot of meat with me because I'll
probably need it and oh yeah I'm going
to leave all my valuables here stuff I
won't need on our trip we're not going
far we're just going to that other
Island next to here and I will show you
guys how I hunt for iron and stuff
usually
that should be pretty close to good I am
going to make a boat too
so we can get to the island quicker and
because boats are simply awesome okay
and leave my stack of wood here but
always that sleeve that in half steps
tilted glass okay oh yeah I'm gonna make
a bunch of big taxes and stuff and it
sounds like there's a night time which
is not what I was looking for okay so I
think I'm just gonna make a run for it
looks kind of light outside still oh man
oh man it is on hard and I just saw a
creeper right there there there why is
why do I always have so many creepers in
my team you know it's never spiders or
skeletons it's always creepers oh well
so yeah what we're going to do is we're
just going to go to this island here and
I don't know for sure but I'm guessing
we're going to find a cave system
somewhere hopefully and there's a
creeper of course so we're just going to
explore this island until we find that
cave system this is already looking like
a bad idea to me there's a ton of skill
things over there these guys no problem
spiders oh I do not like
come on Oh
- no no where's my boat
call me a coward I don't care oh
away - that was come on
that was terrible oh good it's daytime
yes I'm just going to wait here until
it's light I think all right I think we
can go now I hope no okay we just have
to keep an eye out for creepers here Oh
only got one left
so yeah like I was saying we're just
going to walk around this island and
hopefully find a cave somewhere that we
can go in need on our way we lost them
check that up that is pretty cool
found some iron
ultra creepers yay
so this Islands bigger than I thought it
was that's gonna caves anymore
well what do we have here it looks
promising
I think this is where we're going to go
ah that's not a cave oh wait it keeps
going okay this is what we're going to
check out so I'm going to set up my
chest here put some meat in it and some
items we find extra swords in case we
die and we need to come get our items
back real quick just go up to the chest
pick them up and head down real fast
so this is my favorite type of mining
you just go down find a cave and then
you harvest all the iron coal you see
without having to dig really if you're
really lucky you'll find a cave that
goes down all the way to bedrock and
you'll get redstone or gold and diamonds
and all that
stuff - alright so that's just the
entrance of the cave and we already got
tons of stuff and now we're going to go
down deeper and that's our first
zombie hopefully this goes down deep
sounds like there's a zombie down here I
hear something walking around that's a
skeleton stupid f9 so yeah that's why I
brought this stuff because I knew I was
going to die let's take one that was -
yeah right there that was weird
let's still see what's down here
huge empty area in here huge empty area
kind of strange kinda scary okay that
was a spider
all right I'm kind of lost down here I I
still haven't gone down there or up here
so I'm hoping I'll find my way out of
here and there's nothing in here well
maybe there is something I keep hearing
these spiders and skeletons and zombies
and I have no idea where they are
you hear that oh crap okay I jumped in
real life that scared me
little butter how about fighting fair
huh dead yet
guy has a freaking bow and arrow and I
have a sword like that's not fair
ah okay so I think there's other guys
behind here or not
all right back to harvesting Hey oh come
on you got to be kidding me who shot me
is that from in there what the heck was
that okay we're going twice
surface here stupid idea make sure
there's a lab around yours it's weird I
think I'm still really low but I heard a
chicken which makes me think I'm at the
surface but I don't this is very
confusing
okay
we are at the surface I know as soon as
I walk out there creepers going to land
on me
oh speaking of buggers
it helped me mind all this coal please
hey what was that okay either explode or
let's get this now he gets now I don't
know where I am
this symbol I can recognize she said I
hear Jay
oh I'm vulnerable
yes you get from here before oh man
forget that I don't know where I am
running for my life
Negi oh man I just happened to land on
the tallest tree in the world to get off
this island
yeah I don't want to die
oh man I hate this over yes I'm pretty
lost oh my
ah well that whole adventure didn't work
out too well um I mind lots of stuff got
lots of cool lots on and then I went out
to the surface I got lost then I died
and then I went back to figure out where
I got lost and I got lost looking where
I got lost and I died again and I lost
everything so now all my stuff is lost
for good and I hate that stupid Island
that's not really an island so the new
plan since I'm probably never going to
go mining like that ever again because
it doesn't work well on hard
is I am just going to start a mine here
right here right here and I'm just going
to do straight down to bedrock because
every experience minecraft or knows you
should dig straight down always and so
what I'm going to be doing is I'm going
to be mining underneath this ocean here
near the bedrock probably ten or sixteen
levels above bedrock and I'm going to
mine out a huge room underneath it and
it's going to work as a mob catcher so
I'll work on that slowly over time as I
need resources I'll clear out the room
and at the same time I'll be building a
mob catcher so that should work out good
and just going to be using ladders to
get out of the hole for now and what is
what is that is that more clay oh good
more clay I needed some more that's
awesome
I just about used up all the other clay
I had J so I'm going to dig this down
and then I'll see you in a bit so
digging has been going very well as you
can see I'm pretty deep now and I got
some iron some coal I can have some
torches in
and I know what you're thinking and no
I'm not an idiot the reason why you
shouldn't dig straight down ever is
because you will fall in lava but as
long as you dig like sometimes you don't
think the block you're standing on
you'll be fine and that's what I've been
doing and that looks like there is a
huge lake under there which is good
actually because I need lava but just do
max nice and I think this is level eight
or something where you'll find lava so
this is probably the level I'll make the
mob trap can't quite see which way I am
so speed going what I'm going to do is
I'm going to put ladders up here and get
a base settled I hope have enough enough
sticks I don't think I do
this is not going to be good
come on make it make it 5 4 3 2 1 ah now
yeah that works too okay so I'm going to
mark which way I need to go with a torch
so that I can see it down there and make
a little building around this so I don't
fall down it for some reason not for
some reason out of stupidity all right
cool
and and that's where I'm gonna end the
video so we got a mind started Fiverr
need resources I'll go down here for it
and instead of going to this stupid
island over there and dying over and
over and yeah so until next episode