hey everyone Etha here this is a Episode
four and I just want to say thanks to
all my subscribers and all of those who
leave comments and thumbs up and all
that good stuff I do read the comments
and happy to see everything's been
pretty positive so far and also I
noticed a few people have been telling
me to harvest this clay over here from
my spawn so I figured that would be a
good way to start off this episode I'm
finally going to harvest this clay
alright you ready you ready you can
harvest it now now I'm just messing with
you I'm not going to harvest this clay I
am going to leave this clay here and
you're going to see it every episode and
it's kind of tormenting you and you're
gonna be like come on II thought where's
the frickin clay already what's the
matter with you and I'm just gonna laugh
because I am evil and I have a sick
sense of humor and I think it's going to
be funny and just so you know how evil I
am just so you know check this out
oh yeah there's more clay and I'm not
going to harvest this either and it's
just going to kill you guys okay alright
so here we are back at the tree farm I
was going to work on making it bigger
right now it only holds nine trees I
want to make it set hold at least 16
trees but I've realized I'm pretty much
out of cobblestone so I think we're
going to work on the road but first
we're going to cut down some trees for
some wood at the clear the area
actually I'll just meet you down at the
road alright so I didn't cut down to may
trees my axe broke so gettin our supper
and then we're going to work on the road
a little bit as you can see you I don't
really have a whole lot of stuff here so
I really need to gather some resources
oh yeah I needed the wood because we
need some ladders because I think I'm
going to start on the dispenser and show
you guys how to do that
and that should be plenty okay like I
said this is the dispenser this is a
return system all we really need to do
is dig these two holes down as deep as
we want I usually start with the return
so that I can place ladders back up to
get back out and oh man I don't have any
torches oh this is brutal
well maybe I'll wait then because you
guys probably can't see anything okay
first I'm just going to dig out here and
I'll probably find some coal I'll see
you back in a sec so I ended up with
clearing quite a ways and I only found
enough coal to make about 64 torches
which is not much at all and I grazed
the ocean a little bit and made a huge
leak I'm going to show you how to plug
that up it's very simple
yes like that
I don't like being under the ocean
because in sand falls and you always
have this problem it takes a long time
to dig that it's a real pain
I don't do that later I did find some
iron ore which is awesome because we
need some buckets and we we made it
about a third of the way to the island
which is pretty good and I got lots of
resources now lots of cobblestone so we
can work on the dispenser again I'll
show you how much I got about five
stacks cobblestone and we're going to
smelt some iron okay back to it so yeah
so we dig down full as deep as we want
the deeper you dig the more boats your
dispenser can hold and since there's
since I'm the only person playing on my
server I don't really need it too deep
because I don't need many boots
that's probably plenty and then dig down
the other one but for first you should
connect it's leaned out far to dig just
like that
get out easy with the ladders they all
find some coal on the way down I are not
seal that back up so this is a shaft
that's going to have the water elevator
in it and this one's going to be dry so
the boat falls down here then it flows
here and then it goes up the elevator
and then that is held by a door at the
top so what should we do next
um question
jump it down to half steps here I'm not
sure why and we're going to make some
buckets I usually only carry two budgets
to make it anytime and we'll get some
water I think it's probably daytime
oh man that's not good that's uh good oh
I can't see anything I swear if another
creeper gets me I am going to lose it
all there's one right there
well whoa whoa ah that's much easier to
do this stuff on peaceful good thing I
got some meat though Jay so I just feel
like the infinite water screen down here
just do that enough you probably know
how to do that you just need a 2x2 area
place one water bucket here another one
diagonal grab water from anywhere as
much as you need so set up the water for
your dispenser you need place two blocks
down here one there to here and place
the water in there you just need two two
water sources and
oh yeah ah that's annoying with your
dispenser it's good to drop it down one
more block in case of boat breaks or
something then the wood has like
eye-catcher area and it doesn't
interfere with any other boats that are
coming up and I'll be quiet I'm gonna
make some smooth stone so when you break
this that's the water elevator just like
that I've made about four different
types of both dispensers so far the one
we're building here is my version four I
call it the rapid dispenser and then be
quiet and that's because it shoots boats
out really fast at excellent speed and I
hope he gets trapped I really do
so we're gonna place a door I'm trying
to talk here that'd be a bad idea bad
idea
interrupting cow says what okay you're
going to place the door over here
and I'll explain why in a bit when those
guys shut up and puts pressure plate
here and we're going to place to here to
stop the water this water and yeah and I
sell place it
yeah that's pretty much set up what was
that
oh it's data Skelton creeper I see you
creeper
come on let's let's get this over with
aw sweetie oh no we didn't put a nice
spider got show these guys who's boss
freaking towels for your Pig seriously
what's with all these guys around here
yeah I am going to place uh what do you
call it the median I think
down the middle here and this separates
the two lanes so the water doesn't flow
together I think I forgot to mention
that I'm not just building a road here
I'm actually working on redesigning it
too so I don't know exactly what I'm
doing at the moment the way I normally
do this return system is going to have
to be changed so just for now I'm going
to put an easy loader here which is a
way of getting boats safely into the
dispenser so to do that I need pressure
plates and some glass and some water
so an easy loader is basically a water
pattern oh yeah I need a sign to the
sign keeps the water from flowing over
the edge okay so you place the water and
it makes this six block pattern and then
you place the boat in the center one and
L lines the boat properly you need to
place is you don't need to should be
watching now try out then try placing a
boat in it oh yeah I should put
something over the dispenser to keep it
from floating up we're going to place
three glass blocks here and then we
place the boat in the center it hits
this wall hits that wall falls down
water pushes it up our elevator
and yeah that's good so when I hop in
the boat it presses the pressure plate
and that's going to open this door
once I wire it properly but I do not
have any redstone right now so that will
have to wait and going to show you why
it's a rapid dispenser place two boats
the reason the boats don't break is
because they're always traveling
straight in my system you can you can
run a boat as hard as you want into wall
as long as it's going straight it won't
break so this this dispenser area is
only 3 by 2 which is about as tight as
you can fit two boats together see how
one is this way and one is lengthwise
you cannot fit two boats lengthwise in
this small area this is very tight and
it like shoots the boat pressing against
the other boat boosts that out the
system
so there's pretty much no acceleration
time so this episode's running a little
bit long so I'm going to end it here and
thanks for watching and I'll see you
next time