Roger that Houston
standing by
all systems article
initiating countdown Fagor t-minus three
two one blast-off Oh steam is awesome
hey everybody just having a little fun
here need some meat now see I got that
mob system all rebuilt now so let's go
check it out
there's a bunch of guys in there I'll
stuff the other
shailen try some
and so what happens when you touch them
it's like getting pumped by 50 or 100
guys all at once
which makes you fly very far
it's crap honey listen
okay so
let's get started here so what happens
is they all get compressed the other in
this one you walk area and even if you
open the door they're not all going to
get out
whoa so a bunch of guys made it through
but the rest of these guys they're stuck
in there for good
pretty crazy
now even with both doors open not able
to get through the door hinges because
they're basically one big entity now
we're just going to switch to peaceful
for now so let's see so what we're going
to need to do is build like a
decompression chamber for these guys
because we're not able to sort them if
they're all stuck together like that so
we need to be able to sort them one by
one
so that's what we're going to do off the
start here I'm going to keep it on
peaceful just so we don't have them
annoying us up here going to block this
off for now and oh yeah I added a sign
over there I don't think I had that
before it blew up
and since our elevator thing is over
here we're going to have to do it make
it go around a bend I think like that
I guess this thing's on the way too and
za Bandito
this is what your problem was - untry
figured this out already
but all the guys are getting stuck
together and your spartacus machine
which is why you can get only one out so
you need some kind of decompression
chamber and I think I'm going to try
make one that is a 5x5 area I might have
to play around with it and adjust it a
bit and I just help build it right here
I probably have to tear this down and
redo it but okay and then that's not all
mentally for long
and so this is going to have space for
five times five is 25 so at least plus
all this tunneling and stuff it should
handle around 50 guys no problem
and hopefully it'll handle more but I'm
not sure okay and I'm just going to put
a block roof over top this
okay so that's our mob decompression
chamber we're going to have an opening
over here yes and it's going to put a
pressure plate down here and one over
here then we're going to have a water
stream over there and there and it's
going to push them into this tunnel here
kind of like that zombie trap thing we
made and then over here we're going to
have a door actually
let's get this water going here I'm just
going to fill this up with pressure
plates for now I might change that one
down there so the water stream should
force them around the corner and then
we're going to need some signs here I
guess
and with the signs I'm just going to
block that other stream merging place it
sign there and then assign on another
side OOP I missed
there
so yeah they'll get forced through into
this room and the water will push them
into this area here hopefully one by one
and then we need a door there one sec
I'm going to think about this all right
I think I figured it out now so with
this full of water water only goes up to
here so I'm going to place door right
here
but the door needs to be dropped down
one block and I'll explain why in a sec
replace a block underneath and we're
going to need to place a stair here door
will be facing this way and need another
sign
that sign is going cool on this block
here because there's going to be a water
source above this door and mm-hmm maybe
I'm doing this wrong okay I've been
poking and prodding at this thing for a
while now very slowly making changes to
it and I haven't had a whole lot of I
haven't had a whole lot of success I on
the verge of giving up on it actually
and resorting to another method that I
know will work um so I built a little
testing attachment here and this ladder
is pretty much my last hope I don't know
if this is going to work because the
mobs are getting recompressed at this
point so will this wait till if you
build up I put slow sand above because I
thought it might help I don't I don't
know if it really does and this door
opens the other way now and so I think
so if a mob goes in here the goal is to
make its only one will go through and I
think only one can go up if there's a
ladder here
yeah this is a little harder than I was
expecting it to be all right I'm going
to let them build up for a few seconds
and then we'll start it again all right
things are getting more compressed in
there now so we're going to try and see
how this works basically one mobs going
to push them in and the door hinge might
be an issue I'm not sure yeah not
looking too hopeful right now
be very careful guys stuck Oh
soé creepers will blow up if you're
within two blocks of them if they can
see you I walk a little closer as before
oh yeah so it's not working more than
one is going up with the ladder at a
time so going to resort to another plan
and I'm going to assume that this method
is actually impossible until someone
proves me wrong alright so we've taken a
few steps back quite a few steps back
actually um I don't like that other
method is going to work so this is the
new plan oops
if any of you can get that other method
working please let me know because I
would like to see your solution to the
problem but the goal was to get only one
mob through the door by pressing a
button 100% of the time without any gaps
in the water stream either which was
pretty challenging the new plan this was
my original plan much simpler
new plan is to use minecarts something
kind of like this we're just testing
this here and so this is a special
corner I think hopefully we don't get a
skeleton here oh that's not good pretty
sure I tested this before maybe that's
the wrong corner oh boy this better not
be like last time oh okay so I guess
it's that corner actually
it's probably any corner but I think
down below I have the water moving
toward this corner and that's why
they're against this corner so I should
be able to choose whatever corner I want
the met by changing the water flow
diagonally actually let's try so I kind
of want them over on the side I think so
we'll put it like we had it before
water there and water here seal it up
and now I think they'll get into this
minecart I hope and yeah so the plan is
to make this semi-automatic I don't
think it's possible to make an automatic
sorting system because all the tall mobs
have the same physical characteristics
as far as I know so the only other
option would be to do something with the
pathfinding but I have no idea how you
would do it so basically we're going to
set up some kind of minecart system here
to pick them up and then put them into a
buffer and then I'll have a control
panel with three buttons on as a little
be like three buttons and I'll click one
if it's a creeper another one of its
skeleton one if it's a zombie and then
I'll put them into another buffer for
their type
so they'll be four buffers at the end
one for spiders one for zombies
skeletons and creepers probably actually
changes and have a pressure plate
underneath them like and detectives are
there too and I'll send the card to pick
them up no enter the buffers that works
pretty good that's stuck on that feather
I think that's not me now
and it's safe I can bump into this it
won't hurt me yes that's what we're
going to do something like that I'll
think about it and that's a much easier
way to separate them one by one it'll
need a lot of minecarts but not a big
deal I have lots of iron and I'm
probably going to rip out this elevator
because I'm not liking it because the
boats are moving around for some reason
anyway what else should we do probably
wrap up this episode pretty quick I'm
going to show you guys how I kind of
plan on having part of the storage room
so for items you need sort of often I
think I'm going to have something like
this walls of dispensers and I think
buttons underneath each one something
like that and then
and then the type of material it is
above so if there is soil in this one
for example there would be a soil block
above if there's cobble in this will be
cobble above that way from a long
distance I can tell what's in the
dispenser without having to read a sign
which is kind of handy and we're just
going to test this to make sure it works
yeah so they don't need to interfere
with each other
pressing this button doesn't make one
shoot out of here so that'll work and
I'll probably like to have a storage
chests over here maybe we'll make some
and then for like materials that are
used a lot probably just cobble stone
sand planks and dirt I'll probably hook
up those rapid four dispensers I'll
probably just have four in the storage
room probably can't put one here so I
might alternate them I wonder if there's
a way to put a button on a chest because
that would be cool too but anyway I'll
play around with it and you guys give me
your ideas and I'll take them into
consideration too
but for now we're going to end the
episode and I'm going to think about how
to do this a little better and think
about this too and thanks for watching