[Music]
welcome everybody this is etho I just
recorded a five minute intro and I
discovered I didn't have my mic plugged
in so let's try this again now we're
going to go down to the nether and I'll
show you what I've been up to since our
last episode
[Music]
not a whole lot but I've got the glass
tube running all the way up now at some
point I will be building something
around the portal so it doesn't get
destroyed and so now we can climb up to
the ceiling safely we'll get shot at
when we're in this tube and look around
[Music]
by holding shift on ladders you don't go
down which is nice
in future I would try to catch that guy
but I think he'll move if I go near him
[Music]
and so I've just built this long tunnel
I'll probably be looking up mine carts
and stuff in the nether soon or sometime
anyway so that we can get around faster
but for now what I did it at just the
mines a long distance it is solid up
here I think I got this idea from
co-star actually I think this is what he
did in his LP if I remember right so
it's easy to get around
I put glass where the ceiling is so we
can look down which is a nice for future
around over here this opened up to
another region I was able to walk around
around here and get some more glowstone
which is nice I like glowstone like that
that's out in an open area above lava
with gas all around I probably can't get
that stuff or it'd be extremely
difficult to so I'm going to show you
what I've been up to over here yeah a
glass tunnel type thing here I built
which is nice to get a nice wide look of
the area and I decided this is where
we're going to place the 360 cannon I
probably want to drop down about 20
blocks or so and then start building a
base fort and an enclosure so that we
can safely inside without getting shot
at
but getting down is a hard part because
once you go up you can't place water
anything to go down so I the only way I
can think of getting down is to place
Ravel ad it fall and I'm going to make
like a travel tube that I can safely go
down without getting shot at and then
somehow start killing like a stone
foundation for the cannon and then
enclosure so that you can safely build
the cannon inside so that's what I'm
going to do I then make a gravel column
here and I'll see you in a bit
excellent the gravel cube is complete um
you know what a lot of people don't like
gravel but I do not recommend getting
rid of it a lot of people throw it in
consider eaters but you never know when
it's gonna come in handy
I really glad I'd have to use sand for
this
I think yeah I'm just going to fill this
up with gravel to the top I think and
then I should be able to dig down as far
as I want to go have ladders with me and
this is going to be extremely dangerous
very good chance I'll die and it does
like five stacks of gravel at least okay
so we are at y99 let's go down to let's
go down to 80
[Music]
and let's try take a look outside there
if you're really fast in place class
before the gravel falls dope dope
[Music]
excellent how do we expand this further
well you know what I think we should
actually replace this with the something
that will get destroyed our little tube
here if we can
[Music]
otherwise were bowling you know one bad
move and I'm dead no no no no
that bugger man good thing Mel gravels
it is it fixes itself based let's try it
yeah slowly but surely we can do this
I'm sure not he missed all right we have
a ladder so slowly I'm gonna try to
expand this more and more and I'll see
you in a bit
not just spoils us all these new
features makes a game easier and easier
all the time so it's solid cobble now
they can't destroy this
[Music]
so now we can somehow start expanding
outwards this is where things get tricky
[Music]
probably replace this with obsidian at
some point it's fine it's fine you just
can't let them see us oh that's not good
I think you thought
[Music]
gravel I'm going to get rid of using TNT
I think so that we don't have that giant
pillar out of the ground
[Music]
all right that's a good start so that's
a that's all I'm going to show you guys
for this episode I might continue it off
camera let's go do something else so
it's Cannon time people I felt bad
last cannon launch I forgot to load
these two yeah I make mistakes sometimes
hope you guys forgive me and then I was
going to acknowledge my mistake last
episode and I forgot to do that too so
hopefully I can sort of make up for it
by doing a daytime launch for you guys
so MP thank you well and Sagi the sage
that's right
thank you I did get your cobblestone
stairs
alright next time next time I'll
remember I promise
alright so it turns out I'm having too
much fun with this I want to keep
building it instead of doing something
else so let's keep on keepin on
I'm gonna store some stuff so so because
I grabbed some TNT from the cannons
there and I don't want to lose it all if
I die and we should try to blow up the
gravel because I don't want that there
cuz it'll make it look worse
looks cooler physicists hanging from
ceiling I think that's add one more okay
[Music]
well I guess let's just try it happens
oh what the heck I thought couples don't
absorb more of the blow than that ah all
right one second all right let's go
check out the damage oh yeah I have a
lot of a new subscribers so if you're
not really sure what I'm doing
i building a 360 cannon so that i can
shoot at gas for the fun of it and for
our party practice because they're
moving targets and the wide open area so
it should be pretty fun if i could get
it to work
[Music]
that's a big if she also this is my
first iron sword i've ever crafted
before ever not just in this series
[Music]
other options just a little higher
rebuild
[Music]
yes I'm gonna build it a little bit
higher I think oh this is just getting
silly now see I just have to make it go
at it all you gotta be king we're fine
we're fine
[Music]
come on
so I am such all right but we salvaged
it I think somehow excellent okay okay
let's try this again shall we
this time let's think it through a
little bit better though it's not good
to be impulsive all the time
[Music]
all right I think we're safe now
I think much better shoot it back up oh
[Music]
yeah
I accidentally placed a few candy while
falling down Oh best Bell walked off all
right that is all taken care of now so
right here is the base I think I can
build it exactly the same as my 360
cannon the original one I think all I
have to do is replace the water which
with lava and it should work I think
[Music]
yeah but we're going to end it here guys
so thanks for watching if you guys are
getting sick of the nether just let me
know and I'll do something else but
that's it for today see you later