another beautiful sunrise hey you guys
you're hanging out with me Ethel this is
episode 18 and this episode we're just
kind of going to kind of chillax got no
nothing new to show you and no real
building plans this episode we do have
an agenda we're going to be researching
ideas I had in minecraft to see if they
work and oh yeah another thing you got
to mention this last episode but some
people commented that I should hook up
the musical note blocks to this warning
system but I'm not really musically
gifted so if somebody wants to figure
out a cool tune to play something simple
upload a video response and then I'll
copy it into my world
something simple oh like because we
don't have a lot of space maybe 10 or 20
notes and if you can copy a song part of
a song from cave story you win extra
points but yeah anyway
we're going to be researching things
this episode and one of the first things
I wanted to check out is this bone meal
deal so I've heard
I haven't tried it yet I've read that
you can use bone meal to instantly grow
trees and wheat so I want to experiment
with that first first was the trees and
looks like a good spot plant the tree
I've heard you need to stand back from
it otherwise it can suffocate you yeah
that's pretty cool I'll just leave it so
that worked pretty cool next thing I
wanted to try that's the first time I've
seen that by the way the next thing I
wanted to try is to see if it'll grow in
[Music]
it'll grow in a compact space so I got a
block here so the leaves are going to be
forced to be
actually let's do it like this the
leaves will have to be forced to be
three blocks high minimum interesting so
it does work but you have to use several
bonemeal until until the random tree
fits the space and we're going to try
another one
a two tree don't really know what shape
I'm making here this is pretty cool if
it you can grow a [ __ ] trees using
bonemeal 1/2 second try that's cool and
we got ourselves a [ __ ] tree
I'm definitely liking the bonemeal that
beautiful [ __ ] tree that's nice okay
what did I want to try next let's find
someplace with some more grass yeah the
next thing I wanted to try is that since
[ __ ] trees work we're going to dig a
hole
creeper check look safe we're going to
dig a hole actually that's probably too
deep how many is that one two three four
oh it's good we've got a soil block
there we're going to place our sapling
on it and what we're going to do is try
to create Minecraft hedges or bushes
type things so we're going to place a
limiter above our tree so the highest it
can grow is a up to here and we're going
to place our bonemeal it might kill me I
don't know one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten whoa all right
so it's a little bit dangerous to do it
that way but I'm sure there's a safe way
to do it too and now we got this little
leaf itch at ground level and we can
take our leaf cutter and shape it
however we want
and for example make little hedges at
ground level or bushes that won't die
now we got three leaf blocks at ground
level that aren't going to die that's
pretty cool I think and you can shape
however you want let's see what should
we try next oh yeah I wanted to try
growing some crops so we are going to
craft your mom we're going to use your
mum to find some seeds you're wondering
where this goes I got the the mob pads I
think underneath this cobblestone I
guess I forgot to explore down here too
it's big
I'll do it some other day
all right so we got some cultivated land
here we're going to plant some seeds and
we're going to place our bone meal
instant crop awesome world's smallest
wheat farm and the towels killed it you
stinking cow anyway next thing I wanted
to try
is we are going to go back to the new
grounds the nether I don't know if I
should leave my sword here or not
probably won't need it but just to be
safe that we're going to bring some
meats and stuff even though we probably
won't need it is very lame place okay
and we have our bow so pretty much
indestructible down there and we're
going to see if we can grow a wheat in
the nether using bone meal cuz I
honestly have no idea
[Music]
oh I'm so scared
Wow this place is actually giving me
health since I've gotten here and we're
going to cultivate this actually
probably gotta do this quickly cultivate
it place our seed and then our bone meal
and we just ruin the nether how crazy is
that with no water Wow we even have
jelly music jolly music in here okay
that's all that's bone meal tests I
wanted to do let's go back
[Music]
you
and obviously you can grow trees in the
nether that's that's nothing new
um what to do now I'm going to check how
long this videos been and then I'll
decide so see you soon so yes we're
about 13 minutes in so we have a little
bit of time left I waited till it was
light up I know there is a problem with
this thing here this guy stuck inside a
block right now and I think it's because
we went to the nether and when we came
back he was doing that so I think that
might be able you can fix that by
putting another block on top I'm not
sure and yeah so I looked on the wiki
how to build a fishing rod because
apparently I didn't look hard enough
yeah I'll be right back that was
embarrassing
okay so I've never crafted a fishing rod
before this is my first time don't
really know how to use it the wiki said
to make two and that they stack
and you ten is there way to do it
[Music]
or does he just follow you until he's
all the way in I don't so I wanted to
found some animals my little animal trap
here and so for this I'm going to be I
thought about a second floor for this
mob trap thing I also want to make a
third floor eventually that is going to
spawn the farm animals
so let me grass on the third floor and I
want to make a mob separator for them
too and I think it might be possible to
make it automatic for them because they
all have different sizes according to
the wiki and I know for a fact you can
separates pigs and chickens from sheep
and cows because let's see here how to
do this
experiment to get this before because
pigs can fit through one block space
where's my fishing around this is
probably impossible yeah Mon that
doesn't work I don't have a million
comments telling me what I'm doing wrong
here
move oh gee fishing rods don't work
where's my water and run out of time
compare out with this let's be in here
yeah so chickens and pigs can fit
through one block space and I think
sheep and cows can't there he goes
I would like to test to make sure but
there are not around when you need so
that's why I made the fishing rods flew
we can catch something quickly okay what
am i doing around here can't use a
scroll wheel oh good click again get
over here not down there this is harder
than I thought it was going to be get
over here don't fall down
for my dough I might have to be
continued later uh just go in the hole
going to walk into the fire a bit lake
[Music]
usually a million sheep and cows right
here and when I need one this month be
fair yay Oh No
finally okay we need to find out is it
down there
Oh get your butt in there
[Music]
stop jumping start walk okay so I don't
think he fits in a one-block space and
does he fit in a block and a half all
right let's try this now
who's the good cow oh yes he does okay I
guess we're probably out of time now so
we're gonna have to leave it at that and
I'll experiment with this more later so
thanks for watching and I'll see you
next time