hello ladies and welcome back to ethos
lab that name was suggested by Nintendo
otaku most definitely said his name
wrong yeah we're at our lab here I'm
anxious to get this all built and get
everything working here I've completed
the circle for the black wall it's
really dark here I'm a little worried
about placing torches because they will
melt our ice below if I'm not careful so
I'm going to make a backup before I do
that and as you see we have a huge
floating thing above us now instead of
just a small floating thing I started
expanding this floor out of snow still
got a ways to go this will be the mob
sorting floor as I said before and it
will also be our ceiling for this room
down here although we may if it seems
like it's too high we may add extra
floors in between and lower the ceiling
it's up to us we can decide later I
moved our stick our ladder it's over
here now and it looks like I'm gonna
have to move it again because it's in
the way again and yeah things are
different around here now what happened
is I realized that the spawning pads
were just too small
I'll explain how I threw that out later
but yeah that was a problem they're too
small so I expanded them here before we
just had that one that one that one and
that one for spawning pets 100 us now we
had a hundred blocks of spawning space I
added this one in the center
maybe you suggested that and then I
added these ones on the side so we have
12 big pads now in this little one in
the center so we had a hundred 100 spots
originally now we have three hundred and
five six eight five three hundred and
thirteen bondable spots now and we will
get rid of
it's a little extra stuff we have I also
realized last episode that I built my
spawning pads in the wrong place they
were shifted over one block so I fixed
that to extend this I simply went up one
block vertically and extended out
another eight blocks so we have another
full-length water stream here that's one
of the reasons why I've made my diamond
shape spawning pads
base seven one two three four five six
seven with the one block airspace
between each one because that that makes
it eight blocks so that's the same
length as water will flow so this works
out pretty much perfect if we want to
extend it and it's this be spawning pad
zero higher one block as well sorry
sorry about that mine sheep bad habit
okay the one thing I need to decide
right now is what I'm doing for the
ceiling in here people have told me not
to use sandstone since of the snowy
biome I like using sandstone I have
tried both here and I believe I'm gonna
use sandstone for the ceiling now keep
in mind there's not gonna be any snow or
ice anywhere near these passive mob
spawning pads you won't see any snow or
ice and the sandstone is gonna be
covered so I don't think there's
anything wrong with using it it's not
going to clash with snow and ice because
they'll be none around basically
and over here I had a test setup where I
was seeing what level grass will stay
alive if it's covered by water
as you can see none of it has
disappeared here
lucky for me I saw in my comments for
last video a guy named Skyliner W tested
this out and he found grass will stay
alive if it's at light level seven or
more it's covered with water so we have
torches here that's light level 14 at
the torch down one blocks 1312 above the
grass there except water lowers light by
two instead of just one like air does so
it would actually be 11 directly below
at this point here 11 10 9 so I could go
on other two blocks covered with water
and it still wanted to grass still
wouldn't die if it was covered by water
at this light level that's good to know
so I'll have glowstone in the ceiling
yeah I'm gonna take a break from talking
I'm gonna work on expanding this using
sandstone and then I will be back so
this is pretty strange I came back here
to get some sandstone some glowstone
I've got three minecarts running around
my track now they don't know what the
deal is with that because I'm positive I
only had one going around before I have
no idea where the other two came from
I'm not kidding
and they're evenly spaced that is one of
the strangest things anyway getting its
my clothes stone I have a stash actually
went to the nether a while ago and
explore some new areas I died by the
zombie pigmen turning on me unexpectedly
again I got super mad like unbelievably
mad not not that mad actually but I was
pretty ticked off and I had no idea
where I was far away from like the
starting point in my nether somehow I
managed to find my way back within the
five minutes and I got all my stuff back
I almost lost two stacks of glowstone
know which would have really sucked yeah
anyway back to the lab okay we're back
here again I'm just finishing up this
sandstone giant plus sign we're making
here it's gonna cover over everything
below so above some of the spawning pads
the ones on the outside it's only gonna
be too high two blocks high and the
middle ones at 73 blocks high will have
glowstone in the ceiling in places
prevent the grass from dying if there's
water being poured down vent passive mob
spawning again you don't really need
this feature I don't think I don't even
really need it but if you want to do it
it's up to you somebody told me another
day that squid have their own mob limit
of 8 and I agree with that seems to make
sense when you're moving around though
you'll have a lot of mobs like you might
see
over 40 or so that's because there's a
lot of ocean around when it tries to
place them
it'll place a bunch there's lots of
spots available because what it what the
game does when it's placing the mobs
it'll go through all the chunks every
cycle and they'll it was my awesome
explaining skills again yeah so like for
every cycle if the mob count is below
the mob limits then it will try Place
mobs and it will go through all the
chunks and if at that chunk they're able
to place mobs they will and it's
possible that they could place mobs in
every single chunk if it picks the right
place every one of those chunks but
that's unlikely but if you have lots of
ocean it's more likely that they will
find a spot for the squid to spawn and
then it will place some and it can place
as many as it wants in that cycle and
then you might have 40 squid after that
one cycle which is above the limit of
eight assuming that's what it is so the
next cycle it won't try to place any
mobs because it's above that limit so
when you're exploring new areas it's
likely that you like this common that
you'll see lots of squid but if you're
in that area for a long time number of
squid seems to dwindle down to around
eight or so maybe slightly higher
and I don't know I'm rambling about that
it's really late here I'm just trying to
feel time in this episode I guess you
could say so that I can get it out
tonight otherwise it's gonna be another
day without Minecraft ok that's done
sweet just below the clouds and it's
really dark under here now so our next
step will be will have walls out here
I'm not really sure I'm gonna use I'm
guessing sandstone and above every
center of these pads there'll be a hole
that water to flow down to flood it so
I'm gonna work on that have to come up
with some pattern for the post stone
probably try to place four for every pad
for glowstone for a pad type of ink
evenly spaced and I'll see you in a few
minutes as I work this out a bit so
we're up here again I'm thinking we're
gonna work on setting up our water
shut-off system and I believe we're
gonna use one water bucket per for every
two spawning pads so these are the
centers everywhere I have these uh
blocks missing I think they'll work best
if we have a regular piston over here
and water being held in place
in here and when released it will flow
to the two holes because it's in the
center of both of them and when the
piston is powered it'll shut it off
that's the way we'll do it whoo I felt
my damn leg when I shut that water off
yeah so for all the outside ones just in
their water held there you really don't
need much to it this is pretty simple
those animals are really annoying and
one more here two three four I thought
we were gonna do the mob spawning today
or the mob sorting but I don't think
that's gonna happen
at this rate okay so now we have yes
there's only five more holes left and
this one is if we place water here I'll
cover three of the holes
so maybe we'll do that oh but you know
what
no yeah that'll work that will work
pretty sure or no no it's nothing work
hmm yeah we don't really want that
though because it's gonna wreck our
wiring yeah do that and 20 here but if
that's and we'll have one final one over
here do have redstone on me not much it
should be close to enough
I wonder what the best way of doing this
would have been okay I'll finish this up
this is getting really boring and then
we will be back I got this wired now
didn't use too much redstone so the
controls gonna be on the side here and
redstone powers this one signal flows
goes to the very center one here splits
off to the right and left right 1 hours
this piston here also goes off to the
side and it also goes no it ends there
this side goes off that way powers this
one here this wire here powers this and
it keeps going here to this very far one
it's a very minimal requirements for
this and one of my goals was keeping
this all within 2 Box high that's why I
have the repeaters like this to send
power through this block to the other
side because I need this open because
water flows through here that's how we
get our redstone wire over our wire
that's how we get our redstone wire over
our water stream within two blocks
height switch it really likes a game
when you switch it because that's a lot
of water currents to update
for about 30 seconds to a minute then it
seems to settle down now it's now it's
pretty much settled yeah
pretty simple oh damn stealing all my
grass you know yeah I don't have to
glowstone up yet so the grass will die
like this
pretty quickly
brutal alright so we need glowstone in
here see diagonally how should we space
it this is a center it's one two three
four five seven block gap between holes
in some places oh it's eight
so I think maybe we'll just have
redstone the second block out diagonally
from the center so one here one here one
here and one here on all spawning pads
thinking maybe I'll try that out and
then we will be back I'm gonna make a
backup first all right so this is what
the glowstone looks like space like that
I'm pretty happy with it looks okay to
me let me know what you guys think I do
have a backup in case I wanna change my
mind
yeah it should work good
most of the grasses grown back now that
died from the water now that we have the
glowstone it shouldn't die it looks like
with them all flowing it will mess up
the water patterns below which will
likely trap animals in the system at the
time this is not a feature I really
intend on using all the time if at all
ever if I do want to switch Basset mob
spawning off it'll probably for probably
be for long periods of time and as soon
as I walk away from this area any mobs
that are stuck up here will be spawn
actually I don't even have to leave the
area because on these spawning pads my
y-coordinate is 102 and down by the EMP
units is this 71 so it's about 31 blocks
above that mobs despawn if they're 32
blocks away from you 3 dimensional space
so they should be spawn if I'm on the
EMP I guess will be a little bit lower
there'll be about 27 28 blocks above me
and if I'm slightly sideways from them
they will be over 32 blocks away
so they'll despawn if they're stuck up
here even if I'm in the area but yeah
it's a feature I don't really plan on
using much if at all ever but it's nice
to have just in case I need it for
something
all right so let's shut it off cool
thing is the glowstone lights it up here
and it also lights it up below so
double-double function and all these
water screens are thought out now I
thought them
we do need sidewalls for here I'll do
that
off-camera after this episode let me
know if I should use cobblestone if I
should use sandstone I should use snow
tell me what you think or any other
block for the sides yeah so water pulls
them all to the center and then they
fall down that three wide hole there
they'll try to fight it a little bit but
they can't forever
not sure if having ice below would make
that better and I don't know if it's
really worth the hassle even if it does
but I'm kind of curious
okay we're gonna go down below alright
so the reason why I made the spawning
pads
bigger is because of this experiment I
did here I have the mobs falling down to
their death once they get to that center
point so they die quickly so that more
mob stand spot on the patch and what I
found is with only 100 spawn table
spaces the mobs just weren't spawning
quick enough there's only about 5 to 10
up there at once maximum and since the
passive mob spawning tap is bigger than
that let's say I don't know what it is I
think it's either 15 to 25 somewhere
around there so that's how many mobs I
want up there when I'm running this test
and that's what I have now that the pads
are bigger I'm gonna kill all these
chickens otherwise you just run away
they have no way of dying at the moment
but yeah I see 3 5 there's about 15
passive mobs up there all the time
so it's the mob system the spawning pads
been keep up at this rate which is good
and once I add the mob sorting stuff
it'll take them slightly longer to die
in these EMP units because they'll have
to travel a little bit further so I'll
give them even more time to spawn up
there so at this rate it seems to be
good it's a constant stream of falling
mobs
and so far I haven't had any problem
with Bob's not spotting glitch so I
think building my spawning pad on the
Ford region borders is working out good
as they seem to spawn in all four
regions still as far as I can tell my
other passive mob system it would work
for about five ten minutes then it was
just stopped working for you know half
an hour to an hour and I'd have to leave
the area and I'll come back to get it
working again this one is this keeps on
working which is really really good I'm
happy about that okay so we're gonna end
it here and maybe hopefully next time
I'll work on the mob sorting if we do
another mob episode and I will see you
then and thank you for watching take
care bye bye
yeah yeah yeah no it's always fun