hi everyone this is etho now we got
another episode here today the new vita
1.6 batch came out and we're already at
the 1.6.4 patch and so at this episode
we are going to dedicate to talking
about it and its changes and features
let's see where to begin
I don't know if I'm really gonna refer
to this as a patch because for me
anyways it has broken more things than
it's fixed so it's not really beneficial
to me but well as you can see the
passive mob system is still working
maybe not as well as it was before
basically the advantage of having mobs
spawn near torches is gone they spawn
evenly at nights but since I have
removed most of the grass within the
area it still works for me
is what I found there's still some mobs
spawning on my passive mop pads up there
which is good I had to leave the region
and come back to get it working again
though so I think that's still a feature
or bug or whatever
so yeah I have I'm peaceful right now
just for this video let's turn it back
to hard the hostile mob system is also
working still which is good you can see
there spawning down there hopefully the
4-way mob evader still works but I have
heard from people that it no longer
works for spiders that they get stuck in
it now
I haven't confirmed this but that's just
the rumor that's going around which is
probably true since the water behavior
has changed drastically yet again but
you can see they're going up it's good
very glad that didn't break
I'm not gonna talk about everything that
changed with this patch if you want a
good coverage of what happened I'm going
to link statics overview of the patch in
my description you can check it out
I made I'm mainly gonna talk about which
of my designs have broken and also puff
up the features later in this episode
and on a positive note hopefully yeah
that's still working the killing
mechanism is still working I just heard
my Zelda tune so I guess that's still
working I didn't know that uh-huh okay
see how do I get up something that isn't
working anymore is the water sensors I'm
officially locked out of my control room
I replaced up the blocks that were here
with the new trapdoors which would have
been nice if this actually was working I
think I can get this working again
though I say I'm gonna stop the video
now and try something if it works I'll
try it on one of them and if it works
I'll show you what I did on the second
one alright good news the ID I had it
worked so I'll be able to fix these the
only problem is it reverses the doors or
it reverses the signal so that might be
an issue
I'm just gonna grab some more water
everything out here seems to be fine my
tactus farm and i believe my tree farm
is okay i haven't tried a harvesting any
trees yet though I am having issues with
my dam crashing frequently when I go
fullscreen still that was before this
patch but this patch didn't fix that for
me so a lot of times when I press f11 to
go fullscreen the game crashes which
sucks so what I have done
very simple I've added another water
block another water source in the sensor
so I'm gonna do the same thing for this
one it's kind of hard to do so
diagonally of where the water stream
goes down normally I'm gonna put another
water source here and I have to be very
careful not to leak water and destroy
all my redstone wiring and destroy the
boats which is a bit of a challenge
especially in this tight area so when
I'm placing this water block I have to
be very careful not to click this boat
so I aim for the very corner and I'm
gonna place the glass and it's fixed
that's all I had to do so the way the
new water works if a boat touches a
water source block it will float up very
slowly if it touches like
a water stream that's flowing downward
like you see in front of you here the
boat will sink if the boat is in the
water source block and a stream that's
flowing downward like the boat is here
the stream that is flowing downward
overpowers the buoyancy from the water
source block so even though this block
here is pushing it up and this one is
pushing it down the block that's pushing
it down is more powerful so it stays
down is what I have found so far so with
this in mind if I remove the water above
this water source back here will cause
the boat to float and go off the
pressure plate so it's reversed from
what it was before which is kind of
weird
I'm going to connect those two again and
let's test it out doors are still closed
there we go takes a little bit longer
for it to activate as well because the
boat Rises slower or could deactivate
uh-huh so before when I had to water
these two water sources here the door
was opened but now it's closed so it's
reversed not a big deal
and I can fix that by inverting the
redstone signal if I want let's get rid
of that
please sir trapdoor back there that's
one thing fixed let's see what else
let's take a stroll many many bugs were
fixed in this patch which is good glad
to see that because there's a lot of
annoying bugs in this team unfortunately
some of those bugs were actually what I
consider features which are now gone oh
yeah that's what I was going to point
out I almost think the game is a little
bit lay here now I'm not sure though or
here is the spider separator I had and
they were being killed by lava using the
southwest corner glitch that no longer
works so this will still drown the
spiders what I have here but the lava
won't do anything because it won't hurt
them through the way through the corners
anymore so that kind of sucks but at the
moment I don't even have spiders coming
up
so it's not not a huge issue pretty sure
all this stuff works the same although
that wasn't supposed to happen oh you
know why I'd have this opened
I think I'm not sure how that should go
down there I'll have to watch this video
again after
oh yeah let's go down to the mine hurts
I heard when I heard that the old
booster glitch with my carts was gonna
be fixed I really didn't care because I
didn't think it was gonna affect me but
then I was like oh yeah I'm actually
using that with this thing I completely
forgot
so uh my whole minecart system is busted
control room is pointless because it was
supposed to control this minecart system
so yeah I'll probably fix this by using
one of pearl squirrels minecart
solutions I'll link that in the
description as well I had to rush down
here I used to have lava in this column
here I had to rush down here and remove
it
as soon as I patched my Dame because I
have the wooden half slabs here which
used to not burn but now they do with
this new patch so if I didn't catch that
quick there was a good chance my storage
room would have burnt down I believe oh
hey oh darn did you guys see that
I guess the leavers still floating not
okay it is fixed let's go down to the
east road it seems every patch that's
released the east row takes another hits
and it has to in its worst hit yet
okay maybe before we go to the ether I
should explain something
this new faucet sprinkler or sprinkler
system I have installed in my house you
see how it's raining right now ah boat
is floating how does that work well if I
push this boat into the water stream
that's flowing down there's only one
source block and it's at the top there
and there are so this is a downward
flowing water stream and yet the boat
rises in it very very slowly but it does
that's the new nerfed water elevators a
new speed of them very very slow but
with our water sensor doesn't work that
way does it
why well if there is air around the
water stream blocks it seems to make the
boat rise but I believe I haven't tried
this yet if there is solid blocks next
to this water screen it won't rise if my
understanding is correct like I said I
haven't tried this and I am correct so
the boat isn't rising because there is
solid blocks next to this water do you
remove one still not rising for some
reason
that's kind of strange still not rising
aerial yes that is definitely less Baidu
looking knotch good job on this fix I
don't know why he wasted his time doing
this so yeah that's the new principle
with the boats maybe before we go down
to eats let's test out the new minecarts
too apparently these power rails give
you a better boost I haven't seen it for
myself yet except through statics video
I watched I think they were a lot faster
oh yeah that's fast that's fast that's
too fast I can't even catch it
here comes let's try this again let's
hop in at this time huh
I know that looks about the same speed
to me maybe the momentum just last
longer it's probably what it is
okay now let's go down to eats eats is
very broken by this patch I have been
down here though fixing it little by
little I've been coming up with ways to
fix it going through lots of boats okay
first thing the easy loader was broken
I'll show you what it was doing this is
how I had my ez loader normally when you
place the boat in the center it aligns
it properly but after the patch it just
explodes into this wall I almost think
boats travel faster in water now from
what I've seen and I think that might be
why that's happening but I'm not
entirely sure why or what has changed
thankfully I have come up with a new ez
loader using this new pattern just to
get our stuff down here
so I'm glad there's uh other ways of
doing it I've heard other people's easy
loaders are working too so they probably
have them set up slightly different than
I had mine here but this method is
working for me place in the center still
source blocks over here and it gets
aligned properly which is great and now
due to only having source blocks up here
I only have two before the boats women
tries but I have changed that this water
elevator is solid source blocks now so
that's why the boat was able to come up
it just takes a lot longer now for it to
get up
major lake Wow
yes oh these are all solid water source
blocks I have the sign here to hold the
water in place with this new easy loader
it seems to line them properly so they
get snug like they are supposed to here
now the problem is though that eats Road
at least my design here is broken it
works if you're not in the boats if you
try to hop into a boat like you normally
do something really bad happens boat
goes backwards for a second it breaks
and if it's hollow underneath you fall
through the ground so that is garbage
the boat actually goes backwards for a
second when you hop into it for some
strange reasons definitely seems more
bug to me I had to make one other change
here before I had a downward water
stream here well let the whole elevator
I can't put a solid source block here
because the water will pour out and wash
away my redstone wiring so instead I
have a sign there to hold the water in
place and it seems to work just fine
so yeah
now if you try to hop into a boat while
it's already moving it breaks the old
vitro did that - I'm pretty sure most
the time so yeah this current road
design does not work I have an idea on
how to make a working one but it
involves more work which sucks
and with the new improvements with the
minecarts you're pretty much better off
just using mine carts from now on in all
honesty you were before - really it's
just if you want something different in
your world and you then eats road is
like a choice because it's pretty cool
in my opinion and this is another water
elevator with the water source box at
the top and none throughout so that's
why the boats boats are getting stuck
here so that's another major kick in the
shins for eats
one of the best features of it before
was you could go up and down pretty much
instantly using water elevators and now
that feature has been removed from the
game so yeah but if you want to boat
dispensers still work it's just the road
itself you can't really ride with this
current design so I'm gonna do some more
experiments with it and I'll hopefully
release tutorials like I keep promising
except with the new fixes I think that's
all I wanted to talk about it for eats I
think I've covered the whole world now
it's a pretty small world
the barns still working still not done
though oh yeah
gee all nether mod still works
of course even with the new patch just
to clarify one thing guys I wanted you
to figure out that it was a trick
I wanted to mislead you for the first
few minutes and then keep giving me more
and more hints until you finally
realized what was going on was my plan
and that's exactly how it worked out so
I'm happy about that because people
still are telling me what those blue
shiny rocks are for everyday and that's
getting annoying because I didn't
clarify that it was a joke so I don't
want people telling me we're talking to
me about mods constantly so that's why I
wanted to reveal that that was a joke if
I really wanted to mislead you I
definitely could I'm pretty sure
okay so I think I covered all the
negative and broken things about the
patch so let's try to end this episode
on a positive high note if we can let's
go to the nether I'll tell you some of
the new features of this patch one thing
I saw in docum seventy sevens video
about the patch he tried to sleep in a
bed in the nether I thought this was
pretty funny I want to see if it works
for me too doc has a pretty good sense
of humor
that's pretty cool exploding beds in the
nether
so another support has been added in
multiplayer apparently I don't know if
that's true or not I haven't checked it
out for myself but that's cool and
apparently some other
fix's like network packets gets
compressed more so that's good be less
lag that's cool that's the first time I
went through the portal since I built
this thing I didn't know it brought me
back out through that one Wow today I
got 60 to another rack from that
explosion oh I'm gonna be abusing
exploding beds for as long as they last
that's a really good way to go mining in
the nether there's a new bug in the game
every time you start in your world you
seem to lose half a hearts oh no no I'm
done talking about the problems we're on
to the positive sorry I forgot yeah so
leather support in multiplayer that's
cool
lots of bug fixes like you can I think
yeah when a player shoots their arrows
and stuff in multiplayer it looks a lot
less glitchy things like doors and that
place sounds and multiplayer when they
open and close that's cool you can craft
maps now not a very useful feature for a
single player in my opinion but that
would be cool and multiplayer if you
could hand out maps to people of the
world that's how you craft it this is
the first one I'm making select it and
my team legs like crazy there we go wow
that really causes a bit of lag
so if you look down towards the ground
you can see the map how it works
don't know if you can zoom in or
anything and there might be a way of
naming them too but I have no idea how
that's cool be cool and multiplayer or
if people make challenge maps and stuff
I could see maps being useful it's a
very cool from a programming perspective
a very cool feature um you've got the
trap doors oops
make them like that they can be
controlled with redstone as far as I
know this is my absolute favorite part
of this patch these trap doors I've
wanted something like this for a long
time
it's basically my minecart skate
compressed into a single block except
even better
yep
and controllable by redstone well that's
strange then to go back down there when
I remove the torch huh wasn't expecting
that
leader and I don't have any buttons on
me otherwise I would try that
yeah that makes it closed a little bit
strange okay what I like most about
these doors as they open upward I was
sure they were gonna make him open
downward and if they did that they would
be a lot less useful in my opinion and
here's why so if they opened upward the
hinge doesn't get in the way because now
when I opened this the door will be
inside of me
so I'll fall straight through it that
means you can drop a one by one block
like and drop a tower that or any other
mob will fall through this hatch thing
very cool very useful for mob systems
among other things I see lots of
possible uses for this new door doors
are one of my favorite things in the
scheme so to have another type is very
cool I'm gonna set one other thing up
here another cool use of them alright
here's another cool thing about these
new hatches or trap doors you can use
them as item drop junctions or gates
right now they're collecting there if I
was to open this they would fall down
again that's pretty much what I was
doing with my minecart gates except this
is much better and so if I wanted it to
fall down this one instead had it opened
and they fall down there instead of
going to this one so that's really cool
if they're on top they fall down even if
they're above the hinge that's great
mobs will fall down I'm pretty sure if
you have a minecart on they'll fall down
boats they'll fall through players
probably TNT I would like to try sand
actually I don't think the sand will
fall through yeah it just floats on top
yeah I like these things though they're
very cool favorite part of the patch by
far yeah there's just so many things you
can do with these yep pretty cool I like
those a lot of some other things
there's tall grass in the game now that
showed to you if I saw me but I have no
grass around so yeah apparently mushroom
spread very slowly these two were here
before and no new ones I've shown up and
I think guy why didn't cover everything
but I covered all I wanted to they're
just so cool okay
yeah lots of stuff broken I'll fix it I
feel really bad for Doc to him though he
his whole world got messed up so show
him your love guys and make sure you
watch his a new world before that he's
gonna be giving because he's a cool guy
he'd ask cool designs and stuff and I'm
sure his new girl it's gonna be awesome
as well alright and that's it for me
thank you for watching if you did and
goodbye