hello everyone this is etho and we have
another wonderful episode of let's play
minecraft today with me ito what slopped
here I'm chewing gum right now I'm not
sure if it'll pick up over the mic but
my throat usually gets sore doing these
so I'm hoping I'm hoping I can chew gum
without it being annoying but we're
gonna be working on this again today a
hostile mob system so no more tests for
right now we're gonna just go ahead and
start building yes we got the cows so we
miss him turn that down I was told this
spider separator that I wanted to make
was done by a drinker tank and I found
his video for it too so I'll post in the
description hopefully if I remember
oops dang it but it looks pretty good so
I'm just gonna build this up three high
three high is my lot man just like that
and fill it in with water it's gonna be
another building episode I'm sorry I
don't know what you guys like I try to
do a mix of everything except for
spelunking oh yeah I'm thinking about
making my world a little bit nicer soon
I've been doing a few odds and ends
around the place like getting rid of you
know over there we I had that big hole
where I took out all the sand there's
still one there but I got rid of one of
the islands so it looks like water now
and I've been cleaning up a few other
things to completely redoing the barn I
think but let's let's work on this uh uh
transporting water takes so long
sometimes I hate tearing more than two
budgets just clogs up the your inventory
so I think I'm gonna make it go this way
so I'm gonna build this up some more -
hi and there'll be a cover over it and
the water needs to flow I can put these
here they won't flow over and there will
be a hole here and then yeah so the tall
mops are going to fall down here that's
the way it works and the spiders are
going to keep going I hope never made
this spider separator
Gavin's gonna do a soil roof for right
now temporarily and I wonder wait - oh I
did that wrong right yeah just don't go
there do that I could probably make
this only one high after that point so
spiders will fit through there
Paula mobs will fall down here and I'm
gonna put some signs just so that the
water doesn't flow over and from what I
saw in shrinker tanks video
this is absolutely clogged free which is
what I want because that's actually
pretty hard to do
Jay let's get some more water a secret
project progress I've somewhat started
it but I haven't done too much with it
yet we kind of kind of busy lately but
I'll I'll get to it once I start I know
I'm gonna get lots done put that there
so the tall mops will fall in a stream
below spiders will swim up and drown
somehow
how should we do that well we can cover
this let's hit some torches so we can
see and we will extend this some more
okay that should be good
I'll fill this in and we should have a
hole for the items to fall down to we
need to root the items down or that
water is and make them fall down there
and I know I know how I'm gonna do the
record studio finally it's been like 50
episodes but I finally have like the
perfect idea which I will hopefully get
to see Rijn bust that out that's where
the items will fall down and we'll have
a sign
feel like I forgot something all right I
went to got some more glass and I stick
today so that we can see a little bit
better it's kind of dark here still so
the way I'm going to do this actually is
I'm going to put another water here so
then it's little straight there's
something I want to try we're gonna make
this two blocks otherwise it'll make
it'll be hard to get this streams to
point right without adding more water so
it'll be like no that's not what I want
and it's not what I want Jay I want the
signs over here
like to that okay so the spiders will
get pushed in then I want a stream over
here pushing in this way and I want a
trapdoor
oops
I'm gonna put my trapdoor on there
hopefully oh wait no that's too low
oh yeah well let's do the stream first
then stream we'll go across I should
probably be doing this off-camera oh
yeah if I do that to cancel them up huh
I guess I'll have to use signs actually
when replace this with actual glass and
so what we learned from our last video
the water is I think it was five level
five they won't drown that would be
eight seven six we got to go one more I
think I'll run it here like this and
something like this
[Music]
so the water will go here and that will
allow the spiders to swim up it and then
we'll place a sign a lot of work to
making a mob system keep that in mind if
you ever do lots of lots of little
tedious work like this but the sign
there and I suppose one over here now
ouch just for now I'm going to put dirt
under here so you can jump up so
basically I have a water block pushing
to the right here that the spider should
swim up without drowning and then we can
have a trapdoor over here like that so
they won't drown in this in this stream
here and the streams pushing them this
way so they hinge on this trapdoor ssin
and being away either
hopefully okay so we've got that we can
injure that way we can control if we
want the spiders to drown or if we want
them to collect and why you'd want them
to collect I don't know but it's just
something some little extra control we
can have for no real purpose
cuz that's the way I roll okay okay I'm
gonna finish
okay we can cover this we'll put some
more signs
I'm so glad knotch added shift-clicking
okay so we need something for the water
to be suspended by so we're going to put
signs and we'll have water and you need
one over here okay let's go up some more
so I'm gonna fill this in with water and
then they should drown so I'll be right
back alright I finished filling that in
with solid water somehow I fell through
this glass - I like stepped in the water
and then fell through the glass kind of
strange this is all solid water and
sorry I hope you guys aren't getting
sick so there's three air pockets here
and one stream pushing them to the right
or that they won't drown in trap door
holding them down if we want if it's
open they'll swim up and drown hopefully
cover on that and I just did it again
and again man that's weird
right now I just have a lever hooked up
to the trapdoor but I'll probably hook
up redstone and wire down to the control
room
yeah so this should be ready for a test
so that's what I'm gonna do the might
how's this work
tall mobs fall down here string falls
down here okay so I'm gonna get some
spiders up here and see what happens
here they come
oh oh
no he's not swimming up oh because I
have the trapdoor help yeah that's
exactly what one
they're very cheerful feathers shooting
through the glass yeah
oh dang they hit a creeper oh okay I'm
gonna let them collect and stand far far
far away as that happens houston we have
a problem there's a jam the spiders they
climb up and then get stuck in the
ceiling so I need to put instead of
having the gap down there I need it up
there after all so I might have to redo
all this let's try the release it's good
swims up should drown
Oh major like the skeletons don't shoot
if you put blocks in the corner
and let's see if the string falls down
here oh shoot
okay I heard some skeletons shooting
alright that sound nice Lili grouped
together so I'm gonna fix that and then
we'll be back alright so I made the
changes it's still not perfect but it
works
they kind of kindly get stuck here but
the mobs pushing them will cause him to
eventually go so it's only if they're on
their own like that like you would
probably get stuck there forever
if I'm unless another mob came up behind
them then he'd get pushed in and of
course he's doing that because there's
tons of mobs there a normally a stream
would take them away and I think I've
reached the mob limit almost so what I
ended up doing I had to raise it all up
another block and I added in it's the
same thing I just raised it a block up
and I added in a few extra signs here
and that's it so watch these guys should
push this spider into here
or maybe not there's this too many guys
there he's not not going
they keep knocking him back but anyway
it does seem to work pretty good
I'm and this release works good they
drown there so that might be useful for
example let's say them mob limit was a
hundred hundred hostile mobs at a time
if I wanted spiders to collect I would
have this trapdoor down and I would have
these Paul mobs being killed constantly
and over time oh oh that's a problem
string landed on the trapdoor oh well I
guess I got to get rid of this feature
then because that's going to be a
serious problem and there's no way
around that
okay well you say I do better than that
I can get rid of it just by lowering it
one level so the next thing I need to do
is I need to run a water stream to this
hole here and I'll probably have another
trap door above right here I got it
working really good now guys I made two
main changes to this
the really important changes I have
half-slabs there now whole date that was
a close one
those skeletons can see me through these
coroner's here I would need to put
blocks here
just keep that from happening but yeah I
have half slabs there so it's a block
and a half opening there's a water
stream above pushing the spiders to the
left and since it's a block and a half
tall mobs don't fit but the spiders do
and yeah and then this is actually not a
problem because if if I want them
drowning it needs to be open like that
what I did is I removed the two source
blocks here so now there's a stream
going to the right so if any string was
to land on the trapdoor that a little
section there the stream would pull it
off anyway so that is not a problem
after all because the door won't be down
like that it'll be up so yeah I'm gonna
let this thing fill up and then you'll
see it's getting pretty full now
so since those are half-slabs now if the
spiders fought like before those were
glass blocks where the half slabs were
and when the spiders were forced against
the glass blocks it was like them being
against the wall but when when their
force against the half slabs it forces
the spiders climb up them much like we
walked up half slabs and so they're
forced up half a block and then they are
in the water stream above so they're
forced through it kind of thing so we
got I would say at least pan in there 10
spiders let's see it
that stream over there pushes them away
from the hinge so they all do what no
problem and since the water over here is
level 7 it's still drown no problem it's
only if it's level 5 or less that they
won't drown
and all this drink Lex 100% so it's 100%
efficient so all in all I'm pretty happy
with this so we just need the stream
below and then we'll have a trapdoor
here and that will be controlled at the
front of our collection area I have
those two levers if this is closed items
can't fall down if it's open
they can't pretty simple so I'm gonna
run a stream and I'll be back so then we
stood a ton of glass building the same
but it works really well it's all done
now well basically all done very happy
with how this turned out
spiders go up they drown none get stuck
there's no dead zones they all drown
items get collected 100% and there's
just a stream underneath there now that
goes left goes around this Bend through
this trapdoor here see all the string
down there it was
yeah listen and make sure no creepers
get shot so it goes here this trapdoor
here will allow me to turn string on or
off in my main collection area down
below so if I just want to collect say
gunpowder for example I don't want
spring in the stream I would have this
closed if I if I want the string I would
have it open and it would go down this
trapdoor is for turning on or off all
hostile mob drops so if I wanted just a
passive ones on and the hostile ones off
I have that option that's idea behind
these ones here and that's all there is
to it so
Spyder handling is done so now I just
need to do the tall mobs and I still
need to do the passive mobs redo them
get that working better it's weird it's
like there's two clusters here there's a
block over there and this one here and
anything else is is bouncing back and
forth between them really quick
but the next thing I need I think I'm
gonna have a junction of some sort one
option will take them tall mobs to a
cook house which is a way of killing
skeletons and zombies from sunlight I
call it a cook house and the creepers
will live the other option for the
junction is to go straight to a killing
machine that kills all all three of them
and sends the loot to our trap door
there that's the logic behind this but
yeah that's it for today guys
thank you for watching I don't know if
I'll I'll do that next episode but the
next time I work on this hopefully soon
I'll I'll be doing that but anyway thank
you for watching and have a good night
or morning or afternoon or whatever it
is for you