[Music]
hello people
how we doing today
[Music]
i hope you're all ready to watch some
more minecraft
make sure you got your snacks and
beverages all ready
yeah that's how we do it okay so what
have i been up to
i have collected some more resources
uh what um let's see
okay first of all i used the bone meal
we had i drew a bunch of trees here
chop them down got a bunch of wood so
that's where this came from
i also went to the desert with some
shovels
and i got a ton of sand sandstone
and a little bit of cobblestone so so
we're getting some blocks together
trying to get a jump start for our
project
uh yeah i've been thinking up of plans
of how we're going to build our main
base our starting base here
before we get to that though i want to
play around with some of the new blocks
and that's why i got this stuff cooking
here
first of all i want to make the new
stone blocks
i think i know how to it's just a four
and you get forced stone bricks
cool
and then you can make half slabs
get three
and you can also make stairs
there's one thing i really want to check
out here
somebody told me if you place the stairs
and break them you get the mossy
stone bricks and i want to see if that's
true or not
of course it's a lie darn it
i was excited i thought you could
actually check the wiki just to make
sure
okay well i'm really glad i checked the
wiki because apparently it is true
this is a very interesting
uh they only produce the mossy stone
bricks if they're facing
i forgot already i think it was north
so that's regular
did we get one yeah we got one there
cool so that's facing
that's east if we go by real world
sun rising that's west
oh i'm really bad at this game east west
then that would be
north so if the stairs facing north you
get mossy
south is regular
west is the crack kind so that's cool
you can get
get all three
you stay put so i'm happy
uh because don't tell sandstone i said
this but these are actually my
new favorite block i love them they're
so cool
however one thing
like i'm really happy you can you can
actually make these because
since this is my favorite block it's
cool to have variety
with it and we have
three different types plus we have
stairs
and we have the half slabs
very good so lots of variety with these
things
and i want to see what happens if you
break one of these
do you get it back you do good
very good
yeah i still do like sandstone though a
lot i
i find it works better for dark areas
like if you're building something
underground
because it's a block with a high
luminance
and it's a plain texture so it seems to
make it brighter than
actually is if you're in a dark area
while these are
gray ish so they don't do that as well
but they sure do look good when they're
in the light
and from a distance they look really
good too i imagine
because uh it's a large
texture unlike cobblestone
which is a small repeating pattern type
thing while this is a large
repeating pattern so it looks better
from farther away
i'm assuming and they actually blend
together
well that's good if you have like a
cracked one next to it
cool okay uh moving on
we also have the new glass panes i
believe you make them like this
oh and you get 16 cool
that is very good so what i want to try
out
today you know like how every patch
seems to mess up each road
oh this is like the first patch in a
long time that i think is gonna
really help it out so i'm gonna set up a
small eats road here
using the new glass panes and see
if they work how i think they'll work
yeah so what we're gonna do i made some
water buckets here
we're just gonna set up a very small
eats road
test over here if it goes well i will
probably use
eats roads a lot in my new
base that i'm making
and i want to try these glass panes out
because they have a unique property they
are very thin and they
fill in like the middle of a block
so if i place them like
like this
boats are between one and a half and two
blocks in size
so this is probably
about two blocks wide here the space
between these two panes
so really a boat should fit between here
and it's only one two
three four five blocks this way for two
lanes
so it's smaller than the ones i usually
make and it will be enclosed still
that's really good so let's let's extend
this
won't get too crazy i don't want to
waste all my supplies here
oops stack them on top of each other oh
what you get them back
okay that's awesome i did not know that
all right well i don't feel bad doing
this now
i wonder why you get them back doesn't
make much sense
okay so you do that i'll make some
wooden pressure plates to hold the water
actually that's another thing i wanted
to check do vines
hold water in place
nope they don't water destroys them
but doesn't harvest them
let's try to get to bed before the
monsters come out
actually i should see if these give you
what these give you
oh they give you the whatever they are
the wiki said silverfish will hide in
them if they sit for a while
i think even if their player placed but
to correct me if i'm wrong on that
because i would like to know
and stone blocks look pretty good with
them too so they're very
very versatile these are the blocks i'm
planning on building
the new base with
the main blocks and also grass water
stuff like that
but these five are the main ingredient
come on come on come on
yeah we made it some people were
wondering why monsters weren't attacking
me there when i sleep in my bed if you
do it
while it's still getting dark monsters
won't be spawning yet
and they seem to only attack you if
they're within
the area when you go to sleep
otherwise they won't attack you
okay so where are we at here yeah we
gotta place water in here
put pressure plates to hold it
now we'll put it here water
three blocks water
and one more here and maybe we'll end it
there we'll just have a small loop
okay and do the same on the other side
missed maybe i'll have a cut here to
speed this up
i got it set up for our first test
so i just had to use whatever blocks i
had around here i've used sand on top
these will replace using ladders having
full blocks above
glass panes because
you have that air space between so this
space here holds the boat down still i
hope
we'll see this is the first test let's
try it out
very nice very very nice
that is what i wanted to see
now i want to try to do it with me
riding it and see if
these blocks will suffocate me
if they're sticking out far enough
i don't know these easy loaders though i
don't think they're working anymore
oh i missed it
yeah it breaks um
i don't know why it's doing that i think
one of the patches change things again
what i'll do maybe try set up a door
let's do it over here
don't have a lot of space to work with
uh no we want the door to open the other
way towards the boat
where's my door
so this way
opens towards the boat now
and that should stop it
so if i try to enter the boat loading it
with the easy loader it will
break but if i align it with a door
i believe it will work
oops
dang it
[Applause]
getting dark again
i thought i just slept
here we go again okay
out of boots
would be really good if i could get this
working
i want to do it while i'm in the boat um
uh we can make a lever
just for testing
i believe yeah right here
good it didn't break oh we took some
damage there
but we were able to ride it that's cool
so after that
this is what i think is going to look
really good if we replace all this
with the glass
and then it's all glass throat
that's pretty cool so that's like my
new eats road design and i'll probably
use it a fair bit
in this world
because it's a lot more compact than it
used to be and i think it looks
pretty good
all right cool um if we break glass
blocks now
i'm assuming we don't get them back yeah
we still don't
darn okay
um moving on let's do something else
actually there's one more really quick
thing i want to try out here uh so i
want to see
if we have the blocks above the middle
divider here instead of on the outside
if that will work uh it would be cool if
it did because then you would have
it more open on the sides and you'd be
able to see
your scenery in that a lot better if you
don't have the blocks in your face
let's see let's see
it held it down it's being held down
cool i still got it okay
yeah it works cool
so that's even better i like it i like
it a lot now we can do something else
all right so we're back here this is
that location i found last episode where
i want to build my new
base i've been marking some
key locations here with sand and gravel
right now we're at the 250 250 one
the mob system the hostile one's going
to go directly above here this is going
to be the center point of it
this 250 by 250 and i'm going to build
i'm pretty much going to copy the last
one i made
there's going to be four towers
put together and there's going to be
four layers in each so 16 layers
total and they will
occupy this space here from this gravel
column
to that sand there to
that gravel over in the back there and
then
to there that's how big
the mob floating mob
terrible looking thing in the sky is
gonna be
uh these two by two
columns are where their center points
are going to be for the four different
uh towers and i'll have to join them
together somehow
and then over there is another like
uh so
this makes a 31 by 31 square
that's how big the mob towers are going
to be
and then further over that we have
another 31 by 31 square
that is for a courtyard i want to build
i most likely will uh
not i have a general idea of what i want
to do but i don't know
exactly what i want to do i was thinking
of
maybe making a giant tree like doc m did
but i know one thing i need to keep the
area above these two by two columns
clear
so if i put the tree here i would want
the tree to hide the floating mob towers
above
i could hide it in the tree canopy
the giant tower
quiet quiet
if i did that but what i found out is i
would need to make
the diameter of the tree about 30 blocks
which would look a little silly i think
because if you have a tree with diameter
of 30
and a height of 64. it's only going to
be
twice as high as it is what wide you
know
it'll look a little strange so
uh the giant tree idea is kind of out at
the moment and
instead i'm thinking of just having a
lot of little trees around the place
because i want the green look of the
trees
you guys suggested something really cool
too i should build my storage room
underwater so
that is a very high probability i'll
probably do that
around my courtyard there's gonna be
boat docks i think
and they'll also probably be bridges
which will lead off to other areas such
as the desert over there
and those bridges will probably be eats
roads
i don't know just thinking way in the
future
uh but one thing i i'm planning on here
i need
blocks i need a lot of dirt for this
project i need
sand stuff like that so what i'll do
is i'll harvest it from the seabed here
as much as i can
so like this it's only one block deep
here i
this would be a good place to get blocks
from
especially if i plan on building the
storage room
underwater i would like this water
deeper then
so that's one thing i'll probably do off
camera
i would use tnt but i don't have it
unfortunately
so until i get some i have to use a
shovel
here we go everyone i'm about to start
placing down our foundation for this
thing i'm just going to make a huge
square here
to save on blocks i'm going to make it
too thick for right now and we're three
blocks
above the water
so yeah i'm going to use a lot of blocks
in this project
i'm basically building an island here
it's not just
not just a house or anything it's going
to be an island
there'll be grass and stuff uh the
courtyard
this is where i'm planning the courtyard
right here
uh it'll be kind of like a garden area
there'll be flowers and trees and stuff
like that in it
just to look nice
and i got other things planned for it
too
there'll be a fountain in the middle of
it i'm assuming
so yeah i'm gonna make a square all
around
and then i gotta get grass over here too
so i need to find
i guess that's a pretty close spot to
get grass so i'll have to
bring that over here and start
grassing up this giant square i'm making
and this will just give us a nice
starting foundation to work off of
check it out it's coming together
placing lots of blocks here i got a lot
of them
from the sea floor
the water is deeper now in a lot of
places
but i was finding about 70 of the block
size gained from the
sea floor were actually sand and i need
soil
so instead i went to
over there where those pine trees are
next to the desert and i started just
harvesting soil
from that island that area over there is
kind of what i designated as
my feel free to wreck place
so that's where i'm going to get my sand
from mostly and
from and i'll probably
bulldoze that island slowly as i need
resources
[Music]
because it's within range of the mob
system i need to get rid of it too
so yeah just placing down soil i noticed
something though
uh in the new 1.8 patch when you hold
down
right click for me anyway with your
mouse
it's placing blocks a lot slower now
like a lot
a lot slower
before when i would do this it would
skip like every 20 blocks or so now it's
dipping every
four or so so i need to spam right click
now instead
can't just hold right click
[Applause]
yeah i got to fill this all in this is
about 2 000 blocks this
first square pretty plain right now
but it's like our blank canvas
and this new lp i'm going to try to be
less
indecisive about things that was another
issue i felt i had
before i would plan things out
in too great of detail and then they
would
rarely work out because a patch would
mess them up or something
in this one i'm just gonna get a rough
idea of what i want to build and just go
ahead and build it
it might not be perfect but i'll figure
it out as i go along
and that way stuff will actually get
built quicker
i'm hoping we'll see uh so i also
put up a path here for the dress to come
in
i could move it with pistons but
it's just easier to make a soil path
build it and forget about it
i've heard that you move faster if you
jump while you're dashing
slightly faster and yeah
this is all the soil i have left it's
not going to be quite enough so i'll
have to go get some more
in total i've used about 20 to 30
shovels iron shovels in this world
already
harvesting soil and sand
i'm actually running low on iron because
of that so i'll have to go
caving again soon
but yeah just gonna fill this in and i
will call the episode an
end here for today uh thank you for
watching as always and hopefully we can
start building
something interesting soon and until
then
take care