hi everyone this is evil how y'all doing
raining like crazy
strain all the time
good thing I have a nice shelter over
top anyway this episode we're going to
be working on waffles again last episode
I said I wanted to redo the Baconator so
that the pigs will fall
down there I moved it over one block
then I tested out the astroturf ID it
looks decent so we're going to be
dropping the pigs down here either into
lava or fire I'm not quite sure yet what
the pork I'm like all out of food in my
world now so we need to get this working
ASAP so let's get let's get to work here
yeah I just ate my last piece of bacon
so we need to carefully demolish this
without spreading water everywhere
hopefully and let's place our lab over
here there's going to be a mostly
building episode so yeah I'm completely
get rid of this thing
because I would like to get some court
cooked pork chops instead I kind of keep
switching between saying bacon and pork
chops so I guess it's kind of to please
everybody pick out four for calling
bacon though even though that's probably
not correct J yeah so this update no no
aah
eat one water preserve much damage that
do
that's probably fine okay so the really
hard to see with we're all the glasses
here I'll probably run last longer
bottom here yeah okay
so pigs and wolves will fit through this
actually can't put it on there
the thing is that pigs can fit in a one
by one space so we kind of make these
half blocks when we to extend the screen
so we need sign here and this will keep
going out
okay I want to make sure the water
doesn't spill out I'll probably actually
close this off some updates things okay
and then we can place more water I'm
just going to place another sign here
and make sure the water doesn't spill
half there they will come along get
pushed up and then we're going to make
them fall again I'm going to build some
I'm going to place some cobblestone here
so I can walk around and then then we'll
be back okay so I just realized
something
excuse me it's going to be really ugly
if I have this sticking out like I do
plan on making this look better when
it's all done but it's going to be
really hard to make something that
sticks out that far that looks normal
I think so I'll probably just make the
pigs come down here instead
make it make it have a lower profile I
guess you could say so yeah it'll
probably make it drop around here the
same time I don't want it to be in the
way of my hostile mob system I don't
exactly know what I'm going to be
building down there but what can you do
I guess yeah so let's just punch a hole
down here
that pigs gonna push me off and you know
it now here X yeah we need one more sign
and then the pigs and wolves are going
to fall down that hole and then we'll
probably have a water break so they
don't take damage get this all closed
off okay that should be good I think
yeah so I will be destroying all this
combo light is placed unfortunately but
I'm not going to be doing that just yet
I'll do that off camera because that
stuff is painful to watch okay so let's
make a tube that comes down here
I hope none of us get motion sickness
all right yeah so this will be a lot
nicer will be lower profile still having
a huge platform sticking out of my
hopefully will be a finished basically
and I think I have some more science
down here yep so we'll have a water
break here's probably good that way they
don't take damage and then
I'll drop there will be a water source
here I'm kind of making this up as I go
along
okay oh you know what yeah we should
probably start the Wolfe separating as
soon as possible here so I'm going to
have a diagonal stream of water I guess
[Music]
I'm not sure if my idea here is going to
work but we'll find out I guess um let's
see let's just use cobblestone and so I
think if we have a block of cobblestone
ladder
[Music]
I think this is going to work I'm not
sure if we make these little gaps like
this
the pigs won't fit through these but the
wolves will then we'll have a water
stream below the ladder that hopefully
the Wolves will drop into that's my plan
not sure how well this is gonna work
[Music]
it's a little bit hard to build it here
- yeah I think this will work I don't
know I don't know how many of these
we'll need to get all the Wolves out
separated properly I'm just going to put
a cap on the end here for now and then
we'll extend it if this idea works now
let's do one more of these ladder things
I guess
and the water will flow like this so
they'll fall down and they'll get pushed
to this wall here only the Wolves will
be able to fit through so I'm going to
put glass overtop this so that they
can't jump around and we'll see if the
wolves and I dip through that or how
well they do I'm not sure it's probably
better if the ladders on this side
instead of this side I think so that's
what I'm going to try first and I'll let
you know how it turns out I'm going to
take a while so I universe so I'll be
back in a bit all right finally we got
some wolves oh I've been waiting for
like 15 minutes for them to spawn and
yeah this idea seems to work the pigs
can't fit through these gaps and the
Wolves can as you can see I've been
killing tons of pigs stuck over here
so yeah this should be pretty cool I
think three is probably enough like
three of these ladder separators I think
they're most likely to go into this one
or this one
all right so we can we'll just have like
water to pull them to where we want them
to go and the pig thing will just keep
extending here up to I just cook house I
don't know what to call it anymore
yeah you can see the pigs can't fit
through so this works out great I was a
little worried the wolves are gonna like
it stuck climbing the ladders but they
seem to fall down pretty good
so that's how to make a proper wolf
separator that doesn't damage either
pigs or wolves because my other one
actually I wanted to mention this to
CoStar made the exact same thing in his
world I saw so it's not like I invented
that or anything but yeah the problem
with that to design was that it damages
it has to kill the pigs to separate them
and also the Wolves get damaged from the
lab of my old speak inator so this way
both the mobs are fine
let's see let's extend this out I think
one more I lose those ah aerial and let
creepers been hanging around scaring me
let's put a slab here break this now
let's put a slab here yeah okay I'm just
going to seal this off for second place
this with glass I think I used up most
of my sword just trying to get the
Wolves to spawn
okay and now we'll just keep extending
this now the question is oh yeah where's
that creeper I just got to be really
careful here ah
so I want to now there is astroturf
looks a little bit fake it will look a
lot more real if you like plant trees on
it I think and if you have flowerbeds
around and stuff it might look a lot
more like grass than the bright green
stuff though is just too fake looking
unfortunately because I think I like
that color more let's see yeah I'm going
to finish extending this and then we'll
work on making our tiny little building
here I think okay one thing I wanted to
address that keeps coming up in the
comments like probably gotten at least
100 comments on this what happens if
lightning strikes your house etho it's
going to go up in flames right well I'm
really not worried about it as far as I
know lightning won't cause fires on
wooden houses and be pretty dumb if it
did and I would strongly suggest people
complain to notch if it does as far as I
know that doesn't happen if it did it
would mean like you can't build anything
out of wood would be stupid no um yes
these are the wouldn't take what jerk
these are the wooden half slabs so
they're they act like stone or petrified
wood I didn't do it with the whole whole
building though but if it is a problem
I will replace all this wood with half
slabs and I have many world backups so
if my storage room does burn down like
it has before I can just recover and fix
the problem moving on this is close to
done yeah let's let's feed his piggies
and let's cover this up should cover it
up first so one of the reasons I want to
separate the pigs is because when I had
it going to the main collection area I
pretty much always had the broke chops
shut off because they were clogging up
my inventory every time I picked up
gunpowder and stuff and it was really
annoying so it really is better to make
them drop to a separate location I think
and since I'm separating them it makes
sense that they should have a separate
drop location too
oh that figis messed up tape so the
fancy way of doing this probably is to
make the pigs fall through lava and then
burn up in midair and drop a pork chop
into water since this is my collection
area above here I don't really need to
drop the pork chops into water because I
don't need to carry them off anywhere so
this is really simple for me if you guys
need me to invent something fancy for
you maybe I'll do that but for me I
really don't need to over complicate
this a few more signs hey oh cool
alright hey I thought spiders don't
attack during the day very strange
yay how to do this now and I probably
should have thought this out a little
more yeah let's extend this a little bit
more I counted that's about a five-block
drop so wouldn't really work well for me
dropping them through lava anyway
because they don't have enough of a drop
now let's go get some more water this is
a this is pretty close to done so I
think I'm just going to drop them into a
flame I'm pretty sure it will work
almost 100%
as long as you keep it open around the
flame that they have no wool no walls to
bump into and it's gonna hurt ya I hope
this doesn't pitch anything on fire too
is another thing I'm concerned about
can't remember if fire can spread if you
use another rack I think it might not
actually okay so one more water source
and this should be ready to kill some
pigs I think
oh no that's not gonna work shoot all
right well let's extend this then
because the pigs will just swim if
there's water above that hole oh all
right nice grass oh yeah
so I need to build some staircases up to
this thing
probably have some storage chests it'll
be all closed off so the pigs can't get
out this is open all the way around so
they should freely walk off onto this
glass here so I'm pretty sure this will
work pretty good yeah so I'm going to
kill these pigs wait for night and then
we should be able to watch this in
action all right it's night time things
are starting to funnel in
hmm yes I might need to do some
adjusting after all even if they die on
the flames the pork usually jumps away
from the flames but this is this is by
far the simplest way of doing it I think
some other ideas are - I could probably
put lava block it in this open-air space
here and they'll take damage through the
glass using the southwest glitch or
whatever it is and I'm sure you guys are
going to send me a hundred ideas and
I'll probably get a good one too so I
think I think the majority will walk off
and even if I lose a few pork chops I
don't really care because it's more than
enough as is and this is working good so
all in all I'm pretty happy with this so
I'm going to join these three ladder
things together and then I'll funnel the
volts off over that way and probably
start building a barn or something for
the other animals and I'm not quite sure
what I'm gonna build
this out of
yeah I got a switch let me try lava
think see if it works alright here we go
so you're a little holder here nope no
good all right well I just want to try
drop on through lava then yeah this
looks like good winner after all and
it's pretty simple to do ki it's just a
lab assisted by it's sign if you wanted
to drop the cooked four drops into water
you could place a ladder here or no do a
sign go down to rocks place a ladder
with the one one by one to hope and they
won't even fit past the ladder after the
burn on the ladder and the pork chops
will drop down the teeth into into your
water below this is suggested to me also
by one of my viewers thank you for that
the only problem with there is some pork
chops we get stuck on the ladder
but it's pretty minimal so yeah this is
cool not sure I might put glass around
here probably have like four or two HS
to store the pork chops and yeah I'll
make it to look a little bit more pretty
probably two eventually and this um well
I guess we can probably quickly work on
this
that's not good that's not good
these guys are mad at me
oh yeah okay not all out of a small out
of glass yeah I'm pretty happy with this
works pretty much exactly like I wanted
it to and they don't seem to be getting
stuck in the lava which is nice and the
wolves are going through that I've seen
so far so yeah very cool so this thing
let's
I guess so best way of doing this is
probably just have glass here just make
it scream out like that
and then that's we're pretty good I
think
hopefully the wolves don't get stuck
swimming up here no I'll have to keep an
eye on that
all right cool so we got a bit done this
episode and if you guys have any
suggestions let me know but all in all
I'm pretty happy with how this turned
out next episode we'll be working on
[Music]
this squid farm I think I figured out
how to make them go up blocks really
well now and I'll show you how that
works next episode and we'll probably
build an aquarium and maybe some way of
killing them automatically - there's now
that I can move them up I can place them
anywhere I want really in my world like
I could have a floating aquarium in the
sky if I wanted where they would collect
so that's that's pretty cool and at some
point we'll have to finish our hostile
mob system and we've done much with that
lately
nothing happy about the jammer and it's
raining again not right cool so thank
you everyone for watching
and we how did you not to
that's weird
oh the rain put some ropes I think
I'm very interesting
let's test it out show
I can't light a fire
yeah
but I don't think the water passes
through glass in horse and that's good
we should use it a fix all right but
that's the end guys thank you for
watching and I'll see you again some
other time