hey everyone Etha here again with
episode 8 and I am completely out of
wood right now so the first thing we're
going to do today is we're going to go
harvest our tree farm I had two sticks
left just enough to make an axe and of
course it's nighttime there's a bunch of
creepers around that works okay
hopefully the coast is clear here
alright so I'm going to harvest these
trees and I'll be back
woohoo
peek-a-boo peek-a-boo oh yeah I almost
miss it tonight this is a no blasting
zone
I'm stupid and that's not that bad blow
up the torches so okay the Sun is up
guys how about you go die or something
alright all harvested only died once so
far I'm going to have to make this tree
farm bigger because it's just way too
small
well I'll do that later get 41 logs and
so we're going to head down through a
new mob trap area I'll start to eating
that out
at first I'm going to drop some stuff
off alright so here we are down at the
bottom of that shaft at the lab level
and we're just going to work on setting
up a little base here first and then
I'll start digging so I'm going to make
some chess a furnace just so we can do
stuff down here and put some wood here
and I'm going to make a water break here
so that if I fall so I can just fall
down the shaft real quick so I'll need
three signs
of course I have no sticks
okay one two three and what I'm going to
do is I'm going to place it around this
2x2 area here is probably good actually
no um yeah that's fine actually place
one there and another two here and that
blocks the four squares and then oh yeah
I need infinite water pool down here
always useful to have around and then I
just need to place one here here
all four blocks and I think oh I need
some ladders to finish where I didn't
put them there
and use the bulk of it already
good enough okay so I'm going to try
fall down here and see if it works I
think it does eventually I'll have some
way to get up here faster but this is
good enough for now hope I don't die
perfect I think in on multiplayer that
doesn't always work so be careful if you
do that there okay so I need to dig this
way and I'm going to I think I'm going
to start us three blocks above the lava
level because I might need to take two
blocks down four canals for the mobs to
fall into this is by the way my first
mob trap I've ever made so it might not
turn out perfectly
it probably won't actually and so if you
have any ideas on how to make it better
let me know
and all I'm going to be doing is I'm
going to be clearing out that I think a
too high space all under the ocean here
and collecting resources while I do it
I'm not sure if you're supposed to I
don't think it needs to be three high
but if it does please let me know but
I'm just going to make it two for now
because adding one more block is going
to make it take a time and a half longer
so I'm going to be mining and I'll see
you soon
okay so I cleared a bit of space out
this should give you a better idea of
what we're going to be doing down here
I'm just going to be editing out this
area or under the ocean right now and
once it's all set up and may get rid of
all the torches and it'll be completely
dark down here and mobs will spawn in a
very large area and we're going to set
up water canals that push the mobs this
way and collect them all to one one area
and then there's going to be a mob
elevator that brings them up to the
surface or something and then I'll set
up a grinder to kill them or do other
things with them I'm not sure yet and
believe it or not clearing all this area
I only got three iron and about 40 coal
no redstone no diamonds I did find some
gold so yeah it's going to take a while
and before I start the next episode I'll
probably clear out more of this and get
some redstone and that way we can start
it by wiring that eats Road and I do
have a big project I want to start soon
it's a pretty cool idea not going to
tell you what it is just yet but I think
you guys will like it and it's getting
late here now so I'm going to end the
episode but before we end it I'm
starting a new feature in my episodes
I'm going to be showing random clips
that I think you guys will find
interesting or or funny or whatever
because that I keep getting lots of them
and I don't know what to do with them so
enjoy