hey everyone episode 5 here so as you've
probably already heard minecraft has
made the change from alpha to beta which
actually means very little at the moment
a lot of people were upset with the
recent patch but I myself absolutely
love it
and that is because notch has fixed the
tree issue saplings once again fall from
trees which is awesome I've been waiting
for that for a very long time now
that I had a lot of fun in my other
world I ran around and collected 261
saplings before they disappeared it was
a lot of fun oh yeah I forgot about this
guy I wanted a lot of people have said
you can put water in here to kill them
too I'm not sure if it actually works he
seems fine to me oh there we go
then then this is not so tough anymore
so I guess it does work but laughs it
works also
so this episode I think we're going to
be working on the road again and the
dispenser and everything first say I'm
going to do I am going to move this ez
loader as now when we work down the road
there I'm going to put the ez loader
over here that way I can work on the
return area here so it's the gold here
some water down and the sign how you
need to use a sign you can't use a
ladder for this because signs have no
collision mask while ladders do if you
use a ladder the boats going to run into
it and then stop this up again
okay all right
so this ez loader will still work here
because you don't make the bull the boat
to hit this wall here which is what we
need we need the boat snug against this
wall so that when it enters elevator
here it's gonna hit this wall here and
that's going to be snug against this
wall which is important this area here
has a problem still I'm gonna have to
probably change it
so in my road system the boat is always
snug against the right side and same for
on the other Lane which means doors need
to be placed on the left side like that
the hinge here needs to be on the left
so that boats and still pass through if
this door was over like that the boat
would run into it and then stop
there's the door hinge is over here with
the doors you don't need to place them
too high if you don't want I kind of
like how it looks when you place them in
a hole like this oops the door needs to
be the other way so that we have the
three three block area only and like I
said this pressure Pat's going to open
up the store when you hop on it once
it's wired I'm going to harvest some
wood so that we can make some ladders
and get started on the road so I'll be
back in a sec alright we're back I
didn't stay out too long like that
pretty crazy pretty fast I made some
dolls already and the ladders yet so I'm
picking so we're going to work on the
return here I think I'm going to put a
door here eight the hinge on the other
side so we'll place the block next to it
now it opens right way and we'll put a
pressure plate here so by two by default
we're going to have this door open then
when a boat comes down here it's going
to hit this pressure plate and this is
quickly going to close and stop the boat
and then the player is going to get off
the boat either here or I'll make a
doorway here and when they get off the
boat they'll open and they'll go down
here and back into the dispenser and I'm
going to add another door I think over
here so those pressure plates going to
close open and close both doors it's
going to be hooked up to both of them so
if a guy is waiting here another guy can
come down the system and safely wait
here with the crashing into the other
boat until he gets out hopefully
I'm gonna lower this to so if you're
having that problem you'll have to
destroy this block but there's nothing
next to the left side of the door and
then replace the block with something
else that and I think there's going to
be a water stream here I'm gonna have to
play around with this a bit I'm going to
replace this with a normal block oh wait
no I can't
hmm
all right well it's only that for a
moment so how to do this um I'm gonna
play around with this a bit off-camera
and then I'll show you what I figure out
so I ended up moving this ez loader one
block up and the only reason I have this
in my system right now is to make
testing easier I'll be getting rid of it
eventually
so this return system I'm going to try
make it eight blocks long which is one
two three four five six seven eight and
then the road section is going to start
here and I'll place a stream here and
don't make a sign
it's more water and we're gonna place
this street here
other side take another side there all
right I'm hoping that will work I am
going to put some ladders and then I'm
going to test this out not quite sure
where we'll still put them but we'll try
that for now and we're going to make
some more pressure plates
I'm going to be using pressure plates
instead of signs just for convenience
but you can use whatever you want and we
make our road sections the water three
blocks long if you want a better example
of how to build these roads check out
this link here and we'll show it
tutorial of it and then do one more
section and then I am going to build an
easy loader for testing yep and what I
want to see mainly is that the pressure
plate gets pressed when I'm on the boat
as if it doesn't I gotta redo this off
need some glass make a boat I'll
probably have to need some more wood
and we here see sandwich this ez loader
down that should work
I'm going to place the boat in the
middle
hop on we're going to open this door
and I wanna see if this gets pressed yep
that's just perfect so this will work so
now that we know that we know we can
start the boat here and keep things
consistent place that there oh well
that's wrong
wanting it's the other way I think that
will work
the ladders should go now we'll probably
start interesting please okay so I think
we got this working pretty good now
yep that looks good
beautiful so I think I'm going to work
on extending this I'll see you back in a
bit okay we're back as you can see I
extended the road up to where we had dug
and filled in all the water ladders and
torches and everything again you can
check out my other eats tutorials on how
to build these road sections if you need
to know and I just put a bend in the end
here because we're just going to be
testing this and later I'll get rid of
that and make it go all the way to the
island so we're just going to finish up
the last few touches here and then we're
going to take it for a test drive
I haven't tested it yet so you'll see
with me if it works or not
okay so we're gonna make a few boats I
go through a lot of wood making boats
okay now we're going to put them in the
easy loader
it works good
comes up in the corner there door open I
hope that Ben works yeah it did it
and then the player would get off the
boats throw it open
let's back down and all is good again
we're gonna close this and we're gonna
go for a first test drive you ready here
we go oh yeah I won't be doing that the
Redstone yet I'll do it later when I get
some other boats following us awesome
so that's how it would work player would
get off both doors would open and then
close again if there's a player on it
they get it the next player would get
off it open and around and round she
goes so at the end of this road I'm
going to build another section like this
and it will form a loop and it should be
good so I'm going to end that episode
here and next episode we'll probably go
look for some redstone or something like
that
so bye for now