hello my fellow Minecrafters etho here
with episode 6 and this episode we are
going to be doing something special
something out of the ordinary we are
going to visit my private world world 2
and the reason for this I spent about 3
hours today working on a new
intersection for the etes transportation
system and this is what it looks like so
I built for small roads the test it's
and one of them is a bit longer right
now we're inside the intersection and we
are going to take it for a test drive
all right here we go
arms and legs inside the boat at all
times whoo
and then we can exit the boat you're
left it goes back to the dispenser up in
the stack and if we want we can ride one
back and same thing happens over here
this door stops us because we are on top
of a pressure plate right now and this
door here is in case someone else
arrives while we're waiting here so the
boats don't crash together and when you
exit the boat both of those doors open
it goes underneath into the dispenser
and there's a pressure plate under this
boat so when you hop on this door opens
just like that
and these pressure plates are hooked to
this door and the reason for that is so
when you arrive here it's going to
release a boat to make up for the one
you just took from over here and that
happens on both sides and the reason for
that is so that there's always boats at
each station you could ride from over
there five times and five boats will get
sent back so that's one thing you can't
really do with minecarts which is pretty
cool about this system so this isn't a
tutorial video this is just to show you
what I've done and what it might look
like if you wanted to build your own
intersection the way I got the setup is
pretty nice
so you exit here then if you want to
keep going straight you just walk up up
here up on the next boat and it takes
you straight or you can go right or left
or hop off and go visit the town and do
whatever you want so it's pretty cool
it's technically not an intersection
because the boats don't cross paths but
I'm going to call it that anyway and you
can take your time choosing where you
want to go I recommend putting some kind
of information inside here saying like
which direction you're going and where
the road takes you
so for example this road takes you to a
dead end at about 0.1 kilometers which
is 100 meters or 100 blocks that's kind
of cool to have and same down here tell
the player which direction they're going
and if you want you can put what
destinations are at the next stop so
yeah I'm going to release the tutorial
video later and I'll explain everything
in that like what why I have these
ladders here why these are only three
blocks long stuff like that um I will
take you grab a boat I will take you
down and show you the shafts here so I
just built this little room here to get
down or I don't know if I want to keep
it like that what I've done here this is
a return shaft this water stream is
eight blocks long so that the boat will
bottom out when it hits here and then it
goes up into the water elevator and the
reason why I have it bottomed out now is
because if you just have a normal stream
like this
if one boat is here and another one
lands on top of it
the the second boat isn't going to move
forward when it touches the water it's
going to get stuck which is a serious
problem if the bullet Center the return
system too close together yeah so
another problem I had though is I don't
really have any place to put easy
loaders to stop the system so what I
figured out is I can do it from down
here
just by placing boats right here
the reason I can't build an easy loader
anywhere is because all the return
shafts are right next to an elevator
like I think it's behind here yeah and
that is interfering with the water flows
but anyway so one thing I figured out
tonight is that these rapid dispensers
do not work in multiplayer at the moment
some reason the boats won't point
straight they're kind of crooked always
and that causes the boats to bounce back
and forth and I think break eventually
which is a problem in single-player they
won't break like this and hopefully
notch will fix that problem later so at
the moment boats and my carts and
everything are still pretty buggy in
multiplayer servers if you don't want to
wait for things to improve and you want
to go ahead and try build one of these
already what you'll have to do is modify
this dispenser a little bit you'll
basically need to cut out one block so
it's so it's just the elevator so it's a
2x2 area instead of this three by two
area that will only allow one boat to
float up and you won't have issues with
the boats being placed in properly and
if you have any ideas on how to improve
this please let me know if you can think
of any flaws please let me know and I
will try to come up with solutions to
those problems and improve the system
before I release a tutorial is a video
so one more thing I want to do is I
wanted to give a shout out to the
Minecraft planned ona
I visited their server this evening and
a cool guy named Heather amp is working
on building one of these roads in his
server and he pointed out that this wrap
dispenser is not working very well so
thanks for that
and as well I wanted to give a shout out
oh yeah this is a little bit glitchy but
the road itself is working ok in
multiplayer easy loaders work OK in
multiplayer and everything else seems to
work fine too but it is a bit glitchy
that's for sure so as well I wanted to
give a shout out to at as yox is sorry
for between your name
ey o X I said he sent me a video he made
of the eat system and I'll post a link
of it here and you guys should check it
out it's kind of different might give
you some other ideas and that's about it
for today
it's getting late here so I'm gonna have
to make this a short episode but thanks
for watching and next episode we'll be
back in our world so have a good night