hey everyone thanks for joining agent
not a whole lot you to show you
oh yeah I got creeper the other day so
hey this is all got destroyed so I
placed it with ladders and I don't
really have any plans this episode but
at the same time I wanted to get one out
because people get antsy if there's not
one every day so this is new as is
playing around with mine carts and I
think I invented a new type of booster
not a very good booster but it and I
don't know anyone watch you use it but
it's kind of an interesting thing this
goes on forever because it's uh goes
down a down slope at every corner and if
you hop in it it speeds up to the
maximum speed because it's like you're
going downhill
so I think you could hook up a track
junction to send it out onto a track and
it's kind of like a booster without
needing another minecart to boost it
kind of weird I thought it's actually
useful for anything
well it does make me laugh and I was
doing a test over here I needed to know
what happens if you try to stack my
carts like the PEZ dispenser method if
there's mobs inside try show you guys
and go too easy into pieces skeleton
comes out here of course um I hate doing
that but oops also I've spent some time
down below at the mob spawning grounds
and I've been making it bigger and also
I've made a few adjustments down there
to make it more efficient and I'll
probably show you guys that this episode
- I still haven't quite figure out how
to how I want to set up our station here
is really what I'm building here is a
minecart station for it for the mobs
really but instead of only handling like
one player it's like handling hundreds
because I have I think up to 200 mobs at
a time
so it's going to require quite a bit of
planning the gnosis is sped up quite a
bit now brilliant skeletons here no good
alright I'm gonna stop in I'll show it
once I get it going good
all right I think it's gonna look this
time so yeah I guess that they would
suffocate if you stack one on top but I
guess they don't it just goes right on
top the head of the mob below
so this guy's really like two blocks I I
think so you can stack them like that
it just takes up two spots and if the
guy blow moves out of the way or dies
then the next cart falls down so kinda
interesting it was important that I
figured that out because I might stack
you guys to save space I'm not sure or I
might send them into the water somehow
into water streams inside charts not
really sure something else I've been
playing around with is our panel here
just trying to figure out some way to
have a button to shoot out one and I'll
leave her above to trigger a clock to
shoot out lots at a time and pretty much
figured out it's not going to work
because
know what I'm saying yes I got a 5
o'clock here with a wire long and it
sends power to all five of these but the
problem is if so you could override it
by having a lever and you would have
that down to shut it off and then if you
wanted lots to come out you flick that
up and keep shooting but the problem
with that idea is you would need it
wouldn't work because the this lever
would be down on all of them so it would
always be overridden if that makes sense
so you would need to have some sort of
an end date on every one of them and
pretty sure I could do that pretty
compact but the other issue is see what
this button is doing it's very important
that only one comes out that's what I
want but the thing is if there's power
anywhere near a dispenser pressing a
button makes to come up so I'm probably
just going to keep it really simple and
just have one button like I originally
was planning and not have a 5 o'clock or
pulse or anything like that because it
just complicates things too much and
there's no good way of doing it without
using up a lot of space that I can think
of
so next thing we should do said I was
going to show you the mob grounds and it
changes this is my total TNT stock oh
yeah another thing I did
off-camera I found I found a tape system
that I went exploring I was going to
record it but it ended up taking about
three hours and I found probably uh
about seven stacks of iron and tons of
redstone like twelve diamonds and
probably oh I don't know fifteen stacks
of coal and two stacks of gold and it's
a huge cave so yeah I've been making
this bigger there's probably you
probably can't see it but I think I got
12 or 13 pads now before I only had
eight as going to ask you guys opinion
on something
I was thinking of abandoning this road
and building another one above-ground I
wanted to try out a few new designs oh
and the reason for that is because this
is kind of a prime location for the mob
spawning grounds I want to put pads in
here and it just so happens the road is
the exact same height as these pads so
it's in the way and I kind of want to
get rid of it and reuse this area for
the spawning grounds
and then try build up roads at the
surface because it will be easier and
faster anyway the only reason I was
building one down here is because I
needed cobblestone once I started this
world but now I have tons there's no
points going slowly underground and the
way I've been making up these mob pads
bigger is basically now I'm finding four
squares in a skip two blocks four
squares in kind of like this some of my
comments are suggested that there's a
more efficient ways of using the TNT and
they are right basically if you have air
spaces around the TNT it will blow up
more area when it blows up and so
digging for blocks is pretty easy and
then what I do is I just place it three
blocks in
all along and then you just run across
pretty cool only downside is it blows up
some of your iron and coal but not a big
deal
saves a lot of time and then you just
clean it up a bit so every TT that way
pretty much blows out 40 blocks which
saves a lot of time and wanted to show
my new method of doing the water streams
so the issue with them right now is I
have a these gaps in between I tried
going over before but then the mobs were
going back on the pads and then some
people suggested I should take one block
lower ah that would work but it requires
a lot more digging so the way I
decide to do it now I use signs instead
of pressure plates of course gives me
the feather and same positioning two
blocks from these edges what I do is I
have a sign where the pressure plates
were Oh actually gay yeah I forgot
something I need some stairs for this
and so what you do is get the pressure
plates dug out and you dig down one
block and you dig down one block this
way one block this way and then you have
still water here
so that's bad then what you do is you
place two stairs here and it creates the
flow again and so the mobs just keep
going through and they have pushed it up
the stairs and it's like there's no
space so it's a better way of doing it I
think I noticed the quite a bit of
improvement right after I changed a lot
of it
so yeah I'm going to keep building this
bigger this area and mobs will spawn
faster and I changed the water at the
start here a bit too so unless you guys
oh yeah so unless you guys say don't
tear this out I'm probably going to and
just build it at the surface
a guy named uh oxys a youtuber has been
working on eats road designs and I kind
of wanted to try out some of his new
roads so the way I have the water now um
don't think this these this water was
here before so it all merges together
here these signs keep the water from
flowing back toward me there's no dead
spots anymore I still have the angled
thing here to keep the tall mobs from
getting stuck over here you get pushed
to the left and everything else is
pretty much the same
so soon as mobs get passed through here
they're pretty much forced all the way
through because they can't jump which
means they can't go back you can keep a
mob from jumping he won't be able to go
against the stream like I'm doing right
now but this mob system is far from
perfect because I still have issues with
spiders climbing around in here even
after they fall in the water can Alice
Li can climb out if they want but it
does pretty good with spiders and like
I've said before I think the main
purpose of this mob system is control
it's not yet as many items as possible
there are much better designs for doing
that you should be trying to kill the
mobs as fast as possible if you want a
mob system solely for items the goal
this is control so I can kill them if I
want I can send them to other places if
I want I can sort them if I want that's
kind of what I'm trying to do so what
should we do now
I'm going to check the time and maybe
figure out something fun we can do
Wow yes it's been like 20 minutes
already yes we should should end it here
thanks for watching