my craft doctor down minecraft hello and
welcome back to the exciting world of
Minecraft this is episode 2 in our
series and we are going to kick things
off right where we left off I'm hoping I
don't die here we go
creeper and zombie waiting to kill me
I think I'm going to make a sword real
quick there it is alright alright come
and get me well he sees me he sees me
what hello how's it going
umm that's weird
here you go
I had I don't know what to say about
this whoa that was weird
maybe he's narcoleptic or something
anyway
that creeper gave me an idea a few weeks
ago I wanted to make a certain type of
mob trap I had an idea and I'm going to
try make it this video it's very simple
first I'm going to get some wood though
basically I'm going to need four doors
and a pressure plate and that's pretty
much all the trap is all right that's
good enough and any type of pressure
plate so I haven't made sure I don't
know if this works for sure but I think
it does I haven't built it off camera or
anything like that so this is the first
time I'm seeing it and the first time
you're seeing it basically just decide
where you want to put it get your four
doors and I'm going to put it above my
little station here because I think
there'll be lots of that creepers
walking around here and just put your
four doors around you
at and it's your pressure plates put it
inside so that doesn't work because the
doors are reversed but there is a way to
fix that let's go start over here so if
you need to reverse doors you need a
block next to the door well oh that's
the hole light up okay so that's the
wrong way so we need the door hinge on
the side like that so now the door is
going to be open by default and when
they step on the pressure plate it
closes yeah I think that's what I'm
going to do
oh you know what I put the door the
wrong way ha ha ha okay this time that's
what I want so that was on the right
side I think yes place the four doors
like that get rid of your sand and
that's our trap so if a creeper walks in
here he's automatically trapped you
can't get out unless maybe if you jump
if you jumped you can get out so we're
going to put a block above also and you
can use you could use a glass block if
you want them to be killed by the
sunlight I'm just going to use it
regular block so I think that should
hold hold them yeah the doors don't open
now when I jump that's my very simple
mob trap and I'm hopefully I'll capture
somebody tonight see if it works
now I'm guessing you can also probably
modify this trap to only catch chickens
if you want I think all you would need
to do is lower this block by one so let
the trap is only one block high and only
chickens will be able to fit in it and
you could probably also change it to the
base area here to a two by two you
wanted it to catch spiders instead of
this one by one area but I'm not going
to bother trying to do that I'm sure you
can figure it out if you want using the
same idea what you would use it for I
don't really know that's up to you
personally I'm hoping that creeper will
walk into it randomly tonight and I can
come here and point and laugh at it
hahaha but we'll see if you if you want
you can direct mobs into it somehow or
set up many of them I don't know I'll
leave it up to you that's the design
though very simple alright so I think
I'm going to start a new project I'm
going to try make a tree farm because in
my last worlds I didn't build a tree
farm and I regretted it later because I
thought not just going to fix the
sapling issue I've been not falling from
trees and every day I kept hoping you
know please fix the issue and he never
did while he did one day I saw on his
blog that he fixed it but then like a
few minutes later he he undid the change
because it was causing crashes and I
don't think he's worked on it since so
I'm going to build a tree farm so that I
don't run out of wood in this in this
world I think I'll just build it
should I find a nice flat spot for it
there's more ocean over there don't need
that probably going to have to build it
somewhere around here
Oh a peek finally I'm hungry I don't
know where you went ha ha
all that cheap bugger all right oh it's
night time already I just started yes
I'm going to build a tree farm around
here I think and I might have to level
this out a bit
I'll probably work on it in my next
state
because I'll probably die if I can build
it tonight I really need to make some
kind of storage chest or else I'm going
to lose everything so I think I'm going
to go hide and work on the road a bit
more I'll probably have lots of projects
going at a time
because I don't like to work on just one
thing make a chest or two and all that's
where that you can fell down one of
these type of holes
anyway build the chest store my chunk
and yeah so I'm going to build a furnace
- and then I'll probably make this class
alright so I'm just going to clear out
some more of this area here off camera
and I'll see you in a bit
zum-zum all right
so clear out some space I lowered
everything by one block and got some
cobblestone two pieces of iron I
installed a little skylight here so I
can see when that's day just turned a
and I'm going to head outside I don't
think I caught anybody nope it was
pretty quiet all night all right well
that's the end of this video and thanks
for watching I'll see you next episode
well we'll wait one second now as soon
as I stop the video I saw this creeper
over here so we're going to try lure
them into our trap before we end this to
see if it works and I hope it does oh
man
awesome now he is stuck forever that's
pretty cool as it going in there oh yeah
I want to sewer that chicken went to
he's not down there anymore that's weird
okay until next time see ya