hello everyone this is Ethel still
working on the mop system but it's
getting very close to complete things
are going really well I have made a
number of changes but yeah it's working
really well it's still not up to full
scale or full speed here but it's it's
getting there so I will take you up
there and I'll show you what's new
what's different here we are at the
tower you can see it's looking a little
bit different now for some reason it's
because I've made it smaller now I got
rid of the outside canals in it so two
blocks smaller all around it so four by
four or less in size and the wall is
here now instead of having the two wide
canals all around it's the thing so I
decided to do that to simplify things
and from what I can tell it's just as
efficient like this but I have no way of
knowing for sure without using like an
mcedit world and watching mobs spawn and
compare the rates between the two
methods and I just can't do that but
from my observations in this world it
seems about the same and the nice thing
about this style here it's a lot faster
to build simpler easy to understand it's
absolutely no signs in it now and yeah
it takes up less space so should be good
the way I have a water
it goes in like this it runs the full a
block lengths and ends it the hole there
so I'm liking this new style more I'm
glad I made the change and this is kind
of what I'm recommending for hostile mob
systems now I may make a tutorial for
this if you guys want but I'm sure you
can figure it out just by looking at
this yeah I haven't fixed the lighting
yet I'll get to that pretty quick
and this outside stuff here I'll
probably remove but I'm not sure yet I'm
gonna leave it until I decide if I'm
building more than one Tower that's that
mate I might build two or three towers
or just leave it as one here haven't
decided so I'm just gonna leave this
extra bit here until I do decide anyway
let's head up to the lighting room I
want to say thank you to everybody that
sent me video responses and suggestions
I would not have been able to figure out
the lighting thing on my own I don't
think so it's a big help and the
solution is very simple apparently
basically the problem I was having is
there's four blocks on every level of my
system that was only light level seven
so mobs could spawn even if my
lightening was on so I gotta change what
I have in here you can see I'm watching
on half slabs so mobs won't spawn in
here when it's completely dark and I
just had two levers one for water and
one for Lila
so I'm gonna work at applying the
changes you guys recommended and then I
will be back yeah yeah and a big thank
you to everybody that gave me
suggestions on how to do the lighting
system the simplest solution
I think people gave me is I can just
copy what I have here will still be two
Pistons per 4 holes the only thing is I
need to change where the lava comes down
so the way I had it before lava was
coming down inside here this hole here
all these inside holes and then at the
very far end here there's one block that
was light level seven which is low
enough to allow mobs to spawn on it but
the trick that you guys gave me is I
need to kind of rotate the lava so I
need Labbit come down this hole here and
leave this hole here this one here and
this one here and then what that does so
let's take this pad here for example the
light level seven block could be over
here but since lava will be over here
this lava light the dark spot on the
other pad so the lightning jumps pads
and they work together that way to
remove all the dark spots so it's really
awesome so I just need to change where I
have the lab coming down and since I
wanted yeah I have half slabs on this
stuff too it's really weird
so I'm going to move it how should I do
this I need to go like this and then
have slaps on top of that if I had
enough yeah and then I got to move this
stuff
I think the wiring will get a little bit
longer now but hey it's worth it if it
works so definitely gonna make the
change and it's getting dark in here so
maybe I'll finish this off camera I got
one left to do here so I'll show you how
to do it or how I have to fix it that's
to keep this thin that controls the lava
and then we have regular piston please
set with a solid block and I
oops that doesn't go there buck there
make a little pocket to hold the lava
and then a little pocket to hold the
water here I believe that's it so lava
goes down here it'll flow like this and
water is in this one and it spreads out
and yeah it will be a little bit more
tricky to do the wiring not really
tricky just us space consuming because
the pistons were really close together
before now they're far apart but I
figure these ones are all on the inside
so I'll have one why are you going to
the inside here
and it will branch off Oh actually I
can't hmm maybe I'll just have a wire
going all the way around the outside
here I think that'll be easier so it
seems like I've made a little bit of a
mistake since my mom tower is smaller
now I have a new problem
this is where the wall should be now and
that's where I had this piston so that
won't fly but I have found a solution to
this what I am doing now I am putting
the sticky piston over here just
changing it slightly then removing this
one like that and then this is within
our boundary which is over here so
that'll work better and I think it'll be
easier to wire them with the lava piston
move to where it is now fairly certain
and the water still seems to flow okay
so that's good just a minor adjustment
but if people copy this I want to make
sure it all fits within the same size as
the spawning area below otherwise it's
very foolish if your top is fatter than
the bottom parts awesome okay it's all
wired now it was actually really easy to
do much easier than before I moved that
lab a piston so this one here is for
lava turns all four on or off and this
that's wire going up to this repeater
repeater sends wire to yeah it's really
hard to see in here sorry - this thing
here and it branches off - all for lava
Pistons in a symmetrical design very
simple and then these ones control the
water and this just wraps around behind
this block here is our first water
piston I use a repeater here to send
power into the block Jen gets sent to
the piston and also it sends it to the
wire on the other side here which
continues on to our next further water
piston and of course it extends the
signal otherwise this wire wouldn't make
it that far the power and same on the
side exact same thing
so it was fairly easy and yes it did fit
within my boundary here so it's perfect
and what I'll do next
is uh as I'll build my wall up to the
ceiling here and then all remove this
outer wall but I'll do that some other
time okay one other thing I should do in
here oh yeah by the way if I want I can
keep these two wires separate and what
that'll do is I'll be able to control
how many spiders I did like every water
column here that flows down decreases a
spider spawning a little bit so this
decreases by half if I I keep these
separate I'll probably join them
together but if I want I have that
option to where I can control the amount
of spiders not just simply turn it on or
off which could be cool but I don't
really care enough to bother and I need
to make this room mob proof so mobs can
spawn on top of redstone so I need to Oh
getting dizzy I need to make sure
there's no two air spaces or no air
space above the wire so I'll do that for
all these wires and it will be pretty
much ready here actually one thing else
I will comment about this I didn't
really think of when I was building this
but now that it's all done I'm really
glad it turned out this way this is the
top of the map right here's the cool
thing I was worried that mobs would
spawn on top here like I can't place any
more blocks at night because there would
be no light up here right but it turns
out mobs can't spawn at the top of the
map so that's something new I didn't
know before
and I don't have to worry about lighting
it up up here so that's cool
very nice
apparently snow does land here though
I'm surprised because you can't place a
block oh just about fell so I will
finish this up
and we will move on to something else
okey so I finished up that wire room
it's all sealed off I made it smaller
completely darken it now so the lighting
the lighting won't interfere with the
layer below and it's working good again
so really happy with how this turned out
I still need to decide if I'm building
more than one of these towers I'm not
sure at the moment it's working really
good and I've been working at lighting
up more and more caves and every little
bit I light up seems to help a lot with
the spawning rate so I'm gonna try to
get them all and then see how this works
before I decide if I'm building more
than one and let's head over here the
way I'm lighting up the caves is by
something you all pointed to me last
episode a new development looks
dangerous it's not aha x-ray vision is
back guys the glitch I love this glitch
it makes building a mob system so much
easier and it does not bother me using
it so this is all the cave systems
around the area as you can see I had
most of them lit up already but there's
a few dark spots like there's one
there's a few I need to get to all of
those light them up and then there's a
big one
if I can see it it would be good to
light it up anything out of my vision
right now I don't need to worry about
and stuff at the very far distance there
I don't need to worry about either but
yeah there's the slime farm below
apparently slimes are still spawning on
it even though I have it flooded hmm it
must have figured out the wrong position
for it so yeah that's cool um I don't
think I should show you how to make one
of these I cannot find the video link
that people do before the video I use to
build it but yeah it's very simple where
the heck did that guy hey what's the
matter you want to be friends now is
that it oh you know it would be so cool
if you could put a saddle on a spider
and like ride them during the day like
this that would be so awesome and then
then they could like climb up cliffs and
OH
notch why did he do that that would be
fun okay let's head over there and
alright guys what are we doing over here
well I just want to point out a few
things to you you can see I am moving
this cliff back even further yet why
well remember the other day when my mom
stopped spawning and my passive mop firm
I was experiencing the mobs not spawning
glitch a guy on youtube named hypnotised
released a video recently explaining why
this glitch occurs at least as much as
we know
about it we don't know exactly why it
occurs I will post his video in the
description and many people on the forum
seem to agree with them from what I've
seen but what happens is a mob will
spawn and then he'll walk away from you
lay a mob far away from you will spawn
and then walk away a certain distance
and then he seems to get stuck loaded in
memory and he won't despawn at all until
like when I experienced that glitch the
other day I walked up to this cliff here
and there's about 15 all 15 passive mobs
were here waiting for me and then I
walked away from it they'd be spawned
and then it was working again you can
also fix this by going to the nether as
many of you have pointed out because it
clears all loaded mobs from memory to
make room for the zombie pigmen it yes
so yeah if mob spawn with far distance
away from you and then walk even further
away they seem to somehow get stuck
loaded in memory and don't be spawned so
I thought the reason I wasn't really
experiencing that glitch was because I
built that mob system between four
region borders and many of you have been
wondering why I didn't build this one
between four region borders and it's
because that's not why I'm not
experiencing the glitch or not very
often it's because I have all this ice
around me it was just a coincidence
that's the ice that's preventing that
glitch because mobs do not spawn on ice
so if they can't spawn on ice they can't
wander further away and get stuck loaded
into memory is my understanding but you
can see if I'm standing here legit hours
at kornpett 493 let's walk over here
mobs can spawn as fur as far away as a
hundred four
four blocks from you okay so if we're at
493 there let's do a little bit of math
I got my tuck you later we're ready for
when we get there
my ti-83 oh yeah i stinking like got to
get rid of my ramdisk I know it's the
problem okay this is where the cliff was
before when I experienced that glitch we
are at Z 379 so 493 - 379 is 114 so
that's within 144 blocks which means it
is possible for me to experience that
glitch although very rare it is possible
because I'm within that 144 block range
same if I'm if I'm on the wall area
there it's still within that range so
that's why I think I experienced it for
the first time the other day so yeah I
don't know exactly all the details as to
how this glitch occurs it's merely my
opinion or speculation whatever you want
to call it but it most definitely is a
glitch the game doesn't seem to be able
to handle mobs properly when they walk
past a certain point a certain distance
I don't know what that distance is how
it occurs the weird thing is mops as far
as I know mobs despawn like within a
second if they're more than 128 blocks
away from you in a sphere sphere
distance so I don't know how it works
but one thing I do know for sure if I
clear this land up to about 350 or so I
will at all times be more than one
hundred and forty four blocks away from
any land which means no mobs will be
able to spawn I don't necessarily have
to clear
I just need to light it up and clear the
grass but I will probably blow it up
anyway but yeah I'll be more than 144
walks away they won't be able to spawn
and then wander away and get unloaded
improperly so I'm almost guaranteed sure
that will work but again it's my opinion
all right another thing I wanted to show
you was how to do that x-ray glitch how
to set it up again I did not discover
this trick someone nearly showed it to
me if I can find the link given to me
for the original video I will link it in
the description but I'm pretty sure I
lost it so this is how I set mine up I
cleared this area here and I use sticky
pistons - away from you yeah and let's
see the wire comes down there runs over
here I'm taking a roundabout way with
the wire just to maximize your viewing
angle with this thing wait was that
where it was I think it was over my
redstone I think I had the lever like
this yeah so power is the wire over over
here it wraps around points directly to
the two Pistons if you don't want mobs
to spawn put in a half slab or something
paste in a piston and cover this up and
sticking your TNT I tried glass I tried
leaves and a few other things tangent is
the only one that seems to work oh yeah
let's do all those dark spots I have to
light up yet
that's a bad one right there definitely
need to do that one soon I did all the
caving I've done the eyes look at that
crazy and much much more believe me yeah
and then when you want to get out of
here just jump jump I think I had a
ladder in mine somewhere like over here
so you can just climb out and that's all
there is very simple very cool x-ray
trick I like it
and that's that's it well I guess I'm
gonna call it the end for today guys
thank you for watching as usual also I
want to express my condolences to you I
know many of you are back in school now
ah well summer is only nine months away
yep
and also look forward to the 1.8 patch
coming out soon was that a spider jockey
oh and also something else cool I saw
there today
I guess spelunky is coming to xbox so
I'm excited for that I had no idea I
love that game for PC so that'll be cool
and yeah take care bye bye do well in
your studies