[Music]
hello everyone this is ezel and no this
is not a rerun I know you've seen this
before but charity one explain what's
going on here now you just want to stand
and do nothing useless oh I made the
assumption that if you shoot a sheep
with the dispenser with arrows filled
that it went into shear the wool and I
made the assumption that eggs and
snowballs work either but then many
point people said that they do so now we
need to check them too here we go
get into position
Oh move over you stupid sheep there we
go all right this is snowballs snowballs
do not work and now I haven't tried this
already
let's try eggs eggs do not work I think
the chicken just spawned inside the
dispenser and died no doesn't work guys
I'm fairly certain
let's try snowballs again nope okay it
doesn't work
all right everyone here we are again we
are in level two and you've probably
noticed it already
oh no he tore down the mob sorters yes
well no kind of after last episode I
came back here I was kind of shocked at
this the vertical spider separator
didn't quite work so I tried it again
and then I don't know if it was one
creeper or a bunch of creepers but he
blew the heck out of this place he blew
up the separator he blew up part of this
thing
and he blew a big chunk out of the mob
separators and he even blew a few holes
in the ground here and water poured out
and destroyed all the buttons down below
and the tracks and torches oh it's just
insane and so I tore down the mob
disorders they had to be moved anyway
because I don't know if I'm going to use
them I might not my videos jumping here
one second alright is that better I
think so okay so the first thing we're
going to do is we are going to let's
jumping again where I'll live with it
we're going to be fixing this thing
changing it a little bit it's actually
kind of weird like since the dawn of
time
oops I don't try to do that since the
dawn of time
like me and za Bandito have been working
and building on the exact same thing by
pure coincidence and just so turns out
that this week he was also making one of
these vertical spider separators
and so I'm going to give him props for
figuring it out on his own
all right everyone sorry about that but
we lost some video due to video hiccups
that won't seem to go away probably
windows update doing something I don't
want it to do but anyway like I sang
props to solve Angie dough for making
his own spider separator and I'll post
the link in description to his video but
I don't know how much credit either of
us can really take for it because I
think a lot of people have figure out
how to make them like I know
let's see Joyner made one recently in
one of his older videos and think like
five people PM me their own designs for
a vertical one and I had it figured out
in my head how it's going to do it and
all their designs are pretty much
similar if not exactly the same as mine
and similar to exactly the same as each
other as well so I think it's kind of a
common-sense thing but yeah this is kind
of challenging as I found out to make
one that doesn't Jam like the design I
made last episode was good like you
would work if if the mobs were coming up
one at a time like most mob systems but
since this is super efficient now we
have to make it so it can handle mobs
clumping up and stuff like that anyway
I'm going to stop talking here because I
can barely build anything when I'm
talking nonstop
I can barely coherently put a sentence
together even when I'm completely
focused on talking oh I'm having trouble
with the water patterns here not doing
what I want them to do we're going to
kill that side there we go that worked
um so I think I know a way to make it
better no my class that was only two
that's fine the old one I made last
episode I had put like three blocks and
the mobs could only swim up one of them
the tall mobs I think ideally you only
need one block to block the spiders I
think ideally
we should only use one block to do that
then and place signs I think I got more
signs in here yeah all right place three
signs spiders can swim up because of
that block and yet there's three holes
for the tall mobs to squeeze through if
they're bouncing around I think they
should manage to bounce their way free I
hope J and then we're going to make a
water B and more leg
do you guys download my world be
prepared like your computers and I might
not be able to handle it
many people have complained about that
already
ah CA so that should work so they get
pushed by both the water streams ah stop
playing
towards this corner so we're going to
build we're going to make it so that's
the corner where the mobs come up and oh
wait I think I wanted to come down here
for something I don't remember what now
okay let's let's try this out I'll show
you how fast this thing warms up and if
you're wondering about my computer many
of you were I have an i7 processor the
860 model I have a 1.5 terabyte hard
drive yes
7200 rpm I have minecraft running on RAM
disk though and I have partitioned 500
Meg's of my RAM which I have 16 gigs
around total partitioned 500 of it 500
Meg's for Minecraft and I think I got an
ATI if it's a 5850 video cards and that
seems to be working
oh yeah I gotta move away from here for
the scalp and start shooting he's gonna
shoot and it is not a custom-built
computer I went to the store I bought it
and yes 16 gigs of ram is excessive kind
of why I got my computer for so cheap -
originally this computer like a year ago
was $2,100
at future shop which is like Best Buy if
you live in the u.s. I think the King
can done all because they're all stuck
in that point that's fine as originally
$2,100 but future shopkins Delanie
they're having a hard time selling the
computer because it was so high-end that
consumers in general don't want to buy a
computer like this and so they kept
lowering it lowering it I bought it six
months ago they had it down to 1800 and
they were throwing in a $300 monitor a
23 inch LED monitor and they had one
left when I went in 6 months ago
and I asked him what kind of deal he
could give me on it and he said 1750
with the monitor after about 30 minutes
of talking to the store manager I
managed to get him down to $1400 with
the monitor and a 3-year warranty for
free so I was pretty happy about that
this computer is custom over here in
Canada - and it was six months ago I
think is a pretty good deal but yeah
this works there are only getting fan
because the tall knobs are stuck in this
spot here but they'll be moving out of
that spot so it's not an issue seems to
work good um so we're going to route the
spiders to a killing chamber here and
then the string will get to routed to
our minecart gate here somehow and what
I'm gonna have is like a door
this is like the simplest item Junction
you can make you can place a door and
say there is a water stream above sure
let's build a crude example here if you
can get I should do this a little better
[Music]
let's try this yeah so what if you have
a water stream going over a door you can
make it so that items will pass over top
the door if there are lines to the right
side like the doors on the sides of the
items right against that side I'll go
over top the door but if you open the
door they'll fall and so I'm going to
use that simple method of choosing
whether string gets sent to the main
collection point down below and I'll be
doing that with with string this film
with bacon and leather and feathers and
eggs and all all the different things so
I'll be able to choose individually what
items I want sent where something like
that
you align them to one side by having a
diet I'll stream of water which I should
probably show you to otherwise
everyone's gonna be like oh I know how
to do it I know how to do it think this
will work
uhh
well anyway I'll figure it out I've done
it before
not that was kind of embarrassing but
you basically need a diagnosed stream of
water and always get aligned to a
certain side if you do it right kind of
like how I have on my main collection
area they always get sent to the same
side like they always get sent to the
side so let they're close to the feather
which is always sent on this side oh
yeah I replace this with wood now kind
of cool and it's super bright I'm sure
you know why I might um some of you
commented I should fill this with water
I probably will solid source blocks I
think just to make it look better I'm
going to check the time on the video and
we might do some more work down here and
we're like out of time already guys and
we didn't really do anything this
episode we're going to do some quick
building it's kind of a bonus
before we finish things up so remember
this is going to be a control room so
hopefully I'll get to show you what I
mean by that
and we're just going to be using wood
planks right now I might switch them or
add some kind of texture or something
later well let's make this come out more
a need more time I'll do it later
um so I think we want to leave like a
one block space from this these soil
blocks so probably here would be good I
don't I'm just kind of crazy building
here and something similar on the other
side people one block space as we're
going to be running vertical wires these
chests are actually in the way darn and
they're full hmm
all right I'm going to move the chest
guys and then we'll do a little bit more
here all right let's took a while to
move
I moved the wall in by one I replace the
soil with wood just so we can have an
extra block space make it a little bit
more roomy slowly little by little house
is coming together some of you have
wondered how much I play Minecraft today
well I think this project speaks for
itself I still don't have a roof over my
head
nothing seems to get done people have
actually downloaded my world and
finished the storage room I think like
five people have done that already
before me and it's my world I play
Minecraft about an hour to a day on
average I don't play in any other worlds
and I don't like start to play SMP a
little bit again not much on Taikan
server I'm going to actually put a link
in the description to Titans Channel
he makes Minecraft videos I he's pretty
good to watch
and thank you tycoon for letting me on
your server even though I never see you
there and yeah I don't really spend much
time on a server yet anyway but I'm
going to be showing you the plan
so this is a control room on this side
and one of these sides we're going to
have levers for hostile mobs there's
going to be four options I think this
side will be for passive mobs there will
be five options five levers and I'm not
putting them there I'm just using this
example for the passive mobs one of
these levers we're going to run vertical
wire up so it'll be torches on the back
and you can run vertical wire by placing
a block above and then more torches and
keep the string going right now it's off
flip it on you can run as high as you
want that way much like this so the
ah these ones are going to go to level
three the hostile ones are going to go
to level two the options we're going to
have feathers on or off using that
simple door junction thing and we're
going to have bacon or pork chops or
whatever they're called wool I do have a
method plan for getting the wool off
sheep I really hope I can get it to work
because it's going to be complicated and
always done it yet so I'm hoping I'm not
stretching my limits too much leather
and there's also going to be a egg farm
[Music]
the way that's going to work normally
the chickens will be sent to a killing
chamber um there's going to be a
junction that will either send them to
the killing chamber or second option
will be to a like a caged area with a
water stream that pushes the eggs they
lake to our main collection area here
and say there's about 20 chickens in
your egg place if you switch this off
again then those 20 chickens will be
sent to the killing chamber and you'll
get the feathers from them and chickens
lay eggs every five minutes I believe
and oh yeah if if you're collecting eggs
the chickens won't die all the other
animals will so eventually the amount of
chickens you have will keep growing and
growing until you reach the limit and
you'll have probably 24 chickens
producing eggs without having to do what
some people do and spawn if you like do
a youtube search for chicken firms
they're all kind of cheap people just
shoot a bunch of eggs into a hole and
they call it a chicken farm this is
going to be a real chicken farm egg farm
whatever moving on hostile mobs will
have a door junction for string and will
have a cook house a cook house is a path
that the tall mobs will take where
they're exposed to sunlight and only the
creepers will survive or mostly just the
creepers and that will make it so pretty
much only gunpowder will drop
so if I have string shut off so the no
string will go to the collection point
and I have the cook house on pretty much
everything that comes to the collection
point will be gunpowder which would be a
nice feature and I've run out of signs
let's hope I have some left
okay really need to end this episode of
quick I think record studio you guys
know that's about kind of I'm going to
be using the same method in my record
studio as I am going to use for sharing
wool hopefully you know I'm just going
to tell you guys what the method is if
you watch ribbits video he made a way to
shear sheep he found a way skeletons
if they shoot sheep they'll shoot the
wall off the sheep and you can get wool
that way also works for fur creepers too
but I don't know how you do that
reliably so my plan is to have some way
of getting new skeletons
probably using the quick and dirty mop
separator method get them into isolated
locations and they'll be looking at each
other and I'm going to walk over on one
side of them and one skeletons going to
shoot the other skeleton and they're
going to enter a fight and I'll have
bamboo here or something to protect me
so I don't get shot and then I'll push a
button and they'll get sent away through
the tube into each in their own separate
tube and then they're going to get sent
to a place where they'll both be on one
side and the sheep will come in between
them and while they're having their
fights I'm going to make it so they
can't actually kill each other and
they'll just be an endless fight forever
constantly shooting arrows at each other
so anything that passes in between them
like a sheep will get their wool shirt
off
or in the case of the record studio
I'll have the creepers down to one hits
and as they pass through they instantly
will produce a record and it all gets
sent to the main collection area and so
all I have to do is set the system once
get them into their fight and I can be
down here doing whatever I want and I
will be automatically creating records
up there because they're doing all the
work for me and they're sharing the wool
and all that that's my plan it's going
to be hard to do though finally question
question question probably you mob the
automated mobs order will be the last
option possibly but yeah that's the plan
IQ excited chicken ah thanks for
watching went way over time I think and
I'll see you next time