hello peeps and peepers
II throw it here again with episode 17
and I guess I'm kind of in trouble with
you guys because as Eleanor pointed out
I'm not really upholding my real number
for her let's play videos which is I'm
supposed to be showing you guys stuck by
those as I build it other one and so I'm
kind of guilty of that and is like one
guy left the comments it's like whether
at least build the timer on video and
set while I was reading I was like oh
dang I already have a timer all built
and everything so yeah I'm sorry about
that guys I will I will try build more
in my videos
another guy said you know I would rather
watch you bill Jesus mom dude instead of
watching you go to the nether but the
thing is you know this thing could
probably be built in like 15 minutes
which we've filled in episodes nicely
let me actually inventing this thing and
working out the kinks and everything but
well over three hours which would take
over twelve episodes because I also
think slower when I'm trying to I'm
trying to talk and build things at the
same time so those twelve episodes would
me would be me just getting late you
hear those twelve episodes it'd just be
me walking around incoherently and you
know so I'm trying I'm going to try to
build more on-camera homes and same with
this timer thing you know I it took well
over two hours in science and another
leg hour to wire it and that would be
another twelve episodes and nothing
would ever get done in our world and I
want to do lots of different things but
I'm gonna explain how this works in a
sec and episodes after insulter I build
quantum on camera and I'm going to run
through you through the thought process
I had with the timer so in our last
episode episode 16 I started building
this thing pretend these dirt blocks
these floating ones are slow sand
and let's get some votes so the concept
with this timer was the boat would
travel along here and this would be the
interval or the time passed and how do I
explain this I was going to have a stack
of boats here so say this the time it
takes to go from here to and around say
that was 30 seconds to make 5 minutes I
would need 11 boats and what would
happen is when a boat gets to here for
example it would send another one and
eventually all 11 votes would get sent
they would be stacked here and on this
pressure plate once the 11th boat leaves
here it would trigger that a 5 minutes
have passed and then they would go up
and I started building up what do you
call it my minecart gates a modified
version of it here and I modified it so
that it would hold a stack of boats and
I did that by removing the corner here
so let the corner boat would run against
this wall here and the corner of the
boat would bump into the corner of this
one and then an inverted stack of boats
would form underneath this boat
I'll show you how that worked I think it
still works and obviously this is very
rough because I never actually finished
this because it was getting stupidly
complicated and big and also so I have
an inverted stack of boats here
underneath the minecart Cape thing and
so this was to be the reset button so if
I would pick up the items the timer
would get reset and the stack of boats
would fall back over here onto a stack
here and it would go again but then I
realized that this inverted thing didn't
work because the votes do that so I
would have to make it fall onto the mine
party I kind of had one of those what
the heck am i doing moments and thought
this was way too complicated it's not
worth doing and I needed to try
something simpler so this was our first
model then I came up with this idea
so the goal with this idea was to make
the timer simpler and smaller but most
importantly smaller and as some of you
also pointed out in the comments
since I'm measuring the time it takes
for an item to de-spawn I should
basically just sacrifice an item and
when it despond it should trigger that
the time is up so I thought I had this
figured out now I don't know if you can
see it but I got a door here and a water
stream leads up to a pressure plate I
figured I need two pressure plates to do
it the first one would be the one that
has the item that Dee spawns and the
second one won't be where the items
would drop so if I had a stream of items
coming first one that hits this pressure
plate would open the door and then all
the following items would fall down
ideally onto another pressure plate but
then I realized it's impossible to make
the items fall onto a pressure plate
down here because you must have a block
underneath the door so I couldn't put a
pressure plate below here so this idea
didn't work then I moved on to the next
idea the same concept except with my
minecart date which is broken at the
moment it seems
unfortunately but the way this worked
was the item stream would come and it
the items you pushed around and when we
did this pressure plate the boat would
move out of the way and then the items
would fall down onto another pressure
plate but the problem was the boat in to
occupy a full block space and items
weren't able to make it across so
anaphor unfortunately the boat is stuck
in the land right now so I can't show
you then this was a failed attempt to
make the boat fit in a block space like
right now this area here is in a full
block space this boat but if you adjust
the levers here you'll notice it just
goes past here that's one two and you
have to treat your reserve time to make
it stop where we want it well this is
another failed idea and then finally as
some of you also suggested in the
comments I should use a dispenser and
that worked awesome
so this was my prototype I used to build
it first I'll show you at the time how
the timer works and then we'll come back
to there so right now
Oh fine Hey ouch
aah my game is getting laggy Oh
oh great starting to think switching to
a ram just was not a good idea okay
idea what the timer was if items would
be spawning and it's time to pick them
up these lights will be flashing there's
no items the lights go off and if there
are items the lights come on though
we'll just throw an item here and that
trigger dispenser which shoots out a
feather lands on the second plate which
makes lights go on and winces feather
despawn after five minutes it'll start
triggering the flashing which means it's
time to pick up your items or else are
gonna disappear so it's easier to see
how this works with this prototype I
built
I built this first this is the one this
is the pressure plate the items land on
this is the one the feather timer lands
on
so we'll call this one a this one B so a
connects to a NAND gate here and it also
connects to the dispenser here which
shoots the block which falls on two
pressure plate B the timer plate and the
timer plates pressure plate B has a wire
that leads over to the and eight as well
and also there's a five o'clock here
which triggers the flashing which is
connected to the wire as well and then
the signal gets inverted and this is our
our light so
the feather didn't land on the pressure
plate yeah that's why I'm using water to
guide the feather onto the pressure
plate to because the dispenser shoots it
out unreliably so there's no feather on
this pressure plate which indicates a
theis pond which means it's time to pick
up your items so it was flashing there's
nothing on it's off if something is on
both of them it stays on because it's
sending a signal which overrides the
five o'clock here and goes to the and
eats and I'm using feathers because
they're the most useless mob item so I
don't care if if I lose a few and the
way this looks over here slower the
volume a bit
so the water streams merge and they go
to this one which is when items come
from
got the dispenser there
it's like a feather which lands on
specially and items always come on this
side of the block the right side the
dispenser shoots it to the left side so
they bump together on both pressure
plates so that when I pick them up I
make sure I always grab them off of both
pressure plates then I got the levers
for the doors Junction still it works
pretty good thought time this wire will
trigger the dispenser even though when I
test fitted Dennis like when I when I
flip the door Junction I think if
there's an item on the pads it does that
and now it's not shooting a feather out
so and it flashes for a while until the
first stuff the feather falls down then
it stops flashing until it be spawns and
let's go look down at the wiring which
took me a good hour it's gonna head to
see where to start
okay so as you ring here next to the two
indicator lights this one here which
goes up
sends a signal up through this block
here to one of the indicator lights and
then this one goes to the other
indicator light which sends a signal up
through this block and this lit up wire
here is some pressure plate a the one
where the items land on a little hard to
move around in here this is what the
item pressure plate activates and it
sends a wire to the dispenser which is
over there there's no space in here and
I can't really break out these blocks
because there's water above me it sends
a signal underneath these blocks here
so this torch goes up and up and through
here and then the dispensers above and
it also sends a wire to the antique same
exact thing is about that I showed you
and this wire here is from pressure
plate to be one that the these funny
feathers on its ends there's a redstone
torch right there sends the signal down
and it gets inverted back to a softer
way that's along the wire got the five
five here which is overrides and it goes
to and eats and egos two goes up here
torch signal to this block and set the
torch signal up to our indicator lights
so ya big pain to build it
I have no idea how to get out of here
now another reason that why I didn't
want to build this on camera inside the
taking too long is you guys probably
would have got claustrophobic down here
and dizzy from you camera all over the
place
and yeah so it's all done quite happy
with the dynamic and I am lagging again
all right sorry about that I just
checked I guess we're about out of time
too so we're going to wrap it up here
and I'm going to work on my rule number
four some more
hopefully we'll build more things
together from now on
sometimes I just get carried away
building things and I don't want to stop
so I'll work on it
we'll build more things together but at
the same time
I refuse to upload twelve incoherent
episodes of me building things like that
we have to reach some kind of compromise
and even like building this thing I
actually had to go to youtube and check
out how to build a minecart cake because
I forgot I had to look at my tutorial
and I have to draw diagrams on paper
like like we couldn't have done that
together anyway so so we'll have to
reach some kind of compromise but anyway
you guys want we need to figure out how
what kind of flooring we're going to use
in our storage room and what kind of
walls like should we build with wood or
sandstone that type of thing I'll let
you guys help choose and whoever
whatever gets the most votes that's what
we'll build so any ideas on that is
definitely welcome
actually any ideas are welcome so
rambling now so I'm going to say goodbye
and thanks for watching