hello hello this is etho
well i got big news guys you're never
going to believe this
i never thought this day was ever going
to come
you were wondering where was spaz last
episode i was wondering it too
he ruins every one of my specials for
some reason he didn't show up
what was the dealio when i finished
recording i kind of
took a few steps back to my admire my
emp unit and while i was looking for at
it from a distance admiring its beauty
i noticed spaz creeping out of the
forest
to come take a look at the unit for
himself i think he was
curious he was looking around and then
i noticed he went inside of it
so i kind of snuck around
creeped around and then i flipped the
lever and guess what
the barrier came down and he's trapped
some of his friends came to help but
their efforts were in vain
oh this is such a great day victory
spaz hello spaz
how's it going how's it going in there
calm down calm down just kidding
you want a sandwich you look kind of sad
maybe you want a
tissue
what's wrong are you feeling confined
restricted
powerless okay calm down buddy
calm down i'm just kidding i'm just
kidding
oh you think you're mad mouse fast just
wait until you find out what i have in
store for you
ah so how should we do this guys what
should we do with spaz we have so many
options
you know
maybe maybe we'll let them out
let's flip the barrier
oh but the top one's still there i'm
sorry it's fast
you can't come out no um
this is so fun teasing him
he's been a jerk he really has he
deserves it
you know what spazz if i pull this lever
here
yeah that lever there you know what's
gonna happen
the floor is going to open up and you're
going to fall in lava
is that do you think i should do that
spaz
i don't think he likes that idea
i know i sound like a crazy lunatic guys
and it's true i am evil
but really what's that expression
i'm the lesser of two evils spazz here
is the big evil guy
yeah you know i think the best
i think what we're gonna do spaz
drowning yeah we're gonna drown you
any last words
no he's just mad this is
it spazz uh i always fix my levers up
i think it's this one
oh no
oh it doesn't work
or does it
i think i need to modify this guys spazz
how's it going in there
you okay
we'll do this slow guys we'll just we'll
just
torture him by a little bit so how does
that make you feel spazzed
are you upset you sound upset
[Music]
maybe we'll maybe we'll uh do it some
more
drown them a little bit more oh wrong
lever
wrong lever