oh man I just had the best idea ever
window oh why did I think of that before
ah makes the place so much bigger it's
like the world he's inside my house now
as totally awesome what's up everybody
this is Eko thank you for joining me so
I got a lot of great response uh telling
me what this is someone told me you use
it to make blue fire apparently so I'm
guessing it must be copper chloride or
something then I thought it was emeralds
but I guess it looks like copper
chloride I don't know what else it could
be
so we're going to try make some blue
fire with this stuff and I'm guessing
you can make blue torches no huh
um maybe you got a melon wonder I doubt
it was a false tip it's probably yeah
you probably need to throw it into a
fire now let that make the fire blue
let's try it again oh that's weird
oh you know unless maybe you need to
throw like a bunch of them on the ground
first and then light it on fire and then
it probably makes blue fire no huh he
didn't tell me how to use them properly
I just kind of assumed well unless oh
you know what it's probably maybe it
turns lava blue that's probably what it
is
No now what the heck Oh unless it's to
make like blue fireworks that could be
maybe it's like what do you call it that
make nelem or whatever it is let's make
some copper chloride blocks or made now
um it'll probably make blue fire Robson
no now what that is so weird
I must I'm going to fall stick then who
would give me a false tip like that
that's that's just rude
no don't worry I haven't lost my mind
it's just that it's the ten thousand
subscriber special which is just a poor
cover of excuse for me to act stupid and
blow stuff up but yeah ten thousand
subscribers it's amazing thank you
everybody
growing fast unbelievably fast I think
I've been doubling just about every
month now and I owe it a lot of it to
you guys I'm sure because I think you do
a lot of advertising for me on the
forums and whatnot when people have
problems you throw my name around which
really helps me out a lot so thank you
for that I appreciate it
thank you for liking my videos when you
do because that also helps to get more
attention to my channel cuz it shows up
in other people's the boxes and stuff so
yep but mostly thank you for watching my
episodes you make it a lot of fun by
commenting and stuff otherwise I
probably would have stopped doing this
long ago yeah I kind of got carried away
the other day when I finished up because
I didn't want to stop working on the
tree farm so I just kept going I was in
the zone you know so fortunately I built
it off-camera but I really enjoyed it
very fun and relaxing to just build
without worrying about other people
watching they mess up and stuff so this
is the tree farm
it's uh covered up now I don't have to
worry about creepers jumping down on me
and it still functions well it's a
little bit darker in here but it's not
too dark it's kind of nice and we got
the windows I really like this method of
putting a glass out one box
and then I've been putting torches on
the inside of the window it looks really
cool especially outside during the night
yeah so the tree farm is done and then
of course I just tattoo cactus farm
which is pretty much a copy yep pretty
much copy now the exciting part though I
don't have a proper way to get up so I'm
just going up through the through the
Takas farm for now but yeah this is a
this is above the farms spent a little
time trying to make it look a little
better got a cool little bridge here I
don't know what you call this a pond
with a cover over top and benches to
pretend to sit down at yeah oh that's
nice too bad I'm all alone here but the
thing I really like about this is the
tree canopy which is a pretty cool we
got the astroturf which actually looks
good in my opinion and in between the
two the bridge we have water
and which is above class and since this
is above class I had to place every
single one of these water box took
a long time and yeah this looks pretty
cool though I think it's not done of
course I'll probably make a tree canopy
above here yet and do something similar
that I have over there and my frame rate
just drops I'm going to stop for a sec
all right sorry about that
it gets better now okay so the way this
canopy works is ah yeah my team's really
lighting right now I basically I just
kept growing these trees over and over
until I got ones I liked you you'll
notice most of them are the great trees
and then in the center I have these
hovering logs and all I've been doing is
like placing dirt too high and placing a
sapling on top growing it with bone meal
and then cutting off the logs beneath
and the leaves stay up in the middle is
how I've been how I built that canopy
over there a word of caution now if you
do that it's going to like your game
like crazy because the code is very
unoptimized for a leaf decay and yeah
this is partially done only um when I
figure out what I'm going to do with all
this stuff this part here will probably
join with that part over there somehow
and it'll be all green and trees and
nice because
that's the way I like it somehow they'll
join together and all work and let's go
down below and it right now these water
screen or like this River in the middle
just cuts off real sloppy here I'll make
something nice or later and on this end
I plan on building some type of
waterfall maybe I have one here already
but I don't like quite how this looks so
probably build something slightly
different and yeah I'm happy with how it
looks uh something you guys might might
not like it tore many of you guys it's
kind of a weird style but I don't
usually build things normally and
underneath the farms I have these wooden
supports pillars which aren't really
necessary for anything except looks and
that timers in my way now so I really
need to make the tutorial to the cannon
to get it out of here and the house is
kind of in my way so yeah but they'll
probably be a waterfall down here you
might be able to ride a boat down
somehow eventually and will probably be
a big pool of water underneath the
waterfall and maybe I don't don't know
exactly how it's been work but hopefully
it will be cool looks pretty neat
underneath here too ah there probably
won't be like a building here it'll
probably be the green astroturf and
fountains and stuff and trees maybe
maybe some flowerbeds
we'll see I'm going to give you a far
distance look at it I think and this is
what it looks like from a distance at
night
and cool very strange all those torches
I had like on the astroturf I'll
probably make little lanterns or
something instead something that looks a
little bit more fancy I guess step just
having torches on the ground uh-huh
work in progress you guys have ideas let
me know but hey hello
they're huge like that's I think it was
like 20 blocks up or so to the green
grass part so pretty big farms but yeah
we're running out of time so let's go to
the cannons shall we
toward Tillis okay here we are at the
cannons guys and I've added some new
ones as you can see we'll go up there in
a sec what I've done is I've actually
pre-loaded most of these already the
save time here so we're just going to
run through them real quick thank you
everybody for donating as always and I
very much appreciate it it always puts a
smile on my face when I see someone else
has donated
and yeah I didn't fully run the numbers
but since last time we did this
I think there's 10 new donors and I
think like another $100 so thank you
guys get this evil knock crap oh oh I
can't get out because of the stupid
ladders now thinking ah not I got
unpeaceful for right now yeah I don't
know where we were I think it was around
here yeah we did these furious George
robot Evan
ch Zhou Jimmy I can't see a thing
and again if any of these things are
wrong let me know we're ready to change
anything
I'm kind of like in a rush here to
finish up this episode because it's
getting really long I'm probably going
to actually stop recording in 720p just
because it's causing me problems my
internet sucks so it takes forever to
upload the videos and it's causing other
issues to also is this taking longer to
make an episode because of it which is
kind of annoying and this is where I
left off I ran out of tea and he
actually and I brought like four stats
with me but it wasn't enough and I will
remember to load these ones this time I
didn't change any of the settings from
last time because I kind of rushed you
so sorry about that I don't remember
what it was like anyway so you guys
probably figure out - okay so those are
all loaded um let's go up there okay so
I made like a new cannon design for you
guys I hope you don't mind stepping
vertical cannons who get these weird new
ones and I'll get to the explanation of
them pretty quick
but these are all the new donors thank
you guys I am really curious about your
name most likely a coincidence of course
yeah so these cannons are triggered by
fire and they have water timers so the
fire burns this block here which
destroys a sleeve er which activates the
boosters when the lever gets destroyed
and also it releases this water which
pours down flows destroys another lever
and it activates the missile
so that just for something different
something different ten interesting
they're easy to reset I just need to
replace two levers and the block that
burns of course so yeah that's about it
so I'm going to set up the wicks here
I'm going to connect these all together
then we're going to do our launch
hopefully before day I just made a bunch
of wicks here and I'm connecting them
all together with wood that's pretty
simple I'm doing a bat-like I'm going to
make a backup here before I did all this
so it'll be easy to return back to
normal without using all this TNT
so just the reignite this block
underneath the glass here all right not
that one the one with the lever on okay
so we're all set up here
and I'm going to make a quick backup
first all right I have a backup before I
start loading the cannons and now I have
one with them all loaded so I should be
set for any problem and I'm going to
start the launch so I'm going to light
this and then run over to our other
button hopefully fast enough and in the
future I'll probably set this up a
little bit more fancy okay thank you
everybody enjoy the show
Oh
well let that happen last time they must
interfered with each other somehow on
some of the animals live that sucks
okay now let's head back to the base now
there's one thing we need to do before
we can end this well we've come a long
way guys since since I've started this
and really curious to find out how
things are going to turn out I've got
some good ideas in store yet but of
course time is kind of limited at the
moment so for the next month or so I'm
probably not going to be interacting
with you very much by PMS and stuff I'll
still keep reading your comments and
stuff but yeah I only have so much time
but then in June I'll be back but before
we can end this you know what we need to
do we need to harvest the clay
but your clay jokes are lame no one
cares let's settle this my Beach now you
die Oh general spat all I have been
waiting for this oh he finally wants to
have a direct fight a fair fight
oh sweet
okay I'm gonna we're gonna suit up and
then we're gonna go to his Beach and
we'll finish this off because this is my
Island and I I plan on defending it
uh-huh
I knew it what the hex pads I thought
we're going to settle this like man the
fair fight
come down
get get down here oh boy oh oh you
little cheapo Manny always does this he
always aah he can't beat me in a fair
fight and he knows that he always has to
do this crap I mean surprise attack
me I finally thought we were gonna fight
fair this time and he's built himself a
little tower get down here
Errol blast
get down here you look ah how did he get
up there hey how do you have a thirst
fast come on come down stop jumping
around I'm gonna get you hey you know
nope okay let's sink this through it I
think there must be a ladder in the back
I think that's how we got up okay so I'm
going to sneak around real quick and I
climb up cuz he's stuck up there you
can't run
oh crap EST no no that's it's bad I'm
going home right if you don't want to
fight fair oh man I just happen
ah I'm not out here Spencer you know
when you're ready to fight like men when
you grow a pair of arms any tension