[Music]
hey everyone welcome back
uh thanks for joining me again today got
big plans for today's episode we're
going to try and build
our passive mob spawning pads for
the ice base here so that's what our
goal is
hopefully we can get as much done as
possible
but before we begin that we need to put
the floor in here
and it seems like the black and blue
wool
was the winner people didn't like
sandstone too much so
i think we're gonna go with black and
blue
[Music]
so
yeah we're just gonna do a straight line
type thing
a few people suggest that you try to
like a pattern
like a fancy pattern on the ground but i
don't know
this is supposed to be a lab i think we
want a clean look
[Music]
so straight lines are okay for me
if we don't like it we can always change
it
yeah we got blue and black i probably
don't have enough wool to finish
the whole thing
[Music]
but it definitely uh contrasts with the
snow pretty good
yeah it looks pretty good i think
gonna get rid of all this soil
oops should we need that gun
uh maybe i'll try to talk about the
passive mob stuff as
i do this uh so i've decided on a
pattern
for the passive mob system it's a
different than anything i've done
yet uh it's only going to be
100 blocks of spawning space my old one
on chocolate island has about 500 blocks
of spawning space
so the new one's going to be
significantly smaller
which isn't a bad thing really
we don't really need it as big because
here we have all the grass cleared i
think
pretty sure but on chocolate island we
never
cleared all the grass around the area so
in order to
keep the mob spawning
efficient there we needed larger
amount of space for them to spawn on
and another thing about passive mobs
their cap is a lot lower than it is for
hostile mobs
like i believe hostile mobs
is 70 i could be wrong i think passive
mobs
is about 25 i'm probably wrong about
that too though
so roughly let's say roughly about three
times less
is the cap so we really only need a
spawning system that's three times
smaller
uh we're not going to reach
the cap nearly as likely
so that's kind of why i'm making this
smaller
and also uh like dot dm has one i think
it's a hundred and forty four blocks and
it seems to keep up no problem
he only has four six by six pads
so i think this will work pretty good
and i have decided to do a diamond
uh pattern for the spawning pads instead
of square
so that we can uh flood the pads
some people were worried that flooding
them with water is going to kill the
grass
it's not an issue because i will have
enough lighting
so that the grass doesn't die even if
it's underwater
[Music]
yeah that really stands out
i wonder if it needs to be three wide
maybe too wide would have been good
enough
okay well i'm going to finish this up
off camera so that we can actually start
our spawning pads this episode and then
i will be back
yeah even this spiral grass structure i
have here keeps up with the
spawning passive mobs pretty good and
it's only about
50 spawnable places so my
pads are going to be twice that size and
also
this structure here is only in one chunk
and my pads will be in four different
chunks so every time the game tries to
place mobs
this structure here it only tries to
place them once
in my pads it'll try to place it four
times so
i should get way more mobs than i'm
getting over here
and over here is pretty good as it is so
my pads should be
really good even though they're pretty
small
i ran out of wool but this is what we
got so far
don't know if i'll keep the snow in the
middle and this will
probably end up looping like connecting
to over here will be stairs either
up or down here and same with on this
side
i'm thinking i might have like my
controls for the spawning pads over here
i have a wall here with uh
the ability to turn
like my passive mob farm on or off
hostile mob farms on or off lighting on
or off that type of thing
uh but yeah we're ready to start
building our pads i believe
this is where you don't want to make any
mistakes because this is a
this is a pretty definite thing once you
start building it i do have a world back
up in case i need to
in case i change my mind about something
major
okay so passive mobs are going to go on
this side
this is our center here these four soil
blocks i've marked
i think i want to start here
yeah okay so this is where
our center for the passive mob farm is
going to be
that's going to be based on an odd
number
instead of an even number so that's why
we're only choosing one
of these blocks instead of all four of
these
so this is our center for our past mop
firm
and we need to go up minimum
24 blocks so i'm going to write down our
y-coordinate 71
oh actually you know what the sun's
going down i'm going to skip
a day so that'll be light when we're
doing this
okay here we go new day let's start
building
this is our center we're at 71 we're
going to go up
to 90.
and two more okay at 90.
so our 20th block will be our ceiling
probably make the ceiling out of snow
had a little bit of lag there
make a little platform here kind of like
oh i'm really lazy
okay and
i think i'll place water
here we go
okay i hope that didn't wreck any
wiring oh crap it might have
no because that snow is still intact
it's fine
okay so we have a wave king up and down
that is pretty high we need it to be at
least our spawning pads at least 24
blocks up
so this is going to be a huge room if if
that's the ceiling for it
should be pretty cool
okay so we have our platform here on
this level here we'll be doing
kind of the mob sorting and stuff out of
sight
so like the pigs the chickens the cows
the sheep will fall
down here and then they'll go through
some pipes which will sort them into
their individual
chambers there it's a plan the actual
spawning pads will be a little bit
higher
this is our center uh we're gonna make
this
sorting room i think five blocks
then the sixth block will be our
start of our spawning pad
system and we'll probably build it out
of cobblestone just because it's cheap
and we will go to
three
okay so this is our center don't want to
lose sight of our center
wow
okay uh we're gonna make our opening
three long like this so that mobs don't
get stuck
going down the hole this is a hole for
them to fall down
and we will extend this
a fair bit
i think we need to make each of the
sides about seven
long
or so
i don't know exactly how i'm doing this
i just have a pretty
pretty decent idea in my head
okay so i think we're above the blue
wool right now
so let's go that far on the other side
here
okay and then we will
line this
brought lots of cobblestone with me
because i figured we would be using a
lot on this
okay good
um one
two three four five six
we probably want this eight long
seven
[Music]
eight
and there'll be a water stream here
flowing right to the end and same with
on the other side
one two three four five six
six two three four five
six seven two three four
five six seven okay
eights and
that should do it
okay so we'll have a water stream there
we're gonna get rid of this for now
and now i just need to make a huge
flat ground section here that'll go
see one two
three four five six
seven eight nine
i thought i saw a sheep on our
cobblestone here but he's on the spiral
so we're going to connect this to the
other side and we're going to have water
streams
on this
we don't want to use my other style with
this
the no dead zone trick using the stairs
because uh chickens get stuck in stairs
so we have to do something else with
this system
so i'm going to fill this in and i'm
going to make an exact copy on the other
side and then we will be back
so i did that i filled it all in
so now we've got a big flat surface here
to work with and we're going to put a
border all around this
this is to hold water in place
that we're going to place soon
it's pretty simple with this new system
there's going to be almost no signs used
for uh
controlling the water which is good in
case that notch ever
changes that favor makes it so signs
can't hold water back
this thing should still work okay
not that i'm too worried about that
okay i'm gonna make a water pool here
yeah so we'll have water here
it ends over there right at the edge
because it only flows eight blocks
maximum
one two three four five six seven eight
okay and then for uh
these side things we made they'll be
water placed all along this
back wall here
all the way down and that ends
right at the edge as well so the mobs
will flow
straight down they'll fall into this
stream they'll flow this way
and they'll fall down this three wide
hole here it's three wide so that they
don't
clump up and prevent each other from
falling down
uh but we're gonna wait on doing that
just a little bit oh yeah i gotta
remember to cover this
otherwise it's gonna freeze too oh
like
okay uh
so i suppose the next thing we're gonna
do is build our spawning pads we're
gonna have four
um four spawning pads are gonna be
diamond shaped
with a base of seven
so wow this game is really lightning bad
two three would be seven
here would be
the start i believe so
diagonally from this corner is one two
three four blocks it's the fifth block
and we want it three off the ground
that's the center of one of our diamonds
and it'll come out uh one two
three
two three
each of these pads has 25
spawnable blocks on
and since there's four we'll have a
hundred total
because 1 plus 3 plus 5 plus 7 plus 5
plus 3 plus 1
is 25 the total
and we can shut it off by dropping water
right here
okay so i'm gonna build three more of
these and then i will see you
after that's done
the spawning pads are done they did not
take long to build
they're very simple but now before we
look at them we want to
get a grass block to them so we're on
our spiral tower here
and as many people suggested i can just
use pistons to
move the grass
hopefully
there we go
so we're going to move this upward first
and we will fill in with more soil
get the height we want about
um yeah it's good i think
and now we want to move it sideways
and we'll steal our lever back
now one thing about the spawning pads
minor diamond shape that's just because
i want to be able to
oops wrong level
that's just so i want i'll be able to
easily turn
passive mob spawning on or off really
though
you probably don't need that feature
i don't even really need it i just want
it as a just in case
and if i ever need to do testing i want
to have that feature
like if if notch decides he wants to put
all the hostile mobs and passive mobs
if he wants them all to share the same
spawning cap then
i may want to be able to turn passive
mob spawning off
but at the moment there's really no
point to it
so yeah you probably don't need to make
yours diamond shaped if you're going to
copy me you could
probably just do a square
it would be more space efficient if you
do a square
not that it matters much because i'm
pretty sure a hundred uh
100 spawning spots is going to be plenty
and
that's the limit and there's plenty of
space in minecraft for you to build
for you to waste space with the diamond
shape stuff
oops yeah go here put another one down
ah darn it there i didn't give it to me
either
last one
and we're about there i'd say
uh we want to move it two more blocks i
suppose
good
okay uh maybe we'll just let it spread
the rest of the way
i'll go out of the soil
i have our water set up on the sides
here and ice form
[Applause]
and we will disconnect this
good okay so that grass will spread to
our diamonds here
uh when this is all done i'm gonna cut
out this
connecting piece to all of them
and the mother should spawn on these and
they'll fall off and
to our water here and since it's only a
one
two three block drop they'll freely walk
off
mobs will freely walk off any spawning
pad that's within
three and a half blocks drop this one's
a three
yeah so that should be good the only
place they won't walk off is if they try
to fall down
if they were going to walk off into this
lower part here in the center
it's too far down for them to fall
all right so i'm going to clean up a
little bit here and i'll see you
in a little bit
i went to remove that spiral grass tower
and when i was down on the ground
this one little grass block spawned the
sheep
so it's working
oh yeah and i fell down and died that
kind of sucked
i'm glad you missed that uh
so we are just waiting for the giraffes
to spread now
uh we need to set up
our water shut offs above
the center point on each of these
spawning pads i may
make the ceiling in here only too high
above the pads
uh underneath these pads there's a too
high clearance so
even if a mob falls off let's say
over here the water will push him under
and he can swim underneath the pads here
to this point
and then he'll go this way so
very simple water setup i may play
around with the water stream to try make
a
diagonal flow so it pushes more towards
the center instead of
straight here i don't know why my game
is so lady today
i probably need to do a computer reboot
um yeah maybe we'll
end it here episodes long
ah come on
so i'll expand this floor out
and it will come down
and there'll be walls behind my emp
units probably
that go all the way up to that snow
there
and now it's dark underneath here so we
need lighting of course
and uh i may
have a blue stripe running around
somewhere like at this level here like
where the glass block is
a blue or green stripe running around
these emp units as well
just to bounce out the look
and we should make sure these things are
working
what was that oh
oh you know how i should wire these
actually
yeah i just thought of something here
if this bottom glass block is up this
shouldn't open
if the water is on because the water is
not flowing here anyway
so i may look into changing that yet
oh one of my levers is gone
i wonder how that happened it's probably
when water flowed
when i let that water go down here
yep seems to be working okay
all right well i think that's it for
today next episode we'll probably work
on the passive mob sorting
on that snow level there and by that
time the grass i'll probably all the
grass spread
and i might work on setting up the water
shutoffs
we'll see that's it for today thanks for
watching
take care until next time