this thing is just so awesome
creepers go up jump falls down I just
love watching it anyway hey everyone
this is etho this is our 40th episode
yeah that's pretty cool and have you
guys been I've been busy that's why
there's been no episodes recently and
also I should probably mention something
I haven't played Minecraft in like two
days
but like two days ago I had about 20
messages in my inbox on YouTube private
messages that I haven't responded to yet
and I haven't done anything in two days
and now I have about 80 so if you're
wondering why I don't respond to your
messages it's because usually I I try to
respond to 10 to 20 a day on average
but you know now that I have 80 it's
like that's gonna take forever to catch
up again it's actually at the point
where you guys send me messages faster
than I can respond because I'm kind of
busy but I don't want you guys to hate
me like if I don't respond but at the
same time I don't want you like to stop
sending any messages because I do read
every single one that is for sure I
always read them I check out the videos
you send me and stuff like that I just
might not necessarily respond to them
or respond to them right away sometimes
it takes me a few days so please don't
hate me keep sending me messages I love
getting the great feedback from you guys
and yeah so I want to finish up my mob
system we got a lot of work to do yet
though but before I can really do
anything with the friendly mobs or the
hostile mobs I need to figure out what
I'm going to do about the the record
station and the record studio sorry or
the wool sharing so this episode I'm
going to be going to the stupid Island
over here and I am going to be playing
on that other mob system I built and
testing out different things and I'll
see you in a second all right guys here
we are been doing a little bit of work
here already probably won't have time to
show you everything I do so I'll just
show you little progress clips I make
and I up a spider separator just
so that they are out of the way they
instantly die and I'm trying to figure
out a way to do the cookhouse and as
little space as possible so I got water
running up this pipe here they go over
then they fall and I'm going to be
testing I'm going to make them fall
through some lava
and see how little space I can make it
work
I want them to take like one hit from
Sun oh boy I gotta get out here
I want them to take one hit from
sunlight and then pick the rest of the
damage from a lab a damaged fall damage
whatever but yeah so I'll play around
with it a bit and I'll see you again
soon okay our first test is all set up
here um so the goal with our cook house
is to damage the mobs to the point that
if they take one hit from sunlight or
one shot from a skeleton arrow they will
die so there's a no sunlight in this
area here I would just use gravity and
fall damage so you get them to the point
I want them but it would take a lot more
space so I thought I could just use a
lab a blade and drop them through it
they would take fire damage and then
they should be close to the point to die
but I guess the fire damage completely
kills them so that's not going to work
also sometimes they get too stuck in the
lab of the blade they try to swim up so
it's not reliable either but while I was
making this I got an even better idea so
that's what our second test is going to
be and I will show you that to you
shortly
that's a little strange I can't like put
the lavvo Network alright here's the
second idea this works very similar to
the way I did the spider killing thing
I'm using the Southwest trick or
whatever lava diagonal water I get
pushed in this corner here to take
damage but I don't think this is done
with you
[Music]
I'm really not evil guys I promise
yeah I don't think it's very reliable is
the problem but sometimes it seems like
they take five it's sometimes six
sometimes for this is just a little
stretch - I think I would need to make
it quite a bit longer like four times
longer at least to get them down to the
health I want
so I'm probably just going to use
gravity after all hey check out what
happens with spiders this is cool I'm
not evil I promise it's just funny
actually let's check this to make sure
one two three arrows si was four so it's
not going to work although zombies can
actually attack the skeleton I don't
know it I thought they just chased them
okay enough time wasting I'm going to
try gravity now okay so what I've done
now is I've set up a tall pillar and
I've found out that pulling up 22 blocks
is about as high as you want using
myself as um whatchamacallit a dummy I
found out that you don't want to go any
higher
this gets my hearts down to either half
a heart or one heart so gravity is a
little bit unreliable but it's pretty
good half a heart and switching to heart
or anything else makes no difference so
I think mobs are affected the same way I
think they have the same amount of
health so making them fall 22 blocks
should work pretty good I think okay
here we go again
gravity test 22 block drop there's an
air space over there so that they don't
drown on their way up looking good so
far oh oh
one of them died from falling but yeah
that works pretty close to what I want
it to we need the creepers to die with
one shot from the skeletons we want
these guys to die quickly from sunlight
one shot that's good hmm try place one
block below their feet creeper won't let
on me
[Music]
one shot still that's good
yes this is probably what I'm going to
use for weakening the mobs down to one
hit I think it's probably the best and
simplest method if you guys didn't think
of something better let me know but
remember it needs to be reliable if it's
not reliable I don't want to use it but
I'll probably an episode around here
since it's getting late here so next
time we'll work on getting the skeletons
to fight without killing each other
I guess dropping them 21 blocks is
probably a better way of doing a instead
of 22
yeah works good though so I'll see you
guys later
and thanks for watching I hope you liked
this episode and keep sending me your
messages just the don't be mad if I
don't respond okay bye bye