hello everyone Etha here again with
episode 9 of our let's play minecraft
adventures and before we can do anything
this episode i noticed i just passed
1000 subscribers on youtube a thousand I
am blown away over a thousand people
willingly choose to watch me do crazy
stupid stuff in this game and I think
that is just awesome
so thanks to everybody who's who is
subscribing and please continue watching
we'll have lots of fun together and to
celebrate the event I planted this tree
Tuukka moderate it and it's gonna be a
great tree but I think we need to need
to have some kind of party so I made a
shopping list of items we're gonna need
and I'm gonna go go collect those right
now so let's go get them alright we're
gonna need redstone yes we have redstone
I'll explain it a bit first we have to
party
we need a log and gunpowder sand and a
pressure plate an epic button regular
buttons won't do and we're gonna need
some wood
with the wood we're going to make four
doors
and we need a couple signs this is gonna
be a great party guys trust me and what
else what else every party needs a
bucket of lava and that's probably good
for down here I need some more gunpowder
of course he's a loser
[Music]
you need some gunpowder more gunpowder
we need some TNT obviously and we're
gonna need a few reeds and you're
probably wondering what the heck we're
gonna be doing all you'll see soon okay
we're back at our soon-to-be epic tree
celebrating this momentous event and
we're gonna start setting up the party
and hopefully this tree will grow soon
we are going to lift it all around it
oops make sure I don't do that again
need more space okay de Gaulle and I'll
do these under it's just like that and
then we're gonna dig out a little pea
hair like so that's probably good we are
going to place redstone here
they're just like that
and we are going to place our epic
button which will light up our redstone
and then we can cover this okay what
else do we need we need our Twix place
that under our tree and will please stir
it around a tree let's see what else
what else
I think that's that's pretty much all we
need okay so we got our lava and our
reeds using a glitch here we're gonna
place our reed right here so we need the
labid a flow one block and then we have
to quickly place the reed wait yeah
that's right since there's a drop there
the lava will float down instead of
going into the redstone here just like
that and then cover this up you leave
that uncovered so we can see okay let's
set this up
again thanks to everybody that's awesome
and since it's an epic button we need to
put one of these signs like so alright
that's pretty much set up we just need
to wait for that to grow and then then
we'll finish setting up an trees take so
sneaking along to grow when you're
waiting for them sun's almost setting so
we're going to try finish setting up
here and hopefully we can get our guest
of honor to arrive it might be a bit
challenging
that's all right much better
all right you guys all know what that is
gotta work fast here so much work to
planning a party
yeah this is a safety precaution Jay so
this is where the gist of honor is gonna
sit and I really wish sure you got a
better tree out of this button whatever
lame is tree ever so now that it's grown
we can remove its dirt block and that
allows free air around the all six sides
of this wick which allows it to catch on
fire much faster oh yeah how to do this
this is a lot easier with a better tree
stick some TNT in there
[Applause]
totally totally unnoticeable
all right let's try to get our gist of
honor
there he is
don't leg the leg come on in
come on oh don't do that come on this
party is for you
we're gonna try this again hopefully it
works this time I built some nice stairs
for you come on come on come on
[Music]
[Applause]
epic fail our guest of honor did not
want to join the party and I am NOT
setting this up again so we are just
gonna use cotton to rebuild our tree and
we're gonna have a party still and we'll
try build it exactly the same or as
close as possible running out cut
put a plus sign good enough cotton tree
all right you guys already 1,000
subscribers thanks to everybody seal
this up alright here we go
I don't know why but I love doing this I
probably did this to five trees already
and it usually takes about 40 seconds or
so if everything is set up right here
goes
party's over time to clean up so sorry
for that mess up but those things happen
I just wanted to give you guys an update
of what's been going on down here
been getting lots of resources so I
should be able to start building some
bigger things now I've got a fair bit of
redstone iron and getting lots of gold
we got lava if we need it and I'll just
show you how much I got cleared out
quite a bit um while I was working down
here I kept hearing like skeletons and
stuff so I dug up and discovered a bunch
of cave systems I'll show you these next
episode and yeah so I kept finding like
these pools of water which I found
strange and then I remembered not
chatted that feature the maps now and
this is the first map I've generated
that has it so I thought it was pretty
cool and then I realized something
terrible these are placed randomly
throughout the map I found one that goes
down
past where the bedrock should be which
means I have been I was dealing that all
out way above the lava level which is
actually where this is where I actually
should have been digging and this is
where I've been doing all the redstone
up there I wasn't getting any redstone
or
any diamonds or anything so kind of kind
of made a mistake but I'll just join the
two layers and it'll work fine and this
is gonna be the main layer though this
is well cheap data this is where I'm
gonna keep digging and I did find some
diamonds first ones and I'll probably
start digging out some canals and yeah
so thanks for watching thanks for
subscribing and until next episode I'll
see you