all right guys let's get something
straight here this is not your Island
this is my Island and the only reason
you're living on it because I let you
live on it all right everybody welcome
episode 14 what I've done here is I've
these guys are really loud what I've
done is I shut the lights off downstairs
and built this casing around the
elevator and it does kind of work I
guess not exactly like I would like it
to for one thing I basically I went away
for 15 minutes when I came back it was
like this there's probably close to 100
100 guys in there
but as you can see there's no spiders
and this thing fills up very slowly and
it only fills up if you're standing next
to it so
and if I walk away from it like 25
blocks for more than 30 seconds they're
going to start disappearing facility
spawn so those are the flaws with it
still but it does work so I think I'm
going to keep it
I actually wanted to try
hook a door up here see what happens
so die try put a door right here put
door there looks like they're having fun
in here okay you guys are not allowed to
destroy this quick
that's over the shoes
okay should I open it no I don't think
so
all I want to see is if they'll walk
through the store yes they do okay so
yeah I'm going to redo this and
change it around a bit okay this might
be the worst idea I've ever had but I
just I just can't help but I have to do
it
I can't resist
uh yeah I might be ready yeah that was
pretty cool I want that stuff though I
should write another one I'll be right
back
fire in the hole
don't tell me don't tell me don't doing
don't do it came to say hi whoa yeah saw
that coming
oh there's another one
I just want my stuff bad
ah he wasn't even flashing ah
stop blowing up all right temporarily
shut down for now okay
I said I was going to work on the
storage room this episode it's going to
be a pretty big storage room I think
it's going to be this big area I'm going
to have to level this all out and a big
square around type thing and I'm going
to show you what I'm going to do with
the dispensers hopefully I have enough
fat spider-strength so I'm going to get
some supplies
okay this is pretty freaky this is the
first time I've been down here when it's
all dark like this yeah it's got
problems anyway I got some bows made
we're gonna make some dispensers I only
had enough string four or seven oh but
that should be good enough to show you
what I want to do they look pretty fast
yes so if you don't know how to make a
dispenser yet you need do that bow and
redstone
and I'm going to be using dispensers for
instead of using chests in my storage
room just just to try something
different I'm going to show you how I
plan on setting it up don't have a lot
of working in here so I'm going to have
eight dispensers and yes I know I only
have seven but just pretend I have eight
something like that and pretend this
block in the corner is a dispenser too
so if if the dispensers have a
cobblestone in I'll have a cobblestone
block in the middle and they'll be eight
dispensers around then I plan on setting
up a pressure plate probably a stone one
in front of the dispenser is probably
like here and then I'm going to wire
underneath like so for things that don't
stack like meet Matt I'll just be using
one dispenser instead of a single bait
specially J and that is going to connect
I haven't figured this out exactly yet
so over here we need a redstone dust I
think here a block there another dust on
top like that and then we're going to
put in and heat
output here and light the dust on top -
okay pressure plate is going to light up
one of these and we'll just do this
rough for right now
and then the other one is going to be
controlled by a five o'clock this is
just an example I'm going to destroy
this once we're done
so five torches make a five o'clock no
that's not going to work like that yeah
all right and then this goes back okay
so we have a stable 5 o'clock here
that's running through the and eat and
we have the pressure plate hooked up to
the and heats so an and 8 soaked up
through the eight dispensers so what's
going to happen is we're going to put
some cobble in here
the reason we're using 8 of them is
because it divides into 64 so say we
wanted to get cobblestone we just walk
up to our pressure plate and it would
not work why is it not working wires too
long
all right
yeah we're going to just put up a
repeater here that's why we're going to
use it stone pressure plate if you want
cobble you just walk up oh it's burning
out anyway you get the idea I'll I'll
fix it all up and so eight of these
things holds a roughly a time and a half
I'll put a double chest hold so it's
going to be a bit bigger but it'll be
convenient because if you want something
we'll just walk up and they'll do it to
you
get crazy the particle accelerator
oh my things like like crazy now okay I
figure I'm gonna need about probably 20
of these dispenser panels and storage
room and and like I said the storage
room is going to be round over here and
it's going to be big so I'll probably
build most of it off camera because it's
going to take a while and I'll probably
hook up a grinder or something to that
for now so that these guys don't go
waste but we're going to end it here now
and thanks for watching
oh yeah and it's all glass now just to
see if it works
come on
yeah and you know I do not recommend
using glass because it lets light in and
it's it doesn't work so unless I'm
setting this up from somehow Flast is
not okay see you guys next time