hello hello yeah yeah yeah yeah our
island has a name now the Dane master
800 has named our island it is called
chocolate Island due to all the soil
looks like chocolate so I like that name
so we're going to officially name our
Island and I'm going to place a sign
somewhere where it'll probably never be
removed here's good welcome to chocolate
Island dope is I'll correct Island
population 1
aha I need more room
sadface there Oh oops
this is officially chocolate island now
anyway we're going to start building I
suppose
I'm gonna shut mobs off just so that you
don't have all the noise J we're going
to need redstone and don't need
repeaters any torches and if you'll
notice I got rid of all the lava finally
so no more random fires just have
torches here all the way around not
quite as bright but it's a lot safer and
I think um
darn it any cobblestone
I guess that's one way to get
cobblestone we're going to be replacing
with this this with wood anyway I think
oh what the I don't remember this is
from oh this is a got the timer down
there
I must get stuck into the hole up and
key a and replace this with wood and got
some stairs on me still
the cows are really annoying really
annoying okay just want to get rid of
all my stairs so what were you doing
here is we're hooking these two levers
up we're going to run a vertical wire
for both of them up there and I'm
thinking to make the wire go one more
block I guess I don't need cobblestone I
can use wooden planks and same for the
side works
that one works good so we need to run
wire all the way to the ceiling place
blocks right on top of torches if you
aim on top of the torch oh I don't you
can't it's one done do it for the side
too and these wires are going to control
one of them is going to control whether
a hostile mobs loot falls onto our
wooden pads over there and the other
ones going to control if your friendly
mob loot falls down these pipes here I
got like this big plan I'm like to be
doing here
and be very complicated okay
now I can't get through that's not cool
alright this is like take number two for
attempt number two because I kind of
messed up building this um it works
boats like that items can fall down the
pipe and stream and when the boats like
this that you're not but the problem I
ran into is I built it too close to our
mop evader here so I have to move it
over a little bit oh don't fall down the
hole actually know what let's find that
cow because he's driving me crazy
oh hello Wow I keep shooting myself okay
let's try this again
the wire is I had it open there I have a
feeling I'm going to mess this up again
place a torch there
block we want until the doors over here
this time instead of over here so I
think it works if you just branch
torches like that I hope I just will
have to do it like that and play some
cobblestone okay and when we place the
door we want the hole in the top right
corner from the direction replace it
just like that
this is actually kind of high ah
alright I'm going to fix it one second
and this is take number three okay so
this is a good example of the do's and
don'ts in building I built the wire
first building the wires the easy parts
and because of that my door was out of
position so since building the minecart
gates and getting it the position right
is the hard part I should have done that
first and now I have that's exactly
where I want the door to be and so I
need to run a wire to it now and it's
easy to change the path of wire takes
but it's not easy to change where the my
card where the minecart deke goes so
going to I still want it the wire away
from this glass so because I might place
wood up so you can't see the wire just
to make it look better I'm gonna have it
spaced one away from the glass at least
and we're going to build the wire from
the top down which is kind of weird but
it works better this light well worked
out pretty good and then we run the wire
to it we can walk through here that's
good and we should be able to control it
with this lever now yep perfect
all right let's get back up there finish
building the sheets and just place
cobblestoned around here and then
let's see here
more there and then we'll place class so
that we can keep an eye on the boat
there much better okay so we place a
sign over top of the hole and we need
lock open
there actually we do that later first we
place the boat can't place it inside you
got to place it and then push it in okay
and actually know what I'm just going to
cover it with with glass
I forget which way to place the water
maybe it doesn't matter no it matters
the other weight is right there let's go
test it out we're going to pretend that
a bunch of creepers drop their gunpowder
pull right now we have it set so that
their drops don't fall down here now
we're going to flip the lever and really
come awesome they're eight that worked
out pretty good this one's going to be a
little bit different
one second
okay so I moved our second wire over so
it matches the same as our first one
same pattern
I had to run a wire over the feather
dispenser unfortunately so every time
you flip this a feather is going to
shoot out - not a big deal that was
doing that before anyway okay so this
one goes up to level two the hostile
mobs this one's going to control a
minecart eight on level three for the
farm ops let's finish this one up first
cover this up so nothing can interfere
with the boat the boats actually pretty
stable okay so now we just need to run
now water streams with our items to this
hole here and let's find the wire from
our second one right over there good
yeah so this thing's definitely in the
way um so we're not going to do that day
I do want to set up the slider separator
thing that should be pretty easy I think
I hope I make this go up one more I
think and we're going to place some
signs in there really wish signs are
stackable now use them a lot and
everything yes good ah
do the same for the other side fill that
up with water so we definitely want to
separate spiders here no matter what
options we have in our system that's one
thing we're going to be doing for sure
so we're going to make a hole here that
they can fit through
and let's see those are covering in
front so that water doesn't spill out
place a stream of water here I guess and
it doesn't go quite far enough what's
the trick for that in place another one
I think place one there and remove it
yeah good enough okay so the tall mobs
won't be able to fit through there
but the spiders will stream goes to this
block here so we're going to make a
little opening for the tall mobs to fit
through and at the same time the spiders
won't be able to swim up any higher
because they'll hit their head on this
glass block here and here
pretty simple place another sign and
water okay I think that's all we need
all right I'm going to run a test all
right here they come first ones haven't
seen it yet pushed over good up and
they're ready to kill me already
fighters hey I should have thought that
test up their algorithm spiders
this is incredibly babies what do you
reckon oh you blew up right here no
biggie oh all right well I'm going to be
modifying this a bit but that's it for
today for that we're going to do one
more test yet all right one last quick
test here I caught myself a sheep I one
of the features of the level 3 is we're
going to have a system this year the
wool off sheep automatically and I want
to see if this works
placing arrows and the dispenser
shooting the Sheep with it I kinda don't
think it does but I've heard conflicting
things so we're drying it out here just
to make sure
no okay that kind of sucks but I have
another method I'm going to be using
instead and it'll work too but we're
going to wrap it up here thanks for
watching I'll see you next time