alright guys so today I kind of wanted
to start working on that trivia game
idea we had and I think I found a
location for it that'll work out pretty
good
so our first base is over there so we're
close to that I wanted to pick a
location that would be easy for you to
find because this is mostly intended for
you guys something fun for you to do if
you download my world and this is the
spot I found it's just off the ocean
here to the right you'll be able to see
it if you're going by pretty easy and
we're close to zero zero so pretty sure
you'll be able to find it yeah it's
gonna build it over here I think it's
far enough away from our first base
there that shouldn't be any leg issues
with redstone and that I hope I hope you
never know and yeah it's gonna build it
here I'm thinking kind of having a log
cabin style thing and maybe it dock for
the ocean boat dock that type of stuff
but I'll worry about the redstone stuff
first and then we'll put a building
around it after and this is a spot I
thinking I'll have our question board in
front of us I'll have to remove a lot of
this soil here but it's not it it's not
gonna be too bad the main reason I want
to build it here is because we've got
this hillside in the back and I don't
know how much space I'll need for the
redstone wiring and all that so if I
need more I can just build it into the
hill and it will be nicely hidden out of
sight so should be good should be good I
hope so I'll start working on it and I
will see you shortly
I got a bit of the hillside clear away
now just enough to allow us to get
started here we'll probably have to
clear more eventually but I just wanted
they be able to put down our panel here
this is the quest
and panel so on the first row here will
have a glowstone indicator light to show
us which question we are on could be 11
questions total then this first set of
signs all the way long is the questions
all 11 questions below that is the ABCD
possible choices possible answers to the
questions and then finally finally we
have something that was highly requested
or suggested I should say it's our spore
board it's not set up now of course
nothing's behind here yet but I did find
a way so that when you start the game
all these lights will be off all these
redstone torches and if you get a
question wrong they'll stay off but if
you get a question right they'll come on
so if you a question one right two wrong
three right
it'll be on off on and the rest will be
off until you go through them so
normally to do that I'll be like
normally to do that you would need a
bunch of T flip-flops and it would be
very difficult to get them that close
together like all these indicator lights
together like this but I found a pretty
good way of doing it with using pistons
and I will show you that shortly the
very first thing I'm going to do is this
scoreboard here the second thing I'll
probably do is a glowstone thing above
there I haven't decided yet if I'm gonna
do another scoreboard like one that
keeps track of your losses and wins
vertically maybe but I haven't found a
good way of doing that yet and that's
the progress so far and of course I did
use sandstone again for the border here
I think it looks good dark wood in the
back
I kind of suggested either dark wood
black wool or glowstone for the back and
most people seem to prefer dark wood and
definitely don't use glow stone black
was a possibility but more people said
dark wood so that's what I used and I
think the sandstone looks good with it
but I'm no expert and the dark wood
should match the rest of the building
we're gonna make here since I'm thinking
log cabin should work out pretty good
so I'm going to start working on this
poor display and I will see you shortly
so I had the score display about half
done now I wanted to show it to you guys
before I finished it up so that you
could see how it works easily right now
you will see these torches are all off
by default now and this here is my
memory unit system I built pretty happy
with how this works
we got Pistons underneath all these wood
blocks they're facing up sticky pistons
just have these buttons here temporarily
so normally these blocks go up and then
down and they retract but if this is
powered this wire here it sends power to
all these repeaters and so when you hit
a button the block goes up but it stays
up it doesn't retract back that's
because this for Peter sending power to
the wood block which then sends power
down into the piston so it's being
powered so it won't retract and it also
sends power to the left here too this
repeater sends power to this block to
this torch up into this wood block and
on the other side is our score display
indicator lights which is now on so
that's pretty cool do that now we have
five blocks up and so those effectively
act as RS nor latch --is but they're
very you're able to build them very
compact together they're pretty simple
quick the build which is nice and then
when you're ready to reset them all I
have this master wire here if you
unpowered these repeaters this block
becomes unpowered and the Pistons are
able to retract so you would do that by
sending a pulse into this wire here like
that and that's how that works it's
pretty cool I'm gonna finish it up now
I'll see you again in a little bit okay
guys we are back Lots has changed since
he last saw this and it's actually been
over a week for me since I last worked
on this since that last video clip you
saw my memories getting a little bit
hazy on how this all works but I'll do
my best to explain it let's go let's go
behind the yeah there's a bin
you things added here first of all we
got our thing here which keeps track of
a question we're on so this thing is one
two three four or five six seven eight
nine ten eleven blocks wide and we have
eleven questions so each one of these
blocks represents our question and the
wood block indicates what question we
are on so one two three four five six we
are on the sixth question right now if
we hit this if we if we got the question
right we would send a pulse to this wire
here I'll just press a button to make it
and you can see one two three four five
six our sixth question is correct now
and then it would move ahead to the next
question so we hit this one more time
you can see this is on the seventh one
now one two three four five six seven so
it moved ahead what this is doing
there's Pistons moving it to the right
then this one moves it down there's
another piston here moving it to the
left and below here is an exact copy of
this row above so we have ten glass
blocks and one wood block
so there's 22 blocks total and two wood
blocks in that so it's just just a copy
and yeah we have our thing above here
power goes here just like below we have
a thing that keeps track of what
question we're on this is just for
visual purposes this one up here I'll be
replacing the wood with glowstone when
this is done but it just tells us we are
on the seventh question because that's
where this soon-to-be closed stone block
is above all right
and so if we send a pulse to Swire this
is of the only blocks that power will
get sent through to our piston on the
other side which causes it to go up and
since this is being powered it stays up
and it causes power to go through to the
other side to our indicator light so
that's how that works and then when we
get to the end of all this when we
finish our last question here I will
have to send a pulse to this thing which
will clear it all and it will start
fresh again
so watts to it I believe the thing I was
having trouble with last when I was
working on this was this selector panel
and I never did figure out how he's
gonna do it
so this button here would be a B C D for
our ABCD answers to the question above
multiple choice I decide to have a gap
between a B and C D just to to make it
look more symmetrical because it's an
odd number of questions so need an odd
block in between the wiring though is
kind of from E to D so yeah I had a wire
below here any of these buttons you push
will light this wire up this is the
player made a choice wire and then we
need to separate each of the button
things as well so this button would go
left I think
it's that one as trying to trying to do
it without blocking the players view of
the board here which is very challenging
I could put a half slab over that no
problem then the problem is like it that
just doesn't doesn't look the best I
would have to put a full block here and
yes no I I can't it would cut the wire
and if I leave it open like that you can
see the wire from the side so I don't
know I'm not sure the best way of doing
these panels the selector panel would
you shut up thank you lamb chops
I wonder if notches adding lamb chops to
the game in 1.8 he's adding a whole
bunch of different kinds of meats like
chicken and that steak so maybe could go
for some lamb chops
yeah so I would have to have a block in
front here be covered I'd probably run
this wire
through here and make it go down there
somehow so to be fairly nicely covered
and I would probably just have this like
that yeah I don't know kind of like that
I'm thinking and then just have the
crack open here you won't be looking at
the crack if you're on the side and you
can still see the board pretty easy yeah
I think I got it now
I think this is how I want to do it I
think it looks good I got to be careful
not to abuse sandstone too much people
chew me out for that so this is probably
all the sandstone I will have in this
building that we're making what you see
here and I'll probably do the rest out
of wood and stuff it just looks so good
I can't resist
yeah well the wires come out the back
like this there's a 1 yep 1 wide gap
between them which is nice so this
button lights up that wire and then this
button lights up this wire so I need to
keep them separate and I'll probably
spiral them down into the ground run
them underground underneath all this
stuff we have here it'll have to be
fairly deep and then further to the
right here we'll have that I don't know
if you remember that memory punch card
unit loop thing I had in my previous
video I got to build that and the
win-lose logic all that stuff over there
somewhere and this covers up relatively
nicely you know something like that
looks okay I think could even put one
more in here yeah
that's what you would see on the bat if
I did it this way which I I feel it's
acceptable otherwise I'd have to build
up higher and it would block your view
of this panel and that would suck okay
and I'll probably have like wood planks
and stuff around the sandstone but I'll
do that later much brighter well guys
I'm about to go to bed here it's getting
late so I'll probably wrap this episode
soon wrap this episode up soon one thing
I want to say those a big thank you to
everybody that has contributed to this
project a lot of you have sent me your
ideas and I will be using some of these
so it's much appreciated especially I
want to thank everybody that sent me the
note block sequences they are very handy
because I'm not very good with music in
that so I have lots to choose from it's
great and this wiring here turned out
really well it just spirals down it's
easy to keep separate like this still
separate here but at some point we need
to join it together which I'm doing over
here and these will connect to that
punch card memory thing I got to build
that like we originally planned you know
if you watch the I think his episode 95
where I did all this and I'm trying to
keep it 16 blocks away or more from the
player over here so that the player
won't hear the Pistons looping around
just to make it a little bit nicer
that's good I haven't run this wire yet
though so I'll just probably run it
beside these ones once I figure them out
yeah so I think that's where I'm gonna
end it because I'm I'm getting tired as
you can probably tell by my voice
although I always sound sleepy so it
should be cool when it's done and I will
say thank you for watching take care
have a good night's sleep if it's night
for you bye bye