hey everyone is down here working on
eats eats Road and I've discovered that
I really do not like mining very much
unless there's a chance of getting
redstone diamonds or gold otherwise it's
just boring so finish mining out the
rest of this I've just done my TNT chain
here they're spaced five blocks apart
from each other this is longest chain
I've done yet it's forty PNP total so I
thought you might like to see it and I'm
just gonna put a lever on it and so
instead of mining out this whole 3x3
wide by four high thing I just stepped
the mine out the one wide by two high
area so it goes much faster if you use
TNT
oh I must've made a mistake son
I think travels fast
another dead end so I guess it's not
perfect if it's five blocks apart like a
four block spacing and the TNT being the
fifth block failed again unreal
so and that's it that's done that was
about a hundred blocks in length didn't
take too long so now I just need to run
the road which takes a while and clean
up these little bits sticking out here's
a little progress update for you guys on
the East Road I just dug down these on
the left and the right here and I filled
it in with wood all the way down it's
really really far and now I have to put
all these apps labs here all the way
down over over a hundred blocks this
roads gonna be I think at least 200
blocks long or 0.2 kilometers and it's
just gonna be a straight road nothing
fancy
really with wild OB an elevator going
back up to the surface at the end there
I found this huge hole here which so I
might put glass over top it I don't know
and that's all there is to this I'll
probably change the sides make it look a
little bit more polished and it's
thinking about replacing the roof with
or the ceiling with sandstone and that's
my plan
mm-hmm well it seems I forgot to do a
few progress updates and now we're
really far into the construction of the
East Road where to begin well I did
replace the ceiling with sandstone and
there's torches little little lights
above it looks nice
and then on the left this is how I'm
planning on doing it I believe we have
flowers that are gonna go all the way
long same width on the right side and
they have little spotlights above to
make them stand out kind of and some of
my torches got destroyed and yeah
so lots and lots of work to this
obviously if you guys are planning to
make an eats Road you don't need to do
this much to build it really all you
need is a three wide by two high tunnel
minimum and you can make it bigger if
you want so mine's a six wide by four
high now with these little things on the
sides as well and I've replaced all the
blocks with wood and sandstone just to
have a nice polished look to it and yeah
it's going along pretty good
the way I'm doing this is that basically
I have to go all the way along the top
here movies all the way along then I
need to do it again one more block in go
all the way down the full 150 blocks or
whatever this lower part is and then
once I've done that I have to take that
out this as well and replace this with
soil fill in any gaps I find and then on
these I plant the flowers and I have the
flowers of reef four blocks and yes you
can see those are note blocks I'll get
to that in a second having a lot of fun
building this it's been a while since
I've worked on anything needs related
and so I just went along every four
blocks alternating flowers
obviously I'm not gonna show you the
entire construction of this because it
would it took too long I'm sure I've
spent at least three hours on this now
and I'm sure you guys know why I built
the green house now
I needed flowers and in between the
flowers I'm planting what do you call it
wheat that's what I'm planning on doing
I might replace it with saplings I don't
know I just wanted some green so we have
yellow green red blue you know I like to
have a mix of colors in my building
projects and then the other thing I do
is I just run anything a wood and place
a torch above each of the flowers like
this on the inside and Sam let's doubt
that wall and behind each of these
torches any place would because you can
see it from down there so lots of lots a
little detail to building this and then
I fill in you know like that so we have
been doing it it's going pretty quick
it's just there's so much to do that
it's taking a long time and the other
thing I've started to actually place in
a song that plays as you ride down and
really faster on the boat it's my first
attempt at doing anything really with no
blocks I don't know a whole lot about
music so it's probably not going to
sound
great but I'm trying and that's it for
eats for right now some of you might
wonder why I bother polishing it up so
much well I have thousands of people
watching my videos that want stuff to
look nice for them and you would be
surprised how many subscribers I get
just from people being impressed by my
storage room or anything that I spent a
lot of time polishing up so if I polish
this up and 50 videos from now if I get
a new viewer watching my video and he
sees this eats road he might just
subscribe because he likes how it looks
you know so if you guys have your own
channels don't just build something and
move on take your time make it look nice
and you'll find people will like your
building projects a lot more if you do I
think and that's it for right now
and I probably won't finish the eat
throughout this episode but maybe next
episode I don't know but another thing
I've been messing around with was trying
to figure out how you want to do the
exterior of the storage room this is
kind of just one thing I played around
with using sandstone and having a lining
at the bottom and around the doors I
want your opinion on this guys what do
you think I should do another is the
thing I was thinking of doing it was
maybe replacing it with the logs instead
just give me an idea what it would look
like
something like that I don't know having
a hard time deciding
another possibility might be to use this
dark wood Oh major like except it's
gonna be a lot harder to come across if
I do use it that's all I have of it let
me know what you guys think of that one
I was thinking about using green wool so
it would match with kind of that style
there but now after seeing it I don't
think I want to do I don't want to use
green wool and of course on other
options just to use the standard
planking but it might be a little bit
plain I don't know maybe I'll leave it
up to you guys tell me which one you
like or if you have another idea
let me know because I'm having trouble
choosing excuse me
what style I'm gonna use for the
exterior which is one of the reasons why
I haven't done that yet
so I think I'm leaning towards sandstone
at the moment but I want to hear what
you guys think and maybe he'll give me
some other ideas I probably won't make
the whole wall completely flat like it
is if I do something like this I'll make
I'll put something on it to make it
stick out kind of because it looks
pretty plain just totally flat as well
but it's it's a bit of a dilemma for me
Oh No
well I'm sorry guys but it's time I made
sure I was gonna do this when it wasn't
a subscriber special just so that you
would know I'm serious
I'm not joking around this time it's
gonna happen and you've been asked me to
do this for such a long time now and
it's become an inconvenience so this
might seem random but I'm finally
dealing with the situation I finally
made a reliable way to go up and down
the shaft
so let's look underneath the clay and
this is it I dubbed it the tornado and
this is actually very similar to
something I built a long time ago back
in my newbie days before I knew what
water elevators were it's just a giant
minecart spiral tower thing of course
when I built it originally back in my
starter world we didn't have these power
rails but with them it's so easy so you
can see the minecarts at the top here
fall down instantly we're at the bottom
and I've started to convert this room at
this something else try to make it look
nice and get backed up well we have our
netherworld here instant access insta
portal i plan on expanding down here
with additional project so that's why i
wanted a quick way up and down so this
is a quick way up often my Kurtz hit the
button and we go up the tornado if any
of you have motion sickness close your
eyes now i probably should have said
that before and we're at the top just
like that we can write it down using the
minecart as well but i prefer just
falling down the middle that's pretty
cool
and we're at the bottom yet so i lined
the whole outside with sandstone and
then just wood underneath the tracks
it's pretty simple how I did this is
just the three high clearance above each
of these tracks so you won't take any
damage and these power rails are being
powered by a lever I decided to use a
lever instead of redstone torches
just because leg is something that I'm
always concerned about and I think
levers probably laid your game last
because they don't emit any light and
they don't have the particle effects
that redstone torches have so I'm
guessing they're probably better for leg
and I don't like getting rid of redstone
so didn't need to use any for that and
so the minecart is up here if we take
the quick way down land on a pressure
plate which sends a signal all the way
to the top and it calls our minecart
down so you can see it coming
so it'll always be here waiting for us
to go up which is a nice feature and if
we step on it again I made sure to
separate the wires otherwise this will
just get sent back up if you pressed it
again so I'd like it's the tornado
finally have a reliable way of getting
down here and up here and I'm pretty
happy and these are just the tracks five
by five and in the center is the quick
way down and so we can only make it go
up two blocks every every side if it was
six by six we could go up three if it
was seven by seven go up four but we
need to have the corners flat and also
this one here for this to work for the
tracks to connect and yeah that's what's
underneath the clay now and I'll
probably do a bit more work around here
I think it's fitting because the clay
always reminded me of a giant storm
cloud so underneath it is a tornado
pretty cool and finally the last major
change I've made to my LP world is I
built this greenhouse thing for
harvesting flowers I'm sure most of you
have seen this already so I don't need
to go into detail about it you just
stand in the center place water
and it all flows toward you and washes
all the items to you which is pretty
cool I have been informed that there's
other green houses that use an exploit
for automatically harvesting the flowers
in a dark area which I didn't know about
I think in the last day I've seen at
least 10 new videos on that since I
released my greenhouse tutorial so
that's something to keep in mind but I
do like this design still obviously the
real jewel of it is the water flow
patterns I think oops by the way that's
it's a glitch in the game you can some
how place water unist where that there's
a ladder and then I don't think you can
place the ladder in it anymore
oh you can't okay never mind Wow very
strange aerial
so I'm thinking of making a mushroom
from somewhat similar to this as I
really like the water flow patterns and
the trick of using these signs so I just
have to modify this a little bit and I
think I can make a mushroom farm out of
it as well so that's gonna be one of my
future projects so another thing I plan
on doing soon is replacing the wood
underneath these signs with glowstone
since that patch came out it's now
feasible to do that since a drop more
glowstone and it takes less to craft
them craft event seat so yeah it's now
feasible to do that so I probably will
unfortunately I harvested most of the
easy glowstone so I'll either have to go
further and the nether to get more or
I'll have to go for the hard stuff and I
haven't done anything to barn it's okay
I'm gonna let them up just to see what
happens sometimes they chase the Sheep
around the top layer it looks funny
there they go I think they're starting
to you like cluster together like that
and they sometimes jump around a bunch
too anyway so I gotta get rid of this
and where you going buddy
you got to fix that yet one thing I just
thought about actually is I think
something else broke over the weather so
I want to check it out
so let's go to the nether the real
nether
spend so little time in here lately yeah
the thing that I think is broken for
sure now is that a little minecart track
I had set up that had document II sevens
me switches well that was weird
it triggered you guys see that it moved
I shouldn't have done that
very strange
okay I don't know what the deal is with
that pretty sure they patched that it
doesn't work like it used to but
definitely it's nudging it very
interesting and I don't know if the 360
cannons working and I'm not gonna test
this episode because I haven't made it
back up in a long time and that is weird
and of course this thing is useless now
I don't think I've ever showed you guys
it actually but the way I was getting
down before as I placed a sign on a sign
here
this will kill me but I'm gonna try hop
out of the boat before I hit the ground
to see if that'll make me live but you
just before I was just placing this boat
on the sign here oops
okay well I did that wrong let's try it
again
yeah that was cool
no fall damage for me but anyway guys
that's the end of this episode last few
minutes weren't really planned so well
that's it for today thank you for
watching
yeah div yeah I'll talk to you later