hello hello hello this is ezel thank you
for joining me again everybody
I went spelunking again got tons of
stuff um I got about eight stacks of
redstone which is which was a major
score I also got a little bit of iron
some gold I think I got at 38 gold and
these are all filled with iron that I
have had sitting around for a long time
I finally smelted it and I found three
dungeons I believe and got two stacks of
mossy cobblestone and about a stack of
lupus and yeah good times good times
so I did have a specific thing I wanted
to work on this episode but I've kind of
got sidetracked and started working on
the barn Hey and I got rid of the roof
here and so before I get too far ahead
of myself
shut up guys I thought I would start
recording what I'm doing here so let it
when I have to show it to you after you
can actually be with me as I'm changing
it what I did this used to be solid wood
blocks and I've replaced these with half
slabs oh yeah my peaceful I play on
peaceful something guys I'm not gonna
lie and yeah they fall down three and a
half blocks they'll walk off on their
own at that that's the maximum distance
they will fall and they'll actually take
damage from that
what I was just working on is setting up
the trapdoor thing here - how does he
walk over that till the walls and I'll
have lava underneath or fire it's a real
pain trying to wire these four doors
though because I have four sets of
double doors right next to it but
somehow managed to do it by having
sneaking in this redstone torch here
opens and closes all four of them the
only downside is I have to have exposed
wires above here so I got to run a wire
to the back there and attach to that
block there so out here and I'll hook up
the kill switch to here I guess
shouldn't be too hard
you know a lot of people comment about
the way I say lava am I saying it wrong
or what because I sometimes hear people
say lava like la wva is that the right
way of saying it some people say larva
kind of British people and yeah I'm just
kind of curious about that I always
thought I said it proper but maybe I
don't actually after looking at this
again since my levers about over there
I'd rather have the wiring and closer to
this side instead of on the back side so
I think I can just place a redstone
torch here yeah and it doesn't interfere
with these doors I don't think
let's Merc that spots I'll have to run
mmm
although I will have to put wiring under
water that might be a little strange
oops alright it's okay so that's done
the other thing if I'm putting lava lava
larvae whatever underneath these doors I
can't have any wood around here so I'm
gonna have to replace that wood with
sandstone or something
cows are annoying me like crazy you have
no idea okay so the lever is a excuse me
over there two blocks in should be under
here then I think that's it so I need to
run
sure wish this wiring was in here just
gonna make this a lot harder run a
redstone there run back up turn it on
make sure that's the right spot yeah
it's on good okay I probably have to get
rid of this move this over one
and then start going down yeah don't you
guys just love redstone wiring something
like that look at all these animals this
is so annoying why did I built this
thing I built an annoying machine okay
it's dumb wire comes down keep going
yeah we're just gonna have to run it one
block over I like to try to always keep
my wiring as compact as I can but you
know sometimes it's just easier to make
it a little bit bigger and I'll need a
repeater somewhere in here right there
and you still have to make this go out
the other way didn't work it was
interfering with the double doors after
all so I had to go back to going around
the back so there's a redstone torch on
the other side of this block and that
should do it so I just need a repeater
in here and then we'll try it out yeah
there's actually a lot of wiring under
here get a repeater you hurt them shut
they're a little bit so I think it's
already Oh guys just so annoying
okay oh yeah I'm gonna replace the wood
here yet hey they're closed they're open
doors are still open yeah that works
let's see if they interfere all right
now they're closed and they're open and
the double doors are still closed so
that's exactly what we want may as well
put a light there
little indicator lights there so now we
can choose to kill them here if we want
so that's pretty cool oh yeah I need to
put the lavend right
probably just have
locks up the here and I think I can I
think I might be able to fill this in
actually yeah I think I can't so I can
put blocks here here
all the way around and then blocks up
and I don't think that will interfere in
any way and when you just fill that in
flava I could use fire and not have to
worry about it spreading to the wood
here but I hate that sound fire makes
with a passion it's ok once in a while
but when it's going all the time it's so
annoying and hopefully I never have to
rewire any of this because that would
suck ok so good it's gonna change the
wood and it should be good to go
such a pretty view this is like my Lunar
biome what I'm that's what I'm gonna
refer to that as seems I didn't have any
sandstone left so you know what that
means gotta get some more James really
lightning from all these items and that
should keep me sit for a while I'd say
again I don't know where all my
sandstone is going I think never use
this stuff
so you got plenty of sandstone again and
my sand supply is really good at the
moment although my gunpowder supply is
also really good at the moment so I'll
probably make a bunch of TNT soon again
and let's finish this thing up brown
sheep brown sheep yay get rid of this so
we gotta replace this wood with
sandstone and we even have trapdoors to
stand on as we do it which is pretty
cool oh I forgot good good sandstone
I love this block looks so good and our
trapdoors see how did I do that before
that that that's and that's their wiring
back good okay
is there any more wood nearby I think
the stuff here will be safe I really
don't want this to burn down everything
actually I don't want these guys pushing
me there so I better close the doors
yeah
I gotta make sure I don't come in here
when the doors are open though or I'm
gonna be very upset with myself sweets
okay and that'll even give us some light
at nights it's good all right
I brought some signs with me and then
mark these this is the wolf lock and
this will be the wolf
cue Larry yes and yeah
now wolves should be handled however we
want them to be you know a whole bunch
of wolves entering the barn right now so
we're gonna try it out one thing I think
I may need to add on to this is some
type of animal lock on the front door
because they tend to get out when I'm
enter or leave the barn so may have to
figure something out with that shouldn't
be too hard
wolves
I forgot they're gonna be trying to get
the sheep so they might not want to go
to the center one one one all right um
are there any dog lovers watching right
now you might want to turn away for a
second any cow lovers or sheep lovers no
okay good I wonder if they will go on
their own if the Sheep
well the Sheep would have to move around
I don't know what was that no that
steams too much fun
hmm yeah they sure like to go after the
sheep if it's open they will drop down
into it I'm pretty sure it's as if
they're in there already and you open it
and you might might take a little longer
for them to you know so the last thing I
need to do is get rid of I think I'm
gonna get rid of this marine since it's
not needed anymore
that goes all the way around and I need
to put some kind of sealing on here
and then of course we need the squid
aquarium here I have a general idea how
I'm gonna do it but not exactly yet and
there's huge ocean out in front of yours
so I'm thinking something with boats
might be on the barn as well some kind
of boat dispenser maybe so I can go into
the ocean or if I start like an
underwater project that might have a
tube that goes underwater here not fully
sure what I'm gonna do yet anyway I
think I got all the wiring done now too
so I can probably go ahead and put a
hurting on the middle there so you can't
see all that wiring and I'll probably
also maybe trim it all around like this
just to give it a little bit more shape
and then possibly put those legs on it
or something and that looks a little
strange looks even more strange I'll
figure something out
you guys may have seen the eats road
already the latest addition I cleaned up
this spot now so it was pretty tall in
here so I decided to just grow trees and
have them kind of go over was not easy
to do that's for sure took a long time
but it's kind of unique I got a ladder
on every one of the trees use tons and
tons and tons of bonemeal trying to grow
them in such a little area and so close
together and one other thing I no longer
have glass over top my thing there
where is my crafting bench who stole my
crafting bench so the easy loader is
over here you just pop a boat down in
the middle here this is covered so I
don't fall down it anymore I've done
that enough times this ladder here holds
them down
just like that and when they're like
this it's safe to walk over top and you
don't have to worry about then you ain't
nudged out a place or anything it's just
like walking on the ground so that's
kind of cool so let's go for ride hey
got a tower sound up there no and over
here I hooked up a dispenser as well you
guys may have seen this already if you
download them if you downloaded my world
I built this right after the last
episode and it's pretty much exact same
thing
okay so this ez loader here is different
than my regular style it's a different
water pattern I've showed you this
before this is uh what I did when I went
other ez loader broke I made this so the
water source goes here there's one two
three pressure plates here and you use
this style if if there's if the boats
sandwich down like this otherwise you
use the regular style and that's how
that works
okay so seeing a little bit more
polished up in here I have lots to
polish over here I may eventually just
rip out this whole minecart thing and do
something a lot simpler and practical
because I built that when we had the
booster glitch and now we have easier
ways of getting around Oh left the door
open
no no you guys are not allowed you're
not allowed in there you thought only
okay
I'll tell you what is when it's done and
over here I got tired of water washing
away my wires so I made a kind of
waterproof got like a trapdoor here go
down and you're in the wire room go back
up hit the button
jump you're done and yeah that's it for
the e throat for now and I think that's
the end of the episode covered a few
things so and it's getting long so thank
you for watching
and I'll see you again next time