hello again and welcome to episode 11 of
our minecraft adventures got some good
news and some bad news good news is the
mob the image is done the bad news is it
doesn't really work so it's kind of all
been for nothing
although it has taught me a lot and has
given me new ideas and I'm just gonna
show you oh not good it kind of works it
doesn't do what I don't want it to do oh
boy please don't die please don't die
there's somebody in this elevator
[Applause]
I'll come on get me through the flats
okay so it works like it does what it
was supposed to do the problem is I
found out that mobs
[Applause]
okay as I was saying I found a thread on
the forums that says mobs these spawn
after Kennedy spawn after 30 seconds and
that's the main issue so I took out on
two of the pads I took out the lights
there and you can see barely some mobs
spawned and they're jumping around back
there this is how I had the elevator
waters floating on its floating signs
here with one column in the middle and
it works but the problem is when I'm at
this surface by the time the mobs get to
the surface they'll already have this D
spawn because the time it gets takes to
get from that end all the way to here
and then up his way over 30 seconds so
it's not gonna work
and also the way I had the water
patterns here isn't very good the water
should flow smoothly around corners not
he stopped with pressure plates so I
never really explained what my goal was
with this thing unlike a normal mob
pitcher / grinder my goal wasn't just to
get the items from the guys what I
wanted to do was build like a cage over
here to capture them live and then if I
wanted to I could press a button and
kill them all and get their resources or
if I wanted to do something else like
put them in my carts and ship them out
somewheres I wanted to be able to do
that too
so if you want it just for the items you
should try to kill them as fast as
possible
instead of making them go up a big huge
elevator and all that kind of stuff
so I'm getting kind of led you here I
haven't given up on this idea I'm gonna
have to redo how I do it though I've
been experimenting in another world and
I found that few pop mobs and minecarts
it's they don't seem to D spawned in the
earliest quick-like I've had I've had
guys out for 10-15 minutes and mine
carts without them desponding and I was
outside of the 25 block radius or
whatever it is so I might do something
like that I'll have to think about it a
bit more before I try to
but enough of that for now we're gonna
do something else this episode because
I'm being tired of working on that mob
trap I think we're gonna let's see what
should we do
oh I know what we'll do
one sec okay so I got the items we need
for our quest here while I was digging
this out here this upper section I was
like cheering noises above so I dug up
straight up and I found these cave
systems and I've explored them all wait
it's been a while since I've been here
which way was it oh yeah
up here while exploring up here I found
a mob spawner and I left it untouched as
I wanted to conquer its while recording
if I can find it in is it over here nope
right here must've been down and we're
hopefully going to build another type of
mob trap
hmm I get lost so easy in this game it's
unreal okay I think it's around here I
think it's in here and this is the way I
found it it was covered in gravel so
this should be very easy hopefully
spooky music there might be some guys
here I think it's a zombie one not
entirely sure that was pretty easy
[Applause]
alright what did we get
redstone nice saddles good stuff and
alright gunpowder not bad not bad other
buckets you never have too many of those
steel the chests okay so I'm gonna mine
this stuff out and then we'll start
building a that killer machine for it
alright it's all cleaned up now and I
got torches around it so that
nothing will spawn over here while we're
working on it and that actually made it
smaller it was a seven by seven area in
here before
I've I'm gonna make it five by five and
the reason for that is so that because
we're gonna use this is going to be a
drowning trap and we're gonna use water
to siphon all the zombies to this point
here and this is actually the simplest
way of doing this I've come across it's
my own design but most of the designs
are pretty pretty similar
they'll either they'll either use lava
or fire or cactus or drowning and this
one uses water
okay so we got our walls around we're
gonna put a three high ceiling okay and
then for this front hearts I like to
have a two high ceiling so that they
can't jump around
so yeah this this is a good one to do
because you pretty much don't need
anything for it except water and a
pressure plate and we're gonna build out
a glass so that you guys can see it yep
and oh you know what I need more water
meet three buckets of water and guess
what we just got another budget
okay so when one zombie spawned the
waters gonna push it him here onto this
pressure plate and he's gonna stop he
won't move at all and then when a second
one spawns its gonna get pushed here and
it's gonna push the first zombie over
one square by force and we're gonna dig
down its reefs where's and let's see
here this is where the items are gonna
are going to come out okay so we're
gonna put up blocks here and since
there's blocks all around this this
empty space here we can place water
inside and it falls down
and that's pretty much all there is to
it so they're gonna fall into this hole
and then they're gonna get stuck and
drown and up to two can drown at once
which is all you need is the only spawn
so fast and when you get it all set up
just knock out the lights lock this up
and it's all done you fell in there
after a few seconds they'll start
drowning and you want to completely dark
in there and there's his feather super
simple and build this early up in the
game if you're exploring and you have no
items really you should be able to build
this still and this works with the
zombies and skeletons
I still haven't tried making something
for spiders
he's not moving right now then the other
guy pushes ahead and then he falls and
he doesn't try to swim up for some
reason so pretty cool
I like it let's hope you guys do too
let's go do something else now so the
other thing I wanted to do or try to do
before we end this is a expand on this
idea and make a make this into a wall so
I got a bunch of doors with me I have to
be pretty quick cuz here because we're a
SEPA so it's getting pretty long already
not that I have a limit but I still try
to keep it within 15 minutes okay
this always confuses me that one's right
that one's wrong so each each block is
only gonna use two doors to it place
this here wrong if I place on the right
side of the other door
oh wait it's confusing fast Jason should
be in this block yeah if you place on
the right side of the door place a bunch
of doors not going to make a huge wall
I love doors in this game okay so let's
piss on the right side so I should have
this here right I thought there a place
watch here good
so hopefully this next door is right too
okay so I should start the other end and
that the best time ever and we're gonna
hear this one I guess it's because I'm
too lazy to make more doors make sure
you do this in the right order I could
do that all day I'm gonna place blocks
over top and I think we're gonna place
watering and someone suggested I should
oh it's nighttime already I think you
got a place in every block because it's
floating water seems to behave
differently good
so someone goes in they'll get drowned
and I don't think they can just walk
next door this is the time yay
so one other thing I wanted to try I
brought some buttons with me and a lever
let's see what happens if you attach
them
that doesn't do much and I brought some
redstone so now alright that doesn't I
thought maybe they don't all close at
once but it's not linked it is unhard
just so you guys know even when I'm not
recording that keep it on hard I'm not
I'm not a wuss like that
that's not gonna work you there she want
them all to be late so you have to run
wires underneath the pads and probably
the same problem on Savi okay well
that's all I wanted to see I might try
figure something else out but that's it
for now thanks for watching