[Music]
hello everyone this is etho
we're at the lab right now i made a
little bit of a boo boo
with this thing here
this is the very end of the water stream
there's no sign holding the water in
place
get out of here chicken and so when i
flooded the pads the other day
above the water extended and it
flowed into my lava i had there and
turned it into obsidian so
i'm gonna fix that really quick here
much better
there we go so i had a pretty good day
today
i got a shout out from captain sparkles
that was pretty cool
i don't know if you guys know this but
uh
like doc am co-star and captain sparkles
are about my favorite commentators for
minecraft so
now all three of them have given me
mention in at least one of their videos
so that's kind of
uh that makes me very happy
so that's cool welcome everybody who's
visiting me
from jordan's channel and also i want to
give a especially a big thanks to
everybody who
left comments like etho is awesome on
captain sparkles video there that was
cool
there was a lot of them i was impressed
thanks guys
so i did end up reverting back here got
rid of the spider
the spider thing i built the other day
because it wasn't working we have to do
something different
i at the moment i'm not really sure what
i'm doing i kinda don't think i'm gonna
be doing a spider only
spawning system my current thoughts
are just to have
like my standard water canals with the
spider option
i'll have the 6x6 pads
and i'll probably have like four of them
let's pretend these are 6x6
pads mobs will go to the center
with the water canals i'll probably have
lighting on the outside
and the spider option will pop out of
the floor those half slabs
and i may make it a spider only thing
but i don't really think it's worth it
to be honest
uh unless i make a really huge
spawning system it's just not going to
be able to keep
up because spiders
only spawn one quarter of the time so
not even one quarter of the time so
probably need a huge system
if i was to make it a spider only thing
because
like for tall mobs you have zombies
skeletons and creepers that's three
different types of mobs
so let's say that's so that's like 75
percent of the mobs and then spiders
are the other 25 and if it's only
spiders then
you're spawning is a lot lower than if
you have like the other three spawning
or all four of them together you know
so i kind of don't think it's worth it
but i want your guys's input should i
bother with it
um or do you have any other ideas
because
i would like to know from you i'm going
to take a break from it this episode
though
i'll wait for your feedback i
kind of want to do something fun today
something random
and i have an idea i will meet you
at a little uh work area somewhere flat
we can work
all right here we are one of my
preferred
working areas in my world because it's
nice and flat some of you might
recognize where we are
and i'll just quickly run through the
idea i had today
something fun i wanted to try make
a lot of people seem to like to download
my world
i constantly get requests for me to put
new versions of my world up for download
and every once in a while when i
release my world for download again
i'll put in a little something fun for
people
to make it a little more interesting for
everyone that downloads my world
and i kinda wanna add more interesting
things
in my world when people download it that
they can play around with and uh
that's what we're gonna be doing today i
had the idea that i would make like a
trivia
minigame thing and every time i put my
world up for download i'll
add new trivia questions and people can
play a mini game if they want
uh you'll get a better idea pretty quick
here
so every time i put my world up for
download i would pick a new theme
for the trivia questions so
let's say our theme is
seinfeld so i'd have a sign that says
seinfeld is our theme really i could
pick
any anything it could be questions about
minecraft it could be math questions
science questions you know movie
questions
anything anything i want anything you
guys want
okay so seinfeld's our theme then uh
there would be a list of questions so
let's say our first question
is um let's see which our first question
be
how many
episodes were
there okay
so let's say that's question number one
then i'm planning on making it a
multiple choice like
you'll have four options so then i'll
have another sign
then it'll be like a 100
b 120
c 150
d 180
okay and you'll have four buttons to
choose a b
c or d and if you
hit d the d button then you would be
correct you would get a point
and i'm thinking i'll have 11
questions in total every time i do a
trivia
so 11 questions you would need six
wins to win the match and i might make
special bonuses if you get like
all 11 right i don't know we'll see
uh yeah that's idea so we're here to
kind of figure out some of the
components some of the logic
there will be some redstone involved but
most of this will be pretty simple
by using pistons
so if you hate redstone don't worry we
will be using
pistons and block movement for a lot of
this
it's actually pretty simple and i'm
hoping
so uh let's begin here
so i just made a world back up so we're
free to play some
glass or glowstone if we choose without
feeling
guilty about destroying it after and
we're going to build our different
components figure them out each
individually and then when
we get it figured out pretty good we'll
build the
whole thing put everything together at
some other location we choose and
hopefully build a nice building for it
and that kind of thing
let's begin here our first most
important
thing will be
the memory unit so we can do this pretty
easy
using glass and
glass pistons and redstone
so let's pretend this is our multiple
choice let's say
whatever my question is the answer is c
this would
this glass block would be a this would
be b
this would be c and then this would be d
and we can take advantage
of a nice little trick
die
thank you nice little trick we can do
with the redstone
so here's something cool about redstone
if you try to send power through a glass
block
you can't but if you try to send power
through a solid block
a non-translucent block
like cobblestone you can
and so that's how i will be programming
everything just using glass blocks and
solid blocks
so um
what i'll do i'll have
repeaters at all these
um two of them will have to have
a double and then we'll have wire like
this
let's try to figure out our
our option switching thing here
or multiple choice chooser i should say
let's see so if we were to have
buttons i kind of want them set out like
this i think
if we were to press this one
and this is how we'll know if we get the
right answer if the one we choose
sends power to this wire here then we
got the correct answer
but we need to be careful not to cause
our wires to interfere
it's the main challenge
let's see what's a better way of doing
this
we'll make these ones go up a level
then we'll cut the wires with the block
i suppose and then we'll have our panel
and these wires will come out further
so now they all should work i think
so the correct answer would be c in this
case and you can see it lights up the
wire on the other side
and it's the only one that does so that
is how we can do it
so that's one thing figured out we can
make a our chooser like that
i guess selector was the word i was
looking for not chooser
so this is our option selector panel
here
i've added a few things here i'll show
you
uh first of all i was playing around
with the wiring
how i'll do it because i have some
pistons here that'll be
operating and i don't want to hear them
operating when i'm you know making my
choices
so i need our panel here to be at least
16 blocks away from these pistons so
that they won't make any noise
so we'll run our wire 16 blocks and i'm
just
i was just trying to find a way to
neatly uh
separate our four individual wires here
and then rejoin them
over here and this is what i came up
with i got wire
then a torch for
one side and then repeater and regular
wire
and when you cover up
these wires it cuts the wires and they
stay separate so you notice all these
went off now they're all
they're all separate so
that's how i plan on running them a long
distance without them interfering
the other thing i realized though is i
need another wire here because
right now all we can detect is if we get
the right answer
but we need some way of detecting if we
got the wrong answer as well
so we'll have another wire underneath
our panel
hidden and that will tell us if we've
made a choice so it could be the right
choice could be the wrong choice but we
need to know
if the player has pushed a button
so that's how we'll figure that out and
then we'll have
this wire here tells us if they made the
right choice
and we'll have to do something fancy
with an and gate
and we'll get to that later this is what
else i've been working on
this is uh my programmable
memory array i guess
glass blocks are the wrong answer
cobblestone is the right answer we got
four sets of four pistons controlling
everything
and this is a five
by uh well five
five one block in between one of them
has to be
an air space so in total we have 11
rows here for our planned 11
questions so it worked out perfect and
in the
between all this is our our
you got the question right wire here so
we can sneak that in
in the middle there which is cool and
these
four pistons we'll just have a wire over
top
and we'll need to connect them all
together so the way
this will work we'll need to uh
so we have the air space here so we
would have to activate this
one
then this one would go up and this one
go right
and then this one would go down
and by doing those four switches we will
iterate through
one of the questions so we'll make our
choice
for the question we either get it right
or wrong
we'll figure that out later but then
we need our next question so that's what
this takes care of it switches to our
next question
and when it gets the airspace that means
you're done
type thing so that's what i got figured
out so
far
this is why we're planning it before we
actually build it guys because i
found out a mistake i made here uh first
of all i have this wired now this button
goes
first of all to these lower ones
then there is a two torch delay here
goes to this
set of pistons
the wire runs up the back up the stairs
there
spiral staircase and it
activates uh its top right set
and then another two
torch delay here goes to this set here
so it does a full loop
uh but what i realized now is that i
actually need
three air spaces and one of them solid
in the corners so we don't have 11
spots here
we only have one
no one two three four five six
seven eight nine it's only nine
questions
of info it's only information for nine
questions there
so that won't work we either need to
expand it or cut down our questions
but this is what it does
apparently nothing
why isn't that one firing i'm not giving
enough time i guess
because the pistons are still extended
when those ones activate
so let's try setting them to
four
and that should do the trick i think i
hope
maybe three is what we need
there we go
this is a pretty common way of people
doing memory now
if you saw that grand piano video that's
that's how they did it it's cool because
in the past you didn't
have to set up these huge giant
redstone tower things just to hold
a few bits of information and now as
pistons we can
store one bit of information in each
block
so it's much much more compact
and a bit if you don't know it's like
a yes or a no or on or off it's
two states we can store
so yeah it's iterating through them
so how would i have to adjust this if i
wanted 11 i would need
i guess i would just need to make this
two wide instead of one wide
because that would add one extra block
there and one extra
block down there so in the final version
that's what i'll do i'll make
it five by two well five
how would it be five by four
would be the dimension of the spiraling
thing
yeah yeah i'm right i'm right here
okay this thing
here is another important
problem address is another important
problem
uh we need a cheat prevention thing
because uh
we don't want a player pressing two
buttons or all four buttons and
always getting the right answers so
that's what this is
what we'll do is we'll have our
wire here the one that says player push
to button
it'll go to an rs nor latch which again
just holds a memory state of
yes or no and
it'll switch rs nor latch and it'll
cause these pistons
to retract like that
so you'll push your button
power will go through this block here
through this cobblestone
to this wire to your choice whatever
and as that's going on this wire will
also be sending a signal at the same
time
and it'll be timed so that as soon as
your
one signal goes through here it'll
switch rs nor latch which acts much like
this lever here
and it'll cause these to go up and now
if you try to send a signal
again like if you try to press two
buttons
the blocks not there the power can't go
through so you can't make a second
choice
and then when the final
when all the processing is done for the
button pressing at the end
it will reset the rs latch and this will
come down
ready for our next question
type thing but i can see i'm having a
little bit of a problem here
these repeater i'm suffering the
repeater bug here it looks like
possibly no
no it's because there's a torch here so
i'll have to make a few adjustments yet
to fix that
this is an example of an rs nor latch
just in case you're wondering
again it keeps a yes or no state on or
off
that type of thing uh i added
i added these buttons on so we can
switch the state
so press that you see the power goes
there if i press this one
it goes over here if i press this one
several times
it still stays over here and same with
this one
so let's stick up a door just to help
you visualize
how this works
our door doesn't want to cooperate there
we go
so this is the yes the door is open
state
when the power is over there
and when we hit this one it's the no the
door is not
open state so
that's what that does a lot of people
don't understand how this difference
how this is different from uh lever
stumbling with my words now i'll
demonstrate this to you very simply
oops two wires there we go
yes the door is open state no the door
is not open state
this is how it differs there's no way of
switching this lever
using redstone if i send power to it
it's still in that state there's no way
of
changing it that's the only difference
that's why we use these
when instead of levers at certain times
okay pretty simple
so i just figured out a very important
part of our trivia minigame
the logic yes the logic the thing that
determines if we
won or lost a question
so here we have the you just correctly
wire now that alone you could use
like if you only needed to know if you
won then
this wire would suffice but i want to
know if we
won or lost
and so we need to do some logic figuring
here
because if we lost that will just stay
off it won't switch
we don't know anything from it but this
one
always comes on it could mean you won or
you lost you don't know so that's where
i set up this example here to
demonstrate how to do the logic behind
it
what we need to do is uh get those two
wires in sync
so that they have the exact same delay
when they reach a certain point here
which is uh demonstrated by this button
here when i press it
the two wires come on at the exact same
time they're both changed at the same
time
on the right represents the correct
button
was pressed wire so that one over here
on the left is the any button was
pressed wire
that button was pressed wire so that's
this one here
so if they're in sync we got two and
gates here
this is the one that represents that you
won
and this is the one that shows that you
lost right now they're both off like
they should be
so if we press this button
it says we won this flight didn't come
on only that one did
so how did that happen
the button was pressed wire came on that
one always comes on
and the correct button was pressed wire
came on so this one only comes on
if you guessed correctly so that makes
sense
we won but now
if we were to lose how would we figure
that out
well i just put an inverter there
so that when the button is pressed that
wires off
the correct button was pressed wires off
and we have an inverted and gate here
and so what happens
the you lost came on and
the one e1 stays off so it knows
it knows what happened he knows the
truth
and if we have these two separate
we can cause different things to happen
depending on whether we win
or lost so if we won you would probably
get a score
point added somehow you might have nope
a note block sequence play a jolly tune
or something
or if you lose you might have a note
plots a note blocks
a note block sequence a sad tune
like
you know you have
you can get input from
whatever condition happened is what
happens
is what happened it's getting late here
i gotta stop talking
i gotta finish this episode
ah okay so we have a lot of this figured
out now there's a few
minor things to figure out yet
all right this is our question list
with our possible answers below each
question
question one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven
with the the possible answers directly
below the question asked
i didn't write up any examples for them
all that would
take a while and i was thinking of
having the
selector panel here so you would have
your choice
and you should be able to read all those
from here
it's probably a little bit blurry on
youtube but in the game
you can clearly read them pretty good at
this distance
tell me what you guys think is this a
good height for it is that a good
distance back for it
uh what should i use for the back
coloring should i use black wool
or should i use glowstone
let me know i want your input on this
since it's for you
and yeah that's another thing
as we're going through the questions
here there's no way
you can possibly expect the player to
remember what question they're on
so i will have an indicator above
i think of using glowstone
so if you're on question one there'll be
a glowstone block above that sign
and as you press a button it would move
over one to the right
to question two and that's how you would
keep track
maybe i'll set up some pistons to see if
we can get that working
here's a visualization to help you
understand what i meant
so there's the glowstone block above
question six
you would not be able to see anything to
the left of
here or above here
like you wouldn't be able to see the
second glowstone block
or anything right of here so it would
all be covered up nicely
neatly and i don't plan on using soil i
just
that's all i had on me i would probably
use something that matches
whatever we choose for the back there
just so it doesn't stand out
and the glowstone does that's the piston
loop going counterclockwise
let's see it going
that's how it goes
so every time you
answer a question you'll go through all
that
stuff over there and then it will also
send power to our our switcher here
and that'll tell us that we're on the
next question so
that memory unit will move forward to
the next question this thing will
show that we move to the next question
it'll all be in synced
uh so let me know what you think of that
there was one problem with this so i
have an
odd number of blocks in the loop there's
no way of avoiding that i think and
that's going to
cause a problem because
in one of these cases the glowstone's 11
blocks ahead and the other one
it's only 10 blocks ahead i think so or
12 blocks ahead
i don't know it's off though and it's
going to be a problem
so i need to find a fix for that
and finally the last thing we are going
to consider today is the score display
this is what i was thinking using
redstone torches
let me know what you think of this this
is how it works
got to all these
powered
and then we're using the same glass and
solid block trick
and these cycle around using pistons
so let's see it work
you got one point two points
every time you send power to this thing
you get a point
the problem is uh we will be hearing
some of this piston noise
i don't think it's avoidable like
especially if we do this
because that's not far away from us at
all
so there will be some piston noise
problem with this thing too is we need
to reset it
so now it starts going in reverse until
it
makes it all the way around and it
starts over
but yeah that's the ideas
should be a fun build
let me know what you guys think i
welcome any feedback you have
this is where it resets
and yeah if you have ideas if you have
anything like that just let me know send
me video responses
uh i would really like help with any
noteblock stuff i would like to have a
a win lose and final victory tune
or final losing tune would be cool
something under 20
note blocks under 20 notes would be cool
or 10 under 10.
yeah let me know what you want me to do
next episode if you have any opinions
i'm always open for
suggestions you want another odd episode
like this or do you want me working on
the hostile
mob system again let me know
i find all this stuff fun though so i'm
up for anything
and yeah that's it for me
take care bye bye hope you enjoyed this