[Music]
dangit spaz you've gone too far this
time too far my friend and now it wasn't
fast I wish it was hey it was my own
fault and I left the island because I
noticed there was a huge grass outbreak
so I went to clear it when I came back
this is what I saw burnt down my new
tree farm burnt everything down
and this was the cause
stupid lava I placed a wood block near
it I think it was I think about two
blocks away and I wasn't sure you know
if it's going to catch fire I watched it
for a while it was fine it's fine
15 minutes later it was fine thirty
minutes it was fine an hour later it was
fine I left the island I came back and
everything was gone so took forever but
it did eventually burn and that's what
started the fire I'm pretty sure
it wasn't the flaming minecarts because
they don't spread fire but lucky me I
just recently made a backup for episode
50 so I only lost about an hour or two
of effort
no biggie hey guys this is etho thanks
for joining me again and I've got two
large additions to the house now if you
didn't see the cactus tutorial I've
built a cactus farm and the tree farm
now and I was going to build them in LP
but I figured a lot of people would want
that tutorial for it so I just went
ahead and built it in the tutorial so
you can watch me building if you want
there and get some details on how it
works and if you don't want it you don't
want to do that I'll give you a quick
overview of them now so to our right
here is the tree farm I got three paths
here and by the way I really like this
tree farm I think it's very cool so we
got water paths that pull us up here
goes around this little spiral staircase
and pulls us up to our tree farm here
it's not done yet but it's fully
functional right now
it's actually really simple there's four
water sources all the saplings that fall
in the water get brought to the center
and the way this works is actually
really cool oh yeah over here I got a
chest for fertilizer crafting bench
chests for the saplings and then we have
a dispenser full of axes so when we come
up here we just head over here
right-click for an axe
grab some saplings we need fertilizer
grab some fertilizer I have some bones
on me so I'm just going to make some and
this tree farm is kind of uh it only
works if you use bone meal that's that's
what my intention was with this it will
grow on its own but it takes forever for
like this one tree to grow because it's
surrounded by other trees so it's very
takes a very long time for the trees to
grow if you just leave them on their own
so this is a bone meal tree farm and
what you do you just can reach the trees
from here they're at eye level which is
nice and you just spam the right-click
and the trees drill
and you don't have to worry about
right-clicking too many times because it
doesn't use any fertilizer if you
right-click on a log so just throw all
the trees once you got solid wood all
the way around just grab your X Maggie's
go around harvesting solid wood blocks
all the link pretty cool I think very
fast way to get wood and I'm saying wood
a lot this episode so please refrain for
making jokes because I know everybody
wants them okay so I usually just clear
out the bottom two blocks all the way
around and then I do the top ones and
above us there's a glass glass blocks
all the way around eight blocks up it
seems to be the ideal height to go nine
blocks up then you have issues with the
trees branching which will will get you
more wood doing that I just know this
want to be and really enjoys they'll get
more we're doing that but they branch up
to two blocks out so you have to destroy
leaves sometimes
so I find a putting the glass blocks
neat
eight blocks up is the best and I go all
I'll harvest it now the leaves all die
saplings fall some of them fall off on
the side not a big deal usually I don't
collect those ones most of them fall in
the water I an over here I have a
storage thing for wood and a storage
thing for charcoal this spot here is
dedicated these furnaces to making
charcoal just drop in a stack and then I
can store them here and when I have a
big load of charcoal or whatever then I
can pick it up and then take it down to
my storage room and so usually what I'll
do is out the school got saplings aim
straight down and right-click again
there's no dead zones in the water flow
which is nice it all goes right right
there
got a little bridge for getting up here
and by the time you have the trees all
planted again usually will sluzer
dead so you can go ahead and start
growing your next crop
oh yeah those are the glass blocks I'm
talking about there directly above the
soil eight blocks up
so I finally have a use for all the
bullets I've been getting just cool
I think it usually takes about three
stacks of bonemeal to draw them all and
I got 24 trees with this setup I use
mossy cobblestone just for looks there's
a ring 13 by 13 for the collection point
and then on the soil blocks I have these
torches so that saplings will uproot for
having a lack of lights if there's a
tree grove the bubble
[Applause]
so it works works really well I don't
recommend you building this style of a
tree farm if you don't have a steady
supply of bones it's more of a if you're
settled in your world like I am then
this works pretty good actually really
good and when you're done deposit your
stuff back and this you can't go down
the up way I've got a little drop zone
here for exits all the saplings that
float to the center you can pick up and
deposit
usually it's pretty close to 24 you got
21 that time now on the other side is
the cactus farm pretty much identical I
went to the nether I got some more
glowstone I'll lock the stuff here
so the cactus farm much the same thing
tree farm you enter over here opposite
side is the cactus farm go up the spiral
stairs and if you want details on how
this works please watch the tutorial I
just recently released it's pretty
pretty straightforward this parts not
done either yet and I have a drop here
just like the tree farm has a chest here
deposit them and then these two furnaces
are dedicated to making the green the
green dye and when I have this chest
full of either cactus or the dye I can
pick it up and then haul it to the
storage room and deposit it so it's
pretty cool I really like these two
farms they're almost identical and yet
they do two different things and I even
have this little up neat little
passageway here
to get from one to the other which is
pretty cool I think I have a feeling of
someone behind me and it looks kind of
cool too the passage between the two and
so this is where they all collect the
center here and then piping here takes
them to the collection areas
[Applause]
very nice I think so you guys might have
notice but the minecart track is still
here last episode I was really intent on
ripping it out and add my tool belt on
and everything but like some type of a
protective mother you guys tried to
plead a case or you know try to convince
me that it might have some use still and
at best you know I thought it would
serve as a science experiment something
that looked cool but you guys made a
pretty good case one thing you suggested
is to set up some sort of button or
buttons or levers or something to
control this door to turn the system on
or off so if I leave my base I can shut
it off and I won't have a with my cards
getting stuck on the track and that's
something I thought about doing - it's a
good suggestion but I still wasn't quite
happy with it because even if I do that
if I somehow have to leave the game
quickly or if I forget to shut the
system off or I die or you know game
crashes anything could happen then I
have to deal with the carts on the track
and like I said I can't really destroy
them because they fall into these cracks
where the stairs are and I can't pick
them up so I would have to push them all
which would involve walking around the
whole storage room
every time that happens which is a huge
pain well not a huge pain it takes a
minute but you know not something I want
to do all the time so another good
suggestion you guys gave me is to use
one of those furnace mine carts and to
set up some system for it and it'll come
up and push them all around and you guys
told me something I didn't know that if
you have one up if you have one of those
furnace mine carts not on a track it
doesn't use the coal so you could
probably put it on a door like this and
then when you want to call it open the
door and it'll start going on the track
and using the coal so combine those two
ideas I think we might somehow salvage
our minecart track system here I think
it might be fairly cool so that's what
we're going to do right now I've decided
to put call buttons here at all the
corners I don't have a whole lot of
options where I can put them because any
redstone wiring risks interfering with
my dispensers so the corners is a pretty
good place where I don't have any
problems
anymore Peters I think the buttons on
all the corners and then we'll run
redstone both these buttons will power
the Redstone and I kind of a mind out
the area here already to save time
actually I'll give you guys a little
tour of underneath my storage room
because I don't think I really show you
as this there's actually quite a bit of
hollowed out area this is the timer room
and then note blocks I hate coming in
here because it's really hard to move I
don't know how you got down here okay
you can have this room this is your room
how far down they were way down somehow
you found his way down here
and the collection points right above us
here these are the torches lighting it
up through the stairs there's the clock
someone said that like I mentioned that
my wiring is pretty calm back there and
he's like you don't know what contact
wiring is yeah you can't even move down
there I think that's pretty compact okay
so three four five six seven eight nine
10 11 12 13 14 14 I'm going to put a
repeater actually we'll run one more 15
is the limit oops get that repeater 1 2
oh yeah that's going to guys torque this
is the well there's not much of it or
this is a for the water control double
doors above us there's the old not the
old old but the old spawning pads that
are now abandoned
we got the station in here and that's
about it and there's an ice road and
some other stuff but I can't get to it
from here I don't think 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
I like placing a wire on soil
one two three four five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
fifteen oh let's put it over here this
is the other side so all eight we're
going to have eight buttons they're all
going to merge together and then they
are going to control a T flip-flop you
can't use an RS nor latch for this
because an RS nor latch is wolf RS nor
latch requires a tube inputs and we are
just going to have the one input the
button 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13
wait why was that one 13 then I said
odourless 14 one two three four five six
seven eight nine ten twelve thirteen now
whatever
Chie just going to go around here need
another repeater two three four five six
seven eight nine 10 11 12 13 14 15 one
two okay and that brings us to here
we're not going to hook this up yet I
need to lower this all I think probably
four or five blocks is at the moment our
PEZ dispenser only holds I think seven
mine carts and we need it to hold at
least eight but more is better
underneath us is the mob system so it's
all hollowed out already so it shouldn't
be too hard to add and I'm just I think
I'm just going to copy it all exactly
like it is here
yeah okay so I'm going to lower that my
card stuff later off-camera sometime
because it's not going to be all that
interesting and then we're going to have
the eight buttons which can control the
system pressing it once turns it on
probably within 30 seconds mine carts
will be all the way around the track and
I'll be working and then when we shut it
off we'll just press the button again
and it will start collecting all of my
carts that's pretty should be pretty
good I think okay guys I'll let you out
if you have to promise me you'll stop
pressing the sheep okay all right
be good be good
get what did I just tell you these guys
are awesome yeah you can have fun too go
ahead so something interesting I noticed
these guys don't seem to attack cows
anymore I don't know I think I'm pretty
sure they did when they first came up
and then there was a package and I think
one of the patches made selected attack
cows the only attacks sheep not only I
think they attack pigs and stuff
I'm kind of glad I didn't to work on the
whole thing in because if I had made a
chamber that would have been screwed
because they went till the towels in a
chamber like I had planned I let's check
if there's any leather oh I think I had
this from that wasn't a very good check
okay let's do one last thing before we
end this all right so we're just going
to go to the nether really quick and I
want to explain one of my new plans I
have really quick I think I thought I
had some armor here
[Music]
so when I was hunting the glowstone
before omit this games get laggy yeah
and I sent him the glowstone before I
just about got lost I did get lost and I
ran out of supplies pretty much and I
almost didn't make it back so whoa
that's close so I'm thinking I need to
develop some way of getting around here
or efficiently something I can depend on
because at the moment I could very
easily die in here and lose all this
stuff and I take it lost pretty easily
so my plan is just to make a giant
ladder Quigley's little die that goes
all the way to the ceiling and then I
should be able to come around leather by
mining out the ceiling and the building
a vase in the ceiling because it I think
it's all solid
[Music]
oh man I'm at the top okay
so that works oh so now I need to get
down yeah so it should be solid another
raft I think in the ceiling and I cannot
mine it out safely and get around
through the ceiling without getting shot
at or falling into lava think this is
probably common sense but I didn't think
about it just recently that I could do
this oh oh
where the heck is that boat now there we
go like that with two well and then I'm
just going to ladder and then I'm going
to put glass all around this side and
climb up safely and yeah that's the plan
guys let's try uh I'm stuck
[Music]
Geronimo all right
okay that's a wrap guys thanks for
watching I'll see you guys later