hello minecrafters this is evil and boy
do I have a treat for you guys I think
you guys are really gonna like this
episode actually you guys seem to like
most my episodes but this one in
particular I think it's gonna be awesome
look at all that leather because I have
lots of cool things to show you guys and
not only that I think you're going to
learn a few very helpful tips in
Minecraft this episode so without
further ado let's get this show going
and bear in mind what I'm about to show
you is not complete still making lots of
tweaks to it and there's still a few
flaws but the mob system is just about
complete here
all right so I should probably explain
how this is all working because they
kind of got ahead of you guys quite a
bit here but I was having trouble
building this so when I have been very
interesting to watch okay so what I'm
gonna do
you'll notice there's no real numbers
above us and the spawning pads there's
not a whole lot of mobs I back away
instantly we got like ten mobs up there
and we're gonna get into that a little
bit later oh darn it
butcherin episode already okay so I'm
gonna break this up for you I got the
pig separator working like perfect now I
don't think it'd be made much better I'm
calling it the bacon eater
Lucas died here
bacon drops goes down the stream goes it
goes over one of these doors you open
the door the bacon falls down that's how
you control whether it enters the system
or not the collection point so what's
the trick how did I get the story might
be a little bit hard to see so we're
actually gonna go inside out so the
trick is last episode you'll you'll know
you might remember I had the stream on
the ground and I realized that the trick
is just to have the diagonal stream
above the ground one block above I have
it set on top of these half blocks and I
can't really go in there because they're
in the way but the stream pushes them to
the left there's a one block high
opening here
and so they jump up they swim to the top
diagonal screen pushes them and they get
pushed into here and then there's like a
staircase thing that brings them up
higher and then I have kind of similar
to a lava bleed
and any non Pig thing keeps going and it
falls okay so we go down here the sheep
and the cows they fall down here they
get sucked up to here there's a little
bit of an indent here which with a
stream that pushes them against this
wall they swim up into here and we come
across a special door junction I
invented the door is open they fall down
if it's closed they go across the stream
I mean now and there's a ladder on the
other side of this I basically realized
that cows sheep and pigs cannot fit you
got a block here a ladder another block
they won't be able to fit into the space
here they're too fat same if you have a
door over here they won't be able to fit
so I wasn't able to do the mob junctions
like I've been doing with the tall
hostile mobs so I had to invent this
other type of Junction
I had chickens what did I do with the
chickens
well they had separated by this water
here diagonal screen pushes on to that
area and I got a bunch of lava waiting
for them and the door you'll notice is
kind of sometimes it's stuck which isn't
good there's sort of a dead zone there
but usually they'll start moving around
and and die
I don't think get in there anymore not
maybe I can't so if the door is closed
they get stuck here and they collect in
this little chamber here they lay eggs
every five minutes and then the eggs
they fall down this little hole here has
a stream and goes to collection point
here I still have to remove this block
and then it everything will fall down
the pipe and yeah I don't really need
the feathers but at the same time I need
a way to kill the chickens otherwise the
chickens are just going to keep
accumulating and it'll get to the point
where no pigs cows or sheep will spawn
because it's all chickens so that's the
whole point of the door if I want to
collect their eggs I don't want the
chickens to die if I don't want the eggs
I want the chickens to die and I did
kind of cheat because I was supposed to
set up a way to collect the feathers but
yeah I've discovered this is a lot
harder to do than I initially realized
handling these passive moms is a lot
harder than handling the tall hostile
mobs there's chickens for example they
fit they're less than half a block tall
in less than half a block wide so
they're really hard to control pigs they
can fit in a one by one space that makes
them hard to to move around and same
with sheep and cows they're shorter than
tall mops and also fatter so that makes
things tricky too
and a hard time finding out ways to kill
the mobs but these this method here
works pretty good and so you might have
realized this already but I did not do
my skeleton idea I had for sharing wool
off sheep I still might do it I haven't
given up on that idea but you know just
for now I wanted to get the same all
setups so that could mean working order
and then I could maybe later add the
skeleton idea because I kind of left
from that I would just have to remove a
pipe and then attach it somewhere and
same with the chicken thing if I ever
want to collect feathers I got plenty of
room on the side still where I could set
something up so I'll still looked into
that idea because I think it would be
good
so what this pipe here is doing this
other Junction this is going to bring
cows and sheep and possibly wolves I
don't know what the dimensions of wolves
are gonna be but I think they'll be
similar to cows and sheep and if they
are it'll bring wolves also I mean I
decided I'm gonna send a pipe that's
gonna land somewhere down there in the
front of my house
I'm gonna set up a little pasture
probably with the astro turf fake grass
and I'm gonna drop the cows and sheep a
long distance just so that they're
basically one hit to John and then in
front of my house it'll be somewhere
probably around here it's gonna be right
next to all my dies so say I had a blue
die I would just go here pick it up go
outside oh look here's 20 sheep out here
and then go nuts you know die alder will
collect the wool and also I'll have the
cows will fall here too and if I can
collect milk from them and they will be
one hit so if I see a sheep if I left
click on it the wool will fall off and
they will die
it's a plan and it'll be fenced off so
that they're stuck in a little area so I
got to finish setting that up still got
quite a bit to do on that mob system and
I will release my world again not this
episode because I just released it at
the last episode but sometime soon and
then he gets and
I checked this out for yourselves how I
got everything set up in more detail
because I know it's kind of hard to see
in just the video especially with me
moving around all over the place and
then you can dissect the system and take
a better look actually quite quite a lot
of detail to it I even here you'll
notice the calves that she'd get pushed
over and I got a sign over there so that
I don't know drops land on a block so
all the drops are 100% collection there
same with the pigs the eggs it's all
100% perfect the labid is in story lava
doesn't destroy any of the blocks or any
of the items I mean so that's good I'm
gonna point out some of the flaws in the
system sometimes if two animals fall
down here they can sometimes Jam and
prevent each other from flowing in here
usually they free themselves though by
jumping around or if another mouth mob
comes along so that's one fly I got
right now I've discovered there's a
slight flaw in the spawning pads
apparently you know I have the stairs
here apparently chickens can get stuck
in the stairs in that quarter block
space I think chickens can actually fit
and then eighth of a block so if you
divide one block into eight pieces
that chicken could fit inside one of
those so sometimes chicken stuck in the
stairs but if another mob comes along
I'll push that you can outs so that's
another flaw not a major one I think it
may be possible for a pig to get into
the chicken area but I haven't seen it
happen yet it would be pretty rare if it
ever does happen but since that is one
block high it probably is possible
somehow so that might be another flaw
this stream is pretty long 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
it can probably handle 10 pigs if you
have more than 10 pigs then the pigs
might take the sheep and cows pass just
because the buffer is only good for 10
10 pigs or so and same with the sheep
and cows I only have but buffer for
maybe yea probably around 10 and if I
get more than 10 in the killing line
then they might take the other path
there even if the door is open so the
buffers are a limited size that's
another flaw there is a dead zone in
that Junction I invented which kind of
sucks
if the door is closed at our sheep we'll
go over top it and then they'll get
stuck and it'll require another sheep or
cattle come along and push that previous
one through so there's usually always
one mob that gets stuck here but that's
not a big deal either just a small dead
zone and that's I think that's the only
flaws and so I'm going to be hooking up
this is where all the drops come I'm
gonna hook up the item gates here
probably so that I can control if I want
passive mob drops using this lever here
but so I'm going to show you how you can
make your own passive mob system in any
world you can do it in a brand new world
and make your own that works pretty good
probably in five minutes or less I have
a theory I want to test out so we're
gonna go in adventuring
to see if it's gonna work or not so I'm
gonna get my supplies ready and then
we're doing it on a small adventure
woohoo adventure finally we get to go on
an adventure I've been craving this for
quite a while now what's wrong with her
sound but you guys don't like me going
on adventures
because you want me to stick to the
science well this adventure is for
science but I'm gonna have some fun
oops accidentally stopped the video yeah
we're gonna have some fun here stuff I
brought and let's go so what we're just
doing here is we're going away from our
base so that it doesn't interfere with
our tests we're about to do and what I'm
about to show you guys I think might
actually change people the way people
play Minecraft like the way they start
out a new world because I think you can
make a very effective passive mob system
in under five minutes using basic
materials nothing complicated just by
exploiting the way mob spawning works
because it's actually quite simple so
you remember that thing I showed you
when I walked away from the spawning
pads like instantly a bunch of mob
spawns
that's because it's nighttime it was
nighttime when I did that normally
during the day if I do that cool
pumpkins normally during the day that
doesn't happen I might get the odd mob
spawning after a minute or two but at
night it's almost instant and lots of
mobs
so we're looking for a flat grass area
and we're gonna build our spawning area
hopefully quickly because this video is
getting along so yeah it's really simple
all mobs the passive mobs need is grass
and light has to be a light level 9 or
greater according to the Wikipedia I do
kind of trust the Wikipedia
I think it's right
all right I'm just gonna do it here I
think I'm gonna clear some trees real
quick and then I'll be back
actually you know what I'm not going to
do this off camera because I said five
minutes or less and they'll probably
actually take me longer but it is
possibly to five minutes or less I have
cleared one tree and place some soil
here that's all you need to do
I brought some fences with me and if you
have a nice level spots I just fence out
the area you want with your mobs to
spawn it however big you want and in
whatever shape you want and it doesn't
even need to be that big actually there
that's probably fine
and you fence out your area then all you
have to do is place torches don't need a
whole lot and you're done that's it so
let me explain you need grass and light
level 9 or more to spawn passive machs
during the day they're gonna spawn
anywhere around you within 128 blocks
because there's grass thousands and
thousands of grass blocks all around me
that they can spawn it but at night that
changes they can't spawn in the grass
blocks because it's too dark
so the only place they can spawn at
night is in this little enclosure I made
because I have torches and grass okay
they won't spawn if I'm close to the
silk they'll only spawn if I'm 24 blocks
or more away ah I don't know if you've
ever seen like a lava pool if you
approach a lava pool in the middle of
the night there'll be tons of mobs
around it because it's a natural source
of light and there's usually grass near
lava pools and that's why you often see
a lot of mobs around lab of pools so
that's basically what I've done here
I've made an artificial light source for
them to spawn it passive mobs are not
attractive to the torches they like a
lot of people think they're it's just
where they spawn and so they're usually
near torches and you know what I'm gonna
set up a little quick killing machine
very simple dig down to go up three go
all the way around
take out the corners if you want
we're gonna place a door here I forgot
to bring that door okay we need a door
and what else did we need oh yeah and
we're just gonna place water inside here
in all four blocks this is similar to
that water wall thing I made it my base
I think this will work any mob that
wanders into here they'll fall down and
drown and then you can collect their
loot and for the sake of this experiment
I'm going to kill all the mobs around
this area within 24 blocks of here so
that will be no mobs
and then you can see there's a sheep
kind of far away from there I'm gonna
wait a while and they'll be spawn and
then I'll zoom recording and I'll show
you guys something that I think will
work now you guys were back that's about
the middle of the night now it's been
about five minutes I'm a little bit
surprised the Sheep didn't wander into
the water on its own this is kind of a
random trap played yeah only works if
they randomly walk into it but it's one
you can set up really easy without
having any water canals or anything
complicated like that oh oh he's come
off it close but we're gonna kill so
haven't tested this yet but my theory is
most of the passive mobs should have
gone by now I was shocking and since
it's too dark for them to spawn on the
grass around me the only place they can
spawn is on is inside my trap here the
bigger you make this trap the better it
will probably work
you know I'm just gonna switch it easy
very peaceful just because I don't want
them annoying me so pretty much as soon
as I walk 24 blocks away from here
this is the only place they should be
able to spawn in and it should be pretty
much instant I see Chao already one cow
that's all I see not cheap
oh there they go yeah so I'm right so
it's kind of cool you know cuz you can
be during the day you're usually out
doing stuff in your worlds exploring and
whatever building then at night a lot of
people run back to their base to their
house wow that actually worked really
well there's a ton of guys all these
smokes
and they are randomly falling in and
drowning so that yeah if you come back
to your base at night you can't collect
meet you but Julie can collect leather
for armor and it just works really well
it's very cool very easy setup that took
me about five minutes ideally you should
do it on flat grounds and a square it
probably works better if I killed all
these guys and then left and it was
still night in here and that walk 24
blocks away the same thing happened
again because this is the only place
that can spawn unless there is a lava
pool somewhere on the surface but if you
do do this you have to be careful
because you have if you're building a
base somewhere say I have a house built
on grass and I place torches on the
exterior of it
well then mobs will be able to spawn in
that area because you have torches in
your grass so they'll be able to spawn
outside of your trap same as if I put a
torch here outside of my trap and mobs
can spawn outside so you want to place
torches on the outside of your house and
it's at grass you will need to replace
the grass with something else so just
keep working
and you should probably figure out some
better way of making a killing thing a
bit of meat down there oh yeah anyway
that's it that's it guys thank you for
watching I hope you enjoyed this hope
you found it interesting I ramble quite
a bit so I'm sorry for that
[Music]
wasn't quite as coherent as I was hoping
I would be this episode but I hope I
think I was clear enough anyway so thank
you for watching and we'll see you next
time