ah it's going to eat me
aha I'm trapped oh where are we guys
where are we what's going on here this
is my new the start of my new mob
spawning grounds with the improvements
that I want to try out
not much is done on it I tried to make a
4-way mob evader works very well for the
tall mobs but it does not work for the
spiders so I'm going to do something
different and we are at level 39 I
believe
so the goal with the new system is it's
only going to be about 12 pads I think I
don't think I need to make a huge mob
system and it's below its like 24 blocks
below the surface so I'm not going to be
hearing all the stupid mob noises
anymore just by chance there was a
dungeon down here at the same level so
that's what this game from and I am
going to give huge props to freak
entertainer that guy is a genius because
he has shown me one of my favorite
tricks yet he told me I don't know if
you guys can see it but say I want to
look through this wall and this wall all
I need to do this is freak entertainer
snip stand just outside of this box here
so I'm outside of the box place gravel
[Music]
well anyway you can see through the
ground if you do this and by doing that
I can see all the tunnels I have lit up
and all the ones I haven't so I don't
need to use the f3 trick to look for
monsters and tunnels and then light up
the tunnels I can just look through the
ground at all the tunnels I've lit up
using freak entertainers trick here oh
yeah and if you go to different
difficulty you can actually see the mobs
jumping around in the tunnels you see
there's one down there there's a creeper
in that dark tunnel I got most of this
area lit up pretty cool going to make
things a lot easier do it over here you
can see my old those are the abandoned
spawning pads and it's pretty cool
alright but enough wasting time this is
not what we're supposed to be doing this
episode we are going to be building
level 3 starting it anyway where we will
spawn and click farm animal mobs and so
I've shut this all down
[Music]
okay going to gather some resources and
then we'll get started all right guys
you ready let's go so layer we're on
right now is the storage room
y-coordinate is 65 this is level 2 up
here this is the mob once I finish the
new mob system if I ever do this is
going to be where I kill the mobs and
sort the mobs and do whatever crazy
thing I want to do with the mobs and
it's at level 74 so let's 11 blocks up
three four five six seven eight nine mmm
yeah they'll probably be good I don't
know how much space I'm going to need on
the second level so I'm just going to
make it 10 high and hope it's good
enough this mob sorter probably won't
need to be any higher than this so this
is level 3 and I know you guys are
probably thinking on [ __ ] for
starting level 3 before finishing level
1 or 2 um I may be but there is some
reasoning behind it namely I want so I'm
going to be killing the farm animals on
level 3 here and doing other things with
them and so I want their loot to fall on
our five-minute timer on level 1 and to
do that I need to set up the piping and
I can't let anything get in the way of
the piping like
oh not very good at explaining things I
need the area above the the five-minute
timer clear so if I was to build level
two first and build the a mob sorter in
a record studio and all that crap
there's a good chance I'm going to build
in the way of where I need to run the
piping for the loot so there is some
reasoning behind starting this level
before I'm done the other ones but guess
what this isn't the level we're going to
be working on why not well this is the
mob
this is level four killing the mobs and
stuff like that the actual level for
spotting them is going to be even higher
three four four five six seven eight
what are we at 92 um let's see here how
do I get down ah dang it
all right
this is level 3 3 4 5 7 8 I can't
remember what the number was was it 63
down here the positioning is actually
pretty important 65 jazz we need the
spawning grounds to be out of the 24
block radius so it needs to be at least
24 blocks higher than ground level there
and yet we want it within the 32 block
radius a level 3 so and yet we need
enough space in case we set up anything
it takes a lot of space but I'm guessing
this will probably be good enough so
we're going to start the ceiling
no more levels after this one this is
the end and I'm going to lay the
foundation for the ceiling now voiceover
commentary alright guys so building this
farm animal mob collection system seemed
like a pretty simple idea in my head but
in reality it's actually pretty crazy
and insane to do so the whole thing took
me roughly four hours so I'm just going
to show you different steps I took and
building it first thing I'm doing here
is laying a 30 by 30 cobblestone base
one layer thick
so that I think builds for spawning pads
on it next thing I'm doing here is I am
finding my coordinates for the very
center of my storage room the x and z
coordinates the very center and then up
I go up and I mark them using these
wooden planks the very center of the
storage room the 2x2 area and then I
build all around that Center and then I
start building the actual spawning pads
out of soil similar to my mod system
they are 14 by 14 I might make some
adjustments to them later but that's
what I'm doing for right now you got to
be kind of careful when you're doing
this kind of thing that you light up the
area around you otherwise you might get
some surprises yeah not my proudest
moment ever and it gets worse
never take your eyes off a creeper that
was embarrassing
I was like trying to do this like jump
onto his head sword attack move in it I
missed and that's the whole thing pretty
much all done so what I do here is I am
running a spiral staircase to bring my
brass up to the top you should do this
early because it takes grass extremely
long to make it to travel that distance
I actually left my game running while I
was doing something else for about an
hour - and it's still grass still hasn't
spread all the way yet now once you get
your spiral staircase lighted up so let
the grass will grow and then wait a few
hours and I decide to add another layer
of soil over the whole thing you could
obviously do this using a lot less
resources you only need it to be one
layer thick but
I decide to go all the way out and I
pretty much used up all my soil supply
making list I have only four ads I don't
think I need to make it any bigger
but I can if I need to play some torches
and then fill up another layer and the
canals it's just so that I can do my
trick with the stairs and the sign to
keep a continuous flow in the water
canals I need it to three thick and now
for the longest part of the whole thing
we use your mom to clear the grass here
all around the island and the goal of
this is to make the only grass the grass
on this bonding pad so that the farm
animal mobs can only spawn on our
spawning pads and nowhere else and if
you're going to make one of these things
bear in mind this will take forever and
I actually have it pretty good because
most of this island is surrounded by
water and or sand
so there's actually very little grass
surrounding and it still took me I think
two hours then I didn't even do it all
as you'll see soon
[Music]
so anything's going to discourage you
from making a mob system like this it's
clearing the grass he hid works ha ha ha
ha ha oh I'm so glad it works if I did
all this junk work and it didn't work I
would be pretty upset all your bacon is
mine yeah that's only one spawning bed
so the grass is still spreading takes a
very long time um we're not going to
finish this up this episode next episode
we'll work on setting up the water
canals I'll probably put a fence around
this thing not that the mobs will fall
off but it's more so so I won't fall off
advert looks and checked it out I think
that looks awesome I have a feeling I am
the only person in Minecraft history
completely remove the grass why didn't
completely do it but almost completely
remove the grass from an island and I
had to battle the grass because as I was
clearing it it was spreading back to the
places I cleared it and yeah it's pretty
crazy but I won so there'll be a hole
here which will bring
mobs down to level three which is where
we will sort them and harvest them and
do crazy things with them and I know
everybody wants to make a joke about
that I'm going to show you guys one
thing I don't really you know if you
want to build this thing it's up to you
it's quite a bit of work though I'm up
to four hours and still not done and I
could remove more grass yet because it's
still nuts
I think mobs can still spawn around the
area so what I've done is I've put this
cobblestone barrier here to prevent the
grass from spreading further back into
our Island because I didn't really want
to finish this all because it's actually
a pretty big island I might do more
later I don't know if I feel like it it
wasn't that bad I watched a movie while
I cleared the grass made time to go
faster but yeah it wraps around and so
that barrier keeps it from spreading
back because if you allow that to happen
it'll completely overtake the whole
island again but I'm going to wrap up
the episode here thanks for watching and
oh yeah you gotta keep a lookout too
because sometimes you miss one and then
it starts to spread in so I need to get
on this
and that's what she said I know
someone's going to do that okay I'll see
you next time oh boy what can I say guys
I'm as shocked as you are
thank you very much everyone I got to
get to work
and also congrats on bowling at 300
that's very impressive
can't imagine too many people have ever
done that
and now you need to bowl up 450 in five
pin that's my challenge to you see
everybody