hello everyone this is etho thank you
for joining me again today so I got your
feedback I read through all the PM's you
sent me all the comments you left last
episode over 2000 comments Wow
incredible that's the most I've ever
received so thanks for voicing your
opinion everybody to the question should
I start a new world for 1.8 and most of
you seem to be leaning the way I wanted
you to about 90 percent roughly agree
that I should make a new world which is
good because that's what I wanted to do
don't get me wrong I know I don't have
to make a new world but I want to make a
new world I think it'll be fun I'm
excited too
and you know I'm not really that sad
leaving this place behind I'm not I'm
not very sentimental
you know I am to an extent but you know
like remember that glass block when I
was making the eats Road and how I
polymerized it just destroyed it and all
of you were like now you should have put
it in behind a picture frame or
something saved it made a throne for it
well you know that's not me if
something's not working or fits in the
way I like to move on and continue on I
look look forward to the future I guess
you could say and that's what I'm going
to do with the 1.8 things are changing
in Minecraft I'm going to change with
them and it's going to be great so it
didn't feel right just to say good just
to leave this world and not say goodbye
to it so that's what this episodes for
today the number one thing people seem
to want me to do is harvest the clay and
that seemed very fitting to me it's been
with us all this time
we should we should get rid of it I
suppose I figured tnt's the most fitting
make it quick and painless but before we
blow it let's let's kind of have a
little funeral procession for it and for
the world goodbye world we loved you we
enjoyed you had many good times here but
don't be sad people even though we're
saying goodbye to it today we had good
times here and those good times aren't
leaving us we learn many things here and
we will continue to remember those so
it's not like we lost anything
all the all the fun I had in this world
I bring with me really and when we start
a new world well we'll have fun there
too will learn new things there it'll be
good
so don't don't worry it's not really a
sad event it's a exciting event new
beginnings so I got my trusty flint and
steel with me I can't believe that I had
to read the name and we are ready to say
goodbye to the clay once and for all ah
goodbye clay you served me well I never
would have thought a few clay blocks
control people so hard it's been real
I'm going to do it I can't believe I'm
really going to do it what
it didn't work what the heck
now if you left click with if you left
click with flint and steel yeah it sets
TNT on what the heck
Australian ah what is going on I don't
understand
Lester Lester I come on the clay is
resisting me oh my goodness sorry guys
it's not gonna happen
nope not gonna happen you know I said it
would be there forever throughout the
whole LP it stayed I want you to I want
you to know that it's never being
harvested that it's going to be sitting
on my computer unharvested and whenever
you you're going to think of it and it's
just gonna torment you and I'm gonna
laugh cuz it's so funny oh good times
good times anyway today's episode is
going to be called Ola
which means goodbye and hello in Hawaii
so we said goodbye to the last world and
now say hello to the new world ah hello
world nice to meet you oh yeah we're on
hard to good ok yeah so I just took a
quick peek around here my two favorite
biomes in the new patch are the mountain
one and the swamp one and this is a
spawn right off the bat epicness
we got swampland right in front of us
we're on a mountain right now and I saw
we got like crazy stuff over there so I
know the seats going to be good I'm
happy like really crazy
stuff it's taking a while to load so
yeah let's let's begin our adventure
we're killing sunlight here maybe just
quickly we'll take a closer peek at the
mountains here I want you guys to see
what I saw
yeah it looks pretty good
I think this will be good I like this
world but I don't want to start in the
mountains because as you know mountains
don't have many resources so we're going
to go down to swamp area it looks like
there's some cool mountains over there
too which we will check out sometime
aha our first victim I will call you KFC
yes alright
raw meat with every adventure wants yeah
so we'll go to the swamplands
we will check things out a bit try to
get some resources I'm really pumped up
guys like I'm excited a little bit
nervous haven't been this nervous about
making an episode in a long time since
the first one really I don't know if you
guys could tell but I was really nervous
my first episode but now I have more
experience have more knowledge I feel
feel revitalized revamped and just very
excited it's going to be good and as you
know of course the reason I like the
swamplands is because of the green grass
it's the greenest grass in the game
right now possible key iron whoa very
nice
maybe we will take advantage of this
first tree right here and be a lot of
firsts today yeah I like the green grass
here and you know I'm sad about the
changes with the passive mob system
about the spawning and that we can't
really make a good system anymore but at
the same time I don't have to consider
killing all my grass in this world I
actually get to keep the grass which is
awesome I'm excited about that
chocolate island is cool but I did start
to miss the grass after a while and I'm
actually I really enjoy terraforming in
this game so now that I've grasped work
with I'll probably spend more time on
aesthetics and this playthrough but of
course a big part of its going to be
inventing and figuring out new stuff but
I don't want to ignore aesthetics as
much this time and we will be playing on
hard for hopefully the whole thing last
LP I did I cheated when I started
building the mob system I believe is
when it began like if I was in my
storage room and a creeper was about to
blow up
I would quickly switch the peaceful like
a baby and I just started cheating more
and more and eventually I just started
playing on peaceful a lot of the times
every now and then I would switch back
to hard and and try to make an effort to
get back to it but I just couldn't
because I I broke the rules once you
break the rules it's like it's like you
are more willing to make the exception
in the future you know if diamond blocks
are gonna blow up you're more likely to
press the Steep and go to peaceful then
if you've never done it before
what's this nothing nothing
so yeah let's get resources here
wondering why they're not showing up
there there and yeah we'll show some
resource gathering but I'm not going to
do it to the point that it's really
boring huh I'll start cutting stuff if
it's if it's game boring like it is
right now but thankfully we're going to
go do something else now because we have
enough cobble to get started and I will
make my tools I cannot function without
my tools let's see okay oh no we don't
want that yes I'm pretty pumped up I
really haven't played the 1.8 too much
like I've spent a lot of time looking at
different seeds and how the world
generates what am i doing here oh my
goodness what am i doing such a noob
sometimes I spent a lot of time just
looking at seeds and I had a lot of
technical problems with the 1.8 patch my
game kept in corrupted stuff like that
it was frustrating I think I figured out
what the problem was my RAM disk messed
up so now I'm playing off the hard drive
I'm gonna snag this tree maybe we'll I'm
not going to cut down the whole thing
just in case I want to rebuild it in the
future
if that makes any sense yet so we'll be
fighting mobs for real
none of that peaceful garbage and
hopefully we'll find some meat before
nightfall here I'm not going to start
building a house right away I want to
collect resources and probably make a
few chests
when night falls we'll probably do some
fighting I don't know we'll see don't
have any real plans at the moment I'm
just I'm just so excited this is cool a
nap in the new patch here we got trees
that actually start in the water the
swampy areas very different
I love the vines the lines are really
cool I'll probably use them a lot just
for looks
I'm kind of hoping to find some cows
here it's the trees very good we should
explore a bit too let's see what what's
our time oh it's it's sunset darn it oh
there's a squid have to kill him for
some reason now he's going away from me
come back yes why am i using an axe I
have a sword oh well yeah okay let's
let's set up base here the restaurant up
in the last two seconds this seems like
a pretty good starting area actually
it's like a little swampy island Oh cow
house full speed add a little bit of
sand here
anybody Wow one hit did you see that I
didn't know you could do that one hit
one hit nice cool okay
little protective tree here get this
going get a furnace going we got quite a
bit of wood ah
I'd say the shift-clicking is really
messing me up the new changes with it ah
thing that was a mistake okay now I need
more wood because before it would just
move it to your to the bottom bar here
now it like fully crafts everything
which is really confusing once you get
used to the other way so now then make
some charcoal get some chests gone
and hopefully do some exploring maybe
not at night maybe next next morning
we'll do some exploring okay I'm going
to put this in here yeah okay that's
good I'm actually getting really hungry
dum dum dum dum
ooh and we got some zombies let's go to
our secret mode here so we can actually
see guys are easy before they're even
easier oh yeah
what's this have I been here nothing
here um where should we go
maybe we'll just wander around explore a
bit fight some mobs good stuff oh yeah
and get some chickens
oh yeah new fighting systems pretty cool
I like it makes things a bit easier
of course oh we got egg what's with all
the chickens really hot some pigs or
something cool
all right maybe I'll head back
well this is embarrassing I was going to
do a cut and like go to the main base
and save some time but I got lost
I haven't wandered far but I don't know
I don't want where the furnaces oh I
didn't take any damage
I lost the furnace and stuff the chests
got beat around here man
well okay three guys four guys this is
getting tense five guys six to eight Wow
creeper island man what is up with this
ah
no run you stupid thing yeah yeah
absolutely ones in it there was at least
there's like ten of them
you saw that make one of them blew up
here oh this is what one on one eight is
on with other guys back to the basics Oh
too close too close
ah as about to say something I thought
if you like circles what is it to the
right of skeletons that they're less
likely to hit you than if you circle to
the left is what I thought but now I'm
starting to think that's not true okay
well I'm not healing am I gotta do it
make it sick I'm good
this is where they blew up and be loaded
with TNT soon alright let's try to find
like I've been here I cut these trees
down those are the mountains so it must
be to the left right or not I don't know
no no I think it's over here get some
string where's my furnace okay this is
such a small island why can't I find it
not there there it is okay cool
oh that's gone crazy okay sweet okay
we're back we did pretty good there
that's really thought I was going to die
cook that it's got some belongings here
what I'll do safety check you got some
torches let's maybe place a few
just be a little safer all right it's
nice and bright
let's what I want to do I want to make a
little wheat farm if possible I'm
addicted to running I love running again
still yet okay there we go
I said I wonder if you could get seeds
that way left and right down to you
there okay okay that's good I'm full no
use first death there'll be many of
those I'm sure okay I'm going to run
back get my stuff I'll see you there
okay we're back was around here all
right
there's okay whoo yeah it is kind of a
mistake on my part for some reason I
thought I could still heal myself like
my heart's eating food you know what I
forgot for a second that you can't do
that anymore and that's kind of why I
died there otherwise I would have stayed
and fought or built up a wall or
something I don't know still adjusting
to the patch I think I got everything
very good
no harm no foul plant some dreams get
some seeds all the mobs seem to be gone
now so I read on the forums today that
passive mobs seem to spawn about every
for it the game checks every 400 ticks
if they should spawn instead of every
tick like that did before so yeah it's a
lot they're a lot rarer now but they
don't seem to de-spawn like they used to
from what I've noticed so yeah they are
more persistent they're around longer
okay do I have food yes good good let's
go do some quick exploring I think the
episodes almost at the end though don't
need that
oops I'll put that stuff in there
okay where should we go let's go check
out well one of the best ways to explore
is with the boats all out of order here
let's not lose a spot and let's see
what's around so there's a pine forest
over there there's only like six biomes
now right there's a what do we have we
have Mountain we have swamp pine forest
regular forest there's Plains ocean
desert that's it right that's that's
seven so there's seven biomes now I'm
assuming if you have a 1.73 worlds
whatever biomes you had before got
converted to one of the seven new ones
I'm assuming okay lots of water around I
hope this is an ocean
I think the ocean and the pine forest
are my least favorite we got some pigs
but with the passive mobs I'm guessing
if you continue to explore if you leave
the area they darn it they probably
still let the spawn if you're more than
128 blocks away I'm assuming or
something like that okay where are you
hiding from some snake really need to
get iron armor quickly or some coal or
something oh here we go let's go caving
a little bit not too much
and first guy that greets us is it
creeper hey all is water that's crazy
yeah I see you watching me oh that's
from San thieved in here oops
cut it they're not seeing any resources
how is there no iron and no coal here
oh okay we got cool cool first coal and
I believe what I will do is actually
harvest this gravel so that I can get
some Flint for arrows cuz I'm desperate
alright it looks like I found a Plains
biome over here there's a bunch of sheep
around here phew
oh it's just a really small vial ocean
that way pine forest and then we're back
to the swamp over here so I'm going to
stick closer to the swamp and maybe
we'll check out the mountains it's a
mushroom Oh desert over there guys
desert let's get some cactus cat died
and we have enough wool now to make a
bed
cool
lots of water trees over there I am a
little bit lost again I think we came
that way but I could be wrong should be
easier to spot was that that pig or that
skeleton pig should be easy to spot
where we were there because I place
torches pumpkins here
I guess you decide yourself don't have
to run jump at them it's a lot more fun
are so died okay I'm not gonna be greedy
here I just want to get a few cactus oh
boy
endure men still haven't fought one of
them what am i doing those zombies get
Hey and then I'm getting out of here
mission complete we got a cactus Sam
quickly let's get out of here before I
die again yummy hey I got these
mountains man they're so cool
very impressed that is a lava pool that
water flowed into those are pretty
common creeper nice try buddy aw cool we
found iron coal good good okay guys I
found a really deep hole here looks like
there's some cool cave systems below so
I marked this area with torches we might
come back to here later and check it out
might be a good start for getting iron
and coal and stuff right piggy very good
okay I'm heading back to our chests
there okay I made it back safe and sound
guys I thought that we get to get a good
look around the area it's fairly nice I
like it happy with this world and we got
a nice little start yeah yeah you're mad
at me what are you gonna do I'm Way up
here you're burning to death
as hopefully it's in front by doing this
got lots of resources already good first
start anyway
and I will see you guys next time thanks
for watching