yes what guys I just got back from Ikea
splurged a little bit and got myself a
new painting for the house very excited
to see what it is
ah well you know what they have a good
return policy well I decided to go with
the sandstone lining at the bottom oh
yeah by the way this is etho and the
video etc etc so I went with a sandstone
lining I left it up to you guys to try
choose for me but you pretty much won
50/50 again so I think more people
prefer the sandstone it's over the logs
but it was really close and I did too so
that's why I went with sandstone didn't
do the lining though around the door I
tried it with logs that looks weird with
logs
well maybe I'll do it just for you guys
so you can see if I have any on me yep
just so that you don't wonder yeah it
looks a bit strange to me and dark looks
dark logs look strange too so just gonna
leave it with planks ok another big
change I went to the nether and got a
bunch of glowstone again it's so much
easier to collect it now so the good
news is I can actually see in my storage
room once again better than before even
another good thing is I can very clearly
read the signs now so you can't get them
any brighter than that so
even brighter than having the torches
through the stairs which by the way I've
been having a lot of people tell me
works again I don't think it does not
cording to any of my tests still really
dark yeah so we got glowstone got the
new lining put a new creeper face out
here
why not hey but yeah like I said I'll
stead of having the wall completely flat
here I'll try to do something to give it
more character is the plan yeah still
haven't fixed the barn of course I have
worked a little bit on the beats Road
let's go check that out it's almost done
kind of not really make myself boats
well let's do two and apparently that
someone has discovered how to make a
quick water elevator now so I might
experiment with that then eats as you
probably saw in docked in 1767
and that's where falls apart I have both
bullets don't let oh yeah I'm gonna do
this one more time because that was kind
of crummy all right
second attempt here ignore these first
few notes and here we go okay so that is
supposed to be the intro to the cave
story theme song someone gets that with
only four notes last episode don't know
how how he did that that's incredible
but the problem with doing this music
with the e throat is timing for each of
these things is equal but if you try to
add repeaters on to these pressure
plates or any type of delay using
redstone it doesn't work because it's
time different so you can't get equal
notes
if that makes sense I'll show you what I
mean okay so that plays two notes going
over that one pressure plate and this is
what it looks like inside here it goes
to that one then there's a two torch
delay and then it goes to this one so
you can't time it using the e throat and
then have like a repeater like I have
here and expect to hit the timing right
so I'll probably just remove that
jumbled part of the song
and just keep that intro the way I could
get this to work is to let's see
I would have to shorten these streams to
only too long so that it's a repeated
pattern every three blocks and then I
would be able to space the song properly
it's other thing is it playing a little
bit slow the tempo so it would be better
if it was only like that instead so I
would increase the tempo to do the
proper speed of the song and also I
would be able to time it properly using
pressure plates instead of redstone
repeaters and stuff but anyway I'm sure
you're getting bored with this already
people have very short attention spans
myself included okay so I still haven't
done that at that ends guessing this is
where I will probably end the road and I
might have more Road segments around
here I don't know but that's it for eats
so far it's working progress so
something I was hoping to fix this
episode is this minecart system as well
I already went ahead and fixed the
wiring which was washed away and I think
I made it so that won't happen again
so someone op op op op op op op op 31 or
something sent me a video response on
how to fix this it looked really simple
I just need to place some trapdoors here
pretty much
I couldn't find his video again so I'm
going off of memory and I got two
trapdoors can't place these on glass
apparently
I'm guessing a pair of squirrel and
Ralph David also have videos on how to
do this which I will be checking if I
get stuck here and just I'm assuming
this is that I haven't really put a lot
of thought into this to trap doors and
then I'm guessing power rail here and
rail here and now what I think I have to
do but I'm not certain as you see that
power down there right now that's
powering well what's powering that cart
there this power rail I need to run that
wire all the way to these trapdoors and
hopefully that will make this work and
once again I haven't put much thought
into this so there's a good chance it
won't work I'd opened one mmm there's
probably a trick to make them open both
really easily
oh I hate destroying this tract it was
so hard to make this but it doesn't work
so there's no point keeping it around
oops and I should probably keep the
delay because I don't want to disturb
those repeaters if possible that maybe
we'll run it up no there's something up
there going to place its like this or on
a stair chase up there's a reason I
never do wiring on camera because it
you're always redoing everything or at
least I always have to redo stuff I do
ok this can probably just wrap around
like so
and just like that
okay that was pretty good now we just
need to open the other one as well how
should I do that problem is that wire is
in the way and this is probably pretty
messy looking but it's a fixed so it's
not oh I just fell through the ground
guys that glitch is still in the I just
fell through the ground again that still
needs to be fixed happens when you walk
over repeaters and I think this ceiling
is only two I let's try it out now we
want them both to open at the same time
so that should be pretty good yeah okay
so I'm gonna finish this up and see what
happens okay here's the first test I got
rid of the one power rail here replaced
it with a regular rail I powered this
one using a lever which I'll probably
change later and I put a detector rail
here to cause the looping action to take
place and I don't really remember how
this all works down here is a problem I
kind of waited a long time before fixing
this so let's just see what happens here
should drop it down one all right it
snaps to the bottom
and that's not moving I think that has
to be a different block than glass yep
looks like I need more paddles but it's
gone
oh but you know what that's kind of
shorten my stack a lot that's not good
power rail here and so this isn't gonna
loop because there were no carts here
when the trap doors opened on that last
time so for this to keep looping this
always has to be always has to have at
least one in it but overall it seems to
be working okay I just need to fill it
all the way up and get the heck out of
here you loser how did you get in here
you oh yeah okay so this thing's full
now it's holding one two three four five
six seven eight carts used to hold ten
so that should be enough still cuz I had
too many before anyway if I need it to
hold more I tend just lower this thing
which actually wouldn't be a bad idea
because I had to run this wiring up
quite a few blocks and
should be all virgin okay down here I
want to try out my controls in the
control room to see if they work
technically this should be better now
because before every odd time it would
just stop working because it would get
an inconsistent boost using the old
booster glitch and when it quite go far
enough and it would stall out so let's
just see what happens this has to be on
startup but our hot and cold thing is
not going to work anymore and this is
our delay so a button pressure had
always started now I'm guessing
just one downside of this now is you're
gonna have that constant noise but it's
working but am i game sure legs with
that thing with the timer is running
guided me hanging 30 frames per second
now oh yes I filled that in Wow
so that's me there's no problem keeping
up there's it always at least three in
and it shouldn't stall out like it was
originally so all in all this is a lot
better now but I don't know if I'll keep
this running all the time just because
it legs my game a lot especially when
I'm recording well guys I think that's
the end of this episode pretty much did
everything I wanted to do to show you so
gonna end it here so I think we pretty
much fixed everything that's been broken
by the recent patches which is pretty
good the only thing that I think I
didn't fix is the vertical cannons and I
don't think I can without making them a
lot bigger and I'm not really excited
about fixing them so I'll probably come
up with something else
but yeah I'm happy with the storage room
the old stone looks good in my opinion
and it matches the wood kind of so I
guess we should look at the clay I
wasn't gonna say anything earlier
because I didn't want you know it's past
to find out because he likes to wreck
every one of my specials but this is my
fifteen thousand subscriber special and
also my 2.5 million view special so Wow
I just want to say thank you to
everybody very awesome
thank you for showing me your support
and for watching my videos liking them
telling your friends about them is
really really cool I'm amazed so many
people watch my videos and yeah so we've
come a long way guys no no no no it's
bad we're not doing this this episode
we're not bad
look I don't want to fight you anymore
because you're a big loser and the
chicken you are a chicken because whoa
calm down spaz calm calm down man look
you're a chicken because last time we
had a fight you called the fight and
then you hid in your Tower
the whole time and that's not cool
that's that's what a chicken does so
till you grow a pair of arms we're not
gonna fight anymore I know I am NOT a
chicken my viewers saw what happened I
didn't run away from our last fight I
walked away because you were being cheap
I am NOT a chicken no no you're the
chicken I'm telling you you're a much
bigger chicken than I am if I am a
chicken fine you know what I have an
idea of how we can show who's the bigger
chicken so meet me at the track stop
running for me stop Ronnie what are you
doing let's just go to the track okay
we're gonna go to the track
okay I'll meet you there just follow me
it's it's that way okay okay well I'm
just gonna go and then you're following
okay let's go I think I have a boat
around here I'll meet you there okay so
me and spaz have agreed to play a game
of chicken to decide who is the biggest
chicken pretty simple get out of here
whoever wins this is gonna be in charge
of the island that's what we've decided
you ready spaz okay did you get out here
all right here we go
this is it's fast
you're gonna lose you don't stand a
chance and there's no way I'm backing
down oh wait a minute
can't even hop out over my card if he
has no arms