hello everyone my name is Ethel and this
is my new Minecraft world that I've
started lately I've been having a lot of
people asking me to make a minecraft
let's play series and I thought hey may
as well try it see if I can do it and
see if people like it and if people like
it I'll keep making videos for it so I'm
going to be playing on heart just to
keep things interesting
normally I play on peaceful because I've
had issues with creepers but it should
be a fun challenge on hard so I've had a
quick look around this world just to
make sure it's a fairly nice since it is
it's got nice screen grass I like that
lots of trees so should be good and
burning daylight here so I should get
started
punch down a tree so unlike a lot of
let's play videos I'm going to assume
that you know a lot of the basics about
Minecraft I'm not going to explain to
you how to craft a stick or make an axe
or anything like that I'm just going to
assume you know that a cheap also every
now and then I'm probably going to be
making cuts in my video in case I messed
up or run out of things to say because
it's a surprisingly difficult to talk to
yourself for 15 minutes straight without
any kind of a script
and on top of that play a game and think
about what you're doing in it it's quite
challenging but I'm going to try my best
so I'm going to make an X here and I
think I'm going to go to this island
over here to get resources this is going
to be my main island and found some clay
over here which is cool maybe go down
there too
I'll do that later so I kind of had a
plan to build a road from the silent to
this island I'll probably start that
this video yeah I know you're supposed
to like cut down some trees and then
build a house and before night falls but
I don't think I'm going to be doing that
alright so now I can make make stone
tools which is cool I would like to find
some coal before dark oh oh yeah it's a
little bit hard can't do that anymore
actually I'm going to get some more wood
I really like the the lush green grass
in this biome the last world I had I had
green grass like this too but then my
game crashed and when I turned it on
again all the grass is like Ray it got
corrupted which is kind of sad all right
we found some cool
and I'm going to make some stone tools
I hate using wood tools actually I'm
just going to throw that away
be gone it's always fun starting out in
a new world
oh nice lots of coal I don't need a
whole lot but just enough get started
alright that should be good and I think
I'm gonna hit back hey-oh
thought I could make that jump but I
guess that unit deep ocean that's cool
sure wisher some pigs around sigh hey
it's a meat and make some torches
yeah so rather than building a house I
think I'm just going to dig a hole in
the ground for like station and I'll
just hide out in there for this one
night umm yeah here's a good place I
guess this may be like a kind of like a
subway station with my water roads go
straight to that Island so the road is
going to go underwater so I'll probably
want to make it maybe six or seven
blocks deep at least one of the reasons
why I'm digging down instead of building
houses so I can get resources because
right now I have none and I need lots
and lots of cobblestone and stuff so
this works out perfect and I'll try to
keep things lit so you can guys can see
it too
all right so the road itself is about
eight blocks wide
oh it's nighttime oh boy this is dirt
snow myself in so I don't die because I
am a coward
all right good as so the road it's going
to be eight blocks wide so I think I'm
going to start here and make this eight
blocks wide that's four yeah so the road
itself is eight blocks wide but I forgot
I'm going to need some kind of side
entrance to get onto the road so this is
actually going to be wider than that if
you're if you're wondering you know what
the heck is this guy talking about just
check out this link and you can see a
prototype of what I'm building
all right I'm going to make some more
tools so I think first I'm going to see
how far it is to the ocean stick
straight through here it's not very far
I'm sure if I'm under the water and I
can't see
I think I'm under the water I try to dig
up yep all right I guess that's kind of
a good thing
so my side entrance is going to be here
and make that two blocks wide so my road
will start here I think and it's going
to be eight blocks wide clear a little
bit more space all right
one two three four five six eight those
are the two ends of the road and I'm
going to come down the stairs and this
is the start of the road that means my
boat dispenser is going to be right here
and my boat return is going to be over
here and I'm going to have wall there
and wall there so I'm going to be able
to come down the stairs walk in and
there'll be a boat right here I'll
right-click on it and then they'll just
shoot me down to the island over there
that's the plan
I cleared a bit more space and it sounds
like it's daytime now can hear the
zombies dying up there so I think I'm
gonna go venture out and take a look
yeah looks good
so let's enter the first day and I think
I'm going to yeah I think I'm going to
call it an end for right now and thanks
for watching until the next episode