why hello how's it going
thanks for joining me this is at evil
and so I've been working on our storage
room a lot lately having a little bit of
trouble deciding what materials to use
kind of like this we got so at all four
corners of the storage room instead of
it being a perfect square the corners
are going to be like a round circle so
I've got sandstone and wood here I kind
of like how it looks and then there's
going to be a pillar in the center that
goes up to the ceiling and there's going
to be a vertical redstone wiring in the
center and I'm going to have like a
lever and a button and it's going to
send a signal up to the rapid for
dispensers I'm going to have four of
them total one in each of these corners
and one's going to have dirt in one's
gonna have sand one's going to have
cobblestone and I forget what goes
another one so tell me what you guys
think about these materials and if you
think something looks better tell me
quickly because I have to decide soon
[Music]
and so there's going to so I have a
sandstone in the middle of the track
here with wood on the side and there's
going to be chests on the right side
chests on the left side and there's
going to be a wall here with dispensers
like over there and so the minimum width
of the storage room at any place is
going to be 11 blocks so 4 3 4 and like
I said that might make lighting an issue
and glowstone seems to be the winner you
guys seem to if I understand correctly
you guys are ok with me putting a closed
stone in between these chests here
that's nice that's what I plan on doing
unless I understood that wrong I can't
really put torches on the walls because
there's going to be signs and dispensers
and there's no places to put torches
I think glowstone will look cool here
should I fill all these block spaces or
just like half of them like like
glowstone there there there there unlit
then put something else there there
there and there
or should I just make it solid glowstone
let me know what you think it's easy to
say hey use glowstone they look awesome
but the fact is I have to gather it
and that is not easy to gather all that
glowstone there's tons forget what I
said last video about the slows and that
did not work I did find another solution
[Music]
and I'll show you what that other
solution is some other time but for now
we are going to go to the nether we're
going to look for some glowstone and I'm
all suited up here pretty much I have a
feeling you guys said glowstone just so
I would have to go to another so then I
get my butt kicked for talking down
about it before
[Music]
so our mission here is to collect
glowstone slow sand um and a few other
things and I actually expect it I expect
to have trouble this time because what I
want to do I'm not having any trouble
here because I'm in like a Cove but one
of my missions in the nether is to
actually build a pathway out into the
center of this open area that might as
well just start it going to build a
pathway out and the reason for this is I
want to set up a 360 cannon in the
middle of an open space and use it to
shoot it gasps for fun that's one of my
goals in the nether and then I'll have
moving targets which would be pretty fun
I think
and it'll be a challenge too because
I'll have to make a cannon that works
without using water Althea will be too
hard so far so good I was like they're
all above and I was watching I think it
was a co-star guys watching co-stars
videos he was in the nether and the
Jasper shoot he had to his cobblestone
walls and I was surprised that they were
destroying them and so I looked on the
Minecraft Wikipedia why that was and
apparently the fireballs don't destroy
any of the hard materials like
cobblestone brick stone that kind of
thing which is cool because I thought
anything I built in another has a chance
of getting destroyed let's get all that
lava
[Music]
all right guys we're the ghasts I'm
still not impressed with this place okay
I thought as soon as I went out and open
here that they were going to go crazy oh
you know I forgot to check I just want
to see if this points that our spawn in
the nether I think it does if we follow
that to zero the X and the Zed
it'll take us back to our portal I think
mildly all right we made it
[Music]
there set some meat up just to chase you
got our trusty bow whoa did not see that
wait are we on hard even yeah oh it's
because I got an armor
[Music]
and a jerk around here
hey buddy how's it going will you be my
friend
let's be friends mmm try push you off
close stone stuff is awesome but it's a
pain in the button - yep and once you
place it you better not have to move it
otherwise you're gonna waste it all I
[Music]
guess they don't chase you that's good
that's cool mmm where should we go what
should we do
[Music]
I never a deflected a fireball before
come on I want to see if I can take your
best shot I have a feeling I'm not doing
all right
oh yeah
how came to you out here I cannot hear
these guys for meat
[Music]
well I'm going to hit that to our spawn
place back to the portal I have to set
up some mine carts down here or
something
can't touch this very important I don't
follow can't shoot that far oh you got
those guys turned on me
all right I finally died in the nether
[Music]
let's get her step back it was over here
you gonna get with the hash ah
I don't know what's going on now the
Wikipedia said that they won't attack
them unless you attack them
and that if they get by a fireball they
go and attack the gas they're not you
[Music]
I need oh I need another bow
don't like these guys I don't mind I
guess I just thank you my bow
[Music]
I knew I built this for a reason okay so
the new plan is oh wait are these
screams do it why didn't it be any
string oh they put my
[Music]
run for
all right so I'll have to try that again
later yeah so we're out of time and I
accomplished nothing
pretty much so I'm gonna have to go back
in there I'm going to bring a bow and
clear the cove there so that I'll be
safe again and then I'll harvest light
stone near it and slowly venture out to
get more hopefully question is D do you
want to watch me do that or should I
just skip it like I might just make a
video of three times the speed of me
going around the nether I'll let you
guys choose either way I will be doing
it on hard no exception in the nether
always has to be on heart no matter what
I'm doing and so we're going to end it
here and oh yeah so zombie pigmen are
officially my most hated mob even more
than creepers because at least with
creepers I know where I stand with them
but zombie pigmen it's like oh we're
best friends yeah we can all get along
and then as soon as you turn your back
on them they'd shove their golden sword
in your back so yeah okay see you guys