hey everyone this is e to the T to your
mum and the building is looking pretty
cool I think it's going to look a lot
different when it's finished though
you're not going to see all the inside
jets I don't think it'll be covered up
somehow I'm pretty sure and it'll be
terraformed and everything and yeah this
what I've been doing in clearing grass
lots and lots of grass think I'm almost
done it and I've noticed my passive mob
spawners working a lot faster during the
day if I get rid of all the grass that's
interfering with it it'll work just as
well during the day as it does at night
which I think I can do just because
there's so much water around that
there's really not a whole lot of grass
I need to remove but still probably a
few thousand thousand blocks and so I
got a fun fact for you guys if any of
you play Super Smash Brothers Brawl I
don't know if you know this but I
mentioned in that game quite a bit it's
true next time you play as I could do is
up B move and you'll hear my name it's
pretty cool and yeah something else I
needed to mention I've been getting this
in the comments a lot lately
some people math users
and they have been complaining that they
can open my world that they download
because it's a 7-zip file seven sevens
egg and they want me to upload it as a
zip I'm not going to do that if you do a
Google search Mac 7-zip you'll probably
find ten programs that work with Macs
that will let you decompress the archive
I think I did a search and I think one
that looked pretty good was the UH not
the unarchive er so you can try that out
and if you guys oh yeah another thing a
lot of people are asking where they
download my world's just look in the
description of the videos and you'll see
a download link there's usually at like
I have a number next to it right now
it's a 46 that means the download is
from episode 46 that's the last time it
was updated so if that number changes
that's how you can keep track um so
you're probably wondering am I going to
be clearing your ass all episode that's
pretty boring no I've actually been
demonstrating something to you that I
was working on yesterday I don't know if
you notice but I'm not playing Minecraft
with my keyboard right now or my mouse
I'm using an Xbox 360 controller I wrote
an autohotkey strip for this game so I
can now play minecraft with the xbox360
controller which is pretty cool I have a
wireless xbox360 controller hooked up to
my computer right now with the USB
receiver so I can hook up the fork and
rollers to my computer but you only need
one for Minecraft obviously and it works
fairly good actually
it's a little bit jerky when you do the
camera scrolling that's about my only
issue with it so the way I have it set
up a is jump X opens up your inventory
be toss is an item I walk with the left
thumbstick right left down up diagonally
works pretty good then I could I got the
mouse movement hooked up to the right
thumbstick so I can scroll around and
left left click is the left bumper right
click is the right bumper and a left
trigger is sneak that's pretty good and
you can also jump by pressing the right
thumbstick in so I can be moving around
the camera angle and jump at the same
time and let's see what else do I have
select is f3 and start is escape and oh
yeah pressing left on the d-pad changes
inventory to the left and right changes
to the right Y changes the viewing
distance
and I think that's it so now I can play
Minecraft on my couch through my TV
which is pretty cool instead of being
hunched over at my desk but when I do my
recordings I'm probably still going to
just use keyboard and mouse just when I
want to plate Ashley I'll use the
controller and I'm going to put the
download in the description you guys can
download it and hopefully improve it and
if you improve it let me know because I
would like to use your improved version
if you make one got brown there now and
my framerate just dropped so I'm going
to pause the video for a second and one
other thing I forgot to mention if you
push your left thumbstick in you got the
f5 camera too so to make this work guys
you need the program autohotkey it's
free and you need either a wired xbox360
controller or a wireless one but if you
had a wireless one you also need to get
the USB receiver forum so that you can
hook them up to your computer and sorry
but I probably won't help you guys if
you need help on getting autohotkey to
work there's plenty of tutorials out
there just do a google search if you
have trouble because I don't know too
much about it either all right so today
we're not going to be working on the mob
system I'm going to take a break from
that I think I got it pretty much
figured out now I just have to do it but
today we're going to be working on
designing a new tree farm because it's
about time this one gets retired
so the new one I think is going to go
all the way around the spawning pads up
there and we need to figure out a new
design and I got an idea in mind I just
need to see how well it works and then
hollow out a five by five thing and
probably set up the water tool okay I've
always wanted to make a tree farm that
had a Auto collection thing for the
saplings I've never done that before and
so that's what we're going to try to do
but it's not going to be 100 percent
collection either that's that would be
just silly
this is actually what I plan on doing
something like this with Wolves to to
shear the sheep automatically what I'm
going to do is the sheep and cows are
going to fall in to the center of a
whirlpool like this and also I'm going
to have to find some way to regulate the
Wolves so there's always one or two in
this and they'll all be drawn to the
center the Wolves will attack the sheep
and the cows and kill them and get the
wool and leather from them and then
there'll be a collection point in the
middle where all the loot goes to does
it matter where anything drops there'll
be a glass all around this five by five
to so that they can't get out so it all
will float to the center and then go
into another tube and the animals you
swim I think that's the plan something
like that I'm actually going to this was
suggested by one of the viewers I forgot
who it was I probably should have wrote
it down someone left a comment that I
should build a barn in the front there
and I might do that it's kind of a fun
idea too
[Music]
actually no what I'm going to switch
over to the mouse and keyboard because
this is that that's a little bit tricky
to do still because I'm not too used to
the controller yet
okay so trees going to go in the center
of this
[Music]
it has to be up on a loop we'll go to
the saplings Loulou collection area in
the middle
and going to have little drawbridges
[Music]
actually let's set up to tree things
[Applause]
this is just a test guys I'm not putting
them here and I know when you make tree
farms you can cuddle them all close
together but I don't like doing that
because it's kind of a pain to harvest
them when they're all clumped together
okay so we got the Whirlpool's trees one
there and then we'll have stone slabs
going between them probably something
like this probably made out of wood or
sandstone something that looks better so
to go from tree to tree go up here take
my axe out harvest a tree keep walking
harvest a tree all the saplings should
fall in these not all this happens most
of the saplings should fall into these
up water collection things and let's see
one two three
there'll be glass I think oh I need
torches too
I'm going to have class there so that
the tree is forced to grow that tall so
that there's no leaves in my way when
I'm walking through and there's going to
be torches so that there's enough light
for the tree to grow and there'll be a
glass stopper like eight or nine blocks
up so that the tree can't become one of
those giants huge trees because those
are hard to harvest when you get some
saplings now I'm not used to playing
with the keyboard and mouse saplings
we'll go there and we got some bone
let's try that's the other thing with
just the changes in the game I want to
set up so that I can grow them using
bone meal if I want three four five six
seven eight nine ten eleven and twelve
thirteen fourteen fifteen sixteen
seventeen eighteen nineteen Twenty
twenty one twenty two - three - four -
five - six smooth
hmm well I had no stop right now
I should probably set up the stopper
bonemeal is not going to work out too
well fact it press it 25 times that one
to three glass and one two three four
that's probably good enough for the test
[Applause]
okay so now I can't do that
let's see how many it takes this time it
was about 15 I think another option is
to use signs I think yeah select glass
stopper can probably be a bit higher and
their saplings are falling in the water
um see how these signs I think that
would work instead of using the glass it
will force the leaves to go higher than
that point a I hurt you not today buddy
not today actually that probably won't
work out too well
signs I'll probably keep it the glass
like that so the other idea I have is
I'm going to set up like an eats road
around this thing if that makes any
sense somehow
holding a fixed I don't know the zombies
got fixed in the patch so yeah somehow I
want to step in each road I think if I
make pressure plates and line the
outside out of something like that
and then have a wall oh yeah freakin
buggers I wear the Wolves I'm sure
there's a wolf around here
[Applause]
kneadable where's my bowl I saw there's
a creature here okay
like I was saying I'm gonna make some
ladders here
I can't do anything out here I got to
place torches on my because because of
that mob system they spawned like crazy
on the island now I see oh yeah
nice try I heard you again
this isn't working out too well set up
an each road on the outside and water
and gotta make I'll probably just have
one boat
constantly looping around the outside
would be one stream that just keeps
going around and around I guess it would
have to be counterclockwise and I want
to see if I can actually I know I can
get the book only around our loop I want
to see if I can actually reach the trees
from the boat the whole point of this
boat on again so that I can
automatically go around the tree farm
and plant saplings that's too far
so this is going to work I need to raise
the boat I think at least one block
[Applause]
so I have it up one block
oh I see I want my boat move now that's
where it even with the ladders gone it
wouldn't let me move it
hey can I reach now just barely mmm
I think I'm going to have to move the
closer one block one block closer so
this is that like an ideal position the
boat will automatically take me around
I'll be able to plant the trees easily
that way and also I should be able to
apply bone meal as I'm going around I
might have to do that side thing so that
I can lower the stoppers by one so that
the tree is more likely to grow when you
apply bone meal because this isn't going
to work out too well if it takes 20
applications or so ideally I want it in
around five or less
so to get the signs where I want them
I'll probably have to put signs on top
of signs and hopefully it won't look too
ugly and I'll I'll mess around with it
to probably figure out something let me
know if you guys have any other ideas
and so all these collection points are
going to be hooked together and all the
saplings will be brought to one spot
hopefully Wow
but that one spot is not going to be the
main collection area I'll probably do it
in some other area just because I don't
want tree saplings in here I'm surprised
I haven't seen any wolves it usually
comes around but yeah that's the plan
and that's the episode thanks for
watching next one will be the 1 million
view special I think actually this one
is probably going to come out just
before I hit 1 million and so we're
going to launch off the fireworks yeah
we'll be a few more cannons there and
we'll probably do some other stuff too
thanks for watching everybody and I'll
see you next time