hey guys Etha here thank you for joining
me again um I have been working on this
and I've been having a lot of trouble
making it look good so um I thought hey
why not start recording now so people
can watch me fail at building something
I'm working on the barn I've finally
figured out pretty much how I'm going to
do it roughly in my head but obviously
the fine details like this are not going
so well I decided to make it raised off
the ground about five blocks or so just
so it's a little bit to offer a little
bit of variation and Heights and stuff
it's nice but yeah so this is going to
be a walk way to get up into the barn
I'm going to have a balcony round it and
when I say barn I don't mean like a
traditional sense of the word I was
thinking about making one of those nice
big red barn type buildings like an
actual red barn but I don't know if I am
really good enough to do that so I'm
just going to be basically building a
wooden building and calling it a barn
and I'm going to skip ahead to day so we
can see all right much better so another
reason I can't build a red barn is I
don't have that much red dye or that
much wool so probably just be like a
normal type of building probably a
little bit strange of course I'm
planning on maybe moving the ocean out
further so there's probably going to be
a drop down here and they'll be like
land here
or something yeah but let's get the work
here this is going to be mostly a
building episode I was trying to mix
some wood and stuff into this so it one
so it would look a little bit better but
I think it's actually making it look
worse and I've got these windows that
stick out like I like now I'm going to
be using those a lot I think let's build
another one actually I think I want one
right here just a small 2x2 window I
think okay and maybe one on the other
side too would be nice this is gonna be
like a building episode I don't know if
I set that already oops yeah okay I
don't know if I should you know I think
I'm just going to build out a solid
planks because mixing these two is not
working out for me too well that's kind
of what I did with my tree farm and
cactus farm I just made it solid and I
don't think it looks too bad
okay looks pretty weird that's alright I
can keep tweaking it until it looks
proper I kind of think I need this to
come out more I'll probably be a glass
roof over this and the balcony is going
to be here I extend it one more I kind
of want the balcony at least two or
three wide okay I'm going to extend it
one more and I think I'm going to place
the building here
so there might be doors right where I am
here I should probably figure out the
dimensions I actually have a very
specific plan that I haven't tested but
I think it'll work something I'm going
to try to do with the sheep and cows I
kind of figure out something cool when I
was building the record while attempting
to build the record studio a long time
ago a neat little trick that I'm going
to implement into the barn and I'm not
going to tell you what it is just yet
yeah okay I got to figure out the
dimensions so I think it's gotta be
minimum 15 by 15 and how does that
compare with my storage room let's see 1
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15
yeah that's pretty small
maybe I will make it bigger okay well
I'm going to lay the base for the floor
Allen once I figure out what the
dimensions are and I'll do that off
camera and then we will hopefully start
building some stuff in it right okay so
looking pretty ugly yeah you know what I
like about wood if you ever build
something so horrendous so ugly that you
can't believe you built that that it's
the stupidest thing you've ever seen you
can just simply light on fire but this
is going to stay as strange and dumb as
it looks I will make it work somehow
because this is how I want it actually
this is not going to make a whole lot of
sense
you guys just yet these sandstone blocks
are crucial to this design in some
mysterious way oh yeah and this is
without the balcony if I build a balcony
so wait how big is this one two three
four five six seven eight nine 10 11 12
13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 it's going to be
over 20 by 20 mm-hmm
probably should built a little bit
higher but oh well I'll make it work yep
my mind is made up this is what we're
going to be doing this building stays so
let's let's build it up some more shall
we
I'm going to place a wall all around it
and while I do this I'm going to talk
about a few things first of all I want
to give shout outs to people to davy-boy
productions
he made my new channel icon and very
generously he offered to do it for me
and he actually made me one before and I
asked if he could do one with the white
border around it and he did and I liked
it even more so thank you Davey Boy
Productions for making me an icon and I
also wanted to give a shout out to the
mister shizzle this guy's really cool
that he puts himself out there to help
other
people and he's a talented artist he
made em 77s channel background and I
think possibly a few other youtubers he
just offers to do things for people and
he's always leaving nice comments and
stuff in people's videos which is really
cool and so mr. mr. Isabelle offered to
make me a channel background and it
looks pretty good from what I've seen so
far and I'm excited to see what it's
going to look like when it's Sun so
thank you mr. chisel for making me or
working on a channel background for me
because I am not very artistic and
that's just awesome because I probably
couldn't do one myself so thank you
Davey Boy Productions and the mister
chisel you guys are awesome and links in
let the description of this video if you
want to check out their channels okay
see we're going to set up some windows
here 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 4 5 6 good
it's going to be similar to my tree
farming cactus farm ok and I also want
to talk about one other thing there's a
new game coming out called terraria I
believe I said that right um I've been
looking forward to playing this for a
while and the other day actually today
today somebody told me it comes out on
Steam on may 16 and I'm thinking I might
start a new
let's play with it of course I won't
stop the Minecraft one but you know once
in a while I might do some terraria
Let's Plays and I want to know what you
guys think of that I'll put a link to
its trailer in the description as well
and if you haven't seen it already check
it out it looks like a pretty
interesting game a lot of people call it
a 2-d minecraft and it is in a lot of
ways but it really is a completely
different game so it's not really fair
to call it that there's lots of things I
like about it there's a few things I
don't quite like about it but all in all
it looks like a pretty good game it
might be a little bit linear like I
might get tired of it but overall I
think it's definitely worth the 10 bucks
or whatever it it's going to be and I
think I'll have a lot of fun playing it
so yeah let me know if you guys think I
should make an LP on it either way I'll
probably buy it and I look forward to
playing it 5 ok so this is coming
together I probably won't be all planks
like it is right now I'll probably
switch the flooring to include some
sandstone and some logs and it'll look a
lot better when it's done I'm sure but
this is just temporary there's going to
be something special on this side here
so I'm going to leave that for now
it's actually a pretty complicated build
one two three four five six seven eight
don't know why I doubt it I could have
just looked at the numbers one two three
one two three um there there there there
there
good okay
let's place some doors I bet you guys
are just loving and I'm not telling you
what any of this stuff is for I'll
probably explain it in a lot of detail
next episode I don't think I really have
time to get into it this episode so
that's why I'm not really saying
anything
because I kind of want it to be
surprised too and to leave you wondering
because this probably looks really
strange to you at the moment
awesome
okay good these ah what could you so be
doing I wonder
okay let's place our windows I love
these windows a lot it looks a little
weird on the outside though that's the
only thing I don't like about them but
they look better if they're bigger
I'm actually in the middle of a secret
project as well you might see that soon
it's not the secret project but it's a
secret project so we got quite a bit
done this episode I think it's getting
close to the end have fun guessing what
the heck I'm doing here and I know it
looks ugly I do I will somehow made you
look good
but it might take a while but function
comes first
and then looks come second and I'm
really hoping my plan with these
sandstone blocks actually works because
I haven't really tested it and it's
going to suck if it doesn't work because
then I'll have to redo this this will
all be for nothing all right cool
and I'm still working Lots lately I feel
easier to put out episodes and I thought
it was going to be despite my busy
schedule which is good it's especially
easy when I do building episodes like
this because I don't really need to do
anything off-camera
alright um yeah okay so the balcony will
probably wrap around the building
somehow and I'll clean this up it'll
work I just have to keep telling myself
it will work and I'll probably have some
kind of pillars coming off of this kind
of like the tree farm and cactus farm or
like I mean like supports pillars or
columns or whatever they are legs my
plans for the front here are going to be
different that's for sure because I
never really intended on building
anything like this especially not
anything this big and ugly
but it'll work I just have to keep
telling myself okay well thank you for
watching that's it for today next
episode we will will slightly go into
detail of what that stuff is all for and
why I left that one wall and complete
hopefully and I'll see you then